# Transcript
ID: ffa8c660-d534-11ed-8800-85fa158bdfd3
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Twitter blue check chaos and CarPlay squabbles
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6389274455218958759/3063693691983621813/s93290-US-4937s-1680865910.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss the end of Twitter and the future of infotainment.
Links:
The color quiz
Twitter tried to hide who pays for their checkmark, but life finds a way.
https://twitter.com/AlexBlechman/status/1641905502043926530
Substack is getting a Twitter-like ‘Notes’ feed
Elon Musk’s obsession with blue checks is a verified problem
Twitter yanks the New York Times’ checkmark in verification overhaul
Today in Twitter: where are the retweet labels, and why did Doge replace the bird?
Spotify shuts down its Clubhouse competitor
Spotify shows how the live audio boom has gone bust
Everybody hates GM’s decision to kill Apple CarPlay and Android Auto for its EVs
The rest of the auto industry still loves CarPlay and Android Auto
GM is cutting off access to Apple CarPlay and Android Auto for its future EVs
Could a new PlayStation handheld be built for Remote Play? I like the idea
Asus ROG Ally handheld gaming PC is no April Fools’ joke
Walmart’s redesigned website looks better than Amazon
Donald Trump was arrested, please like and subscribe
The Home Assistant SkyConnect is a combination Zigbee and Thread dongle for better smart home control
Vote for us in the People’s Voice Webby Awards for Best Technology Podcast!
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  Support for today's show comes from Deloitte. In the business world, it can
Speaker 1:  be especially crucial to innovate. You can either build your own future or
Speaker 1:  bet on someone else's. No one knows what tomorrow will bring, but you push
Speaker 1:  forward and create enterprise anyway. That's why Deloitte's mission is to
Speaker 1:  help engineer advantage for their clients by harnessing the latest innovations
Speaker 1:  and technology while exploring the ideas and opportunities that can look
Speaker 1:  beyond today. Transform what's next into what's now.
Speaker 1:  See how you can engineer advantage with Deloitte at
Speaker 1:  deloitte.com/us/engineering advantage.
Speaker 3:  The HBO drama's succession is in its fourth and final season.
Speaker 3:  And for diehard fans, some of the characters have achieved pop
Speaker 3:  star status.
Speaker 4:  That just feels like, so like, you know, you're that bitch you calls all
Speaker 4:  that conversation like that. Like he's it.
Speaker 4:  I just kind of like,
Speaker 3:  Did you just compare Logan Roy to Beyonce?
Speaker 4:  Well, I mean, why not?
Speaker 3:  Oh, let's keep this going. We talk succession this week
Speaker 3:  on Intuit Vultures Pop culture podcast.
Speaker 2:  Hello.
Speaker 5:  Welcome to our chest, the flagship podcast of not knowing what color
Speaker 5:  Spotify's logo is. I'm your friend Eli. It's so hard,
Speaker 1:  So
Speaker 5:  Hard. Alex Trans is here.
Speaker 1:  I'm not colorblind, but I think I might be
Speaker 5:  After the color quiz. Yeah. David Pierce is
Speaker 6:  Here. Hi. I got the first four right on our color quiz and was so
Speaker 6:  like absolutely outrageously proud of myself. And then I think
Speaker 6:  got the next three wrong and have not forgiven myself for it.
Speaker 5:  It's not great. So it's design week here at the Verge. It's got a great
Speaker 5:  package. It's super fun. We've got pieces on ui,
Speaker 5:  we've got pieces on the, like how the logout button
Speaker 5:  on website works or more importantly doesn't work. We've got pieces on
Speaker 5:  accessibility and design that are coming that's very exciting. But the
Speaker 5:  highlight of the whole week was our color quiz, which is designed
Speaker 5:  by our associate creative director, Chris Raske, who's a genius, our
Speaker 5:  engineer Graham, who is an evil mastermind and it's ma
Speaker 5:  it's just made to torture us. And all you're supposed to do
Speaker 5:  is you open it, you see five shades of blue and you gotta pick the one that's
Speaker 5:  the Facebook logo. And the the, the thing that makes
Speaker 5:  it evil is that as you roll over each of the shades of blue, there's an actual
Speaker 5:  Facebook logo that changes. So then you just sit there arguing with
Speaker 5:  yourself cuz every one of them looks correct. Well
Speaker 1:  The Facebook one's also like a cheat because there's like an old Facebook
Speaker 1:  color on there. So you're like, that's the one because I haven't checked
Speaker 1:  Facebook in 10 years.
Speaker 5:  I've been taking this quiz over and over again all week. I've, I can't get
Speaker 5:  better at it. The only one that I get consistently is Snapchat. I'm very
Speaker 5:  good at yellow. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Just, just yellow.
Speaker 5:  Well, so the only app on my phone that Max wants to use is a
Speaker 5:  Snapchat, but she can't, she can't read. It's and it cuz she's four.
Speaker 6:  That's an important detail. She's four.
Speaker 1:  Don't worry guys, it's
Speaker 5:  So, she just calls it the ghost button. Yeah, it's perfect sense. First
Speaker 6:  Of all, unbelievable product idea for Snapchat. I love that. To sell something
Speaker 6:  called a ghost button. I don't know what it does.
Speaker 5:  She'll just pick up my phone and be like, ghost button. And I was like, and
Speaker 5:  then we just do the filters so I know what that one looks like. Yeah. Yelp.
Speaker 5:  No, no, no idea what color red Yelp is. And there's actually, there's
Speaker 5:  science in the quiz. If you haven't taken it, go on the site, do the color
Speaker 5:  quiz, it will drive you bananas. And then with a sense of
Speaker 5:  smugness and superiority, go make other people take it. Yes,
Speaker 5:  there are people on our staff who've gotten them. All right. We over 20,000
Speaker 5:  people have taken this quiz so far. I
Speaker 1:  Think it's up to 50,000. It's
Speaker 5:  Up to 50,000.
Speaker 1:  A lot of people have taken this quiz
Speaker 5:  And like you can see the scores they normalize like around 4.5.
Speaker 1:  I got six the sec, the first time I did it, I got four. Oh my God. The second
Speaker 1:  time I got six and the two I got wrong. I was like, that can't
Speaker 1:  be the color. I'm gonna pick this other one. And it was the color. So I feel
Speaker 1:  like I could do eight if I just practiced.
Speaker 5:  See, see, see.
Speaker 1:  Just keep doing it.
Speaker 5:  David, how'd you do?
Speaker 6:  I ended up with six out of eight. Yelp was the one that I got
Speaker 6:  to and was just instantly like, I'm not gonna know this one. This isn't gonna
Speaker 6:  happen. So I just basically like closed my eyes and hammered our shade of
Speaker 6:  red. And that was that the one I got wrong
Speaker 6:  that I'm furious. Like I, I can still, you know, picture the moment
Speaker 6:  when I got it wrong with Spotify and I was down to two shades of green
Speaker 6:  and my, my rubric was basically like pick the second best
Speaker 6:  looking one if I don't know which one it is. Because usually there's one
Speaker 6:  that's like simple and clean and chill and like no tech company's ever gonna
Speaker 6:  choose that one. So you pick the, the second chillest one
Speaker 6:  and that's usually the one. And it served me really well except in
Speaker 6:  Spotify's case where they just went like full bonkers neon and it just
Speaker 6:  is supposed to hurt your brain. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Spotify. Yeah. And Lyft. Yeah. Go take it. Go look
Speaker 5:  at all of design week. It's super fun. It's great. Sarah Jung has a piece
Speaker 5:  about the poop emoji in legal filings and how it's breaking
Speaker 5:  database systems across our country's court system. Very good. Like
Speaker 5:  cackling, when I was reading it, we've got one about the shuffle button and
Speaker 5:  then we, we were doing this big partnership with the Computer history museum
Speaker 5:  about the history of the Lisa Apple, Lisa the precursor to
Speaker 5:  Macintosh. It's super cool. Go watch that video. Go read that piece. All
Speaker 5:  great design week happening. Go look at it. Take the color
Speaker 1:  Quiz. Fail at the color quiz.
Speaker 6:  Tell us what you got. Tell we wanna
Speaker 5:  Know. Well the reason I want more people to take it is right now the audience
Speaker 5:  average score is higher than the Verge team score. I feel like if we can
Speaker 5:  just get more people to take it, we equal the staff
Speaker 5:  can outdo the world.
Speaker 1:  I think everybody's cheating. I think everybody's like going and like they've
Speaker 1:  got it on their phone, they're holding their phone up next to it, whereas
Speaker 1:  we didn't, we took it the real way.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We all had to take it on camera in a conference room so that we could
Speaker 5:  make like marketing videos for it. It's
Speaker 6:  My favorite was someone on our team who I won't name said in Slack cuz
Speaker 6:  we were all talking about it. Like, oh, I didn't do very well. But then when
Speaker 6:  I got to be on a monitor with a better color gamut, I got, I did better.
Speaker 6:  And it was like, oh, okay. I'm sure you
Speaker 5:  Did. My controller's broken.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, exactly. Must have been the lag. I don't know.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  All right. Go take the color quiz. Look at Design Week. A very cool
Speaker 5:  situation on the verge.com this week. Speaking of the verge.com story
Speaker 5:  that we've uncovered. This is the worst segue podcast.
Speaker 1:  This is, where's this going?
Speaker 5:  Speaking of websites that start with the letter T. Twitter is kind of a
Speaker 5:  disastrous,
Speaker 1:  Much better, much better segue. It's
Speaker 5:  Good. It's not great. It's what we're doing. Twitter had a very
Speaker 5:  hard weekend, I would say
Speaker 5:  in the context of Twitter's other weekends actually not that hard. Like
Speaker 5:  equally bad. Yeah, but this is the weekend they that they started turning
Speaker 5:  off verification.
Speaker 1:  Have you, have you been deified yet? No. Same.
Speaker 5:  There was a rumor going around that if you blocked
Speaker 5:  the verified account on Twitter, they could not deify you.
Speaker 1:  I I did it just to see if that'll happen.
Speaker 5:  I was like, I got nothing to lose. But like David,
Speaker 5:  the the actual mechanics of unifying and then what they
Speaker 5:  actually did. None of it seems to make any sense.
Speaker 6:  No. So what turns out to be the case there was some really good Washington
Speaker 6:  Post reporting on this a few days ago, is that essentially there's just
Speaker 6:  like a database of all the verified people on Twitter. You would
Speaker 6:  think this is like a, a thing that lives inside of the app that is somehow
Speaker 6:  sort of controllable and understandable. It's really not. It's like somebody
Speaker 6:  just went and like pasted a picture onto your
Speaker 6:  profile and then like wrote down in a line of a spreadsheet. I pasted the
Speaker 6:  picture onto their profile. Yes. It's slightly more technical than that,
Speaker 6:  but not much more technical than that. And so what that means is what seems
Speaker 6:  to be happening is there is no way to sort of systematically find
Speaker 6:  out and remove verification. So simultaneously
Speaker 6:  what has been going on is that the whole idea of
Speaker 6:  paying $8 a month for Twitter blue has become deeply embarrassing, which
Speaker 6:  is what we've talked about on this show. And so
Speaker 1:  I called it Victory Lap for
Speaker 6:  Me. Yeah, you did. Like you, you continue to have been right about that.
Speaker 6:  So
Speaker 5:  I'm so worried you're gonna be right about the other thing.
Speaker 1:  I am, I'm gonna win that bet. Monica. Liz, get ready.
Speaker 6:  We're not talking about this now. This is, listen, we this, a lot of things
Speaker 6:  happened while I was on leave, but I'm back now and we can't do this anymore.
Speaker 6:  Alex,
Speaker 1:  It's coming. Just
Speaker 5:  Alex thinks Elon's gonna tweet a dong. I just, let's be clear. That's what
Speaker 5:  she thinks is gonna happen.
Speaker 1:  It's it's every day we get a little closer.
Speaker 5:  Anyway, Alex victory lap one blue check
Speaker 5:  mark of shame. Go ahead, continue David.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so I, being verified is now bad
Speaker 6:  if you've paid for Twitter Blue and also they can't unverified people. So
Speaker 6:  it's become this messy thing where they've actually changed the
Speaker 6:  message on verification to, they either paid for Twitter
Speaker 6:  blue or are a legacy verified account and there's no
Speaker 6:  real indication if that's sort of the end state or if it's gonna change.
Speaker 6:  People have come up with chrome extensions that will show you which is
Speaker 6:  which, like there's one script that replaces the verified
Speaker 6:  icon with the nerd emoji if you paid for Twitter Blue, which is just
Speaker 6:  wonderful. And so it's gotten to this point now where this, there's, it's
Speaker 6:  just a disaster, right? Like the upside of paying for Twitter blue is that
Speaker 6:  you get more play, you get shown in the for you page, you
Speaker 6:  get supposedly up ranked in replies and things like that. So it's
Speaker 6:  literally just a mark of thirstiness and so there's no reason anybody would
Speaker 6:  pay for it. And so you've had people like LeBron James say, of course I'm
Speaker 6:  not gonna pay for Twitter blue. Which is a terrible look for Elon Musk and
Speaker 6:  Twitter. You have folks like the New York Times who have said there was a
Speaker 6:  big round of media organizations talking about whether or not they're gonna
Speaker 6:  pay for Twitter Blue. And then Elon Musk Vindictively was like, well then
Speaker 6:  we're gonna take that away from them. So he took off the blue check for the
Speaker 6:  New York Times, but not a bunch of the other New York Times accounts. So
Speaker 6:  it's just
Speaker 5:  Some of which by the way, some of which have gold checks,
Speaker 6:  Whatever that is.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So the is my, here's my understanding in
Speaker 5:  this disclosure alert we run Twitter
Speaker 5:  accounts. I yeah, sure. I dunno what to
Speaker 6:  Tell you. We're all verifi verifying Twitter.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Dis disclosure. I I have a phone. It contains
Speaker 5:  all the apps. I used them all. We
Speaker 6:  Have accounts. Mila, did you pay for Twitter Blue? Be honest, I did not.
Speaker 6:  This is a safe space. Did you pay?
Speaker 5:  I paid for Twitter Blue. He paid for it. I paid for all Reckless
Speaker 5:  Patel. Paid for, yeah. Reckless Patel and then got banned. My, my
Speaker 5:  Dopel gang got banned for impersonating me. Even though that person was
Speaker 5:  Alex who's sitting right here. What? It's gone now. It's gone. It's all
Speaker 5:  gone. Alright. Truly, truly wonderful. So we run Verge
Speaker 5:  accounts. Yeah, the Verge has an account. We verge reviews
Speaker 5:  Verge Science, we got a bunch of accounts. What we were told and I think
Speaker 5:  has become publicly disclosed by Twitter is that if you were
Speaker 5:  one of the top 10,000 followed accounts on Twitter, you
Speaker 5:  got Twitter blue, you got a check mark for free and you have to like
Speaker 5:  use the API tools and then you could like have five
Speaker 5:  affiliated accounts. But then if you weren't one of those and you paid for
Speaker 5:  it, the affiliated accounts got like gold check marks and then like
Speaker 5:  icons next to them. Too much very unclear. Like how it actually works.
Speaker 5:  So the times some of their accounts have gold check marks, which means
Speaker 5:  they're affiliated with the New York Times, but the New York Times does
Speaker 5:  not have a check mark because Elon's mad at them. Perfect. I
Speaker 5:  dunno man. Like all that's crazy. So we, the Verge
Speaker 5:  accounts are affiliated, they're in it something, something something.
Speaker 5:  API usage rules, something, who knows it will change tomorrow. Our
Speaker 5:  poor like audience director Ruben is just like beside himself
Speaker 5:  every day, softly weeping what's going on. And then the
Speaker 5:  other piece of the puzzle as far as I understand it is like he's
Speaker 5:  just adding labels to things like NPR saying you're state affiliated media.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And you just get, there's just a, there's a conference room, a Twitter
Speaker 5:  headquarters that's been stripped to furniture cuz he sold it all on eBay
Speaker 5:  and he is just sitting on the floor like adding and removing labels
Speaker 5:  from people's Twitter's account. There's an air mattress in the corner for
Speaker 5:  someone. He has added beds. Yeah, there's beds. Like people are living there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And he's like, he's like, I don't know, make it the Doge icon. It's
Speaker 5:  actually good. Like there's a part of it that I love. Yeah. Which is what
Speaker 5:  if you were allowed to screw the
Speaker 5:  major social network? It's like, yeah, I would just do whatever he wanted.
Speaker 5:  And he did.
Speaker 6:  I mean, it, it is sort of fun to imagine like what he would do differently
Speaker 6:  if he were trying to kill it as fast as possible. Like would,
Speaker 6:  would any of his moves change it? None. This all seems so destructive. And
Speaker 6:  the thing is like the Twitter blue stuff is, is silly and funny and
Speaker 6:  whatever. And like the changing the Twitter icon to the Doge icon is like
Speaker 6:  whatever. Ultimately I have no feelings about that. It, it's, it's sort of
Speaker 6:  hilarious and doesn't really matter at all. But like Twitter Blue is the
Speaker 6:  overwhelming favorite to be the future of Twitter. If Twitter has a
Speaker 6:  future, like its ad business has tanked, its usership is going
Speaker 6:  down. Like Elon Musk get said over and over, he has like big weird banking
Speaker 6:  ideas that he won't let go of. But like fundamentally the way Twitter is
Speaker 6:  going to survive if it's going to survive is to get a lot of people to pay
Speaker 6:  for Twitter blue. And basically all that has happened so far is
Speaker 6:  paying for Twitter. Blue has gotten deeply embarrassing and
Speaker 6:  no one who has any actual like reputation to protect
Speaker 6:  will do it. Like there was somebody who was tweeting the other day, like
Speaker 6:  imagine if you had a platform, imagine what it would cost to get LeBron
Speaker 6:  James to provide content for you. And imagine if by some crazy miracle you
Speaker 6:  had done that for free. Imagine then what would happen if you just
Speaker 6:  systematically drove him away.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. For $96 a year. Yeah. It was a very good tweet. I don't remember who
Speaker 5:  it was. It was very good. It's
Speaker 6:  A good tweet. We'll we'll find it and put it in the show notes cuz it's,
Speaker 6:  it's a good tweet.
Speaker 5:  That is the part to me and there are arguments that I've seen from people
Speaker 5:  I respect for paying, right? If you run
Speaker 5:  a small publication and you are paying and you get boosted
Speaker 5:  in for you Sure. That might work for you. I've seen arguments from
Speaker 5:  advertisers right now of small companies who are like, this is the
Speaker 5:  most efficient advertising we can buy because no one else is here. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  For eight bucks a month
Speaker 5:  It's working. And then MyPillow guy. Yeah. No, not even like, not just Twitter
Speaker 5:  Blue, like actually buying Twitter ads right now. Oh,
Speaker 6:  Interesting.
Speaker 5:  Because they're so cheap cuz there's no, it's it's you,
Speaker 5:  it's you and the MyPillow guy. Yeah. Like it's what you're doing. And so
Speaker 5:  you can just buy a reach on Twitter as long as it exists. So there's, there's
Speaker 5:  a dynamic there that's happening, but the more important thing
Speaker 5:  that's happening, and we don't have to like talk about Mask done
Speaker 5:  because who knows, but the mo more important thing that's happening is
Speaker 5:  anecdotally a lot of people I know are like, my engagement on Twitter has
Speaker 5:  plummeted. Yep. The audiences aren't real. It it's all just a bunch
Speaker 5:  of people yelling about Elon all the time. Even there was
Speaker 5:  the, the, you know, the Trump indictment this week. Like it's quiet.
Speaker 5:  There was a time when not being on Twitter during that day
Speaker 5:  would've felt like a huge miss. Like all the actions unfolding on
Speaker 5:  Twitter. And I was like, I just opened cable news.
Speaker 5:  Like I I'm, ooh, this is weird. Yeah. Like what
Speaker 5:  a weird reaction to this day is like, I'm gonna watch cable news
Speaker 5:  because Twitter isn't any good.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It was not, it's not worth it anymore. Yeah. It's like just kind of
Speaker 1:  weirdos being angry about, I say that as somebody who's still on Twitter,
Speaker 5:  I I'm one of
Speaker 1:  Those weirdos, I count myself as one of those weirdos. But yeah, it's just
Speaker 1:  people being vaguely angry about whatever's happening that day.
Speaker 1:  And it like boils Twitter's boiled down to like the most
Speaker 1:  obnoxious elements of Twitter previously. Yeah. With no
Speaker 1:  real value
Speaker 6:  Added real. And Elon Musk tweet in every other slot on your
Speaker 6:  timeline because he demanded,
Speaker 1:  I I actually don't ever see him on, on mine. I don't know why.
Speaker 6:  How is that possible?
Speaker 1:  Maybe he blocked me, maybe I blocked him. I don't know.
Speaker 5:  A very funny thing that happened this week is that Elon is using the four
Speaker 5:  UAB as well. Yeah. So he's just replying to ancient tweets.
Speaker 5:  So he just replied to an ancient tweet from our own James
Speaker 5:  Vincent about Bard and Bing citing each other. Yeah. And he just
Speaker 5:  hit it with a lull. So like James woke up to an army of
Speaker 5:  bots that follow Elon around the internet, repeating whatever he
Speaker 5:  said, replying to like a tweet from two weeks ago. Like a
Speaker 5:  perfect encapsulation of the, of the Twitter moment.
Speaker 1:  Do you think Elon's ever gonna realize that so many of his followers that
Speaker 1:  he thinks love him and adore him are bots? Like we knew he, he's always had
Speaker 1:  an issue with bots, but do you think he realizes that like what he bought
Speaker 1:  was a giant bot network?
Speaker 5:  Oh he definitely knows Cheer him bought, he tried to not buy it because of
Speaker 5:  the bot networks, if you will recall. That's true. And now he's like, wait,
Speaker 5:  they're the only, they're what I got. I don't want a, a big theme
Speaker 5:  of the podcast today for the audience is the host
Speaker 5:  assigning themselves stories that we have talked about and not yet published.
Speaker 5:  So David, I don't want to get too much into what comes next in, maam, but
Speaker 5:  you and I have talked a lot about Activity Pub we have, and you have promised
Speaker 5:  me a story next week on this so we can follow this up. But there's no big
Speaker 5:  competitor to Twitter yet, right? Like every other social network is like,
Speaker 5:  ah, what if we were TikTok instead?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That is kind of happening and I think it, it looks
Speaker 6:  increasingly unlikely that Mastodon is going to be that thing like
Speaker 6:  Macedon scoring really fast. It's doing really well. I think anyone paying
Speaker 6:  attention would say that Macedon is a success story, right? But it is like
Speaker 6:  several orders of magnitude smaller than Twitter
Speaker 6:  and it's even having its own funny issues now because Macedon set itself
Speaker 6:  up as such an aggressive counter to Twitter that
Speaker 6:  now like if you're on Macedon, you're obligated to call Twitter the bird
Speaker 6:  site. You can't even say Twitter. You just say the Bird site. And if
Speaker 6:  you, if you acknowledge being on Mastodon and on Twitter, it's like you've
Speaker 6:  violated the spirit of Mastodon and thus everyone
Speaker 6:  will yell at you. Like it's, it's really become a thing that if you are a
Speaker 6:  person who uses Mastodon on Twitter, you are like unwelcome on Mastodon.
Speaker 6:  And in a really funny way, that is a huge problem for Macedon because
Speaker 6:  it is supposed to be the place that is like better than Twitter.
Speaker 6:  And instead it's just people yelling about Twitter, which is also what Twitter
Speaker 6:  is like, we've accomplished nothing here. And so I think we're in a place
Speaker 6:  now where I keep talking to people who are really excited about like the
Speaker 6:  next phase of things, right? And I think Activity Pub in this whole idea
Speaker 6:  of a decentralized internet and social ecosystem that
Speaker 6:  doesn't rely on one platform and one person because we've seen
Speaker 6:  what happens now, right? Like we, we all used to talk about, you know, what
Speaker 6:  would happen if Mark Zuckerberg stopped being the CEO of
Speaker 6:  Facebook and someone with less good intentions came in. That all seems like
Speaker 6:  hilariously naive now in retrospect. But like we used to have those conversations
Speaker 6:  and then it was like, what if a maniac buys Twitter and does
Speaker 6:  insane stuff with it every single day like we know now, right? And so there's
Speaker 6:  this big push towards an internet and a social world that is
Speaker 6:  immune to those things. But I think there was a brief moment where it was
Speaker 6:  like maybe mastered on is ready to take all of this stuff in and for a
Speaker 6:  big variety of reasons, including like discovery and identity and
Speaker 6:  its own like toxicity. It's just not there. But I keep talking
Speaker 6:  to people who are absolutely not put off and are like, fast forward 12 months
Speaker 6:  from now and we're gonna have really exciting answers to these questions.
Speaker 6:  Sure.
Speaker 5:  So there's a difference there between Mastodon and we
Speaker 5:  just had Eugene Rajko the c o of mastered on the
Speaker 5:  protocol on decoder. So masked on there's masked on the company.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, there's masked on the protocol. Okay. There's masked
Speaker 5:  on that social, the website, these are all different things. It's like
Speaker 5:  Apple tv. Yeah. There's masked on plots. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Max, they're all different things. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  David, when you say like you can't talk about Twitter or Masson, do you mean
Speaker 5:  on mastodon.social because there's like 9,000 different servers?
Speaker 6:  Yes. Well, and like welcome to the problem, right? It's like
Speaker 6:  on Mastodon, where do you go? Do you go to a server
Speaker 6:  that is just like run by a dude with a server in his
Speaker 6:  house? Like a lot of people do. Do you go to macedon.social, which is the
Speaker 6:  one that is officially run by Macedon the company, but is so
Speaker 6:  overloaded with people that it crashes all the time and they actually don't
Speaker 6:  allow signups often. Do you just pick one and then move later? Like we,
Speaker 6:  these are questions you don't have to answer when it's go to Twitter
Speaker 6:  and pick a username and the the like workflow for like, I
Speaker 6:  I want to go to this new internet, where do I go? And, and
Speaker 6:  like Casey Newton keeps making this point, which is like, people don't want
Speaker 6:  to administer their own servers. And we're,
Speaker 6:  we're kind of in a phase where doing this is not, you don't have to administer
Speaker 6:  your own server, but you have to like know what it means to administer a
Speaker 6:  server in order to use Macedon. And that's too much work. And so
Speaker 6:  we're, we're in this interim phase where like Activity Pub is a, is
Speaker 6:  a protocol by which a lot of different tools can come
Speaker 6:  up that you'll use the same follower graph, the same content and build lots
Speaker 6:  of different experiences, right? It was like, what if you could use your
Speaker 6:  Twitter account to post Instagram photos? Like that's the future. That's
Speaker 6:  where we're headed. That's what everybody believes in. None of that is built
Speaker 6:  yet. And the problem with Mastodon is that it just requires
Speaker 6:  two steps. Too much work. And so the people who are mad enough
Speaker 6:  at Twitter to leave are already there and they're mad at the people who aren't
Speaker 6:  mad enough at Twitter to leave. And so it just becomes this
Speaker 6:  sort of self-perpetuating thing that like, until it gets easier, people are
Speaker 6:  just gonna stay where it's easy. And overwhelmingly that's still Twitter.
Speaker 6:  Like it's hard to leave a thing even when it sucks, but
Speaker 1:  It's probably like mastodons not gonna be the thing, right?
Speaker 5:  I don't know. Well
Speaker 1:  What, what comes next?
Speaker 5:  So there's, there's a universe of competitors, right? So Macedon is the
Speaker 5:  decentralized one. It is built on this protocol called
Speaker 5:  Activity Pub. Right. That I will not shut up about. Yes. Like I've been running
Speaker 5:  around the halls of this company being like Activity Pub. I love it. It's
Speaker 5:  kickass making David write a story about it. There's
Speaker 5:  something there, like if you, and you just look at the universe of people
Speaker 5:  who are building on it. Meta is building some sort of Twitter competitor
Speaker 5:  that is built on activity Pub Flipboard is all Tumblr Activity
Speaker 5:  Pub. Yep. We had Matt Mullenweg on Decoder. He said Tumblr and
Speaker 5:  WordPress are gonna support Activity pub. Which is kind of wild to think
Speaker 5:  about Tumblr like being a decentralized social network that can interact
Speaker 5:  with mass. Like that's weird, right? Yeah. Mozilla is gonna do something
Speaker 5:  with it. Like you just see these companies, these like OG web
Speaker 5:  companies and people be like, all right, we can tear the wild gardens
Speaker 5:  down using this new protocol and we'll talk about it more after David's story
Speaker 5:  comes out next week. So I don't get the whole thing away. That's just cool.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Then there's like Post News, which is a
Speaker 5:  Twitter competitor that is totally closed and I think Care Swisher's on the
Speaker 5:  board, they have a great proposition, which is that if you sign up for it,
Speaker 5:  you use it, you see a New York Times article that you like, they've
Speaker 5:  built micro-transactions into the app to let you slide through their paywall.
Speaker 1:  Okay. That's, that's cool. Yeah. That's
Speaker 5:  Cool. Like that's a thing Twitter should have built ages ago and never could
Speaker 5:  get done. Yeah. They're starting with that. Then there's a thing called Spout
Speaker 5:  Ball, which I haven't used,
Speaker 6:  I don't know spout it
Speaker 5:  Seems, but people keep asking me about it, you know, in the way that like
Speaker 5:  it's that it's that moment it's like of evolutionary explosion,
Speaker 5:  like Cambri explosion. Yeah. Where people will just send me emails. It's
Speaker 5:  like, well the Virgin Engage a spout. And I'm like, I don't know what that
Speaker 5:  is. Are you a
Speaker 6:  Cop?
Speaker 5:  But like a lot of sports people are on it and, and you just see like, okay,
Speaker 5:  there's a bunch of new networks starting. Are you looking at it?
Speaker 1:  I'm trying to, but you have to create an account, see, nevermind
Speaker 5:  And bounced right out.
Speaker 5:  I just think it's really interesting to see this many new competitors
Speaker 5:  because it's obvious that the thing is falling apart. Yeah. Yes.
Speaker 1:  That's the best part of this. And
Speaker 6:  They, and the do e everybody, like overwhelmingly in the course of reporting
Speaker 6:  this story, I have asked people like, why do you think this is the moment?
Speaker 6:  Because people have been working on this idea of like distributed open social
Speaker 6:  for 25 years. Like this is not a new idea. There have been a million attempts
Speaker 6:  of it. Like remember Jabber back in the day when you could put all of your
Speaker 6:  IM clients into one app. Like that's this, that's the same thing. You just
Speaker 6:  talk to all your friends, it doesn't matter where they are. Like that is
Speaker 6:  functionally the exact same idea. And we ran away from that because Google
Speaker 6:  talk got really big and Google said, well we don't need to deal with Xmpp.
Speaker 6:  And so they stopped supporting it and it all fell apart. And that is just
Speaker 6:  what happens.
Speaker 5:  Bcast. Yeah. That's
Speaker 6:  Just what happens. And so I keep asking people like, why do you think this
Speaker 6:  is the moment? Why is there so much excitement? And almost every single person,
Speaker 6:  I can't think of one person I've talked to for this story who hasn't said
Speaker 6:  because of Elon, because Elon Musk showed up and made abundantly
Speaker 6:  clear to a lot of people how bad this can go and how fast and how
Speaker 6:  ugly it is to have something that you've invested this much time
Speaker 6:  and energy into fall apart like this. Like there's so many people, and
Speaker 6:  I'm one of them who have stories about making friends on Twitter and like
Speaker 6:  we all, you know, the real Twitter is the friends we made along the way.
Speaker 6:  Like it's a, it's a really important place to a lot of people and it's
Speaker 6:  just crumbling in a way that I think is really painful. And so the pitch
Speaker 6:  is now like, what if that can't happen anymore? And I think it's, it's sinking
Speaker 6:  in for people in a way it never has before. It's just that the right product
Speaker 6:  for it doesn't really seem to have appeared yet.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. If you're listening to this podcast, you are almost certainly the sort
Speaker 5:  of person that can deal with your own server just to guess. I'm making, it's
Speaker 6:  Not that hard.
Speaker 5:  I you've, you've probably got an ass, you probably have a Plex server
Speaker 5:  that you don't wanna tell the authorities about.
Speaker 1:  It's okay. I support you.
Speaker 5:  You're you're using it to distribute Linux. Yeah, I know what
Speaker 5:  you're doing.
Speaker 1:  It's the best way to use it. Only Linux. It's all I share
Speaker 1:  on my,
Speaker 5:  It's open source, open source textbooks and Linux on
Speaker 5:  Alex's Plex server. Look, you're probably the sort of person you can
Speaker 5:  figure this stuff out. You should start a Masstone account
Speaker 5:  just for the experience of doing it because it's difficult. And then you
Speaker 5:  should start a Pixel fed account. Pixeled is the activity pub
Speaker 5:  Instagram. Okay, same deal. You gotta find a server, all that, blah blah
Speaker 5:  da. And then you should see hosting from Twitter to Instagram is a thing
Speaker 5:  you can do with those services. Yep. Right. From Mastodon to pixeled. From
Speaker 5:  pixeled to Mastodon,
Speaker 6:  You can make a pixeled post from your Mastodon account. Like that is, that's
Speaker 6:  the magic, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And there's just something there, like once you do it, you're like,
Speaker 5:  oh, this makes a lot of sense. And I know like usually we spend this entire
Speaker 5:  show talking about AI and that's where all the hype is. But the, I think
Speaker 5:  the thing that actually changes the nature of the social internet is
Speaker 5:  somewhere in here. And then I promise we'll have a story about it next week
Speaker 5:  and we'll actually talk with the actual story with the actual reporting.
Speaker 5:  But like, I just like watching this week in particular with Twitter where
Speaker 5:  like the legacy thing happened, the Trump stuff having no impact on
Speaker 5:  Twitter. Like cable news for the last decade has been
Speaker 5:  people with great haircuts reading tweets and
Speaker 1:  It was beautiful.
Speaker 5:  Was it? I loved it. It might have destroyed democracy.
Speaker 1:  Just a little. Just
Speaker 5:  A little. And to watch it this week and be like, oh there's no, there's literally
Speaker 5:  no loop here. Yeah. It's like, oh, the thing is over. The vibrancy
Speaker 5:  of the thing is over. I don't know when Aaron Rodgers going to the Jets.
Speaker 5:  I dunno if it's gonna happen, but there's, there have been years of
Speaker 5:  my life where I have one Twitter list that's just all the Packers
Speaker 5:  beat reporters and I used to check it a thousand times a day and now I
Speaker 5:  don't. Aw, that's
Speaker 6:  Crazy. To me, that's actually a really good example of like, where are those
Speaker 6:  people gonna go? Like are we gonna lose that? Should we lose that?
Speaker 6:  Are we, does everybody go to Mass? Like, I don't know Casey
Speaker 6:  on platform or wrote a good thing about this, like why journalists can't
Speaker 6:  quit Twitter And like as a journalist who quit Twitter, I'm here to tell
Speaker 6:  you like, it is possible. It's actually not nearly as hard as anyone thinks,
Speaker 6:  but there is just something too, like as long as anyone is there,
Speaker 6:  people are gonna stay. Right? And so I think it's gonna be really
Speaker 6:  interesting to see what it takes and I assume it's like some great product
Speaker 6:  and some huge news event kind of in tandem. That
Speaker 6:  might be that poll. But I don't know, like my, my sense is
Speaker 6:  Twitter can be broken for a long time and we're gonna keep having to talk
Speaker 6:  about it because it's just really hard to leave.
Speaker 5:  So Ben Smith, who is the editor-in-chief at Buzzfeed News and left
Speaker 5:  to found, co-found SE four, the new new site, he's got a book
Speaker 5:  out called Traffic, which not out yet, but it's going at May. He's going
Speaker 5:  outta de coder. Traffic is about Gawker versus Buzzfeed in like the early
Speaker 5:  days of the internet. And he's got, it's great, highly recommended when it
Speaker 5:  comes out, but he is got a theory in there that new, new sites,
Speaker 5:  new properties come into form their opportunities that come into
Speaker 5:  form during election years.
Speaker 1:  Ooh, I
Speaker 5:  Like that. So these, like Buzzfeed news was like rushed out for an election.
Speaker 5:  I actually remember when I was@vox.com, we, we pushed it to hit the election.
Speaker 5:  We like, that's the moment, like those cycles, there's lots of news,
Speaker 5:  lots of whatever this is like, and if you just kinda like look at the history
Speaker 5:  of the media, this is Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Every four years for some reason a new, a new
Speaker 5:  Publication cause they line up with elections cause there's just like, there's
Speaker 5:  two teams and they hate each other and you can't talk shit about it. It's
Speaker 5:  like, it's just very easy. Yeah. Right. And I just wonder if this upcoming
Speaker 5:  election cycle is when you see a mass of like people moving to a
Speaker 5:  new kinda media. So like it's, it's just on my mind that there's a thing
Speaker 5:  happening. The one thing I wanna point out before I move on and talk about
Speaker 5:  Spotify completely not knowing what it's doing, ISCK put out
Speaker 5:  notes this week, which is basically they added a Twitter feed
Speaker 5:  tock in the app. Ooh. That looks exactly like our quick posts on
Speaker 5:  our site. And like the reasoning is exactly the same. Like sometimes you
Speaker 5:  don't wanna write a whole thing and I'm like, yeah, yeah, yeah, we made that.
Speaker 5:  But this is the next move, right? Is to, if you talk to any sub
Speaker 5:  stackers, their biggest audience funnel was on Twitter. Like
Speaker 5:  they, they monetized their Twitter audience with CK and if that goes away,
Speaker 5:  I'm not sure where the next generation of sub stackers finds audience.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, because they can't build it from like TikTok or Instagram.
Speaker 5:  The idea of making a TikTok video that's like sign up for my newsletter
Speaker 5:  is so bonkers. Can you imagine Casey just like dancing
Speaker 5:  for dollars on TikTok? Just a little shuffle.
Speaker 5:  So there's just a yawning need for a platform that's like Twitter, a
Speaker 5:  text-based, real-time news platform and someone's gonna fill it.
Speaker 5:  And I think that's actually really exciting regardless in the, the chaos
Speaker 5:  of Twitter itself is is like regardless of the chaos of Twitter itself. But
Speaker 5:  it's exciting to see this much activity in that space. Yeah. Because there
Speaker 5:  just hasn't been for a long time.
Speaker 1:  But it's not gonna be masked on. I'm just gonna say it now. That's my
Speaker 1:  my third prognostication.
Speaker 5:  So you got, I
Speaker 1:  Got, everybody's gonna think the blue check mark's dumb Elon's gonna tweet
Speaker 1:  his Don and Mastodon is not gonna
Speaker 1:  be the true success.
Speaker 5:  What if he tweets his don on Mastodon?
Speaker 1:  I'll pay you $20 because I'll just be like, oh my God,
Speaker 5:  I feel strongly that we should take a break. I quit the podcast. Goodbye.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna be right back. We gotta talk about Spotify. We gotta talk about
Speaker 5:  GM's doing at CarPlay. We'll be right back.
Speaker 7:  Over the past several weeks today explained has been going
Speaker 7:  downtown, downtown Seattle drug
Speaker 8:  Activity. Like when spring and summer, you know, when they hang out all night,
Speaker 8:  it's worse.
Speaker 7:  Downtown Chicago now
Speaker 9:  Just happens anywhere, anytime of day, morning, night. Like it's just way
Speaker 7:  Worse. Philadelphia.
Speaker 10:  Lot more violence, more homeless people.
Speaker 7:  And New York City, I
Speaker 11:  See a lot of people just going and grabbing people's bags, hitting
Speaker 11:  them. They, it's like they
Speaker 7:  Don't care one through line in all these cities. Crime,
Speaker 12:  The number one barrier that we heard from people was that fear
Speaker 12:  of crime was what was preventing them from going downtown, particularly
Speaker 12:  within the central business district itself. And on their commutes
Speaker 12:  there,
Speaker 7:  Americans are scared of their downtowns, but should they be,
Speaker 7:  we're gonna find out in our City limits series on today.
Speaker 7:  Explain.
Speaker 13:  I am Preed Barra, the former US attorney in Manhattan. My
Speaker 13:  podcast stay tuned is about law, justice and politics.
Speaker 13:  The Manhattan District Attorney's case against Donald Trump is one of the
Speaker 13:  most consequential, legal and political stories of our time. So
Speaker 13:  this week I was joined by two top legal experts, former US
Speaker 13:  Attorney Joyce Vance and Law Fair editor Ben Whits, to
Speaker 13:  analyze the charges.
Speaker 14:  While I don't think this is a no-brainer case to bring,
Speaker 14:  I do think there is a fairly solid basis
Speaker 14:  for
Speaker 13:  It. The potential evidence,
Speaker 15:  I think the jury hearing the evidence that at least if Brad can
Speaker 15:  prove what he's laid out in the statement of facts, the evidence
Speaker 15:  will be compelling on these charges.
Speaker 13:  And where we go from here, it's not clear that a conviction on
Speaker 13:  one or more of these felony counts would result in prison
Speaker 13:  sentence or a substantial prison sentence to listen. Just search. Stay
Speaker 13:  tuned wherever you get your podcasts, new episodes drop every
Speaker 13:  Thursday.
Speaker 13:  Stay tuned.
Speaker 5:  Welcome back to the Verge Cast where we don't
Speaker 5:  make bets about dogs
Speaker 1:  No more. It's done moratorium on that.
Speaker 5:  It's good. Yeah, it's a family show. Find your children.
Speaker 5:  Don't explain what's going on. We gotta talk about Spotify. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So in the pandemic, Spotify decided that it was
Speaker 5:  all in on podcasts and then it was all in on live audio. Right? And then
Speaker 5:  it is not,
Speaker 1:  It's done, it's done with both of those.
Speaker 5:  So Spotify bought this thing called, what was it, green Room David It
Speaker 6:  Renamed it Green Room. The app before it was bought by Spotify
Speaker 6:  was called Locker Room cuz it was specifically about like live talk about
Speaker 6:  sports was like their
Speaker 5:  Main thing. And then they renamed a Green room and they were gonna compete
Speaker 5:  with Clubhouse,
Speaker 6:  Which is itself, by the way, just a hilarious statement. They were gonna
Speaker 6:  compete with Clubhouse is now with hindsight, a very fun thing to
Speaker 5:  Say. Whoa. It turns out you could compete with Clubhouse and the thing that
Speaker 5:  competed with a clubhouse was leaving your house
Speaker 6:  Was outdoors
Speaker 5:  Like any other room with people in it competed with clubhouse,
Speaker 1:  Touch grass,
Speaker 5:  Look in the depths of the pandemic. I swear to God, the tech industry was
Speaker 5:  like, all right, we've got 'em brains and vats. They're never leaving the
Speaker 5:  house again. Software will eat not only the world but the human
Speaker 5:  population. And like I get it, we, we, I we had a million
Speaker 5:  versions of this conversation like what trends are here to stay and what
Speaker 5:  trends are gonna go back and most everybody bet wrong. And now all these
Speaker 5:  companies are having layoffs. But the reason I wanna talk about Spotify
Speaker 5:  in particular is their big bet on podcasts
Speaker 5:  is shaky.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And then this big bet on live audio where you would just like open Spotify
Speaker 5:  at the end of the night and
Speaker 1:  Talk
Speaker 5:  Dudes would be talking does what is
Speaker 5:  next for this company?
Speaker 1:  And they heard of music. Have they heard of like, like
Speaker 1:  I think everybody just needs to go look at Apple Music Classical
Speaker 1:  and do that. Like if Spotify did that and gave you more access
Speaker 1:  to metadata and let you search and and browse that way,
Speaker 1:  that would be better than to spend all the money on locker room and rename
Speaker 1:  it Green Room, which I presume is just Broadway show tunes.
Speaker 5:  So I was reading the comments of your Apple Music classical piece, which
Speaker 5:  was great. Everyone should read it. And a lot of people in the comments were
Speaker 5:  like, this is Roone.
Speaker 1:  Oh really?
Speaker 5:  And so if you don't know Roone is, Roone is like a wild idea. It is a subscription-based
Speaker 5:  music player that has not music in it. So you gotta plug it into a title
Speaker 5:  account or a, a lot of people use this thing called Cobas.
Speaker 1:  Is this the one that like you use for your smart home?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like people integrate it with smart homes, but it's it's a music player,
Speaker 5:  right? So you like plug it in a title or if you have a big local library
Speaker 5:  on your Linux distribution plus whatever server,
Speaker 5:  it'll like read it all. It'll figure out all the metadata. It'll show you
Speaker 5:  like lots of links. It'll reorganize the metadata strike. Okay. This guitar
Speaker 5:  player in this song played on this song. Yeah. And like peop the, the thing
Speaker 5:  people say is like, this is just a discovery interface. Like I'm just like
Speaker 5:  falling down the rabbit hole of music in a way that like,
Speaker 1:  But you don't have kaza to like back up the
Speaker 5:  Falling down. Right. You gotta pay for, you gotta pay
Speaker 1:  Source your music somewhere. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You know, I spent like a significant part of my legal career defending kids
Speaker 5:  who use Kaza. Thank you. They they all lost. Oh no. Just like, you know,
Speaker 5:  these are not winnable cases.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And that's like Lime why is a hundred billion company
Speaker 5:  They did it. Everybody.
Speaker 6:  No, but the, the thing about that is, I I what I was gonna say is what
Speaker 6:  Spotify needs to do is stop thinking about itself as the audio
Speaker 6:  company. Like that's what they've been saying over and over, right? They're
Speaker 6:  not a music thing, they're about audio and what it actually seems like needs
Speaker 6:  to happen and where there is much more room for doing interesting stuff is
Speaker 6:  to go all in on music. Like Spotify should take the
Speaker 6:  fact that every musician has a link tree in their social
Speaker 6:  bios as like a direct threat to Spotify. And like if you wanna
Speaker 6:  buy merch, that should be Spotify. If you wanna buy concert tickets, that
Speaker 6:  should be Spotify. Like there is no money to be made in licensing music
Speaker 6:  to stream on a platform. There's a hell of a lot of money to be made in all
Speaker 6:  of the other ways that artists make money. And that all sucks
Speaker 6:  now. Like everybody's mad at Ticketmaster, thanks to Taylor Swift buying
Speaker 6:  stuff on the internet is a disaster. Everybody's merch stores that are ridiculous.
Speaker 6:  Like if I'm Spotify, I'm chasing the entire music
Speaker 6:  industry much more than I'm chasing the audio industry at this point.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But I, what what Spotify wants you to do is pay them
Speaker 5:  15 or $20 a month and then keep all the money. Right.
Speaker 5:  And the thing you're describing is like, what if other people
Speaker 5:  made money, right? Like when you listen to music on Spotify, some
Speaker 5:  complicated set of algorithms assigns 4 cents to every artist that
Speaker 5:  you listen to per stream, whatever. And they've gotta give
Speaker 5:  a huge chunk of your subscription dollar away when you listen to podcasts.
Speaker 5:  That is not true. Yeah. Because they've already bought and ingested them
Speaker 5:  Right.
Speaker 1:  When they have like a weird relationship with the music industry. Right.
Speaker 1:  Because of the fact that, you know, they only get 4 cents for every
Speaker 5:  Song. But the music industry also owns a huge chunk of Spotify.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So they, so theoretically they could just go in and be like, okay,
Speaker 1:  you're the new Ticketmaster, let's go.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean maybe Ticketmaster also owns all the venues. This is
Speaker 5:  a very complicated thing to unwind. I'm just saying if you look at Spotify's
Speaker 5:  arc, right? Right. They desperately tried to keep more of your
Speaker 5:  dollars by pointing you at audio that they already own they owned outright
Speaker 5:  so they didn't have to pay further royalties on or that other that users
Speaker 5:  are making for free. And things like what Spotify Clubhouse Jr. Or
Speaker 5:  whatever it was called, green Ram, green Room, Spotify, clubhouse,
Speaker 6:  Clubhouse, Junior's.
Speaker 5:  Really different.
Speaker 6:  We don't, we don't talk about that here.
Speaker 5:  I'm just saying like, I think Spotify is not in just in a shakier zone Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Than any of the other big tech companies. Like we, we talk about the other
Speaker 5:  streamer, like we'll end up talking about Disney and it's like war with the
Speaker 5:  state of Florida and it's reorg and Netflix and all this other stuff. And
Speaker 5:  they've all had cuts and they've like stopped spending money. Spotify is
Speaker 5:  a streaming service. It's competitors are Apple and Amazon, which
Speaker 5:  heavily subsidized their services. And then they're
Speaker 1:  And Title
Speaker 5:  Dear
Speaker 1:  Sweet. Oh forget about title
Speaker 5:  Dear sweet title, which is part of Block, which has like a research report
Speaker 5:  that's like block is built on fraud. Very
Speaker 1:  Good. Not great.
Speaker 5:  So yeah, it's just a weird, a weird moment for that company in
Speaker 5:  particular. Yeah. And it the, the same ways with Twitter, right? It's the
Speaker 5:  foundation of like an entire ecosystem and it's like,
Speaker 5:  what if that one, what if this domino falls?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean the the thing for Spotify though is I think because the music
Speaker 6:  industry is so invested in it, it it, they just, they're they can't let it
Speaker 6:  fall. Right. Like you let it fall and it's just Apple, Amazon, and YouTube
Speaker 6:  own the music business. Yeah. And that for the music business is like an
Speaker 6:  abject disaster. So I, I would, I I have high
Speaker 6:  or like geezer like what if geezer just wins? Go get it
Speaker 6:  geezer. Like I'm in on that plan. It's
Speaker 5:  All roone. We should talk. So this brings me to CarPlay.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. Okay. Everybody's favorite Geezer consumption location
Speaker 1:  Only way I listened to Geezer.
Speaker 5:  Well it's interesting, like, so GM had announcement this week, very odd
Speaker 5:  announcement. They released a fact sheet and then I think only Reuters like
Speaker 5:  read it
Speaker 5:  and like Reuters had headlines, like GM walks away from CarPlay and we saw
Speaker 5:  that headline and we were no, yeah, that's dumb.
Speaker 5:  And then we acquired the fact sheet which we published so people could actually
Speaker 5:  see this was sourced. Cuz it is such a bonkers thing to say that we didn't
Speaker 5:  think people would believe our headline. So we like put the PDF in the story.
Speaker 5:  They're walking away from car plan Android Auto in just the EVs.
Speaker 5:  And their reasoning is that the cars are
Speaker 5:  computers now and that they want to do things like have you used the built-in
Speaker 5:  nav so that when you're on your way to a charging station, the batteries
Speaker 5:  pre-conditioned so you can charge faster.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that sounds great. I wish they'd thought of that 20 years ago.
Speaker 1:  Like welcome to the party
Speaker 5:  Gm. I think this is the beginning. I think every automaker is gonna start
Speaker 5:  to do things like this in
Speaker 6:  Five years. That's hundred percent public reasoning. Right. And it's like
Speaker 6:  that, that reading the story, it was like that's the one thing they could
Speaker 6:  think to say that sounded like a feature. And then everything else is just,
Speaker 6:  we don't make any money from CarPlay and we think there's a lot of money
Speaker 6:  to be made in not CarPlay. Right. Like how, is there any other way to read
Speaker 6:  this than that?
Speaker 1:  Yeah, Patrick George did a great piece for the site that was just
Speaker 1:  that he went and spoke to a lot of people and they're like, oh yeah, they
Speaker 1:  just wanna make money and so they're gonna, they're gonna kill it so that
Speaker 1:  they can like Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The future of cars is no steering wheels and you're shopping all day in the
Speaker 5:  car. Yeah. Or looking at ads while you like stream movies or
Speaker 1:  Whatever. Like, just like minority reports.
Speaker 5:  I have been to enough ces future of car
Speaker 5:  panels where they're like, soon we will reclaim the time you
Speaker 5:  spend commuting. And it's like, oh awesome. For what? For literature, for
Speaker 5:  art and like for advertising and e-commerce. It's like, oh,
Speaker 5:  that's not what I thought.
Speaker 1:  We get 30%.
Speaker 5:  It's like to improve the human condition and it's like, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 5:  Shopping
Speaker 6:  Can't crush,
Speaker 5:  Can't crush. So yes, I think that's what Jim wants to do.
Speaker 5:  I do think there's some valid stuff in there, right? If you make a self-driving
Speaker 5:  car and you, you don't control the navigation system, you
Speaker 5:  almost certainly have a problem.
Speaker 1:  Are you saying this because you hate CarPlay and you wanna support big
Speaker 1:  big car?
Speaker 5:  Yes. I love big car. Big car. Big car's my favorite,
Speaker 1:  You know, big car. Who doesn't
Speaker 5:  Love a big car? Yeah. My parents by the way refer to our cars as small, medium
Speaker 5:  and big. That's, that's why my mom's like, can we borrow your
Speaker 5:  medium car? It's a real thing that happens. I love that so much. It's very
Speaker 5:  good. No, I, I think CarPlay is bad. Like, just to be clear, I,
Speaker 5:  this is my opinion. CarPlay is bad. It is superior to have
Speaker 5:  the radio on the bad infotainment screen and then mount
Speaker 5:  your phone using a MagSafe charger. We'll put an affiliate link in the show
Speaker 5:  notes. This is my white whales, like the world's best MagSafe charger.
Speaker 5:  If you make a new one that's be like 5% better than what I will buy it in
Speaker 5:  a heartbeat. I will spend $70 on you MagSafe charger. And
Speaker 6:  Imagining like, you know, the people with like McDonald's boxes all over
Speaker 6:  their cars. That's just you with MagSafe chargers. You like can't get in
Speaker 6:  the passenger seat cause there's 200 MagSafe
Speaker 5:  Chargers. It's a perfect impulse by gadget. Swear to God. Because if you,
Speaker 5:  cause you can always make it 5% better. The magnets click a little harder,
Speaker 5:  the charging's a little faster, the mount's a little smarter and you put
Speaker 5:  the ma my phone is almost as big as the infotainment screen in my car.
Speaker 1:  What what year is your car?
Speaker 5:  The Raptor of 2020. Okay. And that's a tiny little
Speaker 5:  screen that's before the new big screen. Okay. So that one is like whatever.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, like that's sync three. I've sworn on blood oath that I will not buy
Speaker 5:  another Ford until they go to the Android based system. I'm like, I can't
Speaker 5:  have more sync in my life. It's real bad. It's not allowed.
Speaker 6:  This is the point, right? Like CarPlay is bad except that it's
Speaker 6:  so much better than everything That
Speaker 5:  Is not better. It's,
Speaker 1:  It's way better. So I've got, I've got a Mazda CX five and
Speaker 1:  I know every single time I forget to plug my phone in cuz they'll be like,
Speaker 1:  I'm just gonna call someone and this robot voice is like, who do you wanna
Speaker 1:  pull? I'm like the hell are you?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I know what you're doing there. You can make it. I'm just saying. So
Speaker 5:  they're all small screens except for our new Jeep, which is an Android computer
Speaker 5:  and is basically like a tamagotchi. Like I have to go into the garage every
Speaker 5:  night and be like, are you okay
Speaker 1:  Petting
Speaker 5:  Car?
Speaker 6:  And we like this better than CarPlay. Just to be clear, this is an improvement.
Speaker 6:  Well it has your phone in and everything
Speaker 5:  Works fine. Consumer satisfaction with car infotainment systems has
Speaker 5:  been going steadily down since wireless CarPlay was introduced because it's
Speaker 5:  so unreliable.
Speaker 1:  That's what Monica was talking about this when we were having a huge argument
Speaker 1:  and I was telling you, you were both wrong for hitting CarPlay because she
Speaker 1:  had it wireless and it kept like disconnecting and she'd be like driving
Speaker 1:  and it'd be like, where are we going? And she'd be like, where You should
Speaker 1:  know.
Speaker 5:  Right. And so integrated is better than weird, fragmented. I'm just telling
Speaker 5:  you it is superior to mount your phone in the car using a i I
Speaker 5:  should just make a wireless MagSafe charger at this point. It's superior
Speaker 5:  to mount your phone, put the map on there and then do your audio cuz you
Speaker 5:  can deal with it. You can get through it.
Speaker 1:  We just, we just need a little slot and you just, you can even Bluetooth
Speaker 1:  your phone in. Yeah. And and it just projects. It's your phone. Yeah. And
Speaker 1:  just done.
Speaker 5:  Anyhow, the reason I'm doing app CarPlay is horrible and I'm correct and
Speaker 5:  I don't know what wrong. No wrong. It's not good. The only thing you wanna
Speaker 5:  do with it is show your maps.
Speaker 6:  Are you so excited about having the one app for music that exists?
Speaker 6:  Like they're literally what the end
Speaker 5:  Of of this is? No, cuz I'm gonna stick my phone on the dash and it's gonna
Speaker 5:  start charging through the power of magnetism. It's gonna be awesome
Speaker 5:  every time. So you can't stop me. You're already
Speaker 6:  Listen to the radio for more Dons
Speaker 5:  Steve Chevy. What are you gonna do my house? Arrest me?
Speaker 1:  He's
Speaker 5:  Getting his little car. Pull me over cuz
Speaker 1:  I, he's getting into small car
Speaker 5:  Because I use the blinding power of magnets to overcome your
Speaker 5:  stupid infotainment. No, do whatever I want.
Speaker 5:  See your point David.
Speaker 6:  Lemme just make sure I understand. So what what you're arguing is I would
Speaker 6:  like to get in my car, I would like to attach my phone to an incredibly
Speaker 6:  powerful magnet, and then I would like to plug my phone in to
Speaker 6:  some thing. No,
Speaker 5:  It's just the magnet is there. It's charging
Speaker 6:  You music out of the speakers of your phone.
Speaker 5:  No, with Bluetooth into the car. James gonna still let you Bluetooth into
Speaker 5:  the car. Okay. So you're playing your music over Bluetooth, your steering
Speaker 5:  wheel controls to control the music player and you got a map on the phone
Speaker 5:  and you're not stuck in some weird projection system
Speaker 5:  and you've got two screens. What Vergecast listener does not want two screens
Speaker 5:  going instead
Speaker 6:  Of one. What if I had one small good screen and one big bad screen?
Speaker 6:  Like what a what a cool future
Speaker 5:  That is the Mercedes experience. I don't know man. I'm just saying
Speaker 5:  CarPlay is not great and Apple's dream that it would colonize all of the
Speaker 5:  screens near car is hitting reality. Remember last year WWE C where
Speaker 5:  they're like, here's the future of CarPlay. Yes. And they showed all the
Speaker 5:  logos and all the car companies, like
Speaker 1:  They were like, Nu-uh,
Speaker 5:  What are you doing? It's about to be a year later, no
Speaker 5:  car makers have announced any plans to support that version of CarPlay. True.
Speaker 5:  And GM's like, actually we're not gonna support CarPlay at all because we
Speaker 5:  need to take the screen back because this is where people will shop
Speaker 6:  In the future by giving it to Google.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like they're just gonna make something crappy. Like
Speaker 1:  all of the other systems, you're still using your phone when you use your
Speaker 1:  very powerful magnet because the system behind your phone is garbage.
Speaker 1:  They're all garbage and CarPlay just a little better. And I really, that's
Speaker 5:  Not,
Speaker 6:  I mean you're, you're
Speaker 1:  The GM's not gonna do better. They did Q like
Speaker 6:  Your car infotainment in the best case scenario now is
Speaker 6:  like a four year old Android tablet. Like, congratulations on your four
Speaker 6:  year old Android tablet,
Speaker 5:  Please. So the the argument that I'll, I'll give, I don't own a Tesla, but
Speaker 5:  every Tesla owner has already experienced this life, right? Where like there's
Speaker 5:  no CarPlay integration. They've asked for it, but Tesla's like, this is the
Speaker 5:  future. We want to control your experience in the car. We're gonna put games
Speaker 5:  on here, we're going to do over the year updates every day. Every automaker
Speaker 5:  thinks that's their future too. Whether or not they can execute at the level
Speaker 5:  of the Tesla's executed remains to be seen.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like I think it makes sense. They all wanna do this. They're doing
Speaker 1:  the exact same thing TV makers did where they're all like, we're gonna own
Speaker 1:  the the home and we're gonna put our smart TV in. And most of them have been
Speaker 1:  like, this kind of sucks. Yeah. Go buy
Speaker 5:  A I'm just saying the outrage about GM walking away from CarPlay, if you
Speaker 5:  just look at CarPlay itself, it's kind of bad.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 6:  Love it. But that's, that's the thing, like the fact that CarPlay and, and
Speaker 6:  there have been all these stats that say like 80% of people won't buy a car
Speaker 6:  without CarPlay. It's not because CarPlay is magical software. It's because
Speaker 6:  everything else
Speaker 5:  Is shit.
Speaker 6:  Like the, the, the thing about Tesla is like Tesla has people
Speaker 6:  who make good software and has a decent reputation for making good software.
Speaker 6:  And a lot of Tesla people still want CarPlay, but at least the stuff
Speaker 6:  broadly works. Right? Like it's pretty good software. There is nothing
Speaker 6:  in the history of the auto industry to suggest that they know how to make
Speaker 6:  good software. They didn't know how to make good simple software. Like when
Speaker 6:  all the software had to do was change the radio station. It was horrible.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And now I'm, I'm supposed to assume that these companies are just
Speaker 6:  gonna turn around and figure out how to make it like car plan Android auto
Speaker 6:  worked because they were so bad at making software in cars.
Speaker 6:  So they just came and said, well, we're just gonna show up and go over the
Speaker 6:  top. And like, what, how is there any evidence that that has changed? Isn't
Speaker 1:  One, one of the car makers is doing like Akm, morphic one, right? Didn't,
Speaker 1:  didn't they all invest in like Epic?
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. No. They all run unreal engineering. Oh yeah. So the new the new
Speaker 5:  Mustang, which is still sink. Why? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But like the, all the graphics in it are unreal engine. There's like Rivian
Speaker 5:  or
Speaker 6:  Unreal engines. Such high res sync. Yeah. It's so high res.
Speaker 5:  Too much. I mean, it looks beautiful and you're like, is this the new Android
Speaker 5:  system that you announced like over 18? And they're like, no, it's not, sir.
Speaker 1:  It's garbage. But it is. It's like hot, hot garbage. It's,
Speaker 5:  It's, look, Q and X will never go away. It's gonna be in Ford forever.
Speaker 5:  They did announce an Android based system. They're supposed, it's supposed
Speaker 5:  to come out. Yeah. No one knows when it's coming out, but it runs Unreal
Speaker 5:  Engine. And that's all the graphics Rivian run anal engine. There's tons
Speaker 5:  of that going on in the auto space because they know that when they move
Speaker 5:  to ev drive trains, the actual difference in driving a car
Speaker 5:  will be n like they, they, they cannot
Speaker 5:  make it ver they all the cars are gonna kind of be the same.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Is that why they're all making such futuristic looking designs to like,
Speaker 6:  because they have to loudly exclaim. This is a new kind of car or else
Speaker 6:  no one will notice.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And put the little Hemi speaker in. So it sounds like a hemi
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  That's my Hemi impression.
Speaker 5:  That's not, that's the wrong sound. That's a Honda
Speaker 5:  impression.
Speaker 5:  You should the frat zanax speaker and the new charger, the EV charger or
Speaker 5:  whatever is No ev challenger. Yeah. It it's like
Speaker 5:  rumbles. Yeah. It's like a dinosaur
Speaker 1:  Sound. I can't get that low. Like my voice doesn't go that
Speaker 5:  Low anyhow. They, they're doing it because this is
Speaker 5:  their opportunity to break from history. And they know, they're like the
Speaker 5:  ev buyer wants to feel special. EVs are more expensive and they have to be
Speaker 5:  more expensive cuz the margins are lower on these cars cuz they're invent,
Speaker 5:  they're full of new technology that hasn't proven out and then they all think
Speaker 5:  we're all gonna not drive and shop in the car. Like, I promise you every
Speaker 5:  auto CEO is like, I can't wait for people to start shopping in their cars
Speaker 5:  on our screens where we take 30%. And like the CEO of BMW
Speaker 5:  is like, and soon you'll subscribe to your heated seats. And
Speaker 5:  they're,
Speaker 1:  And people hate all of that. Yeah. No one like, like Apple,
Speaker 1:  apple was, has the benefit of being first movers and the, I'm gonna
Speaker 1:  bake a big technological walled garden and all
Speaker 1:  the car companies are now like 30 years later saying we're gonna do it too.
Speaker 1:  And everybody's like, no, that sucks.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  We're just heading back to the early days of cell phones where everybody
Speaker 6:  had their own operating system with their own app store, with their own brand
Speaker 6:  new ideas about how to do absolutely everything.
Speaker 5:  And the weird thing that's different here is they're all picking Android
Speaker 1:  Because it's easy to build on.
Speaker 5:  Well, but it's like weird. So like the GM system is Google builtin
Speaker 5:  so it's not a hundred percent clear if the thing is Android.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like the operating system is Android, but the navigation is Google
Speaker 5:  Maps.
Speaker 1:  Is it gonna have like play store in it?
Speaker 5:  Ooh, yeah. I know.
Speaker 1:  Is it, is it Android? Like Huawei is Android or is it Android? Like
Speaker 5:  So my Jeep is Android, like Huawei is Android. Yeah. And boy does it show
Speaker 5:  boy is that obvious and
Speaker 1:  That's bad. That's like not a place to go. Like they're
Speaker 5:  Very proud of it
Speaker 1:  Getting three guys who just graduated from college to build your
Speaker 1:  entire car infotainment system seems like a bad idea. And
Speaker 1:  that's kind of the sense of what I get from all of these, these attempts,
Speaker 5:  Right? They've all forked Android in some way or they're using qnx and Google
Speaker 5:  is there to be their mapping provider. Yeah. Or there's Android
Speaker 5:  automotive, which is Google's a whole os of your car, which is like what
Speaker 5:  Polestar uses, but just in response to David,
Speaker 5:  they're all picking Google services. So Google is colonizing
Speaker 5:  more of the auto industry, whereas Apple is like, what if we do all the screens
Speaker 5:  for you?
Speaker 1:  Same with TVs. They did the same thing. Right. None of the TV makers
Speaker 1:  wanted to, they all wanted to build their own TV stuff and then one day they
Speaker 1:  said, oh Android does it good enough. And then we can still slap all our
Speaker 1:  logos on everything and and pop it out and yeah. That's what they've done.
Speaker 1:  So Android's just doing that again for a new market.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's like, it's hard to see consumers don't change their cars
Speaker 5:  enough. Right. So it's like that market's just moving way, way, way, way
Speaker 5:  slower.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, because it's like every, what, 10 years? I don't know. Yeah, it's,
Speaker 1:  I just got this car. Who know? Have it forever. Forever.
Speaker 5:  Have you gotten a MagSafe Matt,
Speaker 1:  For you? No. Cuz I, I plug in with the lightning and then I throw it in my
Speaker 1:  my
Speaker 5:  I'm just gonna get, I've got like a drawer full. I'm just gonna,
Speaker 1:  It's like, just bring me one, bring me your second best one.
Speaker 1:  You can keep your best one but bring me
Speaker 5:  Like your second. Yeah. That I'm giving you my best one. It's like completely
Speaker 5:  off the table. I don't even know why you not you open that door just to suggest
Speaker 5:  that I give the best one.
Speaker 1:  I just like, how are you gonna convince me? Otherwise I really need to feel
Speaker 1:  that snap.
Speaker 5:  It's very good. Oh my, oh the good. A good MagSafe click. It's very good.
Speaker 5:  Anyhow. Yeah, this is, I'm telling you by the, by
Speaker 5:  at WWDC this year Apple will say nothing about CarPlay. This is my prediction.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Cuz it has gone nowhere. It's all, it's all me headset talk. Anyway.
Speaker 5:  And then this time next year, two more automakers will have dropped. Phone
Speaker 5:  projection. Mm. That's my another prediction.
Speaker 1:  I can see it. Wow. That's no jogs
Speaker 6:  Sight. Glad I bought a car already.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. My bets are better than you. All right. We gotta take a
Speaker 5:  break and we got a little bit of a lightning round. There's a lot going on
Speaker 5:  in the sling round. We'll right back.
Speaker 5:  Alright, we're back. What? I'm super right.
Speaker 6:  I just realized at some point on the Vergecast we're gonna do an entire segment
Speaker 6:  about Eli's favorite mag safe chargers and I could not be more excited
Speaker 6:  about it.
Speaker 5:  Right now I'm on Bekin, like I've got a Mofi one
Speaker 5:  in the, in the truck. No, I don't, don't I have a
Speaker 5:  moment. One in the truck.
Speaker 1:  I wanna just hear the click. I want you to do a whole segment where you just
Speaker 1:  click 'em all against the microphone so we can really Oh,
Speaker 5:  That's good. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Andrew Producer just instantly green lit that segment. Absolutely guarantee.
Speaker 5:  Done. So the, the truck is weird cuz there's not a a a a
Speaker 5:  cigarette port or power port. Yeah. Close enough to it. It's just a weird
Speaker 5:  situation. So I can use the moment ones which aren't actually Chargers and
Speaker 5:  moment uses stronger magnets. Ooh. And they're very proud of their
Speaker 5:  stronger magnets, which are not mag safe approved.
Speaker 1:  So if you get in a car accident, your phone probably isn't
Speaker 1:  twirling
Speaker 5:  Around.
Speaker 6:  All the metal in your car is just gonna attach
Speaker 5:  To the
Speaker 5:  That's very good. Welcome to the third segment of the Vir House where we
Speaker 5:  just continue the previous segment about how cool magnets are.
Speaker 5:  Mag Save is legitimately my favorite feature on the phone.
Speaker 1:  Is that your lightning
Speaker 5:  Room? Have you done the thing where you hang the puck in your bathroom yet
Speaker 5:  next to your mirror? No, you gotta get a mag save. They're like five bucks
Speaker 5:  in Amazon. Like I,
Speaker 1:  I live in an, a small apartment in New York
Speaker 5:  City, whatever. Just saying the puck on the mirror and then when you're like
Speaker 5:  brushing your teeth, you can like have YouTube TV open. It's great.
Speaker 1:  I'm all right. All
Speaker 5:  Right. Okay. I'm tired. It's like, it's the best thing you can do.
Speaker 1:  I'll believe you all. I believe you in my heart. I'm never gonna do it.
Speaker 5:  House has a five-year-old in their house. Like, this is my me time baby.
Speaker 5:  I'm like, just like rocking and rolling. Close the door, watching TV in the
Speaker 5:  bathroom. Alright, lightning round.
Speaker 5:  David, you start.
Speaker 6:  Sure. So I had two. We'll do, they're both fairly quick.
Speaker 6:  The first one is that Walmart rolled out a big redesign of its
Speaker 6:  website because Walmart, which I have been proclaiming, is a secret like
Speaker 6:  sneaky tech giant and nobody realizes it is now a drastically better
Speaker 6:  looking website than amazon.com. Which yes, a very funny thing that
Speaker 6:  happened this week was when this news came out, everybody sort of all at
Speaker 6:  once had this moment on our staff of being like, wait, Amazon is ugly. Like
Speaker 6:  what a bad website amazon.com is. And we've all just been
Speaker 6:  sort of slowly like frog boiling and water to
Speaker 6:  amazon.com and we just didn't realize it's a hideous website. And then Walmart,
Speaker 6:  which used to be a like roughly equivalently hideous website, came
Speaker 6:  out and said like, oh, we care about curation and we're gonna make things
Speaker 6:  look a little nicer and we're gonna use like colors and the names of things
Speaker 6:  aren't gonna be 65 words long and we're gonna have like a, a thing
Speaker 6:  that actually makes sense for shopping. And everybody's just like, oh, Amazon
Speaker 6:  sucks. That was my favorite part of this whole thing. It was like Walmart
Speaker 6:  did a redesign and everybody was like, you know what's bad? It's amazon.com.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It does look very pretty. It's
Speaker 1:  Nice. Looks nice. I'm still not gonna shop there, but like I, I appreciate
Speaker 1:  that Walmart was like, we're getting our asses kicked and we're actually
Speaker 1:  gonna come back and, and go after a big tech company even though we're just
Speaker 1:  the guys that like destroy small towns with our giant, very convenient
Speaker 1:  and lovely shopping centers.
Speaker 5:  We had the CEO of Barnes and Noble in Decoder and I was like, this is quite
Speaker 5:  a turnaround for you. You remember he used to like destroy small town bookstores
Speaker 5:  and he is like, who? No Amazon exists now.
Speaker 5:  He's like, don't worry about it.
Speaker 1:  We're the little guys.
Speaker 5:  We're we're what you need. Like, he's like, small bookstores can't exist
Speaker 5:  without Barnes and Noble because they're the distributor to the small bookstores
Speaker 5:  now. Wow. Ooh. So like your local independent book seller is like,
Speaker 5:  it needs a Barnes and Noble to exist, otherwise Amazon will crush
Speaker 5:  it. Very good.
Speaker 1:  That's incredible. I love that.
Speaker 5:  I don't know if Walmart is that thing for people, but
Speaker 1:  Not yet. Not yet. Quite
Speaker 6:  A take though. But yeah, Walmart has been on this like, relentless quest
Speaker 6:  to just solve logistics in a way I think is super funny and interesting
Speaker 6:  that during the pandemic they, they started talking a lot about we're gonna
Speaker 6:  turn our stores into essentially like super optimized warehouses
Speaker 6:  for Instacart shoppers to come pick stuff up. And they were really
Speaker 6:  big on curbside pickup and they've just, they have this like
Speaker 6:  omnichannel by everything any way you want. It all magically
Speaker 6:  appears at your house vision in their head. And I don't know if it's
Speaker 6:  what anyone actually wants out of their life, but it is the vision that I,
Speaker 6:  that that Walmart has. And I find it sort of fascinating watching them
Speaker 6:  go after
Speaker 1:  It. Well they're like, they saw Amazon doing what they do best
Speaker 1:  and doing it a little better and they went, oh wait, no, we're the biggest
Speaker 1:  guy in the room. We're not just gonna give that up. And as a me
Speaker 1:  have a me because they were, for the longest time, they were like the largest
Speaker 1:  employer in the United States and Amazon took that over. And so Walmart's
Speaker 1:  like, no, no, no, we can employ the most people. No, we actually already
Speaker 1:  have all these warehouses built out. We don't have to go do it. We just call
Speaker 1:  them stores. Right. Supercenters. And in fact, we can just fill that
Speaker 1:  with crap and get it to you faster. So like that part of it I think is really,
Speaker 1:  really interesting. They just said Nu-uh, we're really good at doing this.
Speaker 1:  F you there's
Speaker 5:  A weird set of rumors that Walmart will be the one to buy TikTok, which I
Speaker 5:  think is just like perfect.
Speaker 6:  What?
Speaker 5:  It's very good. I don't know. It's true.
Speaker 1:  I've just love this for the
Speaker 5:  Wall. I just heard the rumors. Okay, here's my pick. Speaking of Amazon Okay.
Speaker 5:  And things. Amazon does pretty devastating report in the
Speaker 5:  Hollywood Reporter this week about Amazon Prime Studios. Oh yeah. Yeah. How
Speaker 5:  badly it's going over there.
Speaker 5:  I'm just gonna do disclosure now I'm gonna talk about streaming.
Speaker 5:  Get ready, buckle up. Comcast NBC
Speaker 5:  Universal Division is investor in V Media. They own Peacock. They Comcast
Speaker 5:  does not love me, but they own Peacock. That's a competitor. We made a
Speaker 5:  Netflix show on the EP of a Netflix show. I've used Hulu. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Everyone in this room has opinions about the I like Obsession. It's on hbo.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Disclosures. Amazon Prime video that invested a
Speaker 5:  ton of money in the Lord of the Ring series. Yep. 37% completion rate.
Speaker 5:  Ooh, it's brutal. No one talks about
Speaker 1:  It. Did you watch it? No.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 1:  It, I watched all of
Speaker 5:  It. It's from Nerds. What do I
Speaker 1:  Like? It was real bad. I got like, I fell asleep. I didn't like laundry during
Speaker 1:  it. It was one of those shows.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. When I was told it was slow, their quote in the piece was like,
Speaker 5:  we we're definitely doing a second season. This was all world building,
Speaker 5:  which is bad. Season one was just set up for season
Speaker 5:  200 million of world building. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Whatever. Nerds. Yeah. Nerd stuff. Yeah. Look at these wizards.
Speaker 5:  Huh? Elves. Tsm. Elves.
Speaker 1:  That's what it was though. You're right. That's what it was.
Speaker 5:  You met Hobbits, you love those. Right? Here's Sumo all
Speaker 5:  Collide.
Speaker 5:  It was, it's very slow show. But the bigger point is,
Speaker 5:  Amazon's entire idea about this thing is you
Speaker 5:  will subscribe to Prime, then you'll get great shows and then
Speaker 5:  it'll make you stay, subscribe to Prime. So you keep shopping on Prime. Right.
Speaker 5:  And the thing itself does not need an identity just has to be good enough
Speaker 5:  that you're happy about it and stay subscribed to Prime. What is fascinating
Speaker 5:  to me, and Alex, I really want your view of this is the
Speaker 5:  normals that I know are all fire TV people. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like everyone, all of Becky's aunts are like fire TV people.
Speaker 1:  Not
Speaker 5:  Roku. Not Roku. It's all Fire tv. It's bonkers to me.
Speaker 1:  That's wild.
Speaker 5:  And I'm like, are they happy with Prime? Are they watching the Lord of the
Speaker 5:  Rings? I think clearly not
Speaker 1:  Prime is stealthy. Like it does technically. It has like the, the largest
Speaker 1:  number of subscribers or the second largest, it's over 200 million
Speaker 1:  subscribers. But they're also, that's because they're also just regular prime
Speaker 1:  shipping subscribers. Yeah. And so most people I don't think really think
Speaker 1:  about it that often except for when they wanna watch a movie and it happens
Speaker 1:  to have it. Or they, they heard like, oh, leave it their own and then they
Speaker 1:  watch it and went, this is gay because it's very gay, it's great, watch it.
Speaker 1:  But a lot of people then were like, no, I didn't want that. And clicked
Speaker 1:  out. So I don't think as many people are engaging with it. And we, and
Speaker 1:  we're, there's that was a big part of that piece too, was about how
Speaker 1:  it hasn't had a big hit. Yeah. Like the closest it's had is a couple like
Speaker 1:  bro shows like the Boys and The
Speaker 5:  Boys is
Speaker 1:  Great. Jack Reacher. Do you like Jack
Speaker 5:  Reacher? I didn't watch
Speaker 1:  Real Bro. Like, it's like bro spy show
Speaker 5:  The Boys is particularly weird because I think people are taking the wrong
Speaker 5:  message from the boys. Yes. Which is that Homeland is cool and it's like,
Speaker 5:  mm. That's not it. That's not what that show's about.
Speaker 1:  They're like, what a white supremacy was awesome. No, no. Wrong. Wrong.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Kill
Speaker 5:  It. What if we lasered everyone's heads? If they pissed us off, that would
Speaker 5:  rule the boy. It's like, no, that's not, yeah, that's not it. Everyone,
Speaker 1:  Most people, it's, it doesn't have these big moments. Like
Speaker 1:  it got Fleabag, but Fleabag wasn't even an Amazon show. They picked it up,
Speaker 1:  they acquired it from, from I think the BBC or something. And
Speaker 5:  That's fine. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Well, and then, and this was a detail that, that was in the story. Amazon
Speaker 6:  then gave Phoebe Waller Bridge who created Fleabag a truckload of money
Speaker 6:  to make more stuff. And then she didn't make anything for them.
Speaker 1:  So she was supposed to make the part of the issue here is that their, their
Speaker 1:  idea is, okay, we need to get people on board, so we're gonna
Speaker 1:  throw money at creators. Which reasonably good, especially nowadays where
Speaker 1:  everybody's throwing money around. That's what everybody, but then they're
Speaker 1:  not following through. And so like Phoebe Waller Bridge and Donald Glover
Speaker 1:  were supposed to make a Mr. And Mrs. Smith show. There was things did not
Speaker 1:  go well there, there were some personality classes, clashes and stuff. So
Speaker 1:  they, they parted ways and she's still now doing a Tomb Raider show,
Speaker 1:  but she has a tendency to go and come up with the idea for a show and then
Speaker 1:  walk away. Huh. Because that's what she's like killing Eve. She did the first
Speaker 1:  season and she was like, this is cool. Bye. And the show got progressively
Speaker 1:  worse as different showrunners came on.
Speaker 6:  The first season's amazing though. It's
Speaker 1:  Really good. The show still was great. I loved it. But yeah, so they're doing
Speaker 1:  that a bunch. They're just throwing money at people and then being like,
Speaker 1:  Hey, did you you do anything with that 20 mil we gave you? No. Cool, here's
Speaker 1:  another
Speaker 5:  Thing, why can't I get these deals?
Speaker 1:  Right. Like, I gotta go do that. That sounds great.
Speaker 5:  The thing that really strikes me with all of these is the harshest
Speaker 5:  criticism. And I think the most devastating criticism in the story is they
Speaker 5:  don't know what they want. Yes. Yeah. Right. And that is to some extent the
Speaker 5:  criticism of Netflix. All the big sort of data driven to
Speaker 5:  some extent the criticism of YouTube is like, this thing has no point of
Speaker 5:  view. It's just a mishmash of stuff. It's all driven by data.
Speaker 1:  Well, and they hired, so the person who's running Amazon Prime, she was hired
Speaker 1:  to have vision and she does have vision, like she was a big fan of Ali, of
Speaker 1:  their own. She's been pushing some other stuff and she's running into
Speaker 1:  conflict with the people who are data driven. And then also the stuff
Speaker 1:  that she puts all her effort into aren't,
Speaker 5:  It's not good. Not
Speaker 1:  Working. Doesn't actually land
Speaker 5:  Lord of
Speaker 1:  The Rings. Yeah. So it's, well that wasn't her her deal. Like she came in
Speaker 1:  to do that. That was Jeff Bezos being like, I wanna watch my Nerd show. And
Speaker 1:  and
Speaker 5:  They In The Expanse Yeah. Which spun completely in like literally into
Speaker 5:  Orbit. Yeah. The second they went through that gate, I was like, the show's
Speaker 5:  dumb, like come over it.
Speaker 1:  And more seasons came.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. They kept making it so many seasons. I just wanna compare that
Speaker 5:  to hbo, which absolutely has a point of view. And just
Speaker 5:  like fires off hit after hit, right. Even with all the corporate chaos of
Speaker 5:  HBO and at t and all the rest, they're like, what we do is we
Speaker 5:  make things we like and then we show them to people. And that's how you get
Speaker 5:  the White Lotus and succession and all the rest of it. And it just doesn't
Speaker 5:  seem like the tech companies that want to take over streaming have gotten
Speaker 5:  it with the notable exception of Apple.
Speaker 1:  Yep. Apple's the only one. And they, they, and that was partly because they
Speaker 1:  hired a bunch of H B O people. Yeah. So part of this is, is Amazon doesn't
Speaker 1:  wanna listen to, to these people that they hire. They go and they hire
Speaker 1:  them and they're like, let's do this. And Amazon's like, nah, let's do this
Speaker 1:  other stuff. And, and so there's just this constant disconnect. And Netflix
Speaker 1:  is having the same issue. Netflix is totally driven by the algorithm to the
Speaker 1:  point that it cancels shows that are really, really popular and then gets
Speaker 1:  people, people furious and lots of bad press and everybody yells at them.
Speaker 1:  And Apple has figured this out because they just trusted
Speaker 1:  that we don't know what we're doing here. We're gonna pay people who do
Speaker 1:  and let them work and like get out of the way and also give them a
Speaker 1:  ton of money to do it. Just a ton of money.
Speaker 6:  Well, and and to be fair, apple has had its share of
Speaker 6:  stinkers. It's just also had some really massive successes
Speaker 6:  in a way that Amazon hasn't. But the thing for me is it's always
Speaker 6:  been like this at Amazon. Like, do you remember when Amazon would put out
Speaker 6:  a bunch of pilots and let people vote on which ones they thought should go
Speaker 6:  to series? Like it turns out that if you do the whole Amazon thing, which
Speaker 6:  is like start with what the customer wants and you know, go out
Speaker 6:  to the end, which is how Amazon says it does everything, you're gonna get
Speaker 6:  shitty stuff because people don't know what they want. And if you ask people
Speaker 6:  what they want, they're gonna say Lord of the Rings. Yeah. And then you have
Speaker 6:  to make a good Lord of the Rings show. And that's much harder than just saying,
Speaker 6:  do you like Lord of the Rings? But then on the flip side, Amazon a at least
Speaker 6:  as far as I can tell, has never been at all clear about what its video stuff
Speaker 6:  is for. And even in the course of this story, they talked a bunch about,
Speaker 6:  like, one of the compelling things about Lord of the Rings was all the like
Speaker 6:  merchandising opportunities. Right? And they, they've talked about this with
Speaker 6:  football too, that if you get people to sign up, like we're gonna be able
Speaker 6:  to sell you football related things like maybe you'll buy
Speaker 6:  todos through Thursday night football. And that that's actually as big a
Speaker 6:  victory as getting you to watch Thursday Night Football through Prime video.
Speaker 6:  And so there's just been this weird thing where it's like, what, what
Speaker 6:  are these shows and movies here to accomplish for Amazon? And
Speaker 6:  I don't necessarily think Amazon has a clear answer to that. They at least
Speaker 6:  have not communicated that to Hollywood. And until they do, it's gonna
Speaker 6:  keep being the same thing where people just come and they're like, what,
Speaker 6:  what do you want from us? Like, what does success look like here?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And and they had even people saying that, I think the guy that did
Speaker 1:  a league with their own was like, what do you want from us? Like Green Lit
Speaker 1:  our
Speaker 5:  Show. They wanna sell baseball pads. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Apparently just the little girls.
Speaker 5:  All right. This is the longest lightning round ever. You can tell we have
Speaker 5:  a lot of feelings about this story. Yeah. But it is notable that the
Speaker 5:  data driven streamers are not producing hits at the rate of
Speaker 5:  the people who are just like have taste. Yeah. Oh, there's a lesson there.
Speaker 5:  Shock. All right, what's your lightning round item?
Speaker 1:  Ooh. So mine is kind of, I'm, I'm folding two in together because we had
Speaker 1:  some handheld news this week. Oh boy. So first of all, Asus,
Speaker 1:  on April Fool's Day, it was like, this was not great. It was really bad.
Speaker 1:  Asus was like, Hey, we're gonna do a really cool handheld April
Speaker 1:  Fools. And everybody's like, well that's stupid. Like the steam deck exists.
Speaker 1:  You could have done that. And then a few days later they're like, oh actually
Speaker 1:  we are doing it. And everybody's like, well that was stupid. Why didn't,
Speaker 1:  why did you message it with April Fools? And I think the idea there was supposed
Speaker 1:  to be, you'd get really excited and wish it existed and then be really excited
Speaker 1:  when it did exist.
Speaker 5:  Oh the the classic April Fool's Gambit.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And instead they just pissed everybody off. And we
Speaker 1:  don't really know a lot about the pricing or what's involved. There's a couple
Speaker 1:  of YouTubers that have seen it so far, it seems potentially really cool.
Speaker 1:  It runs Windows. Could be neat. Could be $600 and nobody would
Speaker 1:  want to spend that on a handheld when a steam deck explode.
Speaker 5:  Why is it called the RO ally? Because
Speaker 1:  It's your ally in gaming.
Speaker 6:  Oh my God. Also, have you ever seen Jesus's product names? Ro
Speaker 6:  Ally is like the best it's ever done. RO
Speaker 1:  Is Republic of Gamer, which was a gaming Yeah. Thing that
Speaker 1:  they acquired years ago. And so they
Speaker 5:  Just, this is the ally. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  All
Speaker 5:  Right. This is your
Speaker 1:  Friend, I'll take it. And then the other part of this is Sony is
Speaker 1:  considering also making a handheld super late to that party in some
Speaker 1:  respects. Even though they did the Vita and they did the PSP and they're
Speaker 1:  both were great overpriced, nobody bought them except for me and
Speaker 5:  Probably Sean. I had a psp.
Speaker 1:  Okay. You, me and Sean. Yeah. We were the three that owned the psp. It
Speaker 1:  was great. Mine was pink.
Speaker 5:  Did I have a Vita too? There's a real chance I might've had a vita along.
Speaker 5:  The
Speaker 1:  Vita was like, it had like 3G in it. You're like, it's like it's practically
Speaker 1:  a phone. I can justify this
Speaker 5:  Purchase. It's weird that a gadget made so little impression that I can't
Speaker 5:  remember if I owned one. But it feels like the sort of thing that I bought
Speaker 1:  It was not great. The games were great for it, but so
Speaker 1:  Sony is looking into this again, curiously not for
Speaker 1:  cloud gaming. That's probably because they have a really bad cloud gaming
Speaker 1:  infrastructure. They farmed it all out to Microsoft. They don't
Speaker 1:  everybody's now somebody's gonna yell at me in the comments and I'm sorry,
Speaker 1:  I know you all love it and it works, but it's garbage.
Speaker 1:  So they're not making it for that. They're making it for remote play. So
Speaker 1:  you can just play your PS five. Yeah. Far away from your house. That makes
Speaker 1:  sense. But that might be the only thing you can do with it. And how much
Speaker 1:  is it gonna cost? Cuz everybody's struggling to get it under $400.
Speaker 1:  And why would you spend $400 on something to just play your PS five
Speaker 1:  that's at home when you could spend $400 on the steam deck
Speaker 1:  that lets you do that and play other games.
Speaker 6:  I would assume this has to be coming alongside
Speaker 6:  some like huge expansion in Sony's cloud gaming
Speaker 6:  stuff because if not, yeah, you're exactly right. This just becomes like
Speaker 6:  history's most expensive, barely useful PlayStation
Speaker 6:  peripheral. Just slightly edging the, the move sticks
Speaker 6:  that existed. But just
Speaker 1:  The recording was was like emphatically like it's not for cloud gaming,
Speaker 1:  it's for remote play, which is why it's so weird. Also the name is
Speaker 1:  bad.
Speaker 5:  What's the
Speaker 1:  Name Q Light.
Speaker 5:  It's okay. It's worse than Rogue
Speaker 1:  Ally. Yeah, it was like, which do you want Rag Ally
Speaker 5:  Or QAN on the
Speaker 6:  Videos? Hope that's a, let's hope that's a code name.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Can I tell you whatever? They can do whatever they want. Okay,
Speaker 5:  that's fine.
Speaker 1:  You'll buy it.
Speaker 5:  Sony needs to put psvr two Grand Teresa
Speaker 5:  mode demo stations in every mall and store
Speaker 5:  and seven-eleven in America. How
Speaker 1:  Many times have you vomited playing it?
Speaker 5:  No. So the first day was really bad. Okay. So I had Addie send me
Speaker 5:  one of our PSVR two review units and then I bought a
Speaker 5:  Logitech G 9 23 wheel in pedals and a love it and a
Speaker 5:  chair just it's, I was like whatever is fully
Speaker 5:  ridiculous, but I live in the woods, I'm in the basement, no one can see,
Speaker 5:  see me headset on and the first day I was like, Ooh, this is a
Speaker 5:  mistake. Super queasy. And then just a couple days later
Speaker 5:  is fine. Okay, so a couple days of queasy. I'm obsessed. It is
Speaker 5:  like being in the stupid cars.
Speaker 1:  Love that. Do you like miss the break? Do you have break
Speaker 1:  pushback and stuff like when a real car you can feel it when you're breaking?
Speaker 5:  No, because it's just, they're plastic pedals.
Speaker 6:  You know, you can spend like 30 grand on this setup mil Eli and I feel like
Speaker 6:  we are, we're headed down a
Speaker 5:  Dangerous road. Yeah. I've spent a bunch of credit card points and fine,
Speaker 5:  like I haven't spent like, it was like a hundred dollars on a bunch of credit
Speaker 5:  card points to accomplish this setup. It is legitimately
Speaker 5:  the most compelling thing you can do in vr. Yeah. Like it is so cool.
Speaker 5:  It's so much fun. You convince yourself that you're moving,
Speaker 5:  which is bizarre. Like absolutely bizarre to
Speaker 5:  be sitting dead, still holding a plastic wheel that you cannot
Speaker 5:  see cuz you're wearing a VR headset and like leaning your body like it's
Speaker 5:  crazy. I took off, my wife came down the stairs the other day and I took
Speaker 5:  off the headset and I literally went, you gotta try this. And she was like,
Speaker 5:  what is wrong with you?
Speaker 1:  Just went right back up the
Speaker 5:  Stairs. I'm outta here for all of the, we talked so much about last week,
Speaker 5:  talked about AR killer apps, all this stuff. It's an incredibly complicated
Speaker 5:  full setup. Yeah. It's like $1,500 worth of stuff, right?
Speaker 5:  You need a PS five, you need a head sandwich, another five, $600. You need
Speaker 5:  to buy a wheel A, it's all ridiculous chair. And you
Speaker 5:  can, you can spend like $30,000 on like full motion
Speaker 5:  iRacing PC based max for stop in the F F1 racer
Speaker 5:  has a full rig in his trailer. So he leaves F1 races
Speaker 5:  and then sim races against people using his real name,
Speaker 5:  which is incredible. It's
Speaker 1:  Badass.
Speaker 6:  Devastating sim racing as yourself is the coolest imaginable thing
Speaker 5:  And all. That's fine. And like I have friends and I've tried those things
Speaker 5:  on screens with the three, three screens around you. I'm telling you put
Speaker 5:  on a VR headset, you're like, oh, this is the coolest thing you can do in
Speaker 5:  vr. Yeah. So needs to throw this cloud gaming,
Speaker 5:  whatever, get people the headsets with the racing games
Speaker 1:  That should, that's like they're Tetris.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's $1,500 of sim racing setup.
Speaker 5:  Also, it judges you every time you put it on. It's like, are you sitting
Speaker 5:  down again? And it's like, I'm definitely sitting down again. It's like,
Speaker 5:  don't you wanna play standing up, moving around? It's like, no, no, no. I'm
Speaker 5:  in the chair, bro.
Speaker 6:  Stationary mode. What's up?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, let's go. It's like every time it's like, are you, you're stationary
Speaker 5:  again, huh? It's like sure am. Let's just put the pedal
Speaker 5:  to the metal, bro.
Speaker 5:  It's very good. Okay, one more. Wait, how many picks are we at?
Speaker 5:  That was like one each, basically we
Speaker 6:  Did one each. You you get one more and then I think we should probably go,
Speaker 5:  All right, let me wrap this up. Last lightning round item. This is me just
Speaker 5:  assigning myself a story again. We'll have it on the website tomorrow. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Something is happening in Wisconsin.
Speaker 1:  Cheese, it's 49ers.
Speaker 5:  Aaron Rodgers is
Speaker 5:  leaving the only things anyone can think of. So as you
Speaker 5:  know, I'm obsessed with the fox on plot, which is just minutes away from
Speaker 5:  the child, my childhood home in Wisconsin. Yeah. They're gonna do something
Speaker 5:  on it and it's not coffee robots or whatever nonsense they claim they
Speaker 5:  were doing. It's definitely not building TVs.
Speaker 6:  A K A I. Yeah. Wait, so the first thing, let's just, let's run through the
Speaker 6:  history of this real fast. So it was real
Speaker 5:  Fast. You think
Speaker 6:  It was gonna be, it was gonna be TVs,
Speaker 5:  Right? Yes. So in the Trump administration, Donald Trump
Speaker 5:  golden shovel breaks ground with Terry Go, chairman of Foxconn says we're
Speaker 5:  building a TV factory in Mount Pleasant Wisconsin. They ram
Speaker 5:  it through the bulldozed houses, the whole
Speaker 5:  thing. AI eight k plus 5g. Sure. The plus they're gonna
Speaker 5:  do 15,000 jobs, billions in tax subsidies. I don't
Speaker 5:  need to tell you that this did not happen. It was never
Speaker 5:  gonna happen. And it definitely did not happen. At one point in the course
Speaker 5:  of this story, when they broke ground on the factory
Speaker 5:  display experts told us that foundation doesn't look correct
Speaker 5:  for an L C D fab. And we asked them and they said, the
Speaker 5:  special clay soil in Wisconsin does not means that we do
Speaker 5:  not need to build the foundation that you need in the rest of the world.
Speaker 5:  And I went, I'm from there. And no one ever told me that the dirt was
Speaker 5:  special.
Speaker 5:  So that was weird. So then they built this weird building, they call it the
Speaker 5:  multi-purpose building. It is all but empty. They used it for storage, edit
Speaker 5:  rezone to storage. They claim they coffee robots. They think they're making
Speaker 5:  server boards for Google there, but they won't claim no reporters have ever
Speaker 5:  been there. There's a tiny dome they claim is a data center, but the
Speaker 5:  actual data center is in shipping containers outside the dome. It's a, it's
Speaker 5:  all very good geodesic dome, right? Yeah. It's like a little,
Speaker 5:  it's so, it's like by my parents' house. Every time I go home I look at it,
Speaker 5:  I'm like, it's so small.
Speaker 6:  It's just a little, little snow globe data center.
Speaker 5:  And it's not, it's just like a conference center. You can rent it out for
Speaker 5:  weddings. Anyhow, first
Speaker 6:  Of all, let's, let's do that. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  If any our casters are getting married in Wisconsin. Might I interest you
Speaker 5:  in Mount Pleasant Wisconsin?
Speaker 6:  Mili will officiate your wedding at the do.
Speaker 5:  That's true. Every time when my sister got married, my parents renovated
Speaker 5:  the house. When my, when I got married, they did the backyard. My parents,
Speaker 5:  they're looking to do the bathroom and apparently it takes a wedding to kick
Speaker 5:  him into gear. So if you're listening to this,
Speaker 6:  Get at us.
Speaker 5:  Let me know.
Speaker 5:  So there's a news report. Somebody tweeted this at me and
Speaker 5:  just looking at Twitter in the background, I, I came upon it DA
Speaker 5:  Mount Pleasant, the board that approved the Fox End deal, just like quietly
Speaker 5:  announced that Microsoft would be building a data center there. They did
Speaker 5:  this a week before the election. So they announced this thing Microsoft is
Speaker 5:  building a data center. They have not taken the votes to do it, but they
Speaker 5:  announced it before the election to prove that fox hunt is a great idea.
Speaker 5:  So I'm looking at the story and I'm like, I don't, I don't know about this.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I will say Microsoft President Brad Smith is from Appleton, Wisconsin,
Speaker 5:  loves Wisconsin. There's a big tech campus at Lambeau Field called Title
Speaker 5:  Town Tech. Okay. The man loves Wisconsin. He likes investing in Wisconsin.
Speaker 5:  Love it. Love it for me. Love it for him. I've not yet been invited to Lambeau
Speaker 5:  Field. I'm just putting that out there. But I feel like it's two hometown
Speaker 5:  boys. We could really vibe. So I asked Microsoft, Microsoft sends me the
Speaker 5:  following statement. This is all they say. Our data center campus investment
Speaker 5:  plans with the village of Mount Pleasant in Racine County are part of
Speaker 5:  Microsoft's long-term commitment for the local communities in Wisconsin.
Speaker 5:  We look forward to our work there. Other than that, we don't have more to
Speaker 5:  say, nor are we doing interviews.
Speaker 6:  So that's nothing.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 1:  All right.
Speaker 5:  I was like, can I talk to anyone about how many jobs are Will this data center?
Speaker 5:  It's a room full of servers.
Speaker 1:  It's a one job.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Microsoft data centers, they're around the country. You can see they
Speaker 5:  don't make a lot of jobs and they know it. Kevin Scott, the CTO of Microsoft,
Speaker 5:  has a whole book about how data centers don't make a lot of jobs. It's a
Speaker 5:  great book. He was on again on Dakota. We've talked about it. He's like,
Speaker 5:  this is not the thing that is like an engine of job creation. Yeah. But you
Speaker 5:  need to have them and like then you build infrastructure and you have power
Speaker 5:  grids and this helps local communities. They're getting tax rebates and subsidies
Speaker 5:  for it as always. And Mount Pleasant and Foxconn are like, this
Speaker 5:  is what happens when you build the infrastructure. The clients
Speaker 5:  will come and it's like, no, you guys were, you tore down
Speaker 5:  people's homes to build the TV factory. Where's the
Speaker 5:  TV factory?
Speaker 1:  Where we're the jobs? Where are the jobs?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So we're gonna be tracking the Microsoft data center in Mount Pleasant.
Speaker 5:  I'm sure they're actually gonna build it, but I think
Speaker 6:  They literally, they field of dreams did they just, if you build it, they
Speaker 6:  will come just throw up a giant empty building and somebody will come put
Speaker 6:  servers
Speaker 5:  In. And by it, just to be specifically clear is it is
Speaker 5:  declaring the land on which people's homes sit as
Speaker 5:  blighted, tearing them all down. Trucking water from
Speaker 5:  Lake Michigan over there and building a power substation for no one
Speaker 5:  to life fallow for three years. So that eventually Microsoft
Speaker 5:  is like, yeah, sure. We'll put one
Speaker 1:  Classic
Speaker 6:  Field of dreams.
Speaker 5:  That's it. I mean that's field of dreams too.
Speaker 1:  Just the movie.
Speaker 5:  We're so, we're again, we're tracking it. I, I dunno what to tell
Speaker 5:  you. Like it is very silly. I think it is
Speaker 5:  very odd that Microsoft isn't like pounding its chest. They're building a
Speaker 5:  data center in southeastern Wisconsin. Like they just, they just don't want
Speaker 5:  to talk about it. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  When do you run for mayor of Receipt Wisconsin? This is the only outcome
Speaker 6:  here.
Speaker 5:  I don't know that I could get my dad to vote for me, so that's gonna be tough.
Speaker 6:  You did swear once on the ver.com. He didn't like
Speaker 5:  That. Did My parents were not, I think I could get my mom. Okay.
Speaker 6:  It's a good start.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Just promise you'll never swear again. Would that help?
Speaker 5:  I don't know that I'm prepared to make these commitments to the people of
Speaker 5:  Wisconsin today.
Speaker 5:  And I will consider my options at this time hearing from my
Speaker 5:  attorney.
Speaker 6:  We're not doing interviews.
Speaker 1:  We're not doing no interviews. No press. Sorry. Sorry. No
Speaker 5:  Press. All right. That's it. That's a vergecast. I promise that
Speaker 5:  all the stories we've talked about will be published. David will publish
Speaker 5:  about Activity Pub. Yes. I will write about Wisconsin.
Speaker 1:  I made no promises today.
Speaker 5:  You did one last week, right?
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I did one last week. I I did
Speaker 5:  The album music classical.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So I promised it and I
Speaker 5:  Delivered. I swear to God this entire show is just for us to ideate stories
Speaker 5:  put on the website. But that's why you love it. That's the ver cast stuff
Speaker 5:  on the website you should look at. We do have a retrospective of Lisa going
Speaker 5:  on the Apple, Lisa, the precursor McIntosh, the Computer History museum.
Speaker 5:  It's great. Go look at it. I really want people to read McKenna's story about
Speaker 5:  the Donald Trump protests in front of Matt and
Speaker 5:  Courthouse and how they, everyone there was a streamer. It is one of the
Speaker 5:  verges verge stories we've ever published. It's very good. That's really
Speaker 5:  good. And we have the same with the home assistant Sky Connect, which is
Speaker 5:  another just extremely verge story.
Speaker 1:  It's so verge, so new.
Speaker 5:  Like that's the range. And then take the color quiz, whatever. David,
Speaker 5:  do you wanna tell people to vote for the People's Choice Award?
Speaker 6:  Yes. So the Vergecast is nominated for a Webby Award for best technology
Speaker 6:  podcast. We're currently losing to a TechCrunch podcast.
Speaker 6:  Ooh. I like TechCrunch fine. They're all lovely people. I would like to
Speaker 6:  destroy them and bury them in the ground with our votes. Please
Speaker 6:  go. We'll put the link in the show notes. Please go vote for the Verge so
Speaker 6:  that we can gloat to everyone we ever met that we on the webby and they didn't.
Speaker 2:  It's like a spring.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The award itself is rad looking and I want one, so
Speaker 6:  let's, let's
Speaker 5:  Get it. Very good. That's it. That's for Trust rock.
Speaker 16:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you
Speaker 16:  enjoy the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend,
Speaker 16:  you can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is
Speaker 16:  produced by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 16:  This episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose
Speaker 16:  Smith. Our editorial director is Brooke Min, and our executive producer
Speaker 16:  is Eleanor Donovan. The Verge Cast is a production of the Verge and
Speaker 16:  Box Media Podcast network. And that's it. We'll see you next week.