# Transcript
ID: c4e76b29-8580-4dda-9aa9-c832d7f101c6
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The fight to save old games
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7722564044131987305/-8856097628957405036/s93290-US-4317s-1699884327.mp3
Description: In episode two of our gaming mini series, The Verge's David Pierce chats with Polygon's Russ Frushtick and Chris Plante about the obstacles around both preserving and emulating video games from discontinued hardware.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  Support for The Vergecast comes from Quest three, the new mixed reality headset
Speaker 1:  from Meta. Now you can expand your world in ways you never thought possible
Speaker 1:  with the new Meta Quest three meta centers wanted to try and man does this
Speaker 1:  thing look futuristic? With over 500 titles, it's easy to dive into whatever
Speaker 1:  you're into. You can check out the new meta three now available for 4 99.
Speaker 1:  Learn more@meta.com. See child safety guidance online accounts for 10 years
Speaker 1:  or older. Certain apps, games and experiences may be suitable for a more
Speaker 1:  mature audience.
Speaker 3:  Welcome To, The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Horizontal Scan Lines.
Speaker 3:  I'm your friend David Pierce, and this is the second episode in our three-part
Speaker 3:  miniseries about the future of gaming. And today to talk about the future
Speaker 3:  of gaming, we're gonna talk about the past of gaming,
Speaker 3:  specifically these decades of video games on old
Speaker 3:  consoles and old media systems. Like remember the cartridges you had to blow
Speaker 3:  in? What happens to those games as the companies that make them
Speaker 3:  disappear and the consoles that they worked on disappear. And the CRT
Speaker 3:  TV V, you plugged it into disappears. How do we save those games?
Speaker 3:  Do we wanna save those games? What does it mean to save those games? That's
Speaker 3:  what we're gonna get into today. My colleagues from Polygon, Chris Plant
Speaker 3:  and Russ Frushtick are both back with me today To get into all of this,
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna consult with them and then go out, try to find some answers and
Speaker 3:  then present them with my findings. Let's get into it.
Speaker 3:  Russ. Hello. Welcome back.
Speaker 4:  Hello,
Speaker 3:  Chris. Hello.
Speaker 1:  I'm back baby.
Speaker 3:  We're doing this again. I'm excited for our second topic in this
Speaker 3:  series. We picked something, I think, if I remember correctly, I brought
Speaker 3:  this up when we were talking about what we wanted to cover on this series
Speaker 3:  and you immediately were like, David You know Nothing. Let's explain how
Speaker 3:  this actually works. Which makes me very excited about this because this
Speaker 3:  is a subject I find very interesting and know very little about and I'm excited
Speaker 3:  to dig into the weeds of it, which is essentially how
Speaker 3:  we adapt and change very old games to be able to play them.
Speaker 3:  Now some of that is old hardware, some of that is you can play old N 64
Speaker 3:  games on your phone. There are like people who exist
Speaker 3:  in the world to try and preserve these games. I guess it's, it's, would we
Speaker 3:  call it emulation and preservation as a topic? Is that a good
Speaker 3:  way to look at it?
Speaker 4:  I think there are two separate concepts there. Okay. Emulation and
Speaker 4:  preservation are like two obviously related, but there are a lot of people
Speaker 4:  that are focused on preservation that aren't using emulation and vice versa.
Speaker 4:  But they're both equally important when it comes to preserving the history
Speaker 4:  of video games overall.
Speaker 3:  Catch me up just really quickly. Again, this is truly a world I know very
Speaker 3:  little about except that it's very popular and it's the kind of thing that
Speaker 3:  like a lot of people like to buy an Android phone just to do.
Speaker 3:  Like one of the things I hear over and over is people like to buy Android
Speaker 3:  phones just to play old video games on them. And I'm like, sure, that's a,
Speaker 3:  that's a reason How big a thing is this? Like you guys are in the
Speaker 3:  day-to-day of covering games. Like is this kind of emulation world something
Speaker 3:  you spend much time thinking about?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, honestly, I mean it's not just people just downloading
Speaker 4:  like a rom online to play contra on their pc.
Speaker 4:  Nintendo uses emulation on their official switch online. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Service to allow their games to run on modern hardware.
Speaker 4:  So everyone is using emulation at that point to play older games.
Speaker 4:  But emulation is not perfect when it comes to recreating every
Speaker 4:  aspect of how the game originally ran. And some of those aspects are bad.
Speaker 4:  Like the game ran at 10 frames a second when there were 30 bullets on the
Speaker 4:  screen. But that is like the true experience that developers
Speaker 4:  kind of created when they originally made the game. So a lot of people really
Speaker 4:  focused on when recreating those experiences as authentically
Speaker 4:  as possible on as many platforms as possible.
Speaker 5:  And I, I think that's where Fresh mentioned the difference between emulation
Speaker 5:  and preservation. Preservation is trying to
Speaker 5:  either recreate that perfectly, which we will get into with things like the
Speaker 5:  MR device or system or making it so that you can
Speaker 5:  just still play your original hardware. Right? Like
Speaker 5:  can you find an old school CRTV and an original Super
Speaker 5:  Nintendo and the original game, they all kind of can blend
Speaker 5:  together. You know you can get emulation that is close to preservation perfect.
Speaker 5:  But it, it gets really nitty gritty really fast. And
Speaker 5:  we thought after last week's episode you didn't kick the
Speaker 5:  kind of purest nest hard enough so this
Speaker 5:  week you would really go for it and and awakened the the
Speaker 5:  beast within. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I'm partly fascinated by this because I think I have always
Speaker 3:  struggled with this idea that you should preserve something exactly as it
Speaker 3:  was in the time in which it existed, right? Like the idea
Speaker 3:  that a video game from 25 years ago deserves to be played on a crappy
Speaker 3:  console and a crappy TV that is like only has three channels and rabbit ears
Speaker 3:  is like, I've always had a hard time with that because part of me is like,
Speaker 3:  well at most things are better now, right? It's like we, we don't eat
Speaker 3:  like cavemen because we have better diets now because we've figured out how
Speaker 3:  to not die. And a lot of the same stuff is true. I think like this stuff
Speaker 3:  gets better and I think a lot of these ideas about how do we preserve what
Speaker 3:  these games were sort of in the essence of them so that they don't go away
Speaker 3:  separating that from TVs were worse 30 years ago and
Speaker 3:  they're better now and maybe that's okay. It has always been hard for me.
Speaker 3:  Even just like emotionally,
Speaker 4:  I'm about to blow your mind even further. The problem is all of these games
Speaker 4:  and all the art in these games was made for those shitty TVs.
Speaker 3:  That is true. I play like the old, old, old versions of some of these
Speaker 3:  games and they just look like crap on new TVs.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. 'cause they were designed for CT TVs. Like it's really wild. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I guess the big question that I have for you is
Speaker 5:  the mix of legality and purpose of emulation and
Speaker 5:  preservation. I was
Speaker 3:  Just about to ask am I in for like a, do I have to go talk to a bunch of
Speaker 3:  lawyers about the rules around this stuff?
Speaker 4:  I think you might. Okay.
Speaker 5:  I think you will because yeah, pirating ROMs and playing them
Speaker 5:  on your emulated handheld is illegal Like that.
Speaker 5:  That's just like a hard, a hard truth of it, right? Whether or not it is
Speaker 5:  like morally okay or you personally can justify it or you own
Speaker 5:  the game and then that's, you feel that that is comfortable enough.
Speaker 5:  That's all I think very valuable. But then when we get to the question of
Speaker 5:  preservation, a lot of these companies are not preserving
Speaker 5:  their games and either are actively
Speaker 5:  or passively creating blockades that would allow
Speaker 5:  people to preserve the games for them. So by that I mean why can
Speaker 5:  libraries not allow you to emulate video games, right?
Speaker 5:  Like that seems fine. That seems like a, a good and reasonable
Speaker 5:  thing. You know there are video libraries where you can see
Speaker 5:  Broadway plays that were filmed, right? Sure. Like there are libraries that
Speaker 5:  allow for things that are legally tricky and you, you make that kind of
Speaker 5:  carve out. And I think what is kind of led to this
Speaker 5:  emulation boom is publishers being so protective
Speaker 5:  of their stuff, so unwilling to make it more
Speaker 5:  widely available or their own, I think
Speaker 5:  legal murkiness when they look back at their old paperwork, they might not
Speaker 5:  even know who owns certain things or they might not even have the original
Speaker 5:  source code. So there's just a lot of
Speaker 5:  problems that I think are getting in the way of preservation and emulation
Speaker 5:  has been able to answer those. We're kind of creating
Speaker 5:  its own.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. That's really interesting. Okay, two more things I'm curious about
Speaker 3:  and then I'm gonna, I'm gonna go chase a bunch of people down and see what
Speaker 3:  I can figure out. The first thing, Chris you mentioned the mister. I had
Speaker 3:  never heard of the mister until you mentioned it. Tell me about the mister.
Speaker 5:  I'm not going to. I said it's your turn to kick
Speaker 5:  the Hornet's. That's not my turn.
Speaker 3:  Oh crap. Okay.
Speaker 5:  But the basic idea is what if
Speaker 5:  you could virtually recreate
Speaker 5:  the physical boards that powered video games
Speaker 5:  in the past? So you are not creating a, an
Speaker 5:  idea, an emulated version of of the Super Nintendo. You are
Speaker 5:  digitally recreating the Super Nintendo so it should run
Speaker 5:  one for one. I think that's right. I think there's a
Speaker 5:  real chance that you play that tape back for him and he is like, I think
Speaker 5:  I need to go fire somebody and his name's Chris Plant, but
Speaker 5:  it confuses me. I can say that I have one right behind me
Speaker 5:  and it plays Simpson's arcade or whatever really, really well. And that's
Speaker 5:  pretty cool.
Speaker 3:  That's the dream. And then the other thing is Russ, when we were planning
Speaker 3:  this, you mentioned games that are for one reason or another
Speaker 3:  unlikable and, and the challenge that comes with that. What's on your mind
Speaker 3:  when you think about that?
Speaker 4:  I don't think there's a game that is 100% un emel able.
Speaker 4:  Okay. But there are games that are surprisingly resource
Speaker 4:  heavy for when they came out. The example that springs to my mind is
Speaker 4:  Yoshi's Island, the original Yoshi's Island which came out on Super Nintendo.
Speaker 4:  People use the start menu of Yoshi's Island
Speaker 4:  as a benchmark for whether a device can handle an intense
Speaker 4:  handheld emulation experience because it uses this
Speaker 4:  wild mode seven three D art thing that doesn't
Speaker 4:  exist anywhere else in the game. But like that's an example of something
Speaker 4:  that is like, that's what people look at when they're testing like an emulation
Speaker 4:  handheld for example. And there are a number of those examples I'm
Speaker 4:  sure that pros can point you to, but that was the one that jumped to my
Speaker 4:  mind. I'd
Speaker 5:  Give two other types of emulation where you are gonna have trouble,
Speaker 5:  anything that required specialized physical hardware. So like Warrior Aware,
Speaker 5:  twisted I think Sure. Had a special cartridge. I'm curious about how
Speaker 5:  people emulate things like that and they preserve those things.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We games for example.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And also online games as we get more and
Speaker 5:  more to You know always online video games.
Speaker 5:  Fortnite, like what does it mean to emulate or preserve
Speaker 5:  Fortnite in its mini manifestations, right?
Speaker 5:  Because Fortnite today is, might as well be Fortnite 12, right? It is
Speaker 5:  not the same game that came out or was even out a year ago
Speaker 5:  and I, I don't know, I don't know the answer there.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Yeah. So I think I, I need to go figure out basically what does it
Speaker 3:  look like to preserve this stuff? Is it allowed?
Speaker 3:  And, and, and then like how are we as people supposed to interact with it,
Speaker 3:  right? Because I think there's a version of this that it's like, it's cool
Speaker 3:  that this stuff exists for sort of purely archival purposes, right? Like
Speaker 3:  put Fortnite 1.0 in a museum. It's cool that we can see what that looked
Speaker 3:  like at the time. That's one version of it. But there's also a version of
Speaker 3:  it that it's like, what if we as people who like to play games had access
Speaker 3:  to every game that has ever existed in something like the form in which it
Speaker 3:  was intended to be consumed. That's very cool and very exciting and
Speaker 3:  super, super complicated for a thousand reasons So I. Think I'm gonna, I'm
Speaker 3:  gonna run both of those things down and see what I can come back with. Does
Speaker 3:  that sound good?
Speaker 4:  Rock and roll.
Speaker 5:  I love it.
Speaker 3:  All, right? We're gonna take a break. I'm gonna go explore a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna come back in a couple of weeks. But for you thanks to editing,
Speaker 3:  it's gonna be much faster. We'll be right back.
Speaker 6:  This podcast is brought to you by Meta Quest three, the new mixed reality
Speaker 6:  headset from Meta. Now you can expand your world in ways you never thought
Speaker 6:  possible with the new Meta Quest. Three, put on the sleek most powerful
Speaker 6:  quest yet and jump into fully immersive games or blend virtual
Speaker 6:  elements into your physical surroundings with mixed reality. Instantly
Speaker 6:  Go from watching to playing the part in your favorite show with Stranger
Speaker 6:  Things vr. Live the action and really feel what it's like to step into
Speaker 6:  the shoes of an assassin, an Assassin's Creed nexus. Even turn your
Speaker 6:  couch into court side seats with X stadium and watch your favorite
Speaker 6:  NBA team. With over 500 titles, it's easy to dive into
Speaker 6:  whatever you're into, expand your world with me. Quest three, see
Speaker 6:  child safety guidance online accounts for 10. For 10 and up Certain apps,
Speaker 6:  games and experiences may be suitable for a more mature audience. Learn more@meta.com.
Speaker 3:  All, right, Welcome back. It's been a few weeks. I've gone all the way across
Speaker 3:  the country. We're recording these. I've discovered where I'm in a different
Speaker 3:  place every single time we record. This is like a fun game. We're playing
Speaker 3:  for an audio podcast that no one will get anything out of. How are your lives?
Speaker 3:  Tell me everything. What have you been up to?
Speaker 5:  It's been such a, a thrilling time. Fresh. Actually
Speaker 5:  solved a cold case 30 years in the making. Wow. Huge. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It turns out it was me the whole time. I just didn't want to admit it. So
Speaker 4:  it was actually a pretty easy case to
Speaker 3:  Solve. It's open and shut when you get to it. Well, okay, emulation and preservation.
Speaker 3:  This turned into kind of a, a strange like philosophical rabbit
Speaker 3:  hole for me of talking to folks about what it means to keep
Speaker 3:  video games around And. what we did last time was I had sort
Speaker 3:  of five pieces of evidence for a theory that I developed in the course of
Speaker 3:  talking to people. And we talked about why handheld gaming is the future.
Speaker 3:  This time I have come to you with, I would say, five ideas about how we can
Speaker 3:  make game emulation and preservation work for everybody.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Some
Speaker 3:  Of these I think are very good ideas. Some of these I think are very bad
Speaker 3:  impossible ideas, but they are ideas that I have heard from people over and
Speaker 3:  over. So I'm gonna throw them all at you and we're just gonna, we're
Speaker 3:  gonna litigate what happens to old games. How does that sound? I love it.
Speaker 5:  Why am I afraid that we're, you're gonna throw five very good ideas
Speaker 5:  at us and all of them are going to end with unfortunately that
Speaker 5:  requires legal changes and there will never
Speaker 5:  be any movement on this for at least 10 years.
Speaker 3:  I have really great news for you. Idea number two is change all the laws.
Speaker 3:  So we're getting great at that. Cool, cool,
Speaker 5:  Cool, cool. Cool. Cool. Cool. Cool. Cool. Covered.
Speaker 3:  We talked a little bit about the UpTop, but I just to like reset the scene
Speaker 3:  here a bit question I found myself asking everybody is basically like why
Speaker 3:  do we wanna preserve old games? And I got a lot of good answers from
Speaker 3:  smart people, but I just have a couple that I want to play for you right
Speaker 3:  now. One thing a couple of people told me was that they compared the
Speaker 3:  video game industry now to like the early days of the film industry, which
Speaker 3:  I think is a fairly common thing in, in this space. It's a, it's a useful
Speaker 3:  metaphor for how we think about how long things live and the formats of them.
Speaker 3:  And a thing that people told me that I had not realized but is very true
Speaker 3:  is there's a huge amount of stuff from like the twenties and thirties in
Speaker 3:  Hollywood that is just gone like fully gone, does not exist. No one will
Speaker 3:  ever see it again because it was made once it was put on one thing, it was
Speaker 3:  shown in theaters because that was the only way to watch movies and then
Speaker 3:  it just died and those things are gone and there's this real sadness in that
Speaker 3:  industry about how we lost what turned out to be these crucial
Speaker 3:  parts of film history. But at that time it wasn't history, it was just like
Speaker 3:  this weird lark that people were doing. So there was no feeling that this
Speaker 3:  is a thing we need to preserve. And there are a lot of people who feel like
Speaker 3:  the early days of the video game industry in particular has really
Speaker 3:  run into that. One of the people I talked to for this was a guy named Frank
Speaker 3:  Safadi who I'm sure you guys know, he runs the video game history foundation
Speaker 3:  and he told me a bunch about the idea of the old film industry and and he
Speaker 3:  made that same comparison but he did this really great thing where he was
Speaker 3:  like, let me explain to you what it's like to have a video game right now.
Speaker 3:  And I just really enjoyed the way he explained it. So lemme just play this
Speaker 3:  for you real fast.
Speaker 8:  We often compare it to like if movies were only released on
Speaker 8:  like VHS ever and you wanna watch
Speaker 8:  back to the Future All, right? Well you have to go on eBay and you have
Speaker 8:  to like find an antique VHS copy that's
Speaker 8:  degraded a little bit from use of Back to the Future. You have to find
Speaker 8:  AVCR that works a TV that it plugs into
Speaker 8:  or you have to like find the external scalers that make it look
Speaker 8:  correct on your modern tv. You might need a time-based
Speaker 8:  corrector 'cause and those are really expensive because the the
Speaker 8:  magnetic fluxx signal is like out of sync or whatever, You know what I mean?
Speaker 8:  Like that, that's where video games are in in the
Speaker 8:  legal world. That's literally the same thing.
Speaker 3:  I love this explanation and it makes it seem like a mess. Does this feel
Speaker 3:  right to you? Like does his way of thinking about it track?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, so in other words what he's saying is because games are
Speaker 4:  specifically designed for very specific hardware, in order
Speaker 4:  to experience them now the way they were intended, you
Speaker 4:  need to have the hardware itself. So in his example you need AVHS
Speaker 4:  player to play A-V-V-H-S tape and that's the case with so many
Speaker 4:  games, which I think is fair, especially for the games from like the
Speaker 4:  eighties, nineties. Absolutely I think it's gotten a little better but
Speaker 4:  it's still definitely true.
Speaker 5:  I think there's another way of kind of hearing what Frank said that I had
Speaker 5:  not considered, which is with an original movie you
Speaker 5:  would have the original elements like the actual film that you shot right
Speaker 5:  before it then gets like transferred over and over and over again.
Speaker 5:  And the comparison to AVHS tape is really interesting because
Speaker 5:  we don't have the source code for so, so many
Speaker 5:  games. The original code of most games is lost
Speaker 5:  even very big games. And with the
Speaker 5:  VHS tape I, there's a way of hearing that as we are not even
Speaker 5:  getting the best version of it. We're just getting a version of like how
Speaker 5:  they could print it at the time. I think that that gets into like
Speaker 5:  real nitty gritty of preservation. Are you the person who thinks that a game
Speaker 5:  should be experienced? Exactly. Was it experienced in 1996
Speaker 5:  for You know Nintendo six super or whatever Or do you think it should be
Speaker 5:  experienced like literally the code that they wrote? And yeah, I had never
Speaker 5:  considered it like that. If you think about it as the latter, I mean
Speaker 5:  wow that would be, that actually really messes with preservation because
Speaker 5:  it, I can think of very, very, very few games where the
Speaker 5:  code of a game is available.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So okay you, you just brought up a thing I was gonna get to later but
Speaker 3:  let's just talk about this now. The single most controversial thing
Speaker 3:  I talked about with all the people I talked about for this was this question
Speaker 3:  of is the right way to preserve a video game to
Speaker 3:  preserve it exactly as it was and exactly as it felt and like
Speaker 3:  the most true to the experience at the time. Like should the way you
Speaker 3:  play a game from the 1980s be on a 1980s TV in like a
Speaker 3:  shag carpet living room with fluorescent lights everywhere? Like
Speaker 3:  should it be as close to what it was when it came out as possible? Or
Speaker 3:  are there ways we can like modernize and improve these things? And
Speaker 3:  a lot of people use the word artist's intent, right? Like to what extent
Speaker 3:  can we infer what they wanted to do and were technically constrained from
Speaker 3:  being able to do versus what was it at the time and
Speaker 3:  which of those is actual correct preservation? And I have a bunch
Speaker 3:  of, I have a bunch of theories and some answers that I got that I'm gonna
Speaker 3:  play for you guys, but I wanna know what you guys think about this 'cause
Speaker 3:  I suspect this is a debate that's happening all over the gaming industry
Speaker 3:  all the time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think there are people that only see what
Speaker 4:  you were describing early on the experience. You have to have an eighties
Speaker 4:  TV and you have to be running on original NES hardware and I
Speaker 4:  think there are definitely people that consider that to be really the only
Speaker 4:  way you can experience an NES game from that era properly.
Speaker 4:  I think the fear is that if you view that as
Speaker 4:  video game preservation, it really puts a box
Speaker 4:  around the number of people that can then experience the thing
Speaker 4:  moving into the future because so many people are not gonna have that hardware,
Speaker 4:  not gonna have that setup. So by gatekeeping it and saying that's the only
Speaker 4:  way to do it, I think that will limit really You know. I think
Speaker 4:  the one thing we can be sure of in terms of artist intent about video games
Speaker 4:  from that time and even now is people who make games want
Speaker 4:  people to play them and as many people as possible to play them
Speaker 4:  because they spent all their time and energy and soul into this thing.
Speaker 4:  So if the pixels don't look quite right, even though that's not ideal,
Speaker 4:  I think they would probably still rather people are playing them than not.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I, I mean why not? Both is kind of my approach
Speaker 5:  I think of film preservation 'cause it is a really useful comparison
Speaker 5:  here. Most film preservation these days is like
Speaker 5:  eight K, 12 k even restoration of
Speaker 5:  if they can find them original elements, right? And then they go in and they
Speaker 5:  can digitize that and they can You know actually like clean up the image
Speaker 5:  and try to get the color closer to what it would've actually looked like
Speaker 5:  and use AI tools to get rid of damage to the film
Speaker 5:  and, and various things like that. I think that like for most people
Speaker 5:  that is the right answer because again, it does give you an experience
Speaker 5:  weirdly closer to what it was like to watch back in the day or
Speaker 5:  again the artist's intent. That said, there's a YouTube
Speaker 5:  channel that I follow from a person who uses AGIY
Speaker 5:  tool that captures old film trailers, like actually off
Speaker 5:  of 35 millimeter film. Oh wow. And those You know
Speaker 5:  they're not putting any extra work into the preservation. It it is
Speaker 5:  as it was after degrading for however many decades and everything else.
Speaker 5:  And for certain movies that's like a very appealing thing. I think there
Speaker 5:  are a lot of people who like Star Wars because they saw Star Wars prints
Speaker 5:  that had been screening for decades by the time it got around to them as
Speaker 5:  a kid in the eighties, right? And that's their idea of Star Wars So
Speaker 5:  I think when you can have both with games. I think that is yes, having
Speaker 5:  the original s and s experience and then having one
Speaker 5:  that works on your emulator, having a Nintendo 64 and now having one that
Speaker 5:  up Perez's to four K on your emulator. I think those are both good.
Speaker 5:  I also think that there is a middle ground in Mister and I have a feeling
Speaker 5:  that we'll talk about mister a lot more and hopefully people can explain
Speaker 5:  it way better than I can. But when you are able to kind of
Speaker 5:  recreate the original hardware in digital form,
Speaker 5:  I think that allows for what I, I suspect a lot of people will
Speaker 5:  say, which is some of these NES games in these
Speaker 5:  classic retro games, you actually, they don't really work on
Speaker 5:  modern screens. Like you, you actually need the the kind of like
Speaker 5:  jumpiness of the frames and other things to experience them
Speaker 5:  appropriately. And that is something that can be created with a tool like
Speaker 5:  Mr. But I'm excited to hear more because it, it sounds like
Speaker 5:  you've, like you've spoken to all the right people.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I think the, the place that I've landed I think is it's kind of about
Speaker 3:  how you think about the goal of preserving these games, right? Like I think
Speaker 3:  there's a divide I've come to think about where it's like, and this actually
Speaker 3:  informs a lot of what we're about to talk about, where one way of thinking
Speaker 3:  about what we do with video games is, is like as sort of historical artifacts,
Speaker 3:  right? And that's where the goal is to understand them
Speaker 3:  as they were when they were around, right? And I think like
Speaker 3:  one of the things Frank talked a lot about when he and I talked was this
Speaker 3:  idea that one of the things the video game History Foundation does is context,
Speaker 3:  right? Like they have this big idea of you can't understand a video game
Speaker 3:  without understanding the world around the video game. So not only do we
Speaker 3:  have to preserve the game as accurately as we can,
Speaker 3:  we also have to like bring in these other things around it.
Speaker 3:  Whether it's commercials or like things going on in the world or other games
Speaker 3:  that were before and after to help you understand what this game meant in
Speaker 3:  the world. So there's a version of it that I think, I think you're right
Speaker 3:  Chris, that is like, this should be as perfectly preserved as possible
Speaker 3:  for that particular use because you should understand it as a thing in space
Speaker 3:  and time there. But then the other half of it is like, what if you want people
Speaker 3:  to play these games and this, this is where I really come to kind of Russ
Speaker 3:  your way of thinking about this. Like these games can be better now
Speaker 3:  and in so many ways. Like one of the things Frank was talking
Speaker 3:  about was there was this little thing actually You know what, let me just
Speaker 3:  play it. He gave me this whole really funny speech about the NES and blinking
Speaker 3:  lights. Let me just tell you about the, the blinking lights.
Speaker 8:  I, I think preserving that experience often
Speaker 8:  requires You know, just fixing up little things. You know really,
Speaker 8:  really easy example is the, the NES, the eight bit N-E-S-I-I worked
Speaker 8:  on a few collections that that had NES games in them. And
Speaker 8:  one thing that was an absolute no-brainer for us was
Speaker 8:  the NES has a limitation on how many
Speaker 8:  sprites like moving objects can be on one
Speaker 8:  horizontal line. And if you go over I think the number eight, there's
Speaker 8:  more than eight objects on one line, they start flickering
Speaker 8:  because the NES can't render that ninth object, right?
Speaker 8:  So what it does is in hardware, it just kind of turns one off and You
Speaker 8:  know like it alternates turning them off at that point. And so a really
Speaker 8:  no-brainer thing that we do is like no one wants this is we we up
Speaker 8:  that limit to, I mean it might be infinite, I don't know, but we up the limit.
Speaker 8:  So we're we allow more than eight sprites on a scan line and all that does
Speaker 8:  is eliminate flicker. And it's like did artists
Speaker 8:  maybe sometimes intend for there to be flicker on this
Speaker 8:  part? You know theoretically, but I think for the most
Speaker 8:  part artistic intent was like, did this look good?
Speaker 8:  You know and we don't have to be slaves to this hardware anymore.
Speaker 4:  That is a great example quite honestly. Like he's right. It's so
Speaker 4:  rare to think of a scenario where an artist or a game developer wanted that
Speaker 4:  to be flickering but they just had to 'cause that was the only way to pull
Speaker 4:  off the game.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, the this idea of like artist's intent I think is always sort of tricky,
Speaker 3:  right? Because it's like how do you guess what somebody was thinking
Speaker 3:  about when they built these things versus what was just like a technical
Speaker 3:  limitation versus like art comes from constraints You know what I mean? So
Speaker 3:  I think it can get tricky. But things like that seem to me to be not all
Speaker 3:  that controversial. I suspect there are people out there who will think that
Speaker 3:  is like bastardizing what this game was. I increasingly don't buy that
Speaker 3:  argument.
Speaker 4:  I think where it gets interesting and tricky is when you
Speaker 4:  talk about where that line is, right? Because there you can certainly go
Speaker 4:  past that line and start making changes that arguably make a game
Speaker 4:  look dramatically better but are pretty far afield
Speaker 4:  from what the original source material was. An example that jumps to my mind
Speaker 4:  just recently, a collection of metal gear solid games was released
Speaker 4:  and it's every metal gear solid game, basically one through three and the
Speaker 4:  original NES metal gear solid games and the original metal gear solid came
Speaker 4:  out on the PlayStation one and in this collection the game runs
Speaker 4:  at two 40 p. And if you push out a two 40 P
Speaker 4:  image to a four K screen, holy cow, that looks like
Speaker 4:  jaggy and messy and not the prettiest look. Yep. But
Speaker 4:  emulators and, and people that work in emulators have figured
Speaker 4:  out ways to upscale an image from a two
Speaker 4:  40 P image to look actually quite clean and quite
Speaker 4:  good on a four K image. But it looks dramatically
Speaker 4:  different from what it looked like when you were playing it on a PlayStation.
Speaker 4:  And is that a bridge too far or do we just like that people
Speaker 4:  have the option to do that? That's where it gets tricky.
Speaker 3:  I tend to increasingly think that is not a bridge too far. I really like,
Speaker 3:  so this is, this is ultimately like theory number one of how to make this
Speaker 3:  stuff work is is make the games better. Make them work the way
Speaker 3:  that they would if you were building them now. Which is obviously there's
Speaker 3:  a lot of like interpretation and complicated stuff in there and I think reasonable
Speaker 3:  people can disagree on whether that's the goal. And Chris, I think that is
Speaker 3:  not exclusive of the idea of we should also preserve these things as cultural
Speaker 3:  artifacts. Right? But I think that's not gonna be a big reason
Speaker 3:  for folks to do this. Right. And I think one of the things that I've heard
Speaker 3:  a bunch in talking to people is that the problem with emulation,
Speaker 3:  and I suppose to some extent this brings me to idea number two about how
Speaker 3:  to make emulation and preservation more successful is that it's not a very
Speaker 3:  good business. One of the things people have said to me that I thought was
Speaker 3:  surprising was that if your Nintendo or Sony
Speaker 3:  or anyone else who has been like making games for a very long time, everybody
Speaker 3:  brings up Nintendo just 'cause it's sort of the best example of like they've
Speaker 3:  had a million different consoles over a million years and figuring out what
Speaker 3:  to do with those things over time. Nintendo kind of has that challenge more
Speaker 3:  neatly than anybody. So everybody talks about Nintendo when you ask about
Speaker 3:  this. They also just have the longest history of great games that people
Speaker 3:  love. But if you're a Nintendo, I always sort of thought there was just like
Speaker 3:  a database of games sitting somewhere and you just like click eight
Speaker 3:  buttons and it becomes available again. And I have been aggressively
Speaker 3:  disused of that idea that actually it is more work than people
Speaker 3:  give it credit for to make that stuff available. And if
Speaker 3:  you're a Nintendo, you can probably resell some of those games and that's
Speaker 3:  cool and exciting. But the case a couple of people made to me that I can't
Speaker 3:  stop thinking about is that if you're Nintendo or any other game maker, you
Speaker 3:  can spend your finite resources and energy bringing these old games
Speaker 3:  forward, which will sell to some people. There's a cool nostalgia factor
Speaker 3:  you can, you can help some people encounter new kinds of games
Speaker 3:  or you can spend that time and money and energy
Speaker 3:  building new stuff that is going to make you lots of money and sell more
Speaker 3:  consoles and be good for your bottom line over time. I
Speaker 5:  Would clarify a little bit on that I think. Okay. Which is,
Speaker 5:  it is very, very easy for Nintendo
Speaker 5:  or anybody else to take a bunch of ROMs, put them into an emulator
Speaker 5:  and put it on the switch. That itself is very, very easy.
Speaker 5:  What would be difficult is the paperwork.
Speaker 3:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  Which that is not for me to say that, that that is an excuse. I think
Speaker 5:  that's actually very legitimate. Especially I think a lot of people
Speaker 5:  believe that developers should be paid for their
Speaker 5:  creations. Right? And a lot of these games were made before
Speaker 5:  people could even conceptualize something like this sort of em emulation
Speaker 5:  or a game that's being widely available like this and digging up
Speaker 5:  who even owns some of these games. I mean I think I've, I'm curious if
Speaker 5:  people talk about this on in any of your interviews, but I think listeners
Speaker 5:  would be shocked how many popular games nobody
Speaker 5:  knows who owns them. Yep. Or knows where the
Speaker 5:  original code is. They have been over the years,
Speaker 5:  caught in so many various mergers or acquisitions that that
Speaker 5:  paperwork is gone. And if you've ever wondered why your favorite game is
Speaker 5:  just never made available on the Nintendo Switch, often the
Speaker 5:  answer isn't somebody's punishing you. It's that they would love to, but
Speaker 5:  like you said, it's really hard to figure out how or if
Speaker 5:  it's even possible so people just don't.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I would also add to your point about kind of triaging
Speaker 4:  where your priorities should lie. You're right. It's, it is more time
Speaker 4:  that you would spend bringing these older games that a lot of people wouldn't
Speaker 4:  play. The amount of time required is
Speaker 4:  so small compared to the amount of time required to make a brand new from
Speaker 4:  scratch game. Given the fact that at least for the first party games
Speaker 4:  that they have access to, like they don't have to worry about that paperwork,
Speaker 4:  they own all this stuff, right? Already. I mean that's really what they've
Speaker 4:  done with the Nintendo Switch online subscription model is like those are
Speaker 4:  all running through emulators that emulate an N 64 GBA or
Speaker 4:  whatever and they kind of pumped them through. And
Speaker 4:  Nintendo has some stipulations about like, we want it to
Speaker 4:  look pretty close to the original hardware, but they've also released ports
Speaker 4:  that are like pretty rough on there. Pretty not well emulated.
Speaker 4:  I think the original version of Oh, green of Time look pretty
Speaker 4:  rough on the Nintendo Switch online version. So I
Speaker 4:  think they're still doing it and I don't think it's that hard for them to
Speaker 4:  do it. And it hasn't, certainly hasn't prevented them from making new stuff
Speaker 4:  as well. And I think you're seeing a lot of companies
Speaker 4:  like Microsoft as well and, and Sony doing this with their
Speaker 4:  back catalogs because they have the access to that back catalogs and
Speaker 4:  they own the games already, so might as well, like, it just adds more value
Speaker 4:  and more incentive for people to buy the hardware.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, no, I think that's right and I think over time that's a victory, right?
Speaker 3:  Because it's like, it is a, it is a small but predictable business for those
Speaker 3:  companies and they can kind of add to it over time. But like, I mean we
Speaker 3:  talk about like the the weird incentives of like venture capital all the
Speaker 3:  time on the show, right? And one of the things that it does is say like,
Speaker 3:  old games are like a lifestyle business, right? Like it's a, it's a nice
Speaker 3:  thing, it's predictable. There are people who will like it. There is no earth
Speaker 3:  shattering gigantic business in that, right? And the, the incentives
Speaker 3:  in the other direction are like, if you can go out and stumble
Speaker 3:  into being the next Fortnite or Call of Duty or Roblox or
Speaker 3:  whatever you wanna be, that's so much sexier that I think especially
Speaker 3:  if you are in a position of having to like make hard decisions, it's just
Speaker 3:  so tempting to go that direction even though the
Speaker 3:  audience and ability to do that older stuff is there. And my hope is that
Speaker 3:  calculus like shifts more over time as, especially as a lot of these companies
Speaker 3:  try to like, make smarter decisions about how they make games because
Speaker 3:  this business has gotten so chaotic. But I don't know, a lot of the folks
Speaker 3:  I talk to are not crazy optimistic about that happening. But I I sincerely
Speaker 3:  hope it does.
Speaker 5:  I I think we're all on the same page. I, and I think the where the
Speaker 5:  sexiness of this, if there ever was or is or will
Speaker 5:  be one, is the streaming services is subscription services
Speaker 5:  because it is a number that you can add to the list of how many
Speaker 5:  games are on your platform. Yep. If you can easily go from a platform that
Speaker 5:  has a hundred games to 600 games, that is appealing
Speaker 5:  even if it is disingenuous maybe. But I agree
Speaker 5:  and I I think Sony said as much when they were asked about backwards
Speaker 5:  compatibility versus Microsoft You know. Like it does not behoove
Speaker 5:  us to spend all of our resources on a thing that we have
Speaker 5:  tried to appease fans with time and time again. And, and we do not see a
Speaker 5:  big payoff for
Speaker 3:  Chris. You just brought up the thing I am perhaps most excited to talk about
Speaker 3:  in all of this, which is what I would call Spotify for video games
Speaker 3:  before we get into the Spotify for video games thing. There is, I do wanna
Speaker 3:  go back to the thing Chris, you were saying about basically the paperwork
Speaker 3:  part of preservation and emulation video games because that is something
Speaker 3:  I heard a bunch about. One of the people I talked to for this was Chris Kohler,
Speaker 3:  who was a video game journalist for a long time now works at Digital Eclipse,
Speaker 3:  which does a lot of really interesting work about emulation and preservation
Speaker 3:  of video games. And he was saying they worked on a Teenage Mutant Ninja
Speaker 3:  Turtles thing. He basically said it's a miracle that that collection existed
Speaker 3:  because there are so many different rights for different
Speaker 3:  versions of those stories and different actors and different
Speaker 3:  characters and different platforms of different games in different countries
Speaker 3:  that he called it kind of a minor miracle when all of those things come together.
Speaker 3:  And then I asked him like, is there a version of this that is just totally
Speaker 3:  impossible? And he thought about it for while and he's like, I don't really
Speaker 3:  want to say because as soon as I say this, like it'll come together and it'll,
Speaker 3:  everything will be great. But he did say that anytime somebody comes to them
Speaker 3:  and says, can you bring back this big hit game that we loved when we were
Speaker 3:  kids? They've almost always looked into it. And it's almost always just
Speaker 3:  logistically like paperwork-wise impossible. But then he told me a story
Speaker 3:  about NBA jam that I'm just gonna play for a very quickly 'cause I thought
Speaker 3:  this was a really good example, something
Speaker 9:  Like NBA jam where NBA jam has all of these
Speaker 9:  likenesses of all of these individual basketball players and it's like
Speaker 9:  they will never, ever, ever be able to re-release
Speaker 9:  You know the first NBA jam. But does that mean that
Speaker 9:  literally like no one gets to play it
Speaker 9:  unless they go and You know buy an
Speaker 9:  aging piece of hardware and spend a bunch of money getting a, a Super
Speaker 9:  Nintendo running on a You know. It's like, does that mean literally, like
Speaker 9:  you don't ever get to experience that, that important
Speaker 9:  very important part of history. And I think that that's, that's an untenable
Speaker 9:  position.
Speaker 3:  I love this because a, I think NBA jam is like a perfect example of why this
Speaker 3:  is so impossible to do. 'cause you have to call up a bunch of NBA players
Speaker 3:  like Living and Dead and try to convince them to do this with you, but also
Speaker 3:  kind of perfectly describes this tension right between this stuff feels
Speaker 3:  intuitively like it should be available in some way. And it
Speaker 3:  is a part of history. Like NBA Jam is maybe the game I
Speaker 3:  personally have the most childhood nostalgia for. I played the shit out of
Speaker 3:  NBA jam and I loved it so much and I miss it terribly. And it,
Speaker 3:  it is sort of sad that in a very real way that game is probably never gonna
Speaker 3:  come back into my life in a meaningful way. And like I just,
Speaker 3:  I like that as a way of thinking about like why this is complicated and
Speaker 3:  for perfectly valid reasons is complicated, but it also sort of
Speaker 3:  sucks that that's the way that It works.
Speaker 4:  Okay. But it kind of then begs the question, and I don't, again,
Speaker 4:  I'm sure this is part of this episode of
Speaker 4:  obviously there are ROMs out there that you can get within 30
Speaker 4:  seconds of Googling NBA Jan Ro I'm sorry, like I, I don't
Speaker 4:  wanna like step too far a field of midway in their lawyers, but like
Speaker 4:  you
Speaker 3:  Just did the same thing that almost every single person I talked to for this
Speaker 3:  show did, which is you kind of can't have this conversation without basically
Speaker 3:  saying, yes, this is illegal, but it shouldn't be go do it. Like,
Speaker 4:  Well I'm not necessarily saying go do it, but I am saying like, I think
Speaker 4:  everyone who knows this space knows how easy it is to
Speaker 4:  do,
Speaker 5:  But there's step one and there's step two there, which is yes, there are
Speaker 5:  ROMs and that's creating more VHS tapes, right? Like that's
Speaker 5:  what we're kind of talking about there. And the problem with relying
Speaker 5:  on ROMs and relying on piracy
Speaker 5:  forget, like all the legal stuff for a moment is it's just
Speaker 5:  not organized. Yeah. So it's still so easy for things
Speaker 5:  to be lost and to slip through the cracks. It it really actually
Speaker 5:  relies on popularity and a, a collective
Speaker 5:  willingness to remember something versus something
Speaker 5:  that is more official, like a library where
Speaker 5:  whether or not it's popular is irrelevant, it existed, it will be
Speaker 5:  preserved. And then if, even if people forget about it for 30 or 40 years,
Speaker 5:  when people go back to look for it and the future and there is suddenly a
Speaker 5:  reason to care, it'll be waiting for them. It won't just be lost
Speaker 5:  because it didn't keep getting uploaded over and over again onto different,
Speaker 5:  like random rom sites that were getting whack-a-Mole by Nintendo and other
Speaker 5:  companies.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But don't you think that the You know non-centralized
Speaker 4:  distribution of this stuff ensures
Speaker 4:  its longevity rather than relying on like a singular?
Speaker 5:  Not at all. I mean, I I, I appreciate a Bitcoin mentality my friend,
Speaker 5:  but
Speaker 4:  That's not me. I'm not that guy.
Speaker 5:  I think it's idealistic in that again, it it's so informal
Speaker 5:  and it's so easy for those sites to get taken offline at any moment
Speaker 5:  here. Actually, there's a really easy way for me to point this out. When
Speaker 5:  Napster was popular, and this is when I was in high school,
Speaker 5:  there were a lot of songs that were like alternate versions of songs
Speaker 5:  or live versions of songs that I loved and some of my favorite music
Speaker 5:  and I cannot find it anymore. And a
Speaker 5:  lot of those I was like, why don't need download? It's gonna be on that.
Speaker 5:  Like it's in the air, everybody's sharing it all the time. It's just available
Speaker 5:  there forever. And now I'm sure it exists. I'm sure it's on some like
Speaker 5:  You know 40 and 50 year olds hard drives somewhere, but they're not sharing
Speaker 5:  music anymore. And then younger people don't care about those bands. So
Speaker 5:  it's just gone. And that is what I
Speaker 5:  always worry about with ROMs in the world of gaming is it, it it is
Speaker 5:  easier for it to disappear than I think we think because
Speaker 5:  generational shift is a real thing. And a lot of You know 40 and 50 year
Speaker 5:  olds right now really care about seventies and eighties game preservation.
Speaker 5:  But like who knows if that'll stay this You know true another 10 years from
Speaker 5:  now.
Speaker 3:  The question there is kind of who should be responsible for it, right? And
Speaker 3:  this is, this is where we start to get into like some of the legal stuff.
Speaker 3:  But I, I did have a couple of conversations with people who think that public
Speaker 3:  libraries are really the correct home for this as, as we
Speaker 3:  were talking about at the beginning of the show, that that is a place that
Speaker 3:  can not only sort of preserve this stuff for historical reasons
Speaker 3:  and has good useful like loopholes by which to do
Speaker 3:  so, but also can give you access to it,
Speaker 3:  right? Like we have, we have this idea of controlled digital lending, which
Speaker 3:  is very much under threat because of what like the internet archive did with
Speaker 3:  books during the pandemic. Like it's all very complicated and, and we'll
Speaker 3:  get into some of that in a minute actually. But I think this idea of who
Speaker 3:  is the right steward of that is really the question. And this is where we
Speaker 3:  get to Spotify for video games because there are a bunch of people out there
Speaker 3:  who think that maybe the way to do this is to
Speaker 3:  essentially bundle it all together. And I think you have to sort of
Speaker 3:  set aside a bunch of realities in order for that to be possible. Like
Speaker 3:  the idea that a bunch of these companies that have been making games for
Speaker 3:  40 years are suddenly gonna decide to all kind of throw in on a single service
Speaker 3:  for old video games. Probably super unrealistic. But who knows, maybe we
Speaker 3:  would've said that about the music industry 20 years ago and now here we
Speaker 3:  are, Spotify exists. Like I think the theory of it is a really
Speaker 3:  interesting one for two reasons. One, because it gives it a real chance I
Speaker 3:  think, of being an actual business in a way that I think these sort
Speaker 3:  of mini libraries and multiple different services is less compelling. Having
Speaker 3:  this like one giant place with all the old stuff
Speaker 3:  could work in a more convincing way. I talked to some people who do not agree
Speaker 3:  with that and I talked to people who do. But the other thing is I think it
Speaker 3:  would just make it easier. And I think like it's definitely true that you
Speaker 3:  can Google video game name and rom and we'll talk about the
Speaker 3:  legality of all this in a minute, but you can Google that and find it. But
Speaker 3:  the gap between that and actually playing it somewhere
Speaker 3:  is bigger and more complicated than it often is. Like one of the first people
Speaker 3:  I called for this episode was a guy named Ri Tessit who made this
Speaker 3:  emulator app called GBA four iOS a bunch of years ago. Yeah. He
Speaker 3:  exploited the like enterprise certificate thing on the iPhone so that you
Speaker 3:  could download games onto your iPhone and emulate them and play them there
Speaker 3:  doing all these really cool old video game things. And
Speaker 3:  he then made a thing called Delta, which is this very professional
Speaker 3:  kind of high touch, beautiful way of emulating old video games.
Speaker 3:  It's not a way to get ROMs, it's, it's very
Speaker 3:  like cognizant of the fact that it can't have the ROMs for you, so you have
Speaker 3:  to bring your own ROMs and it just kind of turns a blind eye to where those
Speaker 3:  ROMs come from. But it's in this place of like, he built a really
Speaker 3:  great app and went to Apple and said, I, I built
Speaker 3:  this app for emulating old video games. Can I put it on your
Speaker 3:  platform? Let me do it for you. It'll be awesome. And
Speaker 3:  let me just play you the, the way he described what happened with Apple
Speaker 10:  After GB eight five was shut down. I like tinkered away at what would become
Speaker 10:  Delta like just to entertain me and also to learn Swift. It was like a fun
Speaker 10:  thing. But then I was like, You know what? I should just reach out to Apple
Speaker 10:  and see what I could do to get it in the app store and like is
Speaker 10:  there anything, and So I talked to like the app review team at WC and they
Speaker 10:  basically told me Apple's problem is mostly that
Speaker 10:  they don't wanna allow people to install any game that they can't approve.
Speaker 10:  And I believe them, like I believe they were concerned that people could
Speaker 10:  down like go around like the age rating and stuff if they just like downloaded
Speaker 10:  old games through Delta. And I I've heard that and I'm like, You know what?
Speaker 10:  That makes sense. I understand.
Speaker 3:  So that's the first half of the story. The second half of the story is he
Speaker 3:  figures out how to make kind of an allow list for these games. He's gonna
Speaker 3:  say only these ones are allowed. Which again is a complicated legal thing
Speaker 3:  to do because if he's saying you can bring your Pokemon RO and emulate it
Speaker 3:  on this thing, you've sort of entered into a world of hurt. But then Apple
Speaker 3:  ultimately just said, nevermind, we don't want emulators on this device at
Speaker 3:  all. So he built this weird complicated thing where you essentially use your
Speaker 3:  computer as a server to run Delta on your phone and it does work.
Speaker 3:  You have to like turn on developer mode and it's really hacky and most people
Speaker 3:  just aren't gonna do that. Right. And I think we're just in a position
Speaker 3:  now where if you want easy access to these old video games,
Speaker 3:  the best move at least that I've found is to buy one of those
Speaker 3:  slightly sketchy things on Amazon that ships with like 27,000 games on it.
Speaker 3:  And some of them work and some of them kind of don't. And some of them are
Speaker 3:  definitely like porny and gross, but it just doesn't feel like we
Speaker 3:  have the good system for it that would even give it a real fighting chance
Speaker 3:  to work
Speaker 4:  The good system for like easy emulation for the masses basically.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like even, even leaving aside the legality of it, like it just doesn't
Speaker 3:  feel like there is a good tool by which I can get
Speaker 3:  access to this stuff. It's all out there if I'm willing to You know search
Speaker 3:  through Reddit and GitHub and find all this stuff. And this is also kind
Speaker 3:  of where we get to the emulation hardware and software side of things. Like
Speaker 3:  the thing that surprised me the most honestly in doing this research is how
Speaker 3:  sophisticated the emulators are for basically every console
Speaker 3:  ever. There are amazing groups of people out there working on
Speaker 3:  this stuff, mostly in an open source way, mostly just out of the goodness
Speaker 3:  of their hearts. The software behind it is incredible. It's just really
Speaker 3:  inaccessible to most people,
Speaker 4:  Which makes sense because whoever would centralize all
Speaker 4:  of this stuff would need all of the permissions that we've been talking
Speaker 4:  yet about that are next to impossible to get. So that's why we
Speaker 4:  don't have the core main person doing this. They don't want the responsibility.
Speaker 4:  Right. It's much easier to just say, okay, it's on archive or whatever.
Speaker 4:  You know you'll find it somewhere, but I don't want to be the person that's
Speaker 4:  responsible for that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I mean I, I do think that's part of the challenge is it's like building
Speaker 3:  the Spotify for video games would be 5% really interesting product
Speaker 3:  challenge and 95% just nightmare legal
Speaker 3:  paperwork scenarios. Like
Speaker 4:  I would say literally impossible from a legal standpoint.
Speaker 4:  Literally impossible to get the clearances on the entire catalog
Speaker 4:  of
Speaker 3:  Old games. I think that's probably right. But even in theory, like just play
Speaker 3:  out this flight of fancy with me for a minute. If if in theory it worked,
Speaker 3:  do you think there is a real business for the Spotify
Speaker 3:  of old video games?
Speaker 5:  Not at all. No. No. It's why it should be in libraries. Be Well again, I'm,
Speaker 5:  I'm obviously, I'm very clear with my belief here. Who gives a
Speaker 5:  shit? I mean I an adventure capital size thing, right? Like
Speaker 5:  music, people love music every, like you, you go out
Speaker 5:  to a stranger and like, have you heard The Beatles? And they're like, yeah,
Speaker 5:  I know a few of the songs. Definitely. You go out to a stranger 10 and you're
Speaker 5:  like, Hey, did you play Belmont's Quest? And they're like, can you
Speaker 5:  stop talking to me? I'm trying to buy my groceries. Like, I love this.
Speaker 5:  I am a huge advocate for it. I would love for it ex to exist, but as
Speaker 5:  we already said with Microsoft and Sony, part of it sure is the legal
Speaker 5:  part of it is the financials again of all of the legal.
Speaker 5:  And then part of it is just the hosting of it. You put up thousands and
Speaker 5:  thousands of games, most of which you're like bad. That's the
Speaker 5:  other part of this. That doesn't mean they shouldn't be preserved, but just
Speaker 5:  like early film, most of it's garbage. Yep.
Speaker 5:  And then you get into like, it, it, it is a spiral of more
Speaker 5:  questions, right? Like, okay, well we did all of that.
Speaker 5:  How do we curate it? Okay, we did all of that. But all that people are playing
Speaker 5:  is Mario and Mario Kart and the original Zelda, which have
Speaker 5:  always been, not always but are, are, are relatively readily
Speaker 5:  available. I I'm not saying let's not do it, You know,
Speaker 5:  fight a fancy money is no object. I I can't wait for
Speaker 5:  somebody to like lose money on this. But when I think of things that are
Speaker 5:  important for history, important for culture, and are going to lose
Speaker 5:  profound amounts of money, there's only one group that comes
Speaker 5:  to mind and it's the good old USA government and
Speaker 5:  they are going to do a great job doing what they've
Speaker 5:  done again with books in the same way that only now are we seeing Barnes
Speaker 5:  Noble try to figure out how the hell to make a business out of books.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I just, I don't buy that it is a business on practically any
Speaker 5:  facet unless you did very specific targeting, which is, is again what what
Speaker 5:  emulation is now, which is you can pay and get metal gear solid
Speaker 5:  collection and you can get just the game that is like very
Speaker 5:  specific and they'll charge you a ridiculous amount of money for it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Or you subscribed to Nintendo Switch online, which is the
Speaker 4:  arguably the closest comparison David, to what you're talking about.
Speaker 4:  And obviously that is the, the main selling point. Like you get a few other
Speaker 4:  perks with Nintendo Switch online, you can get cloud saves and various other
Speaker 4:  things, but what they're selling is access to this library of old Nintendo
Speaker 4:  games and it's a pretty big library. I don't have an account in front of
Speaker 4:  me, but it's a lot of games. And so they do view
Speaker 4:  that as at least some level of an incentive. I don't think it's
Speaker 4:  a genuine like big tick on their balance sheet, but it's
Speaker 4:  there.
Speaker 5:  And I'll I'll say even with Nintendo Switch online, it's telling that they
Speaker 5:  advertise that, but then they also advertise the free DLC for their major
Speaker 5:  games. They advertise the Mario Kar You know courses or whatever. It's
Speaker 5:  even, even they see Nintendo You know with the best
Speaker 5:  collection is not like, well it's, this is enough
Speaker 5:  You know, like we, we have these great old games that surely will be enough
Speaker 5:  to get people to spend it each month even. They're like, we gotta get some
Speaker 5:  new stuff on here or else we're not gonna get people.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I think I want desperately for it to be a thing. And I think the
Speaker 3:  case for it, which Chris Kohler made to me is that essentially if you can
Speaker 3:  get to a world in which everybody has a handful of games they wanna play,
Speaker 3:  right? And that handful might be totally different, but if I'm willing to
Speaker 3:  pay 10 bucks a month for access to all these games, even though I'm gonna
Speaker 3:  play 10 of them, you're gonna play a different 10, somebody else is gonna
Speaker 3:  play a different 10. That's kind of how you can build a sort of omnibus service
Speaker 3:  that works. Everybody else I talked to said seems super fun,
Speaker 3:  incredibly niche, probably not gonna be worth anyone actually investing in
Speaker 3:  So. I I tend to land on like, I wish it existed. I'd be very surprised if
Speaker 3:  anybody actually does the work to make it exist.
Speaker 5:  The other flag that I would say, even if it did exist, is does
Speaker 5:  it fundamentally devalue video games in general?
Speaker 5:  If you do that in the same way that Netflix trying to have as
Speaker 5:  much as possible on streaming has devalued
Speaker 5:  media in the same way that Spotify having music has pushed it so that musicians
Speaker 5:  have to tour to make their money and they, like, people don't expect
Speaker 5:  to make money off of the music itself. I think that's a, a pretty fair
Speaker 5:  concern that people have had about Game Pass. Is that like, are we
Speaker 5:  seeing this yet again with a devaluing of creative
Speaker 5:  work? And I, I think that's been a big part of the unions all the strikes
Speaker 5:  in Hollywood, right? Is like, if you're going to do this sort of thing,
Speaker 5:  how do you pay people? Because the audience isn't
Speaker 5:  gonna like the answer, which is we should be charging way, way, way,
Speaker 5:  way, way more stuff for, for all of this, for these services
Speaker 5:  if we want people to be paid how they were in the past. It is
Speaker 5:  tricky.
Speaker 3:  It is tricky. I, I really agree. Okay, let's switch gears. We're gonna take
Speaker 3:  one more break and then we're gonna come back and we're gonna talk about
Speaker 3:  the law. And I have learned more about copyright than I ever
Speaker 3:  intended to for the purposes of this show. We're gonna get into it right
Speaker 3:  now.
Speaker 6:  This podcast is brought to you by Meta Quest three, the new mixed reality
Speaker 6:  headset from Meta. Now you can expand your world in ways you never thought
Speaker 6:  possible with the new Meta Quest. Three, put on the sleek most powerful
Speaker 6:  quest yet and jump into fully immersive games or blend virtual elements
Speaker 6:  into your physical surroundings with mixed reality. Instantly Go from
Speaker 6:  watching to playing the part in your favorite show with Stranger Things vr,
Speaker 6:  live the action and really feel what it's like to step into the shoes of
Speaker 6:  an assassin and Assassin's Creed Nexus. Even turn your
Speaker 6:  couch into courtside seats with X Stadium and watch your favorite
Speaker 6:  NBA team. With over 500 titles, it's easy to dive into
Speaker 6:  whatever you're into, expand your world with Meta Quest three. See
Speaker 6:  child safety guidance online accounts for 10 and up certain apps, games and
Speaker 6:  experiences may be suitable for a more mature audience. Learn more@meta.com.
Speaker 3:  All, right, we're back. We've been sort of circling this the whole episode.
Speaker 3:  So let, let's just dig into this now. I called up a guy named John Loman
Speaker 3:  who works at a, a law firm. He's been in the gaming industry for a long time
Speaker 3:  now. He's a lawyer thinking about a lot of this stuff. And I basically asked
Speaker 3:  him, like, walk me through what is going on
Speaker 3:  with the, the legality of emulating and ROMs and where we
Speaker 3:  are in this space. And it turns out it's both like very simple and very
Speaker 3:  complicated kind of all at the same time. And basically the
Speaker 3:  first thing he told me was that emulators are
Speaker 3:  lawful as a, as a general rule, if you want to emulate a thing
Speaker 3:  that exists, you wanna reverse engineer something and figure out how to run
Speaker 3:  it in software that is generally considered to be lawful, that's fine. So
Speaker 3:  the actual act of emulation is okay. And he, he explained it in a way that
Speaker 3:  I really liked. Lemme just play this for you really fast.
Speaker 11:  An emulator is considered to be lawful
Speaker 11:  because it doesn't actually copy
Speaker 11:  anything. You know An emulator is software that is designed to mimic
Speaker 11:  the function of another piece of software, which doesn't necessarily require
Speaker 11:  you to copy the code or to copy any You know binary
Speaker 11:  executable component of it. You can monitor how that system
Speaker 11:  works and then you can make another system that functions the same
Speaker 11:  way. And copyright law only applies to
Speaker 11:  the expression of an idea and not to the idea itself.
Speaker 3:  So I thought that that's, it's very good and straightforward and helpful,
Speaker 3:  right? And, what he did say is, do you guys know the story of the Dolphin
Speaker 3:  emulator And? what, what has happened to Dolphin over the years?
Speaker 4:  Not recently. I am familiar with it, but I, I don't know what the backstory
Speaker 4:  is.
Speaker 3:  So Dolphin, as I understand it, and, and please everyone email Vergecast
Speaker 3:  at The Verge dot com and tell me all the reasons I'm wrong about this story.
Speaker 3:  But the way I've come to understand it is Dolphin is a, a group of people
Speaker 3:  who made a we u emulator and it was very good and very
Speaker 3:  successful. The Weu as a, a hard console to get right and emulate, but they
Speaker 3:  worked on it really hard, did a good job, and it was made available
Speaker 3:  through I think the Steam store. And Nintendo
Speaker 3:  basically went to Valve and said, take this thing out, it's breaking
Speaker 3:  the law. And, what it turned out was happening was, again, it's not
Speaker 3:  illegal to build an emulator. So the fact that it existed was okay, but what
Speaker 3:  Dolphin had done is found an encryption key, which
Speaker 3:  is what allowed Weu to connect to the games and content. They had
Speaker 3:  this key that basically was a handshake between the two things and
Speaker 3:  the copying and distribution of that key was illegal.
Speaker 3:  So if, if Dolphin had shipped the emulator and said, bring
Speaker 3:  your own key like Riley did with the ROMs, right? It's like where you get
Speaker 3:  them from is not my problem. It's readily available on the internet, but
Speaker 3:  I'm not gonna tell you how to do it. But if you bring them, we're cool. That
Speaker 3:  would've been okay. But instead Dolphin got basically booted
Speaker 3:  outta the store, not because it was illegal, but because of like the
Speaker 3:  policies of Valve and Nintendo like that just they agreed and took it down.
Speaker 3:  But it did get into this tricky legal gray area where suddenly
Speaker 3:  it's not as straightforward a thing because you are taking something that
Speaker 3:  belongs to the company and distributing it. And one of the things that
Speaker 3:  John said to me is he's, he would bet that as gaming goes forward and
Speaker 3:  as we get more consoles, they're gonna find more ways to lock those things
Speaker 3:  together, which is gonna make them even harder to emulate. Which I think
Speaker 3:  is a big bummer.
Speaker 5:  I will ease the raging nerd fire in,
Speaker 5:  in certain listeners hearts and minds. Right now The dolphin
Speaker 5:  emulates the game cube and the we,
Speaker 3:  What did I say? The we UI did say the We U Yes, you're right. Thank you.
Speaker 3:  There's
Speaker 5:  I, I believe there's a different emulator for the Weu. See Mu. But
Speaker 5:  otherwise, I agree with you. I just love that we live in a world
Speaker 5:  where I have to push my glasses up my nose
Speaker 5:  and be like, mm, that was a great point, but actually
Speaker 3:  Listen, this is what you're here for. Okay. So that's, that's the first piece
Speaker 3:  of it. And then the other thing that he said, which I thought was really
Speaker 3:  interesting is that Straightforwardly ROMs are illegal, right? Like that,
Speaker 3:  that's very simple. The act of distributing and selling ROMs
Speaker 3:  is against the law because that is just straightforward copyright infringement.
Speaker 3:  You are making a copy of things, you do not have a right to make a copy of
Speaker 3:  super straightforward where everyone seems to agree, at least in this
Speaker 3:  space. And where there seems to be real energy is that that is bad and
Speaker 3:  broken and we need to fix it. Like almost everybody I talked to
Speaker 3:  ended up on some long rant about how the copyright system in America is broken,
Speaker 3:  which listeners to The Vergecast will be very familiar with Neli doing So
Speaker 3:  Don don't need to like redo that rant. But this idea that by default
Speaker 3:  essentially a game has to exist for 90 years before
Speaker 3:  people can have it and access it and do what they want with it
Speaker 3:  outside of just hoping and begging for one of these companies to
Speaker 3:  re-release it for you. Everyone I talked to seems to think that's a very
Speaker 3:  bad idea. Even John who is a lawyer was like, this is bad
Speaker 3:  and we have to fix it. Which I thought was really fascinating.
Speaker 4:  So let me ask you, 'cause my understanding has always been
Speaker 4:  that if you own a game, like if you went
Speaker 4:  and you bought Super Mario RPG on Super Nintendo and you have the
Speaker 4:  cartridge in your home, it is not illegal to
Speaker 4:  back up the data that is on that cartridge, which in turn would
Speaker 4:  basically be a rom. So the actual doing of that, using
Speaker 4:  your own personal cartridge that you bought is legal,
Speaker 4:  but distributing it to other people is not legal. Yes. So
Speaker 4:  that's my understanding of it. That's
Speaker 3:  Correct. And one, one of the reasons that is the case is John told me about
Speaker 3:  basically the, the federal regulations that govern a lot of this stuff.
Speaker 3:  Actually, lemme just play this clip. He, he introduced this thing 37 CFR
Speaker 3:  2 0 1 and he was like, if people wanna know what's going on, they should
Speaker 3:  read federal regulations 37 CFR 2 0 1. And rather than
Speaker 3:  read that to you live on the show, let me just show you the way he explained
Speaker 3:  it.
Speaker 11:  There are exemptions for preservation of video
Speaker 11:  games, but it's a little bit more narrow because You know some of those
Speaker 11:  preservation exemptions only apply to libraries
Speaker 11:  and museums and certain types of organizations.
Speaker 11:  You know there are other exemptions that are specifically listed in there
Speaker 11:  for You know in cases where you own the software already and now
Speaker 11:  you're allowed to make copies of it for different purposes. And there's
Speaker 11:  some specificity in the code of federal regulations about that.
Speaker 11:  There's also provisions in there about games that require
Speaker 11:  some online component and there's ways that if you own the
Speaker 11:  game, that you can spoof these to play it locally.
Speaker 3:  So this is also back to the like make games better thing, I think is an
Speaker 3:  interesting way of, of think how do you keep a game playable way past
Speaker 3:  the like online infrastructure for it is gonna be a really interesting question
Speaker 3:  for the kinds of games people are playing now. But yeah, to your point, Russ,
Speaker 3:  the, the federal regulations are what really govern a lot of this stuff.
Speaker 3:  One thing that John told me is there's not a lot of case law around
Speaker 3:  things like emulation and preservation. And his theory for that was
Speaker 3:  essentially that the people doing the emulation and preservation
Speaker 3:  are so small that they literally can't afford the court fees. So the way
Speaker 3:  that it has been is you would need some big
Speaker 3:  player to have the wherewithal and resources to fight against
Speaker 3:  Nintendo or Sony or one of these companies picking this fight. But what it
Speaker 3:  has been is you have occasional times where
Speaker 3:  Nintendo will say, take this down, and they take it down because they can't
Speaker 3:  afford the fight. But mostly we've just ended in this place of like
Speaker 3:  Deante, I guess where it's Nintendo doesn't want there to be precedent
Speaker 3:  that this is a thing that is legal. So they don't really want the fight either.
Speaker 3:  They want to have this ability to sort of take down things that they want,
Speaker 3:  but also leave well enough alone. And like we've been saying, this is a niche
Speaker 3:  enough thing and it's for people who love games the most, that
Speaker 3:  it's just a weird group of people to pick this fight with, which
Speaker 3:  what John and others said is, is kind of the license for freedom
Speaker 3:  in this space. Like you can do stuff and try things and do interesting things
Speaker 3:  as long as you're not sort of flagrantly trying to become a billionaire selling
Speaker 3:  old versions of Mario on the internet, you're gonna largely get away with
Speaker 3:  it because this is just not a space that these companies want to pick fights
Speaker 3:  in. Which I thought was really interesting way of thinking about it. Like
Speaker 3:  it is you'll lose if it comes to that fight, but nobody really wants
Speaker 3:  to have it with you.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I think they know well enough that the idea of deleting
Speaker 4:  something from the internet is impossible, especially something that people
Speaker 4:  really, really want, like an old version of a game that they loved when they
Speaker 4:  were a kid. So even though you're right, they have tried and I think they've
Speaker 4:  shut down some of the more popular, let's say, rom sites, but
Speaker 4:  largely speaking, there's nothing you can permanently do to get rid of this
Speaker 4:  stuff, right.
Speaker 3:  And you just kinda look like an asshole. Like chasing people, making Brahms
Speaker 3:  of old video games they wanna play is, is a tough PR look for a lot of these
Speaker 3:  companies, which I think is how some of these things continue to survive.
Speaker 3:  The other thing John said that I thought was interesting is those federal
Speaker 3:  regulations are updated every three years and actually next
Speaker 3:  year is an update cycle. And so his,
Speaker 3:  his argument was like, if you wanna make changes to how libraries
Speaker 3:  can access and distribute video games or how these things are preserved or
Speaker 3:  what's allowed And, what isn't like don't lobby Congress, it's a waste of
Speaker 3:  time. Don't waste the company's time lobbying for that either try and get
Speaker 3:  the federal regulations changed and let's change the carve carve-outs and
Speaker 3:  let's increase the things that people are allowed to do with this stuff for
Speaker 3:  the sake of preservation and backup and keeping things that you already own
Speaker 3:  as yours that are accessible. That was his advice kind of over and over was
Speaker 3:  like, that's the move. If you wanna make change, make that change. Who
Speaker 4:  Do I email? David? Tell me who to email. It's,
Speaker 3:  It's barackObama@gmail.com. No, I don't know. It's actually, it's a good
Speaker 3:  question, but I, I should figure that out and if I find an email address,
Speaker 3:  I'll put it in the show notes for this episode. But this stuff is also
Speaker 3:  opaque that way. Right? And this, this kind of goes back to like this is
Speaker 3:  almost an official industry, but it's not quite, and
Speaker 3:  as a result it's just so complicated. And this gets back to like a lot of
Speaker 3:  the emulator software and hardware that's out there. Like we, we should just
Speaker 3:  talk about the mister for one minute before, before we get outta here. We
Speaker 3:  are in this place now where a, a device like the mister is able to
Speaker 3:  successfully emulate lots of different things at like a hardware level, right?
Speaker 3:  One of the things that it does is it's not just sort of making
Speaker 3:  software that operates on a much faster device the way that an older device
Speaker 3:  might have worked. It's actually better at like on the board running it
Speaker 3:  the way that it would've run a long time ago. And Mr is such a weird and
Speaker 3:  distributed thing that I literally wasn't able to find someone to talk to
Speaker 3:  me about it for this. I emailed a bunch of like no name email
Speaker 3:  addresses and nobody ever got back to me. I even tried Chris Grant
Speaker 3:  America's number one, Mr. Fan, nothing. Wow. Things like that
Speaker 3:  are really fascinating. But what Mr can't be is like an official product
Speaker 3:  that you buy at Best Buy because that is just going to like open it up to
Speaker 3:  complicated troubles that it doesn't need. But until you get there,
Speaker 3:  it's just too complicated, right? It's like what, what you want is like the
Speaker 3:  raspberry pie version of something like that that is like much more
Speaker 3:  accessible to regular people and the emulation community
Speaker 3:  seems to want that. And I talked to a couple of people who are like, we can
Speaker 3:  get to the point where this is easier for people to get their hands
Speaker 3:  on at a software and hardware level and install new things and find stuff,
Speaker 3:  but it's just every step of that you risk kind of
Speaker 3:  raising the ire of one of these companies that doesn't wanna fight you but
Speaker 3:  Will if it has to.
Speaker 4:  But I would counter that by saying I think there is one company, and people
Speaker 4:  will probably know this if they're in the space that has done a very good
Speaker 4:  job of getting misters out in the world and that's analog. Oh yeah.
Speaker 4:  So analog sells, You know devices that do You know they
Speaker 4:  sell the, the analog pocket, which handles basically the Game
Speaker 4:  Boy, game boy color, bunch of handheld systems. They have devices
Speaker 4:  for old consoles, NES Super Anys, et cetera. And
Speaker 4:  they have made a business out of it. It is a niche business, but they sell
Speaker 4:  those things out frequently and they have constant models coming out.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's also a bit of a, for people who have not used the analog system,
Speaker 5:  you have to have the original video game cartridges to play
Speaker 5:  games on it unless you happen to find
Speaker 5:  some additional firmware software, whatever the word is that you could put
Speaker 5:  on it, that that would allow you access to start playing the ROMs
Speaker 5:  directly through it. So I. I think that's true for yeah, sure, if you have
Speaker 5:  the VHS tapes on hand, but even analog is not
Speaker 5:  putting out an official emulation
Speaker 5:  machine.
Speaker 4:  That's true. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I do think you're right that analog is proof that from a hardware perspective
Speaker 3:  that is the kind of thing you can do really well. But even it is like, it's
Speaker 3:  very clear about the lines it can't cross. And I think until we make those
Speaker 3:  lines easier to cross, which is really complicated again because like for
Speaker 3:  the reasons we've been talking about, the people who made these things both
Speaker 3:  under the law and just in sort of like moral reality, like deserve to
Speaker 3:  be compensated for the art that they made and the idea that everything from
Speaker 3:  the You know whatever, 2006 and before should now just be freely available
Speaker 3:  to everyone is just not how It works. But it does seem like there
Speaker 3:  should be a better way of doing this. Like one of the things that John proposed
Speaker 3:  when he and I were talking was that AA reform to the copyright system that
Speaker 3:  he likes would be one where let's say 10 years after you release
Speaker 3:  something, you just have to do an incredibly basic
Speaker 3:  thing to keep your copyright. Like you, you just have to send in a
Speaker 3:  piece of paper that says, yep, I still want this and it keeps it as yours.
Speaker 3:  But what that means is for companies that go outta business or for things
Speaker 3:  that just literally nobody caress about that are, are going to otherwise
Speaker 3:  just kind of die and there are a lot of those out there, what it would do
Speaker 3:  is without that one tiny piece of effort, that stuff would
Speaker 3:  become public domain. And he's like, that's how we get to a point where things
Speaker 3:  that are no longer cared about become the property of everybody. And I think
Speaker 3:  as, as like a common sense way of thinking about it, I like that a lot.
Speaker 3:  I don't, again, that's like a giant legal minefield that I suspect will never
Speaker 3:  happen, but like spiritually that feels about right to me.
Speaker 5:  I agree with that. I think that will raise a lot of questions like what
Speaker 5:  about disputes over ownership? So who sends in that
Speaker 5:  sheet of paper, right? And what, what happens there?
Speaker 5:  But I I I agree. I also am a version of that that I think
Speaker 5:  is, I would hope much more doable again with
Speaker 5:  ROMs and libraries is like after five years or
Speaker 5:  10 years, you still have obviously the right to sell your game,
Speaker 5:  but libraries have access to make the
Speaker 5:  game available in however many copies you want for free at their
Speaker 5:  discretion. And then it's like, yes, you still own your
Speaker 5:  trademark, your copyright, whatever, like you still own the game.
Speaker 5:  But in terms of public good, we can open this up. I also, I'm, I'm a firm
Speaker 5:  believer that that should be true for not just games. I think the,
Speaker 5:  the laws in our country in terms of preserving art as
Speaker 5:  capital are deranged. But, but like that's a whole
Speaker 5:  separate podcast. I'm sure we'll do one day. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I agree with all that. And I will say there was real both enthusiasm and
Speaker 3:  optimism among the people I talked to that we can get to the point where
Speaker 3:  libraries can be that thing that we're still, we're still figuring out so
Speaker 3:  much about digital lending and how that interacts with copyright.
Speaker 3:  And I mean, we're talking about this with eBooks now, right? Like is it the
Speaker 3:  same thing? You have to buy a copy of an ebook for everyone you wanna lend
Speaker 3:  out or can the library buy the book once and then lend multiple copies? Like
Speaker 3:  we just don't have answers to this stuff, but I think we're gonna get them
Speaker 3:  one way or another and there's a chance it's really ugly and essentially
Speaker 3:  kind of kneecaps everything libraries wanna do everywhere. Because there
Speaker 3:  are some publishers out there who would like that and are very powerful,
Speaker 3:  but there's also a version of it that says like, even digital goods
Speaker 3:  can be accessible to people as a public good through libraries. And almost
Speaker 3:  everybody I talked to was like, that's an outcome we can absolutely all get
Speaker 3:  behind, which I thought was very encouraging. What do we do about the fact
Speaker 3:  that it's not gonna be a business? This is the question i I want to leave
Speaker 3:  with is like, do we have to just think about this as
Speaker 3:  artistic preservation and a thing we do because it's important and worthwhile?
Speaker 3:  Or do we need to find a way to like inject capitalism back into old games?
Speaker 3:  Like as we think about this issue over the next 10 years, do we think about
Speaker 3:  this as a public good or like a line of
Speaker 3:  business?
Speaker 5:  Absolutely. A public good. And that doesn't mean that like the really big
Speaker 5:  things can't still be a viable business that keep people aware.
Speaker 5:  For example, I oh humble brag here in a shout out.
Speaker 5:  I'm on the board of my local indie movie theater here in Orange County.
Speaker 5:  Of course you're in Santana called the Frida. People should go to it and
Speaker 5:  see great movies like Dog Day Afternoon was just there, right? And
Speaker 5:  really great old movies like that and some small ones that could get lost
Speaker 5:  screened there. And that is great and that is a great service and it is a
Speaker 5:  nonprofit even to show very famous movies like Alien,
Speaker 5:  you still are probably gonna need to be a nonprofit status just to,
Speaker 5:  to justify your business. But even we are not going to be
Speaker 5:  showing the lost movies of like 1928,
Speaker 5:  right? And as time goes on, as this becomes a more mature
Speaker 5:  medium, that's going to be more and more true for video
Speaker 5:  games. And I think yes, we, we can use
Speaker 5:  the machine of capitalism to maintain interest in older games,
Speaker 5:  but it's gonna need to be the big ones just like it is with any other form.
Speaker 5:  You know how many novels from 1944 do people read
Speaker 5:  on a regular basis, right? Like you have to find other ways of
Speaker 5:  preserving them. So, I think it, it's a bit of everything. You're gonna have
Speaker 5:  the market keeping us aware of the really important stuff.
Speaker 5:  You should ideally have libraries or nonprofits that are able
Speaker 5:  to preserve the stuff that people wouldn't care about. You
Speaker 5:  can do total remakes, like Resident Evil four remake that are
Speaker 5:  kind of doing I think something that you got, which is even if you do preserve
Speaker 5:  this, sometimes the games just aren't that fun anymore. Yeah. And you need
Speaker 5:  to kind of like upgrade it. Demon Souls on the PS five I think is another
Speaker 5:  example. I think it's a multi-pronged approach. And I, I do think
Speaker 5:  you're right that the fact that I can give all those examples is encouraging.
Speaker 5:  The one that I can't give is what do we do about all the
Speaker 5:  99% of games that are not the big stuff? And right now
Speaker 5:  the answer is pretty much exclusively piracy and ROMs and
Speaker 5:  that's just neither, it's not good for anybody. It's not good for the companies.
Speaker 5:  It's not good for preservation to not have better options. It's not good
Speaker 5:  for availability. It has people having to look at some really
Speaker 5:  nasty ads on their browsers. Yeah. Yeah. I I I think,
Speaker 5:  I think it's time for change in that department.
Speaker 3:  I agree. Russ, any thoughts before we go?
Speaker 4:  No, that's, that is a good summary. I I, I do love old games and
Speaker 4:  I love very esoteric old games as well. Stinger
Speaker 4:  is a side growing shooter where you fight a giant floating
Speaker 4:  watermelon. And if I can't play Stinger every other year
Speaker 4:  when I have the urge that is a real crime. So, I think we
Speaker 4:  need to make this a huge priority across the country and across the world.
Speaker 4:  Really
Speaker 3:  Do it for Stinger is a, is a slogan I can get behind. I like this.
Speaker 4:  Amen. All,
Speaker 3:  Right. Thank you guys as always. We're gonna be back for one more of these
Speaker 3:  next week, but this is really fun. Appreciate you guys dealing with this
Speaker 3:  with me as always.
Speaker 3:  All, right? It's been a lot today. That is it for the show. Thanks to Chris
Speaker 3:  and Russ for being here. Thanks to everyone who talks to me for this show.
Speaker 3:  And thank you as always for listening. As always, if you have thoughts,
Speaker 3:  questions, feelings, games you'd like to emulate or just more things
Speaker 3:  to say about the fact that I called the Dolphin a we you thing, you can always
Speaker 3:  email us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or call the hotline eight six six
Speaker 3:  Verge one one. Love hearing from you. Send us all your questions and thoughts.
Speaker 3:  This show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James Vergecast is Verge
Speaker 3:  production and part of the Fox Media Podcast network. We'll be back on Wednesday
Speaker 3:  to talk about Spotify, Netflix, and the hotline, and we'll be back on Friday
Speaker 3:  to talk about all the news of the week because the news just keeps coming,
Speaker 3:  my friends. We'll see you then. Rock and rolling.
Speaker 1:  Support for The Vergecast comes from Quest three, the new mixed reality headset
Speaker 1:  from Meta. The New Meta Quest three lets you expand your worlds in ways you
Speaker 1:  never thought possible. It's their most powerful quest. Yet Meta sent me
Speaker 1:  one to try and I was so amazed by how easy it was to set up with
Speaker 1:  the Quest three. You can live in the action, you can feel what it's like
Speaker 1:  to step into the shoes of an assassin and Assassin's Creed nexus. Play a
Speaker 1:  part in your favorite show, like Stranger Things, or even turn your couch
Speaker 1:  into courtside seats for your favorite MBA team. It's easy to dive into
Speaker 1:  whatever you're into, fitness, social apps, or a fully immersive gaming experience.
Speaker 1:  For over 500 titles, check out the Medi Quest three now available for
Speaker 1:  4 99. Learn more@med.com. See child safety guidance
Speaker 1:  online accounts for 10 years or older. Certain apps, games and experiences
Speaker 1:  may be suitable for a more mature audience.