# Transcript
ID: 0e30667a-89ec-432f-bd7a-17abacd3be09
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Emergency podcast: chaos at OpenAI
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6449502415614577915/-4703972831952406030/s93290-US-4289s-1700520094.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel and Alex Heath join David Pierce after a long, winding weekend reporting on the dramatic shakeup at OpenAI, still in progress.
Speaker 2:  This podcast is brought to you by Meta Quest. Three, the new mixed reality
Speaker 2:  headset from Meta. Expand your world in ways you never thought possible with
Speaker 2:  the new Meta Quest. Three. Put on the most powerful quest yet and
Speaker 2:  jump into fully immersive games like Assassin's Creed Nexus or blend
Speaker 2:  virtual elements into your surroundings in games like Stranger Things vr.
Speaker 2:  With over 500 titles, it's easy to dive into whatever you're
Speaker 2:  into. Expand your world with Meta Quest three. See child safety guidance
Speaker 2:  online accounts for 10 and up. Certain apps, games and experiences may be
Speaker 2:  suitable for a more mature audience. Learn more at Meta dot com.
Speaker 3:  Support for this show comes from Kraken. Crypto is like the financial
Speaker 3:  system, but different. It doesn't care where you come from, what you
Speaker 3:  look like, your credit score or your outrageous food delivery habits. Crypto
Speaker 3:  is financed for everyone everywhere all the time.
Speaker 3:  Kraken. See what crypto can be. Not investment advice.
Speaker 3:  Crypto trading involves risk of loss. Cryptocurrency services are provided
Speaker 3:  to us and US territory customers by pay Word Ventures incorporated. View
Speaker 3:  PBIS disclosures at kraken.com/legal/disclosures.
Speaker 4:  Hello and Welcome To, an emergency crossover episode of The Vergecast
Speaker 4:  and Decoder. I'm Eli Patel. I host both shows. I've got David Pierce
Speaker 4:  with me. Hello Alex. Heath is here. Hello. We are supposed to be
Speaker 4:  off on both shows this week, but given what happened with
Speaker 4:  OpenAI over the weekend, which is a story about org charts, in
Speaker 4:  many ways we had no choice but to do an emergency episode of our podcast,
Speaker 4:  especially because Alex and I spent our weekends on the phone
Speaker 4:  breaking a bunch of news about the discussions that led to what
Speaker 4:  at this moment is Sam Altman Microsoft
Speaker 4:  employee, which I can confidently say is an outcome no one thought would
Speaker 4:  happen in this entire saga. This is so bananas.
Speaker 4:  It is. The whole thing is in insane. I'm very much in the weeds on this whole
Speaker 4:  thing. So David, can you help us get through what happened
Speaker 4:  this weekend because it is crazy.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Okay, so we're, we're gonna do the following in
Speaker 5:  three parts because I think this is the only way to do it in a way that makes
Speaker 5:  any sense. The first thing we're gonna do is just basically
Speaker 5:  tell the story of the last 96 hours, starting from
Speaker 5:  sort of midday Friday until where we are right now.
Speaker 5:  Things are still changing. There's a non-zero chance that Real News will
Speaker 5:  break while we're recording this, but we're gonna get as close to the moment
Speaker 5:  as we can as we do this and So I, just wanna tell the story all the way through.
Speaker 5:  Then I wanna talk about the, the org charts piece that you're talking about.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna talk about OpenAI as a company and how this happened and I know
Speaker 5:  that's a thing you two have spent a lot of time trying to sort through and
Speaker 5:  others have done really good reporting on over the course of this weekend.
Speaker 5:  So we're gonna talk about that and then at the very end, I wrote this down
Speaker 5:  as just winners and losers. Totally. But I think it's useful to talk about
Speaker 5:  kind of what this landscape looks like going
Speaker 5:  forward. So all of that said, let's, let's just start at the beginning
Speaker 5:  and, and the beginning is Friday afternoon, at least as far as I can
Speaker 5:  tell out of absolutely nowhere. OpenAI publishes a blog post
Speaker 5:  saying in basically as many words, we have fired
Speaker 5:  Sam Altman as our CEO. That's where all of this begins. So the
Speaker 5:  board fires him, they kick Greg Brockman
Speaker 5:  off of the board. He then a few hours later, immediately quits.
Speaker 5:  And as far as we understand, and you, you two should correct me if I'm wrong,
Speaker 5:  because I think the like minutes leading up to this are very important. No
Speaker 5:  one, including most people at OpenAI had any idea
Speaker 5:  this was coming. Correct.
Speaker 6:  It's not only that they didn't know it was coming. They were actually on
Speaker 6:  a company holiday, so they were taking a like day of rest because of
Speaker 6:  all the craziest of the previous week where they were announcing all these
Speaker 6:  products that Sam was the face of. So not only were they weren't prepared,
Speaker 6:  but it was actually when they were all actively not looking at what
Speaker 6:  was going on at the company.
Speaker 4:  And then externally, the company was totally business as usual, right. Sam
Speaker 4:  had just been on the Hard Fork podcast.
Speaker 4:  He had taped an interview with Casey Newton and Kevin Rus an interview, which
Speaker 4:  they had to can because he got fired two days later. He had been doing other
Speaker 4:  appearances like from all external appearances. This was totally
Speaker 4:  business as usual for this company. And Sam was completely shocked when the
Speaker 4:  board called him into a Google meet, which is also very funny
Speaker 4:  and fired him. And for everything we understand about that Google Meet
Speaker 4:  is they basically read him the statement which is, you have not been consistently
Speaker 4:  candid with your communications to the board and we don't think that we can
Speaker 4:  trust you around the company. And that's all he got. That's all anyone has
Speaker 4:  gotten.
Speaker 5:  So Alex, one of the things we all immediately started
Speaker 5:  talking about was the like ruthlessness of this
Speaker 5:  statement. Yeah. Normally when, when you're getting rid of your CEO, even
Speaker 5:  if you're essentially firing your CEO, you find a way to do this sort of
Speaker 5:  slowly and nicely so that they get to like step away to spend more time with
Speaker 5:  their family or You know take some time off or whatever and everybody
Speaker 5:  pretends this is nice even when it's not. This was the
Speaker 5:  opposite of that. Like I don't, don don't know that I can remember a thing
Speaker 5:  that felt as much just like a knife of a blog post as this one.
Speaker 5:  Oh
Speaker 6:  Yeah, this is ice cold. I mean, this is saying that you are
Speaker 6:  firing someone in a fairly direct way for a situation like this.
Speaker 6:  Usually when it is a co-founder and it is someone as high
Speaker 6:  profile as Sam Altman, like Neli was saying, this will be very managed.
Speaker 6:  It will phase out. You know he'll phase out of the company.
Speaker 6:  It looks like You know he's wanting to pursue his passions, those kinds of
Speaker 6:  words. And this was like, no, we, we have knifed, Sam Altman
Speaker 6:  in the back in the night. And I mean, just like what Neli
Speaker 6:  was saying about this being business as usual, he was literally at
Speaker 6:  a conference the day before and the night before even.
Speaker 6:  And I'm told was like, I've gotta go. I've got a meeting. And I think
Speaker 6:  it was right when all this was starting. So he was literally on stage
Speaker 6:  representing OpenAI with a bunch of artists in Oakland right
Speaker 6:  before all this happened.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So all this happens. Mira Meti, the cce, the CTO
Speaker 5:  of OpenAI is promoted to interim CEO and this is where we are. So then
Speaker 5:  immediately everybody starts scrambling to figure out what the hell is going
Speaker 5:  on here basically was the vibe at the time you guys started talking to people
Speaker 5:  and this one answer about what
Speaker 5:  was going on starts to trickle out again, this all feels
Speaker 5:  like thousands of years ago now. Yeah. But my, my memory of this is like
Speaker 5:  the, the leading reason became a split
Speaker 5:  between sort of two factions at OpenAI. One that said
Speaker 5:  basically we are a research project designed to make sure that we can make
Speaker 5:  AI good for the world. And another side that said, this is a
Speaker 5:  gigantic business that we're gonna continue to run like a gigantic business.
Speaker 5:  And that starts to percolate up as like first sort of a, a
Speaker 5:  leading like educated guess. And then we got some reporting that said that
Speaker 5:  was part of the split. But how would you frame kind of what we learned in,
Speaker 5:  in the early hours of like what the actual
Speaker 5:  fight was that led to Sam being fired? Neli? What was your sense You
Speaker 4:  Know, I still think we don't know, especially because today Ilyas
Speaker 4:  Sr is saying that he regrets his actions. But the theory
Speaker 4:  on Friday night, on Friday night, the theory that started
Speaker 4:  bubbling out and the thing everyone started talking about was that the
Speaker 4:  nonprofit of OpenAI, which owns OpenAI, the commercial
Speaker 4:  entity of which Sam is the CEO and micro, The
Speaker 4:  theory on Friday night that started bubbling out is that OpenAI is
Speaker 4:  a nonprofit that's the board of directors. That nonprofit
Speaker 4:  controls a commercial entity of which Sam was the
Speaker 4:  CEO and of which Microsoft as an investor, that board
Speaker 4:  thought the commercial entity was moving too fast to commercialize
Speaker 4:  oms, right? But that they thought that the danger
Speaker 4:  of the products was too high for how fast Sam was moving.
Speaker 4:  And there was some religious split ideological
Speaker 4:  split, like that was all very hazy between the people who believed
Speaker 4:  we were on a course to destroy humanity and Sam Altman saying, we're gonna
Speaker 4:  do a store for GPTs and you can make laundry buddy that was out there. Like
Speaker 4:  that was the conversation that was happening was, is Sam moving too fast
Speaker 4:  with a dangerous technology? Did the board cannon for that? Is Ilya
Speaker 4:  a religious believer in the idea that we need to be safer? Which is what
Speaker 4:  You know OpenAI was founded to, to do this safely and make AGI
Speaker 5:  And the existence of that tension is not new by the way. Like that whether
Speaker 5:  or not that led to what has happened in the last four days. Yeah, I think
Speaker 5:  you're right. We still don't know, but the existence of that tension between
Speaker 5:  those two sides is pretty real and well established at this point.
Speaker 6:  That tension is why we have Anthropic and why Elon is
Speaker 6:  doing another AI company right now. So OpenAI has been consistently
Speaker 6:  chaotic and consistently splitting itself apart really since the beginning.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I I just don't think anyone expected it to split from the top
Speaker 6:  in such a dramatic way. And Neli, I think maybe now is where it's
Speaker 6:  probably good to explain who actually made this decision. 'cause really this
Speaker 6:  comes down to six people, right? And so we should, we should go through exactly
Speaker 6:  who the people were that made this decision because increasingly it's becoming
Speaker 6:  clear that now it's three people against the rest of OpenAI,
Speaker 6:  which is just an insane position, which
Speaker 4:  Is insane. Also, this is not a public company, so we don't have a record
Speaker 4:  of these votes. The board has not said anything.
Speaker 4:  We don't know if this was a unanimous vote. We don't know if a majority like
Speaker 4:  the reporting is that it's a majority vote. But because of what Ilia is saying
Speaker 4:  today, it is actually really unclear what happened here.
Speaker 6:  Well here's what we know. So Sam and Greg posted on X that
Speaker 6:  Ilya, who is a co-founder, the chief scientist really described
Speaker 6:  to me by many as like the brains of the operation, one of the most
Speaker 6:  influential AI researchers in the world worked at DeepMind before kind of
Speaker 6:  the AGI Doom person, I would say the most prominent one
Speaker 6:  inside the company. He was the one who told Sam and Greg that they were being
Speaker 6:  fired by the board. At that time the board was six people including
Speaker 6:  Sam and Greg. So Greg is the board chair. So the board chair
Speaker 6:  found out he got fired from his own board, which is, I don't know how that
Speaker 6:  works.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no clue
Speaker 6:  What what's clear because we know Ilya was the one who communicated
Speaker 6:  the message is that the board needed a majority. So
Speaker 6:  they needed four people. The other three members of the board
Speaker 6:  besides Ilya, are not open eye employees. Right.
Speaker 6:  So they got Ilya to side with them, kick Sam and Greg out
Speaker 6:  without any notice. And now Ilia is saying after all of this and
Speaker 6:  after pretty much all of the company is set to resign and go to Microsoft
Speaker 6:  with Sam, I actually regret this. And I also will go to Microsoft
Speaker 6:  with Sam if we don't bring them back. Okay.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna get to that like a Heath unbelievable spoiler alert on this
Speaker 5:  story. Like, come
Speaker 4:  On. Sorry. Anybody listening to this is well and spoiled. Like if you're
Speaker 4:  listening to an emergency episode of this, it's like you're in it. That's
Speaker 5:  Fair. Yeah, no, I think where all this goes is very interesting and I think
Speaker 5:  the, the Ilia piece of this is actually super interesting, but just to, just
Speaker 5:  to get back to Friday night. 'cause I think like the, the timeline here actually
Speaker 5:  matters a lot. So Friday night we start learning the reasons it happened.
Speaker 5:  I believe three high level OpenAI employees
Speaker 5:  all resign right after this all goes down with Sam and Greg Sam and Greg
Speaker 5:  as far as we can tell. And I'm curious, If, you guys have heard anything
Speaker 5:  about this immediately go to work spinning up a new
Speaker 5:  AI company? I think it, it was very obvious to everybody immediately that
Speaker 5:  they could just like have a company with an LLC
Speaker 5:  and a name and people would throw billions of dollars of investment at it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And so they started the, the things that have been reported are
Speaker 5:  that they were building or they were thinking about building an
Speaker 5:  AI chip company to rival Nvidia. There's been the thing with Sam and
Speaker 5:  Johnny, ive and Masa son working on AI hardware, Sam's
Speaker 5:  ESS investor in Humane, which is forever hilarious. Did you guys learn anything
Speaker 5:  about what the like counter idea might have been if
Speaker 5:  we landed in the world of Friday night where they just went off and started
Speaker 5:  their own company?
Speaker 4:  No. And I, I think it's actually important to, to fill that in a little
Speaker 4:  bit. I dunno if you've ever been fired You know the first thing you
Speaker 4:  do is you plot your revenge, like very emotionally plot your
Speaker 4:  revenge, right? And that is what was happening. That is what that
Speaker 4:  communication was. We'll just start a new company like it just a, like it.
Speaker 4:  These are still people. They are very human people as we
Speaker 4:  discovered throughout their actions of the weekend. They might think they're
Speaker 4:  the masters of the universe. They might be playing with $80 billion worth
Speaker 4:  of shareholder value, but they are people like
Speaker 4:  just deeply emotional, flawed people just like everybody else.
Speaker 4:  And so that first wave was very much a
Speaker 4:  revenge wave. Like they had no notice. So they had necessarily no plan.
Speaker 4:  So we'll start a new company, I can get the money, everyone will come over.
Speaker 4:  That was a burst of communication that I
Speaker 4:  think was rooted in just the emotion of the moment. Then
Speaker 4:  I think everyone got some sleep. And then we, we entered into
Speaker 4:  Saturday where Alex and I broke the news
Speaker 4:  that the investors were pressuring the OpenAI board to bring these folks
Speaker 4:  back, which bled into today. And
Speaker 4:  again, the, the the absolutely unpredictable outcome of today. But
Speaker 4:  I think the Friday night, we're just gonna go start a new company was just
Speaker 4:  the first heated emotion of that moment. And all the people around
Speaker 4:  them were very much saying, hold up. Like can we
Speaker 4:  just control z this thing and fix it? Like
Speaker 4:  I heard like my interest is just fixing it. You know like very directly from
Speaker 4:  some people. Like, I'm just trying to fix it. This is ridiculous. This should
Speaker 4:  have never happened.
Speaker 5:  So, I, I believe that, but also Alex tell me If, you agree with me
Speaker 5:  on this or not, I would assume that every venture capitalist on earth
Speaker 5:  with Sam Altman's phone number called him on Friday night and said, tell
Speaker 5:  me how to give you money for your next thing.
Speaker 6:  For sure. So I mean is, is your point that like they should have just
Speaker 6:  left and not tried to?
Speaker 4:  No,
Speaker 5:  I just, I think Neli I think you're right, but I also think the,
Speaker 5:  the sort of parallel universe in which they went to start that company is
Speaker 5:  not that far off. Right?
Speaker 4:  I'm not saying, I'm not saying it was impossible. Right? It was, it was a
Speaker 4:  very easily accomplished thing. I think you're correct. The the money was
Speaker 4:  flowing, the the support was public, right? You saw
Speaker 4:  Vinod ksa who runs KSA Ventures just publicly tweeting how much he supported
Speaker 4:  San like the money was available from all of his existing investors, probably
Speaker 4:  from Microsoft, right? But the thing that I, I'm just trying to
Speaker 4:  underline here is that first wave on Friday night of, we'll start our own
Speaker 4:  thing was reflexive. It was not considered and
Speaker 4:  I, there there's a big gap between we'll support you in
Speaker 4:  whatever your next thing is and writing a check against a business plan.
Speaker 4:  And that gap was as far as we can tell that no one ever thought about
Speaker 4:  crossing that chasm.
Speaker 5:  Okay, that's fair. All. right? And so let's get to Saturday because that's
Speaker 5:  when stuff gets even weirder somehow. But first we're gonna take a quick
Speaker 5:  break. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  This podcast is brought to you by Meta Quest three, the new mixed reality
Speaker 2:  headset from Meta. Now you can expand your world in ways you never thought
Speaker 2:  possible with the new Meta Quest three, put on the sleek most
Speaker 2:  powerful quest yet and jump into fully immersive games or blend virtual
Speaker 2:  elements into your physical surroundings with mixed reality instantly
Speaker 2:  Go from watching to playing the part in your favorite show with Stranger
Speaker 2:  Things vr, live the action and really feel what it's like to step into the
Speaker 2:  shoes of an assassin in Assassin's Creed Nexus. Even turn
Speaker 2:  your couch into courtside seats with X Stadium and watch your favorite
Speaker 2:  NBA team. With over 500 titles, it's easy to dive into
Speaker 2:  whatever you're into, expand your world with Meta Quest three. See
Speaker 2:  child safety guidance online accounts for 10 and up certain apps, games and
Speaker 2:  experiences may be suitable for a more mature audience. Learn more at Meta
Speaker 2:  dot com.
Speaker 3:  Support for this show comes from Kraken. Crypto is like the financial
Speaker 3:  system but different. It doesn't care where you come from,
Speaker 3:  what you look like, your credit score or your outrageous food delivery
Speaker 3:  habits. Crypto is finance for everyone everywhere
Speaker 3:  all the time. Kraken gives you the tools to access this new world of
Speaker 3:  finance. Whether you're a pro or just starting out. Kraken
Speaker 3:  is the simple powerful way to buy, sell and learn about crypto.
Speaker 3:  Their intuitive trading tools grow with you, empowering you to make your
Speaker 3:  first or your 100th trade. In just a few
Speaker 3:  clicks and If you get stuck. Their award-winning client support team
Speaker 3:  is available 24 7 along with a bunch of educational
Speaker 3:  resources to help you on your way. Kraken, see what crypto can be,
Speaker 3:  not investment advice. Crypto trading involves risk of loss. Cryptocurrency
Speaker 3:  services are provided to us and US territory customers by pay Word Ventures
Speaker 3:  incorporated view PVI disclosures at
Speaker 3:  kraken.com/legal/disclosures.
Speaker 5:  All right? We're back. So we've had the breakup, we've had the feelings,
Speaker 5:  everybody's putting up angsty away messages and, and then Saturday morning
Speaker 5:  in the Bay area somewhere I don Reconciliation
Speaker 5:  begins. Neil, take me through like the beginning of the story on Saturday.
Speaker 4:  So what we had heard is the investors and opening
Speaker 4:  I, which is mostly the commercial entity, they're putting a lot of pressure
Speaker 4:  on, Hey, we need to at least know what happened. We need to know your reasoning
Speaker 4:  and we need to see if we can resolve this. This situation that led
Speaker 4:  to what I am guessing is yet more Google Meet calls. And I just wanna keep
Speaker 4:  highlighting this because I think we are all imagining some like
Speaker 4:  very tense in-person meetings and really everyone
Speaker 4:  was kind of just on the phone.
Speaker 5:  I mean, we're all imagining the board room from succession, right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like that's what's in everybody's mind as we go through this. Like a bunch
Speaker 5:  of people sitting around a table raising their hands, like with great intentions.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 4:  I'm saying I don't even know if their cameras were on. Like, this is a lot
Speaker 4:  of people who are like alone or like in small groups of, of, of people
Speaker 4:  in various places
Speaker 6:  Also. Well just very important note, $10 billion from
Speaker 6:  Microsoft's can still not make you use teams.
Speaker 4:  It's the most important. So we start hearing, there's all this pressure
Speaker 4:  and Alex actually hears, hey, they might bring him back. So
Speaker 4:  Alex and I just start calling everyone and we broke this, we beat, I don't
Speaker 4:  remember who we beat, but we beat someone by six minutes to this story that
Speaker 4:  open as board is in negotiations to bring Altman back.
Speaker 4:  And the most important piece of that story is he was
Speaker 4:  ambivalent about it. That was reporting that we had. And his
Speaker 4:  condition was, I'm not gonna go work for these people again. They just fired
Speaker 4:  me for no reason. They all have to go.
Speaker 6:  Which is understandable.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like just an incredible condition to impose, right?
Speaker 4:  So e even from that moment, like we get this reporting, we break the story,
Speaker 4:  we're like high fiving, I'm thinking, and Alex is thinking, okay,
Speaker 4:  to make this happen, four people have to
Speaker 4:  publicly admit they made a mistake and resign in disgrace. Yeah. This is
Speaker 4:  a, a high mountain, who knows what will happen next. And then
Speaker 4:  we spent the rest of the weekend on the phone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Alex, what was your sense of whether that those were
Speaker 5:  kind of real requests, whether that was, again, Sam saying,
Speaker 5:  I'd like to come back, here's my rational list of what it will take. Or Sam
Speaker 5:  being like, fuck me, fuck you.
Speaker 6:  I think it was pretty clear that Sam had the upper hand as of like
Speaker 6:  Saturday midday and then You know we had reported that they had a
Speaker 6:  5:00 PM deadline to reach a deal with the board.
Speaker 6:  And the thing that was going to happen at that point was if it wasn't
Speaker 6:  reached, Sam's camp was telling the board, there's gonna be mass
Speaker 6:  resignations, You know the entire company is behind us.
Speaker 5:  Is that why you think he had the upper hand? Like just because it was so
Speaker 5:  clear so quickly that OpenAI as a company was behind him. I,
Speaker 6:  I think what everyone underestimated is the resolve of what ultimately
Speaker 6:  was three people to not have him come back. But at the, and
Speaker 6:  the thing is like the board has been radio silent, You know, aside from that
Speaker 6:  initial statement and an internal email that reiterated the statement to
Speaker 6:  employees Sunday night, no one from the board has said anything publicly.
Speaker 6:  Not, they haven't elaborated on anything. So that's important. But it seemed
Speaker 6:  like Sam was getting the upper hand, the 5:00 PM deadline passes
Speaker 6:  on Saturday. I'm at a party and Neli is like, we're,
Speaker 6:  I'm like stepping aside and Eli's calling me and we're like, what is happening?
Speaker 6:  Does this mean mass resignations? And then we look on x and I I
Speaker 6:  want to note it is deeply ironic that all of this has been playing out on
Speaker 6:  X because it's all training data for grok.
Speaker 6:  It's all training data for Elon's OpenAI competitor. And
Speaker 4:  This is all just a plan to poison grok. You're like Right grok, how do I
Speaker 4:  replace the ceo? And it's like, here's some ideas, right?
Speaker 6:  And, and it's also, there's a lot of deeper irony there with Elon we can
Speaker 6:  get into at some point. But we saw this very public
Speaker 6:  display of support for Sam Saturday night with
Speaker 6:  pretty much everyone at OpenAI You know quote tweeting him with the heart
Speaker 6:  emoji, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So Sam tweets something like, I love the OpenAI team
Speaker 5:  and as if they had You know coordinated this in like a high
Speaker 5:  school cafeteria, they all quote tweeted it with
Speaker 6:  Hearts. They all quote exactly major high school calf vibes.
Speaker 6:  And then we're all thinking like, okay, this maybe
Speaker 6:  means he won. Like we're all, we're like Neli and I are scratching
Speaker 6:  our heads. And then You know you wake up the next day and you realize that
Speaker 6:  was a pressure campaign to show that Sam actually did have the backing of
Speaker 6:  the whole company.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And so we had heard, we, we had reported this
Speaker 4:  5:00 PM deadline, 5:00 PM Pacific. So
Speaker 4:  that deadline just comes and goes and we are scrambling texting
Speaker 4:  everyone in the universe like, what is happening? This was a deadline, right?
Speaker 4:  Everyone's supposed to quit. So they start tweeting the hearts and
Speaker 4:  it was actually very unclear whether this was, we're all quitting
Speaker 4:  right now, or Sam has won. And the
Speaker 4:  online reaction was like instantly polarized, right?
Speaker 4:  Binary action. Like people are like Sam's one, it's done. And our instinct
Speaker 4:  was we would know, right? Like this is cryptic, we're
Speaker 4:  doing high school away messages on X,
Speaker 4:  it's, it's absolutely not done. But we still don't know. And there was
Speaker 4:  no further conversation after that. Like
Speaker 4:  I was basically told go to bed by a source, like you're done for the day.
Speaker 4:  Like we did this thing, we, it's the show of force. Like everyone has to
Speaker 4:  go to sleep now. We'll try again tomorrow. So that was the end of that day.
Speaker 4:  I will say that my favorite conspiracy theory about this is that a misaligned
Speaker 4:  AI was instructed to get people to watch the Las Vegas F one Grand
Speaker 4:  Prix, which started at 1:00 AM Eastern. And I was like, this almost worked,
Speaker 4:  like I almost watched this but I went to bed anyway. But then we woke up
Speaker 4:  the next morning and we were, it was basically the status quo, like this
Speaker 4:  pressure campaign had not moved anything. And we were told Kara Swisher
Speaker 4:  has reported this, we were told that there was a noon Pacific deadline, which
Speaker 4:  they blew right by. And then we reported again there was another
Speaker 4:  5:00 PM deadline. So my response to that was, is this real? Like you can
Speaker 4:  only issue so many 5:00 PM ultimatums in your life, especially in
Speaker 4:  sequential days. And I was told, yes, this is a hard deadline. It's real
Speaker 4:  today. Like either this happens at 5:00 PM today or we go in another path.
Speaker 4:  And I thought, oh man, how do I report this? And that is when Sam
Speaker 4:  tweeted a picture of himself in the OpenAI offices holding
Speaker 4:  a guest badge with the caption first and last time I ever wear
Speaker 4:  this badge, which is right, that's the ultimatum. Like either this is getting
Speaker 4:  fixed or I'm never coming back here again. And so that was when I felt
Speaker 4:  comfortable saying, okay, it's like we're doing the 5:00 PM thing again,
Speaker 4:  but we've, I've got the guy like issuing the ultimatum,
Speaker 4:  like this makes sense to me.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So then they then spent the whole day at OpenAI headquarters
Speaker 5:  hashing this out, basically having what I would assume is just the same fight
Speaker 5:  over and over and over again. Sam trying to get the board to resign in disgrace
Speaker 5:  and the board not wanting to resign in disgrace.
Speaker 4:  There were some internal discussion there about picking
Speaker 4:  the successors for the board and the, the feeling, and
Speaker 4:  we, we don't have this on the site, but, so this is a little shakier, but
Speaker 4:  the feeling was they, people were suggesting candidates. We heard
Speaker 4:  a lot of what I would call like Web 1.0 names
Speaker 4:  Cheryl Sandberg was in the mix. Like, okay, right. Marissa Meyers
Speaker 4:  in the mix, like all these like old heads who are from that era, You know
Speaker 4:  the adults, like, we're gonna hire adult supervision for Google. Like
Speaker 4:  I was like, when is Eric Schmidt gonna show up? Right? Like this is, these
Speaker 4:  are the kinds of people we're talking about.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean If, you saw a very public web 1.0 tech
Speaker 6:  executive like tweeting support of Sam over the weekend. They were most likely
Speaker 6:  trying to get on the board.
Speaker 5:  Dick Costolo just appears out of nowhere
Speaker 4:  At one point. Alex is like, these people are just like in the firmament.
Speaker 4:  They're available to show up and like run your company for a couple years.
Speaker 6:  Like Brett Taylor, we should know. I mean Brett Taylor would like the guy
Speaker 6:  who literally just negotiated the sale of Twitter to Elon in the
Speaker 6:  second most dramatic boardroom tech situation of the last decade.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Nuts.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like it is just like, I keep calling 'em capital a adults, although
Speaker 4:  no one here was acting like an adult, but like they You know they have that
Speaker 4:  rep, like here's the cast of characters. And we had heard that such an
Speaker 4:  nadela was mediating this conversation. Right. And his
Speaker 4:  point of view was he's pretty neutral. He just wants this over with, he needs,
Speaker 4:  he needs a story to tell Microsoft shareholders on Monday morning. And that
Speaker 4:  is Microsoft's interest is stability for shareholders. 'cause they have this
Speaker 4:  massive dependency in OpenAI. And
Speaker 5:  That was one of the other things we should have said on Friday is that this
Speaker 5:  all happened while the markets were still open on Friday and Microsoft's
Speaker 5:  stock like tanked. Yeah. As a result of this happening. Like this was the,
Speaker 5:  the biggest public blowback on this was gonna come back to Microsoft in
Speaker 5:  a pretty real way. So it makes sense that Nadella was going to be directly
Speaker 5:  involved in doing this.
Speaker 4:  And th and this ticking clock for Microsoft, I think it is
Speaker 4:  underappreciated, but it was very real that Microsoft
Speaker 4:  needed a crisp thing to say on Monday morning. One way or another.
Speaker 4:  So I always had it in the back of my head. Like at some point this has
Speaker 4:  to hit some kind of resolution because
Speaker 4:  Microsoft will not demand it, but will just create a
Speaker 4:  resolution to say to its shareholders so that there's all this like vetting
Speaker 4:  of these like old heads, the the OGs come to town, right?
Speaker 4:  So the vibe I'm getting, and again, we don't actually know if everyone was
Speaker 4:  all together. We know there was a lot of opening high people at that headquarters.
Speaker 4:  We don't if the board was there actually. But the vibe we're getting
Speaker 4:  is people are firing names at this board and the
Speaker 4:  board is not taking it seriously. And in the meantime they are running their
Speaker 4:  own search for a new CEO because their interim
Speaker 4:  CEO Mira Mirati has sided with Sam in the meantime, like
Speaker 4:  publicly during the hearts campaign on Twitter, she's posting the heart,
Speaker 4:  right? So she's
Speaker 5:  What a sentence she's
Speaker 4:  Gone over. I mean it is just absolutely childish when I say these are very
Speaker 4:  flawed human people. Like we're gonna win this fight by posting hearts on
Speaker 4:  Twitter is I don Dunno what to say about it one day I will like
Speaker 4:  have had enough time to process that situation. But Mira has gone over to
Speaker 4:  Team Sam like very publicly. So the board needs a new CEO so that
Speaker 4:  they're getting tossed these names and everyone is hoping that they will
Speaker 4:  accept some names and resign and the new names will take over. And in the
Speaker 4:  meantime they are looking for a new CEO and that is more or less what is
Speaker 4:  happening all day Sunday as the 5:00 PM deadline draws
Speaker 4:  ever near.
Speaker 5:  So we hit that deadline. And again, nothing Alex, what would you have,
Speaker 5:  where was your head at sort of the end of Sunday? Like obviously things
Speaker 5:  get crazy several hours after that deadline, but like where were we at the
Speaker 5:  end of that day on Sunday, do you think?
Speaker 6:  I was feeling like if we didn't have an announcement by
Speaker 6:  five, it wasn't gonna work out. And we were kind of getting back channel
Speaker 6:  that by midday Sunday things were taking a
Speaker 6:  turn and I, I didn't, obviously no one could
Speaker 6:  have expected what actually happened. This is the most, like I was saying
Speaker 6:  at the top bananas thing. But yeah, I think people were
Speaker 6:  generally, people who were close to the story were thinking like, okay, he
Speaker 6:  made it very clear publicly, this is the last time he's setting foot in the
Speaker 6:  building. The deadline has passed and it's not looking good.
Speaker 5:  And and there's a version of that that would've been a very dramatic weekend
Speaker 5:  that ended in a relatively okay thing, right? Sam and Greg
Speaker 5:  go off to do something. They bring some OpenAI people with them. OpenAI hires
Speaker 5:  a new CEO, everybody moves on with their lives like that. There's a
Speaker 5:  version of this where like a lot of people had a lot of feelings, but it
Speaker 5:  turns into a relatively normal corporate change.
Speaker 5:  Right? But that is obviously not what happened,
Speaker 4:  Right? The negotiation to bring Sam Altman back has failed. Mira Mirati continues
Speaker 4:  is interim CEO Microsoft wishes Sam the best and says they'll support
Speaker 4:  him in the new venture. Right? Again, the the thing that needed
Speaker 4:  to happen by Monday morning was a Microsoft statement to the market and
Speaker 4:  you really just cannot underestimate how much pressure that was
Speaker 4:  applying to the situation. Like yeah. So I'm expecting that
Speaker 4:  statement, right? Like here's the forcing function. We just have to be
Speaker 4:  ready for this deal is gonna fall apart. Microsoft is
Speaker 4:  gonna issue some holding statement and say, You know we have a
Speaker 4:  deal with OpenAI, everything's fine, our contracts are rock solid.
Speaker 4:  Brad Smith or Chief Legal Officers, a great lawyer, like whatever Microsoft
Speaker 4:  is gonna say to, to calm everybody down. But instead,
Speaker 4:  and all credits to Bloomberg. Bloomberg has a report I don know 10
Speaker 4:  minutes before the thing actually happens that Mira
Speaker 4:  Murti has hashed a plan as interim CEO to just
Speaker 4:  rehire Sam and Greg as employees while
Speaker 4:  the board is out calling people to interview them
Speaker 4:  to be the CEO to replace Mira. And so what comes out in
Speaker 4:  the end, I'll just like fast forward a little bit, is Mira's plan was to
Speaker 4:  quickly hire Sam and Greg as employees, again
Speaker 4:  forcing the board to fire all three of them, which would've
Speaker 4:  led to presumably lawsuit. Like who knows what was gonna happen in that moment.
Speaker 4:  But that was the last swing of chaos when it was,
Speaker 4:  I think obvious, oh this just fell apart. Like it, we're not
Speaker 4:  in a place where we're negotiating four people resigning. We're in a place
Speaker 4:  where we're actively trying to create legal
Speaker 4:  leverage for a lawsuit to come. And the board is actively trying to
Speaker 4:  replace the person that they just hired to replace the CEO. They fired.
Speaker 6:  Sorry. It's just, it's I know it's just like this whole thing
Speaker 6:  has been such a blur for Neli and I like when you say all this out loud,
Speaker 6:  it's just truly, it's insane.
Speaker 5:  And it does seem like, I think your, your instinct there is right Neli that
Speaker 5:  it's at that point what you're saying is, I'm not gonna quit. You have to
Speaker 5:  fire me. Yep. Like I'm, I'm going to cause so much trouble for you that you're
Speaker 5:  gonna have to get rid of me and then I'm gonna have ammo kind of in whatever
Speaker 5:  direction I want to use it. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Exactly. Right. And the rehiring of Sam and Greg is like a deeply
Speaker 4:  funny idea. Like you have to fire them again.
Speaker 4:  It's just
Speaker 5:  Like a, just like hire them as interns and watch them get fired. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  all
Speaker 4:  Three of them will then sue the board. And this is when
Speaker 4:  Alex and I just started sending out hundreds of text messages. This is about
Speaker 4:  to fall apart, like this is absolutely about to fall apart. And
Speaker 4:  it, it fell apart and it fell apart in the weirdest way possible. Which is
Speaker 4:  the board just, I didn't even announce
Speaker 6:  Like
Speaker 4:  The information broke. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  This is just like coming from sources. Like the board has been in a bunker
Speaker 6:  somewhere. They don't have a crisis comms team, they don't have like people
Speaker 6:  speaking to the media. They, they've just been radio silent. But it starts
Speaker 6:  to trickle out that they've actually named a new CEO
Speaker 6:  and it's Emmett Shear
Speaker 5:  Not on my bingo card for who was gonna be the next CEO of OpenAI.
Speaker 6:  Not on anyone's bingo card. I think it's very safe to call this one
Speaker 6:  out of left field. Emmett was the co-founder of Twitch, which is a
Speaker 6:  live streaming video site, not an AI company. He's not
Speaker 6:  seen as a AI leader. He posted
Speaker 6:  shortly after it leaks that he was being named CEO, that
Speaker 6:  he got the call for the job that day and took a few hours
Speaker 6:  to decide. And You know he's a free agent. He left Twitch
Speaker 6:  earlier this year before mass layoffs. They've had two rounds of layoffs
Speaker 6:  since I can confidently say that the vibe within Amazon
Speaker 6:  is that Twitch has been a, hmm, how
Speaker 6:  should I put this shit show since Amazon bought it? And
Speaker 6:  so no one really thought of Emmett except the board.
Speaker 6:  Apparently he is now the CEO and he sent this note internally to
Speaker 6:  employees saying that he was going to conduct an independent review
Speaker 6:  of the board's actions, which is hilarious because he was hired
Speaker 6:  by the board. I don't think that's possible to have
Speaker 6:  an independent review when you are the person you're
Speaker 6:  represented by the people that you're reviewing. I mean, it just doesn't
Speaker 6:  make sense. And
Speaker 4:  Also those people can callously fire you whenever they want. Yes. Which they've
Speaker 4:  proven twice in 48 hours that they can do.
Speaker 6:  Okay. And we've been dancing around this this whole time. I really think
Speaker 6:  at this point we should just say who these people are because at the end
Speaker 6:  of the day, three people set all this in motion. Three people have caused
Speaker 6:  OpenAI to explode from within. So should we just get into that? Yeah, do
Speaker 6:  it. Yeah. Okay. So OpenAI is very strange in
Speaker 6:  how it's structured. And this is something that people haven't really been
Speaker 6:  paying attention to because we've been so focused on just the, the success
Speaker 6:  of their products with ChatGPT. But OpenAI
Speaker 6:  started as a nonprofit and so it has this weird structure where there's a
Speaker 6:  nonprofit there, there's a flow chart which is like perfect for decoder.
Speaker 6:  There's a flow chart on open AI's website and it, i I
Speaker 6:  challenge you to look at this flow chart and try to make sense of it. It
Speaker 6:  is one of the most confusing, I just
Speaker 4:  Want to be very clear. You can definitely make sense of it and they've drawn
Speaker 4:  it to be more confusing than it actually is.
Speaker 6:  Okay, well we're we're
Speaker 4:  A hundred percent
Speaker 6:  True. We're gonna redraw the flow chart now. Yeah. 'cause it's all different.
Speaker 6:  But, so there's this nonprofit with this board that
Speaker 6:  controls it and importantly the board of OpenAI does not
Speaker 6:  have equity in OpenAI, which is a really wild thing.
Speaker 6:  And so that's the context of the board. There's three of them really that
Speaker 6:  aren't OpenAI people. So one of them is Adam DeAngelo, who is the
Speaker 6:  CEO of Cora. He operates, I should note a competing AI
Speaker 6:  chatbot platform called Poe. He was the original CTO of Facebook.
Speaker 6:  He's a, he's a known quantity in Silicon Valley. He's, he's a really well
Speaker 6:  connected guy. There's a woman named Helen Toner who has ties
Speaker 6:  to the effective altruism movement. She used to work at Open Philanthropy,
Speaker 6:  she's now at Georgetown. She funds AI safety stuff. She was actually
Speaker 6:  on our stage at code in September with Casey Newton talking about
Speaker 6:  AI safety. And then the other one is a woman named Tasha
Speaker 6:  McCauley, who is the former CEO of Geo sim systems. And as far as I can tell,
Speaker 6:  basically no one in tech that I know knows who she is. Okay. So that's
Speaker 6:  the three people. And they are the ones who basically
Speaker 6:  decide to bring Emmett in because as we find out in the next
Speaker 6:  turn of the story, the guy that we thought was the, the
Speaker 6:  architect, the, this mastermind of all of this flipped,
Speaker 6:  which we can get into. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So Emmett's a weird choice. Emmett's a weird choice and also
Speaker 4:  openly a deceleration is, which is a, a phrase that the
Speaker 4:  AI community loves to use. Like there's videos of him being like, this is
Speaker 4:  terrifying. We should slow it down. This will extinguish all
Speaker 4:  value in the cone of light, which is a real thing. He says, wow, it's amazing.
Speaker 4:  Like, and his his point of view is we should slow
Speaker 4:  AI innovation way down before so he can get a handle on how dangerous it's
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So you can see where the board is, right? This is a split that we've
Speaker 4:  been hearing about the entire time. OpenAI is playing with dangerous toys
Speaker 4:  and Sam is running too fast. So we've brought an Emmett Shear
Speaker 4:  to slow this whole thing way down.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think that's right. And then on the flip side, very early this
Speaker 5:  morning, Neli, I think to your point correctly to
Speaker 5:  get something out before the stock markets opened, Microsoft announces
Speaker 5:  it has hired Sam Altman and Craig Brockman to run, I
Speaker 5:  believe the phrase is an AI research
Speaker 4:  Lab, an advanced AI research team is their statement. And can I just read
Speaker 4:  this statement from Saachi Nadella?
Speaker 5:  Please do.
Speaker 4:  Which just contains magnitudes. We remain committed
Speaker 4:  to our partnership with OpenAI, have confidence in our product roadmap, our
Speaker 4:  ability to continue to innovate with everything we've announced at Microsoft
Speaker 4:  Ignite and in continuous support our customers and partners. We look forward
Speaker 4:  to getting to know Emmett Sheer and o's new
Speaker 4:  leadership team and working with them. And we are extremely
Speaker 4:  excited to share the news at Sam Altman and Greg Rockman. Together with
Speaker 4:  colleagues, we'll be joining Microsoft to lead a new advanced AI research
Speaker 4:  team. We look forward to moving quickly to provide them with the resources
Speaker 4:  needed for their success in the journalism business. We call that bearing
Speaker 4:  the lead.
Speaker 4:  And importantly Sam Altman is being given the title of CEO at
Speaker 4:  Microsoft, which is inside Microsoft's corporate
Speaker 4:  politics like a big deal. Right? There are not a lot of CEOs at Microsoft.
Speaker 4:  Usually when they acquire a big company, they give those people the
Speaker 4:  CEO title. So the person who leads LinkedIn as ACEO title, the
Speaker 4:  person who leads GitHub has ACEO title. Phil Spencer is now the
Speaker 4:  CEO of Microsoft gaming. And that's a big deal. You can go listen to that
Speaker 4:  decoder episode where I ask him what that that title shift means. And it
Speaker 4:  basically means he has his own resources, right? He's split off from
Speaker 4:  Microsoft, your own p and l. Well you can go listen to that
Speaker 4:  episode. It basically means you have your own resources and you are more
Speaker 4:  of a free agent to run your little division like
Speaker 4:  it's own little company. So this is the arrangement Sam is getting. What
Speaker 4:  I will tell you is I read this statement especially that we look forward
Speaker 4:  to getting to know Emmett here. They don't know, they don't know these people.
Speaker 4:  They don't know what's gonna happen with OpenAI. They don't know if Emmett's
Speaker 4:  gonna turn the pace of innovation way down. But they are able to tell the
Speaker 4:  market, hey the, the face of the AI winning that
Speaker 4:  we've been doing as Microsoft now works at Microsoft. Does Sam Altman
Speaker 4:  have a contract to work in Microsoft yet? Like, I don't know the answer to
Speaker 4:  that question. Does Sam Altman, the guy who used to run Y
Speaker 4:  Combinator, who has his hands and every startup in the universe has
Speaker 4:  multiple investment funds, is thinks of himself as the guy who was running
Speaker 4:  the hottest AI startup in the world on its way to making AGI
Speaker 4:  Does he want to be a Microsoft employee? I like, I truly do
Speaker 4:  not know the answer to that question. I do know that this statement utterly
Speaker 4:  worked to not only calm the market but to send Microsoft
Speaker 4:  stocks skyrocketing. And we are now sitting here saying, do
Speaker 4:  we need to pre-write Microsoft is now a $3 trillion company.
Speaker 4:  'cause the, the stock as we are speaking is like to the moon.
Speaker 4:  So this statement worked. I'm just cautioning everyone. This
Speaker 4:  in my view is a holding state. It's still a holding statement.
Speaker 6:  Well I think knowing what we know about Sunday, knowing that Microsoft
Speaker 6:  really wanted to have this buttoned up by markets open, this was
Speaker 6:  decided like, it was like almost like 1:00 AM Pacific. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I was asleep like straight up. I was like, I'm done now I'm
Speaker 6:  Thinking that like okay the surely nothing more is to come and then at like
Speaker 6:  around one Nadella t us and luckily Tom Warren is waking up in London and
Speaker 6:  and gets it on the site. It's nuts. But, but I think there's an important
Speaker 6:  thing here, which is we know that Microsoft wanted to get this done.
Speaker 6:  I have to imagine that whatever got Sam and Greg to agree to go to
Speaker 6:  Microsoft was a lot. I imagine they had all the leverage in that
Speaker 6:  situation because they'll, they'll just go do their own thing, right? Like
Speaker 6:  we've all been saying Microsoft cannot make it look like the,
Speaker 6:  the company that they have literally bet their AI Azure future
Speaker 6:  on is imploding before their very eyes. Yeah. And So
Speaker 6:  I have to imagine this is gonna go down as one of the best packages
Speaker 6:  ever from a big tech company to, to a team to come there because
Speaker 6:  they had all the leverage that night.
Speaker 5:  I agree. So this just real quick, this brings us to winners and losers.
Speaker 4:  Wait, we're not done with the story yet.
Speaker 5:  We're not, there's one more turn, but we're gonna get to that. But first
Speaker 5:  we're gonna take a break. We'll be right back.
Speaker 8:  This episode is brought to you by Shopify. That's the sound of
Speaker 8:  switching your business to Shopify. The global commerce platform that
Speaker 8:  supercharges your selling harness. The best converting checkout and same
Speaker 8:  intuitive features, trusted apps and powerful analytics used
Speaker 8:  by the world's leading brands. Stop leaving sales on the table.
Speaker 8:  Discover why millions trust Shopify to build, grow and run their
Speaker 8:  business. Sign up today for your $1 per month trial period at
Speaker 8:  shopify.com/tech 23.
Speaker 7:  The Pitch season 10 is here. Who's ready to tee it high
Speaker 7:  and let it fly? Oh,
Speaker 7:  I've heard a lot of pitches over the years. The founders on this
Speaker 7:  season take it to a whole nother level.
Speaker 9:  If someone like me, an engineer having managed a division at Apple with 37
Speaker 9:  patents, if I don't even have smart home tech
Speaker 7:  Who does and a whole new continent,
Speaker 10:  I wanna introduce you to an industry that's currently experiencing two
Speaker 10:  x yearly growth that you are not invested in in Africa.
Speaker 7:  But this is a tech podcast. Of course we have your college
Speaker 7:  dropout.
Speaker 11:  When I was a freshman at USC, I actually sold my first software business
Speaker 11:  for 300 k. I also just love capitalism and
Speaker 7:  Listen now to season 10 of the Pitch to hear world-class founders
Speaker 7:  Pitch investors for money on the spot. Start your binge
Speaker 7:  with episode one 15, the crown jewel of venture. The Pitch
Speaker 7:  is available wherever you listen to podcasts.
Speaker 5:  All, right? We're back and we are back with the last and current turn
Speaker 5:  of the story, which is a letter. So much of this all is just happening.
Speaker 5:  People writing texts to each other. It makes me very happy. Neli,
Speaker 5:  since you're our quote reader for the day, do you want, do you wanna read
Speaker 5:  part of this letter? Yeah. It's truly spectacular from a bunch of
Speaker 5:  OpenAI employees. They, they, they wrote an open letter to the board.
Speaker 4:  Keep in mind this all starts with You know a 5:00 PM
Speaker 4:  deadline, which is there's gonna be mass resignations unless Sam comes back,
Speaker 4:  right? They've blown the deadline twice and Sam has now announced to go to
Speaker 4:  Microsoft. The markets think Microsoft has conducted
Speaker 4:  a, the greatest act will hire in tech history with no
Speaker 4:  regulatory oversight. Like I have a version of that idea from
Speaker 4:  like 5,000 people in my text message in Box. Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  Satchel is a genius. Okay. What no one is counting on is like, oh people
Speaker 4:  still wanna do the plan, right? Like If you say you either
Speaker 4:  hire Sam or we all resign. A lot of people are gonna try
Speaker 4:  to resign when you don't hire Sam back. So 500
Speaker 4:  plus employees out of it's what it 700 employees? Yeah,
Speaker 4:  it's, I mean by the time this episode comes out it will, it will have been
Speaker 4:  the whole company. The letter says we, the undersigned may choose to resign
Speaker 4:  from OpenAI and join the newly announced Microsoft subsidiary run by Sam
Speaker 4:  Altman and Greg Brockman. Microsoft has assured us that there are positions
Speaker 4:  for all open eye employees at this new subsidiary. Should we choose to join,
Speaker 4:  we will take this step imminently unless all current board
Speaker 4:  members resign and the board appoints two new lead independent
Speaker 4:  directors such as Brett Taylor and Will heard and reinstate Sam Altman and
Speaker 4:  Greg Brockman. Importantly Ilya has signed
Speaker 4:  this letter and he has tweeted, I deeply regret my participation in the
Speaker 4:  board's actions. I never intended to harm OpenAI. I love everything we've
Speaker 4:  built together and I'll do everything I can to reunite the company. Mira
Speaker 4:  has signed this letter and Sam has now quote tweeted Ilya with three heart
Speaker 4:  emojis. Which I just saying this I want to point out we are
Speaker 4:  talking about 10 to $80 billion in
Speaker 4:  shareholder value is happening with heart emojis on Twitter. It's,
Speaker 4:  it's the most emo thing. I've listened to letter to Elise like 10 times this
Speaker 4:  weekend because, because when I was in college, I would just use the lyrics
Speaker 4:  to letter to Elise by the cures my aim away message. That's
Speaker 4:  where we are emotionally with this situation. This means
Speaker 4:  the board might succumb to this pressure campaign because they're gonna lose
Speaker 4:  their entire company. All these employees are tweeting, opening eyes, nothing
Speaker 4:  without its people. The board might succumb, they might reinstate Sam. This
Speaker 4:  whole Sam is now the CEO of a Microsoft research team might not come to
Speaker 4:  pass. I truly do not know what happens next. And that's what I mean by
Speaker 4:  Microsoft needed some clarity and they got it today in
Speaker 4:  a move which maybe seems like Nadella is a genius
Speaker 4:  but also may have just created enough stability for the next chapter
Speaker 4:  to play
Speaker 5:  Out. So Alex, there are two things in here that jump out to me that I'm really
Speaker 5:  curious about. One this means Microsoft has made very clear, very loudly
Speaker 5:  that anyone who wants to leave OpenAI can go work for Microsoft. Which is
Speaker 5:  a pretty ruthless thing to do to a company that you've been saying we You
Speaker 5:  know are committed to our partnership and look forward to getting to know
Speaker 5:  the leader new leadership team. And the other thing is, this is the final
Speaker 5:  form of the kind of the board against the world thing. This is not
Speaker 5:  quote tweets and heart emojis. This is literally the vast majority of the
Speaker 5:  company saying in no uncertain terms, we will leave unless you do this.
Speaker 5:  I'm always of the mind that it's one thing to make big noises about quitting
Speaker 5:  your job. It's another thing entirely to quit your job. This does
Speaker 5:  feel like the board is going to have to call a lot of
Speaker 5:  bluffs and in a way that it's probably gonna lose at this moment in time.
Speaker 5:  Right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean what I was hearing over the weekend is that Ilya is really
Speaker 6:  the wild card here. He has a lot of respect internally. He's a co-founder.
Speaker 6:  He runs the research teams. The fact that he flipped and
Speaker 6:  is now saying, I'm also gonna go to Microsoft means there really is
Speaker 6:  no OpenAI anymore because that was always the key
Speaker 6:  man is like if Ilya's still there, there's still a chance that You
Speaker 6:  know they're not gonna be this like breakneck commercial entity that they
Speaker 6:  have been under Altman, but they at least will do leading research because
Speaker 6:  the research community respects him. If he is go, it is literally Adam
Speaker 6:  DeAngelo, Tasha McCauley and Helen Toner. Those people are gonna be
Speaker 6:  all that's left of OpenAI.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, he was kind of the truest believer, right? Like If, you wanted to pick
Speaker 5:  somebody who was like the most held onto the original vision of
Speaker 5:  OpenAI. You'd probably pick Ilia, right?
Speaker 6:  So The Atlantic has this incredible in-depth story about
Speaker 6:  OpenAI that everyone who's listening to this should go read. And there is
Speaker 6:  a scene where they had a leadership offsite, I
Speaker 6:  think it was last year. And Ilya has a wooden effigy that
Speaker 6:  he literally sets on fire at the meeting to represent non-aligned
Speaker 6:  AGI, which is You know. This is like the idea that You know they're
Speaker 6:  creating AGI in an unsafe way. I mean it's kind of a
Speaker 6:  religious thing in more ways than I think people get in the AI community.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, that's, that's I think for you If, you wanna understand kind of
Speaker 6:  the cultural divide, which is maybe where we go next here. But like the culture
Speaker 6:  divide within OpenAI has become somewhat religious in the last year or so
Speaker 6:  as the company's become commercialized.
Speaker 4:  I told Alex that a real headline we should write after this is, the rich
Speaker 4:  people are crazy
Speaker 6:  Because
Speaker 4:  This is religious fervor. Now these are people who believe that
Speaker 4:  they are going to create the power to destroy the universe. And that is
Speaker 4:  how they talk about it. It's not like a imposition of
Speaker 4:  class warfare on billionaires. It's no, you should listen to the billionaires
Speaker 4:  talk and you should listen to what they call effective acceleration
Speaker 4:  and deceleration. And there's a schism there that is
Speaker 4:  beyond cultural, right? It is reached a level of
Speaker 4:  religious fervor that is making them act irrationally. And that
Speaker 4:  might be appropriate. Like If, you thought that the
Speaker 4:  thing you were building could destroy the world. You should
Speaker 4:  probably reach into some like principles that
Speaker 4:  are not just made up, which is like how you find religion it.
Speaker 4:  But that's like, there's no moderating force on that,
Speaker 4:  right? There's no like centuries of church
Speaker 4:  dogma or liturgy like whatever. There's some forum posts about
Speaker 4:  effective accelerationism that they're all reading that they've just made
Speaker 4:  up. And like that's weird. And it's, it's worth some scrutiny
Speaker 4:  outside of the sort of boardroom org chart battles that You know.
Speaker 4:  That's where I like to focus my attention. But there's something here that
Speaker 4:  is making these people act irrationally and with not just
Speaker 4:  like religious fervor, but with like martyrdom fervor.
Speaker 4:  Like they will kill the company because they believe this is so right.
Speaker 6:  Right. And what's great about this story is that this tension is actually
Speaker 6:  personified in the org chart. So going back to how ridiculous it
Speaker 6:  is that o the way that OpenAI is structured, they have this nonprofit board
Speaker 6:  that controls the company effectively. They can fire people, et cetera.
Speaker 6:  They get to decide when the company has reached AGI, which is a very
Speaker 6:  important power to place in a company that's whole
Speaker 6:  mission is around creating AGI. And so you have that one side of the
Speaker 6:  equation and on the other side you have the for-profit entity
Speaker 6:  that OpenAI created under Sam Altman to raise all of the money from
Speaker 6:  Microsoft, hire all of the top talent from all of the big tech companies
Speaker 6:  that they have in the last year to build wildly successful commercial
Speaker 6:  products. And Sam, Altman is on stage at dev day. I was there a
Speaker 6:  couple weeks ago saying, we are gonna be the app store for ai. We are gonna
Speaker 6:  start sharing our revenue with you. We are gonna give more of our
Speaker 6:  technology to our developers. We are gonna be a platform. So
Speaker 6:  inherent in the structure is this tension where the
Speaker 6:  commercial entity is charging ahead with something that the board is
Speaker 6:  tasked with protecting and act ultimately deciding
Speaker 6:  and incentives drive behavior here. And so it's just really interesting
Speaker 6:  to look at like maybe this was always going to happen. You know the,
Speaker 6:  the favorite theory I've heard over the weekend was like, this is actually
Speaker 6:  Elon Musk's poison chalice because he named OpenAI.
Speaker 6:  He really set it up, gave it its first donation,
Speaker 6:  set up the nonprofit structure and maybe this was
Speaker 6:  always gonna happen. Well,
Speaker 5:  And then importantly stopped giving that money when he stopped
Speaker 5:  being part of the company was a big part of like phos reporting from a while
Speaker 5:  ago, right? That was part of when OpenAI realized we need a lot more money
Speaker 5:  to do the kinds of things we're doing. They went to Microsoft to get both
Speaker 5:  the capital and the compute to do it. And all of a sudden you're just kind
Speaker 5:  of off to the races and as soon as you decide you want the money,
Speaker 5:  it becomes very hard to not want the money anymore. That's one of the things
Speaker 5:  we've seen over and over And like this idea that you can have a nonprofit
Speaker 5:  overseeing a for-profit company is not unheard of in tech. It's fairly
Speaker 5:  unusual, but like Mozilla is a version of this kind of org
Speaker 5:  chart. Signal is a version of this kind of org chart like it's possible to
Speaker 5:  do, but it comes with a really complicated set
Speaker 5:  of trade-offs in every case. Like Mozilla's thing and, and Neli. I know you
Speaker 5:  and I have both talked to Mitchell Baker, the CEO, EO of Mozilla about this.
Speaker 5:  Mozilla's for-profit company gets most of its money from Google. Yep. Which
Speaker 5:  to Mozilla the nonprofit that wants to make the internet better feels really
Speaker 5:  bad. But without that money you can't do the work anymore.
Speaker 5:  And so this, this tension is never going to stop going away or
Speaker 5:  this tension is never going to go away. And so you
Speaker 5:  eventually need somebody in charge who is either so Mission-driven that
Speaker 5:  they stay that way no matter what. Or you get into the Sam Altman thing
Speaker 5:  where you eventually start chasing the money and then the money gets big
Speaker 5:  and then that's what you become.
Speaker 4:  So I, I, I said this earlier and I'm not gonna try to describe an
Speaker 4:  org chart on a radio show, but it is very true that
Speaker 4:  the flow chart that OpenAI has published about its ownership structure
Speaker 4:  is like consciously more complicated than it needs to be.
Speaker 4:  There's only three boxes on this structure. Most of the extra boxes
Speaker 4:  are just labeling who owns what. So there's OpenAI,
Speaker 4:  the public charity, a 5 0 1 C three that owns a holding company,
Speaker 4:  which co-owns OpenAI, the commercial entity with Microsoft.
Speaker 4:  That's it. That's a whole structure of this thing. There's a, there's a charity
Speaker 4:  that owns a holding company so that employees can have some equity in the,
Speaker 4:  on the holding company. And then there's the commercial thing that goes off
Speaker 4:  and does all the work. That structure exists all over the place. It does
Speaker 4:  not exist in Silicon Valley. So outside of Mozilla and these other things
Speaker 4:  that are run is You know, there's sort of like not capitalistic in their
Speaker 4:  way, right? In Silicon Valley, everything is like a Delaware organized C
Speaker 4:  corp with VCs on the board and now all over the place
Speaker 4:  super voting shares for founders. Like there's a way to do it. And they do
Speaker 4:  that because this stuff happens when you don't
Speaker 4:  like, like that's why they do it, right? Like founder drama with their
Speaker 4:  VCs. Like the story of Uber exists, right? The story of Apple
Speaker 4:  exists, like do You know every single year Meta shareholders vote to remove
Speaker 4:  Mark Zuckerberg? Yeah. Yeah. And he just out votes them because he has super
Speaker 4:  voting shares. Like it just doesn't matter that the shareholders of Meta
Speaker 4:  are like, get this guy outta here year after year because he has super voting
Speaker 4:  shares, right? So you get a structure like this and these shenanigans become
Speaker 4:  possible. But then you look around the world and you see functional
Speaker 4:  structures like this at very big companies, at very important
Speaker 4:  companies. Someone pointed out to me that Bosch, which is a huge
Speaker 4:  German engineering firm, very successful in the car world, in the engineering
Speaker 4:  world, is organized basically like this. There are companies that are owned
Speaker 4:  by the towns they're in in Europe, like all these other structures exist
Speaker 4:  and this org chart, people look at it and you look at it and you're like,
Speaker 4:  this is crazy If. you just spend a few seconds looking at what
Speaker 4:  these boxes mean. And I don't know why some
Speaker 4:  of them are ovals and some of them are squares, like it's just three boxes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, right. At the end of the day, there's OpenAI, the charity that owns
Speaker 4:  a holding company that owns OpenAI Global, which is the commercial entity,
Speaker 4:  and Microsoft is a big investor in that entity. And that means Microsoft
Speaker 4:  does not have a lot of control over this board, which I think has become
Speaker 4:  a real problem for Microsoft at this point in time. Yep. It means that Sam
Speaker 4:  Altman did not have super voting shares to stop it, but it also very
Speaker 4:  importantly means that the board was too small
Speaker 4:  and too inexperienced, made a hasty decision and there was no
Speaker 4:  governance check on their behavior. And I think that is like
Speaker 4:  the fundamental mistake of the structure, not the structure itself.
Speaker 6:  Or we find out that I, I and don don't think this is the case, but I just
Speaker 6:  wanna play devil's advocate or we find out that like OpenAI invented
Speaker 6:  God in the last two weeks. There's this, there's this clip of Sam Altman
Speaker 6:  at a conference in San Francisco the day before he was fired, saying that
Speaker 6:  like there's been a few moments in his career where they've gotten to push
Speaker 6:  back the veil of ignorance and like he was talking as if like
Speaker 6:  You know they had made fire and he said one of these moments happened in
Speaker 6:  the last couple of weeks. So everyone is reposting that clip saying,
Speaker 6:  w what if they realized they had AGI or what if they realized the
Speaker 6:  model was about to just accelerate in a way that no one could have predicted?
Speaker 6:  I will say that Ilya has been doing a press tour and
Speaker 6:  being pretty open that the model capability is going to
Speaker 6:  progress a lot faster than everyone thinks. So there
Speaker 6:  has been You know a lot of theory to that, but
Speaker 6:  what it looks like right now is, is inexperience and the board not realizing
Speaker 6:  what was gonna happen when they made such a rash decision.
Speaker 4:  And I just wanna put this out there. The other thing I've heard is
Speaker 4:  it's not that Microsoft and the commercial entity of OpenAI and Sam
Speaker 4:  didn't think safety was a problem, right? Like Kevin Scott, the head of AI
Speaker 4:  at Microsoft was on stage with me at code and we talked about AI safety
Speaker 4:  and the limits and like how careful they should be. This is a thing that
Speaker 4:  Microsoft is publicly talking about. So if Open AI's board
Speaker 4:  is saying, okay, we're we're going too far ahead, their entire
Speaker 4:  job is communicating that there's a misalignment, their
Speaker 4:  entire job is saying to Sam, Hey, you're over the line,
Speaker 4:  like, pull it back or we're gonna fire you. Instead they just fired
Speaker 4:  him. Instead they just went ahead. They gave Microsoft one minute
Speaker 4:  notice that they're gonna fire Sam. And so like the fundamental job of
Speaker 4:  this board is to communicate and set limits and they just
Speaker 4:  didn't do
Speaker 5:  It. Yeah. Well, so, and, and this is another good moment to put a button
Speaker 5:  on what you said earlier, Neli, which is that we actually don't know the
Speaker 5:  whole story behind why he was fired in the first place. And Emmett Shearer
Speaker 5:  in his weird long tweet announcing that he's CEO at the
Speaker 5:  very end says PPS, before I took the job, I checked on the reasoning behind
Speaker 5:  the change. The board did not remove Sam over any specific disagreement
Speaker 5:  on safety. Their reasoning was completely different from that. I'm not crazy
Speaker 5:  enough to take this job without board support for commercializing our awesome
Speaker 5:  models. So before that I'm like, okay, OpenAI wants to go back to being essentially
Speaker 5:  a research organization. Fine. Like whatever you wanna say about that
Speaker 5:  decision, that is at least a decision now. It's like, okay, well then what
Speaker 5:  are we, what are we doing here? Like what, what fight are we having here?
Speaker 5:  It, it's, I'm sure there are people who know, but that part does not seem
Speaker 5:  to have come out in any way that I find at all sort of satisfying.
Speaker 6:  What I think we will find out is that this is a classic
Speaker 6:  business dispute. I mean, yes, there are obvious concerns
Speaker 6:  on different sides of the debate here about AI safety,
Speaker 6:  and I do think that played a role, but what we just saw was
Speaker 6:  a couple of weeks ago, OpenAI hastily, and I can say this confidently because
Speaker 6:  I was part of the, the press scrum and getting pre briefed and all this about
Speaker 6:  the, the app store stuff. Like very hastily OpenAI
Speaker 6:  announced a major business expansion that Sam Altman led,
Speaker 6:  right? They had this huge conference and were like, we are pushing ahead.
Speaker 6:  We're gonna be a new platform. And if I had to guess,
Speaker 6:  that probably led to a lot of this because Sam was
Speaker 6:  clearly caught by surprise. There was nothing You know it. Normally
Speaker 6:  if this had been like a long gesticulating thing over months, it would've
Speaker 6:  leaked in dribs and drabs and it really just came like a thief
Speaker 6:  in the night. And so there was a breaking point here very recently, and the
Speaker 6:  thing I can point to is Sam getting on stage
Speaker 6:  and saying, guess what? We've been going a hundred miles an hour. We're gonna
Speaker 6:  go 200 miles an hour and we're gonna become an even bigger business.
Speaker 5:  And what seems clear now is that a bunch of people at Microsoft, including
Speaker 5:  Satya Nadella, saw that and said, hell yeah. And at least one
Speaker 5:  person inside of OpenAI said, hell no. Yeah. I
Speaker 6:  Mean this is like essentially this is ca capitalism versus
Speaker 6:  hippies. I mean that's what the story is.
Speaker 5:  It's the story of Silicon Valley, man. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I think that's too reductive. I I, again, I, the religious aspect of this
Speaker 4:  is just not to be underestimated. Microsoft sees this and says, yeah, go
Speaker 4:  even faster because every one of these queries runs on an Azure server.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Right,
Speaker 4:  Right. Like that that's great for them. They're, they're, they're ready to
Speaker 4:  go. The OpenAI board sees this and says, okay, you're gonna give
Speaker 4:  people the ability to make computers go take actions in the real
Speaker 4:  world without any oversight and let them build whatever
Speaker 4:  AI tools on our model that they want and resell them
Speaker 4:  and create a commercial incentive to do that without any safety checks whatsoever.
Speaker 4:  And that is opposed to our mission. That is like real, that is a moral dilemma.
Speaker 6:  Do you remember, I mean we were just talking about this on The Vergecast,
Speaker 6:  we were talking about how this store and these a this agent, API
Speaker 6:  thing is gonna open them up to a world of hurt. I mean they literally had
Speaker 6:  to say on stage, we will indemnify you for any copyright violation
Speaker 6:  that may occur from creating bots on our platform. It was very,
Speaker 6:  and like I went to AQ and a with Sam after they announced this at dev day
Speaker 6:  and it was clear that they had not thought through the details, right? Like
Speaker 6:  they, they hadn't decided on how much revenue they were gonna share with
Speaker 6:  creators, how the store incentives were gonna be aligned.
Speaker 6:  It was all just being done kind of on the fly and we were all going like,
Speaker 6:  this sounds like a disaster. Like it's a smart business play. If,
Speaker 6:  you are Sam Altman the venture capitalist, right? It's like, yes, this is
Speaker 6:  what you want to go do You wanna build a moat around You know the fastest
Speaker 6:  growing consumer product of all time, you wanna be a platform, but it was
Speaker 6:  clear that they were moving a million miles a minute. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  Also the problems are not hard to imagine.
Speaker 4:  Okay, you creator sets up AGPT bot that just
Speaker 4:  spams people in their email with marketing messages. Does
Speaker 4:  OpenAI want to be sharing revenue with that creator? Is that a thing you
Speaker 4:  want to incentivize? You can make it even worse. It it's connected to Dolly,
Speaker 4:  right? Okay. You want to make deep fake nudes of people
Speaker 4:  and that's an app you wanna sell in the GPT store. Does OpenAI
Speaker 4:  have the content moderation ability to stop it at scale
Speaker 4:  when millions of people realize this is a thing they should try to sell?
Speaker 6:  Like the most wild thing I heard at Dev day was that OpenAI uses
Speaker 6:  GPT to moderate GPT. Yeah. It uses the
Speaker 6:  AI to moderate the ai and that's how they were, that sounds about it. And
Speaker 6:  that's how, and that's how they were gonna approach the store. Yeah. I mean
Speaker 6:  it's it's truly bananas.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So I. Think there, there's a lot still to sort out here, right? I
Speaker 5:  think including the question of like, does Sam Altman actually ever
Speaker 5:  work for Microsoft? And I think we're gonna talk about this a lot for a long
Speaker 5:  time, I suspect. But just to, let's just put a button on this
Speaker 5:  moment for now because if we stay on here too long, more news will break
Speaker 5:  and this will all be outta date. So we need to like put this thing on the
Speaker 5:  internet. Just five minutes. I wanna do real quick who won and who lost
Speaker 5:  over the last four days? And then we're gonna get outta here. I'm just gonna
Speaker 5:  throw some names at you and you guys are gonna tell me winners and losers
Speaker 5:  sound good.
Speaker 4:  I mean it sounds like an impossible exercise that
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be great. I'm excited about it. Here we go. Person number one,
Speaker 5:  Satya Nadella. I feel like big winner of the weekend, right?
Speaker 6:  He might be the only winner.
Speaker 4:  Okay, everyone thinks he looks very clever today. I do not know
Speaker 4:  long-term, if having your stock price swing
Speaker 4:  this much on the actions of one or two people is a good thing
Speaker 4:  for Sasha Nadella
Speaker 5:  Fair. Okay. Person number two, Sam Altman. I genuinely can't decide.
Speaker 4:  Loser. Huge, huge loser. Really? Yeah, without question.
Speaker 5:  Huge loser.
Speaker 4:  He was the guy and now he, he might still be, he might start
Speaker 4:  a new company, he might go work for Microsoft, he might take everyone with
Speaker 4:  him, but losing the thing you founded is
Speaker 4:  the worst. And it might be that he returns to
Speaker 4:  OpenAI in 12 years like Steve Jobs, but in the meantime, right, the most
Speaker 4:  likely outcome is he owns next.
Speaker 5:  Is this his Elon Musk style joker origin story? Like is that
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I, I don't, I there's no, I, I come back to the very beginning.
Speaker 4:  It's great to think that all these people are, are cogs in a machine and
Speaker 4:  it's a narrative that's playing out and it's a like You know people write
Speaker 4:  about it that way. Sometimes we write about that way. These are people You
Speaker 4:  know and like whatever he does next is gonna be deeply colored by just the
Speaker 4:  emotional damage of this weekend in the sense that he can't
Speaker 4:  trust the people he thought he could trust. And maybe that's just the reality
Speaker 4:  of being the guy who ran Y Combinator for a long time. Maybe he was already
Speaker 4:  like that You know he's been in the scene for a long time. He knows a lot
Speaker 4:  of people. But to go from the top of the world to Microsoft employee
Speaker 4:  in 48 hours, no matter what happens next, he's not the
Speaker 4:  winner today.
Speaker 6:  I think he is more a winner than Eli, but I don't think he's a full
Speaker 6:  winner. I mean I think like Sam, like I was saying, looks like he
Speaker 6:  had all the leverage with Microsoft. Microsoft needed a way to
Speaker 6:  message that this was under control. I imagine he extracted
Speaker 6:  some insane deal terms out of Nadella late last Sunday night.
Speaker 6:  And if he does get the entire OpenAI team to come to Microsoft and he gets
Speaker 6:  to run it like his own little fiefdom, like LinkedIn has its own email, right?
Speaker 6:  Like it's its own building it's own. Do
Speaker 4:  You think he gets to use Google Meet
Speaker 6:  That's, well maybe the You know that may have been the biggest concession
Speaker 6:  of all was that Nadella agreed that they don't have to use teams internally.
Speaker 6:  We'll find that out. I'm sure Tom is on that. But I mean, I'm thinking to
Speaker 6:  why they created the commercial entity. It was because they needed funding
Speaker 6:  for compute to train their models and Microsoft showed up with a
Speaker 6:  bag mostly of cloud credits. Interestingly saying we will
Speaker 6:  give you all the compute you need. Microsoft has gone on, what I've seen
Speaker 6:  some analysts saying is the most expensive
Speaker 6:  infra private company infra build out of all time with its
Speaker 6:  AI data centers something like 50 plus billion dollars in the last
Speaker 6:  few years. So if Sam Sam gets the insulation
Speaker 6:  of being an independent company within a mega
Speaker 6:  cap company and all of the resources that he was desperately trying to raise
Speaker 6:  money for for the last few years anyway and all the people from
Speaker 6:  the company, I mean it seems like he wins. I mean You know,
Speaker 6:  like I don't, like he seems like a winner to me. Certainly this is
Speaker 6:  like for his like yeah, trusting people, not great, but
Speaker 6:  I think he's more a winner than Eli
Speaker 5:  All, right? I, I have a bunch more, but I actually think, I think you're
Speaker 5:  right. Most of 'em are pretty easy. OpenAI obvious loser, Google Win
Speaker 5:  or Loser,
Speaker 4:  Google is the most vindicated of any company right now, right? They, they
Speaker 4:  got so much heat for being slow and not rushing the stuff to market
Speaker 4:  and now they're vindicated because OpenAI
Speaker 4:  itself just tore itself apart over the idea of going a little bit slower.
Speaker 4:  And Microsoft, which is recall Nadella on decoder,
Speaker 4:  I wanna make Google dance, I want them to know that it was me who made them
Speaker 4:  dance. Incredible quote is now having to
Speaker 4:  start a new division, set it up given research funding while
Speaker 4:  navigating meeting Emmett Shear, which is literally in the
Speaker 4:  statement they have to meet this guy. Like I, if you're Google, you're like,
Speaker 4:  wow, we were right to go slowly and carefully and our moment
Speaker 4:  will come to us. Also, we have better distribution for our AI search
Speaker 4:  product than anybody in history. Like maybe we'll just continue to steamroll
Speaker 4:  the industry. I dunno if that's gonna happen. I dunno if Google can actually
Speaker 4:  execute all the many, many questions, but If, you are Sundar Phai today.
Speaker 4:  You're like, phew, missed that one. You know, like you're just fine.
Speaker 5:  I think that's right. I think that it, this is the most like
Speaker 5:  aggressive wrench of instability into its biggest competitor that
Speaker 5:  Google could have possibly hoped for. Bard still sucks though. So there's
Speaker 5:  that Anthropic Alex, you brought this up earlier. I is the team at
Speaker 5:  Anthropic just like giggling and high fiving right now? I
Speaker 6:  Mean, yeah, anthropic was created for a similar reason.
Speaker 6:  don don't know if there was a coup that was failed and that's why philanthropic
Speaker 6:  got formed. But they all worked at OpenAI. They had, they were the kind of
Speaker 6:  more deceleration is effective altruism, You know movement. They
Speaker 6:  broke off as a separate faction, created another AI lab and You know they
Speaker 6:  haven't had the commercial success of OpenAI. I think it's worth noting that
Speaker 6:  the only AI startup that has been You know
Speaker 6:  successful commercially is OpenAI. Like there's Claw, there's
Speaker 6:  all these chatbots, like their usage pales in comparison. So
Speaker 6:  yeah, I think they are winning because of the instability. Like maybe they'll
Speaker 6:  be able to hire some of these people. But I really think everyone lost here
Speaker 6:  except in the short term Nadella and Sam. Altman. I really
Speaker 6:  do.
Speaker 4:  In the short term, every Microsoft employee is thinking about selling their
Speaker 4:  stock to buy a house. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I've seen multiple tweets of just the screenshot of the stock
Speaker 5:  price saying thank you Satya Nadella. Like yeah,
Speaker 4:  All those people won. Yep. Did anybody else win? I remains to be
Speaker 4:  seen.
Speaker 5:  Fair enough. Okay, last one and then we should get outta here. Chat. GPT.
Speaker 5:  Is this the end of the chat GPT era?
Speaker 4:  Is it? Is it even the end of the story? I don't know.
Speaker 5:  I Okay, fair. If we play this out in what seems like the most likely scenario
Speaker 5:  right now, which is that OpenAI becomes significantly knee capped in some
Speaker 5:  meaningful way. It seems unlikely to me that all of the stuff that
Speaker 5:  we saw two weeks ago at dev day comes out the way that we thought it
Speaker 5:  was going to, it seems possible that this organization goes back to being
Speaker 5:  more of a research organization and chat GPT, the fastest growing consumer
Speaker 5:  internet product in history becomes a sideshow for this company. Again.
Speaker 6:  I mean, if there's no one there to operate it. Well
Speaker 5:  Yeah, there's certainly that.
Speaker 6:  Like, I mean that's, that's the re that's where we are right now is like
Speaker 6:  there may not be an OpenAI by the end of the week, right? Yeah. Like
Speaker 6:  ChatGPT PT probably over, which is wild. But like they'll just recreate
Speaker 6:  it inside Microsoft and, and it won't be as cool and it won't be as like
Speaker 6:  You know breakneck and You know move fast break things.
Speaker 6:  You know Microsoft is like a You know regulated monopoly.
Speaker 6:  They're gonna move very slow and thoughtfully on unlike how this is rolled
Speaker 6:  out because they have to, right? So yeah, I do think this marks,
Speaker 6:  this decidedly marks the move fast break things era of
Speaker 6:  generative ai. I think that's pretty safe to
Speaker 4:  Say.
Speaker 5:  I think so
Speaker 4:  Too. Without question
Speaker 5:  The like craziest rise and fall of a app I can think of,
Speaker 4:  Unless Microsoft just takes it like I do not know what happens next. Like
Speaker 4:  we're gonna, we're gonna end this podcast and I'm gonna go think about the
Speaker 4:  org chart a little bit more and by the time I'm done looking at the boxes,
Speaker 4:  everything might be different. And I think that is again,
Speaker 4:  the weirdest outcome of all of this is we still don't know it's been,
Speaker 4:  we might be onto six CEOs of OpenAI by the end of this week at the rate we're
Speaker 4:  going,
Speaker 6:  Each one of the board members is gonna become the CO until there's only one
Speaker 6:  of them left.
Speaker 4:  It is nuts. And it is I think one of the most riveting
Speaker 4:  corporate dramas of our time. It is also just frankly one of the saddest
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Agreed. All. right? I think we're done here. Neela, you wanna do you wanna
Speaker 5:  take us out?
Speaker 4:  That's it. That's The Vergecast. That was also decoder. We love hearing what
Speaker 4:  you think of our shows. You can send us emails at Vergecast at Verge dot
Speaker 4:  com or decoder at The Verge dot com. We read them all. You can follow us
Speaker 4:  all in threads where we broke a lot of news this weekend, sign of the time
Speaker 4:  for Threads. I will say, although most of the action was still happening
Speaker 4:  on X, a lot of it happened on threads. And very importantly, you can
Speaker 4:  subscribe to Alex's newsletter Command Line, which I am
Speaker 4:  100% confident without having asked. Alex First is gonna be full of
Speaker 4:  scoops about what's happening at OpenAI for the next 500 weeks to come.
Speaker 6:  I hope So I. I sure do.
Speaker 4:  That's it. Rock and roll.
Speaker 12:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 12:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The Vergecast is a
Speaker 12:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 12:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.
Speaker 2:  This podcast is brought to you by Meta Quest three, the new mixed reality
Speaker 2:  headset from Meta. Expand your world in ways you never thought possible
Speaker 2:  with the new Meta Quest. Three, put on the most powerful quest yet
Speaker 2:  and jump into fully immersive games like Assassin's Creed Nexus
Speaker 2:  or blend virtual elements into your surroundings in games like Stranger Things
Speaker 2:  vr. With over 500 titles, it's easy to dive into whatever
Speaker 2:  you're into. Expand your world with Meta Quest three. See child safety
Speaker 2:  guidance online counts for 10 and up. Certain apps, games and experiences
Speaker 2:  may be suitable for a more mature audience. Learn more at Meta dot com.
Speaker 3:  Support for this show comes from Kraken. Crypto is like finance
Speaker 3:  but different. It doesn't care when you invest, trade
Speaker 3:  or save. Do it on weekends or at 5:00 AM or on
Speaker 3:  vacation at 5:00 AM Crypto is financed for everyone
Speaker 3:  everywhere all the time. Kraken. See what crypto
Speaker 3:  can be. Not investment advice. Crypto trading involves risk of loss.
Speaker 3:  Cryptocurrency services are provided to us and US territory customers by
Speaker 3:  pay. Word Ventures Incorporated. View p bs disclosures at
Speaker 3:  kraken.com/legal/disclosures.