# Transcript
ID: 34370450-bc80-11ed-9590-99bef8d85709
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: MWC 2023 gadgets, Meta's AR / VR roadmap, and TikTok's Bold Glamour filter
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7771797191398853137/8100773194157605511/s93290-US-4782s-1678149429.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and Richard Lawler discuss the phones and laptops announced at Mobile World Congress, Meta's AR and VR hardware roadmap for the next few years, Tesla's "Master Plan", and more of this week's tech news.
Speaker 1:  This episode is sponsored by TurboTax. TurboTax has
Speaker 1:  experts who can help relieve you from the stress of taxes and follow for
Speaker 1:  you so you can do not taxes. With TurboTax, an expert
Speaker 1:  will do your taxes from start to finish, ensuring your taxes are done right
Speaker 1:  so you can relax. Feels good to be done with your taxes, right?
Speaker 1:  Come to TurboTax and don't do your taxes. You can visit
Speaker 1:  turbotax.com to learn more. Intuit TurboTax, full service
Speaker 1:  products only video meeting while expert does your taxes required. See
Speaker 1:  guaranteed details at turbotax.com/guarantees.
Speaker 3:  Support for this podcast comes from Lenovo. Any team
Speaker 3:  looking to complete a difficult task needs access to the most powerful
Speaker 3:  tools to get the job done. And that's exactly what Lenovo
Speaker 3:  specializes in their think station. P six 20 Workstation
Speaker 3:  allows power users like animators, engineers, and
Speaker 3:  geoscientists to harness the incredible speed of the a m D rise in
Speaker 3:  thread Ripper Pro processor. And with Tgx remote workstation
Speaker 3:  software, realtime access to massive data sets and unparalleled
Speaker 3:  power is possible from anywhere in the world. To learn more,
Speaker 3:  visit lenovo.com/think station P six 20.
Speaker 4:  Hello and welcome to the flagship podcast, mobile
Speaker 4:  World Congress.
Speaker 1:  Did we get that? That one, is that, is that a sponsorship? We got?
Speaker 4:  What we're getting is a letter about how we're not that from
Speaker 4:  the Europeans, but Mobile World Congress is great. There's a, there's a
Speaker 4:  Senate, there's a 5G Senate and then there's a house of Mid-Range Android
Speaker 4:  funds. Every once a year they come together. I don't know why it's called
Speaker 4:  Mobile World Congress. Anyway, I'm your friend Eli Alex Kranz is here.
Speaker 1:  I'm your friend who also doesn't know why it's called Mobile World Congress.
Speaker 1:  Sorry.
Speaker 4:  It is a very European name. Richard Lawler is here.
Speaker 5:  I'm here. I did not vote for any of this representation.
Speaker 4:  I saw a very rude tweet this week that was like Mobile Congress is
Speaker 4:  hilarious. It's thousands of companies coming together to compete with Apple,
Speaker 4:  which does not attend. And I want to say one that is
Speaker 4:  inaccurate and I'll explain why. Two, I lulled like, I definitely just laughed
Speaker 4:  cuz there's like a, there's an internal truth to it. Like if you live in
Speaker 4:  an insular apple world, like that's the most true thing you've ever heard.
Speaker 4:  And it's very funny. And then everyone else is like, no, but we're companies
Speaker 4:  like we build the networks. You, you need us to
Speaker 4:  exist for the iPhone to work
Speaker 5:  Your iPhone uses all of these things.
Speaker 4:  Actually I was entertained. It was very funny and it, and it's like very
Speaker 4:  small way. But Mobile World Congress was this week. If you don't know,
Speaker 4:  I have no idea why you're listening to this show, but welcome all are welcome
Speaker 4:  here. Now I will explain to you what Mobile World Congress or MWC is.
Speaker 4:  This is the podcast you've chosen to listen to. Mwc we've been going to for
Speaker 4:  years and years. The CS is a show. I think everybody who is
Speaker 4:  in and around tech is familiar with. It's the big trade show in the United States
Speaker 4:  where God only knows what happens there anymore. Samsung shows up,
Speaker 4:  they're like, now the fridge has a 47 inch TV built into it. They're, ooh,
Speaker 4:  ah. Then there's Effa, which is the European version of that thing.
Speaker 4:  If A, and then there's M W C, the World
Speaker 4:  Congress, which for a minute I would say Richard
Speaker 4:  was like the most important trade show of them all because it is the mobile
Speaker 4:  phone trade show and it's gigantic. It's in Barcelona. We all
Speaker 4:  have gone over the years like literally thousands and thousands of companies
Speaker 4:  from around the world. This is where 3G was debuted, it was our
Speaker 4:  4G was debuted, it's our 5g. Like this is that show.
Speaker 4:  And what's interesting is well the iPhone kind of won. Like that's why that
Speaker 4:  joke is funny, right? Like the iPhone won in a meaningful way but
Speaker 4:  the show is is back, right? It's like post Covid back in full
Speaker 4:  force and kind of like a lot of things happened there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, back in the days of G P R S, it was a whole different story.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. This is a show where it's like Intel's gonna show up with Ymax.
Speaker 4:  Wow. And it was like, are they right? Like it's a show where these battles
Speaker 4:  happen. It's where Windows Mobile made it debut. Windows
Speaker 4:  Mobile 6.5 actually for like old heads who are listening to this one, remember
Speaker 4:  this when we were all at in gadget and like Steve Bomber was like, here's
Speaker 4:  Windows Mobile 6.5 and all they had done
Speaker 4:  to compete with the iPhone was they took old janky Windows mobile
Speaker 4:  and they added a honeycomb shaped launcher to the home screen.
Speaker 4:  And people were like, it's over. Microsoft's defeated
Speaker 4:  the iPhone. Like that's M W C. There's, there's an a
Speaker 4:  number of amazing Sony Erickson, I I, the history here is great. Again, if
Speaker 4:  you're an old head, a lot of amazing things that happened to Barcelona,
Speaker 5:  What didn't work, the, the list of things that did not work is something
Speaker 5:  that we could go on for literally hours. But what we saw this year,
Speaker 5:  John Porter was there at the show at M W C. He handled all all of these phones,
Speaker 5:  some of these laptops, these other mobile devices. He noticed a trend of
Speaker 5:  seeing kind of the things that you could see in future phones. Each phone
Speaker 5:  kind of had its own distinctive thing. We had something like this. Hm. MD
Speaker 5:  now makes these phones so they call Nokia's. So they've got this G 22
Speaker 5:  that costs less than $200 and it's designed specifically so that you can
Speaker 5:  fix it. You could replace the battery, they say in around five minutes you
Speaker 5:  could swap out the screen in under 20 minutes and they're gonna have a partnership
Speaker 5:  with i Fixit to sell replacement parts. So if that's something that you've
Speaker 5:  been looking for, I want a phone that I can actually work on myself,
Speaker 5:  replace and keep for probably as long as the software updates
Speaker 5:  keep going. You might have that option with this phone that is actually going
Speaker 5:  to be coming out this year or actually coming out now in this next week or
Speaker 5:  so. But
Speaker 1:  It's, it's not a fair phone. It's, it's a little more complex.
Speaker 1:  It's got like water resistance. It's not waterproof but it's
Speaker 1:  got water resistance, which is one of the things they always said, oh your
Speaker 1:  phone can't be repairable otherwise it won't be water resistant. And like
Speaker 1:  watchmakers are like, that's not true. We've done this for a very long time
Speaker 1:  and phone makers are like, oh maybe we can catch up that one. Like that was
Speaker 1:  kind of the one that I was really excited about. Is it weird to be really
Speaker 1:  excited about a phone just because I can replace the battery?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean at, at this point replace the battery and phone is like a deeply
Speaker 4:  political act, right? You're like, you know like if, if you made the movie
Speaker 4:  pump up the volume again in 2023, right? Instead of
Speaker 4:  broadcasting Pirate radio, Christian Slater would be in his basement like
Speaker 4:  doing an iPhone repair kiosk. You know the cops would come to each.
Speaker 4:  But if anyone is listening and wants to reboot the movie, pump up the volume
Speaker 4:  with Christian Slater is a rogue teenage iPhone repairman. I can write that
Speaker 4:  script in maybe an hour.
Speaker 1:  Christian Slater will still be playing the teenager.
Speaker 5:  If only this were the peak of streaming, we could get a 20 episode series
Speaker 4:  Out of that. I can't believe I missed it. How did I only come to us now?
Speaker 4:  So the the Nok story, it is really interesting. This week Nokia is
Speaker 4:  split effectively into two companies. They license the old Nokia name to
Speaker 4:  this company H M D, which is making handsets this handset's. Very cool.
Speaker 4:  The best part is that I fix it is selling a repair kit with it. And you should
Speaker 4:  go look at this picture on our side, pull your car over and go look at the
Speaker 4:  picture. There's, I believe I fix it called this these smudger.
Speaker 4:  That's the tool that you use to crack open the screen, you know like little
Speaker 4:  plastic wedge to get in there. The smudger that comes with this phone, it
Speaker 4:  looks like a pocket knife. It right? It looks like you should be able to
Speaker 4:  like quickly flip it out and then something. I love it
Speaker 4:  like it's perfect. I think more phone repair tools should look
Speaker 4:  vaguely dangerous.
Speaker 1:  Yes, a hundred percent. I think people would be more into repairability
Speaker 1:  if the tools look vaguely dangerous
Speaker 5:  And they're all color matched
Speaker 4:  And they're all color matched. The whole thing's great. I looked at the,
Speaker 4:  I was like is that a knife nuts a smudger. It also
Speaker 4:  comes with these like guitar pick the whole thing's fun. So that's great.
Speaker 4:  But that's HMDs Nokia. Yeah. And so they're still, you know, this is
Speaker 4:  like the classic thing you do when you have a legendary brand. Polaroid is
Speaker 4:  like the example. You sell the brand off for parts, you let people license
Speaker 4:  it. You just squeeze all the money outta the brand equity until
Speaker 4:  you're done. Nokia kind of doing that and handsets, right? Like whatever,
Speaker 4:  we're gonna let this Chinese company make handsets. HMD is doing something
Speaker 4:  kind of cool here but it's still operating at the very low end of the market,
Speaker 4:  right? This is $150 handset. Okay? But cool comes with comes with
Speaker 4:  the weird smudger knife on the other side there's
Speaker 4:  the Nokia that actually remains as Nokia, which is the
Speaker 4:  networking equipment manufacturer. They make the 5G base stations
Speaker 4:  and the cell towers and the software that connects it all together. And their
Speaker 4:  big news at MWC was people think we still make phones so our
Speaker 4:  solution is to change our logo to something ridiculous
Speaker 1:  Real Kia.
Speaker 4:  So I think the Kia thing worked. Do
Speaker 5:  You, in case you don't know Kia changed their logo and now people are trying
Speaker 5:  to Google the K in car. Is it that they're looking for,
Speaker 4:  Wait, let's just, let's just back this up. Let's ba back it up. Let's
Speaker 4:  separate the two words that sound the same from each other. Nokia,
Speaker 4:  the 5G equipment company changed its logo. Yes. And then what
Speaker 4:  we all, all immediately started talking about was Kia the car company,
Speaker 4:  which admittedly is just a confusing transition but makes
Speaker 4:  perfect sense because Kia changed its logo
Speaker 4:  I think last year to something much more angular and stylish
Speaker 4:  and everyone thinks it says K N. So then we have,
Speaker 4:  we have run stories. Other people have run stories that people see the
Speaker 4:  cars, they think the cars look cool cause new Kia cars, a lot of them look
Speaker 4:  cool and then they start Googling k n car. I'm telling you
Speaker 4:  this is a gigantic victory for Kia, right? Like in
Speaker 4:  the boardrooms of Kia when they're like, did the logo redesign work?
Speaker 4:  They're like, yes, everyone is talking about our logo.
Speaker 4:  And now if you know something about cars you are waiting to
Speaker 4:  jump out of a bush when someone's like, what's that can car to be like that's
Speaker 4:  a Kia. And then you then you have a five minute conversation about their
Speaker 4:  logo. Like I'm, I'm telling you this all worked. The earned media for Kia
Speaker 4:  off the charts, everyone's talking about Kia's, the Kia logos. I'm
Speaker 4:  assuming they do not like talking about the Kia Boys, the gang of TikTok
Speaker 4:  Thieves fair, how to steal Hyundai and Kia
Speaker 4:  cars very easily. That seems like a less good
Speaker 4:  outcome for them. This is true by the way, it's Kia boys with a z. We've
Speaker 4:  written about that. I think we talked about them last week, didn't we? We
Speaker 4:  did. Anyhow, so the Kia logo I think like worked really well cuz
Speaker 4:  it was like a consumer and you can probably argue with me about this.
Speaker 1:  I, I would absolutely argue with you cuz I, I rode in
Speaker 1:  one of those Kias with a K and I was just like, what off brand
Speaker 1:  nonsense is my friend bought for a car and now I'm sitting in
Speaker 1:  it and am I going to die?
Speaker 4:  To be fair, that's what people have thought about Kia for a decade.
Speaker 1:  Yeah I I was like why did she meet from Kia to whatever this
Speaker 1:  is? She's got the worst taste in cars. And then I think like
Speaker 1:  Andy or someone wrote the story and I was like, oh,
Speaker 1:  oh she's just with Kia still.
Speaker 5:  Okay maybe it's not a dub for Kia.
Speaker 4:  See you see what I'm saying? This it worked. It's a seared in
Speaker 4:  your brain and now the next time someone's like what's a can car? You've
Speaker 4:  got a whole story about Kia to tell and now you've talked about Kia for five
Speaker 4:  minutes. I'm telling you this work
Speaker 5:  For them. And we did on the podcast and now Nok which is not the company
Speaker 5:  that makes Nok phones, although there is a company that makes Nok phones.
Speaker 5:  There is another company that is still Nok, that is the old Nokia that does
Speaker 5:  not make phones and wants people to know that it does not make phones. And
Speaker 5:  so they did not change their name to something that is other than Nokia,
Speaker 5:  which is still on phones that are coming out now. They just changed the way
Speaker 5:  the logo
Speaker 4:  Looks to make it look more like the Kia logo.
Speaker 1:  No key
Speaker 4:  But so it's, go look at it, they've removed most of the vertical
Speaker 4:  stems from the letters. There's no other way to describe this logo. Like
Speaker 4:  imagine the word Nokia and then be like what if we just remove
Speaker 4:  most of the vertical lines Save for the eye. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So you get something that looks very much like vo Shia
Speaker 4:  and it's gonna be printed on cell towers around the world. Cuz that's what
Speaker 4:  they make. They make cell towers and software and like, you know like quarter
Speaker 4:  zip fleece vests, like enterprise stuff and you're not even getting at
Speaker 4:  that moment where like that car looks cool, what's K N and Google it. It's
Speaker 4:  just gonna be like, what is that weird enterprise company? And you're going
Speaker 4:  to continue riding the escalator at the airport.
Speaker 1:  It looks like, you know when you're watching a movie
Speaker 1:  and the alien picks up their little alien phone and they start typing
Speaker 1:  to other aliens with their alien language. It looks like the alien
Speaker 1:  languages.
Speaker 4:  That's what they were going for.
Speaker 1:  I liked your pronunciation though. That feels like the right pronunciation.
Speaker 4:  That's, it's very finished. Anyhow, that was like the other big news. It's
Speaker 4:  like the biggest story is like Nokia rebrand. It was like the first thing
Speaker 4:  was snatched.
Speaker 5:  That was not the biggest news. Not, not the most I important news.
Speaker 4:  All right, what else you got
Speaker 5:  Richard? The Motorola riser.
Speaker 4:  Oh my
Speaker 5:  God, the riser. The only phone that we want to discuss from M W C, it is
Speaker 5:  not called the riser or it has not been called that yet, but it should be.
Speaker 5:  Everyone agrees. Motorola showed off rollable screen devices. We, we saw
Speaker 5:  a laptop and we saw a phone from Lenovo both using the same technology,
Speaker 5:  neither one with a release date or price or anything like that. But they
Speaker 5:  look like real devices look like something that we could see in the near
Speaker 5:  and near future.
Speaker 4:  So this is a thing that Lenovo does on the regular, right? So
Speaker 4:  the short version of the history here, Motorola was a company that
Speaker 4:  existed then they tried to compete with Samsung, it's in
Speaker 4:  Go so great. Then Google bought Motorola in order to regain
Speaker 4:  some control over the Android ecosystem. Then Samsung
Speaker 4:  made the software on its phone. So ridiculous. This is a true
Speaker 4:  story that Andy Rubin at CES was like, what are you doing to my precious,
Speaker 4:  precious android bring it back to reality. And Samsung said, we'll
Speaker 4:  do it if you sell Motorola and don't compete with us directly. This is a
Speaker 4:  true story. So then Google sold Motorola to Lenovo and then
Speaker 4:  later on bought HTC and that's fine. I don't, that's,
Speaker 4:  it's a little weedsy there. But ever since Lenovo has bought Motorola,
Speaker 4:  they roll out kind of like on the regular, like pretty interesting
Speaker 4:  concept devices, both laptops and phones to show that they sell
Speaker 4:  hardware shops and then some of them come out and some of 'em don't. So they
Speaker 4:  show off this phone, which we will discuss whether or not it is called the
Speaker 4:  Riser, but they show off this phone. That is so cool. So it's a
Speaker 4:  rollable phone, it's not a foldable phone. So it's a little more
Speaker 4:  Squareish Richard. And then when you unlock it or you
Speaker 4:  go to watch a YouTube video or something, the screen rolls out, it extends
Speaker 4:  to become 16 by nine, which is just cool as hell in my
Speaker 5:  Opinion. Yeah, like it goes IMAX mode essentially. Like suddenly you have
Speaker 5:  an ultra wide screen now to watch your videos or whatever. Just when you
Speaker 5:  need that extra space on the laptop if you, if you want your spreadsheets
Speaker 5:  and everything on the screen and you gotta see all your rows. Okay, now,
Speaker 5:  now I need extra space. I think, I think we talked about this what a couple
Speaker 5:  weeks ago where we've said on the plane you're gonna extend your super tall
Speaker 5:  laptop screen. Yeah, they're chasing that market. They, they are,
Speaker 5:  they're following exactly what what we're saying. But the, the phone is something
Speaker 5:  that in your pocket, it's just gonna be the same as any other phone. But
Speaker 5:  then suddenly when you need some extra space, there you go. And it's not
Speaker 5:  super thick or has a hinge necessarily like we've seen from these foldable
Speaker 5:  foams and at least from the demos it, it looks cool.
Speaker 4:  Yeah it looks really cool the, when the screen is retracted because
Speaker 4:  it's a rollable, it's curved around the back. So you can use
Speaker 4:  the rear of the screen is like a selfie camera with the rear
Speaker 4:  camera, which I think rules and then you can get like status updates, all
Speaker 4:  this other stuff there. This is the part of the phone cycle now
Speaker 4:  where it seems like the hardware technology of
Speaker 4:  Rollie bendy flexible screens is not yet mature. It's obviously
Speaker 4:  not shipping in any particular volume outside of Samsung, but it's mature
Speaker 4:  enough that we can see what the product should look like and the ideas are
Speaker 4:  getting a little more sensible as opposed to, I dunno, a couple years ago
Speaker 4:  when we're like, which way should the phones fold? And the answer is like
Speaker 4:  exactly one way and it's whatever Samsung wants, right? But now it's like,
Speaker 4:  oh this is a lot cooler. Like I can see this thing where it's like a
Speaker 4:  more compact than regular phone, but then you turn it sideways to watch a
Speaker 4:  YouTube video and the screen rolls out. That just rules like yeah
Speaker 4:  that's awesome. This
Speaker 1:  Feels like the phone that I would want to own. Unlike a lot of the Samsung
Speaker 1:  ones, the Samsung ones all feel like drawbacks. It's either like, okay you
Speaker 1:  have a little fat square that'll not fit in your pocket particularly well
Speaker 1:  or you have a really long skinny square that will not, you'll have a really
Speaker 1:  long skinny rectangle that won't fit in your pocket particularly well. And
Speaker 1:  this looks like it will fit a little better. Yeah. But also just be cooler
Speaker 1:  and you'll feel like a fancier person using
Speaker 5:  It. And I think that's where, where they're getting the, the wind kind of
Speaker 5:  is that this feels like, this seems like something that will feel cool to
Speaker 5:  use. And they've brought back the razor, which was probably the coolest phone
Speaker 5:  of, of all time by by percentage of the phones that were available
Speaker 5:  versus the razor at that time. It was by far the coolest cooler
Speaker 5:  than anything else has ever been. The revamped foldable screen razor, which
Speaker 5:  they're going to bring out another device and might bring to the US hopefully
Speaker 5:  hasn't really recaptured that, but this rollable screen it, it kind of gets
Speaker 5:  there. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So everyone is calling this thing the riser, which does not
Speaker 4:  appear to be its official name. Motorola is calling it the Motorola
Speaker 4:  Rollable, which is fine. I mean it rolls right off the tongue. Motorola,
Speaker 4:  yes, just try saying it. Hit pause on podcast right now and just go Motorola
Speaker 4:  rollable, look to your partner. Just say it. We'll
Speaker 1:  Wait right in the eye when you say
Speaker 4:  It. Motorola rollable, it's great and I love it. The riser is a cooler
Speaker 4:  name and so they should go with that. Then on top of that, as Richard
Speaker 4:  was saying, Motorola did a couple years ago
Speaker 4:  put out a rebooted version of the razor phone, the classic
Speaker 4:  razor as a folding screen, mid-range Android phone.
Speaker 4:  Do y'all remember this? They went nuts with this launch. They influencer
Speaker 4:  parties, la the whole, they were like, we're back baby.
Speaker 4:  Everybody wants to flip open a razor and drive around in Miatas
Speaker 4:  or whatever. It's, they think the cool kids do and it just,
Speaker 4:  it flopped like total flopped. Like
Speaker 1:  It was a bad
Speaker 4:  Phone. I mean they ran into all the problems that every mid-range Android
Speaker 4:  phone runs into, which is the carriers loaded it with Bloatware. The processor
Speaker 4:  was slow, the camera was mediocre. It didn't have iMessage.
Speaker 5:  It was a Verizon exclusive at first, wasn't it?
Speaker 4:  I think so, yeah.
Speaker 5:  I hate to see it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's,
Speaker 1:  The display was kind of crummy on it too, if I remember correctly.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it was just a bad phone. Yeah, like all the money was in the
Speaker 4:  folding and I don't think that they quite understood that
Speaker 4:  the target market for extremely fashionable phones also cares a lot about
Speaker 4:  iMessage, bump bump and then, and then you're like, oh, and the camera's
Speaker 4:  bad and the screen's a little shitty and the battery's not great. So they're
Speaker 4:  making a third version or Or you on three
Speaker 5:  I, yeah, I think so. I think this will be be number three or four. I, I don't
Speaker 5:  know. I don't know. I've lost count at this point. I
Speaker 4:  Just want to give you the quote from the CEO of Lenovo.
Speaker 4:  This is to cnbc, yang Wonking says to
Speaker 4:  cnbc, I think it's much better.
Speaker 1:  That's some confidence
Speaker 1:  he's willing to put go on the record saying that. That's real confidence.
Speaker 4:  How is the fuck? I think it's much better not, I know
Speaker 1:  Hedge is bats
Speaker 5:  That that's a real rim. We've got like two more blackberries to release
Speaker 5:  type of
Speaker 4:  Vibe. So then we went and asked Motorola
Speaker 4:  one Motorola officially refers to the CEO is yy.
Speaker 4:  Oh wow. Two Ys great. I mean that's, I can't get enough of that.
Speaker 4:  And then they said we're committed to foldable space
Speaker 4:  dedicated to expanding the Razor franchise soon. Stay tuned. So there is
Speaker 4:  another razor coming and the CEO of Lenovo thinks
Speaker 4:  it is much better.
Speaker 1:  Everyone invests that. That's, that's some like real optimism.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. What else happened at nbc Richard?
Speaker 5:  We saw other cool films. We saw Real me and I think they're
Speaker 5:  kind of corporate partners showing off phones that have really fast charging
Speaker 5:  240 wat fast charging in the real me GT three that you'll be able to buy
Speaker 5:  outside of China, although not in the us you'll be able to kind of plug
Speaker 5:  these phones and, and get half charge or full charging in just a few minutes.
Speaker 5:  And these are are real phones that people will actually be able to buy. Again,
Speaker 5:  not not where I live, but somewhere we saw one plus with
Speaker 5:  it, its active cooling phone that they say take several degrees
Speaker 5:  off. So when you're doing gaming on your phone, it won't overheat
Speaker 4:  And Trevor's always doing.
Speaker 5:  Of course it's a problem. Everyone, it's a problem we, we've all had and
Speaker 5:  they finally fixed it. They're launching a foldable later, later this year.
Speaker 5:  Honor has foldable. They they
Speaker 4:  Were just, this is what I mean about the technology is it's not mainstream,
Speaker 4:  it's just hit the part of the technology curve
Speaker 4:  where you can get it. Yeah. Right. And like that's an, it's just an important
Speaker 4:  thing to recognize. This is not limited to
Speaker 4:  a $2,100 Samsung flagship
Speaker 4:  concept phone. Now it's like, well you can just get it. So honor's gonna
Speaker 4:  make one and that's a, it is just, it's important to note that that's where
Speaker 4:  we are with these flexible screens.
Speaker 5:  And I think honors honors looks kind of cool that like you can have it sit,
Speaker 5:  you can use it partially folded. It looks, looks a little like the Motorola
Speaker 5:  mpx I'm saying they could put a physical keyboard on there.
Speaker 4:  It would be better. I see what you're saying.
Speaker 5:  We, we'll get there. But I, I think that was just the kind of the vibe of
Speaker 5:  the show that you had all of these different approaches. You can see the
Speaker 5:  technology coming and we'll, we'll have some, we'll have some of these other
Speaker 5:  things on phones that even, even we can use with this ridiculously fast charging
Speaker 5:  with more ways of using it. And I just want a riser that I can
Speaker 5:  roll up and, and unroll. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's so f well I want that too very badly. I'm very worried
Speaker 4:  that, you know, Lenovo's bar is, I think it will be much better. So
Speaker 4:  they're all concepts we have to see. I'm assuming it will have a
Speaker 4:  mid-range Qualcomm trip, a medium good screen and a bad camera.
Speaker 4:  This is the default for a mid-range generate phone. Now
Speaker 1:  They notably wouldn't let John like play with
Speaker 1:  No he the riser, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think he could see it but he could not touch it himself.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, they wouldn't let him play with it and then he could still see like
Speaker 1:  the crease in the screen even from afar. So, Ooh,
Speaker 4:  That's so good.
Speaker 1:  We got some time.
Speaker 5:  There was the one accessory that we also saw more brand engineering
Speaker 5:  called Motorola, but made by this British company Bullet a Bluetooth
Speaker 5:  fob that you can use with your iPhone or your Android phone and you can get
Speaker 5:  something sort of like iPhone sos. Okay, with all, but
Speaker 5:  it's even better because you can also send messages, it connects to satellites.
Speaker 5:  You, you suddenly get that feature without having to buy a new phone.
Speaker 4:  It's only a hundred bucks,
Speaker 5:  Only a hundred bucks. The service isn't too expensive like 4 99 a month.
Speaker 5:  Whoever you're messaging does need to have this bullet company's app. But
Speaker 5:  it, it just kind of comes in and goes out as a regular SMS from you.
Speaker 4:  Wait, you need the other person needs the bullet app.
Speaker 5:  You can send them an SMS and they'll get it, but they'll get it and a link
Speaker 5:  to the app so that they can reply to you so they can, they can get your messages
Speaker 5:  but they can't send back without the app.
Speaker 4:  That is just something brutal growth hacking right there. It's like I'm trapped
Speaker 4:  on a mountain, I need you to download an app called Bullet.
Speaker 1:  Can you imagine sending that to like your partner who's not very
Speaker 1:  tech savvy and be like, help me save my life. And they're like, ah, I have
Speaker 1:  to log into the app store.
Speaker 4:  Never. I don't know my iCloud password.
Speaker 1:  You just die like you're up on that mountain forever.
Speaker 4:  That's brutal. This should, it should come with a sticker on the box. It's
Speaker 4:  like you need a friend who knows their app store password. Make sure they
Speaker 4:  have face Eddie set up. All right, lastly on the M W C tip, Alex this is
Speaker 4:  your favorite. It's the other Lenovo thing. Yeah, it's the
Speaker 4:  laptop that goes into silly mode.
Speaker 1:  It's, he just goes whoop. He just goes straight up it looks like a normal
Speaker 1:  laptop and you're like, oh look at this little, this little 12 inch laptop.
Speaker 1:  What adorable thing. And then the screen slowly rises
Speaker 1:  from beneath from like the beneath the deck of the keyboard
Speaker 1:  and just gets taller and taller and then you got like two
Speaker 1:  screens stacked on top of each other.
Speaker 4:  It looks so silly. Go watch the video on the website. John did a great job
Speaker 4:  with this video, but you end up with two 16 by nine screens, right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like stacked or at least that aspect ratio.
Speaker 1:  I just, I like Neil, I wanna have this like
Speaker 1:  in when next time we're doing the Verge cast and, and I have this, I wanna
Speaker 1:  be sitting across from you making eye contact and then you'll just watch
Speaker 1:  me disappear as the screen slowly rises
Speaker 4:  So rude. Like the worst meeting etiquette is like boop
Speaker 4:  and the screen slowly rises up and covers your eye.
Speaker 5:  So it's two 16 by nine screens. So it would be perfectly sized for you to
Speaker 5:  be on a Zoom call while also watching Netflix if you wanted to do that.
Speaker 4:  Yes. And no one would know because you've raised the screen
Speaker 4:  so it looks like your eyes are still tracking where they were at the start
Speaker 4:  of the call.
Speaker 1:  Exactly.
Speaker 4:  You see what I'm saying? But you've, you've just gone,
Speaker 1:  I like, I think this is, this is brilliant. I want one tomorrow everybody.
Speaker 1:  I don't know what needs to happen to make this an actual viable product
Speaker 1:  that people buy, but the last few times Lenovo has
Speaker 1:  done something like this where they're like, look at this stupid thing and
Speaker 1:  you're like, that's stupid. Nobody will buy that. I want it. Then they go
Speaker 1:  and they make it.
Speaker 4:  Yes, that's what I'm saying Lenovo, this is Lenovo's thing now they're just
Speaker 4:  like, here it is.
Speaker 5:  And the last dual screen laptop was pretty good, wasn't it? I, I feel like
Speaker 5:  Monica said in the review, am I going too far?
Speaker 1:  That's generous. It wasn't horrible.
Speaker 5:  There we go.
Speaker 4:  Yes, Monica said it was actually good and quote shockingly
Speaker 4:  useful and then she said, as long as you're willing to pay $2,000 for it,
Speaker 4:  which I'm just gonna point out that in laptop world
Speaker 4:  is not a lot of money. She's like, it's shockingly useful for this
Speaker 4:  amount of money. Which again for high end laptop
Speaker 4:  is like the normal amount of money. So I think, I think there's a little
Speaker 4:  qualifier in there.
Speaker 1:  I wouldn't buy it but like I would respect other people who did. I don't
Speaker 1:  know if I'd respect them, but like I'd appreciate hanging out with them.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I just love that Lenova does the stuff like they're the one company
Speaker 4:  now that I think reliably ships the wacky concepts,
Speaker 4:  the dual screen laptop with keyboard in the front. Come on. Who else is doing
Speaker 4:  that? You think Tim Cook is doing that? No. Samsung used to do that
Speaker 4:  now they're like, whatever, it's orange. That's as far as they go. Now I
Speaker 4:  appreciate that about Lenovo. That's what that's and that's what a trade
Speaker 4:  show is for. That's why we go to M W C. So like look at wild
Speaker 4:  stuff and think, okay, like five years from now, this might be the mainstream
Speaker 4:  thing. It's not because we think any of this will actually happen.
Speaker 4:  And I say this because I'm still scarred from when
Speaker 4:  Steve Bomber introduced Windows Mobile 6.5 with a honeycomb
Speaker 4:  app launcher and we were like, this is never gonna happen. And we were
Speaker 4:  inundated to the in Gadget comments four months saying that we were biased
Speaker 4:  in favor of Apple. Sorry, that was like 2007 and I'm still,
Speaker 4:  I told you so fully and I told you so
Speaker 4:  and now Noki is dead. That's what happened. There's a direct line from that
Speaker 4:  moment to whatever the Nokia logo is now.
Speaker 5:  That's your NFT moment. I I get it
Speaker 4:  Exactly Richard. I'm holding onto it forever. Alright, we gotta take a break
Speaker 4:  and come back. Alex Heath scooped the entire meta ar VR
Speaker 4:  hardware roadmap. We gotta talk about it. And then of course Elon
Speaker 4:  more stuff happened. We'll be right back.
Speaker 6:  Mint Mobile offers premium wireless for just 15 bucks a month. That
Speaker 6:  means spending a little less money on your phone bill and a little more for
Speaker 6:  online shopping, probably on your phone. All plans come with
Speaker 6:  unlimited talk and text plus high speed data. You can use your own
Speaker 6:  phone with any Mint mobile plan and switch easily in minutes with
Speaker 6:  eem to get your new wireless plan for just 15 bucks a month
Speaker 6:  and get the plan shipped to your door for free, go to mint
Speaker 6:  mobile.com/fox. That's mint
Speaker 6:  mobile.com/vox.
Speaker 7:  Running a business is stressful, but worrying about how to grow
Speaker 7:  your company in the digital space can make any ambitious person wanna give
Speaker 7:  up. Wouldn't it be nice to have a set of expertly designed tools to
Speaker 7:  help you create your own growth tailored exactly to your company's needs?
Speaker 7:  That's where uny comes in. Uny is a global technology
Speaker 7:  solutions company dedicated to helping people and organizations reach
Speaker 7:  their next breakthrough. They offer tools to help you run your business more
Speaker 7:  efficiently, like systems integration, consulting services,
Speaker 7:  application management and device management software Plus
Speaker 7:  Unisys applies specialized expertise to strengthen and transform
Speaker 7:  teams and processes by helping organizations act on new opportunities
Speaker 7:  through digital workplace cloud applications, enterprise
Speaker 7:  computing and business process solutions. To learn more, visit
Speaker 7:  uny.com, that's U N I S Y s.com.
Speaker 7:  Uny keep breaking through.
Speaker 4:  We're back. Big scoop this week.
Speaker 1:  Big scoop.
Speaker 4:  Alex Heath Scoop machine Scooped met us so hard
Speaker 4:  that they talked about him in all hands meetings after the scoop. Yes. Which
Speaker 4:  is the funniest part of the whole puzzle. That's
Speaker 1:  When you know it's a good
Speaker 4:  Scoop. I can't tell you what I know, I just know that in many meetings at
Speaker 4:  meta after Alex scooped the roadmap, they talked
Speaker 4:  about Alex, which is very good, subscribe to Command line. I think he's gonna
Speaker 4:  have some of that gossip in command line this week. I was like, this is what
Speaker 4:  the people pay for. It's not the scoop, it's the gossip.
Speaker 1:  A hundred percent.
Speaker 4:  That's what I, that's what I pay for anyway. So Heath gets
Speaker 4:  the entire ar vr roadmap outta meta for the next four
Speaker 4:  years.
Speaker 1:  Along with like their insight, right? Like their insight into
Speaker 1:  why they're doing this and how they're gonna do
Speaker 4:  It. Yeah. And Meta has been through like I would say a weird period. They
Speaker 4:  laid a bunch of people off Mark Zuckerberg's under fire for focusing on the
Speaker 4:  Metaverse. The Quest Pro is behind me over there.
Speaker 4:  Haven't put that thing, has not been charged in in weeks and weeks. Now
Speaker 4:  Quest Pro came out, you know, lots of hype. Zuckerberg is like
Speaker 4:  doing virtual kickboxing with Joe Rogan trying to tell people the Metaverse
Speaker 4:  is here, the product is not good. The Quest two in my
Speaker 4:  opinion is a superior product. The Quest Pro a hundred percent because it's
Speaker 4:  more accessible, it's cheaper, it's just value for dollar, right? You get
Speaker 4:  more value for dollar in the Quest two than the Quest Pro
Speaker 4:  and then Horizon is just a mess, just a full
Speaker 4:  mess. And then Meta has layoffs in the advertising market. Sound apple's
Speaker 4:  like done the ad tracking transparency thing. Tough times from it all around.
Speaker 4:  So I think they were having this moment where the idea was we
Speaker 4:  have to re-really the troops around our ar vr
Speaker 4:  plans around reality labs, around the metaverse. So they have this like
Speaker 4:  roadmap presentation of AR and VR and what they're gonna do. And
Speaker 4:  importantly Alex, why they're doing it and where they think the money is
Speaker 4:  gonna come from.
Speaker 1:  It's fascinating. I, because I think we so often just get these
Speaker 1:  roadmaps, a lot of times when these kind of leaks happen, usually it's just
Speaker 1:  like, here's some documents showing the roadmap. And in this case we get
Speaker 1:  so much insight into what they're doing and their plans that I think
Speaker 1:  was really, really helpful. Even if it does showcase like an
Speaker 1:  optimism that I think is extraordinarily foolish.
Speaker 4:  Well, so let's start with the one piece of the puzzle that I think all of
Speaker 4:  us have been curious about. They said they have sold nearly
Speaker 4:  20 million Quest headsets to date. That's Quest one and Quest two, although
Speaker 4:  I think Quest two is the vast majority of that, that's not bad
Speaker 4:  for a games console.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's like pretty solid.
Speaker 4:  Like the Nintendo Switch is the most popular console of all and I think it's
Speaker 4:  over a hundred million and that's where it is. Like we're so used to phone
Speaker 4:  numbers like apple's, like 95 billion iPhones
Speaker 4:  we're like that's the, but like the number for the Nintendo Switch, which
Speaker 4:  is now officially the third bestselling console of all time is
Speaker 4:  122.5 million. That's a lot. Obviously
Speaker 4:  far more than 20 million. But in context, I think we all thought that Quest
Speaker 4:  two or the Quest was smaller.
Speaker 5:  Well I think my question is kind of how does that break down among, among
Speaker 5:  the generations? But the Quest two unquestionably sold pretty well. The,
Speaker 5:  I know, I know a lot of people, we all kind of know people have seen them
Speaker 5:  around this past Christmas who got Quest two s, the 20 million
Speaker 5:  number. There are estimates that say the Xbox Series families around
Speaker 5:  20 million, that's a Fiji charts number if you know, you know, not exact,
Speaker 5:  not totally reliable but probably not that far off. So it, it's a decent
Speaker 5:  number for the hardware. But the thing that was in the article that
Speaker 5:  I kind of didn't understand is they're saying that the Quest three is going
Speaker 5:  to be at least a little bit more expensive. So how do you get people
Speaker 5:  to pay more? What exactly are they gonna put in it that people are going
Speaker 5:  to pay more for?
Speaker 4:  Right? Or are they gonna try to continue to grow the market, right? And say
Speaker 5:  They already raised the price of the quest too,
Speaker 4:  Right? The mean, this is like the classic problem. Like are you trying to
Speaker 4:  get everyone upgraded? You're trying to get 20 million people upgraded and
Speaker 4:  you think that your whole market is 20 million people or do you think the
Speaker 4:  market is a hundred million devices, you're gonna keep
Speaker 4:  supporting the Quest two and you're gonna go try to get the next 80 million
Speaker 4:  people with the Quest three i, I don't know, I I I think they don't know.
Speaker 1:  I don't know that you can get 20 million people or you know, another 20
Speaker 1:  80 million people whatever with the Crest three because it's more expensive.
Speaker 1:  The the, the get for the Quest two was its affordability.
Speaker 1:  It was that perfect blend, which is why I think they were talking in the
Speaker 1:  roadmap. There's plans for another device that's gonna be
Speaker 1:  cheaper, that's gonna hit that sweet spot while also kind of like
Speaker 1:  maximizing the VR capabilities.
Speaker 5:  I've heard this before, it was called the Sega Saturn in 32 x. I don't think
Speaker 5:  that worked out very well.
Speaker 4:  So here's a quote Meta says around the third year of Quest two and the
Speaker 4:  newer people that are coming in, the people who bought it this last Christmas,
Speaker 4:  they're not as into it as the ones who bought it early. Which kinda makes
Speaker 4:  sense, right? The early adopters are into it. The early adopters are gonna
Speaker 4:  use a lot. People get it as a Christmas gift. They're kind of going into
Speaker 4:  an ecosystem that is mature. Horizon is not the thing,
Speaker 4:  it's games like the thing is a games console that need great games every
Speaker 4:  season. I don't think the Quest had great games. So the Quest this year,
Speaker 4:  so the Quest three is gonna hit with 41 new apps and
Speaker 4:  games including some new mixed reality stuff. There's gonna be pass through
Speaker 4:  that works really well. This is the mainstream headset that's coming.
Speaker 4:  What I would put around the, the context I would put around that 20 million
Speaker 4:  number is Microsoft sells 20 million of the Xbox
Speaker 4:  Series consoles and they're like, this is a great
Speaker 4:  business. We sell a ton of games, people love this thing. We should buy Activision
Speaker 4:  because people are buying games and subscribing to Xbox Live. And
Speaker 4:  they're right. They, they monetize that so well Meta is like the new people
Speaker 4:  who buy this aren't even like using it as much. So that entire
Speaker 4:  secondary ecosystem that you need to make money off of this device does not
Speaker 4:  yet exist for meta.
Speaker 5:  One thing that we've seen that they maybe are trying to expand that the Battle
Speaker 5:  royal game, what is that population one or, or maybe I I'm maybe in a different
Speaker 5:  way. Yeah they're making that free to play like games on other consoles are,
Speaker 5:  which is one approach we saw. Obviously Fortnite is the biggest example,
Speaker 5:  but that's one way that you can kind of onboard people onto it. You can say
Speaker 5:  okay look, you get the headset, you can just play it with your friends who
Speaker 5:  are playing it. You don't have to buy another thing. And then of course you
Speaker 5:  start spending money on the in-game cosmetics and
Speaker 1:  Whatnot. I think we're seeing like Meta's misunderstanding of
Speaker 1:  what their audience is. Cuz Meta's so focused on building the metaverse
Speaker 1:  and getting every single person you knows into the metaverse, they
Speaker 1:  forgot that they've just really built a really good game console and they're
Speaker 1:  in the video game business and they need to be doing what
Speaker 1:  Sony and Microsoft and Nintendo do, which is focused on making really good
Speaker 1:  games. And instead they're like, no, no, no, we're gonna go and we're gonna
Speaker 1:  do the Quest three. And yeah it'll be a little more more expensive but it's
Speaker 1:  gonna blow your socks off. And as we saw saw happen with Sega as we saw happen
Speaker 1:  with the PS three, those tend to be kind of like, if
Speaker 1:  not Boondoggles, certainly not successes. Wait
Speaker 4:  To PS three was a huge success.
Speaker 5:  Was it? They lost a lot of ground to Xbox that generation. That was the one
Speaker 5:  generation, the Xbox won, it
Speaker 4:  Still grew the market for games. Like
Speaker 1:  It grew the market F for games, but it didn't grow like
Speaker 1:  the people going and buying the PS three already owned a PS
Speaker 1:  two. It wasn't, it wasn't like a whole new audience. And Meta's right
Speaker 1:  now needs to be building a whole new audience and instead they're like, no,
Speaker 1:  no, no, we want to just go build cool hardware, which I as a hardware
Speaker 1:  lover I respect, but
Speaker 4:  Like I'm gonna make a different comparison for you. I don't think the PS
Speaker 4:  two is right comparison. And it
Speaker 5:  Got better once they revised it and made it not look like a foreman grill.
Speaker 5:  And then they started selling more when they made a slim and they made it
Speaker 5:  cheaper.
Speaker 4:  I have, I have the one that you can run Lennox on and I same, you know,
Speaker 1:  Oh man, you can kill someone with that thing. It's huge.
Speaker 4:  It's huge. It was heavy, it was hot, it was ridiculous. The whole thing.
Speaker 4:  I fine and people can argue about with me about whether PS three was a huge
Speaker 4:  success or not. Whatever. I'll make the same comparison,
Speaker 4:  the same point you're making Alex, I agree with you. The better one
Speaker 4:  is the Xbox One where Microsoft was like, here's what we did.
Speaker 4:  We made a Windows PC for your living room that you can play games on
Speaker 4:  and now we're gonna talk about how much of a Windows PC it is. By the way,
Speaker 4:  it also has an IR plaster to control your cable box. And everyone's like,
Speaker 4:  where's the games? And they're like, no, no, don't you wanna run windows
Speaker 4:  in your living room? And that was a disaster.
Speaker 1:  That's a good
Speaker 4:  Point, right? Like that's where Microsoft lost all the ground where they
Speaker 4:  had the, remember that E three where they talked about everything, the video
Speaker 4:  games,
Speaker 1:  Everybody was so mad.
Speaker 4:  People were mad except, and the people who were mad at where the people who
Speaker 4:  are mad at me, this is just show me airing old grievances. This is the best
Speaker 4:  episode for her chest ever made. I was like nothing with an i blaster ever
Speaker 4:  works and never got mad at me. You know, whatever. But that was right.
Speaker 1:  The Nvidia Shield, that first one had an IR blaster and now we're on
Speaker 1:  what? Fifth gen
Speaker 4:  Boom. And boy has the Nvidia Shield taken the world by storm. There
Speaker 5:  Will be 17 revisions of De Quest three before they kind of get it right.
Speaker 5:  Probably.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's what I'm saying is the, the exact point Alex is making, she
Speaker 4:  you're correct is when you make it a game console and you make it
Speaker 4:  great, people buy it, they love it, they're gonna play it more. When you
Speaker 4:  start to be like, it's also a general purpose computer.
Speaker 4:  And this is true the Quest two, right now, if you open it up, it wants you
Speaker 4:  to do things other than play games. It's like, sign into your Facebook account,
Speaker 4:  here's this new thing. We've, we've added multi window support.
Speaker 4:  I don't wanna do any of this stuff man. I'm just, I'm gonna play NFL
Speaker 4:  Pro era. I'm gonna be bad at being quarterback for a while and then I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  put this down and like that's all you want out of it. My PS five is not like,
Speaker 4:  oh you're interested in grand. Have you thought about opening web browser?
Speaker 4:  It's like, no, like stop. And I think this is the
Speaker 4:  challenge that Meta has with the Quest two, which they're trying to
Speaker 4:  expand, but going Quest two to Quest, read a Quest Pro, it's a
Speaker 4:  replacement for your laptop. This is the next generation of computing devices.
Speaker 4:  I I think it's a bigger gap because people like, they
Speaker 4:  think that games machines are an appliance. Yeah. Right? They're
Speaker 4:  even if the chips and some of the software is all the same as a general
Speaker 4:  purpose computer, they're still like appliances and that they are supposed
Speaker 4:  to do a job and then you're supposed to go away. Now I know there's people
Speaker 4:  right there right now talking, they're like already they're in
Speaker 4:  chat Chief PT being like, write an angry email about my Windows PC that I
Speaker 4:  play games on. I understand. I'm just saying that these devices,
Speaker 1:  It's Tom Warren. Tom Warren is doing that at Sweet Speed,
Speaker 5:  But what, what do they have lined up after that? So, so where do we go from
Speaker 5:  there? I guess we, we've got years of, of data of what, what meta is going
Speaker 5:  to do. What, what do they do next after the de quests
Speaker 4:  Three. So that's the Quest line, that's the VR side of this, right? They're
Speaker 4:  gonna Quest three and then at some point there's a new Quest
Speaker 4:  Pro they talked about they that's a, that that's like a weird product. I
Speaker 4:  think they gotta figure that out. They didn't talk about that very much.
Speaker 4:  The real stuff and this is like the battle with Apple that's
Speaker 4:  coming is the AR glasses. So we are expecting
Speaker 4:  some sort of mixed reality headset from Apple this year
Speaker 4:  and we're expecting a virtual reality headset with cameras. It does pass
Speaker 4:  through. That's mixed reality. Very expensive.
Speaker 4:  $3,000 an app from Apple Developer tool. I think we're expecting it around
Speaker 4:  wwc, this is the rumor, I don't know anything about this. This is what the
Speaker 4:  people say Meta is doing something very different. So in
Speaker 4:  2025 they're gonna release a new set of smart glasses. Like the, like the
Speaker 4:  ones they've already released with Ray bands that just sort of like have
Speaker 4:  a screen in them. You know, like you can get notifications.
Speaker 1:  So like what North was doing there for a while before they got sucked up
Speaker 1:  by the Google machine.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think the current ones, they just like take photos, they
Speaker 4:  don't like do anything. You know it's like it's got a camera in it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah all the all the, the Ray bands just take pictures and gras you took
Speaker 1:  some pictures with your,
Speaker 4:  When I think of things I trust Mark Zuckerberg with, it's putting a camera
Speaker 4:  on my face that other people can't see a hundred percent. See so the, the
Speaker 4:  next generation in 2025, we'll just have a screen in the
Speaker 4:  lens and you'll be able to get notifications like
Speaker 4:  the, they called it a view finder. You like incoming text messages, scan
Speaker 4:  QR codes, translate text from one thing to another. This is like everyone's
Speaker 4:  favorite demo.
Speaker 1:  And what's the other thing they're gonna have?
Speaker 4:  They're gonna have a smartwatch that controls it
Speaker 4:  using a neural interface, which is tech that meta has had
Speaker 4:  and that they have demoed before Addie has seen this technology. She loves
Speaker 4:  it. She thinks it's so cool. She was very worried when Meta's gonna last.
Speaker 4:  They're gonna get rid of this. But they're betting on it that instead of
Speaker 4:  this thing right now where there's a bunch of cameras on a headset and you
Speaker 4:  like wave your hands around and do pinching motions, they're gonna be able
Speaker 4:  to put a a like a smart watch on your wrist that will detect what your hand
Speaker 4:  is doing. Which is, it's just cool. Like they have the technology, they've
Speaker 4:  demoed it well
Speaker 1:  They were gonna do the watch for a while and then the watch got killed. Cuz
Speaker 1:  everybody was like, nobody wants a Facebook branded smartwatch
Speaker 1:  on their wrist. Even if it does do the neural stuff.
Speaker 4:  The entire underlying thing here, not to make this whole thing about Apple,
Speaker 4:  but the entire underlying thing here is Mark Zuckerberg knows
Speaker 4:  that his company is at Apple's Mercy. And we've seen
Speaker 4:  it now several times. Like Apple pulls a security certificate, all of Facebook's
Speaker 4:  internal systems stop working. Apple decides it wants ad tracking transparency
Speaker 4:  puts up the prompt. People say no, Facebook's business goes away.
Speaker 4:  Mark Zuckerberg knows he's at the mercy of apples. So if you wanna make a
Speaker 4:  smartwatch and you're like, you cannot reply any texts on it on your
Speaker 4:  phone like you're done for, there's a reason there are no competitive
Speaker 4:  smartwatches on iOS because Apple restricts all the good
Speaker 4:  capabilities to its own platform. Fine. We argue about
Speaker 4:  that, that whether or not that's right Elizabeth Warren is gonna like jump
Speaker 4:  through a wall like the Kool-Aid man screaming about interrupt whatever.
Speaker 4:  Mark Zuckerberg knows that this is the current state of things. So he's gotta
Speaker 4:  build a new platform. Yeah. And so building a wa a smartwatch that's like
Speaker 4:  still dependent Apple. I don't think he's interested in that. So he is like,
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna build a headset. The headset, you're gonna live in the headset,
Speaker 4:  you're gonna brain in a vat, you're gonna post Instagram all day. I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  read your thoughts and we're going to move your laptop into this headset
Speaker 4:  and now I've got this smartwatch that is the control surface for the headset
Speaker 4:  instead of doing camera-based keyboard stuff or
Speaker 4:  controller based stuff. I think this is the coolest idea they have because
Speaker 4:  everything we know about Apple is that Apple is gonna do the camera-based,
Speaker 4:  you know, pinch in the air situation. Now it's Apple.
Speaker 4:  They'll probably do a better job than what we've seen in the past, but that's
Speaker 4:  what we know so far. So that is the coolest part is like they're gonna do
Speaker 4:  these smart glasses, they're not AR glasses, just sunglasses or the screen
Speaker 4:  that do notifications and then this control system, well
Speaker 1:  They'll have a view finder, they'll, they'll have like that, that limited
Speaker 1:  range that is already capable of in other
Speaker 1:  glasses. Because I think that's the thing that I keep getting focused on
Speaker 1:  in with ar, we all have our little bits where we're like, AR can't happen
Speaker 1:  until this happens because there's so much stuff that has to happen first.
Speaker 1:  And for me, I always get hung up on the like, how are you gonna use these?
Speaker 1:  What's, what's the, what's the technology behind the sway? And
Speaker 1:  in this case it sounds like they're gonna be using kind of robust
Speaker 1:  technology that already exists, which is those little like tiny
Speaker 1:  lasers in reflective, the whole reflective apparatus
Speaker 1:  that North does.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, we'll see, just to like define the terms here again, when we talk about
Speaker 4:  ar, it's, I think what you and I are talking about is
Speaker 4:  you look through a pair of glasses, you have like perfect field of view.
Speaker 4:  The glasses, see that you're looking at a tree and you get like the little
Speaker 4:  label that's like pine tree, right? Yeah. By the way, huge problems with
Speaker 4:  this. Especially if you live in the world of Facebook content moderation.
Speaker 4:  Imagine that you're standing Washington DC and you're looking at the capitol
Speaker 4:  building who gets to label the capitol building what happened at the
Speaker 4:  capitol building, any notable events that your uncle on
Speaker 4:  Facebook might like to notate around that building
Speaker 4:  the content moderation nightmare to end all content moderation.
Speaker 4:  Nightmares.
Speaker 1:  I just got like tired thinking about it.
Speaker 4:  It's exhausting and no one's ready for it. Who will, who will augment reality?
Speaker 4:  A real question that's a real headline we should put on the site, but that's
Speaker 4:  like the holy grail, like Mark Zuckerberg is called this holy grail I, I've
Speaker 4:  said this a a million times in the show. If I could just remember people's
Speaker 4:  names, I'd be the King of America that you couldn't stop me. Unstoppable,
Speaker 4:  charming, a charm. The dedication, the memory that I, I remember your
Speaker 4:  kid's names. I'd be like an unstoppable politician as it
Speaker 4:  stands. I can't remember, I can't remember anyone's names. So all of you
Speaker 4:  are safe for my reign of tear. But these glasses, the problem is you
Speaker 4:  have to build a worldwide facial recognition database to enable that feature.
Speaker 4:  Again, not something I'm sure we want Mark Zuckerberg to
Speaker 1:  Do. I think he's already done it, but yeah.
Speaker 4:  Well I'll be unstoppable. Yeah, you, you can't touch me.
Speaker 1:  Who cares about privacy? I know who all of you are, I know
Speaker 1:  your names
Speaker 4:  But Patel, this is like an interim step. Like that's the dream
Speaker 4:  and that's what we think Apple is building towards. This is like, it's a
Speaker 4:  pair of sunglasses and it's got a little display in it.
Speaker 1:  It's like Google Glass display.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's a little monitor in your glasses and it, it can do things like
Speaker 4:  show you a notification and it sounds like it'll have a camera still.
Speaker 4:  So it can do things like take a picture of a sign in a foreign
Speaker 4:  language and then like show you what that text means. It does not appear
Speaker 4:  that they're talking about you can overlay or augment reality
Speaker 4:  with that screen. Right? We don't quite know. But it doesn't seem like
Speaker 4:  that's the case. Which is interesting because Apple's product is that thing.
Speaker 4:  They're gonna jump right there this year and this Facebook smart glasses
Speaker 4:  is 2025 now Facebook is then gonna do its first true pair of
Speaker 4:  AR glasses code named Orion internal launch in
Speaker 4:  2024. So next year and then a public version in 2027.
Speaker 4:  So we'll see. That's a long way out from Apple.
Speaker 5:  And this is what we're talking about, like it overlays holograms onto the
Speaker 5:  real world, like the demos that that Mark showed off.
Speaker 1:  No, cuz cuz Apple's thing, Apple's still doing pass through. The problem
Speaker 1:  is nobody's figured out the display technology to actually do ar.
Speaker 1:  So the hack right now is to be like, look like a
Speaker 1:  wiener, wear a giant headset on your face and the cameras will pass it through
Speaker 1:  and process the information. So like that's Apple's plan
Speaker 1:  for the foreseeable future. And no, you're not seeing, the thing is there's
Speaker 1:  not a lot of movement in the display technology space to suggest that something
Speaker 1:  cooler is on their horizon, right? Like you would normally hear little
Speaker 1:  trick, you'd hear little bits of that at like C graph and other places
Speaker 1:  and we're not hearing that yet. So it's just like, okay, this
Speaker 1:  big breakthrough that we need to happen for true AR hasn't happened and
Speaker 1:  everybody's like finding hacky ways into it.
Speaker 4:  Somewhere there's like a wave guide engineer listening to Alex right now,
Speaker 4:  like shaking his fist, being like, I'll show you. But
Speaker 5:  That's what they're promising with this Orion thing is that they're gonna
Speaker 5:  do these high quality holograms
Speaker 4:  In 2027. Orion will do the high quality ar
Speaker 4:  that's, that's Meta's roadmap, that's their projection for when
Speaker 4:  they'll do it, allegedly. We'll see. And they'll have an internal prototype
Speaker 4:  in 24. So next year. So between their internal prototype
Speaker 4:  and actually consumer launches on this roadmap, three years,
Speaker 5:  I'll just write a stub for the internal tests have been delayed until
Speaker 5:  2025 right now and just get that ready.
Speaker 4:  But Alex, you're right that that stack of problems is really hard, right?
Speaker 4:  If you, and, and we've gone through it many times on the show, but I'll do
Speaker 4:  it one more time. It's you need glasses on your face. The
Speaker 4:  glasses have to contain a camera, enough cameras to see the world around
Speaker 4:  you. You have to pass all the information from the camera onto a
Speaker 4:  computer that can recognize what you're looking at. Go out to the internet,
Speaker 4:  figure out what it's, what it is you're seeing, figure out what to
Speaker 4:  augment reality with, send it back to you and it will like
Speaker 4:  zero latency or process all that locally. You
Speaker 4:  need a battery that can run all this all day
Speaker 4:  and you need a display that's thin and optically transparent
Speaker 4:  enough so that they're just glasses and you're not like,
Speaker 1:  Yeah, with a large enough field of view that it feels like
Speaker 1:  reality's being augmented and a post stamp isn't.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, this is not a solved problem. Like every part of
Speaker 4:  that is 0% solved, well maybe not zero.
Speaker 4:  Every part of that is way less than 50% solved. Like even the part where
Speaker 4:  it's like you want to go out to the cloud computing center and
Speaker 4:  like identify the tree and send it back to you at zero latency. That was
Speaker 4:  the whole point of 5g. And like, does
Speaker 4:  anyone wanna trust that to the current state of 5G networks?
Speaker 4:  I was in New York City last week. I pulled 35 down on at and t 5G plus.
Speaker 4:  Ooh, you were not allowed to augment reality. Like that is just, it's already
Speaker 4:  a horrible experience.
Speaker 5:  There's something coming for that. Stay tuned. We, we will have, we will
Speaker 5:  have a report. There's something coming that, that may be like 40% solved.
Speaker 4:  The 5G
Speaker 5:  Part? No, the the latency part. It's, it, it's not 5g unfortunately, which
Speaker 5:  did not do what we promised.
Speaker 4:  Is it Comcast 10 G?
Speaker 5:  Maybe
Speaker 5:  it's not, not Comcast 10 G
Speaker 4:  Disclosure, NBC Universalist and Investor in VMedia. Our
Speaker 4:  parent company Comcast owns nbc. They don't love me.
Speaker 4:  Comcast been super thirsty with the 10 G marketing lately. Have
Speaker 4:  you noticed this?
Speaker 5:  Yes. It's And 10 G if you were wondering what it stands for, it is more than
Speaker 5:  5g.
Speaker 1:  Skip for
Speaker 4:  It ahead. You know you love the convenience of the mobile internet.
Speaker 4:  Have you thought about faster internet with wires? It's good. I'll
Speaker 4:  take it. I'll take it Liam, I think Are you upgrading to, to two gig
Speaker 4:  internet home? I know you're talking about it.
Speaker 8:  Still thinking
Speaker 4:  About it the second I can, I'm doing it. I don't care what you say.
Speaker 8:  I can't even use all of what I have now, but I kind of wanna be a monster
Speaker 8:  and just say I have a two gigabit internet connection.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Do you know how many horsepower your car actually needs? It's like
Speaker 4:  50. Has that stopped anyone in America?
Speaker 5:  When you look at the horsepower of cars from the nineties, like what a probe
Speaker 5:  turbo came with compared to what everything has now.
Speaker 5:  It's like a joke. But I, I recently cut the cord. I, I got in touch with
Speaker 5:  Comcast and they had to kick TiVo one more time on the way out. I asked them
Speaker 5:  what I needed to do with my cable card and they said, oh, we don't, we don't
Speaker 5:  get a lot of questions about those.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Wow. You saw the cable card. What was your cable
Speaker 4:  card plugged into
Speaker 5:  A TiVo.
Speaker 4:  Oh man. This is is like the greatest hits vergecast right now. We've
Speaker 4:  dunked on Windows Mobile,
Speaker 4:  got TiVo on the show. Richard's debugging and a cable card
Speaker 4:  that was super right about when mobile. I just wanna put that out. I are
Speaker 4:  blasters.
Speaker 1:  We're gonna talk about boxing next. Let's go.
Speaker 4:  We gotta take a break. We're gonna come back. We gotta talk about Elon. We
Speaker 4:  gotta talk about ai. There's, there's still much to discuss and we're gonna
Speaker 4:  do it all by controlling the British cast with our, our neural smart bands.
Speaker 9:  It's late. You're almost home after catching that concert you and your friend
Speaker 9:  snag tickets to with MX months ago. You're all speechless from the last
Speaker 9:  hour spent singing your hearts out. And the only thing playing in the car
Speaker 9:  is the last song of the night on a full blast in your head.
Speaker 9:  Admit it. You want it stuck there. The live version you can't get
Speaker 9:  anywhere else. Looks like you're getting goosebumps all over again.
Speaker 9:  When the Knight's a hit, that's when you're with amex. American Express.
Speaker 9:  Don't live life without it.
Speaker 10:  The world looks different behind the handlebars of a rat Electric lake.
Speaker 10:  Grabbing takeout looks less like greasy styrofoam boxes and more like
Speaker 10:  a cross town adventure ride shares look less like piling into the back
Speaker 10:  of a car and more like grabbing fresh air with your friends and
Speaker 10:  commuting can even start to look like the best part of your day.
Speaker 10:  That's because with Rad the world is what you make of it. Not what it makes
Speaker 10:  of you see for yourself with a 14 day free trial. Find
Speaker 10:  your fun@radpowerbikes.com.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. We've promised Liam and ourselves that we
Speaker 4:  will get through this week in Elon quickly so we can talk about
Speaker 4:  ai.
Speaker 1:  This is self-care.
Speaker 4:  This is self-care. There's a lot of Elon news but kind of like
Speaker 4:  none of it matters. Like I don't know how else to describe that
Speaker 1:  Alex. I think on, on the clock of Alex winning her bet
Speaker 1:  against Monica and Liz, I think I'm, I'm
Speaker 1:  much closer to winning the bad now cuz he, he was doing
Speaker 1:  some like a plus shit posting this week.
Speaker 4:  He was tweeting, replies to people arguing about the war in Ukraine
Speaker 4:  during Tesla Investor Day. He was backstage
Speaker 4:  at his own investor day replying to randos on Twitter.
Speaker 1:  I'm just saying, I'm so sorry it's gonna happen. I'm gonna get a coffee
Speaker 1:  and a bottle of champagne and the rest of you are just gonna have some nightmares
Speaker 1:  in your head forever.
Speaker 4:  I very much like not acknowledging what the be is. People can just guess
Speaker 4:  what it is. You can guess it's fine. All right, let's go through the Elon
Speaker 4:  headlines. He laid off more people over the weekend, including Esther
Speaker 4:  Crawford, who is a woman who very famously was sleeping on the ground and
Speaker 4:  was gonna be like the head of Twitter blues product. She got laid off along
Speaker 4:  with a bunch of other founders from companies Twitter had acquired who had
Speaker 4:  accelerating vesting schedules, bigger payouts because of their stock and
Speaker 4:  so on. More cleaning house. He apologized, he said it was
Speaker 4:  necessary Twitter financially quite dicey. Like we don't know
Speaker 4:  what's going on there. There's a lot of rumors that he's picked a new ceo,
Speaker 4:  the ceo Esther Crawford slept on the floor by herself in Sleeping Bag.
Speaker 4:  The guy, they think it'll be the new CEO Twitter, he just moved in with his
Speaker 4:  wife and newborn baby and is sleeping there. Oof. So that's
Speaker 4:  the level of commitment that Elon's looking for is does your family sleep
Speaker 4:  here as well? We'll see. Twitter has gone down a lot recently.
Speaker 4:  It's been very slow. Errors are spiking. The main timeline just like
Speaker 4:  didn't work this week. Twitter also shut off its internal slack and
Speaker 4:  employees went over a day without working. Just all fully
Speaker 4:  ridiculous. Then all the things that we thought would happen
Speaker 4:  when Elon bought Twitter have like started to happen. And I don't
Speaker 4:  mean the, he fired everybody and the site's not reliable. We didn't actually
Speaker 4:  predict that part of it. We predicted a bunch of moderation, crises and that
Speaker 4:  is beginning to happen as well. So there was a report under the Department
Speaker 4:  of Energy that the Department of Energy with low confidence has Deduced
Speaker 4:  has decided that Covid leaked out of a lab in Wuhan
Speaker 4:  China. That's obviously, there's discrepancy with what the Department of
Speaker 4:  Energy thinks compared other parts of the government. This is an ongoing
Speaker 4:  debate in a scientific community. Elon tweets about it
Speaker 4:  gets reprimanded in Chinese state media that says don't bite the hands
Speaker 4:  that Fiji in using a Chinese idiom. There's a huge problem. Freelan
Speaker 4:  China is a huge market for Tesla. Like he's gotta keep that in
Speaker 4:  check or leave China, right? Like the same way that, I dunno, the
Speaker 4:  NBA gets in trouble for Cow Island in China. Like Elon's got the same problem
Speaker 4:  only now he owns Twitter and he's addicted to it and he loves owning the
Speaker 4:  lips. This is the problem.
Speaker 1:  He has no one to just say no before that it was the moderators
Speaker 1:  at Twitter and he fired them
Speaker 5:  All. Well he had a response to the s e c. He, he like, he wanted to try and
Speaker 5:  make up a little acronym for them and he's, he's complained and complained
Speaker 5:  and complained about their restrictions on his tweeting. I feel like that's
Speaker 5:  not gonna go over well with the Chinese government.
Speaker 4:  Feel like it's not gonna go over well with the Chinese government. So that's
Speaker 4:  Twitter. So just escalating chaos at Twitter, including now some of the problems
Speaker 4:  that we thought we would see. And then there's investor day
Speaker 4:  which was, we are recording this on Thursday. You're listening to it on Friday.
Speaker 4:  We all watched investor day on Wednesday night. It was very long. It was
Speaker 4:  four hours long. I will say Elon's deputies at Tesla
Speaker 4:  by and large, all very polished, all very put together, very committed, very
Speaker 4:  passionate Elon looking like he just showed up off the street like
Speaker 4:  just ram like rambling. Like they kept dragging him out there to be like,
Speaker 4:  not Elon's gonna talk about robots. And he'd be like, here's a render of
Speaker 4:  optimist. And he'd say something like, yeah I think it's pretty important
Speaker 4:  this could change the economy. And then he would look off into the distance
Speaker 4:  and say, what does economy even mean? And then everyone would politely clap
Speaker 4:  and then they would like bring out the head of supply chain to be like, here's
Speaker 4:  how we're gonna make more cars. But overall it was four hours they announced
Speaker 4:  nothing new. Right. And there's no, they hinted at the new
Speaker 4:  platform. I never thought we were gonna see it. They hinted at cheaper cars.
Speaker 4:  I never thought we were gonna see it, but we didn't see it. And the stock
Speaker 4:  price collapsed.
Speaker 5:  It sounded to me like a long presentation of Elon's people
Speaker 5:  telling investors why they're going to need a lot more money for the next
Speaker 5:  period. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I got some of that vibe. You know, there was something really interesting.
Speaker 4:  So Tesla is very innovative as a company and like the way they
Speaker 4:  design package and build cars is new and
Speaker 4:  novel, right? This core argument they're making, which is that a big car
Speaker 4:  company like a GM or Ford or whoever is, or VW is like
Speaker 4:  their job is to go buy parts from lots of suppliers and they integrate all
Speaker 4:  the the parts and there's like so many parts in the car and that's why they're
Speaker 4:  hard to upgrade over the air and all this stuff. Like all that is a hundred
Speaker 4:  percent true. It's just that was the argument at the beginning of Tesla.
Speaker 4:  That was the argument when the model three was coming out, right? We're we're
Speaker 4:  now making a mass market car. We've designed and built it from the ground
Speaker 4:  up. We are using less computers, less supplier
Speaker 4:  computers in the in the car. We are designing the manufacturing in the same
Speaker 4:  time as like this is all to me, this is all very familiar
Speaker 4:  to the Tesla story we've heard for years. It's also really familiar to the
Speaker 4:  story of every other kind of high-end ev startup
Speaker 4:  that we are now familiar with. Like when you go hang out with Rivian,
Speaker 4:  they tell you a story about how traditional car makers are lazy and they
Speaker 4:  don't realize the cars are computers. None. Like there was just a weirdness
Speaker 4:  to Tesla restating their core value proposition
Speaker 4:  in that way because it's the mar for the larger part of the market.
Speaker 4:  This is always what they've been investing in, right? It's Tesla makes better
Speaker 4:  cars cuz it designs them differently and it's more, much
Speaker 4:  more of a computer company than a car company. But we are now at the
Speaker 4:  point where Ford is like, we've done it like we split ourselves into two
Speaker 4:  divisions and we're gonna act this way too. Like there was just something
Speaker 4:  weird there. I was like, it's weird to see Tesla repeating itself.
Speaker 1:  Well and I think this was, this kind of reinforced a lot of investors
Speaker 1:  fear that he was spending too much time with Twitter and not enough time.
Speaker 4:  Cause he was tweeting during the investor day.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And so he, and then he was like, he, like I think Elon has definitely
Speaker 1:  gotten to a point where he has forgotten that actually he does owe people
Speaker 1:  things he does just because he is the richest man in the world on paper.
Speaker 1:  Well, not anymore. Oh,
Speaker 4:  He
Speaker 1:  Is again, is he again, he's back. He's got a lot of other people that he
Speaker 1:  has obligations to. And I think he keeps forgetting that because he's like,
Speaker 1:  oh, I got a tweet and it's real important. Yeah. And, and the investors kind
Speaker 1:  of reminded him.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I I think there's a real world in which any one of the
Speaker 4:  deputies we saw at Tesla yesterday, he could say, you're the CEO now.
Speaker 4:  And that might be a good thing. The same way like when Shotwell is a, the
Speaker 4:  C SpaceX but very much in charge of SpaceX. He doesn't have that person
Speaker 4:  at Tesla. He does not have that person at Twitter delegating hot
Speaker 4:  management tip fresh from decoder. You should sometimes delegate some things.
Speaker 4:  He didn't roll out the new master plan. It is about renewable
Speaker 4:  energy. It's not really about building cars. He wants to increase the world's
Speaker 4:  energy storage capacity. They have some new ideas about battery
Speaker 4:  technology. Elon, he's like, this will need substantially less than
Speaker 4:  30% of all nickel on earth. Which is an incredible thing to say.
Speaker 4:  It's just good. It's like, yeah, you know, I have a plan, don't worry.
Speaker 4:  It'll be less than 30% of all nickel on the planet. It's like,
Speaker 4:  yeah, you should, you should set your goals high. And then they talked a
Speaker 4:  lot about just in general manufacturing more efficiently. And then they did
Speaker 4:  spend some time talking about full self-driving and how they think
Speaker 4:  they get full self-driving out the door. The cars will be taxis, the cars
Speaker 4:  will be in service more often. They'll be driving themselves around making
Speaker 4:  money for you while you're sleeping. And that will go a long way to sustainability.
Speaker 4:  That was the part of the whole presentation where I was like, what are the
Speaker 4:  car? No, like, we're a long way from there,
Speaker 4:  like as far away from that as we are from optimists.
Speaker 5:  And you've already promised it and didn't deliver it for several years. Right?
Speaker 5:  We, we've heard it.
Speaker 1:  I'm just thinking of the day where like, you forget you left something in
Speaker 1:  your car and you send your car out to be an Uber and like
Speaker 1:  your, your laptop's in there, your child something, your
Speaker 4:  Your
Speaker 1:  Child. I don't know. I don't have a kid. I assume people sometimes forget
Speaker 1:  them in their cars. Look,
Speaker 4:  If you get my car and Max is in it, it's actually the rates goes up.
Speaker 4:  She's very entertaining. She happily sing you any song
Speaker 4:  from Encanto you want while you're on your way to your destination.
Speaker 1:  She's the mc for the ride. She's got a little
Speaker 1:  like bowler hat on. She's like, welcome.
Speaker 4:  She'll tell you any number of jokes about butts. She's very funny, very into
Speaker 4:  them. She's four. And yeah, I just, the the whole thing I think kind of
Speaker 4:  landed with a thought. It landed with a thought with the, the Tesla fanboys
Speaker 4:  who were expecting the c u car and, and said, got very long
Speaker 4:  explanations of like assembly efficiency in
Speaker 4:  factories.
Speaker 5:  And some of 'em couldn't get into the event with the whole Mars blog guy.
Speaker 5:  Like there were people who were supposed to be able to be there who suddenly
Speaker 5:  couldn't.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But then they tweeted Elon, they got in
Speaker 5:  Of course, because customer service is what he does now.
Speaker 4:  That's his whole job. So that's Tesla. There's some other AI news
Speaker 4:  this week that I wanna talk briefly. There's this new filter on TikTok that
Speaker 4:  Jess weathered and me, as Satya wrote about, it's called Bold Glamor. So
Speaker 4:  normally a new filter on TikTok, not a huge news mode. These are really interesting
Speaker 4:  for two reasons. One, TikTok rolled out a new set of tools for filter
Speaker 4:  creators that use AI tools that in
Speaker 4:  particular gns, generative adversarial networks. We've covered these a
Speaker 4:  lot on the site. Basically point to networks as each other and make them
Speaker 4:  fight. So what this thing is doing is, is actually
Speaker 4:  replacing faces. So before TikTok
Speaker 4:  would like make a 3D model of your face, layer the fake eyebrows on
Speaker 4:  it, and then layer that over your face so you could break it really easily.
Speaker 4:  It was very obvious that this is a filter. This is actually replacing
Speaker 4:  your face.
Speaker 1:  So it's like deep faking you with hotter
Speaker 4:  You. And it, it's, it's like smart in like uncanny ways. So
Speaker 4:  it knows a more feminine face from a more masculine face on more
Speaker 4:  feminine faces. It puts like loads of eye makeup and contouring on my
Speaker 4:  face. It just like smooths my skin. It makes my jawline straighter.
Speaker 4:  Which is really annoying because I look amazing in eye makeup. Just give
Speaker 4:  it to me just like, let me have it
Speaker 1:  Like eyeliner improves all faces.
Speaker 4:  I look fucking amazing an eyeliner and TikTok won't let me have it. It's
Speaker 4:  very annoying. So Jess and Mia wrote about it. They talked to some
Speaker 4:  experts in the field. It's obviously gn. And we assumed
Speaker 4:  that TikTok were just like happily confirmed this information. They
Speaker 4:  rolled out the filter tools, they rolled out the first party filters. People
Speaker 4:  are going crazy for 'em. It's fairly obvious what's happening here. It
Speaker 4:  is very impressive. I encourage you to go try it. And TikTok is silent for
Speaker 4:  a full week. Just like, won't even respond to the emails why, like,
Speaker 4:  why It's, it's utterly bizarre. And then when you started
Speaker 4:  looking around at the other media coverage and Fox News is out there being
Speaker 4:  like, this is psychological warfare on young women. NBC News
Speaker 4:  called it terrifying. And it's like, oh they TikTok just doesn't
Speaker 4:  want anyone. Like they're already in so much trouble and people wanna ban
Speaker 4:  TikTok so bad that they're out there being like we've created deep fake filters
Speaker 4:  that put makeup on young women. Like they're gonna get kicked outta the country
Speaker 4:  even faster. It's like totally weird corner of the culture war.
Speaker 1:  It's super, because these filters have been pretty common for a while
Speaker 1:  now, right? Like the, the filters that make people slightly more pretty.
Speaker 1:  Chi China's doing doing that for years. Your phone, if you bought a ch phone
Speaker 1:  in China and you took a photo of yourself with it, a lot of times you'd be
Speaker 1:  like, oh, I didn't remember I put on an eyeliner today cuz the pH the phone
Speaker 1:  would just add it for you. So this is like very, very common
Speaker 1:  in other cultures, in other places and in America
Speaker 1:  where suddenly everybody, everybody is now thinking about this in a way that
Speaker 1:  a lot of places, particularly Fox News wouldn't normally think.
Speaker 1:  Fox News is not really the place I go for really
Speaker 1:  insightful commentary on representation of gender.
Speaker 4:  No,
Speaker 1:  Just not, not my, not my first stop. And now they're like, yeah, it's a culture.
Speaker 1:  They're we're being destroyed from the inside. I was like, well welcome to
Speaker 1:  the struggle. Have you looked at your own desks yet?
Speaker 4:  There has been a lot of coverage on on the right and I'm trying my best
Speaker 4:  to ex it's, I'm trying, there has been a lot of
Speaker 4:  coverage on both sides about social media and young women in
Speaker 4:  particular. A hundred percent like recent coverage about the depression and
Speaker 4:  like this is part of it, right? Yeah. Is people see the filters. I
Speaker 4:  think the filters are reality or they wanna look more like the filter. There's
Speaker 4:  been a wave of plastic surgeries to look more against. Random filters are
Speaker 4:  all real and now you've got a filter that doesn't even look fake. Right?
Speaker 4:  It looks super real.
Speaker 5:  That that's the difference here, I think. And why it has struck people here
Speaker 5:  is that it actually works really well.
Speaker 4:  You have to decide what working means.
Speaker 5:  I I didn't say it's good. It just works.
Speaker 4:  Right? It works well and that the thing it's doing to replace your face
Speaker 4:  is impressive. The actual like makeup
Speaker 4:  look on some people is great. On some people is fine and some
Speaker 4:  people looks bonkers. Yeah. And so Jess, you know, like it's her photo at
Speaker 4:  the top of our story. She's like, this makes me look like a troll. Like I
Speaker 4:  hate the way this looks on me. The thing is that it just looks very real.
Speaker 4:  And I that's, I think there's a, there's an entire tech
Speaker 4:  culture verge story in there that has been distorted into
Speaker 4:  the, this is Alex's point that has been distorted into the Fox News headline
Speaker 4:  of this is Psychological Warfare.
Speaker 5:  And it does, it does look like a person who's had contoured and heavy makeup
Speaker 5:  on, but it looks like an actual person's face even though it really doesn't
Speaker 5:  look very much like your real face is looking at all.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like if I could contour as well as this thing does,
Speaker 1:  I would be a makeup artist.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. But I can't, I see it won't even, it won't even let me see what
Speaker 4:  would I look like?
Speaker 1:  It's always creepy when you, when you do get that that contouring the really
Speaker 1:  heavy stuff that like Kim Kardashian is super known for, like
Speaker 1:  she was kind of popularized that type of contouring. You're like,
Speaker 1:  am I a witch? What's happened here?
Speaker 4:  What's my
Speaker 1:  Face is different. People go oh, and you're like, is it a good o
Speaker 1:  is it a bad O And this just lets you do it without having to
Speaker 1:  like spend hundreds of dollars at Sephora.
Speaker 4:  It doesn't let me do it. You keep talking about it. Like I can, it
Speaker 5:  Won't even run on my phone. It won't run on the pixel.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It only runs on iPhones. Right? It's, there's a lot going on here.
Speaker 4:  Like I said, it's a very vergie story and the amazing thing about it right,
Speaker 4:  is we're talking about something that it's base level is just a really cool
Speaker 4:  piece of tech, right? Whether or not it's the technology is being pointed
Speaker 4:  at do contouring or whatever else. It might be the
Speaker 4:  underlying in real time we're doing generative
Speaker 4:  adversarial networks to remap your face
Speaker 4:  at a frame rate that is close enough for video. That's cool. And then
Speaker 4:  it's the culture war is just come for it to the point where TikTok won't
Speaker 4:  even talk about the technology because the, the culture wars I gotta control.
Speaker 4:  So that one is the one we're, we're tracking. Speaking of Mia, right as
Speaker 4:  we came on air, we have talked a lot about CNET and the use
Speaker 4:  of AI to write SEO spam. Basically
Speaker 4:  we, I feel like I can just condense that story into what's happening. It's
Speaker 4:  a very complicated story but Right. They're using AI tools to write
Speaker 4:  SEO spam articles to get you to sign for credit cards. Natural results of
Speaker 4:  that CNET today laid off 10% of its ma,
Speaker 4:  which is really bad. I mean we, these are people we know, these are, these
Speaker 4:  are our competitors. I don't like it. But you can see this thing is
Speaker 4:  happening where we've talked a lot about AI in the context of Google. It's
Speaker 4:  like CNET turning into the AI content form. Yeah. First they're just gonna,
Speaker 4:  the private equity company, right? Ventures, they're gonna gut cnet, right?
Speaker 4:  But they're gonna point the automated tools at winning Google
Speaker 4:  search terms until Google is forced to contend with it. Cuz that's, that's
Speaker 4:  the money. And then right as we're coming on air here,
Speaker 4:  Mia broke the story that the editor-in-chief of CNET
Speaker 4:  is stepping down and becoming the AI content
Speaker 4:  head of the,
Speaker 1:  Hmm. That's brutal.
Speaker 4:  It's sad folks. I don't, I don't love it. I don't like it.
Speaker 4:  This is the future. I hope you enjoy the vergecast because
Speaker 4:  soon it will just be chatbots or doing with each other about our hair
Speaker 4:  blasters
Speaker 1:  That happened to someone on our staff this week. They didn't realize
Speaker 1:  that they had, I believe it was Otter AI activated
Speaker 1:  and it joined a meeting for them that they couldn't attend and just started
Speaker 1:  like chatting at everybody in the meeting. And everybody's like, why are
Speaker 1:  they ignoring us? And, and not not talking to us. And they just accidentally
Speaker 1:  activated some sort of AI chatbot to show up to a work
Speaker 1:  meeting.
Speaker 4:  This is my dream is it. Soon all of our meetings will just be our chatbots
Speaker 4:  talking to each other
Speaker 1:  And they come back to us with, with like, here's what everybody discussed.
Speaker 1:  Nothing actually happened. You still have to go slack with each other.
Speaker 4:  So like most meetings,
Speaker 4:  just to be clear, most meetings in corporate America are exactly
Speaker 4:  that thing. Bing on the other side, Microsoft's
Speaker 4:  added some personality tools to bing. I think there's been a real, I
Speaker 4:  dunno how you two feel about this. So I'm curious. There has been a real
Speaker 4:  reckoning of whether Bing is actually a replacement for search
Speaker 4:  or it's just a thing that various very smart tech writers wanna
Speaker 4:  smooch.
Speaker 5:  I finally got access to it unfortunately after they, they nuked
Speaker 5:  the personality a bit and I used it. I, there was something I was looking
Speaker 5:  up and I knew that I wasn't gonna be able to Google it very well. I, I've
Speaker 5:  used Google a lot, I can tell when it's gonna give me an answer or not. And
Speaker 5:  I decided to search in Google and also in Bing. And
Speaker 5:  neither one gave me the answer that I wanted. The answer, the summary response
Speaker 5:  that Bing eventually gave me was decent. It was decently written, it was
Speaker 5:  easy to read, but it didn't have the information I was looking for. And it
Speaker 5:  was slow. By the time it actually popped up, I had done three Google searches
Speaker 5:  and you know, it was kind of closer to getting the kind of question that
Speaker 5:  I wanted. So no, it, I don't think it's there yet as a search
Speaker 5:  replacement.
Speaker 1:  It's improved versus chat. G P T cuz in both of 'em, I just asked
Speaker 1:  who I was and chat. G P T was like, she works at Laptop Magazine
Speaker 1:  and I was like, oh, that's a while back folks. That's a while back. And,
Speaker 1:  and like the Bing one gave me a much, it was like, oh, it made me sound fancy.
Speaker 1:  I felt very great for a day. But, but it still struggles with like
Speaker 1:  the searches I do want. Like if I'm thinking about oh I want like what's
Speaker 1:  the best kind of pants or whatever, I don't, I don't wanna go and search
Speaker 1:  that on Google cause it's all SEO spam and Bing's not helping
Speaker 1:  because it's still seems to be based on Bing search results.
Speaker 1:  And I've been trying to use Bing just to like experience
Speaker 1:  the magic boy. It's not magical. Like just
Speaker 1:  the straight ahead Bing search engines real
Speaker 5:  Bad. So they integrated Bing with Windows 11 now and it's really just a button
Speaker 5:  on your search bar that when you click it, it shows you the news widget that
Speaker 5:  you were already ignoring. And then you click Bing again and it opens up
Speaker 5:  edge to the same Bing chat app that everyone else has. It, it's just a button
Speaker 5:  that that's what they did.
Speaker 4:  Here's my idea for Bing. They should stop pretending that it's
Speaker 4:  a search engine and just let it be a dating sim. Just let
Speaker 4:  people date Bing. People pay for Tinder Gold. Be like it's eight bucks
Speaker 4:  a month and you're dating it now.
Speaker 1:  It will not go with you to the wedding this weekend.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's your girlfriend from Niagara Falls. Just like, it's fine.
Speaker 1:  But it will find someone on Craigslist to go to the wedding
Speaker 1:  with you this weekend.
Speaker 5:  Just to complete the Windows Mobile Nokia
Speaker 5:  Triangle. I agree with Steven Kovski. That's basically what he said.
Speaker 4:  Wait, Steven OVS said people should be allowed to date Bing.
Speaker 5:  Not in so many words. He, he said that they should consider these things,
Speaker 5:  features not bugs and just let it go do that and stop trying to challenge
Speaker 5:  Google as a search engine. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But that the money is in search that this is the problem. Like the business
Speaker 4:  model that Nadela is excited about is taking any dollars away from Google
Speaker 4:  search and everyone else is like, what if you could kiss it and like,
Speaker 4:  there's not as much money there,
Speaker 1:  But you can make that money you
Speaker 4:  Charge. It's not the same amount of money. Like one is the, the most lucrative
Speaker 4:  business model in the history of the internet. And the other one,
Speaker 1:  The other one's a very lucrative business model for
Speaker 4:  Millennia in the history of the world in a different
Speaker 5:  Way, but not on the same scale. And, and it's one of those things that comes
Speaker 5:  up I think every time people ask about like, why is this company blocking
Speaker 5:  at olden porn content from their thing? Because it doesn't make as much money
Speaker 5:  as Google does.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's very good. Last little bits here. Sony
Speaker 4:  announced it's 2023 TV lineup. Finally. They didn't do it at ces.
Speaker 4:  Looks pretty good. New gaming menu, Alex.
Speaker 1:  Some nice TVs.
Speaker 5:  There's an anime button on the remote.
Speaker 1:  Yes. It's got the, it's got the crunchy roll, like the, the trajectory of
Speaker 1:  crunchy roll, which was originally where you would watch fan
Speaker 1:  subs of anime. It was all pirated. And then the guy went, the guy like
Speaker 1:  made some deals with anime companies in Japan so
Speaker 1:  he could have the anime air at the same time on his pirate channel.
Speaker 1:  And now it's a button on a, like the trajectory from that to
Speaker 1:  owned by Sony to now being on the Sony remote just
Speaker 1:  delights me to no end.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, good for them.
Speaker 8:  I just have to get in here and say, as the representative of two
Speaker 8:  gigabit internet speeds that they're top of the line.
Speaker 8:  Sony a 95 j I think is the letter this year.
Speaker 8:  4K one 20 capability, but it
Speaker 8:  still has a 100 megabit per second ethernet board on it. I just,
Speaker 4:  What do you need more than a hundred megabits per second to your tv?
Speaker 8:  Well, how about for the Sony streaming service that supposedly
Speaker 8:  delivers you Blu-ray quality 4K content or
Speaker 5:  Streaming definitely legitimate rips from your plex server that are completely
Speaker 5:  uncompressed.
Speaker 8:  I I don't know what you're talking about. I I I have to go now.
Speaker 4:  All right. Alu ray. Okay. 4K Blu-ray is a hundred megabits. I got you
Speaker 8:  Saying that's crazy.
Speaker 4:  But that's a un that's like an uncompressed Blu-ray. There's not a streaming
Speaker 4:  service in the world that delivers a hundred
Speaker 8:  Megabits. According to them, they need at least 80 megabits
Speaker 8:  per second for their streaming service.
Speaker 5:  This only service that no one uses.
Speaker 4:  This is like, just to go back to ver hits from the eighties.
Speaker 4:  Remember when Sony like no one remembers this only, I remember this one year
Speaker 4:  at ces, Sony was like, we have a new 4K streaming device.
Speaker 4:  Yes. And it will download 4K movies in the background. It was a silver
Speaker 4:  circle with a light. It was a huge, it was like a,
Speaker 4:  an oval and it had a a light. Like that's, this was the pro. And I was like,
Speaker 4:  can I see it? And they took me to the booth and they showed me
Speaker 4:  very proudly this device that they were gonna release to consumers along
Speaker 4:  with their first wave of 4K TVs that would download 4K movies in the background
Speaker 4:  and you'd be able to buy them. And it was a whole thing. And I was like,
Speaker 4:  is this actually it? And they were like, no, that's just a
Speaker 4:  box with a light in it. And they like pulled back a curtain and they're like,
Speaker 4:  this PC is where it runs right now.
Speaker 4:  And I was like, only at Cs do you get to fully announce just a box with a
Speaker 4:  light and be like, we're gonna figure this out.
Speaker 1:  Don't worry about it. We got this. It's coming.
Speaker 4:  Needless to say the Sony box with the light did not upend the streaming
Speaker 4:  landscape,
Speaker 1:  But they do have a very expensive service where you can
Speaker 1:  like, and it it's, it's me. It's kind of like a better version
Speaker 1:  of what Apple does. When you buy or rent a movie from Apple, they actually,
Speaker 1:  those movies are higher bandwidth than what you would watch on
Speaker 1:  Netflix or something if same movie because it downloads the whole thing
Speaker 1:  to the Apple TV device. And so Sony has like tech that does
Speaker 1:  kind of similar. So for nerds like Liam and I who really want like
Speaker 1:  to see every little piece of film grain, it's nice.
Speaker 1:  But
Speaker 4:  Aren't you downloading that anyway? No,
Speaker 1:  I just aren't
Speaker 4:  Prefetching that content. You're not streaming it over ethernet to your tv.
Speaker 5:  We, we all need the extra headroom.
Speaker 4:  We all need. Fine. Can I just say, I just got, I recently received the new
Speaker 4:  PDF of stir file I on Apple News.
Speaker 1:  You ready? You're gonna tuck in.
Speaker 4:  It's very good. In the entire editor's letter was written about chat, G B
Speaker 4:  T and he asked it if cables made a difference and chat G PT
Speaker 4:  was like, I know what you want. And it was many paragraphs
Speaker 4:  about why some cables are better than others.
Speaker 1:  Chat G PPG gets it.
Speaker 4:  I was like, no, this is wrong. This is pure
Speaker 4:  misinformation. This is the most dangerous misinformation that's ever been
Speaker 4:  printed. They're just H G M I cables, man. It's ones and
Speaker 4:  zeroes.
Speaker 1:  Some htm I cables are better than
Speaker 4:  Others. So, no, that's it.
Speaker 5:  Monster Cable is back. It's just, here we go.
Speaker 1:  It's happened. You gotta get the gold plated man. That's how you know
Speaker 4:  There's nothing that brings me greater pleasure than tucking in with my iPad
Speaker 4:  in the latest PDF of staring Filing scene. I love it so
Speaker 4:  much. I can't believe I haven't been doing this for years since Apple News
Speaker 4:  Plus came out. But it's true. This is a true story. I'm telling that he was
Speaker 4:  just like, let's see if Chad g d can write the editor's letter. And it was
Speaker 4:  like, cables are great. It's a lot. Okay, lastly
Speaker 4:  this Microsoft phone link iMessage thing.
Speaker 1:  Richard's pumped
Speaker 4:  A lot of controversy this week. So Microsoft releases a tool. They have phone
Speaker 4:  link on Windows, which I dunno if you have it, but they're like, you can
Speaker 4:  now use iMessage trainer PC with it and what they're doing.
Speaker 4:  Microsoft, the company that is at once the forefront of the state of the
Speaker 4:  art, whether it's emotional chatbot that will just lie to you about whatever
Speaker 4:  you want it to.
Speaker 1:  And then you wanna kiss it.
Speaker 4:  They're like, here's what we're doing. We're bluetoothing into your phone.
Speaker 4:  We're reading the notifications that come in and passing them
Speaker 4:  to your computer as though it's a message.
Speaker 4:  The hackiest of all hacks. So
Speaker 5:  It's like your car when you get a text message.
Speaker 4:  Yep. They're using the exact same pass through, right? There's a little
Speaker 4:  notification standard and you can send 'em back. Right? You can, you can,
Speaker 4:  you're, if you have voice integration in your car, you can usually send a
Speaker 4:  text back out and then iMessage will decide if it's an iMessage or a text.
Speaker 4:  Microsoft using the same tool. But is that not the happiest hack that has
Speaker 4:  ever existed?
Speaker 1:  I love it though. Like they were like, no, we're gonna do it. Apple won't
Speaker 1:  give us the tools, so we're gonna gonna just ha one of the largest companies
Speaker 1:  in the world is just gonna hack it.
Speaker 5:  But Apple is letting them and they're, they're friends now. You can get your
Speaker 5:  Apple TV app on Windows. It's all cool. Every everybody, everybody's cool.
Speaker 5:  You just can't get real iMessage on Windows. That's
Speaker 4:  All everything but iMessage the thing that keeps you on the iPhone forever.
Speaker 4:  It's true. Elizabeth Warren, well again, about to jump through the wall.
Speaker 4:  Kool eight man interoperability, she screamed. That's the ver everybody
Speaker 4:  we've gone over time.
Speaker 1:  Liz is coming for us.
Speaker 4:  If anyone wants to draw me a cartoon of Elizabeth Warren jumping through
Speaker 4:  a window screaming at interoperability, we'll run it. I'll put it on the
Speaker 4:  website tomorrow. Just keep that in mind. You can send 'em to Alex. She's
Speaker 4:  at Alex h grandson Twitter. Richard is at RJ c
Speaker 4:  I remain at Reckless. I check it once a day and retweet funny jokes.
Speaker 4:  So that's what, that's how I'm using Twitter. You can also call us for eight sixty six
Speaker 4:  Verge 11. Alex, what happened on the Wednesday show?
Speaker 1:  Okay, so the Wednesday episode, I actually can't tell you it's gonna be something
Speaker 1:  really special. People are really gonna be excited when they get it in their
Speaker 1:  feed. The Monday episode, we've been doing this really great series called
Speaker 1:  Solo Acts with Ashley Escada. She's a absolute delight
Speaker 1:  every single week. She and I run over our allotted time just chatting.
Speaker 1:  She's great. But she's talking to Madison Carr, who is a game
Speaker 1:  designer who designs her games all by herself even though
Speaker 1:  it is potentially more lucrative to go and and join a big studio.
Speaker 1:  And she's going to explain exactly why that is. And it's a really great answer.
Speaker 1:  I loved it.
Speaker 4:  Well, those are great. I really like having Ashley on the show. I know a
Speaker 4:  lot of you have tweeted at us about how great she is. Keep listening to her.
Speaker 4:  It's been fun to have her on. And then next week we're at South by Southwest.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And we're doing a special episode live at South by Southwest
Speaker 4:  with some special guests, including a returning special guest. We're very
Speaker 4:  fun. That's it. That's a vergecast. We are fully out of time.
Speaker 4:  Our master plan is to continue using g r s to control your TV overall
Speaker 4:  higher blasters. Please tell us if you just want us to make entire episodes
Speaker 4:  about how we were right in the past, Richard's NFT special is coming for
Speaker 4:  you. That's it. That's our rock and roll.
Speaker 11:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 11:  us an email@vergecasttheverge.com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 11:  production of the Verge and the Box Media Podcast Network. The show is produced
Speaker 11:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. Our
Speaker 11:  editorial director is Brooke Mentors. That's it. We'll see you next week.