# Transcript
ID: 55eff9b7-94bc-450b-b034-7bdd4ba20a48
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Amazon and Microsoft's AI parades
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8694654348120022283/-178136986552068307/s93290-US-4658s-1695419558.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss all the announcements from Amazon's fall product launch event and Microsoft's Surface and AI event.
Speaker 4:  Hello and welcome to Vergecast, the flagship podcast
Speaker 4:  of a scandal that's taking over the pole dancing, not the pole dancing community.
Speaker 4:  The flagship podcast. Yeah. Of Ed Sheeran
Speaker 4:  tearing the line dancing community apart. What this is, this is just
Speaker 4:  random TikTok knowledge I have
Speaker 5:  Now. Oh, have you entered Shiver TikTok? Yeah. Yeah. Welcome. Wow.
Speaker 4:  It's just, it just follows me around the internet now there's people line
Speaker 4:  dancing to shivers by Ed Sheeran and then the comments are like,
Speaker 4:  this isn't real line dancing, like
Speaker 6:  Doing the electric slide and the little doey d
Speaker 4:  The the line dancing situa. It's the next big trend. It's
Speaker 6:  Coming to a honky tonking view.
Speaker 4:  But shivers by Ed Sheeran is, David appears to know, oh yeah.
Speaker 5:  I've been, I've been deep in, in shiver dancing TikTok for a long time, as
Speaker 5:  we call it. And
Speaker 4:  It's deeply controversial because
Speaker 6:  It's Ed Sheeran. 'cause
Speaker 4:  It's Ed Sheeran. That's
Speaker 6:  Not what I wanna listen to.
Speaker 4:  There are entire people who built careers off of line dancing
Speaker 4:  to shivers by Ed Sheeran.
Speaker 6:  No.
Speaker 4:  And the commenters are like, this isn't country music. And their response
Speaker 4:  to the commenters are, I post other songs. Only shivers gets
Speaker 4:  views.
Speaker 6:  I hate it.
Speaker 6:  I don't like it. It's very good.
Speaker 4:  This is not good. No, it's a, it's, it is easily my favorite low
Speaker 4:  stakes internet drama is
Speaker 4:  why, like do you know how there's a theory that like the Chinese government
Speaker 4:  is manipulating TikTok to destabilize America? That's
Speaker 6:  How they're doing
Speaker 4:  It. The algorithm is like, you will dance to shivers.
Speaker 6:  That's where we get our civil war.
Speaker 4:  It's very good. Hello, I'm your friend. Neli Alex. Cranz is here in the studio
Speaker 4:  with
Speaker 6:  Me. I'm just really upset today. It's all good.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna play shivers later. David Pierce is, is here.
Speaker 5:  Hi. My theory about the shiver thing is that this is this
Speaker 5:  generation's cotton eye Joe, in that it's a song and a
Speaker 5:  dance that don't make any sense in context. And no one should ever do that.
Speaker 5:  Involves like leg kicking. That doesn't
Speaker 6:  Work. You gotta slap the
Speaker 5:  Leg. But it has taken over the universe. This is it's Cotton Eye Joe
Speaker 5:  2.0
Speaker 6:  And it's there. I nevermind. I love this trend now with like that re
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Oh no, it's all good. Beautiful. There's no downside.
Speaker 4:  I'm expecting a 10,000 word shivers feature. How Shivers
Speaker 4:  is tearing country music apart.
Speaker 6:  David and I are on it.
Speaker 4:  The country music has gone through quite a lot. Right now. I'm saying shivers
Speaker 4:  is the sea plot. It
Speaker 6:  Is because there's like, there's the guy who's like the alternative
Speaker 6:  music version Yeah. Of country. And he is taken on bro country.
Speaker 6:  We have
Speaker 4:  So much to get through in the show. Oh my god. We're here at Shivers. Okay.
Speaker 4:  There's a lot on the show today. A lot.
Speaker 4:  Amazon had a big event. They announced not as much stuff as they usually
Speaker 4:  announced their events, but a bunch of stuff. Big push and generative ai.
Speaker 4:  Microsoft had an event, YouTube had an event. Microsoft
Speaker 4:  had massive product leaks, which were vastly more interesting than their
Speaker 4:  event. Yes, yes. There's other stuff going on. There's
Speaker 4:  the Google antitrust case just in the background of all of this,
Speaker 4:  which has its own controversy embedded in it. And the next week
Speaker 4:  is the code conference. So just quite a lot going on in Virg. Like
Speaker 4:  September is here. Yeah. We're no longer getting ready for September.
Speaker 4:  There's enough going on in Virgil this week that the Wednesday show is all
Speaker 4:  about the I iPhone reviews. 'cause we need to just clear the decks for today's
Speaker 4:  show. Yeah, yeah. All right. So lemme give you the quick update on the Google
Speaker 4:  trial and it will be quick because it is deeply
Speaker 4:  frustrating. No one knows what's going on in the Google trial,
Speaker 6:  Including both sides.
Speaker 4:  No, I think they might have an idea. So most federal court cases
Speaker 4:  are locked down. This is true. If you look back over the past
Speaker 4:  year or so, more and more of them are starting to open up, right? They're
Speaker 4:  allowing documents to be posted. There's some cases, audio's being streamed.
Speaker 4:  Certainly reporters are in the courtroom. Just look at the Microsoft case,
Speaker 4:  which has resulted in this giant leak, which we we'll get to. But you know
Speaker 4:  what happened in FTC versus Microsoft, we were able to cover it for you.
Speaker 4:  You know what happened in Epic versus Apple. We were able to cover for you.
Speaker 4:  Do you know what's happening in Google versus the D O J or the
Speaker 4:  D O J versus Google? You don't because reporters in the courtroom are not
Speaker 4:  allowed to have devices, which means they have to take notes by hand and
Speaker 4:  Google, the judge, the D O J are in some extremely
Speaker 4:  annoying fight about public access to documents.
Speaker 4:  So Google published a bunch of documents on it website about its opening
Speaker 4:  arguments, et da da da da. The D O J tried to do that. Google
Speaker 4:  got mad at them. All those documents have now come down off the DO J'S
Speaker 4:  website. And there is some sort of
Speaker 4:  argument happening amongst the two parties and the judge about whether
Speaker 4:  the documents will come back. In particular one document,
Speaker 4:  which we don't know what it is, which is quote embarrassing to Google.
Speaker 6:  I want that one. It's the
Speaker 4:  What I want. One of Google's financial executives was testifying that was
Speaker 4:  closed to reporters. So reporters taking notes by longhand weren't even allowed
Speaker 4:  in the room. We believe that as you're hearing this
Speaker 4:  on Friday, that Apple executives will be in the courtroom. But no one has
Speaker 4:  posted a schedule So. we don't know. It's just
Speaker 4:  bonkers.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And even the like semi haphazard ways
Speaker 5:  that information was being shared have all sort of disappeared in
Speaker 5:  part, I think because of these behind the scenes machinations going on, but
Speaker 5:  also because Judge Meta seemed to get so angry
Speaker 5:  at these documents going up that now everything is gonna get
Speaker 5:  even more locked down for the foreseeable future.
Speaker 5:  Like we're what we're what, two weeks into a 10 week trial? And
Speaker 5:  other than those first couple of days, we basically don't know anything.
Speaker 5:  Somebody sent me a picture of a a like old school typewriter and was like,
Speaker 5:  take this courtroom. They can't stop you. It's not an electronic And I think
Speaker 5:  that's the coolest flex of all time. But it is very weird. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I get why Google in particular would very much
Speaker 5:  like for it to be this way because it's not interested in losing
Speaker 5:  this fight in the court of public opinion. I don't know for sure that they're
Speaker 5:  the ones driving this, but I can certainly see why they would. But it's very
Speaker 5:  strange that this is where we've landed in this process.
Speaker 4:  Addie Robertson is covering the case very closely, closely as we can
Speaker 4:  who's been in the courtroom for us. I'm like, we should write this story
Speaker 4:  that's like Google's trying to hide and she's like, that's not what's happening.
Speaker 4:  It's the judge. Right? Right. Her opinion of this is, it's the judge is
Speaker 4:  like, I'm gonna be in control of this and I get it. And you
Speaker 4:  could make a case from sort of an outcome basis
Speaker 4:  that not making the trial into the circus will allow the court to reach a
Speaker 4:  good and fair outcome. And Then we can like check their work in the end.
Speaker 4:  'cause all of it's public rec. But there's also the fact that like one of
Speaker 4:  the biggest companies in America is facing antitrust charges that may
Speaker 4:  or may not result in it being broken up or the structure of its
Speaker 4:  deals with apple change. And we just don't know. Like we do not know
Speaker 4:  what's going on in that trial right now. I think that's absurd. But that
Speaker 4:  is the state of the Google trial. That's the update, which is
Speaker 4:  it's Schrodinger's trial.
Speaker 4:  Is there an antitrust trial in that? Who knows? Probably is Google, who
Speaker 4:  knows. So that's that. The other update I wanna give everybody is the code
Speaker 4:  conference is next week. Ooh. I'm hosting it with Casey Newton and Julia
Speaker 4:  Rson from C N B C. It's gonna be great. I've been speaking to some of the
Speaker 4:  people to prepare who are gonna appear on stage. So I'm very excited about
Speaker 4:  Getty's gonna show off. I'm very excited about what Microsoft's gonna show
Speaker 4:  off. Adobe asked some stuff they've told us they're gonna show off. I think
Speaker 4:  it's all gonna be really fun. Here's the news though. The u a w is on
Speaker 4:  strike against three major American automakers and Mary Berra, C O G
Speaker 4:  M dropped out today. Aw. She doesn't, she doesn't wanna give any fodder to
Speaker 4:  the negotiations, which I sort of understand. She took with her. I
Speaker 4:  look, it's sort of under, I just wanna be clear. I,
Speaker 4:  I can intellectually understand why she, I do not understand why
Speaker 4:  she doesn't wanna just say what she needs to say. But whatever she took with
Speaker 4:  her, Mike Abbott, their new executive vice president of software, who is
Speaker 4:  gonna, because why does GM wanna be at the code conference? Yeah. Talk about
Speaker 4:  EVs. Talk about the fact that they dropped CarPlay. And so
Speaker 4:  I, I have said to our team, the only moment that matters at code is
Speaker 4:  me asking Mary Bear why she took CarPlay outta the Escalade. Yep. We were
Speaker 4:  like prepared for it and now I cannot deliver that moment to you. Did you
Speaker 4:  have
Speaker 6:  Like four versions of the question for her?
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. You can't evade, you can't dodge it. I think it sucks, but the
Speaker 4:  people love it. Right? Like what are you gonna do? It shivers it. I brought
Speaker 4:  an Escalade out on stage, here it is. Explain. That's
Speaker 4:  true. We have the c e O of Monarch tractor by the way, an EV tractor.
Speaker 4:  And I was like, will you drive the tractor on stage? And he goes, it's very
Speaker 4:  heavy. That was the end of that conversation. It's gonna
Speaker 4:  be cool. The Polestar three is gonna be a code, which I think is gonna be
Speaker 4:  really cool. We'll you'll see some of that. It's, that is basically just
Speaker 4:  released. I'm just excited about a bunch of stuff that's happening at code,
Speaker 4:  but Mary Bear is leaving that said and will not reveal it at this moment.
Speaker 4:  We are 99% sure that another c
Speaker 4:  e o of an EV company will be there. Like a good one. Okay.
Speaker 6:  I was like Elon. No,
Speaker 4:  No, it's, well like it's funny how you can interpret like a good one in many
Speaker 4:  ways. Yeah. But a good one. Okay. Like one that you wanna hear from. Okay.
Speaker 4:  And then I got another idea that I'm working on, which I think will be cool.
Speaker 4:  So that's the code update. It's September 26th and 27th. We'll have like
Speaker 4:  wall to wall coverage on The. Verge. I'll be there with Casey and Julia.
Speaker 4:  You can buy, you go to vme.com/code. You can buy virtual tickets now. There's
Speaker 4:  seven, five bucks if you wanna like follow along. Otherwise tons of coverage
Speaker 4:  on the site. We, you know, pay attention to code. It's the thing I'm doing.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Let's talk about the news. Should we start with Amazon?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There was an Amazon event. David and I went, we hung out. You went?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I took the train down. That was the worst decision of my life.
Speaker 6:  That was horrible. I took two trains out. So
Speaker 4:  There's like a lot of drama with these Amazon and Microsoft events. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like meta drama. Yeah. Oh it's so fun.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's my favorite part of this. Like I think that was the big conversation
Speaker 6:  of the week because the gadgets and, and there was a lot of cool gadgets
Speaker 6:  and the gadgets are deep and we're gonna talk about the gadgets, but the
Speaker 6:  big thing was Panos Pane is he runs
Speaker 6:  all the devices and Windows at Microsoft. Or he did
Speaker 6:  because this week sudden announcement he's leaving. Which is wild
Speaker 6:  'cause there's a Microsoft event this week. Yeah. David Limp left Amazon
Speaker 6:  a couple of months ago and Bloomberg reports, Panos Pane is
Speaker 6:  gonna be taking over his job. David Lim's job at Amazon.
Speaker 6:  So then the Amazon event happened on Wednesday. Microsoft event happens on
Speaker 6:  Thursday. And meanwhile we've got these two guys who've been running these
Speaker 6:  departments, running these events, deciding what's gonna be on
Speaker 6:  stage, figuring out how these things work and operate are
Speaker 6:  both like huge mixup. Huge changeup. Yeah. And it's just like you are,
Speaker 4:  I wish there was, I wish there was a true swap. Yeah. That's really what
Speaker 4:  what it's like, it would be perfect if, if Limp was gonna Microsoft and Panos
Speaker 4:  is going to this just start. But Limp is just out.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Limps done. He's, he seems very happy. He seems
Speaker 6:  chill to be, to be moving on with his life.
Speaker 4:  So I I, I like Dave limp a lot. Yeah. We, we've talked to him a bunch. He's
Speaker 4:  been on decoder. He's a very smart guy. He, he has always said the right
Speaker 4:  things to us. I would say looking at his tenure over Amazon devices,
Speaker 4:  not a lot of heat there. Oh
Speaker 5:  That's not fair. His
Speaker 6:  Strategy was interesting. What do you mean? Because the strategy was about
Speaker 6:  we're gonna see what sticks we wanna, like we're new in this department.
Speaker 4:  Wait, I wanna hear why David says it's not fair.
Speaker 5:  The Echo has been a gigantic success. The Kindle has been a gigantic success.
Speaker 5:  Wait,
Speaker 4:  The Kindle has been a gigantic success. The Echo is not a gigantic success
Speaker 4:  and Alexa is not a gigantic, it does not make any money. Fair.
Speaker 5:  Sure. That's a, those are two different questions
Speaker 4:  And you would not even say that people are,
Speaker 6:  It's a cultural
Speaker 4:  Success passionate about these products.
Speaker 5:  Oh, Dave Limp would say that. Dave Limp said that to me to my face after
Speaker 5:  the Amazon event that people love their echoes. I mean one
Speaker 5:  of the questions I asked him, they had this whole run about generative AI
Speaker 5:  and wanting their AI to seem like human
Speaker 5:  right? Like that's their big thing. They wanted to say ums and ahs. Yes.
Speaker 5:  And feel like a member of your family. And I feel like if we've learned one
Speaker 5:  thing about AI over the last 12 months, it's that that's a bad,
Speaker 5:  dangerous, problematic idea. So I asked him that. I was like, why should
Speaker 5:  this thing just be a tool that I use when I need it? Why should it be my
Speaker 5:  friend that seems scary. And he
Speaker 5:  was like, that's how people do it. They say they love you to their Echo and,
Speaker 5:  and we're gonna keep leaning into that. Like there is
Speaker 5:  real affinity for that stuff. Most people just like play timers and ask silly
Speaker 5:  questions. But like that's, that thing is real Amazon's problem is that it's
Speaker 5:  not a hardware company. Right. Like their whole thing has always been, we
Speaker 5:  don't make money when you buy our product. We make money when you use our
Speaker 5:  product. Right. So like they don't make money on the Kindle. They make money
Speaker 5:  when you buy books on the Kindle. The problem is they never found a way for
Speaker 5:  you to buy anything. Yeah. Through the Echo.
Speaker 4:  But this is just what I mean, I we're agreeing more than disagreeing when
Speaker 4:  I say there's not a lot of heat on these products. The Kindle is its own
Speaker 4:  thing. It's its own weird closed ecosystem. They put out new Kindles every
Speaker 4:  couple of years
Speaker 6:  Monstrously
Speaker 4:  Successful and people just buy new ones. Yeah. And fine. And it is a
Speaker 4:  cultural product in its way. Although I think the, the sort of cultural impact
Speaker 4:  of print books continues and grows in its own way. Which I think is
Speaker 4:  fascinating. The Echo people set timers with and it's really
Speaker 4:  useful and little kids ask it to tell it jokes and you can dress what an
Speaker 4:  Echo dot up like a Mickey and like all that stuff. But it has just been
Speaker 4:  that for the longest time and maybe
Speaker 4:  some of this generative AI stuff will change that. But they haven't grown
Speaker 4:  it into a business. They haven't figured out how to get people to do anything
Speaker 4:  other than set timers and play music at like at all.
Speaker 4:  The smart home stuff has kind of petered out and we're all waiting for matter
Speaker 4:  to do whatever. And they've made some of those spens And then the hardware
Speaker 4:  itself is like somewhat stagnated. Oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Not even somewhat. It has fully stagnated. Even The new stuff they're
Speaker 5:  launching is just like big plushy screens. Just like the other big
Speaker 5:  plushie screens like with
Speaker 6:  Thread routers.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, sure, sure. Yeah. Like they've updated the stuff. And again, I like
Speaker 4:  Dave and I think he has the right ideas and when you talk to him about smart
Speaker 4:  home home stuff in particular, he's like all in on
Speaker 4:  the good standards and making sure the stuff works right. Like he's, he says
Speaker 4:  all the right things and he's honest. Which is like the highest compliment
Speaker 4:  I can give. Yeah. But I think that the fire, that's a
Speaker 4:  good pun frame his on devices, it just seems like they hit a dead end
Speaker 4:  and they didn't know what to do next. And I think you bring in Panos Penne.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Who's all fire all the time and he's going to go
Speaker 4:  and like try some stuff and be bold about it. Which I think is great.
Speaker 4:  I think his tenure at Surface in particular has been
Speaker 4:  underappreciated.
Speaker 5:  Oh I agree. Like
Speaker 4:  He completely rebooted the idea of Windows laptops from his position at Microsoft.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And we've talked about it a bunch on the show, but basically
Speaker 4:  he walked into Best Buy and said why are every
Speaker 4:  Windows Laptop here? Why is it under a thousand dollars? And we have just
Speaker 4:  seeded the high end to to Apple. Yeah. And then they invented a bunch
Speaker 4:  of stuff and importantly I think this is totally undercovered, they gave
Speaker 4:  that technology away to the Windows OEMs. Yep. So I've walked around
Speaker 4:  c e s with Panos and he's like, those are my hinges and pointing at
Speaker 4:  laptops. Like those are my hinges, those are my key. Like here's all the
Speaker 4:  stuff we made that we just gave away. He
Speaker 5:  Pulled off the thing Google has been trying to do with Pixel for years, which
Speaker 5:  is like teach the ecosystem how to make better stuff. Yeah. Like he, he did
Speaker 5:  that to the Windows ecosystem. Yeah. Like if you have a Windows Laptop it
Speaker 5:  is better because of anos pane. Like it just, it just is. Yeah. And I
Speaker 5:  think that's really cool. Can I tell you my most Galaxy brainin take about
Speaker 5:  all of this? I've been talking to people and asking around, and I have
Speaker 5:  no actual evidence for this, but I'm increasingly convinced that I'm right.
Speaker 5:  Do you wanna hear my theory? Yes. My theory is that Panos
Speaker 5:  Pne wants nothing more than to make a next generation
Speaker 5:  smartphone. He has been toying with this, with the Surface duo. He's
Speaker 5:  been goofing around with this idea with a bunch of different Windows things
Speaker 5:  over the years. He has like tried desperately to figure out what is the smartphone
Speaker 5:  thing that comes right after Candy bar smartphones. Microsoft I don't think
Speaker 5:  has any interest in making smartphones anymore.
Speaker 4:  That's Or even supporting the one that it made.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's over that, you know, who desperately, desperately would love a
Speaker 5:  reason to get back into the smartphone game is Amazon. Because the reason
Speaker 5:  Alexa can't win is because it's not on your
Speaker 5:  phone in a meaningful device integrated, super
Speaker 5:  useful way. It is the single most important device you have. And it is the
Speaker 5:  worst Alexa device. And if you gave Jeff Bezos and Andy
Speaker 5:  Jassy like all the money in the world, they would go back and make the fire
Speaker 5:  phone better because it would've changed Amazon forever. And I think
Speaker 5:  somebody came up to PATOS and said, we are going to let you build the foldable
Speaker 5:  phone of your dreams and it's, we're gonna kick ass with it. And that's why
Speaker 5:  he's going to Amazon. This
Speaker 4:  Is your theory.
Speaker 5:  This is my theory.
Speaker 4:  I mean it's a good theory.
Speaker 5:  I I I like it. I know for sure the phone thing at Amazon is right. I
Speaker 5:  I am a hundred percent sure that Amazon believes very strongly
Speaker 5:  that if it wants to win, it should figure out how to make phones and that
Speaker 5:  that is a way to do this. We
Speaker 6:  Saw them set the table for that at the Amazon event. 'cause the Amazon event
Speaker 6:  was about the, the show eight, which seems really nice. I wasn't
Speaker 6:  enthusiastic about it until I spent an hour with Jen and now I'm like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  that's cool as hell.
Speaker 4:  Jen's good like that. Like
Speaker 6:  She's very good at like that. And you know, there was that and there was
Speaker 6:  the Hub and, and all of that. But most of that event was on
Speaker 6:  Alexa and on how Alexa is different than,
Speaker 6:  than Siri and Google assistant and better. And I don't know if that's true
Speaker 6:  because we didn't get to actually play around with it a lot. 'cause all of
Speaker 6:  the the demos were had massive guardrails. Really? Yeah. Like I,
Speaker 6:  I was like, I wanna go break the, that's
Speaker 4:  How you know that generative AI is like about to say some crazy stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's like we want actually because it'll be like you wanna bang. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I wanted to define some weird, I wanna, I was like how can I make
Speaker 4:  It your, what if we set a timer for five minutes to get it on, you know,
Speaker 4:  just
Speaker 6:  Plain abusive.
Speaker 4:  What about you and me? Seven minutes from night? I have to stop it.
Speaker 6:  I just hear the guitar.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying, look, if you're listening and you're at Amazon, you're on
Speaker 4:  the Alexa team.
Speaker 6:  Make it horny,
Speaker 4:  Horny binging, rebooted Microsoft on the front
Speaker 4:  page of The new York Times. Just send one Alexa to Kevin Ru.
Speaker 4:  It could happen to you
Speaker 6:  But not one of the kid exes.
Speaker 4:  No.
Speaker 4:  Wait, so wait, why? Why did Jen get you so excited about that?
Speaker 6:  I think her enthusiasm for it as a Hub. 'cause she, the
Speaker 6:  poor woman is on a quest to find something that will actually work as a Hub.
Speaker 6:  Where you don't have to say, yeah this'll work, but 'cause that's with all
Speaker 6:  smart home hubs. Yeah. Every single smart home Hub, you're like perfect.
Speaker 6:  You will not need anything else except actually you're gonna need this.
Speaker 4:  Can I, can I give you my tiny little example of this right now? Yes. So,
Speaker 4:  we have a new house. So Jen and I, there are lots of backhanding which Oh
Speaker 4:  yeah. And it's not, it's not great Matter is not ready
Speaker 4:  do not buy. Look, it's a bad time to buy a house for a lot of reasons. But
Speaker 4:  if you're listening to the show, it's a bad time to buy a house. 'cause you're
Speaker 4:  gonna want to put smart stuff in it. And the standard is not ready. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Nope. It is just not ready. So you are trapped
Speaker 4:  into buying obsolete technology. It is the worst feeling in the world. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You're like, I'm gonna go all in on HomeKit. Like whatever. Except
Speaker 4:  here's what HomeKit can't do. You can't tell HomeKit where you live.
Speaker 4:  What? Nope. So you just can't, there's no Yeah. Direct
Speaker 4:  interface. It doesn't understand where like my house is here. It just
Speaker 4:  detects it off your phone. And if you set up new routers
Speaker 4:  with new Mac addresses, apple TV doesn't have a G P S
Speaker 4:  in it. So it just decides where your house is gonna be when you set
Speaker 4:  it up as a home. It's like, I've never seen that Mac address before on this
Speaker 4:  router. You probably live in your old house. Right.
Speaker 4:  Just bonkers and every, every smart home thing.
Speaker 4:  Like it's just missing one thing. Yeah. For example, a home kit missing an
Speaker 4:  address field. Minor detail. Minor detail.
Speaker 4:  It's a little one. You look at the, the Reddit threads of people who are
Speaker 4:  like, HomeKit doesn't know where I live. It's like five years deep
Speaker 4:  and the workarounds are ridiculous. But it's true. Most things are
Speaker 4:  matter or thread or is it, they're missing one piece of the puzzle. Right.
Speaker 4:  Matter itself. Just, you know, like when you're like building a new city
Speaker 4:  in Sim City and you're like, I'll just fi finish that road at some other
Speaker 4:  time matter.
Speaker 5:  Yep. It's a good road. It's like a beautiful four blocks of
Speaker 5:  a road. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And you're like, something good's gonna happen and
Speaker 6:  You just stop, park
Speaker 4:  The car and that's like matter and doorbells. It's like you're just an area
Speaker 4:  of your town labeled that and you, you come back around to it later. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And it sounds like the show eight is gonna be a little bit more
Speaker 6:  inclusive. It's gonna have, it's gonna have the stuff,
Speaker 6:  it'll work and theoretically if this
Speaker 6:  generative AI works Yeah. Then, then yeah. We're that
Speaker 6:  one step closer to the Star Trek computer
Speaker 6:  dream, which is kind of how I understand Amazon's dream.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean that that Dave's limb stream, like he has talked to us about
Speaker 4:  ambient computing quite a lot. Yeah. But you weren't able
Speaker 4:  actually to try out these generative AI features.
Speaker 6:  Not really. I tried to, I tried it with a fire TV and I wasn't allowed to
Speaker 6:  ask questions, which Oh. And it was just super, super
Speaker 6:  guardrail. He clearly had like, okay, these are the ones I'm gonna show you
Speaker 6:  to showcase his stuff. Which is fine. I think that's very normal for these
Speaker 6:  kind of situations. The, the Internet's really crappy as we saw when
Speaker 6:  like limp had struggles on stage because it seemed like
Speaker 6:  the, oh boy, the Alexa like lost connection at one point. And he was just
Speaker 6:  like, I'm just gonna stand here awkwardly and wait,
Speaker 4:  See this is why I prefer live demos to whatever Apple's doing. Oh yeah. That's,
Speaker 4:  it's, that's like even that just hearing that is like makes this whole thing
Speaker 4:  much.
Speaker 6:  It was nice and but you have to remember, okay, well you know this is one
Speaker 6:  of the most challenging networking environments you can have. 'cause you
Speaker 6:  have a hundred journalists all with like cameras and
Speaker 6:  laptops uploading a ton of stuff all at once in one
Speaker 6:  small room you destroy the internet.
Speaker 5:  Whatever. Yeah. If Taylor Swift can do it for the ERAS tour. I
Speaker 4:  Don't care. Five G baby.
Speaker 5:  No, I will say the, the thing Dave Limp told me is that most of this stuff
Speaker 5:  is not live yet and finished. Like the, even the folks who
Speaker 5:  buy some of these products early on may not get the full
Speaker 5:  generative AI piece of it. It's all backend stuff, right?
Speaker 5:  Like all the stuff is happening on Amazon's side of things. That's
Speaker 5:  why a lot of this tech is coming to like the original Echo, which yeah
Speaker 5:  obviously doesn't have the hardware to like run LLMs locally, but it
Speaker 5:  doesn't have to 'cause all this stuff is happening in the cloud and just
Speaker 5:  being ported back to you through Alexa. But it's, it's
Speaker 5:  gonna be a pretty slow process for Amazon. Like, Alexa is basically this
Speaker 5:  compilation of like thousands of different little things. We think of it
Speaker 5:  as like one character, but it's actually just a million different pipes all
Speaker 5:  kind of coming into the voice and they're gonna do it
Speaker 5:  as far as I understand kind of bit by bit as it goes
Speaker 5:  before this all becomes sort of fully generative ai. And
Speaker 5:  my understanding is that's gonna take a little while.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's gonna come with the phone.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna come with the phone. There is this new eye Gaze thing where you
Speaker 4:  can just like look at the displays and control them with your eyes, which
Speaker 4:  is a little terrifying. A little Amazon seems much more comfortable with
Speaker 4:  the idea of putting cameras and smart assistant
Speaker 6:  Devices. They have drone that you could fly around your house for
Speaker 6:  security. Like their, their concept of security and and and stuff is way
Speaker 6:  different. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They're like what if Robocop was in your home? There's
Speaker 6:  Like three people in the world who are like, yes. Yeah. And the rest of us
Speaker 6:  are like, mm no.
Speaker 4:  And they're listening right now. Welcome. We appreciate you, we love you.
Speaker 4:  But no, Amazon's just very comfortable with the idea that these things should
Speaker 4:  have cameras as well as microphones. I am hard Stop at
Speaker 4:  cameras. Yeah. Just no thank you. You
Speaker 6:  Don't want a camera owned by someone else in your bedroom at all times. No
Speaker 4:  Thank you. Shocking. I'm good. But you know, when you ask people would you
Speaker 4:  ever put a camera in your bathroom? They're like, no. And they're like, you
Speaker 4:  know, you carry like seven of them in your bathroom every time you, your
Speaker 6:  Foot's free time
Speaker 4:  And there's like, yeah. And
Speaker 6:  Then they lie. That's fine. And they're like, it's in my pocket the whole
Speaker 6:  time. It's not.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I, I hide it. I I wrap it in a little towel like a baby and put it
Speaker 4:  away.
Speaker 5:  But wait, Neli, the, the camera thing is really interesting. 'cause like
Speaker 5:  I, I'm with you on the would not put a camera in like my
Speaker 5:  bedroom that, that's been a non-starter for us for forever. I, we don't even
Speaker 5:  have any cameras in the house.
Speaker 5:  But like you
Speaker 4:  Have seven of them in your pocket right now is
Speaker 5:  What I'm saying. Hey, I mean I have seven. I have one right here. Like, you
Speaker 5:  know what I mean? Yeah. We don't have any like smart home camera things.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But then there are questions like, okay not a camera,
Speaker 5:  but what about like a radar detector that knows
Speaker 5:  when you're getting close and can change the interface so that you can use
Speaker 5:  it. That's
Speaker 5:  not the same but it's not totally different either. It's like my
Speaker 5:  device being aware of me all the way down to like my device
Speaker 5:  can see precisely what facial expression I'm making somewhere on that spectrum
Speaker 5:  is where I get uncomfortable and I don't know exactly where it is. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But I think, and like Amazon is doing this too. They have the, these really
Speaker 5:  interesting ideas with things like the, the Hub Max, the big new smart home
Speaker 5:  controller about when you're far away it should show you one thing,
Speaker 5:  right? Like probably status information. It'll look like a thermostat, show
Speaker 5:  you temperature or whatever. As you get closer, it can start to show you
Speaker 5:  more information and when you get right up to it, it should show you buttons
Speaker 5:  because that's what you're gonna do when you're standing right next to it.
Speaker 5:  And to do that, they have to be able to do presence detection. It has to
Speaker 5:  know where, who you are and where you are. And full
Speaker 5:  color camera for that little much for my taste. But
Speaker 5:  like, I still have not figured out where I go from like, this is a
Speaker 5:  useful way to do a useful thing to like, eh, that's a little much.
Speaker 6:  I like that they're, they're trying to figure it out. 'cause the Echo itself,
Speaker 6:  like the original one was already kind of invasive and people had to,
Speaker 6:  to reconcile that, right? Like, I'm gonna have an always on microphone in
Speaker 6:  my house. That's way more than anybody had had before that.
Speaker 5:  Well and the lesson learned was people got used to that really fast. Right.
Speaker 5:  Like Amazon was like, oh we can just do this 'cause it's fine.
Speaker 6:  And so Amazon is clearly like trying to find, okay, what's we, we have to
Speaker 6:  do this presence detection. We have to do something because you cannot have
Speaker 6:  a super successful smart home without some sort of like surveillance.
Speaker 6:  That's just, you need it. Yeah. And if you want the convenience, you're gonna
Speaker 6:  have to give that up. And so they're clearly trying to figure out, okay,
Speaker 6:  where's, where's most people's line drone that flies around your house
Speaker 6:  robot that drives around your house and gives you beer too much.
Speaker 4:  Well, something those are different. I would say those are different. One
Speaker 4:  was the robot was useful. Yeah. The drone is terrifying. Was the
Speaker 6:  Robot useful?
Speaker 4:  Well I'm saying well I mean it could have been useful but it wasn't useful.
Speaker 4:  It brings me
Speaker 5:  Beer.
Speaker 4:  Right. I think if you, I I think if you can actually solve the it brings
Speaker 4:  me beer problem. Like a lot of people will sign up for that at under a thousand
Speaker 4:  dollars. Yeah, that's fair. The like there's a drone that looks at stuff
Speaker 4:  in my house. A lot of people are like, yeah, I dunno man, just rob the place.
Speaker 4:  Like I I can't be doing this.
Speaker 6:  You are welcome to everything. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But I'm with, I I I'm with you David, that there's like some Yeah,
Speaker 6:  There's that, there's that point. It's fuzzy.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And it seems like Amazon is trying to find that point by
Speaker 6:  throwing things, by doing like the limp strategy, which is like, okay, well
Speaker 6:  we're just gonna release, we can afford to release things so we're gonna
Speaker 6:  release things and see where that line is.
Speaker 4:  I think this is the thing that we'll change on our panas penne the most.
Speaker 4:  Yep. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I think he's gonna have more focus, right?
Speaker 4:  Like Amazon is like, we'll put a mic and speakers in it, Alexa
Speaker 4:  light switches, whatever. And the idea that the market would settle
Speaker 4:  on an idea I think has just not come to fruition.
Speaker 4:  Especially 'cause Alexa hasn't been worth it.
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 4:  Like I, man again, I'm, I'm out here trying to buy a thermostat man. Like
Speaker 4:  the eco b I want is like it has Alexa in it. I'm like, but I don't want that.
Speaker 4:  You can turn
Speaker 6:  It off. I never used it.
Speaker 4:  But why, why does it, why is it even there? I
Speaker 6:  Don't want it. I don't know.
Speaker 4:  Like I don't need a microphone in my thermostat man. I'm trying to tell
Speaker 4:  this to you d it than it has whatever. It's, it's just like, but that
Speaker 4:  was the idea. We'll just like put it everywhere. I suspect Panos will bring
Speaker 4:  much more focus to that program. Yeah. There's a little bit of reporting
Speaker 4:  in Reuters that like morale is low in that team. I think that's to be expected
Speaker 4:  with any gigantic leadership change. But I also think
Speaker 4:  the sort of leadership style is about to go
Speaker 4:  a dramatic change. And if you've been allowed to be like, here's what we're
Speaker 4:  gonna do. We're gonna spend tens of million dollars on a drone that flies
Speaker 4:  around your house and then just put it out there and see what hap like
Speaker 4:  I suspect those days are gonna come to an end.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna be sad about that.
Speaker 5:  I think Neli, the, the truest thing I think about your feeling about Dave
Speaker 5:  Lim's tenure is that the last like
Speaker 5:  big capital and new thing Amazon's hardware division
Speaker 5:  launched was that first Echo in 2014. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  No, I, the Echo shows I think were an important turn.
Speaker 5:  That's fair. Okay, sure. I'll give you that. But, but even that, that's,
Speaker 5:  that's one and a half things in what amounts to a decade and,
Speaker 5:  and everything else has been sort of iterative splinters of
Speaker 5:  the same idea. And I think one thing Panos Pnet is very good at is being
Speaker 5:  a fountain of big new wacky ideas. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You fire TV's in there actually, and Jen read about this, that Amazon has
Speaker 4:  weirdly sort of discounted the fire TV as the centerpiece of its smart home
Speaker 4:  strategy when it is probably by all, like by
Speaker 4:  most measures, the most used Amazon device in most people's lives.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. If you have a fire TV in your house, it is probably the Amazon thing
Speaker 4:  you interact with the most. Yeah. But it's a TV so like
Speaker 4:  you get it to play whatever you want and usually like move on with your life.
Speaker 4:  Right. And I think there's a gap there that I think is fascinating. And they,
Speaker 4:  they announced a new one, right? Yeah. They
Speaker 6:  Announced two. So they announced the, the, it's The new fire TV
Speaker 6:  four K stick and it's, it's gonna be more powerful. It's gonna be faster,
Speaker 6:  it should have better wifi in it. And then there's gonna be a new
Speaker 6:  fire TV Max and that's gonna have a whole like, like that's gonna
Speaker 6:  be more in competition with the Apple tv. Which is
Speaker 6:  great because fire TVs have notoriously stayed far, far,
Speaker 6:  far away from the premium end of things. Which is really annoying if
Speaker 6:  you wanna experience it. But you don't wanna look at garbage on your TV
Speaker 6:  and like, I paid for Dolby vision, I want Dolby vision. Wait,
Speaker 5:  But but Alex can I tell you the wildest thing about what you just described?
Speaker 5:  What the pr your, your description is exactly Right. And the difference between
Speaker 5:  bottom and top is $10. It's
Speaker 5:  $10. Buy the fancy one. People like wait for our
Speaker 5:  reviews. We'll probably review them. Please
Speaker 6:  Buy the Max.
Speaker 5:  There are many smarter people with Virgin on this stuff than I am. But I'm
Speaker 5:  here to tell you, if you are going to buy one of The new fire TV sticks,
Speaker 5:  spend the $10, get the Dolby, get the better features,
Speaker 5:  get the faster speeds. It will last you longer. It will make you happier.
Speaker 5:  It's $10.
Speaker 5:  It's, I don't understand why this other one exists. Like Amazon
Speaker 5:  likes to do the thing where they're like, this one costs $5 and this one
Speaker 5:  costs $50. And then I'm like, okay these, this is, these are real things
Speaker 5:  and then they discount the one really heavily on prime day and they'll just
Speaker 5:  like give it to you anytime you put anything in your cart. Like whatever.
Speaker 5:  That's all fine and good. This one is, if you're gonna have a $50 one, that's
Speaker 5:  fine and a $60 one. That's very good. Like what are we doing?
Speaker 4:  I don't understand.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  All right. Lastly we have to talk about the Echo. Frames Then. we gotta take
Speaker 4:  a break. We do. Why did they make glasses again? So,
Speaker 5:  Okay, I can answer this question because I asked Dave limp this question.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I literally pointed at them on the table in
Speaker 5:  front of him in this conference room. We were sitting and talking and I was
Speaker 5:  like, smart glasses are these, are these a thing? And he goes,
Speaker 5:  I don't know. So what I can tell you is true is that like the
Speaker 5:  last time Amazon had this run of like weird stuff they were gonna launch,
Speaker 5:  they did a ring, they did a whole bunch of other stuff. All with the idea
Speaker 5:  of like things you have on you all the time that might connect to Alexa.
Speaker 5:  Right? Most of those things didn't find an audience. They're not here. It's
Speaker 5:  not an accident that like the Echo ring to does not exist.
Speaker 5:  The Frames, he said caught on, they're not huge, they're not earth
Speaker 5:  shatteringly popular. But he said he was like, we have found
Speaker 5:  a bunch of kinds of people who really love this
Speaker 5:  outdoorsy people who have always been the target market for this, right?
Speaker 5:  Like you want, you wanna be able to listen to music and talk to your device
Speaker 5:  without having headphones blocking you from the world. That's useful.
Speaker 5:  And like Bose is working on this kind of stuff. Meta is working on this kind
Speaker 5:  of stuff. There's like this there teeny tiny little but kind of growing smart
Speaker 5:  glasses world that I think is sort of fascinating. But
Speaker 5:  he basically was like, what we thought happened the last time was that they
Speaker 5:  were severely limited by the fact that they didn't look very good.
Speaker 5:  That we thought there might be more people who were interested in relatively
Speaker 5:  lightweight, relatively simple glasses that
Speaker 5:  let you talk to Alexa and play music, period.
Speaker 5:  So with this generation we made them nicer looking and they are in fact much
Speaker 5:  nicer looking. They have a bunch of different styles, they have some different
Speaker 5:  lenses. They did a thing with Carrera that looked so bad when I put them
Speaker 5:  on, but I'm sure will look cool on other people's faces. Yeah. But they're
Speaker 5:  like, I, I get the sense that they're like, okay this is the good version
Speaker 5:  of this product that some people seem to have caught onto already.
Speaker 5:  Like let's see if there really is a there there on this one. So I'm
Speaker 5:  fascinated to see how well this thing actually does. I
Speaker 4:  Can't wait to make you review these.
Speaker 5:  I'm down, I went back and looked at our old review and all of the pictures
Speaker 5:  are deter looking very serious. Holding one of the stems of the
Speaker 5:  glasses. It's so
Speaker 4:  Good. Yes, it's good. This is why I'm excited for it. I can't wait. Very
Speaker 4:  serious. Can do the same outfit too. That's Amazon. There's lots of
Speaker 4:  coverage on the site if you're into the, there's an Euro Pro Max with wifi
Speaker 4:  7, 2 10 gig ports and two 2.5 gig ports.
Speaker 4:  It's huge.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 4:  Do you need that's it's $1,700 for a three pack. It's
Speaker 4:  great. I love it.
Speaker 5:  You're gonna buy it for sure.
Speaker 4:  Like you know there's like a No you have one gig internet service. Although
Speaker 4:  we could get eight gig optimum service, I just couldn't figure out what for
Speaker 4:  and now I'm like, oh it's so I couldn't buy this router. Yeah, it's a horrible
Speaker 4:  way. It's a horrible way to spend $1,700 is switching to
Speaker 4:  Optimum. No thank you. No thank you. But
Speaker 4:  it's great. The Echo Hub Max, go look on
Speaker 4:  the site. It's all fun stuff to look at. But the real news here is that
Speaker 4:  this is like the end of one line of thinking. Yes.
Speaker 4:  Which is just utterly fascinating to me. Yeah and it all happened on the
Speaker 4:  same day. It is. Great. Okay, so we're gonna take a break, we're gonna come
Speaker 4:  back, we're gonna talk about Microsoft's event, which is on the other end
Speaker 4:  of all this Trump we
Speaker 4:  Okay, we're back. Should we do the leaks first with Microsoft or should we
Speaker 4:  do the event first? Let's
Speaker 6:  Event and Then we. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Let's do the event and then we'll do the leaks because that's way more interesting
Speaker 5:  and the event will seem like a super bummer if we talk about the leaks
Speaker 4:  First. So Microsoft had a a Surface event today. Mm.
Speaker 6:  Is that fair to call it a Surface event?
Speaker 4:  Well, not anymore. 'cause Panos is gone. Exactly. So Panos was like tweeting
Speaker 4:  about this a couple weeks ago. I I'm excited to be in New York. Do the thing,
Speaker 4:  da da da show off The new Surface. We've all seen these events. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  One of them, he was like, I made The new Surface, I made it for you Joanna
Speaker 4:  Stern and like pointed at her. It was great. It's like an all time great
Speaker 4:  tech event moment. And she was like me And he's like, yeah it's you. It was
Speaker 4:  great.
Speaker 4:  He bailed on Monday, just tweet I'm out. Yep. And then there was
Speaker 4:  a scramble and as you said Bloomberg report. He is going Amazon, no one's
Speaker 4:  confirming anything. There's a lot of speculation. What? Whatever. So the
Speaker 4:  Microsoft has to like do this event and they scrambled up
Speaker 4:  some people Nadella showed up. Yeah. And what'd
Speaker 4:  they do? They said it's all about AI now. So what happened at this
Speaker 4:  event?
Speaker 6:  They didn't announce the Surface Pro but we weren't expecting that. They
Speaker 6:  announced a new Surface studio Laptop.
Speaker 4:  It looks cool,
Speaker 6:  But they didn't talk about the plinth. Remember the plinth? Yeah. That was
Speaker 6:  a big part of the last one. The flat part. The flat part.
Speaker 4:  Plinth. It's a good word.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's a good word.
Speaker 4:  More thing you should, you should pull over your car right now and make a
Speaker 4:  list of five things you wish to describe as a plinth and then go to wherever
Speaker 4:  you're going and just say it. Yeah. All the time.
Speaker 6:  If Panos had been there he would've said plinth. Yeah it would, it would've
Speaker 6:  been great. But they announced a new Surface Laptop go three.
Speaker 6:  So that's nice little upgrade there. And they announced a new Surface go
Speaker 6:  four. And I love a Surface go. That's one of my favorite devices in the world.
Speaker 6:  But it's also one of the most disappointing devices in the world. 'cause
Speaker 6:  it's so cute. Yeah. And it's so small and then it's so expensive
Speaker 6:  for what it is. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's also not meant for regular humans like this. This is like a business
Speaker 5:  device for business people. Right? Didn't they? They explicitly pitched it
Speaker 5:  to frontline workers this year. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So this year it is not gonna be sold to us, us normal folks. You're gonna
Speaker 6:  have to like go through your ID it department or something like that. It
Speaker 6:  is still gonna be outrageously expensive at $550. It is still gonna be
Speaker 6:  outrageous. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But if you're provisioning u p s
Speaker 6:  No but it's overpriced because it's got an Intel in 200.
Speaker 4:  Brutal. It's
Speaker 6:  Just like y'all did you try Monica
Speaker 6:  got to chest it out. She was not enthusiastic. It was, it was, it was still,
Speaker 6:  she could see the slow slowness of it. She, she and Tom. I
Speaker 5:  Love that. This is the device you've chosen to focus on so far. Cranz
Speaker 5:  the one device that people can't buy and the worst one by far. And you're
Speaker 5:  like, let's talk about that for a while. That
Speaker 6:  One's my favorite. 'cause it's so cute. And you're just like, want, it
Speaker 4:  Is cute. Everyone loves a cute little tablet. That sucks. All right. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  We all, we've all done it. We all, everybody every who hasn't bought a cute
Speaker 4:  little tablet? That sucks. I've, we've got
Speaker 6:  Four fire key like fire pads.
Speaker 4:  I've heard of Nexus seven for god's sake.
Speaker 5:  Okay, that didn't suck. How dare you
Speaker 4:  Come in? Like we wrapped it in leather, like a motorcycle. I was like, I
Speaker 4:  love you. And I was like, mm.
Speaker 6:  Leather's. Nice. All
Speaker 4:  Right. Tell me about the actual Laptop studio too. Does it have a good chip
Speaker 4:  in it? This is always the the crime. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  With Surface devices. So this was interesting 'cause it sounds like the the,
Speaker 6:  the Laptop too. They actually put the real chip in it. They put, they put
Speaker 6:  13th gen instead of 12 gen, which is like Microsoft's hallmark. They
Speaker 6:  love to put last gen stuff in. Yeah. And they're like, don't you wanna pay
Speaker 6:  the exact same price? No, no one wants to do that. So it
Speaker 6:  was really, really nice that they did that this time. I think the G P U is
Speaker 6:  still an older generation.
Speaker 4:  Of course. I mean it's always, there's always something. Oh
Speaker 6:  No it's, it's an R T X 40 50 or an R T X 40 60 G P U. So that's not
Speaker 6:  too bad and it's real pretty. The
Speaker 6:  last one was really cool like yeah
Speaker 4:  I was gonna get a Windows. Laptop I would get this one.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's the coolest one. Yeah. Is it really expensive? Do
Speaker 6:  most people need it? Probably not. But is it really, really, really cool?
Speaker 5:  It's a MacBook Pro, right? Like this is, this is
Speaker 6:  With a
Speaker 5:  Plin. This is actually a thing that the Windows
Speaker 5:  ecosystem doesn't have enough of. When you get to really powerful computers,
Speaker 5:  way too many of them tend to either get really big and really heavy or super
Speaker 5:  gamery and both of those things are for valid reasons and there are
Speaker 5:  real markets there. But I think one thing Microsoft
Speaker 5:  correctly sussed out with this line was we need a thing
Speaker 5:  that is very attractive. The the size is about right for
Speaker 5:  what it is and it's powerful And it does like
Speaker 5:  nifty surfacey things like the pull forward screen that it has. Yeah. Where
Speaker 5:  it sort of comes off its hinge and you can like drape it over the keyboard
Speaker 5:  is very cool. And if you're a person who uses a Surface pen a lot, it's really
Speaker 5:  useful. And it's like that to me is, I'm like this is how you make the MacBook
Speaker 5:  a touch device Apple. Like there it is. Yes that's the answer. But I feel
Speaker 5:  like I agree that this is not the one for most people but like this is
Speaker 5:  a good thing that should exist and it's good that Microsoft finally got it
Speaker 5:  right. I have the first Laptop studio here, it's my like go-to Windows
Speaker 5:  machine and I love it to bits but anytime you try to do
Speaker 5:  anything like intense on it, it just kind of falls apart. And I'm
Speaker 5:  kind, it seems like Microsoft went after this one. It has more ports that
Speaker 5:  has better power. Like it could be a win if they can get the battery life
Speaker 5:  right. That's gonna be the question. Do you think
Speaker 4:  His Panos is walking out the door? He's scratched out the previous
Speaker 4:  generation processor and was like put a good one in it. He,
Speaker 5:  He just turned the 12 into a 13 and said
Speaker 4:  Goodbye everybody with a bit Surface fan. He's peace. He was
Speaker 4:  like I got like one more thing by the good one.
Speaker 5:  The most interesting thing about this event by far to me was that it took
Speaker 5:  them 40 out of 60 minutes to even talk about hardware. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like this was not a devices event in the way that we're used
Speaker 5:  to. And the same is true of the Amazon event. Like both of these were events
Speaker 5:  about ai, right? Like the Microsoft spent the vast majority of this event
Speaker 5:  talking about Copilot and the idea that you're gonna have this AI
Speaker 5:  assistant that works in all of your apps and on your computer and on your
Speaker 5:  phone and understands everything about you and can just sort of stitch your
Speaker 5:  life together in this helpful AI way. And part of it was like
Speaker 5:  relaunching products we've heard a bunch about already, which was odd. They
Speaker 5:  like announced a new version of Windows but only in sort of passing as they
Speaker 5:  were talking about Copilot. Like this was with Copilot event in which they
Speaker 5:  launched hardware on which you might do co-pilot things. Which I think is
Speaker 5:  fascinating 'cause there was also this business insider story I believe today
Speaker 5:  Thursday as we're recording this, about why Panos left Microsoft. And one
Speaker 5:  of the answers was because he was frustrated that in this huge
Speaker 5:  switch to ai, Microsoft was devaluing its hardware because it's
Speaker 5:  building these things that work everywhere and who cares about having like
Speaker 5:  a flagship device. It's very funny that he would then go to Amazon,
Speaker 5:  which just spent a whole event doing the exact same thing. But like
Speaker 5:  clearly that's what Microsoft is doing, right? Like it's every Yeah. Big
Speaker 5:  bet it's making is about ai. Well
Speaker 6:  It's kind of interesting because this also all came on the same week that
Speaker 6:  there was a whole bunch of leaks about Microsoft
Speaker 6:  and in those leaks they were, it was some of those leaks were about the strategy
Speaker 6:  for Microsoft. And last year, as soon as last year they were all sitting
Speaker 6:  there, Satya was saying we have to have a unified strategy that pushes our
Speaker 6:  hardware, that pushes our software that does it all together. And for us
Speaker 6:  it's gonna be hybrid cloud computing. And so it
Speaker 6:  was this whole thing about game computing and how you were gonna gonna be
Speaker 6:  able to like do some of the processing on the computer and some of it in
Speaker 6:  the cloud. And that was the whole thing. And it seems like AI kind of like
Speaker 6:  has pushed that to the side and they're like, oh we now have a new unified
Speaker 6:  vision and it's AI and then Panos leaves and now it's like okay but the
Speaker 6:  hardware, what's happening with the hardware?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. There's no, like I said, it'd be better if they switch places. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But no one is in charge of hardware. I mean we have a memo and it's like
Speaker 4:  some people but they're shuffling new people into it. Dave
Speaker 5:  Limp coming in to be the Copilot guy actually makes a certain amount of sense
Speaker 5:  given what he's been up to at Amazon all these
Speaker 4:  Years. Do it just drive your cars in different direction guys. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Wave
Speaker 4:  Just like high five on the highway.
Speaker 4:  Let's talk about this Copilot stuff 'cause there's quite a bit of it, but
Speaker 4:  like David said, a lot of it's been announced already. Yeah. So Windows Copilot
Speaker 4:  seems like a big idea. Like the computer will use our computer for you,
Speaker 4:  but it also seems fairly limited. I think it's
Speaker 6:  A terrifying idea. I was talking with Tom about it before we came to
Speaker 6:  record The Vergecast and we were both like, yeah Copilot
Speaker 6:  seems really cool, but how are you gonna trust this AI that we
Speaker 6:  don't know is finished with your spreadsheets for your Fortune 500
Speaker 6:  company?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, you shouldn't do that.
Speaker 6:  Don't do that. And and so I, I really am kind of worried that their,
Speaker 6:  their ambition to show that they are the kings of AI and they're hip and
Speaker 6:  cool now and they beat Google is gonna shoot them in the
Speaker 6:  foot if they piss off all of,
Speaker 4:  Well I think it's important again, Google anti trial is going on. Yeah. The
Speaker 4:  punching bag in this trial is big, at least in secret. Yep. Somewhere in
Speaker 4:  secret. The United States government is just punching Bing in the face and
Speaker 4:  we don't know about it, but we know it's happening. We can detect that Bing
Speaker 4:  is being punched in the face but we can't actually wait. See it. Did you
Speaker 4:  hear it
Speaker 6:  Just got
Speaker 4:  Punched. But what is true is that Microsoft launched all this stuff with
Speaker 4:  Bing that made all this noise front page article in The, new York Times
Speaker 4:  and binging has gained zero market share.
Speaker 6:  Yep.
Speaker 4:  At least as far as anyone can tell. It doesn't case
Speaker 5:  It's zero, but it's gone from no one cares to, no one cares.
Speaker 6:  But now horny,
Speaker 4:  Right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's pretty weird in that room
Speaker 4:  no one goes into, it's like that car on the subway, you know, just don't,
Speaker 4:  don't go in that one. Don't go in that one. But like that's the answer, right?
Speaker 4:  It's like this stuff isn't working. So Microsoft's putting it more and more
Speaker 4:  places in the hopes that it will work. But the turn that is really interesting
Speaker 4:  for me is in Windows where you're like, change my display resolution
Speaker 4:  and it will just do it. Yeah. I, that's like a meaningful, the
Speaker 4:  last digital assistant that attempted to do this was Bixby,
Speaker 4:  but on Windows where it is pretty byzantine I think that might actually
Speaker 4:  make a big difference in how people use Windows. I mean,
Speaker 6:  Windows menus are garbage. And remember how for the longest
Speaker 6:  time they all still had like Windows seven ui even though they're like,
Speaker 6:  we have this new thing and it's great except for all of these really important
Speaker 6:  menus you have to use if you're testing laptops every day. Alex, Cranz,
Speaker 6:  that was just for me. But yeah, I, I just get so
Speaker 6:  nervous about how fast they're moving on AI at Microsoft.
Speaker 6:  Like I just spend a lot of time thinking about this seems like a bad
Speaker 6:  idea. It seems like you're going way too fast and this is gonna bite you
Speaker 6:  in the ass because you, they haven't had the ability to test this as
Speaker 6:  extensively as they'd like. And that's why we're seeing, like, that's why
Speaker 6:  Amazon is going kind of slow here. Even though Amazon did this big announcement
Speaker 6:  and showed all this stuff, they're still going slow and Microsoft is like
Speaker 6:  full Steam ahead on releasing this and bringing this stuff to market and
Speaker 6:  putting this in everybody's hands. And it does need to be in hands, right?
Speaker 6:  Like it needs to be tested, but is the best place to test it.
Speaker 6:  The, the install base for all of the companies that
Speaker 6:  currently pay you lots of money to use your software. I don't think
Speaker 6:  that's the best. Well,
Speaker 4:  You have to pay $30 a seat to use in an office. Yeah. So I, I think
Speaker 4:  that pricing is a bit of a test. I also think it's a bit of a barrier.
Speaker 6:  It'll keep a lot of people out, but
Speaker 4:  The only person who should be using AI and Excel at your company is the person
Speaker 4:  who is best to excel right at this moment. Yeah. To just let you know
Speaker 4:  what it can and can't do. Well,
Speaker 5:  And, and that's actually, that's a pretty good example, right? And I, 'cause
Speaker 5:  I think what Microsoft would say, and I think did say at a, at a
Speaker 5:  panel they did after their event today was basically like,
Speaker 5:  don't trust this thing to do something you can't do
Speaker 5:  yourself. Yes. Just trust it to help you. Right. And I think that
Speaker 5:  is the right, like having the Excel expert say, okay,
Speaker 5:  here's this menial thing I do a hundred times a day. Can the AI do it for
Speaker 5:  me? Is actually a pretty useful and like instructive test. But for me to
Speaker 5:  just go in and be like, Hey Copilot, we making money
Speaker 5:  or what? It's like that's a bad idea. We shouldn't do that. You should do
Speaker 5:  that all the time.
Speaker 4:  I'll pay $30 a seat for you to
Speaker 9:  Do that.
Speaker 5:  How's the money Copilot?
Speaker 5:  And, and I think we're in this place now where with so much ai,
Speaker 5:  it's like if you wanna do dumb stuff, it's gonna
Speaker 5:  go poorly for you and people will do dumb stuff
Speaker 5:  and it's gonna go poorly for them. And I think there are really interesting
Speaker 5:  questions to be asked about whether we should be protected from that as people,
Speaker 5:  it's like, it's the, the self-driving stuff, right? Like if you have a thing
Speaker 5:  that's called a self-driving car, people are gonna do dumb, they're gonna
Speaker 5:  fall asleep and have sex in the backseat and that is not what they should
Speaker 5:  be doing, but they're gonna do it. And so what's your responsibility as the
Speaker 5:  one making that? It's a really interesting question, but I think at some
Speaker 5:  point if I'm Microsoft, you just have
Speaker 5:  to like throw it out there and do your best. And
Speaker 5:  I think the way they're pitching it is really interesting because it's like,
Speaker 5:  it's not a tool for doing
Speaker 5:  spectacular business calculations. It's like a way to
Speaker 5:  play a Spotify playlist, right? Yeah. It's like doing the things that are
Speaker 5:  easy and and tractable and you know how to do, but take 12 clicks,
Speaker 5:  you can just do it with a command now. And that's the kind of stuff that
Speaker 5:  this stuff is generally pretty good at. But then like
Speaker 5:  I think Microsoft has been trying to do this with binging all year too, is
Speaker 5:  figure out how to put a ceiling on that that where it's like, okay, we want
Speaker 5:  you to be able to do this stuff without doing all the dumb shit we know people
Speaker 5:  are gonna do as soon as they're allowed to. And I don't think anybody has
Speaker 5:  figured out that answer yet.
Speaker 6:  I don't think there, there is an answer to that. Like people don't like it
Speaker 6:  when you say, oh you have all of this access to technology, you only get
Speaker 6:  this little bit, right? Yeah. No one like that. That's what bar did
Speaker 5:  And it sucks. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You hate it. Yeah. So
Speaker 4:  Someone told me that LLMs are uniquely good at teaching you
Speaker 4:  how to make chemical weapons because there's so much information about building
Speaker 4:  chemical weapons in the quad that they've just learned it all. And like now
Speaker 4:  we're at the point where like, you shouldn't let them do that. No. But like
Speaker 4:  now it's just built into the sidebar of Windows.
Speaker 6:  No, you just do it. Well, not yet. Not yet. It's coming
Speaker 6:  September 26th.
Speaker 4:  All right, so that's, that was this Microsoft event. Copilot everywhere.
Speaker 4:  Basically a little bit of new hardware. Then there's the other Microsoft
Speaker 4:  event,
Speaker 6:  The big event, the
Speaker 4:  One that you weren't supposed to see, which is, and I want to be very clear
Speaker 4:  about this 'cause there is some narrative out there. The F T C leaked
Speaker 4:  Microsoft's documents. That is absolutely not what happened. So F T C
Speaker 4:  versus Microsoft happens lots and lots of documents are getting uploaded.
Speaker 4:  We can see them all in the docket. The court clarifies Microsoft was
Speaker 4:  asked to do some stuff, failed to redact these documents,
Speaker 4:  just publish them for everyone to see. So Microsoft's just like screwed up
Speaker 4:  in a massive way here.
Speaker 6:  I mean, I'm not complaining,
Speaker 4:  No one's complaining, but the leaks are out of control. There's a new Xbox
Speaker 4:  series X, another new Xbox, a new controller, Phil
Speaker 4:  Spencer idly wanting to buy Nintendo where to begin
Speaker 6:  The controller. Yeah. Yes, I, yeah. Yes. Alex the controller is cool.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Right. It's got the haptics, like the PSS five
Speaker 6:  controller. So it, it'll feel like more real when you
Speaker 6:  do stuff. I don't know if, if all of our listeners have a PS five buy one,
Speaker 6:  it's a lot easier now I we spend that $500 but the haptics feel really
Speaker 6:  cool in it. And this is supposed to have that, it's supposed to be kinda
Speaker 6:  like Stadia where it's got like those haptics also do
Speaker 6:  double as like volume. It's like if you're getting shot or at or something,
Speaker 6:  you'll still feel it and hear it. That's just cool. Like,
Speaker 6:  I don't know, it's just a neat controller. It's gonna have replaceable joysticks
Speaker 6:  out of the box right now you have to spend like what, $250 for a Microsoft
Speaker 6:  Elite controller or one of something from SCUFF or something. And you
Speaker 6:  won't have to do that. It'll just be there. And if you wanna replace the
Speaker 6:  joysticks because you like dig in and kind of distort them because you play
Speaker 6:  too hard, I don't know anybody who does that. But if you do, you'll be
Speaker 6:  able to replace it. That's neat.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's a cool controller. And also I think the, the vision
Speaker 5:  behind it is super rad, which is basically like Microsoft is in this place
Speaker 5:  now where they want you to be able to play all of your games,
Speaker 5:  all of the places, right? Like it's cloud gaming is, is a huge part of this.
Speaker 5:  There was a leak in here that Microsoft is planning to stream PC games
Speaker 5:  through cloud gaming. And there's this line
Speaker 5:  in the roadmap document that came out that says,
Speaker 5:  controller becomes the hero. The new Xbox controller is the only thing you
Speaker 5:  need to play on every device. And the idea is that the
Speaker 5:  controller connects to wifi itself or to your console
Speaker 5:  or over Bluetooth. And so it becomes the console in a
Speaker 5:  super real way. And all you need is a screen and a controller and suddenly
Speaker 5:  you're up and running. It's a very like Stadia vision of the world. And I
Speaker 5:  think that was the single smartest thing about Stadia that ever existed.
Speaker 5:  And I think this idea of like the controller being the thing and you can
Speaker 5:  play anywhere as long as you have the controller is so cool. And I really
Speaker 5:  hope it becomes real.
Speaker 6:  I really, I like that's the thing that I really hope this AI stuff that
Speaker 6:  Microsoft has focused on doesn't distract that much from the cloud gaming
Speaker 6:  things that they're doing because it's so cool.
Speaker 4:  So in these leaks over and over again, Microsoft is like
Speaker 4:  the Xbox is our play for the consumer. Yeah. Yeah. They're not
Speaker 4:  shy about it. Yeah. Phil, Spencer is like, this is the thing that we do for
Speaker 4:  the consumer and like Nadella is like, this is the thing we do for a consumer
Speaker 4:  and also it all runs in Azure. So just like keep that in mind. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  just that's where the money is filled.
Speaker 6:  Don't get too ahead of
Speaker 4:  Yourself. So that's a controller. Tell me about these consoles
Speaker 6:  Disc free. Like that's a big deal. Like I guess for the Xbox series
Speaker 6:  X because the original one had the DISC player separates it
Speaker 6:  from a lot of the other stuff, including PlayStation. Most people don't actually
Speaker 6:  need or want the DISC player. Yeah. Like it's great if you wanna watch movies.
Speaker 4:  I have a digital PSS five and just never comes up. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Most people just go and more storage, which is crucial. I think
Speaker 6:  it's going from one terabyte to two terabytes theoretically.
Speaker 6:  Obviously this is leaked, it could totally change before it comes to market
Speaker 6:  if it comes to market. But yeah. And it sounds like there's another
Speaker 6:  Microsoft Elite controller in the works, which I'm really curious to see
Speaker 6:  how it's gonna build on on this. This leaked
Speaker 6:  cloud gaming controller like just seems cool as hell.
Speaker 5:  It does. There's also apparently an Xbox that has been planned for
Speaker 5:  2028. And we should say by the way, that these are all older
Speaker 5:  documents that may or may not exist in the current
Speaker 5:  reality. Yeah. Like a lot of stuff people were planning a couple of years
Speaker 5:  ago when like Bitcoin was a billion dollars
Speaker 5:  and money was free and everything was fantastic. Like the vibes are
Speaker 5:  very different now and people have made very income
Speaker 6:  Plans and we've seen some of the stuff already canceled. Like the,
Speaker 4:  By the way, in the grand scheme of leaks, the best leak to get is the email
Speaker 4:  about the leaks that leaks. Yes. So Phil Spencer emailed Xbox
Speaker 4:  team Tom Got it. Because you know Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And Phil says the Xbox team. I know this is disappointing even if many of
Speaker 4:  the documents are over a year old and our plans have evolved.
Speaker 5:  Right. But lemme just say, so the the one other Xbox that was, yeah.
Speaker 4:  Now back to the real estate. Now
Speaker 5:  Who cares? Whatever. Let's assume all of this is real. 'cause I want most
Speaker 5:  of it to be, 'cause it seems very cool. There's this plan for
Speaker 5:  a whole new, it seems generation of consoles in 2028
Speaker 5:  that is basically, I think they call it a hybrid gaming
Speaker 5:  platform.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. This was what we were talking about earlier in the show. They
Speaker 6:  wanna basically have it. So the really big processing, the
Speaker 6:  really hard stuff happens in the cloud and Then, we do some of the other
Speaker 6:  stuff smaller locally. And we've heard this talked about before. Sean's written
Speaker 6:  about it. I definitely have said on this show, it's stupid and will never
Speaker 6:  happen. I guess I'm wrong. That's totally fine. And
Speaker 6:  it, it's, it's a really compelling idea if they can make it work. But it's
Speaker 6:  gonna require like a bunch, like they talk about this in their roadmap and,
Speaker 6:  and in the story that Sean wrote about this, that it is really
Speaker 6:  complex issue. There's a lot of like silicon stuff they, they have to do
Speaker 6:  a lot of processor stuff they have to figure out. That will make it really,
Speaker 6:  really tricky. But if it works then you can have like
Speaker 6:  the really expensive quality of a pc. Like you know, those
Speaker 6:  $3,000 PC rigs that people do, four K, gorgeous,
Speaker 6:  everything turned to ultra. You could have that on an Xbox,
Speaker 6:  which is currently totally incapable of that. And you could have it at
Speaker 6:  that Xbox price. And that's, that would be very compelling for a lot of
Speaker 6:  people.
Speaker 5:  Or even further down. I mean there's a, there's a line in one of those documents
Speaker 5:  that says they want to sell something for under $99
Speaker 5:  as like a handheld device. And if anyone ever gets this right,
Speaker 5:  it basically means anything with a screen
Speaker 5:  becomes a powerful gaming system. And if you have more local power,
Speaker 5:  it'll do more locally. And so you'll get a slightly better experience if
Speaker 5:  you have less power, it'll do more in the cloud. So you'll have a slightly
Speaker 5:  worse experience but still get functionally the same thing. And if we get
Speaker 5:  to the like, holy God, is that a hard technical thing to do for so, so, so
Speaker 5:  many reasons. But if we get there that kicks ass like that is the
Speaker 5:  future of how we use computers that I would very much like to live in. I
Speaker 5:  mean it's,
Speaker 6:  It's essentially the like Kindle Ling of of
Speaker 6:  Xbox where you
Speaker 5:  Could play games on your Kindle where
Speaker 4:  It's like, we got it. Anything with a screen bro,
Speaker 6:  We're just trying to get you some hardware so that you can actually go do
Speaker 6:  what we want you to do. Which is buy a lot of games, spend money in our marketplaces.
Speaker 6:  That's like, that's always been the big get for Sony and for Microsoft
Speaker 6:  and moving into that cloud gaming would really like making
Speaker 6:  cloud gaming actually succeed in this fashion would
Speaker 6:  do that. 'cause okay, I spent a hundred bucks and I get the exact same,
Speaker 6:  like a very similar experience to my friend who spent 500 bucks or my friend
Speaker 6:  who spent yeah 3000 and built it all himself. Like just makes things a lot
Speaker 6:  more equitable. So
Speaker 4:  What's funny about all of this, does all this happening, we're we
Speaker 4:  we're Microsoft's running ahead with these plans contextually
Speaker 4:  right now Apple's like the phone is the best game console ever
Speaker 4:  made. Sure iPhone Pro is best, right? And they're all local all the time.
Speaker 4:  And Microsoft can never put a cloud gaming service on the iPhone for like
Speaker 4:  a billion different reasons. Through
Speaker 6:  The web browser, through through
Speaker 4:  The web press fine.
Speaker 6:  Go through Safari.
Speaker 4:  That's like one pressure on this. Yeah. Then the other pressure is that Nintendo
Speaker 4:  exists. Mm. And Nintendo's relationship with the internet
Speaker 4:  is shaky.
Speaker 5:  Nintendo knows the exists.
Speaker 6:  It acknowledges. Yeah. Yeah. I was about to say it knows it exists. Does
Speaker 6:  it want to use it? No. It took so long to get to cloud gaming was, I think
Speaker 6:  it was like last year or the year before that. Yeah. Before it was finally
Speaker 6:  like you can save things on the cloud and use it on your knees.
Speaker 6:  I'm just
Speaker 4:  Saying look at the structure of the game industry right now. The structure
Speaker 4:  of the games in the iPhone. Yeah. All Candy Crush Freeda
Speaker 4:  plays Dlcss, the whole thing. Nintendo biggest game
Speaker 4:  of the century in tears of the Kingdom announces
Speaker 4:  it will not have a D L C because it is complete and just an
Speaker 4:  incredible like beautiful,
Speaker 5:  The flex that that is is so, so powerful. It's like, what
Speaker 5:  more do you
Speaker 4:  Want it So? we don't need to make more money off this game.
Speaker 5:  The last line was to keep exploring high rules. It's like hell yeah. No,
Speaker 4:  It's like you haven't found habit but it's like just incredible weird competitive
Speaker 4:  pressures, right? Yeah. That are nothing to do with this like hybrid future
Speaker 4:  of computing idea one apple's like it's all local and you No, no
Speaker 4:  thank you sir. And Nintendo's like, what
Speaker 6:  Put is internet, please
Speaker 4:  Continue exploring my roll on our console that has like the
Speaker 4:  processing power of like a mid-range H T C phone from 2011. Like
Speaker 4:  whatever, you know. So then in just in, I'm putting that in
Speaker 4:  context to tell you about this email from Phil Spencer where
Speaker 4:  he's like buying Nintendo would be a career moment. He says, I totally
Speaker 4:  agree that Nintendo is the capital V prime asset for us in
Speaker 4:  gaming. And today gaming is our most likely path to consumer Rev relevance.
Speaker 4:  I've had numerous conversations with what we think is lt.
Speaker 4:  I've had numerous conversations with the leadership team of Nintendo about
Speaker 4:  tighter collaboration and feel like if any US company would have a chance
Speaker 4:  with Nintendo, we are probably in the best position. The
Speaker 4:  unfortunate situation or fortunate for Nintendo, he says in parentheses
Speaker 4:  is that they're sitting on a big pile of cash and they have a board of directors
Speaker 4:  that Intel recently has not pushed for further increases in market growth
Speaker 4:  or stock appreciation.
Speaker 5:  The problem with Nintendo is that Nintendo's good.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They're like, Nintendo is a bunch of money and the people who run it
Speaker 4:  are like pretty happy with it.
Speaker 4:  It's like, okay, good luck.
Speaker 5:  It's the most like ruthless capitalist VC
Speaker 5:  funded thing I've ever heard in my life. They're like, how you, you
Speaker 5:  don't want my money? What do I do?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's like your board of re So then he is like, this guy's been buying
Speaker 4:  up shares and hopefully he'll do it. And he is like, I, we've shown the full
Speaker 4:  write up on Nintendo and Valve, interestingly to the Microsoft board of
Speaker 4:  directors and they're fully supportive. S m i, but that it's just like all
Speaker 4:  this stuff, all this technology stuff just sort of falls down in the face
Speaker 4:  of, well, the biggest platform on earth and, and mobile
Speaker 4:  they can't do the thing with and then the best game
Speaker 4:  platform. It's just like whatever. I mean like focus on
Speaker 4:  the games.
Speaker 6:  That's why they've been pretty actively on Epic side
Speaker 6:  for every single one of these Google and, and Apple V
Speaker 4:  By wait, when I say the best game player don't come for me. I'm quoting Phil
Speaker 4:  Spencer saying Nintendo is the prime asset for us in gaming
Speaker 4:  today. That's what the head of Xbox thinks about Nintendo. Not me.
Speaker 4:  I play Madden and I quit playing Zelda right when I got to can.
Speaker 4:  'cause I didn't want to grind for shit so I could beat him. You're it's up.
Speaker 4:  Which apparently is like extraordinarily common in this game.
Speaker 6:  I think that's most people. Yeah. I only did it in like, it was like late
Speaker 6:  at night one day and I went, okay, I'm just gonna do it. Why not? Let's just
Speaker 6:  go.
Speaker 4:  I was like, look, I have a job, all right. I don't, I'm not gonna go look
Speaker 4:  for fruit to kill this guy. Like whatever. You just know that I could
Speaker 4:  Gannon and I shut down my switch and I walked away.
Speaker 6:  Never touched it again.
Speaker 4:  But I just think that's a weird position for the ex especially 'cause they're
Speaker 4:  a third place console.
Speaker 6:  I don't necessarily think it's a weird position because I think they, they
Speaker 6:  are really like, they have a strategy to deal with Apple and their
Speaker 6:  strategy is to say Epic fix it. And and they've they've
Speaker 6:  put a lot of effort into that, right? Like, like they've, they've been on
Speaker 6:  Epic's side for the majority of both of these trials saying, no, no,
Speaker 6:  they're right because they need cloud gaming to appear on these platforms.
Speaker 6:  And they have their work around now with, with streaming and stuff like that.
Speaker 6:  And Apple's doing its whole gaming thing. But Apple's gaming thing, as much
Speaker 6:  as it says it's where gaming happens,
Speaker 6:  game developers have different
Speaker 4:  Feelings. Oh no, we're we're starting to get the emails from the iPhone gamers.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They're they're there, they're starting to come in. They're there and
Speaker 6:  you guys exist and I love you, but like, you're not like,
Speaker 4:  Wow. Yeah, yeah. Watch it. You're
Speaker 6:  You're, you're different.
Speaker 4:  We gotta take a break. Yeah, we gotta take a break. Come back and talk about
Speaker 4:  YouTube and do a little light. Send
Speaker 6:  All of all of your feelings about that to Neli. No
Speaker 4:  Thank you.
Speaker 6:  Neli Patel at the
Speaker 4:  T com. Look, here's what I know. You can talk about Android gamers like,
Speaker 4:  'cause they don't exist. You mention that it's silly that Apple thinks the
Speaker 4:  word pro. I means mobile gaming and the emails come
Speaker 6:  And I know you guys, you can use the controller and you can play it. And
Speaker 6:  I, I think that's great. I wanna use my phone for phone stuff.
Speaker 6:  I don't wanna use it for game stuff. That's why I've got a switch and
Speaker 6:  40,000 other consoles get with the program. I just would
Speaker 5:  Like it on the record that everything Alex just said is wrong and I do not
Speaker 5:  agree with it. Yeah. And I would not like to be associated with the emails
Speaker 5:  that you're going to send.
Speaker 6:  Come at me. You're all incorrect.
Speaker 4:  I have a family. We're taking a break.
Speaker 4:  All right.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. Should we do this YouTube thing very quickly and then
Speaker 4:  do a lightning round? Yeah, we can do it fast. Yeah. So YouTube ad event
Speaker 4:  today made on YouTube a bunch of influencers. I told Charlie
Speaker 4:  Poth was there, Mia who went told me that photos and videos were not not
Speaker 4:  allowed and then Charlie PO came out and all decorum went to the
Speaker 4:  woods and people were just like, I'm doing it. Nah. And he was like, what
Speaker 4:  about a song that went like this? Two, two dude. Like he did the thing Charlie
Speaker 4:  Po. It's great
Speaker 4:  Nature's original creator.
Speaker 4:  What's the call? Right? I've
Speaker 5:  Been trying to profile Charlie Poth for like four years. Charlie, if you're
Speaker 5:  listening, get at me. Let's do
Speaker 4:  This. Yeah, we we're in for it. Our people will obey the no
Speaker 4:  photos and videos. Scroll or will they? Ooh. See
Speaker 4:  every pitch needs a little danger in it. All right, so they announced a bunch
Speaker 4:  of AI stuff. Big theme of all these events. Yep. AI stuff. So this is
Speaker 4:  Google's turn, right with YouTube. So dream screen,
Speaker 4:  which lets you create a background for shorts, generative ai, they showed
Speaker 4:  a bunch of silly stuff. Mia asked a bunch of questions about what the guardrails
Speaker 4:  on that would be. For example, what if you ask it to generate a background
Speaker 4:  for YouTube Short that violates YouTube's policies?
Speaker 8:  I just thought of four.
Speaker 4:  It's not hard. For example, what if you would like a say a
Speaker 4:  Dukes of Hazard themed background for YouTube before
Speaker 6:  I went in a different direction? But yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's just like that's a even that's just a challenging question
Speaker 4:  for a million horrible reasons. So
Speaker 5:  Many.
Speaker 4:  But so it goes, so you two has to figure that out. They said it won't do
Speaker 4:  any of that stuff, but we'll see. Yeah. So that's really interesting. David,
Speaker 4:  you were quite taken with Dream screen.
Speaker 5:  I think it's really interesting. I think this question of
Speaker 5:  how do you give creators tools to use generative
Speaker 5:  AI without giving them tools to make so
Speaker 5:  much awful generated crap that it ruins your
Speaker 5:  platform is like the question of the internet right now. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And it's one we've talked about a lot and I think YouTube is way behind on
Speaker 5:  giving its creators native tools to make things. And
Speaker 5:  this is a way to get into that I just think is really interesting. And like
Speaker 5:  starting with backgrounds is clever, but there's also a thing where
Speaker 5:  the AI tools in the YouTube studio will start to generate
Speaker 5:  topic ideas for creators that it says are personalized to the things that
Speaker 5:  those creators are doing that already work. So like
Speaker 5:  I have a thousand things I hate about that, but I think it's fascinating.
Speaker 5:  And we're in this place now. We're like, everybody is trying to like relentlessly
Speaker 5:  game the algorithm to be successful on YouTube and now the algorithm is
Speaker 5:  just gonna tell you what to do.
Speaker 4:  Yes. That's nuts.
Speaker 5:  This is the thing.
Speaker 4:  This is the most incredible announcement of the entire thing. And it
Speaker 4:  was buried, right? They did dream screen, they did The new editor on mobile,
Speaker 4:  which is basically cap cut, it's called YouTube Create.
Speaker 5:  The only thing to say about that is it's bonkers that that didn't exist a
Speaker 5:  decade ago.
Speaker 4:  They did. They had a thing, YouTube capture or whatever it was called, it
Speaker 4:  was just really bad. Yeah. And it doesn't count, right? Yeah, it isn't nuts
Speaker 4:  by the way. The YouTube is the platform. It is. And basically Final
Speaker 4:  Cut Pro and iMovie and Adobe Premiere Yeah. Are the native CRE
Speaker 4:  creation tools for you. Like that's crazy. Yeah. This
Speaker 6:  Pre, it predates phones being like the primary computing device for people.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But we've been doing this a while now. But sorry, Neli, I derailed
Speaker 5:  you. What were you about to say? So
Speaker 4:  This thing, this automated AI insights thing,
Speaker 4:  I am obsessed with it. It's we, it they buried it, right? It's not like the
Speaker 4:  big flashy consumer feature, but basically, if I'm getting it right,
Speaker 4:  YouTube is gonna look at a creator's analytics. They're gonna say, here's
Speaker 4:  what's working well for you. Then they're gonna look at everyone else's analytics
Speaker 4:  and say, Hey, inside of your library is stuff, you should make
Speaker 4:  more stuff like this. 'cause it performs better for all the other people,
Speaker 4:  which is Right. There's a universe in which creators could hire analytics
Speaker 4:  people. You, you can get there, right? And like big
Speaker 4:  media companies have analytics people that do this stuff, but then there's
Speaker 4:  just the robot telling people make this stuff
Speaker 4:  to get views. Well,
Speaker 5:  And I mean we, we've been through this in so many sort of specific instances,
Speaker 5:  right? Like the, the Johnny Depp Amber Heard trial was one where all kinds
Speaker 5:  of people just started doing that because it was obvious. That's how you
Speaker 5:  get views. This robot is just gonna tell everybody to make Mr. Beast videos.
Speaker 5:  Like that's just what it's
Speaker 4:  Gonna be. We don't know what we think. We don't know.
Speaker 6:  Will it be mouth open or closed on the thumbnail?
Speaker 5:  Unbelievable question. If Mr. Beast isn't getting a cut of this for being
Speaker 5:  the one like training at the best with the best stuff. It's a real shame.
Speaker 5:  But no, I think you're right. And I think this question of whether YouTube
Speaker 5:  can build a system that is like creative and personalized
Speaker 5:  and helpful, or if it's just going to tell people
Speaker 5:  to do more of what's already working everywhere on YouTube until
Speaker 5:  everybody is doing the same thing with the same generative AI tools and the
Speaker 5:  same music library that looks the same. Like unclear,
Speaker 6:  Kind of feels like it's gonna be that given our
Speaker 6:  extensive history. Well, no, with every other push in social media one
Speaker 6:  based on algorithms,
Speaker 4:  Time remains undefeated. Okay. And people get older. It's
Speaker 6:  True.
Speaker 4:  These kids, I hate
Speaker 6:  It, but true. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And people get bored. And so, you know, I am a
Speaker 4:  firm believer that data can only tell you about the past. This is like what
Speaker 4:  I believe in my heart. If, if we followed our own analytics,
Speaker 4:  we would only cover the iPhone. Yes. That's all we would do. It is the
Speaker 4:  it is, we're not doing that. I know, I know you're mad at me for saying it.
Speaker 4:  The end of this f has gotten real spiky. But I promise
Speaker 4:  you, if I just did what people clicked on, we would write about the iPhone
Speaker 4:  fi find one case 500 times a day and Elon Musk for the rest
Speaker 4:  of our lives. Yep. And we, we don't do it 'cause we're bored. We don't wanna
Speaker 4:  do it. Yeah. We can, you know, like there's a thing here that we do where
Speaker 4:  we're like, decide what we're gonna do. But if you're fully analytics
Speaker 4:  driven, you just, that's a narrowing, right? It's just the,
Speaker 4:  the aperture of your interest just falls down and eventually you just make
Speaker 4:  one thing. Yeah. And I think most YouTubers are people and they have
Speaker 4:  that like instinct where they like push against it, but then there's a lot
Speaker 4:  of people who are there to just make money. Yeah. I was
Speaker 6:  About to like, my, my my big concern here is the people who wanna make money
Speaker 6:  tend to be really good at it and they tend to dominate the algorithm. And
Speaker 6:  then what we saw with Facebook, what we saw with even Google Ss e o is over
Speaker 6:  and over and over again. The thing that rises to the top isn't the quality
Speaker 6:  stuff. Yeah. It's the algorithm, the
Speaker 4:  Garbage. But that's thing, like David said at the very beginning, this is
Speaker 4:  the thing that kills your platform. Yeah. Like the dream screen generative
Speaker 4:  AI background is not the thing that kills YouTube. The
Speaker 4:  AI powered analytics that flattens all of YouTube into people just
Speaker 4:  fighting for the same kinds of attention. Well, on the other end is like
Speaker 4:  people as an audience. And if you only get one kind of thing from the
Speaker 4:  platform, eventually the audience gets bored too. Yeah. And I
Speaker 4:  don't, I don't know that YouTube is contended with that cycle, or, which
Speaker 4:  I think is a fair approach for YouTube. They're just like, it'll be fine.
Speaker 4:  'cause there's enough people who wanna be YouTubers. Well, and
Speaker 5:  The the optimistic take on this for YouTube would be that YouTube is not
Speaker 5:  just one thing, right? Like you, you can be a guy who stands in front
Speaker 5:  of your furnace and tells people how to use it and like make a career out
Speaker 5:  of being a YouTuber and to that person, if this tool is any good,
Speaker 5:  it's going to suggest new ways to make videos about furnaces. Right. But
Speaker 5:  it's like, yeah, if, if we get to the point where every creator on YouTube
Speaker 5:  is just being told to like, go livestream Taylor Swift's eras tour,
Speaker 5:  because that's how you make money on YouTube at this moment in time, we're
Speaker 5:  hosted and it's a perfectly plausible reality that that's where we land.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Do you think they start to change the surfacing though? For, for like what
Speaker 6:  you actually see? Like, will it be harder to find the guy
Speaker 6:  who does the TIS videos?
Speaker 4:  Well, no. 'cause that's search, you know, and like, I don't know. I just
Speaker 4:  think that, that this thing, like these recommendation algorithms, these,
Speaker 4:  these metrics
Speaker 4:  drive the dynamics of the platform more than anyone ever really wants to
Speaker 4:  admit. And so here the platform is gonna start interpreting the metrics for
Speaker 4:  you. And that's like some crazy shit's about to happen.
Speaker 4:  I like, I It's exciting in one way. It's also just like, I hope you're ready
Speaker 4:  for it. Yeah. You know? Yeah. All right. Let's do a really fast lightning
Speaker 4:  round. And Then, we gotta we gotta get outta the studio.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. There's like 40 more tech events to go to. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. We're, we're busy. My lightning round is, I'm gonna selfishly say
Speaker 6:  go read my blog. I wrote about how the future of cable bundling is here,
Speaker 6:  which is a David headline, by the way. It's pretty good. Beautiful. David
Speaker 6:  headline.
Speaker 4:  Oh, and it, it's so here, by the way, we are hearing Rivers. The strikes
Speaker 4:  might be over soon. We are.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They were saying as soon as today. But it is now we're recording.
Speaker 6:  It's about 4:00 PM We haven't heard anything. We'll see. All right,
Speaker 4:  David, what's yours?
Speaker 5:  Mine is the Google Bard chatbot can now
Speaker 5:  integrate with your Gmail and Docs and Google Drive
Speaker 5:  and actually like, go find information for you
Speaker 5:  in your other apps. And you look at that and it's like, oh, scary
Speaker 5:  privacy stuff. It's like my guys, it's all Google. They all have it anyway.
Speaker 5:  Don't worry about it. And genuinely, I have found it's totally useless
Speaker 5:  in some ways. But in, in the thing where you're like, I have an email about
Speaker 5:  a thing I don't really remember, but can you find that
Speaker 5:  email for me? It is like surprisingly good as a resource to just
Speaker 5:  dig through all my crap and find that one thing I was looking for. So this
Speaker 5:  is the time where I'm like, okay, this is like a, a digital assistant that
Speaker 5:  we're actually making into something. It's still Bard, so it's still not
Speaker 5:  very good, but it's, this was like the first step forward
Speaker 5:  I've seen for Bard where I'm like, all right, there's, there's something
Speaker 5:  here.
Speaker 4:  All right. I've done enough big thinky thinks on this episode. My lightning
Speaker 4:  round is that I'm sitting here holding a iPhone 15 pro in a fine loving
Speaker 4:  case. And my initials are fully scratched into the back of this case.
Speaker 6:  I can see them and
Speaker 4:  It's not
Speaker 5:  Great. It's as bad as advertised really. It's
Speaker 4:  As bad as advertised. I mean, it's, it's fine, but it's not great.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 6:  Fine. I wanna see you eat fried chicken and then pick it up.
Speaker 4:  No, thank you.
Speaker 6:  That's all I want.
Speaker 4:  All right. That's it. That's The Vergecast thing. We, it's, it's, September
Speaker 4:  continues. Next week we're at the code conference. We'll have links, lots
Speaker 4:  of coverage, lots of stuff has continues to go down here in the craziest
Speaker 4:  September. A fight careers tech journalist. That's it. We gotta go rock and
Speaker 4:  roll.
Speaker 8:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 8:  us an email at Vergecast at The Verge dot com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 8:  production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network. The show is produced
Speaker 8:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. Our
Speaker 8:  editorial director is Brooke Miners. That's it. We'll see you next week.