# Transcript
ID: e01e9f8c-8a48-4eee-b914-fc573f7bd1f9
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Big screens, bigger screens, suitcase screens
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7816251628086116822/3192767630043511469/s93290-US-5194s-1692352494.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, Alex Cranz, and Dan Seifert discuss the iMac's 25th anniversary, the state of streaming, a TV in a suitcase, and a whole lot more.
Speaker 1:  Support for this episode comes from Siren Marine, a Yamaha company.
Speaker 1:  At this point. smart Home Technology is everywhere and for good reason, Well
Speaker 1:  with siren, marine boat owners can take advantage of the same high tech
Speaker 1:  convenience. Their smart boat monitoring system makes it easy to monitor
Speaker 1:  your vessel's, vital signs from anywhere. With a simple app that offers realtime
Speaker 1:  information about battery levels, exact location, and so much more.
Speaker 1:  It all adds up to a connected boat that's more secure than ever before.
Speaker 1:  Siren. Marine Your. home is smart. Your boat should be too To. learn more.
Speaker 1:  Visit Siren Marine dot com slash Verge.
Speaker 2:  It's loading.
Speaker 3:  Wait. You're locked out of your air conditioner.
Speaker 4:  I turned it off. I turned it off.
Speaker 2:  Hello
Speaker 3:  And welcome to our cha, the flagship podcast of gadgets and
Speaker 3:  suitcases. We're bringing it back. So much of what's happening
Speaker 3:  in our culture now is things that have happened previously in our culture
Speaker 3:  and gadgets and suitcases is one of that's some old like 1960s
Speaker 3:  James Bond stuff and LG is bringing it back. We're gonna talk about that
Speaker 3:  a lot, but I'm your friend Neli. David. Pierce here.
Speaker 5:  Hi. I really like the fact that we've talked a lot about how like on the
Speaker 5:  internet it's 2006 again and with
Speaker 5:  gadgets it's 1958. Like I love it.
Speaker 5:  I'm all
Speaker 3:  In. We need a whole suitcase for this camera. Alex Cranz is here.
Speaker 4:  I always liked the the typewriter in a suitcase. Oh that's good like
Speaker 4:  that. That really had a nice appeal to me.
Speaker 3:  Again, more things need their own bespoke cases that you bring
Speaker 3:  around.
Speaker 4:  A hundred percent. I
Speaker 5:  Mean isn't this is the exact same energy as the resurgence of the flip phones,
Speaker 5:  right? Like the experience of I want to use the gadget to, I'm using
Speaker 5:  the gadget right now. It's just like you just like tap your screen. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  that's not enough. Make me do more mechanical stuff to use my
Speaker 5:  gadgets. I wanna have to like take a cover off of my television.
Speaker 5:  I want to have to plug some things in. I wanna like do incantations, like
Speaker 5:  make me work
Speaker 3:  One of those big pole switches like
Speaker 4:  Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I wanna have to turn a key while someone else on the other side of
Speaker 5:  the room also turns a key. Like that's, that's how I wanna use computers.
Speaker 3:  This is gonna be our new published process is like multiple key turns and
Speaker 3:  then a blog post goes out.
Speaker 4:  That's how you stay fast. That's
Speaker 3:  How you stay fast. That's really how You know like did I get it right? Like
Speaker 3:  I'm asking someone else to turn a key. I better have done this correctly.
Speaker 3:  Okay, so it's been one of those weeks where there's like lots of
Speaker 3:  little news going on. So there's lots to talk about. There is
Speaker 3:  a TV in a suitcase, which I suspect we're gonna talk about at length. There's
Speaker 3:  other bits of gadget news, there's a bunch of streaming news. Trump's
Speaker 3:  DMs have been subpoenaed from Twitter, which is amazing and we should talk
Speaker 3:  about just encryption in general as a concept. Lots of that
Speaker 3:  stuff. Dan Sever's gonna join us for the second segment. This week was the
Speaker 3:  25th anniversary of the iMac. We had a big package about that. Lots to talk
Speaker 3:  about there. And then of course we are pretty certain that there will be
Speaker 3:  a new iPhone in September. So I'll talk about that with Dan a little bit.
Speaker 3:  And what's coming, it seems like the camera bump shocker getting
Speaker 3:  bigger on the iPhone this year. It hasn't gone the other way in quite some
Speaker 3:  time. But let's start. There is one big thing happening in the world
Speaker 3:  of tech and media that several of you have asked us
Speaker 3:  to talk about. I've gotten some tweets, I've gotten some emails, I've gotten
Speaker 3:  some Instagram threads and it's what what's happening at at Linus Tech
Speaker 3:  Tips, big YouTube channel run by Linus Sebastian. We are reporting on
Speaker 3:  it. We have a story on it. Alex wrote that story. I sure did. People are
Speaker 3:  talking to us. The basics are like fairly simple. And
Speaker 3:  then what has happened is ever more complex. So Gamers Nexus did a video
Speaker 3:  calling out some inaccuracies in Linus tech Tips testing
Speaker 3:  policies, controversy with a G P U cooling block
Speaker 3:  that ended up at an auction and probably shouldn't have this
Speaker 3:  spiraled into a lot of craziness around that channel.
Speaker 3:  They released a video saying they were gonna pause production for a week,
Speaker 3:  that they'd gotten too sloppy, that they were running too hard and now there
Speaker 3:  are some allegations of sexual harassment in their workplace. That's a lot
Speaker 3:  from my perspective is editor-in-chief of The Verge. Our
Speaker 3:  contribution to this, insofar as we're gonna contribute to it is to do reporting,
Speaker 3:  is to make journalism. That's what we do here. So we're not gonna
Speaker 3:  overly comment or do analysis on that situation or
Speaker 3:  have opinions about it at this moment. We are gonna do some reporting and
Speaker 3:  figure out some real facts. That's what we're good at here in
Speaker 3:  particular. We're good at reporting on creators and we're pretty
Speaker 3:  good at understanding the dynamics of tech creators, right?
Speaker 3:  They're, they sit right next to us. We, we watch them very carefully. We
Speaker 3:  have lots of relationships with them, but we are not that thing. Like we
Speaker 3:  are not in platform dynamics in that way. Like that's, we are journalists
Speaker 3:  over here so we're just gonna maintain some of that distance So. we
Speaker 3:  can put some reporting into the situation. I think that's important. That's
Speaker 3:  where we're gonna be for a minute. The one thing I will say it has nothing
Speaker 3:  to this situation specifically or that channel or that company specifically
Speaker 3:  is that this pattern in media repeats pretty
Speaker 3:  often. So when we were all baby bloggers, we were
Speaker 3:  like screw the big newspapers. Like this is the beginning of my career
Speaker 3:  in the mid two thousands was a bunch of bloggers being like, the
Speaker 3:  institutional newspapers and magazines are garbage. We're gonna undo
Speaker 3:  them. We don't need all their process and all their dumb ethic.
Speaker 3:  Like we, I did it, I was there and now we have The Verge and it's like
Speaker 3:  hard fought over a decade later and we
Speaker 3:  have a huge ethics policy and like our disclosures on this podcast,
Speaker 3:  we do them so often that they're like a joke and we're like transparent about
Speaker 3:  our reporting standards and we have a background policy and if you look at
Speaker 3:  it you're like, oh shit. Like we just recapitulated all of the
Speaker 3:  things of traditional media because the pressure on us
Speaker 3:  as we got bigger and bigger was that we needed that stuff. And yes,
Speaker 3:  we got to reinvent it. And yes, we got yelled at a bunch along the way
Speaker 3:  about not having some of it, but it's largely the same as like what happened
Speaker 3:  before we did it our way. And I think we did it better than
Speaker 3:  some of the ways that had been done before. 'cause I think that's important
Speaker 3:  to try to improve, but we, we had to do it again. And that was like early
Speaker 3:  blogging. I think in general, like the YouTube
Speaker 3:  ecosystem is arriving at that place. So
Speaker 3:  other big YouTubers, they have ethics policies, they have review stamp,
Speaker 3:  they talk about that stuff and they need that stuff because that ultimately
Speaker 3:  protects you when you are at this scale for a lot of
Speaker 3:  reasons. And you need it to build trust with your audience. I think that
Speaker 3:  will happen to TikTok again in a really short order. We,
Speaker 3:  there's a story we quick posted this week in the Times about movie
Speaker 3:  reviewers on TikTok on movie talk who insist that they are not
Speaker 3:  Critics and they take money from the studios and they don't wanna
Speaker 3:  do negative reviews and all that's, and that's just the beginning of the
Speaker 3:  cycle, right? They're like, we're not these old fuddy duddy movie, movie
Speaker 3:  Critics, we're something new and eventually they're gonna, they're gonna
Speaker 3:  not be new.
Speaker 4:  I was like, that's what Harry Knowles said, right? Like 1999 when he
Speaker 4:  launched his movie site, right? Like we see this over and over and over again.
Speaker 4:  There's a new medium and everybody goes into like, you have new
Speaker 4:  access like right? There's different gatekeepers and so you're like, okay,
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna go become a robot, go do the cool things in this medium and
Speaker 4:  not do it like all the other people who've done it in other mediums before
Speaker 4:  me. And then you kind of discover that actually some of that
Speaker 4:  stuff makes sense and there's a reason they do it.
Speaker 3:  Yep. Your desire for access can corrupt you in like very specific ways
Speaker 3:  that are repeatable and understandable and predictable. Your
Speaker 3:  need to have the audience like you, especially on an algorithmic platform,
Speaker 3:  very predictable at this point. Like the pressures are the same and they,
Speaker 3:  they lead to the same outcomes and in particular
Speaker 3:  the algorithmic platforms, YouTube, Twitter, Instagram,
Speaker 3:  whatever, they kind of destabilize groups from working
Speaker 3:  together. It, they are very individualistic. So like there is not,
Speaker 3:  if you look at YouTube, David and I were talking about this today. If you
Speaker 3:  look at YouTube, big media brands are not successful on YouTube
Speaker 3:  that can ban together and say these are our standards and we will enforce
Speaker 3:  them. Like generally that is not the case on YouTube generally. That is not
Speaker 3:  the case on Instagram. It is all individuals. So individuals
Speaker 3:  run into these problems like over and over again at scale
Speaker 3:  and then disaster strikes.
Speaker 5:  Well, and that confluence you just described, I think is the thing that is
Speaker 5:  new, right? Like I think what we were all going through You know in,
Speaker 5:  in the early mid aughts in the sort of blogging revolution was like,
Speaker 5:  it, it was about sort of teams and websites or whatever. And then the next
Speaker 5:  thing that happened was very much the like individual creator.
Speaker 5:  And there's this thing that happens that happens to people over and over
Speaker 5:  and over on these platforms. You get big enough that you literally just
Speaker 5:  hit the ceiling of what you can do alone. So these folks are building out
Speaker 5:  and they're building big staffs and what you do is you end up sort of
Speaker 5:  exporting your own self onto other people as you try to build
Speaker 5:  a business because your audience is connected to you, like as a, as
Speaker 5:  a person. And and scaling that is really challenging. And I think
Speaker 5:  we've seen a lot of folks in a lot of different ways run into trouble with
Speaker 5:  like, how do I make this thing bigger than me when in fact
Speaker 5:  it is all about me? And that, that just becomes messy in so,
Speaker 5:  so many ways that I think no one or very few have like really
Speaker 5:  neatly figured out over time. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And I think it's also just unreasonable to say to an
Speaker 3:  individual creator, like uphold the standards and practices of the AP
Speaker 5:  Right. While running at the speed of every single platform that exists on
Speaker 5:  the internet, which is required for you to do in order to continue to be
Speaker 5:  successful in your business. Yeah. Like it's just, it's just not possible.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I, and I, and I think that's just very challenging and that that sort of
Speaker 3:  this thing I said at the very beginning like what we can contribute here
Speaker 3:  is some journalism. I mean that and we have the opportunity
Speaker 3:  to do it because we are under no pressure from the
Speaker 3:  algorithm to get views about this today. Like we just aren't You know.
Speaker 3:  And that's something that we fought hard for. That's why I care about our
Speaker 3:  website so much, right? We, we want to be apart from these platforms So,
Speaker 3:  we can report on them in a meaningful way. But I just see this,
Speaker 3:  this bigger story is the thing that has caught my interest here. Yes. This
Speaker 3:  the, these allegations are serious and yes, I think we need to report on
Speaker 3:  them and talk to all the principles and we are among the few sites that have
Speaker 3:  statements from some of the principles and Alex's story. I think that's important.
Speaker 3:  But it's because we spend our time insisting on
Speaker 3:  having statements from named principles in our stories. And we get to do
Speaker 3:  that because we run our own little platform and that cycle
Speaker 3:  of, okay, if I'm totally dependent on YouTube, I have to do whatever YouTube
Speaker 3:  wants me to do as a platform to get views. Like you can just see
Speaker 3:  how it just spirals outta control and no one over and over again like
Speaker 3:  YouTubers talk about this all the time. And very few people
Speaker 3:  have the opportunity to step out of that and say, look, I need to impose
Speaker 3:  my own principles here or I need to borrow some principles from other kinds
Speaker 3:  of media that have done this before instead of just, it's a raw
Speaker 3:  competition for attention and views on these platforms. So I just see that
Speaker 3:  very clearly, mostly because I lived through it as a baby in a different
Speaker 3:  medium. Like this has been my experience in media and we
Speaker 3:  have been lucky to say we are gonna build our thing as a
Speaker 3:  group under the brand of The Verge. And if I'm
Speaker 3:  not here, like the virtual will persist because it is a brand that
Speaker 3:  stands for something and like we own it. Like we, we
Speaker 3:  own our platform. Yes, we are very dependent on other
Speaker 3:  algorithmic traffic. Like yes, I've talked about that at length, but at the
Speaker 3:  end of the day, like our website is our website and we get to choose what
Speaker 3:  goes on it and not really overthink it. And like that's the distance that
Speaker 3:  I think is important that enables us to do journalism. But that is really
Speaker 3:  hard fought. Like at no point is that not on my mind
Speaker 3:  like these yeah, Alex and David like know, like this is what I think about
Speaker 3:  all day long. That's what we're gonna bring to this story. Like I don't wanna
Speaker 3:  overdo this conversation. I just see that pattern repeating and it's
Speaker 3:  at one stage for YouTube and it's another stage for TikTok and it's just
Speaker 3:  gonna keep happening as new media emerges. Yep. Alright, so
Speaker 3:  on that note, there are some YouTube news this week, which is kind of fascinating.
Speaker 3:  YouTube is a platform in a really interesting space, right? There's
Speaker 3:  YouTube Shorts and they're kind of adding some TikTok features and then there's
Speaker 3:  YouTube tv. And I guarantee you, with this coming football season, YouTube
Speaker 3:  TV is going to be the thing that they talk about and promote and think about
Speaker 3:  more than anything, which is wild because it's a cable
Speaker 3:  bundle.
Speaker 5:  It is and it isn't, right? So I, I've been talking to YouTube about this
Speaker 5:  for forever and the thing that is true about YouTube is it
Speaker 5:  has all of the pieces of everything
Speaker 5:  on its platform, right? Like every single entertainment thing you can
Speaker 5:  imagine exists somewhere inside of YouTube. And the thing
Speaker 5:  YouTube has never successfully done is put all those
Speaker 5:  pieces together, right? Like you look at YouTube music and it's like, okay,
Speaker 5:  you have a library of music, you also have every live performance, every,
Speaker 5:  you have this incredible library of covers that people do. You have all this
Speaker 5:  fan made stuff. Like how are you not figuring out how
Speaker 5:  to give me every imaginable Taylor Swift thing all in one place? I'm serious.
Speaker 5:  Like no platform has more of that than YouTube and
Speaker 5:  it has never successfully stitched all of it together. And I think
Speaker 5:  what it's trying to do with football is very much the same thing, right?
Speaker 5:  So they paid, what we've heard and reported was $2 billion a year for
Speaker 5:  NFL Sunday Ticket huge amount of money. There's I would say very little
Speaker 5:  chance that that is going to be like a strictly very profitable thing for
Speaker 5:  YouTube, especially in the early days. But what they're trying to do is figure
Speaker 5:  out, okay, how do we use that to essentially sell you a cable bundle? Which
Speaker 5:  like you said is deeply hilarious and we should talk more about the fact
Speaker 5:  that everything is just a cable bundle again. But they're also trying to
Speaker 5:  figure out how to, how to make it YouTube, right? Like one of the things
Speaker 5:  YouTube announced this week is that they're adding a bunch of features to
Speaker 5:  Sunday Ticket. They're gonna have live chat and polls inside a game,
Speaker 5:  which to me sounds like just like a waking nightmare. Like watching football
Speaker 5:  while a million internet strangers like yell about football sounds
Speaker 5:  awful. That's what Twitter used to be for, but I dunno, whatever. And they
Speaker 5:  added a thing where there's now gonna be a live set of Shorts
Speaker 5:  showing realtime highlights from every game on Sunday, which is
Speaker 5:  like technically really weird and complicated and I have lots of questions,
Speaker 5:  but is a really interesting idea. And they're doing all this stuff
Speaker 5:  with creators that they're not really talking about yet. But basically what
Speaker 5:  it seems like is YouTube creators are gonna have kind of
Speaker 5:  unlimited access to a huge amount of football content.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Which is gonna be really interesting and is the kind of thing that
Speaker 5:  creators have not had easy access to before. So there's this thing where
Speaker 5:  YouTube is like, okay, we have football, like boil it all the way down, right?
Speaker 5:  Like we have a, we have football plays that happen on a field.
Speaker 5:  What are like all of the YouTubey things we can do with them? Which I just
Speaker 5:  think is like the most interesting question in the universe. And I think
Speaker 5:  YouTube like has barely any idea of all of the answers that there are to
Speaker 5:  that. But it's gonna be super interesting to like see how all of that shakes
Speaker 5:  out.
Speaker 3:  The creator side is the most interesting thing because it, there's no lack
Speaker 3:  of football plays on YouTube right now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But if you, if you like steal it, you run the risk of like a copyright
Speaker 5:  strike and it's like things can get kind of awkward. Like one thing I watch
Speaker 5:  a lot of is people talking about soccer, right? And there's like this
Speaker 5:  weird game you have to play if you are not the rights holder,
Speaker 5:  where they'll show like awkward animated stick figure
Speaker 5:  pictures of people moving around to like demonstrate tactics.
Speaker 5:  Or there's one guy who does a great thing where it's like an overhead shot
Speaker 5:  of what looks like a, the old Microsoft surface where he'll like
Speaker 5:  move little things around on the screen and people do these sort of clever
Speaker 5:  hacks to get around the fact that they can't actually just use the game.
Speaker 5:  And, and what the NFL is now doing is saying all of these people who wanna
Speaker 5:  make things about football like here have the game and you've been
Speaker 5:  able to watch highlights before but you've never been able to like use them
Speaker 5:  in the way that like you can use music. And I think that is big,
Speaker 3:  That's a good comparison to music, right? Like all the social
Speaker 3:  platforms apart from Twitter, we should, we can talk about that briefly,
Speaker 3:  but all the social platforms basically have blanket
Speaker 3:  licenses to the music catalogs and then creators can use them and
Speaker 3:  there's content ID and blah blah blah and the right to get paid when you
Speaker 3:  use music on YouTube. I'm skipping over an awful lot of
Speaker 3:  complexity there, but that's, that's how that's supposed to work.
Speaker 4:  That's fine, that's fine.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Whereas sports leagues have not issued these sort of blanket
Speaker 3:  licenses. So this is like the first time with a major league
Speaker 3:  in a huge setting that this has been enabled.
Speaker 3:  I'm sort of curious how it works.
Speaker 5:  I am too. Like is
Speaker 3:  There, are they gonna do content id for football play? Like I, I, I just
Speaker 3:  dunno the answer to that question.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. YouTube has not super explained all of that. There's a lot
Speaker 5:  left to do and I get the sense there's a lot they haven't quite figured out
Speaker 5:  yet and I think are probably gonna spend this first season figuring out.
Speaker 5:  But like that's very much the road they're heading down and I think it's
Speaker 5:  really interesting.
Speaker 4:  Why can't you just use the clips and comment on them? Because like with movies
Speaker 4:  and film, like movies and TV shows, you can just be like, here it is.
Speaker 4:  I'm talking about these two people talking because
Speaker 5:  The Roger Goodell, the commissioner of the NFL will come to your house and
Speaker 5:  beat you to death. Yeah. Is basically like, truly like sports
Speaker 5:  leagues are at the bleeding edge of being incredibly
Speaker 5:  litigious about people using their stuff that they're not
Speaker 5:  allowed to use. And the leagues have gotten more
Speaker 5:  permissive over time, I would say, because they've realized that having things
Speaker 5:  on You know House of Highlights on Instagram and on the various
Speaker 5:  accounts on different social media platforms is actually a good
Speaker 5:  marketing thing. The N B A has been way out in front of this. They were like,
Speaker 5:  oh, you want to like show cool highlights and make more people watch basketball?
Speaker 5:  Terrific. Knock yourself out. The NFL has been kind of all the way on the
Speaker 5:  other end of that spectrum where the NFL has been super, super, super protective
Speaker 5:  of all of that stuff over the years. And even it has loosened up a little,
Speaker 5:  but like, it, it's, it's the most valuable video that exists
Speaker 5:  in the world in like a very real way. And they've always been
Speaker 5:  super protective of it.
Speaker 3:  And it You know, it's funny 'cause they were going to sign this deal
Speaker 3:  with Apple and Apple was like, we want to do cool broadcast ideas
Speaker 3:  for our VR headset. And they said no because they
Speaker 3:  don't know how that's gonna work. They dunno where the money will come from.
Speaker 3:  And they ended up with YouTube that's like,
Speaker 3:  we're gonna use your clips across YouTube and presumably
Speaker 3:  when creators use these clips, the NFL will get money. Right? The
Speaker 3:  same way that the labels get money when you use music on YouTube or TikTok.
Speaker 3:  And I think the NFL just like deeply understands that, right? Like, oh,
Speaker 3:  automated, is it like licensing revenue? We understand that weird
Speaker 3:  VR headset idea give us 35 years, like
Speaker 3:  a hundred percent the split that is happening there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They're still stuck on would you like to watch this game on your phone?
Speaker 5:  Like we're, we're not nearly at VR yet.
Speaker 4:  I guess I was just like confused why it's not considered fair use to just
Speaker 4:  do sports videos.
Speaker 3:  So, so it is right. Your, your problem is nefarious
Speaker 3:  is complicated. You need to do, you need to add some value, right?
Speaker 3:  That's basically it. The the, the standard is transformative affairs. You
Speaker 3:  need to make something new out of the clip. So yes, if you are sitting there
Speaker 3:  doing like deep analysis Dan Orlovsky like high
Speaker 3:  analysis of a play that he does on e s PN and you're like using like
Speaker 3:  several short seconds to like show a difference and you're like in it, you
Speaker 3:  can do that. And for example, our sister side SP Nation, you go to
Speaker 3:  secret base on YouTube, they are doing this all over the place and it is
Speaker 3:  great and that is fair use, it's classic fair use, like inside fair use.
Speaker 3:  If you are just a creator being like, look at this cool play, you,
Speaker 3:  you kind of have to fight your way through it, right? And like most individual
Speaker 3:  creators, like we've been talking about, the infrastructure to have that
Speaker 3:  fight does not exist for them. Especially if you're like a new creator. So
Speaker 3:  YouTube content ID and like the platform, like they don't wanna have this
Speaker 3:  fight at scale with the sports leagues who might all become lucrative partners
Speaker 3:  in the future. So they just clamp down on it and you, you just, you just
Speaker 3:  kinda like see that that back and forth dynamic happen all over the place.
Speaker 3:  Whereas You know a bigger company, an E S P N or a
Speaker 3:  Fox or whatever, like has an infrastructure
Speaker 3:  to like push forward the fair use argument.
Speaker 3:  And so like, okay, that makes sense. It should be, it should be like I, if
Speaker 3:  you, if you are like a wealth, an independently wealthy YouTube sports creator
Speaker 3:  can probably solve this problem. Yeah. But like most YouTube
Speaker 3:  creators are afraid to like try 'cause they'd rather just make the next
Speaker 3:  video and make money instead of spending money fighting the NFL.
Speaker 4:  Well, and the take down notice is always terrifying. Even if you're like,
Speaker 4:  I'm in the right. It's like, nope, this is terrifying. I have to burn my
Speaker 4:  entire account and walk away. Not that I have any experience with that.
Speaker 3:  And, and You know the YouTube notice and take down is all in D M C A, so
Speaker 3:  it's all compliance to that and it basically kicks you out into like go
Speaker 3:  have a lawsuit and come back and tell us how it went. Like it, like YouTube
Speaker 3:  itself is not there to mediate the problem with you. They're there to comply
Speaker 3:  with the D M C A, which is to say there was a notice like of a take
Speaker 3:  down and you can appeal the take down and like we'll do a thing and like
Speaker 3:  sort of at the end of that rainbow is, did you call your lawyer? And
Speaker 3:  once you get there you're like, I'm just gonna make 'em the next video. Like
Speaker 3:  screw it, right? Because if you get You know a number of strikes your channel
Speaker 3:  gets to, it's the whole thing. And like I said, like big companies can solve
Speaker 3:  this problem. Individual creators definitely can't. So it is like kind of
Speaker 3:  great that YouTube realize like, oh, we don't just want this in
Speaker 3:  our cable bundle, we want this on YouTube. And they created
Speaker 3:  some financial relationships so that you can use this stuff like you can
Speaker 3:  use music. I'm just very curious to see how the NFL
Speaker 3:  reacts to lots and lots of YouTube creators using NFL clips,
Speaker 3:  the way that they use music. 'cause that is an uncontrolled environment and
Speaker 3:  we have no idea if the YouTube is gonna put guardrails on it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's, yeah, we, there's, there's a lot we still don't know. And the
Speaker 5:  season starts I think like September 7th. So I think what's available on
Speaker 5:  that first day versus what's available at the end of the season, I suspect
Speaker 5:  it's gonna end up pretty different. Yeah. But I'm very curious to see.
Speaker 3:  So that's one part of YouTube. And then on the other side of YouTube, on
Speaker 3:  the short side, they're adding more samples. So they're adding more music.
Speaker 3:  A big part of the TikTok like win has been its relationship
Speaker 3:  to the music industry and breaking new records, breaking new sounds, planet
Speaker 3:  of the base. It's like a thing that is happening because of TikTok. So YouTube
Speaker 3:  music is chasing after that. And then sort of next to all of that,
Speaker 3:  more governments are banning TikTok. So N Y C has banned TikTok and
Speaker 3:  city owned devices. It tracks lots of other cities and states. And then
Speaker 3:  Cranz, you had an incredible reaction to this headline and Nielsen
Speaker 3:  released some data saying, okay, TV viewing is officially down. Like
Speaker 3:  people watching linear TV is now half the people
Speaker 4:  My fury.
Speaker 3:  And you were like, fuck this headline, what is going on there?
Speaker 4:  Okay, so so the headline is, is like, it's accurate.
Speaker 5:  I'm not even sure I agree with that to
Speaker 4:  Be honest. The but there's a big asterisk, there's a huge, huge
Speaker 4:  asterisk in that this is all coming from data
Speaker 4:  that they only started gathering two years ago. So like
Speaker 4:  all time asterisk, we only started doing this two years ago.
Speaker 4:  Okay.
Speaker 3:  The
Speaker 4:  Technically I feel like Nielsen would, pr would come to me and be like, this
Speaker 4:  is technically accurate. And I'd be like, it is, but also it's not,
Speaker 5:  It's accurate, but it's meaningless. Like, and, and honestly, and
Speaker 5:  we, we've talked about this a bunch, but there was also this like big financial
Speaker 5:  time story the other day that was like, streaming is officially more expensive
Speaker 5:  than cable. And it's like, well, okay sure, if you have this gigantic list
Speaker 5:  of streaming services and if you have this made up promotional price for
Speaker 5:  cable that no one actually has, sure. Streaming is more expensive than cable.
Speaker 5:  Congratulations. But we're at this point where like to me,
Speaker 5:  all of this has proven, and this like goes along with what a lot of people
Speaker 5:  in the strike have been talking about with data transparency and stuff. Nobody
Speaker 5:  knows anything. Yep. We don't know the Nielsen is the best
Speaker 5:  thing we have and was reasonably good when most
Speaker 5:  people watched all of their television sitting on their couch in front of
Speaker 5:  their television. Even then it was a mess, but it was, it was good enough.
Speaker 5:  Now it's like, it, it gets this one tiny sliver of how people
Speaker 5:  experience entertainment. It doesn't capture mobile very well. It doesn't
Speaker 5:  capture a huge, a portion of how people spend
Speaker 5:  their lives. And to me, I don't take anything away from any of this
Speaker 5:  data except that like, people watch lots of tv, lots of places and nobody
Speaker 5:  knows anything.
Speaker 3:  This is my, my theory, my underlying theory of the television industry is
Speaker 3:  that no one knows how to measure anything. I I think
Speaker 5:  That's right. All,
Speaker 3:  All the metrics are fake and agreeing to measure everything in the same way
Speaker 3:  is a nuclear bomb waiting to go off for this industry.
Speaker 5:  Well, and ironically now where we are is the streamers know,
Speaker 5:  like Netflix knows and is increasingly
Speaker 5:  disincentivized to tell anybody because like if nobody knows anything
Speaker 3:  You know Netflix is gonna do because of the ads that Netflix is doing,
Speaker 3:  they're gonna do something with Nielsen. Right. Or Nielsen wants that contract.
Speaker 3:  Which one of the reasons I think that this headline came out fair. Right?
Speaker 3:  The headline basically is like the streamers won and then they're gonna walk
Speaker 3:  into Netflix offices Yeah. And be like, Hey, we just said you won. Like,
Speaker 3:  do you want us to measure? By the way, disclosure, speaking of disclosures
Speaker 3:  and transparency, we made a Netflix show. I'm a Netflix
Speaker 3:  cp, you should go watch that show. Someone wrote us a very nice email asking
Speaker 3:  if we're allowed to talk about our Netflix show during the strikes. The answer
Speaker 3:  is that our Netflix show wasn't a, a union production and it's also over.
Speaker 3:  So it, I I don't think I'm gonna be arrested, but let me know if you're in
Speaker 3:  one of the unions. You want me to to stop talking about the Netflix show
Speaker 3:  we made two years ago? Let me know. Anyway, that's one disclosure. Comcast
Speaker 3:  through its N B C Universal Arm is an investor in Vox Media. Our parent
Speaker 3:  company Alex is in the W G A. Our
Speaker 3:  newsroom is organized with the W G A East. I have H B O
Speaker 3:  I've been watching hard knocks like a maniac. It's a crime that hard knocks
Speaker 3:  is on at Tuesdays at 10:00 PM instead of Sundays at 9:00 PM like it should
Speaker 3:  be. I feel very strongly about that. That's my personal bias there. I have
Speaker 3:  really weird feelings about Aren Rogers right now. Is there anything else,
Speaker 3:  David? I think that's it. I think those are all pretty disclosure.
Speaker 5:  That seems right. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's, that's like the, the solidness.
Speaker 5:  I have a TV back there that's disclosure.
Speaker 3:  Anyhow. Netflix is under a lot of pressure to release these ratings. So they,
Speaker 3:  they need to sell ads. You need to tell the advertisers how many people watch
Speaker 3:  your ads. That's gonna happen to H B O max that's gonna happen to Disney
Speaker 3:  plus they're all running these ad tiers. And that is the thing that is gonna
Speaker 3:  provide one set of pressures to release standardized
Speaker 3:  metrics so the ad market can decide where to spend their dollars.
Speaker 3:  And the other thing that's gonna happen is in the strikes, one of the demands
Speaker 3:  from all these unions is tell us what shows are successful
Speaker 3:  So, we can calculate our residuals more accurately and get more money.
Speaker 3:  And I think that's gonna place another amount of pressure that might finally
Speaker 3:  break this fever. But I have no idea how it's gonna play out. Well
Speaker 4:  It sounds like that that was some of the big dues this week was that the
Speaker 4:  producers said, oh yeah, we're now gonna give you more access
Speaker 4:  to data. We don't know all the details yet, but they, they finally agreed
Speaker 4:  to like, yeah, it makes sense that you guys should probably have more data,
Speaker 4:  which everyone knew before this, but it's nice that they
Speaker 4:  agree finally
Speaker 3:  Not to get into the mechanics of that negotiation, but the streamers were
Speaker 3:  going to have to give up this data to advertisers like it was going to happen
Speaker 3:  just because of the nature of that market. So I think this is like the, the
Speaker 3:  concession they were most willing to give because they, they needed to
Speaker 3:  standardize and synthesize all that data. The question is whether it's Nielsen
Speaker 3:  or para analytics or whatever, who knows. But the idea that the data needs
Speaker 3:  to be standardized and everyone can so everyone can understand it, that's
Speaker 3:  coming from the ad market that's not coming from that
Speaker 3:  negotiation. I think it is a good concession and a useful one to all of us.
Speaker 3:  But it's eventually an advertiser's gonna say, how many people saw my ad?
Speaker 3:  You just have to have a real answer. Okay, we should take a break. There's
Speaker 3:  been a, a wild ride in the first segment I have to say.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna take a break. We're gonna come back, we're gonna dip 25 years
Speaker 3:  into the past and talk about the iMac with Dan Seifert. Get your brains ready.
Speaker 3:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 7:  This episode is brought to you by Shopify. That's the sound of
Speaker 7:  switching your business to Shopify. The global commerce platform that
Speaker 7:  supercharges your selling harness. The best converting checkout and same
Speaker 7:  intuitive features, trusted apps and powerful analytics used by the
Speaker 7:  world's leading brands. Stop leaving sales on the table.
Speaker 7:  Discover why millions trust Shopify to build, grow, and run their business.
Speaker 7:  Sign up today for your $1 per month trial period at Shopify dot com
Speaker 7:  slash tech 23.
Speaker 8:  I'm Josh Muccio, host of the pitch from Vox Media. People
Speaker 8:  describe the pitch as the Antis Shark Tank. And I actually agree,
Speaker 8:  take everything you think You know about venture capital startups and
Speaker 8:  fundraising and throw it out because on my show you'll hear
Speaker 8:  the true story of how these deals get done on our upcoming
Speaker 8:  season. You'll hear legendary investors like Charles Hudson and
Speaker 8:  Elizabeth Yin invest over a million dollars in the startups
Speaker 8:  featured on our show. And let me be clear, none of this is staged.
Speaker 8:  Each episode of the pitch features real entrepreneurs pitching
Speaker 8:  real investors for real money Then. we go the
Speaker 8:  extra mile to tell the true story of what happens after
Speaker 8:  everyone shakes hands and walks out of the room. Listen to the pitch podcast
Speaker 8:  to learn from the smartest investors and founders in the world.
Speaker 8:  Season 10 starts on Wednesday, August 23rd. Follow
Speaker 8:  the pitch for free wherever you listen to podcasts.
Speaker 3:  Alright, we're back. Dan Sifford is here. Hey Dan. Hello.
Speaker 9:  Welcome
Speaker 3:  Back to the show. You had a big package this week. Our friend Jason
Speaker 3:  Snell contributed a staffers from on The. Verge contributed this week
Speaker 3:  was the 25th anniversary of the iMac.
Speaker 3:  There's a lot to unpack. Like that means a lot of things. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  It means we're old
Speaker 3:  Means we're old. It is incredible to think that the Mac was a
Speaker 3:  younger platform when the iMac came out than the iPhone is now.
Speaker 3:  John pointed that when he linked to to Umar's visual history of the Mac.
Speaker 3:  So the Mac was 14 when the iMac came out. The
Speaker 3:  iPhone today is 16, which is just
Speaker 3:  bonkers to think about. Yeah. Where these respective products are and their
Speaker 3:  impact on the world. But the iMac really changed a lot of things.
Speaker 3:  Tell us about this package, Dan.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, so You know 25 years since the I'm first
Speaker 9:  iMac went on sales like August 15th, 1998. The iMac as
Speaker 9:  Jason really pointed out really well in his piece. It was
Speaker 9:  the product that really turned around the company's fortunes. It allowed
Speaker 9:  them, it was successful and popular enough to basically develop
Speaker 9:  the iPod, which then became successful, popular enough to develop the iPhone.
Speaker 9:  And then You know Apple becomes $3 trillion company. So
Speaker 9:  without the iMac, like you don't have any of that. And, and Apple at the
Speaker 9:  time was like very on the brink of not existing
Speaker 9:  anymore. And, and all of the products that had been developed
Speaker 9:  in the nineties were like these kind of beige boxes. Very typical looking,
Speaker 9:  not a whole lot of creativity or design were put into them. But then
Speaker 9:  when Jobs came back and teamed up with Ive, and they brought out the iMac
Speaker 9:  and just kind of like changed everything in terms of like the perspective
Speaker 9:  of what like a home or a consumer electronic in your home could
Speaker 9:  look like. It had this like radical design. It was a thing that was like
Speaker 9:  people looked at it and they wanted it. Whereas if you looked at a PC
Speaker 9:  at the time, you looked at it to, maybe you want to use it and like do
Speaker 9:  things on it, but you didn't want the object itself. It was just a box. Whereas
Speaker 9:  the iMac was an object. And then that design
Speaker 9:  was so influential and not only permeated throughout Apple's lineup
Speaker 9:  influencing the design of what the software looked like on Max and
Speaker 9:  then further on down the line. But it also made
Speaker 9:  translucent plastic products really popular at the turn of the century
Speaker 9:  all the way down to the infamous George Foreman Grill. That looks like an
Speaker 9:  iMac.
Speaker 5:  I had never seen that before until this package became a thing. And I'm
Speaker 5:  now obsessed with this translucent George girl.
Speaker 5:  It's fantastic. It is beautiful. It's the thing I want most in the world.
Speaker 5:  If you, if anyone listening wants to buy a new one,
Speaker 3:  Do not buy a used George Foreman grill. What if it's in,
Speaker 3:  what if it's in Mint
Speaker 9:  Condition and then it's got the, the bun warmer
Speaker 3:  A product that can never be cleaned.
Speaker 3:  No one has ever perfectly cleaned a George Foreman girl. No, it cannot be
Speaker 3:  done. I
Speaker 5:  Clean ours constantly and it's just fully disgusting. Wait,
Speaker 3:  You have today in 2023, a George Foreman girl?
Speaker 5:  I am reasonably confident that the George Foreman Grill I have is older
Speaker 5:  than both me and my wife. It was like my
Speaker 5:  wife's grandma's and it just somehow was in our
Speaker 5:  house. I don't know how it got here. Maybe
Speaker 3:  We should just switch this segment to George Foreman Grill. It
Speaker 5:  Just, I use it all the time. It's great.
Speaker 3:  What do you use it for? Are you making like, like stuffed burgers? Like George Foreman?
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Constantly. No, it's like, I'm just saying if you have,
Speaker 5:  if you have leftover chicken breast and some cold bread and you wanna throw
Speaker 5:  it on the for girl for 90 seconds and eat lunch, Bob's your uncle. It's your
Speaker 3:  Panini press.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. No, but the back to the imax
Speaker 5:  Listen, David's recipe blog is another story for another
Speaker 5:  day.
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah. That's gonna be a success. Talk about getting the views. Put some
Speaker 3:  cold chicken on a 30 year old George or
Speaker 9:  I, I wanna hear the story about how your wife's grandmother
Speaker 9:  grew up building with the, with the George Foreman Grill.
Speaker 3:  Will we live or die today at lunchtime with David Pierce?
Speaker 5:  Do You know those things that just end up in your house? You're like, I didn't
Speaker 5:  buy this. I never asked for this. Yeah, I just have this now. Yeah, that's,
Speaker 5:  that's the Foreman grill in my house. Like it's George Foreman himself might
Speaker 5:  have brought it to our house for all I know. Like I sincerely don't know.
Speaker 5:  But the thing about the iMac that most blew my mind, Dan was
Speaker 5:  like reading Jason's piece, the, the full like YOLO
Speaker 5:  energy of this thing from Apple in 1998 where they're just
Speaker 5:  like, oh you want a floppy disc? Screw you U S B,
Speaker 5:  you want a thing that looks like a computer? No, here's this weird
Speaker 5:  Pixar looking piece of nonsense. There's just like, you just get this
Speaker 5:  vibe from Apple that I kind of love where they're like, look, we know if
Speaker 5:  this doesn't work, we're screwed. And realistically we're probably screwed
Speaker 5:  anyway. So like here's the weirdest thing we can think of. Do you like it?
Speaker 5:  It's got a handle. And people did exactly.
Speaker 3:  Well So, we, I was talking about this on Instagram threads with a few people,
Speaker 3:  You know people are keep saying they want a desktop version of Instagram
Speaker 3:  threads. This is like the thing everyone said, we say it. Mark Zuckerberg
Speaker 3:  is replying to JP Peters saying it's coming soon. 'cause we say it a lot.
Speaker 3:  That's a real thing that happened this week. What they mean is a web version,
Speaker 3:  right? Yeah. The the desktop application default that most people
Speaker 3:  think about is a web app is for, especially for a platform like Instagram
Speaker 3:  Threads. No one is out here asking for like a native win 32
Speaker 3:  Instagram threads application. I
Speaker 9:  Mean I was, I I would like a native app, but
Speaker 3:  Yeah, but that's like a very small, it's just like not the thing
Speaker 3:  people are asking if, if Instagram's response was you can run the iPhone
Speaker 3:  app on your Mac using Apple silicon. Some nerds would be
Speaker 3:  very happy and most people are like, what the hell is this? I just wanna
Speaker 3:  run at my browser. And Apple in particular with the
Speaker 3:  iMac, that was the moment that that began,
Speaker 3:  right? Until that computer desktop applications on
Speaker 3:  computers were one generally not connected, right? The web
Speaker 3:  was just starting. That was the Wintel monopoly, the height of the Wintel
Speaker 3:  monopoly. Even like a M D in that moment was not like a serious competitor
Speaker 3:  to Intel. So you had win 32 and you had Intel and that was the
Speaker 3:  application environment for 99% of everything. And
Speaker 3:  the Mac was this like RU platform that Microsoft sort of openly talked about
Speaker 3:  supporting. So they wouldn't be a monopoly. Like they're
Speaker 3:  like, as long as we have this competitor, we won't get sued by the Justice
Speaker 3:  Department. Little did they know this is like, this is a lot like,
Speaker 3:  and in that moment Apple basically said there's this idea of a network
Speaker 3:  computer. And the You know the original vision was like a $500 terminal with
Speaker 3:  just a web browser, which we finally got into with like Chrome boxes. But
Speaker 3:  that was like sort of the genesis and it got bigger 'cause I couldn't really
Speaker 3:  build it then. But no floppy drive was so you could send files
Speaker 3:  radical idea at the time they were like entire issues of Mac World that were
Speaker 3:  like, how will we survive?
Speaker 4:  I think that was like Walt Mossbergs one criticism of it in his review Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Was like, no floppy dis this is
Speaker 3:  Bullshit. And then importantly, the reason that it was a
Speaker 3:  viable product to sell to people was that they were like, you can just
Speaker 3:  plug it into the internet and use the web. Which is the thing you want.
Speaker 3:  You don't want Microsoft Word running on an Intel
Speaker 3:  processor on Windows. You want a web browser that can bring you all
Speaker 3:  this cool web stuff. And if not for the web and web
Speaker 3:  standards, this computer is a gargantuan flock. Right?
Speaker 3:  It looked cool as hell. It dropped all the bullshit. You only really had
Speaker 3:  to plug in what two wires. Like that was a very famous commercial. Like you
Speaker 3:  plug it in and there's no step three Jeff Goldblum, like that whole thing,
Speaker 3:  it signed you up for internet access through an I S P. And then you could
Speaker 3:  just like run a web restaurant and now we're just 25 years later,
Speaker 3:  people are like, I want a desktop version of Instagram threads and they mean
Speaker 3:  a web app. And you, there's just a straight line from that idea to, to
Speaker 3:  this idea that I, I think we often underestimate,
Speaker 3:  like that's the revolution. The phone is very important.
Speaker 3:  It just came at the, it's just the last piece of that puzzle. The
Speaker 3:  first one was, oh, we can sell a computer that basically runs a web browser
Speaker 3:  and like if we do a good job of that, we can become the apple that we are
Speaker 3:  today.
Speaker 5:  Which is why like the Johnny Ive thing became so important,
Speaker 5:  right? Like they timed giving a new crap about
Speaker 5:  design perfectly. Because like, I, I think Jason has this line on his
Speaker 5:  piece that's like on the internet, nobody knew you were using a Mac and I
Speaker 5:  love that because it's it's true. And it's like, oh, you could just buy the
Speaker 5:  computer that looked cool and was blue and had a handle and all the
Speaker 5:  stuff you wanted to do on the internet. You could still do. And it was like
Speaker 5:  Apple being a hardware company worked for it in a
Speaker 5:  sort of unique way in that moment because it had no ecosystem play. It was
Speaker 5:  like we all we can do is build a cool thing and hope that people want to
Speaker 5:  use it because we don't have any other moves.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The power PC G three, have you heard of it? It's,
Speaker 3:  we're gonna, we're gonna walk away from this as fast as we can and like You
Speaker 3:  know all that stuff is really hard for them. Like I, I I think, think we
Speaker 3:  underestimate how You know apple's very good at processor transitions now
Speaker 3:  we take it for granted. They're like, we're gonna run the max on apple silicon.
Speaker 3:  And we're like, oh, you're good at this. In that moment, right? They were
Speaker 3:  stuck on the G three architecture. They were stuck with o the I'm at lunch
Speaker 3:  with OSS nine, which if you, oh wow, I am old.
Speaker 3:  That was not a good operating system.
Speaker 4:  It was sweet. What are you talking about? You could customize your text.
Speaker 3:  You could, this is an operating system that famously until the very end,
Speaker 3:  you could bring the entire OSS to a dead
Speaker 3:  halt by holding down the mouse button.
Speaker 3:  And that was like by design. Like it di was not a native
Speaker 3:  multitasking multi-threaded oss. I think until the
Speaker 3:  very, very end of OSS nine, you could be like, You know what? I just need
Speaker 3:  to everyone stop for a second. And you're just like, hold down the mask button
Speaker 3:  and be like, we're waiting, we're waiting everyone chill the fuck out. Like
Speaker 3:  we're waiting. We like, and they had to do OSS 10, like
Speaker 3:  all this stuff they had to do, but they needed to sell enough iMac to, to
Speaker 3:  get there. That kind of brings us to where the iMac is today. Right. That,
Speaker 3:  that's a history. I will say that we, we, you should look at the visual history
Speaker 3:  that we did and we should all stop and take a moment and
Speaker 3:  recognize the iMac G four as the pinnacle of computer design. Are
Speaker 4:  You crazy?
Speaker 5:  Wait, can I, can I tell you a story about the iMac G four? Yeah. So I
Speaker 5:  bought, let's see, this is probably 2011. I bought an
Speaker 5:  iMac G four because it was the only Mac I could afford, which you, you
Speaker 5:  will, you will realize if you do math that it's a nine year old computer
Speaker 5:  that is long since out of day that no one is caring about it.
Speaker 5:  It was, this is the only Mac I could afford. I bought it from a stranger
Speaker 5:  on Craigslist. We met oh my god in I believe it was Union
Speaker 5:  Square and he literally like went
Speaker 5:  through an existential crisis giving me this computer that I think I paid
Speaker 5:  like $150 for. Yeah. 'cause he wanted it
Speaker 5:  so bad and regretted so immediately selling this thing to me
Speaker 5:  that literally like as he was handing it to me was like, ah, but it's
Speaker 5:  so I just, I don't need it. But like, ah, I love it and it's just,
Speaker 5:  and I was like, yeah, like that's, that's why I want it too. Like I want
Speaker 5:  this old ass computer 'cause it's so cool looking. The, the G four was
Speaker 5:  my first ever Mac period and it was so old and
Speaker 5:  so useless at that point. And I loved it to pieces because it was
Speaker 5:  so cool looking. It was just it the, I
Speaker 5:  genuinely think it, I agree with you. I think it's the best looking computer
Speaker 5:  ever made. I loved that thing. It's
Speaker 9:  A shame they only did it for one generation. Like it was, it lasted for like
Speaker 9:  a year and a half or so and then boom right onto what
Speaker 9:  ultimately looked like a big iPod.
Speaker 3:  Oh wait, I have a story to tell about that. But Cranz, I, I want to hear
Speaker 3:  your bad opinion about the iMac G four.
Speaker 4:  Like did you guys have to use that G four iMac?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, David used it. I mean he still used, it's right next to his George Foreman
Speaker 3:  grill,
Speaker 3:  but he used,
Speaker 5:  It's a family heirloom
Speaker 4:  At the time because it was not great. Like, I don't know, the
Speaker 4:  G three was just, there was something much more charming about the G three
Speaker 4:  imax, like the big CRTs and everything. Well
Speaker 9:  I think that the, the G three was almost like
Speaker 9:  cartoon-like, and then the G four was a much more
Speaker 9:  serious, this is the future looking thing.
Speaker 3:  Hold on. We, we gotta get this timeline right. There's the original IMAX
Speaker 3:  responded blue, then there was the, the, the rainbow ones,
Speaker 3:  right where the, the five colors, those are the ones you might be talking
Speaker 3:  about. Alex.
Speaker 5:  That's the G three thing.
Speaker 4:  That's what I had.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. That's the MX G three. Then there was a bizarre interregnum
Speaker 3:  where Steve Jobs got on a stage and So, we have some exciting new iMac to
Speaker 3:  offer you today. And everyone thought he was gonna do a flat panel iMac.
Speaker 3:  And he was like, these motherfuckers are called Dalmatian and Flower
Speaker 3:  Power.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. What
Speaker 3:  Literally people were like, what are you talking about? And that was
Speaker 3:  like the last gasp of that shape. Go look at a blue
Speaker 3:  dalmatian iMac.
Speaker 4:  It's beautiful.
Speaker 3:  They they cannot be found. Oh my,
Speaker 5:  This is the ugliest thing I've ever seen.
Speaker 3:  Like Apple went across the world and country
Speaker 3:  collected them all and was like you memory hole this Steve
Speaker 3:  Jobs famously walked off of stage when he announced those things after
Speaker 3:  sensing the vibe in the room and said it should have been fucking ready.
Speaker 3:  And what he meant was the flat panel iMac should have been ready. Yeah. This
Speaker 3:  is a real thing. You can go look this up.
Speaker 5:  I just googled this and I'm looking at these for the first time in my life
Speaker 5:  and first of all, everyone should do this and look at these because these
Speaker 5:  are incredible. And what these look like to me is if somebody took a normal
Speaker 5:  iMac and then like You know those really awful like dollar 99
Speaker 5:  skins you can buy on your phone that, that like from Amazon that
Speaker 5:  you, you just like apply to the back of your phone and they don't quite stick.
Speaker 5:  Right. And it's very clear that somebody just like took a picture of a picture
Speaker 5:  of a picture of a wallpaper and then put it on this. That's what this looks
Speaker 5:  like to me.
Speaker 3:  They are nuts. We had them in my computer lab in college
Speaker 3:  and they are nuts. Like they're just
Speaker 4:  So I was gonna say I was, I was in college around the same time and I had
Speaker 4:  to do it. So I had to like work on everybody's computers. That's, that's
Speaker 4:  what my piece on the iMac is about.
Speaker 3:  Is this why we vibe? 'cause we are both like college IT people.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We were both like, we,
Speaker 3:  I don't think we've ever really talked about this, but I've known it in my
Speaker 3:  heart for quite some time. Yeah. That
Speaker 4:  It's why, it's why, that's why we, we always judge David. He,
Speaker 4:  he was in high school being like, oh boy,
Speaker 5:  Jesus, where did that just come from?
Speaker 3:  Damn. That's just like David took a shot.
Speaker 5:  I was out just like partying and getting laid. Sorry guys.
Speaker 4:  We had computers to talk about. We
Speaker 4:  were having a great time over there.
Speaker 5:  Dan suspiciously quiet on what he was doing at this period.
Speaker 9:  I I was an IT person in high school.
Speaker 3:  Here we go.
Speaker 4:  That's where were, where the cool kids,
Speaker 9:  I had a job, a high school job as a, an a PC tech for a local
Speaker 9:  hospital.
Speaker 3:  I think it's very obvious that this group of people was nerds in high school.
Speaker 3:  Alex continue your story and David,
Speaker 4:  But, but no, you could tell like basically how much people's
Speaker 4:  parents spent on them for school based on which generation of, of
Speaker 4:  IAC they had. So if somebody comes in with a Bondi Blue, you're like, Ooh,
Speaker 4:  you got the hand me down. Huh? They had like the blueberry or something.
Speaker 4:  You're like, okay, okay. And then they had that Dalmatian one, you were like,
Speaker 4:  wow, you are loaded.
Speaker 3:  This is a straight class system based on iMac colors that you have
Speaker 3:  imposed on, on your customers in the college it shop. There was like a middle
Speaker 3:  period that we haven't talked about, like the iMac DV where the shells got
Speaker 3:  clear. It was all cool, but I'm just saying that was the last version. And
Speaker 3:  then this is the thing I wanted to say about the G four. It was a Steve Jobs
Speaker 3:  moment unlike any other where they released the iMac G four and he
Speaker 3:  was like, everyone else solves this flat panel computer problem by putting
Speaker 3:  the computer behind the display. And he, he did the thing, he like put up
Speaker 3:  a bad version of that drawing and he was like, this isn't the right idea.
Speaker 3:  We made it a sunflower. And the thing was on the cover of Time magazine,
Speaker 3:  I think it was a Stephen Levy piece on the cover of Time Magazine and Jobs
Speaker 3:  and Johnny, I've told an entire story in Time Magazine about how they
Speaker 3:  were trying to solve this problem of where the computer should go at the
Speaker 3:  flat panel. And they were walking and they saw Sunflower and the, the
Speaker 3:  birds sang and Johnny looked at Steve and Steve looked at Johnny
Speaker 3:  and they were like, we did it. And then 18 months later, like we put the
Speaker 3:  computer behind the display because that's the kids passionately in front
Speaker 3:  of the,
Speaker 3:  but it's like they sold that thing so completely
Speaker 3:  until they were ready to do it the right way. And then they dropped it like
Speaker 3:  a stone. They're like, we actually solved the problem. And here here's the
Speaker 3:  thing you've always wanted. And it has been that thing ever since. And just
Speaker 3:  that thing where they so completely bought into
Speaker 3:  the solution they had at the minute until they were ready to do it the way
Speaker 3:  they wanted and then they never talked about it again. They what?
Speaker 3:  Dead, dead to the world. Like no company
Speaker 3:  can do that now. Like even Apple basically cannot do that
Speaker 3:  anymore. Right? They, there are too many installed devices. There are too
Speaker 3:  many old things to support. They're like all this stuff to be like for
Speaker 3:  18 months we talked about sunflowers.
Speaker 3:  Never remember that again. Erase the sunflowers from your
Speaker 3:  brain. Now it's a white piece of a white rectangle and that's the future
Speaker 3:  of the amac. To me it's like in, in the history of the iMac, that
Speaker 3:  moment is more about Apple's culture than anything else. And
Speaker 3:  it, it's sort of like unremarked upon because no, they, they successfully
Speaker 3:  memory hold the iMac G four. But it was that shift that I was like, oh, they
Speaker 3:  are ruthless. Like they are ruthless about getting to the right answer
Speaker 3:  as fast as they can and not talking about everything they did in the past
Speaker 3:  to this day. Like you think about a car company Ford's like, we made
Speaker 3:  another Bronco. Like it looks like the old Bronco, like here's yet
Speaker 3:  another Mustang. Like most companies are very excited to
Speaker 3:  trade on their past in a way that Apple like maybe a little bit more
Speaker 3:  recently. But you will note Apple said nothing about 25 years to the
Speaker 3:  iMac. Yeah, it just came and went. They had, they
Speaker 9:  Had two opportunities to say it this year, the announcement in May and then
Speaker 9:  the in-store in August, which is when we timed our pie. But yeah,
Speaker 9:  not a peep.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, and I, and I think it's all of that Apple culture is
Speaker 3:  pinpointed in that moment where literally this computer was on the cover
Speaker 3:  of Time Magazine and then 18 months later they're like, here's the, here's
Speaker 3:  the white one you wanted. And like that was it. Like the end,
Speaker 3:  we have this other piece here. It's really about the future of the iMac,
Speaker 3:  right? Yeah. Like where does it go now? It's, it's in a weird spot. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. So Monica wrote a really great piece on You know nowadays
Speaker 9:  Apple's Mac business is 75 or 80% laptops
Speaker 9:  and then the rest is like really niche computers. The Mac
Speaker 9:  Studio, the Mac Mini, and then there's the iMac, which was updated
Speaker 9:  in spring 2021 with the M one chip. It's got the new design
Speaker 9:  and it's basically just been parked for like two and a half years now.
Speaker 9:  We've got M two chips and other laptops or other Mac computers. It's not
Speaker 9:  in the iMac for whatever reason, but like the iMac has been this
Speaker 9:  kind of thing that just kind of ebbs and flows for the past decade or so.
Speaker 9:  Like Apple will release and update and then ignore it for like four
Speaker 9:  years. And Then, we get an iMac Pro and then it gets ignored for four years
Speaker 9:  and then it Then, we get a new M one iMac and then it gets ignored for however
Speaker 9:  many years. So You know, Monica's takeaway was ultimately that like
Speaker 9:  Apple isn't dishing the iMac or getting rid of the iMac. That's just
Speaker 9:  kind of the way, the place that the iMac sits in today's
Speaker 9:  apple is just much less prominent and less
Speaker 9:  influential than it was two decades ago, or certainly two and a half decades
Speaker 9:  ago. So it's just like a different product. What's interesting to me is
Speaker 9:  that the original iMac that we talked about, and all the
Speaker 9:  generations after that were basically safe for the iMac pro pitched
Speaker 9:  as consumer products and consumer computers. And the current iMac is still
Speaker 9:  kind of pitched as that consumer computer, whereas the other Mac
Speaker 9:  desktops are really pitched towards professional creative
Speaker 9:  niche use cases. But Apple doesn't really talk about the iMac all
Speaker 9:  that often outside of, its like initial Launch when they showed yellow iMac
Speaker 9:  in kitchens, which is a very odd place to put an iMac, especially
Speaker 3:  That it doesn't have a touchscreen.
Speaker 9:  Doesn't have a touchscreen. Yeah, no, you, you need your, your touch pad,
Speaker 9:  your track pad and keyboard in addition to your iMac in your kitchen. Oh,
Speaker 5:  Can I run a theory by you guys that I think is right, but have no
Speaker 5:  actual data for just lots of anecdotal evidence? I would
Speaker 5:  bet that people keep IMAX longer
Speaker 5:  than any other single Apple product
Speaker 5:  like I would bet the average use lifespan of an iMac
Speaker 5:  is the longest of any other Mac because the, the screen is very
Speaker 5:  good. The thing works relatively well. You're not gonna notice when the battery
Speaker 5:  starts to give out, which is often the first thing that goes in a lot of
Speaker 5:  laptops and the like, inertia of upgrading
Speaker 5:  is so big because it's just the whole thing. If I have a desktop,
Speaker 5:  if I like wanna upgrade the Mac Mini, I'm sitting here with, I can keep everything
Speaker 5:  else I have and just slot in a new Mac mini upgrading your
Speaker 5:  iMac is like upgrading your whole office all at once. And also, like you
Speaker 5:  said, Dan, these are consumer things that people are like, this is like the
Speaker 5:  familys computer that Apple has, right? And I think
Speaker 5:  if you, if you have like a 2011 iMac that's just like sitting in your den,
Speaker 5:  the like leap to upgrade that is huge.
Speaker 5:  And the reasons to upgrade that when it's like a pretty good screen and the
Speaker 5:  only thing that's really wrong with it 12 years later is that it's like pretty
Speaker 5:  slow. My guess would be that like the average lifespan of one
Speaker 5:  of those things is just absolutely off the charts. And if I'm Apple, I'm
Speaker 5:  looking at that and saying, well, I'm gonna sell people a computer. They're
Speaker 5:  gonna upgrade once every Yeah. 11 years. I,
Speaker 5:  I'd rather sell them a MacBook that they're gonna want a new one in three.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You know what people do with their MacBook errors. They drop them
Speaker 3:  straight, like they
Speaker 5:  Spill things on them. Why
Speaker 4:  The battery, the battery part of this is, is the big, like that's a big part
Speaker 4:  of this is 'cause those batteries go and, and you can't replace them on,
Speaker 4:  on newer laptops and stuff. So it's just like your fubar, whereas
Speaker 4:  your iMac can go forever. I think somebody on this call might be
Speaker 4:  recording with like an ancient iMac.
Speaker 3:  I, I'm, I'm looking at right now, it's a, it's a 20 15 27
Speaker 3:  inch iMac. I will say that I, and you're,
Speaker 5:  You name another gadget you own that is eight years old.
Speaker 3:  The cameras are coming up on that. The D 7,500 coming up on that. Okay. But
Speaker 3:  that's like a, that's like an emotional, like I should upgrade
Speaker 3:  that camera. Like I take a lot of shit from this team for solving, having
Speaker 3:  that camera, but I You know it's never done me wrong. Old man still got it.
Speaker 3:  This computer I basically use for this. I run one web app on it. I run
Speaker 3:  Riverside to do this show and it's this setup and everything
Speaker 3:  plugs into it and it's fine. It is radically over
Speaker 3:  speced. So I, our our studio, Vox Media Studios
Speaker 3:  was upgrading their computers many years ago and they
Speaker 3:  were just gonna recycle this. And I was like, I'm taking it because we're
Speaker 3:  just like sitting on the curb. And I was like, can I, can I just more, and
Speaker 3:  they're like, don't tell anyone now I've told everyone. So it goes, but it,
Speaker 3:  it has, it has, well the key is that it has 32 gigs of ram and this is like
Speaker 3:  the key to longevity of every computer in my opinion is like, it is
Speaker 3:  just, it has massively more RAM than it needed in its time. And that means
Speaker 3:  it stays forever. Which is why I tell everybody who buys a Mac now that eight
Speaker 3:  gigs of RAM is not enough. Like that to me is more of the evidence
Speaker 3:  of Apple's planned obsolescence than anything else is eight gigs of soldered
Speaker 3:  Ram. Like, no, no, no.
Speaker 4:  Nope. Don't do that.
Speaker 3:  And it's just weird. And I, I think David, you're right, the iMac sits in
Speaker 3:  a lot of places. My parents have an ancient one. They refer to it as the
Speaker 3:  mainframe. Aw. It's, it's very good. Yes. And
Speaker 3:  they go to it when they want to do anything serious like
Speaker 3:  logging into the bank. Yep. Because they, they want a big screen and
Speaker 3:  a browser that feels safe. And I'm like, you can't
Speaker 4:  Use your phone. Why do parents like bank apps? Because
Speaker 3:  Their phone, they feel like their phone is not serious enough for logging
Speaker 3:  into the bank. Yeah. Okay. I
Speaker 9:  I think that what You know what you're describing Eli and what David you
Speaker 9:  described as like it's sitting in a den. That is like the concept, the
Speaker 9:  original concept of the iMac. It was a shared family computer. Yeah. And
Speaker 9:  it's just that at this point, at this time, that doesn't
Speaker 9:  exist as a product for a lot of people in functional ways
Speaker 9:  in their lives. If you've got kids in school, they're not coming home and
Speaker 9:  sitting at a desktop to do their homework, they're doing it on a Chromebook
Speaker 9:  that links up to their school's network or and goes with them to school.
Speaker 9:  Or they have their own personal devices, an iPad or an iPhone or whatever
Speaker 9:  smartphone. The shared concept of a family computer,
Speaker 9:  it's like not something that really fits into the modern day life. Whereas
Speaker 9:  the other desktops in Apple's lineup, the Mac Mini, the Mac Studio,
Speaker 9:  et cetera, are, they have like purposes that fit into people's lives as
Speaker 9:  like devices that they work on all day. But the iMac as the family
Speaker 9:  thing doesn't really exist anymore.
Speaker 4:  That was like, I mean the iMac itself was a response to everybody
Speaker 4:  had family computers like in the eighties and nineties. If you had a computer,
Speaker 4:  it probably wasn't in your room unless you were like just Richie Rich.
Speaker 4:  Right? Like you had a lot of money.
Speaker 3:  Alex was like, get that blue All Nation computer outta my face. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Right. Like you didn't have that like everybody that, that
Speaker 4:  so, so the iMac, when the iMac came out, it was like, oh, this is a computer
Speaker 4:  where it's not just the parents using a beige box. Like the kids can interact
Speaker 4:  with this. Which is why my brother watched a Bug's Life on repeat
Speaker 4:  every day over and over and over again on the damn thing. And nowadays
Speaker 4:  computers are cheaper, they're more affordable. So, and and laptops have
Speaker 4:  become much, much more affordable than they were at the time. Like a laptop
Speaker 4:  was still insanely expensive at the time. I, I think
Speaker 4:  all of my laptops until I got out of college were hand-me-downs. 'cause
Speaker 4:  my parents were like, absolutely not. You do not get a brand new laptop.
Speaker 4:  You're gonna drop on its face and break and Then. we have to pay for it.
Speaker 4:  Get out and, and the but the prices have come down so it's like, it's much
Speaker 4:  more affordable. It's much easier to go and buy a Chromebook for a kid than
Speaker 4:  be like, okay, everybody's gonna use this communal computer in the living
Speaker 4:  room. And also like we have to have a space in our living room carved out
Speaker 4:  just for the computer. And then you got one kid on the computer and another
Speaker 4:  kid watching TV and they're all yelling at each other. And now they can just
Speaker 4:  all have phones and be quiet in another room. Or
Speaker 9:  The school dictates that they have a Chromebook, which like takes the decision
Speaker 9:  out of your hands entirely. And then like that iMac that you have
Speaker 9:  sitting there is like not used by them because it's not the tool that fits
Speaker 9:  into the rest of their curriculum.
Speaker 3:  Alex just made a, a striking case to bring back the computer room.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Was I was just gonna say I'm in on this.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I want a computer room. That was the best. Like you were always sitting
Speaker 4:  in like a dining room chair that you should not be sitting in
Speaker 4:  hunched over it.
Speaker 3:  Everybody had that horrible office. Max Furniture. Yeah. And the computer
Speaker 3:  You know what I'm talking about. The the desk and the hutch and the, the
Speaker 3:  whole thing. And you'd roll down. Here's what I want ver has listeners
Speaker 3:  send me photos of your computer rooms? Yes. Not your modern
Speaker 3:  gamer rooms. I mean your childhood computer rooms. If you have
Speaker 3:  such a photo. I just wanna look at 'em and maybe we'll run like a thing
Speaker 3:  about computer rooms. Who knows if they're good enough. Mine's curse
Speaker 3:  again. I do not want your weird gamer den with your l e d lightings and your
Speaker 3:  wifis. I want your 4 86 tower with a turbo
Speaker 3:  button with in Carta Open on A C R T. Hell yeah. That's the
Speaker 4:  I'm looking for exposed photo.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You know exactly what I'm talking about. Show me where you came from.
Speaker 5:  I had a gateway with the cow logo. That was Those are the days.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. Give me your origin story in a photo of your
Speaker 3:  computer rooms. Alright, we should, we've talked about the iMac quite a bit.
Speaker 3:  There is an Apple event coming up where we're assuming in in September for
Speaker 3:  iPhones. That's a pretty solid guess given the
Speaker 3:  decade plus of iPhones coming out in September. iOS
Speaker 3:  17 betas are out. Dan, any thoughts here?
Speaker 9:  They keep moving the the end call button, which seems to be
Speaker 9:  driving people wild. I think You know. Other than that, I think iOS 17 is
Speaker 9:  gonna be for a lot of people and we've, we've kind of said this in our preview
Speaker 9:  coverage already, that it's gonna be a pretty small update across a lot of
Speaker 9:  things. And some people are really gonna appreciate little things like
Speaker 9:  interactive widgets.
Speaker 5:  I was gonna say my one quibble with the characterization of small update
Speaker 5:  is that every app developer that exists on the internet will
Speaker 5:  not shut up about how excited they are about interactive widgets. It's gonna
Speaker 5:  get full crazy with the interactive widgets and I'm very excited about it.
Speaker 5:  Maybe
Speaker 9:  It'll just be more exciting when it launches and those app developers can
Speaker 9:  actually put out their work.
Speaker 5:  Whatever Dan, you're gonna check off a to-do on the home screen of your iPhone
Speaker 5:  and you're gonna freak out. It's gonna be great day.
Speaker 9:  It's gonna be so great. Can't wait at the, at the, at the, at the grocery
Speaker 9:  store. Checking off to-do's on my widget. Like I could, could have been doing
Speaker 9:  on Android since 2010
Speaker 4:  Coming.
Speaker 9:  But yeah, I mean, o other than that it's gonna be the 17th version
Speaker 9:  of ix.
Speaker 3:  It's like, what,
Speaker 4:  What are we, what
Speaker 9:  Are we expecting to change here? I'm,
Speaker 3:  I'm excited 'cause I, the autocorrect situation is bad. It has
Speaker 3:  now that people have pointed out so consistently to us. It has gotten worse
Speaker 3:  in a way that is impossible to measure, but it's definitely worse. And
Speaker 3:  I just, I'm just looking forward to this update.
Speaker 9:  The vibes are off.
Speaker 3:  Gimme your l l m powered autocorrect. Like, I'll take it.
Speaker 3:  Anything has to be better than this. It's weird, right? Have you guys noticed
Speaker 3:  it's gotten worse.
Speaker 4:  Everybody judges me. They always know when I'm on my phone because there's
Speaker 4:  always at least one horrible confusing typo that like
Speaker 4:  Apple was just like, no, I got you. I'm gonna change this word. It totally
Speaker 4:  makes sense. I was like, no, it, it doesn't, it's a terrible context.
Speaker 3:  My theory is that Apple is just trying to push us towards that
Speaker 3:  humane AI pin. They're like, what if you don't use this computer?
Speaker 3:  What if you just talk to your aunt instead?
Speaker 4:  Just, Hey guys, what's up? I have thoughts about the show we're watching
Speaker 3:  By the way, the humane AI pin. This is a totally random, they announced this
Speaker 3:  week that they're, they're gonna Launch or do something in October
Speaker 3:  on the day of a, of an eclipse. That's what I got for you. They put out,
Speaker 3:  you should watch the video. They call out our friend Sam Scheffer in the
Speaker 3:  video that always makes me smile. It's like the only time they all light
Speaker 3:  up, up is when they talk to Sam. Sam's not even in the video. He is behind
Speaker 3:  the camera and they're like, Sam, and they all smile. And that just made
Speaker 3:  me happy. But they're like, A momentous day is coming when the
Speaker 3:  sun will be blacked out forever. And then you will talk to your hand and
Speaker 3:  it's like, okay, so sometime in October they're gonna release this
Speaker 3:  pin and we can all see what's up.
Speaker 4:  Oh the talk to the hand puns. We just gotta get those
Speaker 4:  out of our systems. Or I guess it's probably just me. I just gotta get that
Speaker 4:  out of my system until that it's
Speaker 3:  Announced. I did the post about PornHub MindGeek suing
Speaker 3:  a restaurant in New York City called Donor House. It's a kebab restaurant.
Speaker 3:  And I was like, don't make the joke please. And everyone in the comments
Speaker 3:  made the joke.
Speaker 4:  You just let other people do it like it's right there. It's like, okay, I'm
Speaker 4:  not, I'm gonna resist. Do it for me.
Speaker 3:  I was like, I'm just begging you. And everyone's like, here it is. We
Speaker 3:  said it, it's fine. Okay, we gotta take a break.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna come back and do a lightning round with Dan. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Hi, I am Neli Patel, editor-in-chief of The Verge and host of the Decoder
Speaker 3:  podcast. This September I'm taking over as one of the new hosts of the code
Speaker 3:  conference alongside CNBC's, Julia Borson and Casey Newton
Speaker 3:  from Platformer and Hard Fork. You've heard us all talk to major players
Speaker 3:  in the worlds of tech and business on our shows. But code has
Speaker 3:  live unfiltered journalism you won't find anywhere else.
Speaker 3:  This year we have onstage interviews with x slash Twitter, c e o, Linda Ya
Speaker 3:  carino, Microsoft c t O, Kevin Scott, and many more. From AI
Speaker 3:  to streaming platform shifts to privacy. No one knows exactly where
Speaker 3:  we're headed, but code is where the world's most influential people come
Speaker 3:  together to find out. Join us for the start of a new era.
Speaker 3:  Apply to attend the code conference now at Vox
Speaker 3:  media.com/code. That's Vox
Speaker 3:  media.com/code. We'll see you in September.
Speaker 3:  We are back lightning round time. There's a lot going on in this lightning
Speaker 3:  round.
Speaker 4:  So much good stuff and some like sad stuff, mainly good stuff.
Speaker 3:  There's also an email where the, the subject line is htm I disgust me,
Speaker 3:  which is just, we have found our people. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I was like, they get us, they get us.
Speaker 3:  I, I keep, I I use this line that I I ruthlessly stole from Casey Newton
Speaker 3:  all the time, which is anybody can get traffic but it's impossible to get
Speaker 3:  an audience and it's like oh we have an audience like that. Those are,
Speaker 3:  you have to trust us to send us that subject line.
Speaker 3:  That's a relationship and I appreciate you
Speaker 3:  Sal. It was from Sal. Anyway, his point is that DisplayPort is superior to
Speaker 3:  HT m i because of a piece in Hackaday Hackaday by the way. I personally have
Speaker 3:  a long history with that was there's a long intertwining of Hackaday and
Speaker 3:  Eng Gadget back in the day. We'll link the hack Hey piece about
Speaker 3:  DisplayPort being better but Htm, I discussed me, Sal
Speaker 5:  Ends his email by saying I feel like I've been red pilled by DisplayPort.
Speaker 5:  It's very, is unbelievable.
Speaker 3:  It's a very good look. DisplayPort is packet based and I understand, I understand
Speaker 3:  the point. Fine. Okay. Lightning round Cranz, you've got
Speaker 3:  the best one. Take us away.
Speaker 4:  Are you ever like having a dinner party with your friends
Speaker 4:  outside and you're like, I really wanna watch some tv. So you go, you get
Speaker 4:  your little suitcase out of the closet and you put it out and you watch your
Speaker 4:  TV 'cause it's in the suitcase. And then later you're like, oh man, I'm going
Speaker 4:  camping with the buddies. I need to watch TV on my camping trip.
Speaker 4:  So you bring your little suitcase with you. LG was like, everybody
Speaker 4:  needs to be able to do that. Not just people who built a suitcase tv.
Speaker 4:  The rest of us need to be able to do it. So there's the 27 inch
Speaker 4:  stand by Mego
Speaker 5:  To be clear, not stand by me. Which would make sense.
Speaker 4:  Stand by me stand
Speaker 9:  And, and not, not Migo the right intel based mobile platform.
Speaker 4:  I'm just, I'm gonna sit stand by me, make mego like I refuse to, to
Speaker 4:  break it out into one in multiple words. It's beautiful.
Speaker 4:  It can last three hours on a charge so you can get through one of
Speaker 4:  the Lord of the Rings movies.
Speaker 3:  Wait, I just, how like there's so much room for
Speaker 3:  it's a suitcase.
Speaker 9:  Wait, but it's a 27 inch street. It's huge.
Speaker 5:  You guys, I have, I have a revolutionary idea. Make the suitcase
Speaker 5:  bigger.
Speaker 9:  Give me more
Speaker 3:  Scream
Speaker 5:  And more battery. No,
Speaker 3:  I in a bigger suitcase, my 16 inch MacBook
Speaker 3:  Pro with an M one Pro chip has a bigger
Speaker 3:  battery life than this television
Speaker 9:  11 inch smaller screen.
Speaker 3:  You're telling me that it's just the pixels but it can run
Speaker 3:  an M one chip?
Speaker 5:  Well it runs web oss, which is probably the reason it only gets three hours.
Speaker 9:  My my favorite part of LGS promotional
Speaker 9:  images of this is it's, there's two young, very fashionable hip
Speaker 9:  people sitting by a pool. Yes. And the guy is using the TV
Speaker 3:  Yes.
Speaker 9:  To skip a track on the world's largest music widget.
Speaker 9:  'cause it's 27 inches in size to just go the next track.
Speaker 9:  And then, and they didn't pay for any licensing. So
Speaker 9:  the song is song titled by artist's name.
Speaker 3:  If you, it's a b by the way. This is what I was gonna call out to. Perfect
Speaker 3:  call out from Dan. If you're in your car, pull over now the link is in the
Speaker 3:  show notes. Go look at this picture. When, when marketing
Speaker 3:  agencies come up with briefs for products, they're like, we,
Speaker 3:  here's what we want people to feel. Here's how we're gonna execute it.
Speaker 3:  I want to know what they wanted you to feel when they
Speaker 3:  executed this photo. Right. They had to do it, they had to, they had to get
Speaker 3:  some tables, they had to get a lady with a book. They had to buy white linen
Speaker 3:  clothes for this gentleman. He has a drink here. They put a lemon in it.
Speaker 3:  They opened the suitcase. They were like, they instructed
Speaker 3:  him to be pointing at the next track button in what looks like a clone
Speaker 3:  of Apple music but is not Apple music. All of that happened
Speaker 3:  like a series of decisions happened with intent. And
Speaker 3:  I'm just dying to know, like, I don't believe this
Speaker 3:  TV is a touch screen. I
Speaker 9:  I think it is actually
Speaker 3:  It, it is a touch screen
Speaker 9:  In, in other points about this TV one, it can rotate
Speaker 9:  90 degrees so you can watch TOS on it. Oh
Speaker 3:  It is a touchscreen. It has table mode and Yes. And then
Speaker 9:  You could play chess on it with the touchscreen as they show in other
Speaker 9:  photos.
Speaker 4:  It's got Dolby vision, it's got Dolby Atmos with four
Speaker 4:  speakers.
Speaker 3:  It's 10 80 p Dolby Vision.
Speaker 4:  Oh that's gonna be, yeah, like you're gonna watch your one half hour of a
Speaker 4:  show because you've probably forgot to charge it. So you've only got 30 minutes
Speaker 4:  of time and you're gonna watch your 30 minutes of the nanny in Dolby vision.
Speaker 9:  And it also has to get bright enough so you can actually see it outside.
Speaker 9:  So it's gotta run at like 1200
Speaker 5:  Knits. It has an outdoor picture mode which
Speaker 5:  acknowledges the fact that you are out in the world like Neli. If we're just
Speaker 5:  gonna go down the road of like, how are we marketing this thing? The the
Speaker 5:  idea that they are giving is you're gonna bring this thing, you're gonna
Speaker 5:  put it in the trunk of your car, you're gonna go camping, you're gonna open
Speaker 5:  up the trunk of your car, you're gonna open up the suitcase. You're gonna,
Speaker 5:  you're gonna swivel up the screen, turn it on and you're gonna put on a,
Speaker 5:  a video of a quote cozy crackling fireplace
Speaker 5:  while you're out camping.
Speaker 4:  Is that not what you do when you camp? You don't put the iPad out
Speaker 5:  Like, oh we could make a fire. And you say, what do you mean I've already
Speaker 5:  made a fire. And you just pull the screen up and that's it.
Speaker 3:  I just want to point out, if you watch their video, they're all sitting around
Speaker 3:  an outdoor dining table and she opens the suitcase and
Speaker 3:  opens the screen showing the fire
Speaker 4:  And then makes you watch a YouTube video.
Speaker 3:  Oh it's all very good.
Speaker 5:  Do you, you say I have made fire every time. It's amazing.
Speaker 3:  Every single person on our staff wants to buy this tv. I don't dunno why
Speaker 3:  it's only a
Speaker 4:  Thousand dollars.
Speaker 3:  That's the wrong way to think about money.
Speaker 5:  It's only a thousand dollars.
Speaker 3:  Many, like an iPhone is a thousand dollars.
Speaker 4:  Every outdoor dinner party is just transformed with this a
Speaker 4:  thousand dollars device. But
Speaker 9:  If you pre-order it, you get a free x boom 360 speaker,
Speaker 9:  which is two $50. So really it's like the
Speaker 9:  TV is free. Wait
Speaker 5:  Basically. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Again, if You know what the intent of the man
Speaker 3:  change his track on music player picture is please just like please
Speaker 3:  let me know. Touch I'm, I'm just dying to know. I'm also dying
Speaker 3:  for the first person to take this as a carry on, on a plane
Speaker 3:  and just
Speaker 5:  Bust it out of the tray table.
Speaker 3:  But yeah, just like it's gonna
Speaker 9:  Happen. The T ss a will never let you get on a plane with this thing. They're
Speaker 9:  gonna look at this thing and detain you for the longest time ever. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  They're gonna be like, what is this music widget we need to know. Right.
Speaker 5:  But you show them the fire and it's gonna be fine.
Speaker 3:  Alright Dan, what's your, what's your lightning round?
Speaker 9:  I'm gonna plug myself, I reviewed the three Galaxy
Speaker 9:  Tab SS nine tablets today on the site. And I'm just gonna say it,
Speaker 9:  Android tablets are interesting this year.
Speaker 3:  Really? Yeah,
Speaker 9:  They're back
Speaker 3:  Baby.
Speaker 4:  Finally.
Speaker 9:  Android tablets. It's a year of Android tablets.
Speaker 3:  When you say they're back,
Speaker 4:  They never left,
Speaker 3:  Do you mean that they are back in a way that is competitive with the iPad
Speaker 3:  or back in the sense that someone is releasing them?
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 9:  Would say that they are actually pretty interesting and good.
Speaker 9:  This like, yeah, the, the interesting part about it is Samsung's
Speaker 9:  been releasing high-end Android tablets that have been pretty decent for
Speaker 9:  a few years now, but it's been only Samsung and now there's like
Speaker 9:  actual competition within the Android space. You could buy a Pixel tablet
Speaker 9:  or you could buy a OnePlus tablet or you could buy a Lenovo tablet
Speaker 9:  or something like that. Samsung still makes the best ones, but it also makes
Speaker 9:  like the most expensive ones. So there's like actual variety.
Speaker 9:  It's, there's different ideas happening, there's different experimentation.
Speaker 9:  The software's gotten a lot better. There are actual
Speaker 9:  ecosystems that have been built out. If you're a Samsung phone owner, it
Speaker 9:  makes a lot of sense to use a Samsung tablet because it works together in
Speaker 9:  the way that an iPhone works with an iPad. So wait, it's
Speaker 4:  Dan, aren't you a Samsung phone owner? I,
Speaker 9:  I am. Do
Speaker 4:  You use a Samsung tablet or do you use an iPad?
Speaker 9:  I would say that nobody should buy their purchase decisions based on my own
Speaker 9:  personal device choices
Speaker 3:  Tracks.
Speaker 9:  Because you will be entering regret.
Speaker 3:  I've seen Dan use Dex.
Speaker 9:  I I use Dex. Like, like Dex is, is is fascinating and
Speaker 9:  like surprisingly capable at this point. It used to be a hot mess.
Speaker 9:  But I think I, I wrote this entire piece on Dex and I spent quite
Speaker 9:  a few days actually working on Dex to like test the, the tablets and stuff
Speaker 9:  and it's You know pretty, pretty good.
Speaker 5:  Dex is good now I spent a decade going to meetings with Samsung
Speaker 5:  being like, You know Dex exists, right? What if you did anything to it? And
Speaker 5:  they were like, nah, it's Dex, it's like a thing. We put in
Speaker 5:  slides but no one actually uses and now they've like made it into a thing.
Speaker 5:  You can actually like have multiple windows in a way that isn't bad
Speaker 5:  on your tablet. Like what a concept it
Speaker 9:  Feels like Stage manager, if you took all the binders
Speaker 9:  off of Stage Manager and all the restrictions off of stage manager and you
Speaker 9:  did the thing that you wanna do with Windows on a screen, that's what Dex
Speaker 9:  is.
Speaker 3:  Okay. I'm just gonna, Dan, I'm I'm just looking at your scores. I'm just,
Speaker 3:  I'm just evaluating Enter a tablets are back. So
Speaker 9:  You are a commenter on the website? Yes,
Speaker 3:  I am the people. So you gave the Tab SS nine and eight, which is
Speaker 3:  fair, although 16 by 10 is
Speaker 9:  Yeah, that's why main complete with the S nine is 16 x 10 is still a little
Speaker 3:  Blah. And then the SS nine Ultra, which is the one that like You
Speaker 3:  know the, the YouTubers just waved around in TikTok. It'd be like, look
Speaker 3:  at this and I got it. I was like, yep, look at that. But you gave that one
Speaker 3:  a six 'cause it's gigantic and ridiculous. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And $1,200 it's
Speaker 4:  More expensive than the the suitcase TV too.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, that's true. Well it
Speaker 3:  Has a processor already.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it does anything
Speaker 4:  Outrageously priced
Speaker 3:  And then the SS nine plus you gave a six and this one just
Speaker 3:  blah. Like I don't even like looking at it,
Speaker 5:  I feel like there's, there's required to be one tablet in every
Speaker 5:  lineup that just makes no sense and no one should buy it. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 9:  I You know in a vacuum, the SS nine plus is great. You know it's got a great
Speaker 9:  screen, great performance, it's got all the benefits that the others have.
Speaker 9:  It's just, it's too big to like comfortably use for tablet stuff.
Speaker 9:  And then it's like if you are going to buy it for productivity,
Speaker 9:  just buy the Ultra because that gives you the space to really be
Speaker 9:  productive in a way that the Plus doesn't
Speaker 3:  For for $200 more you can have the one that people go, whoa.
Speaker 3:  Right. I mean that's like, that's this product. Like you look at an
Speaker 3:  Sine Ultra, you're like, holy shit that that's a thing that exists.
Speaker 3:  You look at the SS nine plus and you're like, well I'm gonna buy an iPad.
Speaker 3:  Like that's that product. It's like this is the one that is the most head-on
Speaker 3:  with an iPad. The bezels are big. I would
Speaker 9:  Say that the bezels are not that big.
Speaker 3:  Oh, in this photo it looks like they're huge.
Speaker 9:  Maybe they look that way. The photo huge You know what it is. It's because
Speaker 9:  that photo is a photo of a video in 16 by nine. So it's making it
Speaker 9:  look bigger. But if you look at the side, you can see the, the bezels on
Speaker 9:  the side, they're, they're not that big.
Speaker 4:  So if you watch anything, if you watch the vast majority of TV today,
Speaker 4:  it'll look like it has huge bezels.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. 'cause it's great on an iPad. Four, three movies. That's my favorite.
Speaker 3:  Okay. I'm, this is my defense of four three. Four, three is the god's chosen
Speaker 3:  aspect ratio for portable computers. Our
Speaker 5:  Thorn and savior four, three,
Speaker 3:  I'm saying 16, nine and 1610 screens are horrible. 1610 is the
Speaker 3:  worst of all worlds. Right? Because you watch a movie, you still get the
Speaker 3:  weird letter boxing and then you try to do any work and and or
Speaker 3:  hold it God forbid in portrait. And you're like, well I'm just a
Speaker 3:  guy with a rectangle. Everyone look at me
Speaker 3:  and iPad like four three is like, you make one compromise on watching
Speaker 3:  video, you make one compromise and everything else is great. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  16, nine. You make one compromise, which is useful for, which is that it's
Speaker 3:  useless for, for anything but watching video. Oh
Speaker 5:  My god. The thing is enormous
Speaker 3:  Dan. See that good sport,
Speaker 9:  That's a thing. It's a platter. This is, this is the ultra So.
Speaker 3:  We have not, we have not spent enough time in this show just
Speaker 3:  we look, the audience has grown, we've added a second episode, we gotta do
Speaker 3:  an entire episode. That's just like there's one correct aspect ratio. No,
Speaker 3:  you're
Speaker 9:  Wrong.
Speaker 5:  The correct aspect ratio is three, two on laptops. That's it.
Speaker 5:  There's no other good answer. Four three. You just said the only
Speaker 5:  compromise with four three is watching video, which is the main thing most
Speaker 5:  people do all the time.
Speaker 9:  Like
Speaker 5:  It's like, remember when Max were good except the keyboard sucked. Like it
Speaker 5:  turns out keyboards are pretty important
Speaker 3:  To
Speaker 9:  Samsung's credit. These devices are phenomenal for watching video.
Speaker 9:  Like the screens are tremendous, the sound is tremendous. Like these are
Speaker 9:  entertainment machines. It's just personally, if I'm gonna spend
Speaker 9:  $1,200 on a device, I'm gonna wanna do more than just watch a movie once
Speaker 9:  a week or whatever on it. And so like I do wanna get more out of it.
Speaker 4:  When do we get like a 2.39 aspect
Speaker 4:  ratio on a pathway
Speaker 3:  Like that to Toshiba laptop
Speaker 9:  That had the 21 by nine screens.
Speaker 3:  Right.
Speaker 4:  I wanna feel like I'm watching a movie in the sixties on cama.
Speaker 4:  Like I just wanted Wow.
Speaker 3:  Christopher No was like, I made a
Speaker 3:  laptops. You're not gonna believe how wide. It's,
Speaker 4:  It's all I want.
Speaker 3:  Alright, David, what's your, what's your pick?
Speaker 5:  Mine's quick. It's, I've been following all this Google SS g e
Speaker 5:  ai search stuff for a while and Google this week in
Speaker 5:  the, in the guise of like relatively You know minor
Speaker 5:  feature update rolled out a thing where you can now use ss
Speaker 5:  g e as you look at webpages and it will summarize them for you and you can
Speaker 5:  like interact with webpages through Google's ai. And it's like,
Speaker 5:  that's not a small thing. That's like an enormous leap in Google
Speaker 5:  making Chrome like the AI hub of the
Speaker 5:  internet, which is messy and weird and complicated and
Speaker 5:  fascinating. And they're also putting more AI stuff in the
Speaker 5:  sidebar of Chrome. So it's like very quietly AI is coming
Speaker 5:  like front and center to the entire web browsing experience through Google.
Speaker 5:  And like you talk about kind of AI all the way down, like we're
Speaker 5:  gonna get to the point where Google's AI is summarizing AI generated
Speaker 5:  webpages that you found through Google's AI powered search. And
Speaker 5:  it's just all gonna get real, real, real weird. But Google
Speaker 5:  like binging has been so loud about like we are putting Bing everywhere.
Speaker 5:  Like Google is being very quiet about it, but it's basically doing the same
Speaker 5:  thing.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The the, especially the sidebar stuff. The interesting thing about
Speaker 3:  s G E right now is Google featured snippets are
Speaker 3:  still often superior. Yeah. To s g e. Like
Speaker 3:  the AI will like overwrite in a way like a precocious seventh grader and
Speaker 3:  it's like, nah, I just need the answer to the question. Like Right. I don't
Speaker 3:  need all this preamble.
Speaker 5:  It can't answer a question. Like if, if a question has a simple answer, it's,
Speaker 5:  it can help you like explore the universe of, of your question. But it
Speaker 5:  can't just be like seven.
Speaker 10:  It just can't do that.
Speaker 3:  This thing though, this new SSG features where it's summarizing pages,
Speaker 3:  there's something going on in the background. I dunno what it is. If you
Speaker 3:  work with the New York Times, please tell me what it's, there's something
Speaker 3:  going on with the New York Times and Google and OpenAI that I have not been
Speaker 3:  able to to piece out. But if you look at New York Times' robot,
Speaker 3:  T X T, it, it allows everything. It allows, Google allows OpenAI, it's, it
Speaker 3:  literally it's star whatever I'll add. There's no
Speaker 3:  very few things are blocked, which is fascinating. We got a actually a, a
Speaker 3:  question from our reporter. When OpenAI rolled out its crawler that once
Speaker 3:  you have a crawler you can can block it. So they just rolled it out and someone
Speaker 3:  asked us, Hey, why do you block it? And the reason is actually contained
Speaker 3:  in a piece David wrote about Neva, which is the internet
Speaker 3:  has been so fixed for so long that most places
Speaker 3:  only allowed Google and binging because binging powered all the other search
Speaker 3:  engines for so long. So you only needed to allow Google and binging and
Speaker 3:  everything else was just cost, right? Like a, an infinite amount of crawlers
Speaker 3:  coming over your pages is just server costs. You don't need to pay because
Speaker 3:  there's Google and there's binging. So most publishers, most
Speaker 3:  pages only allow that. So OpenAI, now that they have a new crawler, they
Speaker 3:  gotta go get permission from everyone. The Times allows everything. But
Speaker 3:  then there was a report this week that they might sue OpenAI 'cause they're
Speaker 3:  really mad at them and they want a deal and they have a deal with Google
Speaker 3:  that no one knows the terms of, I'm telling you, there's this thing that
Speaker 3:  is happening with AI on the web and all these features that are quietly rolling
Speaker 3:  out in the background of it is like a nuclear
Speaker 3:  explosion of lawsuits. It is just coming and it's, it's gonna
Speaker 3:  be wild. And we're gonna talk about it at the code conference September 26th
Speaker 3:  and 27th in California.
Speaker 3:  I love it. It was good. I got there in the end. Actually my lightning round
Speaker 3:  ones are all AI two ones
Speaker 5:  You'll notice. Yeah. Neli said ones because unlike the rest of us, NELI is
Speaker 5:  incapable of following the rules. Well
Speaker 3:  It's two that are the same one, it's two that are the same thing.
Speaker 3:  So OpenAI rolled out GPT four to do content moderation,
Speaker 3:  which is terrifying. But
Speaker 5:  Everybody treated this like it was a new thing. They were like, oh they're
Speaker 5:  gonna have humans looking at the production of the algorithm and then
Speaker 5:  they're gonna feed it back into the algorithm. She just did a story, what
Speaker 5:  a novel concept and it's like that's how it has worked forever.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like Facebook and YouTube in particular
Speaker 3:  have been like, this is a problem and maybe AI can solve. Like
Speaker 3:  do you think Google has not been trying to do AI and content moderation YouTube
Speaker 3:  for ages? Like they've been doing it that said, Casey
Speaker 3:  asked a bunch of experts about it and platformer you go read it. That experts
Speaker 3:  seem to really like this idea. They they think it is faster. They think they
Speaker 3:  can build some tools. Importantly they think a bunch of startup social networks
Speaker 3:  can use tools like this. You don't need the resources of a a a Microsoft,
Speaker 3:  you don't need the resources of a meta or a Google or whatever. There's
Speaker 3:  something there. Importantly if you go to Europe and all these other places,
Speaker 3:  they have laws in the books now that say you have to be able to explain your
Speaker 3:  content moderation decisions. And it's not clear if GPT four can do that.
Speaker 3:  So it can't
Speaker 4:  Let's
Speaker 3:  They can't or they or they gotta build it. I mean
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I was like it can't yet.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Part of what they said they're doing is part of the process is asking
Speaker 5:  the model to explain itself. And as we've seen like the more recursive
Speaker 5:  you get with these LLMs, the weirder and worse they all get. Yeah. But,
Speaker 5:  but it's an interesting road to go down. And I think you're right. Like even
Speaker 5:  if all this does is get everybody to like
Speaker 5:  you can plug and play c plus content moderation, like that's
Speaker 5:  already a huge win for the internet. Are
Speaker 4:  We gonna have a point where the content moderation, like where they ask the
Speaker 4:  chat GPT to explain itself and, and we're gonna have to talk about how it
Speaker 4:  just claimed that it was like a unicorn that longs for death.
Speaker 3:  Like, I don't know, like I I I think we'll see, I mean the, the
Speaker 3:  flip side of this, which right we're we're talking about putting a robot
Speaker 3:  in a position to censor content is in Iowa school district. There are
Speaker 3:  book bans across this country right now. This is a real problem.
Speaker 3:  They decided they weren't gonna read the books. They were just gonna ask
Speaker 3:  chat GPT to summarize all the books in the library and tell them which
Speaker 3:  ones to ban, which is like a pure abdication
Speaker 3:  of two D. Like that is the laziest shit I have ever heard in my
Speaker 3:  entire life. If you are going to ban books don't, right?
Speaker 3:  Like first, second like do do the work.
Speaker 3:  Be like we, we asked a robot to tell us what books to ban. Like this
Speaker 3:  is the, the beginning of the use of the tool beyond just
Speaker 3:  the cool demos you see on TikTok. It's oh lazy people are
Speaker 3:  gonna make stupid decisions with it. That impact like lots of things.
Speaker 4:  This was, I mean this was also kind of a protest because they're being
Speaker 4:  required. They have to go do it all themselves. Like they didn't, they weren't
Speaker 4:  given a list of books. They were basically said you'll be like subject to
Speaker 4:  big fines and stuff if you don't put together your list of
Speaker 4:  books and have it done by a certain time. So that's why like they were like,
Speaker 4:  okay, well we'll just do it fast and have chat GPT do it because you don't
Speaker 4:  care about the kids so why should we? It was kind of like my read of of
Speaker 4:  why they were doing it
Speaker 3:  A a protest chat. ChatGPT, GPT banned. Still
Speaker 4:  Not great, still like still books getting banned and kids don't have access
Speaker 4:  to important media but like, well
Speaker 3:  It got attention from us. So there's that. But I would say, this is the flip
Speaker 3:  side of we, we want to be able to explain itself when you start making
Speaker 3:  decisions like we'll let the robot summarize the book So, we can ban it from
Speaker 3:  our library. You really need that robot to be able to explain
Speaker 3:  itself. And so that's why I said it's two things that are kind of the same
Speaker 3:  thing. Like we're gonna put it in charge of speech on the internet.
Speaker 3:  It should really be able to explain itself because people, once you start
Speaker 3:  saying this is an acceptable thing to do with it, people are gonna use it
Speaker 3:  in truly bizarre ways. Last two things. We mentioned this
Speaker 3:  briefly at the top of the show. The special council Jack Smith has obtained
Speaker 3:  Trump's DMs from Twitter. We won't go into it except to say this is why
Speaker 3:  we are constantly banging on about encryption and if this brings our two
Speaker 3:  parties into alignment on the need for end-to-end encryption on our platforms,
Speaker 3:  I'll take it. 'cause that's why you have it. Also your Twitter
Speaker 3:  DMs have never been deleted. They just get hidden when you hit delete.
Speaker 3:  Use encrypted platforms people and tell, use them. Don't
Speaker 3:  DMM people on Twitter. All right, last one. Cranz. There's a Microsoft event
Speaker 3:  in New York coming up.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, September 21st. We're gonna get a Microsoft event.
Speaker 4:  Sounds like we'll probably get some surfaces 'cause they frequently do one
Speaker 4:  in like September, October. There's usually a big surface event. So it sounds
Speaker 4:  like we'll get some of that. Who knows what else. Microsoft's been very busy
Speaker 4:  this year so I wouldn't be surprised if we see other stuff. But who can say,
Speaker 5:  I believe they're gonna talk about AI would be my guess. Yeah, just if I
Speaker 5:  had to just kind of wildly stab in the dark, I think it's
Speaker 5:  possible that the word co-pilot will be mentioned
Speaker 3:  When you turn on the new surface. It's like, have you broken up with your
Speaker 3:  wife yet?
Speaker 3:  I'm here for you. Yeah. Speaking of Microsoft AI Code
Speaker 3:  conference, September 26th, 27th. Microsoft CT O, Kevin Scott. Definitely
Speaker 3:  gonna talk about AI.
Speaker 5:  September by the way is going to be nuts. We
Speaker 5:  assume there's gonna be an Apple event the second week of September. There's
Speaker 5:  gonna be an Amazon event on the 20th. This is gonna be on the 21st.
Speaker 5:  Code is then Meta Connect I believe is at the end of September. Like
Speaker 5:  it's, it's gonna be full crazy coming back. Fun like for all The
Speaker 5:  Vergecast listeners who are like, oh, talk about more gadgets. Oh, it's coming
Speaker 5:  y'all. It is coming.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. These August Vergecast where we're just like, here's a grab bag of
Speaker 3:  cool stuff to talk. No, no, no. Dead focus. Yeah, it's coming.
Speaker 5:  It's four hour don't
Speaker 3:  Episodes. Alright, speaking in which everyone go get some rest. Pull over
Speaker 3:  in your car, take a nap by the side of the road and get ready for September.
Speaker 5:  Put the, put the fire on your suitcase TV and take a nap.
Speaker 3:  Alright, we gotta wrap up. David, you've got a new newsletter called Installer.
Speaker 3:  Tell people about that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's basically just designed to point people towards all the cool things
Speaker 5:  that exist on the internet. We've put out one issue so far. The second one's
Speaker 5:  coming out this weekend. It's been really fun. A lot of people got really
Speaker 5:  mad, which I assume is a sign that it's, it's fun and interesting and things
Speaker 5:  are going well. We're changing up a bunch of stuff, learning new things all
Speaker 5:  the time. The vir.com/installer and also send me all the
Speaker 5:  cool things. The best thing about this newsletter has been that everybody
Speaker 5:  now tags me in funny things on the internet. Great. It's great. Awesome.
Speaker 5:  That's great. I love it very much.
Speaker 3:  Go subscribe to installer. It is very fun. I will say, I will not apologize
Speaker 3:  for not deleting two factor notifications.
Speaker 3:  The number of people are like, why do you have all these unreads? I'm like,
Speaker 3:  they're like five year old, two factor notification. I typed in the code
Speaker 3:  already and they're like, go delete it. I'm like, I'm not using my time.
Speaker 3:  That way you can come over to my house and blow an hour
Speaker 3:  deleting old notifications. I
Speaker 9:  17 is here to save you Neli. Yeah man. It will delete them automatically.
Speaker 9:  Ah,
Speaker 3:  It's gonna be beautiful. I cannot wait. Have the number of emails I get where
Speaker 3:  I'm like, yep, I saw that subject line and I refuse to take, if the phone
Speaker 3:  could just read my mind that it's like your order
Speaker 3:  is ready is not a thing that I need to take any further action on. You need
Speaker 9:  Like Superman's, laser eyes and just like blast them.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Look at the Quint at the phone. That's
Speaker 4:  What Humane's gonna do. Don't work.
Speaker 5:  You just tell your hand like, I got it.
Speaker 4:  Delete all the bad emails.
Speaker 3:  All right. That's it. That's The. Vergecast. Send us photos of your computer
Speaker 3:  rooms. I'm dying to the good ones. Not your modern
Speaker 3:  garbage ones. They're probably great in a couple weeks. We'll ask her those
Speaker 3:  too. Yeah, but I'm looking for You. know that that that tone of
Speaker 3:  wood that was sold in the office, Mac that. I want that.
Speaker 3:  Alright, we love you. That's the rich cast. Rock and roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 1:  us an email at Vergecast at The Verge dot com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and the Box Media Podcast Network. The show is produced
Speaker 1:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. Our
Speaker 1:  editorial director is Brooke Miners. That's it. We'll see you next week.