# Transcript
ID: eaae2493-1b84-4e55-969a-151e9938def6
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Instagram Threads is here to crush Twitter
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7196297431523671109/-7402524581217851141/s93290-US-5170s-1688804316.mp3
Description: The Verge's David Pierce, Alex Cranz, and Alex Heath discuss Meta's launch of Threads, a new competitor to Twitter. Later, Nilay Patel calls in to give his take.
Speaker 5:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of cloning other people's
Speaker 5:  apps and calling them slightly different names. I'm your friend David Pierce
Speaker 5:  and that is all we're gonna talk about today. Alex Cranz is here. Hi
Speaker 5:  Alex.
Speaker 6:  I'm your friend who wants to start a new website called The
Speaker 6:  Splurge. It's fine. It's about flirts.
Speaker 5:  It's like a flirty Verge. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Ooh, I like that better. There you go. Better. That's better. Love
Speaker 5:  It. Alex. Heath is here from I think a studio or
Speaker 5:  just a surprisingly soundproof place. I don't know what's going on. It's
Speaker 7:  Not that secret. It's our's, our LA office. But yes, I
Speaker 7:  suppose, I suppose secret for all intensive purposes.
Speaker 5:  We have to make sure Adam Maser can't find you. That's, that's the important
Speaker 5:  thing.
Speaker 7:  I am here and I have too many damn apps on my phone. I'm not sure what to
Speaker 7:  do about it. I don't know about you all. I
Speaker 5:  Think it was Walt Mossberg who posted something today with just a folder
Speaker 5:  of apps called New Twitter question mark. Yeah. And over like 10 apps in
Speaker 5:  there. It's like, yeah, this is, this is the world we live in now. I
Speaker 5:  suspect we are going to spend the entirety of this show talking about Instagram
Speaker 5:  Threads. So anyone who is expecting anything else, I'm so very sorry
Speaker 5:  this is what we're doing here.
Speaker 7:  We just lost half the audience, but yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's, it's fine. We got a
Speaker 6:  Lightning round. Stick around for the lightning round.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, listen, if, if you want me to have strong feelings about nothing, phone
Speaker 5:  leaks, just wait two or three hours and we'll be
Speaker 5:  there. But let's, let's just get into this. So as
Speaker 5:  we're recording this, it's Thursday afternoon. This app has been live for
Speaker 5:  less than 24 hours and kind of already feels like it has taken
Speaker 5:  over the universe. Heath, you've been, you've been tracking this kind of
Speaker 5:  minute to minute as it has launched. Where do we stand? How is this thing
Speaker 5:  going so far?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, so as we're recording this, mark Zuckerberg shared on Threads
Speaker 7:  this morning that they have surpassed 30 million
Speaker 7:  signups, which I want to be clear blows away the internal
Speaker 7:  projections they had for this thing by a crazy multiple. They're now
Speaker 7:  internally at Meta talking about can we beat the chat G p t
Speaker 7:  record for the fastest Oh wow. Consumer software product at
Speaker 7:  a hundred million users. So that's the, that's the scale of Threads
Speaker 7:  right now. There have been over 95 million
Speaker 7:  posts or I guess Threads, they're called spools, whatever you wanna
Speaker 7:  call them.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna get to that, don't you worry.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. On Threads to date and according to some internal data
Speaker 7:  I reported on this morning on the site, and that sounds like a huge
Speaker 7:  number, but what I think it shows is if you actually map it
Speaker 7:  to the publicly stated signups, you're seeing a similar
Speaker 7:  thing happen to Twitter where, and this has been true of Twitter
Speaker 7:  from the earliest days, the a very small percent of the overall
Speaker 7:  users contribute much of the content and that similar
Speaker 7:  dynamic is starting to play out on Threads even you know before it's a week
Speaker 7:  old.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So let's actually go back a bunch cuz it, the launch was super fascinating.
Speaker 5:  We were all in sort of watching people roll in. I was gonna say we should
Speaker 5:  all compare numbers of who got in first, but Heath, you won so that's no
Speaker 5:  fun. Yeah, Heath cheated
Speaker 7:  Though. These are 2,770 something.
Speaker 7:  Damn.
Speaker 5:  Wow. Look at you. Look at that flex.
Speaker 7:  It's a flex. So backstory on this, like there were
Speaker 7:  only about a thousand people on this app. All mostly internal Meta people
Speaker 7:  and some friends on the 4th of July. They were at just under
Speaker 7:  3000 users when I came on and this was probably four, four or five hours
Speaker 7:  before public launch. They really moved quickly on this thing. They weren't
Speaker 7:  actually planning to release Threads this week. They were planning to do
Speaker 7:  it next week. And what happened is they saw the Elon rate
Speaker 7:  limit fiasco on Twitter over the 4th of July weekend
Speaker 7:  and rushed it out and and employees started working on the holiday to, to
Speaker 7:  get it out. They wanted to have more time for celebs to get
Speaker 7:  onboarded. Celebs didn't get onboarded until about a day before public
Speaker 7:  launch. So this is all moving really fast.
Speaker 5:  I had wondered about that actually because you could not have
Speaker 5:  imagined a more perfect time to launch an app like this
Speaker 5:  and there have been a lot of these sort of fortuitous moments to
Speaker 5:  try and compete with Twitter over the last eight months or so. But this one
Speaker 5:  in particular because I think, what was it Saturday the second I think
Speaker 5:  was when Elon tweeted were rate limiting people and if you're not paying
Speaker 5:  you only get to see 600 tweets a day. They put up the login things so you
Speaker 5:  couldn't see tweets unless you were logged in And there was this very clear
Speaker 5:  like closing down the walls of Twitter thing that everybody, some
Speaker 5:  combination of thought was stupid and ruthlessly made fun of both of which
Speaker 5:  I think were correct responses to those moves. But then I was just thinking
Speaker 5:  about this yesterday as this launch happened, like holy god, what a perfect
Speaker 5:  moment. If I'm a Meta executive sitting there saying we're about to
Speaker 5:  launch a thing that kind of looks a lot like Twitter and if they had launched
Speaker 5:  this four years ago, everybody would've been like, oh God, they launched
Speaker 5:  Twitter but now they pick this perfect moment and everybody's like, oh my
Speaker 5:  god, they launched Twitter. Like it's the best news of all time.
Speaker 5:  Somehow I thought
Speaker 6:  It was impressive that they got around. Like a lot of people might have assumed
Speaker 6:  that the rate limiting and everything was in reaction to the impending
Speaker 6:  launch and it was like, no, this is very clearly these guys suck.
Speaker 6:  We're gonna do it too and hopefully we suck less.
Speaker 7:  How weird is it that we're talking about Meta and like the context of a
Speaker 7:  good guy almost right, right now. Yeah, it's very strange. I
Speaker 6:  Think that's like, I don't wanna call them a good guy, but a more
Speaker 6:  pleasing alternative
Speaker 7:  A more, okay, that's more fair I guess. But like Zuck is on Threads like
Speaker 7:  boasting about how many hours he gets to sleep a night and posting
Speaker 7:  pics of him spending time with his baby in the morning and his meanwhile
Speaker 7:  like record signups. Like it's just this level
Speaker 7:  of like them feeling good and getting really
Speaker 7:  positive energy that I haven't seen in a very, very long time for
Speaker 7:  Meta.
Speaker 5:  It is really fascinating. And that's actually, you talked to Adam Maser I
Speaker 5:  think in like the hours running up to the launch. Yeah and that was one of
Speaker 5:  the things you guys talked about, right? Because there were, there are two
Speaker 5:  things about being Meta that are very funny to me here. One is that like
Speaker 5:  over the last say half decade, I can't think of a company, more people
Speaker 5:  have said oh maybe they shouldn't be in charge of all of our social networks.
Speaker 5:  Like Meta has not been a company you want running your social life over the
Speaker 5:  last several years. And then on the flip side, Meta's history of
Speaker 5:  launching new apps is like as bad as any company other than
Speaker 5:  Google that I can think of it launched a thing called Threads
Speaker 5:  already and killed it. Yeah. But you were talking to Adam and the, the sense
Speaker 5:  I got was there's, there's a lot of confidence inside that company for
Speaker 5:  how they can do something like this right now.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think they were confident but they were at least publicly trying
Speaker 7:  to project the sense of like Adam told me it was a risky bet
Speaker 7:  that they know that launching a new app in the year 2023 has a
Speaker 7:  much more likely chance of failing than not
Speaker 7:  versus tacking it on to an existing app like Instagram that already
Speaker 7:  has over a billion users. I think they're being proven in their
Speaker 7:  early signups that the instinct was right to to split it
Speaker 7:  off. And as Moser kind of explained it to me, the main reason
Speaker 7:  for doing so is they wanted to give equal weight to
Speaker 7:  not only the posts but the comments And on Instagram
Speaker 7:  there that's just really not an intuitive experience. It doesn't make sense
Speaker 7:  on Instagram and it's really Twitter's magic and
Speaker 7:  Threads I mean it's called Threads. They want the Threads to be the most
Speaker 7:  prominent thing and they realized to do that, they wanted to split it out.
Speaker 7:  They've been trying to simplify Instagram, they didn't want to add another
Speaker 7:  tab, which I am very much in favor for and it's smart to
Speaker 7:  use the Instagram social graph as the kickoff here and let you bring your
Speaker 7:  Instagram onto Threads because the kinds of people on Instagram
Speaker 7:  who are active posters probably maps the closest to Twitter's most
Speaker 7:  active posters then any of Meta's properties.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think if it had tried to pull your Facebook friends it would've vibed
Speaker 5:  very differently. Yeah. And I was just thinking about this as I was going
Speaker 5:  through cuz I think one of the first things you have to do is basically decide
Speaker 5:  like do you wanna bring your Instagram graph in with you when you sign up
Speaker 5:  for it? If I'm remembering it right, this is all so long ago now you have
Speaker 5:  to use your Instagram handle. Yes. But then you sort of get to choose what
Speaker 5:  else from Instagram you wanna bring in, right? There's like a button that's
Speaker 5:  like, do you want your Instagram bio? There's another button that's like,
Speaker 5:  do you want your followers and and follows. Yeah. And I was just thinking
Speaker 5:  about it and I was like my Facebook friend
Speaker 5:  graph I just have not like thought about or touched in
Speaker 5:  years. And so it's like all of my
Speaker 5:  exes and people I don't talk to from high school
Speaker 5:  and like my random relatives who I don't
Speaker 5:  ever talk to otherwise who have crazy political opinions, I don't want that
Speaker 5:  in another social app.
Speaker 7:  You don't want your college classmates' opinions on RFK Junior and
Speaker 7:  Threads.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, believe it or not. Come on
Speaker 7:  David.
Speaker 5:  I went to college in the south, let's just say that. That's all Same. That's
Speaker 5:  awesome. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Same. That's why I said that. I think all of us
Speaker 6:  Did.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, Instagram seems to be the kind of place people curate
Speaker 5:  a little more and pay a little more attention to and I think that for me
Speaker 5:  was like the, the startup there was really nice in that I just hit the like
Speaker 5:  follow everybody and it has mostly been okay so far.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, there's something about Meta's relationship with the news industry
Speaker 7:  here that I think it's important for us to talk about early on and I'm curious
Speaker 7:  what you guys think of that. I know they really do not
Speaker 7:  want to, I guess, embrace the news industry on
Speaker 7:  Threads even though they know that that's critical to actually killing Twitter.
Speaker 7:  That's Twitter's, at least up until Elon, that was Twitter's lifeblood was
Speaker 7:  the fact that news broke on Twitter. Meta has been
Speaker 7:  actively trying to distance itself from the news industry, right? For the
Speaker 7:  last several years they've been literally deprioritizing news in the
Speaker 7:  feed on Facebook and Instagram and they didn't do
Speaker 7:  any, you know, concerted outreach to big media brands to
Speaker 7:  journalists ahead of this besides me and a handful of others getting
Speaker 7:  access a few hours early just to just to see it, to write about
Speaker 7:  it. And I think for this thing to succeed, they have to
Speaker 7:  embrace the news industry if they want Threads to be the kind of,
Speaker 7:  as they say, public conversation platform news is such a critical part of
Speaker 7:  that and it's what people got a lot of value out of Twitter
Speaker 7:  for. I think they hope that Threads will just be this kind of
Speaker 7:  text version of Instagram with all the creators on Instagram, the athletes,
Speaker 7:  the celebrities, the influencers and all of that. But I,
Speaker 7:  I think for Threads to really be the Twitter killer, it has to nail news
Speaker 7:  and I'm not sure Meta has the institutional appetite to
Speaker 7:  embrace that right now. And I'm not sure what that means.
Speaker 6:  Well I think they're, they're scared of it, right? Because like when they
Speaker 6:  embraced news there was congressional hearings,
Speaker 7:  I mean they're literally being like sued and forced by the Canadian government
Speaker 7:  and others to pay news publishers for links. And they're saying we were literally
Speaker 7:  just turn off news in your country rather than pay you to,
Speaker 7:  to post links. Which we could. That's a whole nother, I actually think they're
Speaker 7:  right on that, but that's a whole nother discussion.
Speaker 6:  There's an interesting cuz there's an opportunity here for them because this
Speaker 6:  is a different product because it is treated differently by the
Speaker 6:  users so far and and and kind of perceived
Speaker 6:  differently by everyone. There's a real opportunity here
Speaker 6:  to make that pivot and to actually like be a good
Speaker 6:  partner with news organizations. But I think you're right there, there's
Speaker 6:  doesn't seem to be any appetite and I don't now how they get that.
Speaker 7:  There's two parts to that. Do news organizations want to be partners with
Speaker 7:  Meta? I can tell you no. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Right. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  No. Do journalists want a Twitter alternative? Absolutely. So it may be this
Speaker 7:  bottom up kind of bubbling thing that forces the big publishers to
Speaker 7:  embrace it.
Speaker 6:  Honestly, I think that's the way they get out of it too, right? Like, like
Speaker 6:  the problem that they're, they're terrified of is are we
Speaker 6:  putting, you know, Ms NBC at the top rather than Fox News and thus
Speaker 6:  we're like censoring people, right? Like that's the terror there. That's,
Speaker 6:  that's the fear is that they're gonna be accused of censorship from one side
Speaker 6:  or the other of this mass politicization of news and you
Speaker 6:  can get around that by like just not being a part of that
Speaker 6:  by also de-emphasizing algorithms and doing that stuff.
Speaker 6:  Which the algorithm side of this is kind of interesting, right? Like the,
Speaker 6:  that main feed no like do you know what's going on there?
Speaker 6:  Cuz no one on thread stepss are
Speaker 5:  Y'all's feeds like 97% people you don't know. Mine is
Speaker 5:  overwhelmingly no people. I don't know.
Speaker 6:  Mine starts people I know and then the further I go they're like, all right,
Speaker 6:  I'm just gonna start throwing you some other people.
Speaker 7:  I followed a lot of people right before it went to public launch, so I
Speaker 7:  may have a skewed like version of this, but I've been following people pretty
Speaker 7:  quickly. I don't actually, they actually hide how many people you're following,
Speaker 7:  which is an interesting choice. I follow a lot of people. It's actually been
Speaker 7:  pretty good also at surfacing people that I would want to follow that people
Speaker 7:  I follow have responded to and I can see the little plus icon and tap it
Speaker 7:  in the feed. I do definitely get you, you're already seeing the Instagram,
Speaker 7:  LinkedIn type thirst trap influencer. Yeah, that was me yesterday on there.
Speaker 7:  It's it's crazy. The hustle
Speaker 5:  Bros found it so
Speaker 7:  Fast. Yeah, so fast. As the network builds, I have a feeling that we'll get
Speaker 7:  sorted out and they're gonna keep, there's no one who understands tweaking
Speaker 7:  algorithms better than Meta to produce outcomes. So they're doing a very
Speaker 7:  light ranked version of base, basically the Instagram feed for this in terms
Speaker 7:  of what is prioritized, this is built off of Instagram's tech stack.
Speaker 7:  This is basically a a a different version of Instagram. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So no boobies,
Speaker 7:  No boobies, no nudity at all. Yeah. Which is actually a very key
Speaker 7:  difference to Twitter and I saw a very funny tweet today that just said Twitter
Speaker 7:  may just become Tumblr for in sells after all this.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, there's, there's no nudity. This is the Instagram code
Speaker 7:  of conduct community guidelines. There are, I saw some internal docs on this
Speaker 7:  where very severe violations, so sharing
Speaker 7:  csam, that sort of thing on Threads will result in penalties
Speaker 7:  on your Instagram account. But for the vast majority of things,
Speaker 7:  misinformation, bullying, that sort of thing,
Speaker 7:  the penalties and strikes you get on Threads will not ported over to your
Speaker 7:  Instagram account. So for now at least they are treating the apps even though
Speaker 7:  they're sharing account data as separate things to moderate,
Speaker 6:  How is that moderation gonna work? Because I feel like, like Instagram
Speaker 6:  is less of a trash fire than a lot of the other social media products out
Speaker 6:  there, right? And it's because of that extensive moderation, but
Speaker 6:  also how does that help foster the conversations that they seem to
Speaker 6:  wanna foster? I
Speaker 7:  Mean over a billion users, I don't know seems to be working. That's fair.
Speaker 7:  I mean everyone has their own view of this, right? You could have a wildly
Speaker 7:  different experience based on who you are, your race, your gender, your
Speaker 7:  identity, all those things, right? This is the thing with these social networks
Speaker 7:  is we have our own opinions that are based on our own view of them
Speaker 7:  and we're really unable to see the full picture. The only one who sees the
Speaker 7:  full picture is Mark Zuckerberg. They think they can make a nicer version
Speaker 7:  of Twitter. Zuckerberg's been very clear about that publicly in
Speaker 7:  Threads and sees the fact that Twitter has become
Speaker 7:  meaner and I would say a much less friendly place to be in the last several
Speaker 7:  months. And it's very just ironic to me that this is
Speaker 7:  Meta now coming in and saying we're gonna make the nice social network. Yes,
Speaker 7:  we contributed to people rioting January
Speaker 7:  6th, but that was a long time ago. Let's forget about
Speaker 7:  that. Let's move on.
Speaker 6:  Don't worry about it. Don't worry about
Speaker 5:  It. I just went back and found a big wired feature that happened when I was
Speaker 5:  there when Kevin Strom was in charge of Instagram about how they wanted to
Speaker 5:  make Instagram the nicer place and basically moderate more
Speaker 5:  aggressively and push harder towards being a place
Speaker 5:  where people are actually nice to each other. And I do think to some extent
Speaker 5:  that worked. I also think the way Instagram is structured has
Speaker 5:  hidden a lot of that, right? And that goes back to the like posts and comments
Speaker 5:  thing. It's like the awful stuff people do to each other in replies
Speaker 5:  to stories. Most people don't see like so much of what happens on Facebook,
Speaker 5:  people see because it's there and on Twitter it's even more public so it's
Speaker 5:  more obvious. Whereas Instagram is like, everything is kind of a couple of
Speaker 5:  layers down. So just your exposure to the bad
Speaker 5:  stuff that happens on Instagram as a bystander is just much less. Which
Speaker 5:  I think is the thing that is so interesting about Threads. And back to your
Speaker 5:  point about the, the news business coming in. This app is so
Speaker 5:  deliberately public, right? Like there's no DMs, there's no groups, there's
Speaker 5:  no community. Like, and and Moser keeps saying over and over like, we see
Speaker 5:  this as a place for public conversations. And I think what that's
Speaker 5:  gonna do is just show the whole platform to everybody and especially
Speaker 5:  as they do things like improve search and if hashtags become a thing, like
Speaker 5:  it's just gonna be easier to move around inside of Threads and as you
Speaker 5:  do, whatever they don't do moderation
Speaker 5:  wise is going to become really obvious really fast. And I wonder how that
Speaker 5:  changes the way people feel about the platform when you can just
Speaker 5:  see.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I will say that institutionally Meta is in a very much
Speaker 7:  different spot than it was in 20 16, 20 17,
Speaker 7:  20 18. They realized that they really over censored.
Speaker 7:  At least they think that now in retrospect, even honestly
Speaker 7:  through the Covid pandemic, I think they would do some of that differently.
Speaker 7:  I think a lot of the big internet platforms would in terms of what was initially
Speaker 7:  censored versus not. And I do think they want to be a little looser on
Speaker 7:  the censorship this time. And that is a general sentiment in Silicon
Speaker 7:  Valley at the big internet platforms that we are entering
Speaker 7:  a, a looser phase of the internet in that regard.
Speaker 5:  I also think if I'm Meta, I I have been sort of, I
Speaker 5:  don't know, bullied into not caring anymore about some of these things now.
Speaker 5:  Like Nick Clegg gets paid a lot of money to take everyone's heat about all
Speaker 5:  things content moderation. And the rest of the company just doesn't have
Speaker 5:  to care that much. Like Mark Zuckerberg is off doing other things. He's not,
Speaker 5:  he's not picking political fights anymore. He's like, oh, you want, Congress
Speaker 5:  wants to yell at us again. Like whatever, we're gonna keep doing our thing.
Speaker 5:  I just think if I'm Meta they're like so iner to this at this point
Speaker 5:  that I think that fear doesn't seem to exist within the company as
Speaker 5:  much as it used to.
Speaker 7:  Well for now until, until we have the Threads election. Well yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's fair. Yeah. 2026 or I guess 2028
Speaker 5:  election. It's gonna be, it's gonna be wild on Threads.
Speaker 6:  You don't think it's gonna be 2024
Speaker 7:  At this rate if they hit a hundred million users in a week, I mean
Speaker 7:  is RFK Jr on there yet? I dunno.
Speaker 5:  The Threads Chad G P T election is just gonna be outrageous. No one is ready
Speaker 5:  for this Alex. Sh can we, can we talk about what we call these things
Speaker 5:  yet? Alex Cranz. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I mean I have really strong opinions about it.
Speaker 5:  I know you do. I
Speaker 7:  Know you do Cranz
Speaker 6:  And I know you guys all think I'm wrong, but we should just call 'em tweets,
Speaker 5:  Make the case for this. I would like to come back to this, but I would you,
Speaker 5:  you wrote the thing about it, so you get to go first.
Speaker 6:  I wrote it and I was the, the best comment I got was somebody being like,
Speaker 6:  I thought this was just gonna be memes and you actually had an argument.
Speaker 6:  And I was like, yes, that's right. I thought about this for more than two
Speaker 6:  minutes. At least three minutes. We
Speaker 5:  Call that the crayon special. This seems like I'm just bullshitting you,
Speaker 5:  but I actually have some thoughts here.
Speaker 6:  But you know, tweets started as a thing that was
Speaker 6:  necessary because an app needed to put something on there besides Post.
Speaker 6:  Cuz I think post in that language was like weird. That's why it started.
Speaker 6:  And they were like, oh you should just call it a, he was like calling it
Speaker 6:  a tweet and everybody's like, that's stupid. Call it a tweet. And he's like,
Speaker 6:  oh that's a real word. I'll just use that cuz it's a real word that already
Speaker 6:  exists and everybody likes it and he knows what it means. And we, we've,
Speaker 6:  we associated it with Twitter because they eventually trademarked
Speaker 6:  it, so that's fair. But it originally started
Speaker 6:  to just like, I need a way to like pop off a pithy response
Speaker 6:  that's called a tweet. And I think like it's, it's surpassed
Speaker 6:  the company that that trademarked it, right? Like a Kleenex. You're not checking
Speaker 6:  what brand of Kleenex it is. It's just Kleenex. Same with E Ink.
Speaker 6:  It's almost certainly e inked, but like you're not checking what brand of
Speaker 6:  electronic paper it is. You're just gonna assume it's e ink.
Speaker 5:  Google's really the example here, right? Like it's, Google
Speaker 6:  Is the best example of this.
Speaker 5:  You Google stuff on Bing now, like that's a thing people do. Yeah, they go
Speaker 5:  to bing.com and they Google something. Google
Speaker 6:  Hates that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's, it's hilarious.
Speaker 6:  They hate it so much. I think it's a normal thing that the
Speaker 6:  English language does. I think it's okay to accept it and embrace
Speaker 6:  it. And I think that I'm really tired of every single time there's a
Speaker 6:  new platform, everybody being like, I got the jokes, what are we gonna call
Speaker 6:  this one? And then we have to have like this, this joke
Speaker 6:  conversation for three, three cycles it feels like. And
Speaker 6:  everybody's just like, ah, here's my jokes. And I'm like, no, just call 'em
Speaker 6:  tweets.
Speaker 5:  I'm, I worry sometimes that it's not a joke. Like Blue Sky users
Speaker 5:  seem to think they're called skeets and on Macedon they are technically
Speaker 5:  called tuts. Like this is the world we live in now. Like we, we
Speaker 5:  can't let this happen. We can't. They
Speaker 6:  Got rid of tuts once the guy, like the guy didn't know that it meant fart
Speaker 6:  in English. And so like a YouTuber was like, Hey I'll pay your
Speaker 6:  Patreon if you keep using Tut cuz it's so funny. And he's like,
Speaker 6:  okay. And so he did. And then later he was like, oh I was saying farts all
Speaker 6:  this time, that sucks. And he got rid of it like, it was like November, 2022.
Speaker 6:  Okay. He was like, we get rid of Toots and the Mastodon users were like,
Speaker 6:  not our toots. And it's like, I don't wanna be involved in that conversation.
Speaker 6:  You're fighting for the word tut.
Speaker 5:  If I ever pick it for anything, I'm gonna write not our toots on my
Speaker 5:  sign. That's just, that's what the sign is gonna say. Heath, they really
Speaker 5:  wanna call it Threads, right? Yes. That's the, that's the idea is that that's
Speaker 5:  the
Speaker 6:  Official,
Speaker 7:  That's the official thing. You're gonna Threads on Threads. That
Speaker 5:  Sucks, right? Like we don't, we don't like this or
Speaker 7:  Just call it a post. Like we don't, you know, let's not overthink this like
Speaker 7:  we're posting, we're posting on Maine, but
Speaker 6:  They're little posts
Speaker 5:  Posting on Maine. We're gonna open a diner called Posting on Maine.
Speaker 7:  They're 500 characters. They're bigger than tweets. What are you talking
Speaker 7:  about? Cranz 500
Speaker 6:  Characters is not a lot,
Speaker 7:  It's bigger than tweets.
Speaker 5:  It's bigger, it's
Speaker 6:  Bigger than tweets, but it's still, it's double smaller than a blog. What
Speaker 7:  Is a blog anymore? It's they're, these are all posts, they're just posts.
Speaker 7:  Don't call it tweet.
Speaker 6:  We have to be able to drill down. We have to be able to be like, like micro,
Speaker 6:  like no I don't wanna do micro blogs. No I don't wanna call 'em micro post.
Speaker 6:  That's stupid.
Speaker 7:  We're posting on Maine The Verge account Ruben, he's going wild right
Speaker 7:  now. He's posting on Maine.
Speaker 6:  He's calling him Zuck and I'm gonna fight Ruben.
Speaker 7:  I kind of like Zucks.
Speaker 6:  Nope. No
Speaker 5:  I'm out on
Speaker 6:  Zuck. I'm sorry I said
Speaker 5:  It. Zucks is what Facebook has to call, its digital currency. So that is
Speaker 5:  spoken for
Speaker 7:  Which, which is dead now. So maybe it's good for this, it
Speaker 7:  rhymes with, you know, great stuff. Fun fact, Cranz Twitter did
Speaker 7:  not actually come up with the word tweet. The first popularization of that
Speaker 7:  was terrific. A third party client.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it was the Twitter horrific guy was like, I need something to call
Speaker 6:  it. Yeah. And so he called it twit and it was a Twitter employee who was
Speaker 6:  also a Twitter horrific beta user who was like, Hey call 'em
Speaker 6:  tweets. And he used it and then like a year and a half later Twitter was
Speaker 6:  like, we also call them tweets.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Twitter famous for taking all of its early good ideas
Speaker 7:  from its third party developers then it then killed in the cradle.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Weird. And then never having any other good ideas. Yeah. Ever again
Speaker 5:  after that. Let's talk about the decentralization piece of this cuz this
Speaker 5:  is, yes, like for, for me as a, as a open social
Speaker 5:  web believer. Yeah. This is the thing I've been most looking forward to and
Speaker 5:  you've been reporting for months that this is a thing that that Instagram's
Speaker 5:  looking into for threats that it was gonna interoperate with Activity Pub
Speaker 5:  and the masks that on people have been up in arms and
Speaker 7:  Of course, yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. There's been a lot of feelings on the internet about what this thing
Speaker 5:  was gonna be before anybody knew what it was gonna be. But it
Speaker 5:  launched with no fediverse anything
Speaker 5:  yet. But Moser in, you're talking to him, seemed to be more
Speaker 5:  enthusiastic about Activity Pub than I even expected. Is that your read?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So I reported in Command Line last week my newsletter
Speaker 7:  that they were telling big people in the fediverse that they were
Speaker 7:  going to delay activity pub integration into Threads by several
Speaker 7:  months. I have a feeling it may be later now we could be talking
Speaker 7:  six plus months just given how much Threads has scaled beyond what they were
Speaker 7:  initially expecting. They onboarded the entirety of the fediverse to
Speaker 7:  Threads in like three hours. So give a sense of like the
Speaker 7:  scale here. Yeah. Yes. They had been meeting with large
Speaker 7:  server admins, the CO of Mastodon himself, big
Speaker 7:  third party developers on activity pub for the last couple of weeks
Speaker 7:  to talk about this. They wanna set up a round table of, you
Speaker 7:  know, fediverse leaders to kind of inform them as they try to integrate into
Speaker 7:  the network. I was kind of surprised, I guess though
Speaker 7:  not entirely to hear Moster say that he thinks this is the
Speaker 7:  direction that the internet is headed in these decentralized platforms, which
Speaker 7:  I know David, your eyes must have gotten really huge when you saw that. It's
Speaker 5:  Music to my ears man. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And for Meta of course this is a, a
Speaker 7:  creator thing where they think the pitch can be, if you're a creator
Speaker 7:  and you build an audience on Threads, if we decide to shut down Threads
Speaker 7:  like we did every other standalone app we've ever launched as a company that
Speaker 7:  we didn't acquire, you'll at least be able to take everything with you to
Speaker 7:  Mastodon or to another activity pub client. That's, that's at least the
Speaker 7:  pitch. Whether they follow through with that and that all works as planned
Speaker 7:  remains to be seen. And there's obviously, you know, you should have plenty
Speaker 7:  of skepticism with the largest centralized social media platform in the world
Speaker 7:  saying it's gonna embrace a decentralized protocol. Yeah. I do think
Speaker 7:  the fact that they're doing it with Threads with a new app and not Instagram
Speaker 7:  signals that they're serious about this and in most series retelling to me
Speaker 7:  they really can't retroactively and embrace Activity pub on
Speaker 7:  an existing app that's at that kind of scale. They needed to have something
Speaker 7:  fresh and it's pretty clear that he drove this. I was re-watching a Ted Talk
Speaker 7:  he gave last year about this and about how creators will inevitably
Speaker 7:  brace embrace these open protocols for a lot of these reasons. This is something
Speaker 7:  he's been saying even before Threads was a, was a twinkle in Meta's
Speaker 7:  eye. I do think they're gonna be met with extreme
Speaker 7:  fierce backlash in the fediverse. They know this, they're already getting
Speaker 7:  this. I've been hearing from people in the fediverse that
Speaker 7:  you're supposed to just say fediverse not the fediverse. I'm, I'm gonna get
Speaker 7:  a bunch of angry tweets about that. Oh,
Speaker 5:  People from fediverse? No, I'm out on that. Yeah, that's like, it's like
Speaker 5:  Brooklyn. It's like a neighborhood.
Speaker 7:  I I'm all for it. I think activity pub's a great idea. I will say the
Speaker 7:  early pro powerful community on
Speaker 7:  fediverse, y'all are a little too anal on your terms. Like
Speaker 7:  just like, let's just loosen up a little bit. But yeah, there's,
Speaker 7:  there's no trust of Meta here. I tend to side with John Gruber on, if
Speaker 7:  you're gonna really say that this is an open protocol, you need to treat
Speaker 7:  it as one and you need to let anyone come on and not just be already
Speaker 7:  talking about blocking them at least see, see what they're gonna do. But
Speaker 6:  I mean that's like the beauty of fediverse. I'm trying to embrace
Speaker 5:  That. I hate that already. No, there's
Speaker 6:  An article that should go there
Speaker 5:  That was awful. I didn't, it's like, it's like when Tim Cook says we, this
Speaker 5:  is iPhone. Like no it's not, it it's the it's an iPhone. It's
Speaker 5:  the, it is the fediverse. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But this is like, the point of the fediverse is that if you don't, like
Speaker 6:  if you go and you build a big audience on Threads and it finally goes live
Speaker 6:  and you don't like that you can't post Boobies, you can
Speaker 6:  go to a server where you can post boobies.
Speaker 7:  Except the boobies will not be on Threads. So where, right.
Speaker 7:  What server has the biggest audience, it's going to be Threads by a
Speaker 7:  factor of many acts. Yeah. So do you care about, you
Speaker 7:  know, censorship, do you care about distribution?
Speaker 6:  You're gonna have to make a choice. Threads are boobies.
Speaker 7:  It's very clear. And of course Meta knows this better than any other company
Speaker 7:  is that distribution trumps all. Yep. And I will
Speaker 7:  say the earliest bull case for Threads is
Speaker 7:  that the notifications are just popping off. Like I know Nilay and others
Speaker 7:  were talking about this when they first got on.
Speaker 6:  I thought my phone was ringing last
Speaker 7:  Night. It's insane. I had to mute it in instantly because it's got that Instagram
Speaker 7:  graph built in the day one distribution that you have on Threads
Speaker 7:  is just, it's so much more than Mastodon. It's honestly more
Speaker 7:  than Twitter these days. Like there are eyeballs there. Yep.
Speaker 7:  And as a creator on one of these platforms, when you're not getting paid
Speaker 7:  by the platform, guess what? You're gonna want to use the platform with the
Speaker 7:  biggest reach. And so Meta knows this and I think even when they hook
Speaker 7:  into Activity Pub, they know they're gonna be the server with the biggest
Speaker 7:  reach. Yeah. And so they're going to buy that very fact
Speaker 7:  be able to extend their policies, their way of doing things throughout
Speaker 7:  the, the fediverse. And that's I think what's really
Speaker 7:  getting a lot of the other server admins worried is that all of a
Speaker 7:  sudden this giant open protocol may be just governed by the Instagram
Speaker 7:  content guidelines. Are
Speaker 6:  They gonna actually monetize Threads? Like Yes.
Speaker 6:  Like Twitter was notoriously difficult to
Speaker 6:  monetize.
Speaker 7:  Yes. For many reasons. So I would say incompetence was up
Speaker 7:  there.
Speaker 6:  Is that really the play here or is it Yes. Just like we're,
Speaker 6:  this is our Goodwill project now. You all like us go use Instagram
Speaker 6:  and Facebook where we make our money.
Speaker 7:  We're no longer in a zero interest rate environment. Alex
Speaker 7:  grants? No, they're absolutely gonna put ads in this thing. I would
Speaker 7:  say sooner than they had even expected given the scale. This is Met us Playbook.
Speaker 7:  They wait for something to have the kind of velocity that it could hit, hit
Speaker 7:  a billion users and then they do ads.
Speaker 5:  I think Mon wants you to think that they're not interested in monetizing.
Speaker 5:  He has said a couple of times, Like, he keeps calling it a champagne problem.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it's like, well no, this is either gonna work and you're gonna
Speaker 5:  make money off of it or you're gonna shut it down. Like there's no, there's
Speaker 5:  no middle option where this thing continues to live without being
Speaker 7:  Monetized. Yeah. They wanna make sure the product's sticky has good retention.
Speaker 7:  They, they worry about retention. They kind of set the Indus industry benchmark
Speaker 7:  for retention and social networks. They, they have the
Speaker 7:  playbook that they invented that the rest of the industry follows for this.
Speaker 7:  So they will use that playbook. They will add ads when it's at this nice
Speaker 7:  kind of like self circulating, self building
Speaker 7:  place. And yeah, it's gonna look like Instagram in terms of that.
Speaker 7:  I
Speaker 6:  Guess I just wonder how valuable that is because Twitter, in addition to
Speaker 6:  being terrible at monetizing also was much
Speaker 6:  smaller than a lot of these other ones. Right? Like, like it was way smaller
Speaker 6:  than Facebook. It was way smaller than Instagram. And Threads, even if it
Speaker 6:  gets to Twitter size is gonna still be way smaller
Speaker 6:  than the cash cows.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But you have to approach this as a marketer. If it's another toggle,
Speaker 7:  I
Speaker 6:  Can never do that. So walk me through it, please.
Speaker 7:  Okay. I talk, I I regrettably have to talk to these people for my job. Sorry.
Speaker 7:  No, I'm just kidding. I, I love marketers. Keep, keep talking to me about
Speaker 7:  the platforms. Please. If it's another toggle in your dashboard when you're
Speaker 7:  running an ad on Instagram to run it in Threads and you can reach, you know,
Speaker 7:  a hundred to 300 million people on there, you're gonna do it. It's,
Speaker 7:  yeah, it's zero cost to you. It's all upside. This is where the benefits
Speaker 7:  of scale and graphs kind of
Speaker 7:  coalescing at the plus billion. Mark is going to just keep
Speaker 7:  giving Meta kind of tremendous incumbent advantages at, with new
Speaker 7:  products like this. And they know that this
Speaker 6:  Is why we're not seeing it in Europe yet,
Speaker 6:  right. Is like, cuz when when you first hear about it and you hear
Speaker 6:  about Threads, you're like, well this should go in Europe. Cause I know they're
Speaker 6:  afraid of the dma. But
Speaker 5:  That's the first thing you think of when you think of Threads is this should
Speaker 5:  go to Europe. Always
Speaker 6:  Think of it. Threads
Speaker 5:  Seems very,
Speaker 6:  No, we've been talking a lot, like there's been a lot of noise today about
Speaker 6:  how it's not in Europe yet. And that's, that's, that seems to be
Speaker 6:  because of the dma, right? Like that's the fear is that, that they
Speaker 6:  can't do it because of the dma. And what the
Speaker 6:  DMA says is that like you, you have to be kind of open and honest. You have
Speaker 6:  to like be good stewards and you need to let people
Speaker 6:  take their, their followers where they wanna go and all of this. And that's
Speaker 6:  like, okay, well that sounds like everything that Threads does. And then
Speaker 6:  I guess the other side of that is that also it's part of Meta and Meta is
Speaker 6:  huge and will inevitably swallow everything whole. Because when you're that
Speaker 6:  big, that's just how you process everything.
Speaker 5:  I just have one more thing to say on the monetization before we go, which
Speaker 5:  is this is another place that it is very useful to be part of Instagram,
Speaker 5:  which has a number of very good monetization tools for
Speaker 5:  creators that would lend themselves very well to a product like Threads.
Speaker 5:  Things like gifts and subscriptions and the tips stuff they can
Speaker 5:  do and shopping. Like all that stuff is built and at scale
Speaker 5:  and making huge amounts of money for lots of people. And you can just stick
Speaker 5:  it into Threads without all that much work. I think the interface designers
Speaker 5:  would have some work to do. I think the interface designers already have
Speaker 5:  some work to do, which we can talk about about if you guys would like to.
Speaker 5:  But let's, let's get into, I both wanna talk about the the Europe stuff and
Speaker 5:  then I wanna get to some of the questions that you got about Threads on Threads.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But first let's take a break. We'll be right
Speaker 5:  back.
Speaker 5:  We're back. Let's talk about this Year Up thing. I don't wanna dwell on this
Speaker 5:  for too long because it's boring policy, but it is worth
Speaker 5:  explaining. And Heath, you, you talked to Moster specifically about
Speaker 5:  this. What, what is your sense of why this thing didn't launch in
Speaker 5:  Europe?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, so Threads is not available in the EU, I'm sorry to everyone and
Speaker 7:  the French countryside on vacation right now.
Speaker 5:  And according to Cranz it's a very European app. So it's a real shake. Yes,
Speaker 5:  it's very European,
Speaker 7:  Everybody wants it. You have to cry into your cheese and your wine. But
Speaker 7:  that does leave out a market of, you know, hundreds of millions of people.
Speaker 7:  It's a huge missed market opportunity for Threads initially.
Speaker 7:  And they know this, this is a really interesting example of what the EU
Speaker 7:  is doing regulation wise with big tech. They have the Digital Markets Act,
Speaker 7:  which is going into effect next year and it labels
Speaker 7:  Meta and other big companies like Apple and Google as gatekeepers. And
Speaker 7:  with that distinction comes a whole new host of compliance
Speaker 7:  requirements that if are not met, result
Speaker 7:  in insane fines. Like not just like your one-off fines that these
Speaker 7:  companies happily pay, but debilitating fines, which is
Speaker 6:  The way fines should actually function. Sure,
Speaker 6:  sure. They should discourage whatever the things you're not supposed to do
Speaker 6:  from doing.
Speaker 7:  Yes, no, I agree. Fines should be proportional to the company size of Yeah,
Speaker 7:  they, they've been parking tickets so far. This is not, you know, Meta's
Speaker 7:  not alone here. I've heard people at Apple Google are also freaking out
Speaker 7:  about how to comply with the dma. There's a lot of unknowns. There's a bunch
Speaker 7:  of interoperability standards, there's self referencing standards
Speaker 7:  that have to be met. I think with Threads in particular, they're
Speaker 7:  worried about being compliant with the data sharing and the data leakage
Speaker 7:  between Threads and the rest of Meta since Threads is this quasi
Speaker 7:  separate thing, but it still is connected to Instagram. It has its own terms
Speaker 7:  of service, but it also has, you know, Meta
Speaker 7:  influence Meta content guidelines. They're definitely gonna be sharing that
Speaker 7:  data and basically whatever Meta tests to how
Speaker 7:  they operate this, they're very much liable to that at a station
Speaker 7:  being accurate under the new dmma. And if not, they're gonna
Speaker 7:  get
Speaker 5:  Fined. And not only that, they have to be able to prove it like, like
Speaker 5:  aggressively and constantly. Yeah, and that was one of the things most serious
Speaker 5:  said that I thought was really interesting is that like the tooling just
Speaker 5:  to be able to document this stuff is a huge amount of work.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's a huge amount of work. This is one of the companies with perhaps
Speaker 7:  the strongest global, if not one of the strongest global lobbying
Speaker 7:  policy presences in the world. They've had more headroom on this than
Speaker 7:  anyone and they, I think it's very interesting that they don't feel confident
Speaker 7:  to launch what they think could be the fastest growing software product since
Speaker 7:  Chad G P T in Europe. Even though the DMA does not go into
Speaker 7:  effect until maybe spring of next year because they're that worried
Speaker 7:  about potentially being liable. I think this means that other big
Speaker 7:  product launches like this will also not go into the
Speaker 7:  EU region initially as well. I don't think this will be the only one they
Speaker 7:  do really want to get into the EU. I just think it's gonna take several months
Speaker 7:  at minimum before they can make sure that they can hold up to their, you
Speaker 7:  know, attestations of how they're using the data. So
Speaker 6:  Kinda like video games going to Australia where they always have to wait
Speaker 6:  forever because there's all the Australian regulation and they're like, okay,
Speaker 6:  now I get to kill everybody.
Speaker 7:  Or China as in, you know, China's an even more stringent example. Well
Speaker 5:  And again, in this particular case Instagram was in such a rush
Speaker 5:  to get this out. Yeah. That it was, it, it so clearly sensed a
Speaker 5:  moment to do this. Yeah. That it made what seems like sort of a
Speaker 5:  calculated decision to say this is a problem we could not solve
Speaker 5:  by July 5th. So our option was either don't launch on July 5th
Speaker 5:  or don't launch in the EU. And I think they just picked that.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, Moster was very clear to me and others that they felt they
Speaker 7:  had a very narrow window to launch this thing to really capitalize on the
Speaker 7:  Twitter turmoil and they didn't wanna miss that window and their instinct
Speaker 7:  was probably right there as hard as it is to not have a massive
Speaker 7:  market that can use the app. What do you guys think about that?
Speaker 7:  Do you I mean? I think there's a lot of people, we've had people in our Slack
Speaker 7:  that are a little more sympathetic to the EU
Speaker 7:  here versus, you know, Meta. Obviously Meta doesn't have a great
Speaker 7:  track record with privacy. People think that, you know, what the EU
Speaker 7:  is doing is generally good. I don't really know, I haven't formed a full
Speaker 7:  opinion on that. I think GDPR has been widely considered
Speaker 7:  a disaster and did not actually make the internet more private. And if
Speaker 7:  anything just kind of solidified incumbents who could pay for
Speaker 7:  the internal tooling and all of that to, but you
Speaker 6:  Get to click a little button.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, sure.
Speaker 6:  Every time you go to a new website you click that
Speaker 7:  Button. Do you feel like your data is more protected because of that button?
Speaker 6:  No, I feel like I'm annoyed I have to click the button.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. This, you know, the last big sweeping regulation was was that pop-up
Speaker 7:  that the EU gave us. And I haven't seen
Speaker 7:  any independent analysis that what the DMA is
Speaker 7:  proposing will result in anything substantially better. I hope it will.
Speaker 7:  I I think these gatekeepers need to have more incentives to allow for
Speaker 7:  competition. It's just very tough to craft this kind of
Speaker 7:  regulation. Very tough.
Speaker 6:  They're trying to cover a lot of different companies with one
Speaker 6:  law. Yeah. And like every one of these companies is very different. They
Speaker 6:  all have different goals. They all have different like size of customer bases,
Speaker 6:  they, the different stuff that they do really, really poorly
Speaker 6:  that, that destroys our privacy. Like there, there's not a lot of consist
Speaker 6:  there's consistency there and I think it
Speaker 6:  makes sense that Meta said, no, we're not gonna go in there and we're not
Speaker 6:  gonna, we're not gonna challenge this right now. We are gonna acknowledge
Speaker 6:  it. I think like that feels like it's working exactly how it's
Speaker 6:  intended and hopefully European users
Speaker 6:  don't get mad and be like, well we just should get rid of this law so I
Speaker 6:  can have give Meta my data. And I'm sure Meta would love it
Speaker 6:  if, if all the users rose up and were like, give us, give us threats. But
Speaker 6:  I'm like, I think this is working exactly how it's intended and I wish other
Speaker 6:  countries would be thinking more about legislating this stuff, not necessarily
Speaker 6:  in the DMA way. Cause I don't know enough about it to like have a really
Speaker 6:  strong opinion on it beyond, it sounds nice at like first
Speaker 6:  glance and like, I would love more legislation that sounds nice
Speaker 6:  and actually works and actually provides fines that me are meaningful
Speaker 6:  and, and do things like, like I think that's working great. The fact that
Speaker 6:  Meta looked at and was like, I don't wanna risk the fines. I wanna figure
Speaker 6:  out and make sure that we're complying with this law. Like that's wonderful,
Speaker 6:  that's working exactly how it's intended and that's great.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I tend to agree. I think if I'm the European Commission and the folks
Speaker 5:  who wrote the dma, they're, they're probably thrilled that this is how it
Speaker 5:  went down because a big part of the goal is to make these
Speaker 5:  companies sit down and think about the consequences of their
Speaker 5:  actions. And I think that the challenge for a lot of these regulators is
Speaker 5:  that they've always been somewhere between like one and 65 steps
Speaker 5:  behind the tech industry. They're regulating and litigating old
Speaker 5:  problems while all these other companies are out talking about like crypto
Speaker 5:  and ai and then they skip right past privacy and try to regulate AI and
Speaker 5:  they will have moved on to something else. And the DMA basically swung such
Speaker 5:  a big hammer that it was like, okay, we're gonna stop everybody for a minute.
Speaker 5:  And I think this seems like, from what I've heard from folks, the
Speaker 5:  kind of policy that is gonna play out really slowly over time
Speaker 5:  and is only gonna be sort of answered as it gets litigated and questions
Speaker 5:  about like, who is a gatekeeper and what does that mean and how do we decide
Speaker 5:  who has that power and who doesn't like that stuff is gonna take a while
Speaker 5:  to really shake out. But I think just the fact that it
Speaker 5:  made Meta take its time on this, I think they're gonna see as a big victory.
Speaker 5:  And again, this is kind of an unusual situation in
Speaker 5:  that they didn't have time to iron out some of the
Speaker 5:  policy issues for a global launch. The question for me will
Speaker 5:  be whether that becomes the thing like you're talking about,
Speaker 5:  if, if the move becomes these companies take longer to launch their global
Speaker 5:  products as a result of trying to get the regulation right
Speaker 5:  versus everybody launches everything and then launches it a year later in
Speaker 5:  the EU when they can figure out how to do the paperwork correctly. I have
Speaker 5:  no idea which one of those is gonna play out, but one of those is going to
Speaker 5:  be politically significantly less popular among European people than
Speaker 5:  the other
Speaker 7:  People really want their tech and their services and especially
Speaker 7:  things like networks that have a global kind of u utility
Speaker 7:  to them. And I'm very curious to see if the EU gets blow back
Speaker 7:  in that regard.
Speaker 5:  I just keep thinking about all the Instagram users. Like there, there's a
Speaker 5:  thing on your Instagram badge now that shows what
Speaker 5:  number user you were on Threads and I, I
Speaker 5:  bet you there is a not insubstantial number of people in the EU who are pissed
Speaker 5:  at how, not how high their number is going to be. Maybe they'll
Speaker 6:  Give them like a special one. Like they have their, their official thread
Speaker 6:  number and then their EU thread number.
Speaker 5:  Oh that's, that's fun. I like that.
Speaker 6:  That's so that way they can still have a little bragging rights, but not
Speaker 6:  as much as Keith.
Speaker 7:  I wanna get into Threads reader questions, but I also quickly, I quickly,
Speaker 7:  I want to address, I've just seen a lot of commentary on this and have been
Speaker 7:  asked this directly, why didn't ask most sir about this? People have been
Speaker 7:  pointing to the app store privacy labels for Threads and all of the
Speaker 7:  data they collect and we could talk, we should actually
Speaker 7:  do like a what has been the impact of Apple's privacy labels in the
Speaker 7:  app store segment at some point? There's a lot to unpack here. Newsflash,
Speaker 7:  they have not really worked and they don't
Speaker 7:  actually mean anything.
Speaker 5:  I was just gonna say, I actually think there's nothing to unpack here. I
Speaker 5:  think the answer is it's basically security theater.
Speaker 7:  I think the simplest thing we can say now is that if you already use
Speaker 7:  Instagram, if you, you are an Instagram user, you have absolutely no reason
Speaker 7:  to be complaining or saying you're not signing up for Threads because of
Speaker 7:  these privacy labels. You're already using Instagram, which is
Speaker 7:  governed under the exact same data policy as Threads. So that's,
Speaker 7:  that's my short answer. We should absolutely talk more about privacy labels
Speaker 7:  and maybe talk to some developers who have gone through it later. But I just
Speaker 7:  wanted to get that outta the way.
Speaker 5:  No, I that that's exactly right. And I think the argument of is this company
Speaker 5:  collecting way too much data on you? Is the the answer is yes. Right? Like
Speaker 5:  Neil, I posted in Slack, he got a thing from Threads asking to connect to
Speaker 5:  other devices on his local network, which is like insane, right?
Speaker 5:  Like this app wants everything you will give it including like your health
Speaker 5:  and fitness information, but if you've ever used a Meta app,
Speaker 5:  you're already giving it that information. Yeah. Like this is not a new problem
Speaker 7:  If you're mad at still about meta's data collection. Like save like
Speaker 7:  10% of that anger for the data brokers who literally actually sell
Speaker 7:  your data Yeah. To companies without your knowledge that are completely
Speaker 7:  unregulated still in the US because they so effectively lobby the government
Speaker 7:  like they're
Speaker 6:  Terrifying.
Speaker 7:  D direct a little bit of a anger towards that versus Meta. And we may
Speaker 7:  actually actually, you know, solve a lot of these problems.
Speaker 6:  Weren't those the brokers that, like the NSA and CIA
Speaker 6:  were revealed a couple of weeks ago that they were buying data from? They're
Speaker 6:  like, oh yeah, we buy it from them already. Don't worry
Speaker 5:  About it. Like we're, we're veering dangerously close to me giving a long
Speaker 5:  rant about how Cambridge Analytica was a fake made up scandal that actually
Speaker 5:  had nothing to do with anything. So
Speaker 7:  I'm here for it. Let's just, let's
Speaker 5:  Save that for another day. Heath, you asked on Threads
Speaker 5:  for people to ask you Threads questions for us to answer on The Vergecast.
Speaker 5:  Let's do a bunch of 'em. Let's, what, what do
Speaker 7:  You got? Yeah, so this is a great one. I'm really curious what you guys think
Speaker 7:  about this. Do you think the discourse can be different
Speaker 7:  here on Threads than on Twitter? Or will the format eventually produce the
Speaker 7:  same results, aka hate
Speaker 7:  speech, bullying, dunking, all that stuff?
Speaker 6:  I think the format will definitely produce a lot of similar results, but
Speaker 6:  the fact that we're getting the Instagram aggressive moderation
Speaker 6:  might mitigate some of that.
Speaker 5:  I think that's right. I mean, I think the, the thing that we've seen is that
Speaker 5:  these platforms develop different norms really fast,
Speaker 5:  right? Like Mastodon is different from Twitter, which is different from Blue
Speaker 5:  Sky, which is different from, I don't know, telegram. Like these things
Speaker 5:  where people send texts to one another do develop different
Speaker 5:  cultures. I think Threads absolutely risks basically
Speaker 5:  turning into Twitter and in a lot of ways and for a lot of people will, I
Speaker 5:  also think a lot of people's Twitter experiences were
Speaker 5:  sort of self-inflicted. I think who you decided to
Speaker 5:  follow and engage with and what you decided to share. Like if you just went
Speaker 5:  on and talked about nba, you had a very different version of Twitter
Speaker 5:  than people who yelled about politics all day, right? And I think to some
Speaker 5:  extent just having a sort of forced experience of starting
Speaker 5:  over goes a really long way. And I think just that
Speaker 5:  alone is going to change versions of the discourse. But like, are there going
Speaker 5:  to be similarly horrible political fights and are there gonna be
Speaker 5:  main characters on Threads who just get ruthlessly harassed until something
Speaker 5:  horrible happens? Like yeah, it's, it's gonna happen.
Speaker 6:  Are you guys changing how you use Threads versus Twitter? Like,
Speaker 6:  like consciously? Because for me I definitely have like a different approach.
Speaker 6:  I'm like, okay, I learned Twitter was where I could like kind of stumble
Speaker 6:  along.
Speaker 5:  Say more. What are you doing differently with Thread?
Speaker 6:  I'm being more thoughtful about it. Okay. Like, like I'm being more thoughtful
Speaker 6:  about what I post and like I have the urge to post all sorts of horrible
Speaker 6:  shit posting and I usually do on Twitter and I'm like, maybe, maybe I don't
Speaker 6:  on Threads. Maybe a bunch of people don't wanna hear these thoughts about
Speaker 6:  toe hairs and I think they all should. But,
Speaker 5:  But people on Twitter super did.
Speaker 6:  They didn't. They didn't.
Speaker 7:  That sounds like a Tumblr thing. France,
Speaker 6:  That was really a Tumblr thing. I miss, I mistook the audience, but I, but
Speaker 6:  I think that the audience feels clearer and at least in
Speaker 6:  these early days, a thread of like what you can do and kind of
Speaker 6:  how mean you can get, how weird you can get. And you always wanna like
Speaker 6:  scale it back just a little bit. Don't get too mean, don't get too weird.
Speaker 7:  And David, I think your point about, you know, the opportunity to start over
Speaker 7:  is a big one, is totally spot on. And I think the early culture of these
Speaker 7:  networks create matters as we've seen with Blue Sky already,
Speaker 7:  for example, and Macedon in a different way. I do wanna just
Speaker 7:  check our like white man privilege of like using these platforms.
Speaker 7:  I do think because of the public nature of Twitter and Threads,
Speaker 7:  if you are a minority or someone who is easily targetable,
Speaker 7:  unfortunately on the internet you have a wildly different experience with
Speaker 7:  these public platforms and you don't, it doesn't matter who you follow. Like
Speaker 7:  it comes to you. Like I've seen enough examples,
Speaker 6:  The mansplaining still appears in my d Yeah. In like
Speaker 6:  my, my Threads and
Speaker 5:  That's coming to Threads. It really is.
Speaker 6:  It's already there. It's already there. It started last night like as almost
Speaker 6:  immediately somebody was like, lemme tell you what you're saying. And I'm
Speaker 6:  like, no, I, I said it.
Speaker 7:  And, and crayons be honest, like the mansplaining is probably the best of
Speaker 7:  the worst. you know? Like there's actually, there's far worse. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It was like this was, this was like fairly mild mansplaining. I've definitely
Speaker 6:  had it way worse and I'm, I'm sure it's just gonna come. And I think that's
Speaker 6:  just like, I think most people who, who go online and
Speaker 6:  simply exist and people get mad at them, which is a
Speaker 6:  lot of us unfortunately we're kind of accustomed to it by now. It sucks and
Speaker 6:  it shouldn't happen and there should be tools and stuff, but I think that's
Speaker 6:  a hard problem to figure out how you do those tools, how you balance them
Speaker 6:  and don't turn into whatever happened to Facebook in 2016. You just
Speaker 6:  kind of have to, to I mean, this is me saying it as an old
Speaker 6:  haggard witch of a woman who's been on the internet a very long time.
Speaker 6:  You kind of get used to it. You kinda learn to like what stuff to ignore
Speaker 6:  and what stuff to report
Speaker 7:  You shouldn't get used to it. Like these platforms should do better. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  You shouldn't, but like,
Speaker 7:  But yes, I know what you mean. That's
Speaker 6:  A hard, like something like mansplaining, like how are you gonna report somebody
Speaker 6:  for being like they think they know more than me, moderator fix it. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  totally. That's not gonna work. It's just gonna be like, well yeah, I'm just
Speaker 6:  not gonna engage with you. And at Twitter I probably would've engaged a few
Speaker 6:  times, right? Like I probably would've been like, let me explain things to
Speaker 6:  you. Let me be optimistic or eat shit asshole. And, and here I'm like,
Speaker 6:  I've done this before I see you and I'm just not gonna feed the troll.
Speaker 7:  I, I will say it was comforting to see that Threads had basic moderation.
Speaker 7:  Things like blocking and muting built in on day one. Oh
Speaker 6:  I, I've already blocked somebody. It was great. I was like ah beautiful.
Speaker 6:  I won't, you can DM me and I'll tell you who I blocked but I'm not gonna
Speaker 7:  Say it here. Yeah, so optimistic but cautious and we should definitely check
Speaker 7:  back in on this. I thought it was a good question. Next one. Should we expect
Speaker 7:  a high velocity of new feature additions and would that even be possible
Speaker 7:  under the regulatory scrutiny that Facebook is correctly subject
Speaker 7:  to? We kind of already touched on the regulatory scrutiny. I do think
Speaker 7:  there's gonna be a high velocity of feature tweaks and changes to this product.
Speaker 7:  Especially now that it has garnered so much attention
Speaker 7:  that exceeded Meadow's wildest dreams. And what happens in these big
Speaker 7:  companies is that these projects start as like small resource constrain
Speaker 7:  things. Threads has like a few dozen people working on it and
Speaker 7:  when they see that that it's working a bunch more people wanna work on it,
Speaker 7:  a bunch of resources get thrown on it. Zuckerberg himself is very excited
Speaker 7:  about it now. So I expect that the team building it will swell
Speaker 7:  and they'll ship a lot faster. I already know for example, like the internal
Speaker 7:  employee build lets you do things like tap on a profile and it expands to
Speaker 7:  see it in full. Like they're already making a bunch of like small tweaks
Speaker 7:  on the edges that will ship soon. And then yeah, Moser's already
Speaker 7:  confirmed a following only list is in the works. He has
Speaker 7:  told me and others that they don't plan to do DMs. I have a feeling they'll
Speaker 7:  go back on that after they See how much of a loop, a powerful
Speaker 7:  loop that is. At the very least they need to make it easier to share
Speaker 7:  Threads to like Instagram DMs for example, or just
Speaker 7:  other DM apps that's could be a lot smoother and they know that,
Speaker 6:  Let me shit talk in piece.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, any features you guys wanna see like quickly better
Speaker 5:  Search is I think the biggest one and something that the company is
Speaker 5:  relatively good at. So I suspect that's coming. But what I think is gonna
Speaker 5:  be really interesting is to See how much they want
Speaker 5:  to do here. Because I think one of the things that is true
Speaker 5:  is that it is simple and that's part of what is good about it.
Speaker 5:  Also he Moser said this to you Heath that Instagram
Speaker 5:  the app is bloated and messy and too much and they're
Speaker 5:  actually in the, and this is like this whole company goes through this constantly,
Speaker 5:  right? They add a million things to the app and then they go, oh my god this
Speaker 5:  app is a mess. And then they get rid of some stuff and simplify and then
Speaker 5:  they add a bunch more stuff And this is just like, this is the Meta pendulum
Speaker 5:  swing at all times. Yeah and they're in a sort of
Speaker 5:  simplification phase right now. And I think also part of what has appealed
Speaker 5:  to people about Threads already is that it's very straightforward and it
Speaker 5:  works. And so I think the idea that they're gonna be like now you can make
Speaker 5:  a podcast inside of Threads is like they'd be
Speaker 5:  stupid to think that that is the answer, right? And so I
Speaker 5:  think what we're gonna see is them try to figure out
Speaker 5:  what is smart to take from Twitter and what
Speaker 5:  is like actually not what makes the platform
Speaker 5:  work. And I suspect we'll get a lot of stuff really fast. I think you're
Speaker 5:  right because this team is actually just in a position to ship really fast,
Speaker 5:  like building stuff just inside the org structure of something like Instagram
Speaker 5:  and Facebook is hard and takes a long time and a lot of people and this is
Speaker 5:  a team that just can make things and now has like a big win under attack
Speaker 5:  and is gonna be able to make things faster. They
Speaker 7:  Have Jane Wong.
Speaker 5:  Yeah they got Jane Wong.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, legendary app Scoop Jane Wong, which means she
Speaker 7:  probably won't be posting her app dumps anymore, which is a
Speaker 7:  huge bummer.
Speaker 5:  Or they just hired her to be Threads exclusive, which would be a super
Speaker 5:  cool,
Speaker 7:  She's literally working on Threads. She's a Meta employee now. It's pretty
Speaker 7:  wild. Okay, this is a good one too. How will journalists and other people
Speaker 7:  who provide real time important info be able to be verified so users
Speaker 7:  know the info being posted is legitimate. We've obviously seen how
Speaker 7:  this has played out on Twitter since Elon changed the check marks.
Speaker 7:  I am verified on Instagram because a media brand I worked at in
Speaker 7:  2015 had a social media manager who knew someone at Facebook got everyone
Speaker 7:  verified in the newsroom. That's
Speaker 5:  How I got verified on Twitter.
Speaker 7:  Anyone who's worked in a newsroom long enough knows that that's how it
Speaker 7:  worked up until like a couple years ago. Meta
Speaker 7:  has a paid verified program now, so I think they're phasing
Speaker 7:  out the, you have to know somebody to get a check mark.
Speaker 7:  They're gonna let people who got that check mark keep it. So thanks
Speaker 7:  Meta. But yes, I think going forward metal will
Speaker 7:  tell me if I'm wrong, but you need to pay to be verified on
Speaker 7:  Instagram. They actually, I believe Id check you. So I think there's a level
Speaker 7:  of
Speaker 6:  Actual verification. Yeah. So I cannot make a neli
Speaker 6:  burner account. Well
Speaker 7:  You can try I mean I I
Speaker 6:  I will try, but we
Speaker 7:  Should try.
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna wait until he is back on the show to do it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, but there is a level of actual scrutiny of someone's identity
Speaker 7:  when you become verified on Instagram that far exceeds what Twitter is doing
Speaker 7:  currently. So if you see a check mark on Threads, it's the real
Speaker 7:  deal. Don't hold me to that though. I don't wanna be
Speaker 7:  sued. But yeah. How do we feel about this? The, the check
Speaker 7:  mark thing with Threads?
Speaker 6:  I didn't know you could pay that seems Yeah, it it's basically
Speaker 6:  like Twitter in that they're trying to get away from the, the check
Speaker 6:  mark means
Speaker 7:  You're special. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Special. Yeah. Which is honestly the only reason I ever liked the check mark.
Speaker 6:  I love like very visual ways to validate myself. Thank
Speaker 6:  you.
Speaker 5:  But Meta is at least trying to make sure that not everyone
Speaker 5:  demands a blue check,
Speaker 6:  But yeah, Meta's actually checking, whereas like yeah
Speaker 6:  Twitter's thing was like, oh you have a credit card you're in. And so that's
Speaker 6:  good. Like I think that's actually how it should work. Not
Speaker 6:  necessarily that you should have to pay, but that like they are
Speaker 6:  actually checking and making sure that the person is the person. Like that's
Speaker 6:  great. Go for it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think that's right and I think part of me wonders if the whole
Speaker 5:  idea of the blue check is just being sort
Speaker 5:  of beaten out of usefulness, Twitter kind of bastardized
Speaker 5:  what it means. Tumblr would just like sell you one as a joke, which I thought
Speaker 5:  was very funny and still love very much by
Speaker 6:  20 if you want. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And so I, I kind of wonder if we're at a point where we're gonna need some
Speaker 5:  other connotation of this person is who they say they are. And to some extent
Speaker 5:  being connected to Instagram is useful in that way because
Speaker 5:  there are just more tools to verify people on
Speaker 5:  Instagram than there are on Threads or Twitter at this moment. And so I think
Speaker 5:  having those connections might be useful, but I don't know, I, I continue
Speaker 5:  to wonder if any kind of check is is gonna mean much to people for
Speaker 5:  very long.
Speaker 6:  At some point I feel like it's just gonna be a little like thing
Speaker 6:  you kind of look over and you're like, oh that person's really who they say
Speaker 6:  they are. Oh that's a parody account. Oh that's
Speaker 6:  just somebody who's too lazy or you know, a brand or
Speaker 6:  something like I hope so I think at some point we'll get that and that'd
Speaker 6:  be great but different way of working on the internet.
Speaker 5:  This is also, I would point out a potential upside of the fediverse is this
Speaker 5:  becomes a thing that not every platform has to do for itself. That we can
Speaker 5:  have bigger, broader cross system tools for
Speaker 5:  verifying people that actually make a lot more sense. Oh
Speaker 6:  My god, that's gonna be the first big fight between Meta and the fediverse.
Speaker 5:  I think one of my great conspiracy theories about Threads
Speaker 5:  and Activity Pub in general is that Meta actually has no interest in doing
Speaker 5:  things like that and only does it out of basically obligation because it
Speaker 5:  runs the platform. Meta doesn't care all that much about your content.
Speaker 5:  Your content is just annoying for Meta generally speaking, it wants your
Speaker 5:  activity, it wants you to be paying attention, it wants you to be on its
Speaker 5:  platform but it didn't really give a shit what your posts are. Oh it just
Speaker 5:  wants you to like hang out. So giving you a feeling that your posts are
Speaker 5:  yours and someone else can deal with all the hard work of doing
Speaker 5:  something like verifying that you are who you say you are but you can just
Speaker 5:  use Threads because it's a better app. They can just focus on making a good
Speaker 5:  app and all the stuff you do around it doesn't have to be their problem anymore.
Speaker 5:  I actually think that's an enormous win for Meta down the road.
Speaker 7:  I think you're right. Okay, one last question and then maybe we can call
Speaker 7:  Nilay, T B D. Will there be third party
Speaker 7:  API platform integration for other
Speaker 7:  developers on Threads? I highly highly
Speaker 7:  doubt it because Meta as a company, their last time they
Speaker 7:  tried to do a developer platform it resulted in Cambridge Analytica.
Speaker 7:  So they have decided as a company,
Speaker 5:  Jesus, when you say it like that,
Speaker 7:  No more
Speaker 6:  They could do it again. They didn't do a very good job that
Speaker 7:  Time. Well see Mark Zuckerberg still running the company, I think he remembers
Speaker 7:  those senate hearings and the lawsuits and the fines, the record fines.
Speaker 7:  But he took the
Speaker 6:  Wrong, he took the wrong thing from that instead of being like, oh really
Speaker 6:  I shouldn't collect as much data. He was like hmm, I guess that means no
Speaker 6:  third party apps. Like
Speaker 7:  Oh is this really David teases us? Are we really gonna have to explain Cambridge
Speaker 5:  Analytic? I'm not doing though.
Speaker 7:  No, Cambridge Analytica was not about your data, it was
Speaker 7:  because Facebook let third party developers use your data in ways
Speaker 7:  they shouldn't have. Okay, end of story. Go
Speaker 5:  Watch the documentary, the great hack. It gets almost everything wrong.
Speaker 7:  No, quickly just to summarize, no I do not think they will do a third party
Speaker 7:  platform because of that. It's probably a good idea. I don't, I would say
Speaker 7:  it's at the very, very end of their to-do list and probably something that
Speaker 7:  their senior leadership does actually just not wanna do at all. So
Speaker 7:  sorry but it's a good idea. But no, I think
Speaker 5:  That's right. My question would be Heath on on that respect I think because
Speaker 5:  I can't stop talking about Activity Pub, one of the things most area has
Speaker 5:  said a couple of times is that part of the upside of Activity Pub is you
Speaker 5:  can support the standard and kind of be part of the ecosystem, but you can
Speaker 5:  also build Threads only stuff just inside of
Speaker 5:  the app So. what I wonder is less like do they wanna support developers and
Speaker 5:  more, do you think they'll go the road of like, I would call it like the
Speaker 5:  iMessage thing where where it's like you can send SMSs through iMessage but
Speaker 5:  if your iMessage to iMessage you get this whole like universe of other stuff
Speaker 5:  you can do. Yes. Is that where Threads ends? Do
Speaker 7:  You think? That's totally where it's going and it's so ironic given that
Speaker 7:  Meta spends all its time shitting on iMessage whenever it gets a
Speaker 7:  chance in ads and in interviews. But yeah, Threads will be the blue bubble
Speaker 7:  of the fediverse and we're all gonna have to
Speaker 5:  Look that. That's that's good. That's very that's good. Yeah, I like that
Speaker 5:  you just
Speaker 6:  Made all the fediverse green bubbles so mad.
Speaker 7:  Get at me with your tweets guys furiously. Okay those are, those are
Speaker 7:  reader questions. What's next?
Speaker 5:  Let's, can we talk about the Twitter response just for a couple of minutes
Speaker 5:  before we throw to another break? Yeah, it, it got more aggressive over the
Speaker 5:  24 hours but basically the first response from Twitter,
Speaker 5:  well lemme just read you the tweets both from Elon Musk and from Linda
Speaker 5:  Yak the ceo. So Elon Musk said it is
Speaker 5:  infinitely preferable to be attacked by strangers on Twitter then indulge
Speaker 5:  in the false happiness of hide the pain Instagram. That's what Elon Musk
Speaker 5:  said and like what does that mean?
Speaker 7:  That's a sentence.
Speaker 5:  What Sure. And then the CEO Lin Aina said, we're often
Speaker 5:  imitated but the Twitter community can never be duplicated. That is a much
Speaker 5:  better line and a much better selling point I would argue and I think
Speaker 5:  is gonna be the thing, right? And like even Messer said this to you a couple
Speaker 5:  of times, Alex, he's like going way out of his way to give Twitter credit
Speaker 5:  for like pioneering the format. Which I think you could make a strong case.
Speaker 5:  It didn't really do that. Like there are things that look like Twitter before
Speaker 5:  Twitter but also that it is, it is a big community
Speaker 5:  full of engaged people and that's actually a hard thing to unseat and even
Speaker 5:  if Threads works, it probably won't kill Twitter. Both of those read a
Speaker 5:  lot. Like I'm not scared, I'm not scared, I'm not scared. Don't tell everybody
Speaker 5:  I was scared. Responses. Right. Is that, is that what you guys take from
Speaker 5:  this? Okay.
Speaker 7:  Pretty much.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Yes. Cool. And then just to prove it's not
Speaker 5:  scared, Twitter also threatened to sue Oh my
Speaker 5:  over Threads Heath you were looking at this just before we started recording.
Speaker 5:  Do you wanna explain what we know?
Speaker 7:  Oh my god, I was just reading it while you were saying that It is. So this
Speaker 7:  is Alex Spero must personal lawyer who has also been
Speaker 7:  taking point on them not paying rents et cetera. This
Speaker 7:  whole letter is hilarious but it's to Zuckerberg and it, the part that I
Speaker 7:  think is super relevant is that over the past year Meta has
Speaker 7:  hired dozens of former employees. Twitter knows that these employees previously
Speaker 7:  worked at Twitter that these employees had and continued to have access to
Speaker 7:  Twitter's trade secrets and other highly confidential information that these
Speaker 7:  employees owe ongoing obligations to Twitter and that many of these employees
Speaker 7:  have improperly retained Twitter documents and electronic
Speaker 7:  devices. That sounds like your problem. Alex Spero with that knowledge,
Speaker 7:  Meta deliberately assigned these employees to develop and a matter of months
Speaker 7:  met us copycat app with the specific intent that they use Twitter's trade
Speaker 7:  secrets, et cetera and violation of law, et cetera. So
Speaker 7:  this is I guess some vague threat of like a
Speaker 7:  IP software IP property rights lawsuit.
Speaker 7:  Which hate to break it to you Musk and Ox Spiro, but if there's
Speaker 7:  any company that has researched the actual legal
Speaker 7:  grounds for successfully winning a case on copying software, it is
Speaker 7:  Meta considering they have copied more software than any social media
Speaker 7:  company to date in a cumulative
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think if Snap couldn't win a lawsuit, Twitter's probably not gonna
Speaker 5:  win a lawsuit. Yeah, he'd be
Speaker 7:  My guess this is the part of the show where if we had Neli, he would be going
Speaker 7:  on a rant about the state of copyright law in America.
Speaker 5:  Thank God he's not here,
Speaker 7:  Thank God he's not but but
Speaker 6:  It's not really a copyright thing. It's very much like a trade secrets
Speaker 6:  from employees thing. Which is
Speaker 7:  I guess,
Speaker 5:  And again the irony of that is like remember when Elon Musk took over Twitter
Speaker 5:  and promptly fired more than half the company? You're gonna
Speaker 6:  Have a hard time proving it. If you fired everybody, you didn't do
Speaker 6:  any due diligence to recover everything from them because you fired them
Speaker 6:  so quickly And like you have to prove what trade secrets that
Speaker 6:  they're using, which is pretty, in this particular case
Speaker 6:  probably gonna be pretty hard to do unless they're like in Slack saying L
Speaker 6:  M M O, I'm using this, I'm just gonna copy paste this stuff we used on
Speaker 6:  Twitter, which hopefully they didn't do but they might have.
Speaker 7:  Oh and here we go. Andy Stone, a Meta spokesperson has already, this is
Speaker 7:  so great. We're already seeing now. So when Meta people, they finally have
Speaker 7:  a place to respond to tweets that isn't Twitter, he
Speaker 5:  Threaded
Speaker 7:  It. I just got sent a thread for and Stone what a day
Speaker 7:  responding to this letter saying, to be clear no one on the Threads engineering
Speaker 7:  team is a former Twitter employee. That's just not a thing.
Speaker 6:  Oh that's great.
Speaker 7:  So I, yeah, I honestly like, I should have said this earlier, but a huge
Speaker 7:  part of Threads and why Met is so excited about this is that Mark Zuckerberg
Speaker 7:  and all their execs finally have a place to post
Speaker 7:  Twitter like content that isn't Twitter. I loved that. Like his
Speaker 7:  first tweet in 11 years was Zuckerberg posting the spider-man
Speaker 7:  pointing meme,
Speaker 5:  Unbelievable tweet, unbelievable like so good. The best possible thing he
Speaker 5:  could have tweeted who I was so impressed by that we're
Speaker 7:  Gonna enter this hole as a reporter. It's just like I'm gonna have to be
Speaker 7:  checking Twitter for the Twitter response to the story and then Threads for
Speaker 7:  the Meta response, whatever. This is the new world we live in.
Speaker 6:  Which one is getting more engagement?
Speaker 7:  That's a good question. I'll have to report back on that
Speaker 5:  X to that point, my one request, Adam ary, if you're listening
Speaker 5:  and I know that you are build a web app, I'm sure you're going to do
Speaker 5:  it first. Just I don't wanna have to spend all day at work looking
Speaker 5:  at my phone. I'm using my phone as my webcam right now. I can't be on Threads.
Speaker 5:  Come on. Help. Help it out. Help me out.
Speaker 9:  Well David,
Speaker 7:  To be fair, you can open Threads on web if there's a lot of
Speaker 7:  replies, it cuts off and tells you to get into the app, but you can at least
Speaker 7:  see them on the web.
Speaker 5:  I'm just gonna go guess Threads URLs and see if there are any sick posts
Speaker 5:  at whatever URL that's like, it's gonna be amazing. Alright, we need to take
Speaker 5:  one more break but before we do, NELI is pinging
Speaker 5:  me in Slack and apparently just landed and has some deep thoughts
Speaker 5:  about Threads he would like to share. So we're gonna call him up, I think
Speaker 5:  he's at baggage claim and hear what he has to
Speaker 5:  say.
Speaker 5:  Where in the world are you? Neli Patel,
Speaker 9:  I'm at the airport with Mags. Can you say hi Mags. Hi
Speaker 9:  we're waiting for our bags but I need to react to Instagram
Speaker 9:  Threads in a very deep meaningful way, like a
Speaker 9:  spiritual way, which is why I'm calling you from there to force my way onto
Speaker 9:  the show.
Speaker 5:  That's correct. So we, we've spent a long time on this podcast
Speaker 5:  talking about Threads already, but you, I want to know
Speaker 5:  because you are the guy who has been on this show specifically saying things
Speaker 5:  like, I don't want feed-based social media in my life. And then you just
Speaker 5:  showed up guns blazing on Threads, what's going on here?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it's like six posts in a day already. I'm off the wagon. Yeah man
Speaker 9:  they're drinking straight from the hose
Speaker 5:  You're smoking again,
Speaker 9:  It's two things. One, you know I missed it. It's fun to post on a new social
Speaker 9:  network in that vibe. you know, I, I post on Blue Sky a little bit. I, I
Speaker 9:  tooted on Mastodon but here I think the activity
Speaker 9:  pub integration that Meta is promising is
Speaker 9:  actually really interesting in a way that I don't know if the at protocol
Speaker 9:  from Blue Sky will be successful or maybe it will be, but
Speaker 9:  I can just see a world in which having a presence on a large
Speaker 9:  decentralized social platform can connect directly
Speaker 9:  to our work and what we do. And I think that's really exciting and I'd rather
Speaker 9:  be invested in that sort of opportunity than just building on
Speaker 9:  someone else's close platform yet again.
Speaker 5:  What do you make of like the app itself? Heath and Cranz and I didn't talk
Speaker 5:  that much about like the actual mechanics of using the app. I kind of think
Speaker 5:  it's like it works but I kind of think it's like hideously ugly.
Speaker 5:  What's your sense?
Speaker 9:  It's a little bit ugly, right? Yeah it's a little bit ugly. Why
Speaker 5:  Are the share buttons so big? I don't understand
Speaker 9:  The button for reply and the button for whatever the paper airplane. I'm
Speaker 9:  just confused. I don't know what's going on at the bottom of every post.
Speaker 9:  I think they know some of it isn't there and needs to be improved. It's
Speaker 9:  just, it's hard to know how much this version you have to
Speaker 9:  take seriously right at this second. It, it's a very minimum
Speaker 9:  viable product and it, it shows yes
Speaker 5:  They,
Speaker 9:  They clearly rushed this out because of Twitter's rate limits. But I will
Speaker 9:  say this, I posted that the embeds were a little bit broken cuz we wanted
Speaker 9:  to put thread embeds in our stories and quick posts and the feed and all
Speaker 9:  this stuff and like three different Meta engineers, including the
Speaker 9:  person who wrote the embed product replied to me and then they fixed
Speaker 9:  it. And that's just like the most fun you can have.
Speaker 9:  It's everyone's building things together and talking about the products in
Speaker 9:  earnest and that's the fun part of making the
Speaker 9:  internet right. I keep saying the internet feels like 2011 again and that's
Speaker 9:  the part I really like and the part that I want back. Totally
Speaker 5:  And it feels I mean in a funny way. It feels like if you go back to that
Speaker 5:  era that's like the early Instagram era where all of this stuff was being
Speaker 5:  built the first time before it was a giant monolith that was
Speaker 5:  hard to ship new stuff into and before everything that changed got rolled
Speaker 5:  out in tiny little doses. This they're just back to like building it live
Speaker 5:  right in front of us, which I agree is, is fun and different and feels
Speaker 5:  really different from Meta. I wasn't sure Meta like had the muscle to be
Speaker 5:  this kind of company anymore.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I think that same thing. I think they're excited. The energy is like
Speaker 9:  palpable. They have skyrocketing user growth. Again, I also just keep
Speaker 9:  listening how bad it must be in the like reality labs
Speaker 9:  and Horizon worlds division where they're just trying to
Speaker 9:  brute force the next version of like the metaverse internet into
Speaker 9:  existence and they're just like alone in their headsets. While Zuck
Speaker 9:  is a conquering hero, like posting Spider-Man
Speaker 9:  memes, maybe the answer was much simpler than they thought.
Speaker 5:  Yes, I do think it, it's gonna be interesting to See how the vibes
Speaker 5:  shift in like week two of this, right? Because right now it's very exciting,
Speaker 5:  it's kind of amazing that it works as well as it does. But I think the question
Speaker 5:  of like where are we gonna be seven days from now when opening this thing
Speaker 5:  is less exciting is gonna be really interesting. And we've seen this a few
Speaker 5:  times where it feels really cool and everybody like, is this, is this thing
Speaker 5:  gonna be be real or is this gonna be something more meaningful?
Speaker 9:  I think it just comes down to does it send anybody any traffic? Like
Speaker 9:  they did the growth hackiest growth hacky thing, which is they're just always
Speaker 9:  buzzing at you if you have notifications on, so the platform just feels alive
Speaker 9:  cuz it's constantly sending you notifications. I actually turned them off
Speaker 9:  like too much. This is everything I did not want about feed based
Speaker 9:  social media. But then even when you have them off, when you have the app
Speaker 9:  open, it still buzzes at you whenever you get a reply or a
Speaker 9:  notification and that's like pretty good. Like they built a
Speaker 9:  good feedback loop in there and I think that's gonna carry 'em, especially
Speaker 9:  if the pace of signups continues to just accelerate like we've seen.
Speaker 5:  Totally. All right, well before you go, I know you have more bags to pick
Speaker 5:  up and traveling to do the, the one of the last things we talked about before
Speaker 5:  we got on with you was, I dunno if you saw this while you're on the plane,
Speaker 5:  but Twitter is threatening to sue Instagram for
Speaker 5:  essentially ripping off the app. They're saying they, you know, hired a bunch
Speaker 5:  of people with devices and trade secrets and they came and built a
Speaker 5:  copycat app. I would just like to hear lawyer Eli's
Speaker 5:  initial impression of whether this is anything and the extent to which this
Speaker 5:  is nothing.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it's the saddest shit I've ever read, man. Like what are they even
Speaker 9:  complaining about? Twitter's trade secrets? What are Twitter's trade secrets?
Speaker 9:  Twitter's IP stack is basically nothing. And then on top of that,
Speaker 9:  Twitter promised ages ago to never use its patents
Speaker 9:  offensively actually wrote a big story in 2013 about this thing called the
Speaker 9:  Innovator's patent agreement, the ipa, it was a big Twitter initiative where
Speaker 9:  they agreed to never use their patents against anyone except defensively.
Speaker 9:  And they try to get everyone else to agree to it as well. so like they got
Speaker 9:  nothing except quote unquote trade secrets and like good luck. If
Speaker 9:  I'm Quinn Emmanuel, like Elon's law firm, I would be totally embarrassed
Speaker 9:  by this desperate letter. They should have definitely told him not to do
Speaker 9:  this.
Speaker 5:  There you go. All right, go get your bags. Thank you for coming on. I suspect
Speaker 5:  we will have more chances to talk about threats very, very, very, very soon.
Speaker 9:  All right Max, you say goodbye. Bye
Speaker 5:  Mag.
Speaker 10:  Goodbye. Alright,
Speaker 9:  We're outta here.
Speaker 5:  All right. And with that we need to actually take a break and then we're
Speaker 5:  gonna come back and do a lightning round. We'll be right
Speaker 5:  back.
Speaker 4:  Fox Creative. This is advertiser content brought to you by
Speaker 4:  WhatsApp.
Speaker 10:  I'm Alyssa here in Hollywood trying to get complete strangers to read me
Speaker 10:  their private messages
Speaker 11:  Now y'all don't wanna see my text messages? I can.
Speaker 10:  Can I please read your private text messages?
Speaker 12:  No
Speaker 10:  You can't. No, no.
Speaker 4:  Clearly most of us wouldn't want a stranger to read our personal messages,
Speaker 4:  but how secure are they Once we hit send
Speaker 10:  Come on. What? You don't trust me?
Speaker 11:  No, I don't trust no one.
Speaker 5:  Well
Speaker 10:  How do you know your messages are are being sent privately?
Speaker 11:  Oh, you're
Speaker 10:  Right. If you're not using an end-to-end encryption app
Speaker 10:  like WhatsApp, then anyone can be reading your messages.
Speaker 12:  Got hacked. So I learned that lesson. Okay. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  And how did it feel getting a message hacked?
Speaker 12:  It was just like such an invasion of privacy. Yeah, honestly. So you
Speaker 12:  need to have two factor authentication. Yes. You need to have those things
Speaker 12:  in place. Like you're saying, the end-to-end encryption.
Speaker 4:  WhatsApp automatically encrypts your personal messages the moment you send
Speaker 4:  them. So they can only be read by the people you send them to. That means
Speaker 4:  no one outside the chat can read your messages. Not even WhatsApp.
Speaker 10:  Well you let me read your private text messages. No,
Speaker 11:  Why not? They're private. Okay.
Speaker 10:  And what if the whole internet could read them?
Speaker 11:  Oh my god, I don't know. It'd be over. It'd be game
Speaker 11:  over.
Speaker 10:  Wouldn't it feel better to be messaging through an encrypted app? WhatsApp?
Speaker 10:  It's private locked up. You can say whatever you want.
Speaker 11:  Oh, is that right? How
Speaker 10:  Does that sound?
Speaker 11:  That sounds great.
Speaker 4:  Enter a new era of privacy with automatic end-to-end encryption on all
Speaker 4:  your personal messages. WhatsApp always message privately
Speaker 10:  Just because it's Hollywood Boulevard and I'm running at you in heels. What?
Speaker 10:  You don't trust me.
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back. Let's stop with Threads for a minute and let's
Speaker 5:  do, let's do a little bit of a lightning round cuz it is July. so like news
Speaker 5:  is slow and news is going to be slow for a little while
Speaker 5:  because everybody's on vacation for the next several weeks. Have you guys
Speaker 5:  already started getting like the, the increase in out of office responses
Speaker 5:  from people? Mine has definitely spiked the last few days.
Speaker 6:  No, I I aggressively work hard to not email people
Speaker 6:  ever. It's not going well, but it's going well enough that I
Speaker 6:  haven't gotten any yet.
Speaker 5:  I respect that. Just carrier pigeons or nothing. Let's do a little bit of
Speaker 5:  lightning round. The only rule for this lightning round is you can pick anything
Speaker 5:  you want to talk about this week except Threads. Threads is off limits. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Crayons. You get to go first. What do you got?
Speaker 6:  Okay, so we're gonna talk about Daddy's lov, one of my favorite people
Speaker 6:  on the planet who
Speaker 5:  Has had quite a week that been,
Speaker 6:  He has had quite boy quite a week. We, we can go. Do we,
Speaker 6:  should we go into all of it? Should I
Speaker 5:  There's a few. Just give us the quick rundown cuz there's a bunch of stuff
Speaker 5:  happening simultaneously here.
Speaker 6:  Okay, here's the, here's the quick rundown. About two weeks ago,
Speaker 6:  Turner Classic movies lost a lot of employees. People
Speaker 6:  were very upset, particularly a lot of like big fans of old Hollywood
Speaker 6:  movies like Steven Spielberg and Scorsese and Wes Anderson
Speaker 6:  and they all complained and Zla was eventually like,
Speaker 6:  okay, but you guys can come and help us and be a part of
Speaker 6:  this and we won't fire everyone at Turner Classic movies and you guys can
Speaker 6:  like help us choose movies. And so that happened and everybody seemed to
Speaker 6:  settle. There was much joy in the kingdom. As much
Speaker 6:  joys can happen in the kingdom of Zaslav.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Picking a fight with Turner Classic movies by the way. Weird move.
Speaker 6:  Weird mo. Well and also he allegedly loves Classic films.
Speaker 6:  Like he's a big fan of them. He's a huge fan of Turner Classic movie.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, but you know what he likes more Alex is tax breaks.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, exactly. He was like, I love them but I love tax breaks more. And
Speaker 6:  they came and were like, yeah, but do you ever wanna work with any of us
Speaker 6:  again? And he's like, I do so
Speaker 6:  nevermind. Tax breaks bey. So then
Speaker 6:  over the weekend GQ published a story
Speaker 6:  that, that talked a lot about this, but also talked about the fact that
Speaker 6:  Salov is it exactly known for like his film
Speaker 6:  taste? He, he, he's, you know, he's a guy who, who did
Speaker 6:  like the 27 kids and counting or whatever it's called. He did a
Speaker 6:  lot of reality show, a lot of reality TV that a lot of people consider trashy.
Speaker 6:  They don't like it. And, and this, this GQ article really took him
Speaker 6:  to task for, for that and the fact that he was that guy and now he's out
Speaker 6:  here running one of the largest movie studios in the world. And then the
Speaker 6:  story disappeared.
Speaker 5:  Well first it got aggressively edited, it
Speaker 6:  Came back aggressively edited, but with no byline on it and then
Speaker 6:  it totally disappeared. And it turns out that
Speaker 6:  someone on Zaslav camp reached out to GQ and were like,
Speaker 6:  this is really mean. And to be fair, it was a very mean article,
Speaker 5:  But it, as far as we know, didn't say anything that lots of people were not
Speaker 5:  already saying publicly. He was,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, there was nothing inaccurate in it. It was a lot of opinion and that
Speaker 6:  opinion was you suck.
Speaker 7:  It was not that bad. Like this is what you're gonna have your PR person
Speaker 7:  try to spike. Like really?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So it sounds like what happened was that they, they reached out with
Speaker 6:  a whole list of things and PR does this a lot where they really dislike a
Speaker 6:  story but there's nothing actually inaccurate. So they just have a bunch
Speaker 6:  of things to like be like, well, but you could have also said that he loves
Speaker 6:  babies. Why didn't you talk about how he loves babies and
Speaker 6:  people at gq, they pulled the story. There was a lot of upset
Speaker 6:  folks. It turns out that the, the E IIC of
Speaker 6:  GQ is also producing a film that's being made, made at
Speaker 6:  Warner Brothers. Everybody looks terrifically stupid in this
Speaker 6:  situation. Salov just looks really, really thin-skinned and he is
Speaker 6:  still in negotiations with both SAG and the W G
Speaker 6:  A with all the other producers in Hollywood right now. So probably
Speaker 6:  not a great time to look really thin-skinned and like you hate the
Speaker 6:  movies and people
Speaker 5:  And also like truly excellent Streisand effect
Speaker 5:  example, oh my God, of taking a GQ story that I, I had not
Speaker 5:  heard about or seen and no one really paid that much attention to and turning
Speaker 5:  it into like front page news all over the internet. I didn't
Speaker 6:  Read it and until it had already been pulled and then I was like, oh,
Speaker 6:  this is what you went
Speaker 5:  After. Thank you to the Google cash for providing that.
Speaker 6:  I gotta be, I gotta be meaner in in my own stories about Warner Brothers
Speaker 6:  now. So yeah, we'll see what can happen.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Big week for David Lov. Heath, have you picked one yet or do you want
Speaker 5:  me to go while you look?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I have one. We wrote about this, Wes Davis wrote about this on the
Speaker 7:  site. The TSA is gonna be expanding its use of facial
Speaker 7:  recognition to over 400 airports. They claim a
Speaker 7:  97% effectiveness rate on the 25
Speaker 7:  airport pilot program they've been using so far. This is just
Speaker 7:  a bad idea. Can we just say beyond a shot of a doubt that like
Speaker 7:  we should not be giving the TSA our faces.
Speaker 6:  TSA shouldn't have anything. They shouldn't have funding.
Speaker 5:  Also 97% success rate on this is not impressive.
Speaker 7:  No it's
Speaker 5:  Not. Our security system misses three out of a hundred people. It's like
Speaker 5:  not
Speaker 7:  Good. Yeah. Like I've seen these things and I'm sure other people have going
Speaker 7:  through TSA, like I see it at LAX and I've seen it New York obviously
Speaker 7:  like avoid it at all costs. I really hope this stays
Speaker 7:  opt in. They should not mandate this. There is no
Speaker 7:  federal privacy law about facial recognition data.
Speaker 7:  There's no law that stipulates how the US government uses this
Speaker 7:  data. TSA claims they delete it. I do not believe them. I
Speaker 7:  think we have, we can be skeptical of the data
Speaker 7:  practices of private for-profit corporations that we choose to use all
Speaker 7:  the time. I'm not saying that that's bad. We should absolutely
Speaker 7:  be way more skeptical and concerned about government
Speaker 7:  agencies using our personal and face data. And so this is a
Speaker 7:  giant thumbs down for me. The TSA sucks and they should
Speaker 7:  not use our face data.
Speaker 6:  Well someone's gonna get a really good look in his bag next time he
Speaker 6:  flies. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  God, you just made a list somewhere for
Speaker 7:  Sure. I'm definitely on the list now. Whatever. I've got global entries.
Speaker 7:  Stop me bitches.
Speaker 5:  Clear bitches. Yeah, yeah, I love it. All right. Mine
Speaker 5:  is Google. You may have heard of it, changed its privacy
Speaker 5:  policy to say that it uses publicly
Speaker 5:  scraped web data to train things like
Speaker 5:  Bard and cloud ai. I believe those are the two things that added to the PO
Speaker 5:  to the privacy policy. This is one of those things that like everybody already
Speaker 5:  knew and Google is sort of retroactively being like, no, trust us.
Speaker 5:  It's super cool that we do this. It's no problem, don't worry about it at
Speaker 5:  all. And this sparked like a minor uproar
Speaker 5:  because it had a lot of people asking questions about like, okay, is Google
Speaker 5:  using my Google Docs to train AI
Speaker 5:  models? I believe the answer is no, because that doesn't actually
Speaker 5:  count as a thing on the public web. But I'm sure that's complicated. If you
Speaker 5:  like make it a public link, like who knows, all this stuff is a mess. And
Speaker 5:  the response to it, like updating your privacy policy is one of those things
Speaker 5:  you do when you hope no one will notice. Because who reads privacy policies
Speaker 5:  mercifully? There are people on the internet who have it set up so that when
Speaker 5:  Google changes its privacy policy, you get an email about it. Love those
Speaker 5:  tools. Congratulations everybody. But I think this is the kind of thing,
Speaker 5:  there are just gonna be a lot of moments like this in the immediate future
Speaker 5:  and there are a lot of questions about what it means that all of this
Speaker 5:  is happening and what it means for you as a person that
Speaker 5:  none of these companies are doing a good job of communicating. Obviously
Speaker 5:  none of this is regulated in any kind of meaningful way yet. And it's gonna
Speaker 5:  keep sparking all of these fights about all of these
Speaker 5:  companies. Like we went through this with the social networks. Do you guys
Speaker 5:  remember, I think it was Instagram actually changed its privacy policy a
Speaker 5:  bunch of years ago that it was like, we can use your images in marketing
Speaker 5:  materials or everything. And everybody's like, wait, what? You are gonna
Speaker 5:  use my photos in an Instagram ad? And Instagram was like,
Speaker 5:  why would we do that? That's ridiculous. We need it to be able to like propagate
Speaker 5:  your image across our services and this stuff. People just don't
Speaker 5:  understand how this stuff works and they shouldn't have to. And we are reaching
Speaker 5:  a point with all the AI stuff again, where it's gonna get real scary. There's
Speaker 5:  gonna be a lot like FUD out there as people panic about
Speaker 5:  it and it's just gonna get real messy and I'm not looking forward to it.
Speaker 5:  Well it
Speaker 6:  Was really weird for people to be upset about the scraping of this case because
Speaker 6:  like that's literally Google's business. Google, Google's business. Google
Speaker 6:  has always been to scrape the internet and monetize what it
Speaker 6:  does. Like, oh no, they're doing like have a debate.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But this is a new product. This is a new product that
Speaker 7:  further abstracts the core content. The source content. That's
Speaker 7:  fair. That's fair. From the sourcing. I think that's the key thing here.
Speaker 7:  We're witnessing like potentially one of the greatest like copyright scams
Speaker 7:  in history with these models.
Speaker 6:  I mean if they're allowed to maintain copyrights with those models. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Which they might not be able to.
Speaker 7:  Again, if Nili was here,
Speaker 5:  Thank God we already hung up on Nili. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 7:  Thank God. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  He's calling back right now. Liam, don't let him in. Don't let him in. All
Speaker 5:  Right. We should go. This is enough Vergecast. We've gone Long
Speaker 5:  as we all want to do. Should we tell people how to find us on Threads? Is
Speaker 5:  that what we do now? We like stopped telling people our our Twitter handles.
Speaker 5:  Should we tell them our Threads?
Speaker 6:  Yes, we should. Because I want you to say Neli
Speaker 6:  cuz it's funny.
Speaker 5:  The thing is, I don't want to say the phrase Threads me because
Speaker 5:  that sucks. So maybe this is why, maybe tweets is the
Speaker 5:  answer. Tweet me on Threads. See I'm, I'm David Pierce
Speaker 5:  because I'm gonna kill whoever has David Pierce and then I'll be David Pierce.
Speaker 5:  But until then there's an I'm at the beginning of it that other
Speaker 6:  David Pierce dies in the next week.
Speaker 5:  He's like a lawyer in Phoenix and we are in a permanent war for David
Speaker 5:  Pearce usernames.
Speaker 7:  Is there an apostrophe there with the Im or no?
Speaker 5:  Just Im, no, just, just all Just letters all the way down. Alex. You're Alex
Speaker 5:  Heath, you know, whatever. Mr. Low number joined Alex
Speaker 5:  Cranz. Your Alex h Cranz, right? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's, that's what I used on Twitter. It seems fine.
Speaker 5:  The H stands for Hustle. Yes,
Speaker 6:  It does
Speaker 5:  Go to Cranz for all your hustle, bro. Content decoder is a podcast. NI's
Speaker 5:  not here, so don't listen to it. Decoder is awful. I hate it. The worst forever.
Speaker 5:  It's the worst.
Speaker 6:  But where we, where can you follow him? You didn't say where we can follow
Speaker 6:  Nili.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. Reckless Reckless. 1280 on
Speaker 5:  Threads because that's the year he was born.
Speaker 5:  1280. Next Wednesday on The Vergecast, we're gonna talk about ai. We're also
Speaker 5:  gonna talk about video games with Ash Parrish and Chris Plant from Polygon.
Speaker 5:  We talked about all our favorite games. It was very fun. And we're also gonna
Speaker 5:  talk about a whole bunch of new Apple software. We think it's all coming
Speaker 5:  very soon, so we're gonna talk about it until then. We'll see you on Threads.
Speaker 5:  That's it. That's The. Vergecast. Rock and
Speaker 7:  Roll. See you
Speaker 7:  guys.
Speaker 8:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 8:  us an email at Vergecast at The Verge dot com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 8:  production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network. The show's produced
Speaker 8:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 8:  Our editorial director is Brooke Minters. That's it. We'll see you next
Speaker 8:  week.