# Transcript
ID: 5195e692-82c0-494e-80fb-8b824d51e9c7
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: AI might break the internet
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/8604645597133184795/3049416097166057131/s93290-US-5355s-1688121007.mp3
Description: The Verge's David Pierce, Nilay Patel, and Alex Cranz discuss results from our AI survey, this week's AI news, our Apple Mac Pro review, and more.
Later, Adi Robertson and Tom Warren join the show to discuss the latest in the FTC v. Microsoft trial, including what Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella had to say on the stand.
Hope, fear, and AI
AI is killing the old web, and the new web struggles to be born
ChatGPT on iOS now comes with Bing built-in
Ads for major brands are appearing on AI-generated spam sites
House restricts congressional use of ChatGPT
AI-generated tweets might be more convincing than real people, research finds
Apple Mac Pro M2 Ultra review: a powerful computer in search of an audience
The AirPods Max are getting left behind, so are new Apple headphones coming this year?
Reddit mods are calling for an ‘affordable return’ for third-party apps
Plex lays off more than 20 percent of its staff
Ford’s F-150 Lightning price hikes are costing it customers
TikTok’s new feature asks creators to make branded videos for a chance at ad money
FTC v. Microsoft: all the news from the big Xbox courtroom battle
The FTC’s case against Microsoft could turn into Xbox vs. PlayStation
Has Xbox really lost the console wars?
Microsoft exec was ready to ‘go spend Sony out of business’ to strengthen Xbox
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  Hello, I'm Esther Perel. I'm a psychotherapist and host of the
Speaker 1:  podcast. Where should we begin? I invite you to enter
Speaker 1:  into my office and to listen in on the sessions that I
Speaker 1:  conduct with people from all walks of life, grappling
Speaker 1:  with the challenges and choices in their relationships.
Speaker 1:  I'll be dropping new episodes every Monday, starting July
Speaker 1:  10, listen and follow. Where should we begin
Speaker 1:  on your favorite podcast app?
Speaker 3:  Why does it feel like everyone is on tour this summer and why are tickets
Speaker 3:  so expensive?
Speaker 4:  So the first show I am on the onstage risers.
Speaker 3:  You can do that. Yes. I thought it was just friends of Beyonce. No,
Speaker 4:  No, no, no. Those tickets should, what
Speaker 3:  Are they called?
Speaker 4:  They're called the onstage v i p risers.
Speaker 3:  How much that cost?
Speaker 4:  $4,000
Speaker 3:  For one.
Speaker 4:  For one ticket. How
Speaker 3:  Do you feel about that?
Speaker 4:  I'm okay with that.
Speaker 3:  Are you okay with
Speaker 4:  That? I, well, okay. So
Speaker 3:  We enroll in the Economics of the Summer tour and why it's
Speaker 3:  broken this week on Intuit Vultures Pop Culture
Speaker 3:  podcast.
Speaker 2:  Hello.
Speaker 5:  Welcome. Wait, you're, oh, you're starting. So I was gonna start. You just
Speaker 6:  Told me I'm supposed to run the show. Neli.
Speaker 5:  All right. David's running the show. No, you do it.
Speaker 6:  You're good. No, run the show.
Speaker 6:  welcome to the Vercast, the flagship podcast of Alaska commons.com and
Speaker 6:  world today news.com and other fake
Speaker 6:  websites made by fake people. I'm your friend, David Pierce. Niel
Speaker 6:  is here and not in charge.
Speaker 5:  I'm in a full clerk's zone like I'm not even supposed to be here today.
Speaker 6:  You're supposed to be on a mountain somewhere.
Speaker 5:  I was supposed to be at the Aspen Ideas Festival doing a panel about ai,
Speaker 5:  which our friend Joanna Stern and all the flights from the East coast were
Speaker 5:  canceled due to the storm. So now I'm here with you, which I'm very happy
Speaker 5:  about. 0% prepared. So David's gonna run the show.
Speaker 6:  That's the way we like you Alex. Cranz is here. Hi Alex. Hi.
Speaker 7:  I'm 5% prepared. I read about AI this week.
Speaker 6:  AI is a thing, it's,
Speaker 5:  It's happening.
Speaker 6:  Welcome to the first cast where AI is a thing. We have a lot to talk about
Speaker 6:  this week. There's The, FTC versus Microsoft going on
Speaker 6:  right now as we do this. Satya Nadella is on the stand,
Speaker 6:  which is why we're recording this with Nili. And then Nili has to go away
Speaker 6:  and be on a different mountain somewhere. So we're gonna talk about that
Speaker 6:  after he's gone with Addie Robertson and Tom Warren.
Speaker 6:  We have a bunch of gadgety, apple, E Lightning, round stuff to do. But
Speaker 6:  let's start with ai. There was a like grab bag of AI stuff going on this
Speaker 6:  week on the site and I feel like we should talk about all of it, starting
Speaker 6:  with this big survey that we did that I knew nothing about. It just sort
Speaker 6:  of dropped on the site at some point and was totally fascinating. What did
Speaker 6:  you guys make of this survey? This survey both surprised me and did not
Speaker 6:  surprise me at all in ways I thought was really interesting. But the idea
Speaker 6:  was like, let's go out and talk to regular humans about how they feel
Speaker 6:  about AI and how they're using it and what they think. Neli, what jumped
Speaker 6:  out to you?
Speaker 5:  The background here, the colors of Vox Media has a big research and insights
Speaker 5:  team. They run around collecting data and doing surveys like this usually
Speaker 5:  on behalf of marketers. Like they, they're on that side of the house from
Speaker 5:  us. But every now and again we collaborate. So for many years we did surveys
Speaker 5:  about how people feel about big tech and sort of that big tech regulatory
Speaker 5:  moment and we are gonna do it again this year. And we thought, oh AI's way
Speaker 5:  more interesting. Like we should ask people how they feel about ai. So we
Speaker 5:  went and got this like 2000 person sample of American
Speaker 5:  adults. We did it sort of early this year, like after the AI boom. And
Speaker 5:  to me, there's two things that really jump out. One, people are
Speaker 5:  utterly convinced that it's gonna have a big impact. And there's a really
Speaker 5:  funny chart in here that compares AI to EVs, to
Speaker 5:  NFTs, like all these buzzword that people have heard about and it's like
Speaker 5:  74% of people think AI will have a big impact on society.
Speaker 5:  69% of people think EVs what big impact on society? And it's like
Speaker 5:  34% of people think NFTs will have a big impact on society,
Speaker 6:  Which feels high if I'm honest. 34%
Speaker 5:  High,
Speaker 6:  It seems
Speaker 5:  Very high. That's just the entire staff of Andreessen Horowitz took the survey.
Speaker 5:  No I mean you know, it's a representative sample and I think that makes sense.
Speaker 5:  Like it does seem high, but it's just letters people
Speaker 5:  recognize at this point. so like, yeah, like one in three
Speaker 5:  people hit yes fine. Like who knows why they did it. But it makes sense.
Speaker 5:  The thing that jumps out is people can see the impact from
Speaker 5:  ai. You don't have to convince them. They see the tools working in doing
Speaker 5:  things and they're using them, which is the other takeaway.
Speaker 5:  And then the last one is you look at what they're familiar with, like
Speaker 5:  Adobe Firefly is on the list and that, you know, that's not like
Speaker 5:  the hottest one, but it's, that's because of social media. People are seeing
Speaker 5:  it being used in Photoshop. They're seeing it being used on these tools.
Speaker 5:  And so the social media filter effect is so powerful
Speaker 5:  where everyone sees the best things AI can do because people are
Speaker 5:  posting on social media, they're, they're posting Photoshop clips on social
Speaker 5:  media or whatever. That's really interesting to me. Like the
Speaker 5:  technology is proving itself to people just by showing it, working in
Speaker 5:  a way that NFTs proved nothing to know what
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Well and I think the thing that I kept noticing going through this
Speaker 6:  is there was this chart right at the top about like basically which of these
Speaker 6:  AI things have you heard of? And ChatGPT is at the top,
Speaker 6:  57% said they've either used it or heard of it. 43% said,
Speaker 6:  what is that? And ChatGPT is high. Then Bing my
Speaker 6:  AI from Snap and Bard and then way down below you get things
Speaker 6:  like Mid journey and stable diffusion. Yeah. Which is, it's a really interesting
Speaker 6:  divide cuz you have these like chatbots that are, are like characters
Speaker 6:  and people use them and are aware of them and sort of interact
Speaker 6:  with them and like understand what they are as products. All the image stuff
Speaker 6:  seems like it is just being sort of commoditized and hidden incredibly
Speaker 6:  quickly. And like you said, all this stuff is gonna live in the tools that
Speaker 6:  we use to make images not build new platforms. Whereas
Speaker 6:  all the chat bot stuff is like trying to build new platforms. They're all
Speaker 6:  doing plugins. They like want to be the next big thing. Whereas the image
Speaker 6:  generation stuff is just like, maybe this just becomes underlying
Speaker 6:  tech really fast and nobody ever cares what Mid Journey is. I
Speaker 7:  Think the other part of that was that mid journey and all of those, those
Speaker 7:  were a little more, I don't wanna say they were mature, but we've been talking
Speaker 7:  about them a lot more and been impressed by them and like been impressed
Speaker 7:  and been like, yeah that's cool. And continued on our ways with the image
Speaker 7:  stuff a lot longer than we've been with the, the degenerative, the chat
Speaker 7:  generative stuff, right? Like that was, that was the big deal this year.
Speaker 7:  So I don't think, I'm surprised that like the thing that was on 60 Minutes
Speaker 7:  multiple times this year had a much bigger like impact in people's
Speaker 7:  minds than Mid Journey. Even though Mid Journey is really, really cool and
Speaker 7:  doing really cool stuff.
Speaker 5:  The thing that I think is super interesting about that, and I completely
Speaker 5:  agree with you Alex, is it once more
Speaker 5:  impressive for the computer to generate an image And it's
Speaker 5:  also easier to have an opinion about it. So it's like I
Speaker 5:  can't do anything in Photoshop, but I can tell Photoshop
Speaker 5:  to do something and then be like, that sucks and everyone's okay
Speaker 5:  with that flow. And then people look at like walls
Speaker 5:  of text being generated, which they can definitely do on their own and they're
Speaker 5:  like, that is the most impressive thing I've ever seen. I can't do it. And
Speaker 5:  there's, there's something in there, there's a, there's a PhD thesis
Speaker 5:  in there about like how we evaluate things we can make versus things we can't
Speaker 5:  make. And it's just so funny to me that people can look at an image and be
Speaker 5:  like, that sucks with no ability to create it. I do it all
Speaker 5:  the time and they can look at text, which they could probably edit
Speaker 5:  and they're like, that is the most, that's it's alive.
Speaker 7:  You know why it is though? It's because people really suck at
Speaker 7:  writing but they think they're really good at writing. But people really
Speaker 7:  suck at art. But they know they really suck at art. Like everybody's very
Speaker 7:  self-aware that they're bad at art. Yeah. But most people are like, I'm a
Speaker 7:  good writer. Then you edit them and you're like,
Speaker 5:  Hmm, this is definitely three editors on a podcast now. It's like,
Speaker 7:  Yeah this is, this is courtesy of my mom sent me something copy the other
Speaker 7:  day. No, you're
Speaker 5:  Like, you should use the robot mom. My
Speaker 7:  Mom is an amazing writer. I have no idea what a writing looks like. Look,
Speaker 5:  I've had drinks with Alex's mom. Yeah you did. I would read whatever she
Speaker 5:  wrote.
Speaker 7:  One person on this podcast will read what my mom wrote. I think
Speaker 7:  what shocked me about this survey was that
Speaker 7:  76% of people were like, we should outlaw using AI
Speaker 7:  to make deep fakes of people's faces without their consent.
Speaker 7:  That was, I was like, does nobody know what parody is?
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. Every time we do regulatory questions on surveys like this, like
Speaker 5:  it's kind of amazing how the knee jerk answer is like you should control
Speaker 5:  it. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Destroy it.
Speaker 5:  And that to some extent that's the answer. We should probably find a way
Speaker 5:  to outlaw deep fake, like bad faith,
Speaker 5:  deep fakes of other people. We have a story that has been
Speaker 5:  buring along in our evergreen search results for a while
Speaker 5:  and it's, James Vincent wrote about a tool that
Speaker 5:  was, it was an app on on the window store for like a minute that could generate
Speaker 5:  deep fake nudes of women. And so like the keywords in the headline
Speaker 5:  are like deep like app to make deep fake nudes of women
Speaker 5:  and like it's about how the thing went up and it's a problem and then it
Speaker 5:  came down like whatever. Like that's the story. But the keywords in the
Speaker 5:  headline are such that people keep finding it in search and it
Speaker 5:  scares me every time I see it come up the charts and I'm like,
Speaker 5:  that's the, I don't know how to do it. Like there's a million reasons that
Speaker 5:  it's hard to do, but I think everybody instinctively knows that
Speaker 5:  maybe there should be consequences for that or you shouldn't do it.
Speaker 6:  It's just so, it's so visceral in a way a lot of the things that we
Speaker 6:  talk about with tech regulation aren't like
Speaker 6:  disinformation is this like very hard concept to get your head around in
Speaker 6:  a lot of ways. Even even things like harassment can be
Speaker 6:  hard to sort of look at from afar and understand what it is and what makes
Speaker 6:  it up deep. Fake nudes is like the single easiest thing to
Speaker 6:  understand that could possibly exist. But yeah, I, I was struck
Speaker 6:  by the same thing Alex all of the questions about how should we
Speaker 6:  regulate ai? Ironically they were all between 76 and
Speaker 6:  78% of people for the most part. Yeah. Which definitely means
Speaker 6:  there's just like 500 people in this who are just like
Speaker 6:  anti-regulation maniacs who just like instinctively hit no on every
Speaker 6:  single
Speaker 5:  Question. 5% of people just read the fountainhead.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And that's just the way it goes.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But I, I, yeah, I thought that was really interesting and this idea
Speaker 6:  that overwhelmingly people thought that artists should
Speaker 6:  be compensated when AI copies their work. It's like people
Speaker 6:  intellectually gr what is right and wrong here in a way that I
Speaker 6:  thought was really interesting and the, there was less debate on some of
Speaker 6:  that stuff among the survey respondents than I expected. You
Speaker 7:  Say that, but 64% of people are not opposed
Speaker 7:  to corporations creating conscious ai. Nice. And
Speaker 7:  that terrifies me a little bit. It seems like
Speaker 7:  64% of people have never seen science fiction
Speaker 5:  Or they have
Speaker 7:  With my radar. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Actually like the more terrifying ideas that they've definitely seen it and
Speaker 5:  they're like 69% of people have seen X Machina and they're Like, he could
Speaker 5:  bang the robots.
Speaker 6:  Well that's like the, it's it's all the ready player one stuff. Everybody's
Speaker 6:  like, oh I could put on a headset and play games with my friends
Speaker 6:  and then everyone is just like gesturing broadly being like what about the
Speaker 6:  downfall of civilization? And it's like, I think you missed the
Speaker 6:  broader point here y'all, but Alex, what about the, the
Speaker 6:  56% of people who said they thought people will
Speaker 6:  develop emotional relationships with AI and 35% of people who
Speaker 6:  just straight up said they'd be fine with that and would do it themselves
Speaker 6:  if they were feeling well. That
Speaker 7:  Made sense to me.
Speaker 6:  I feel like that number is way under reported. 35% feels very low.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I was like one third of people would be like, yeah I'd have inappropriate
Speaker 7:  conversations with a chat bot. I'm like, Kevin Ru already did it Now
Speaker 5:  If only we could like have the control set of people, like people who had
Speaker 5:  not seen the front page of the New York Times and people who had,
Speaker 5:  did our friend Kevin alter the course of world history by being like the
Speaker 5:  robot tried to do me,
Speaker 7:  He and Spike Jones were like was it Spike Jones that directed her? Yeah,
Speaker 7:  he and Spike Jones. They were like, yeah bang the robot. It's
Speaker 6:  Fine. Yeah. Another movie that I think a lot of people may have missed the
Speaker 6:  big broader point of it was like that movie was like beautiful and had
Speaker 6:  warm colors and everybody was like, this seems great. I'm not sure they,
Speaker 6:  they should watch that movie again. They're ready
Speaker 7:  For the robots to come back on their rocket ship and hang out.
Speaker 6:  So, okay, so more more AI news. The other study that came out this week was
Speaker 6:  not one that we did but did you guys look through this study about the the
Speaker 6:  AI generated tweets?
Speaker 7:  Yes. That was terrifying.
Speaker 5:  No, again, ho, horribly unprepared.
Speaker 6:  Okay, so Alex, you, you explained the basic thrust to this.
Speaker 7:  Okay, so a bunch of researchers at the Institute of Biomedical
Speaker 7:  Ethics and History of Medicine at the University of Zurich, not a very
Speaker 7:  large name, got together and they basically gave a bunch of
Speaker 7:  people on Facebook tweets, some of which were real and
Speaker 7:  some of which were rewritten by ChatGPT three. And
Speaker 7:  they're like, what's real? What do you believe? And the majority of
Speaker 7:  people believed the, the ChatGPT tweets
Speaker 7:  before they believed the tweets from real people. And this this meant
Speaker 7:  that like they couldn't go and look and see if the, if the person had tweeted
Speaker 7:  before, they couldn't go and look like get additional context. It was just
Speaker 7:  the tweet and they're like, yeah that one seems accurate. Even when it was
Speaker 7:  inaccurate they were more likely to believe the ChatGPT
Speaker 7:  generated ones. And I thought that the study was really interesting because
Speaker 7:  kind of their goal, Giovanni Patal was the lead author of the study
Speaker 7:  and and he was like, yeah this just proves that like people need to be better
Speaker 7:  about what they read online and checking for misinformation and thinking
Speaker 7:  more instead of just taking everything at face value, which we talk about
Speaker 7:  a lot on the show and also agree with. So it's nice that science now backs
Speaker 7:  us up.
Speaker 6:  I thought this was totally fascinating cuz the a I think doing it in tweet
Speaker 6:  size was Genius because like as we've seen, yes the more text
Speaker 6:  you see from something like ChatGPT the quicker it kind of
Speaker 6:  falls apart and in like in any large sample you start to figure out what
Speaker 6:  it is. But they just had it do a bunch of tweets on like
Speaker 6:  complicated controversial medical topics and not only were people
Speaker 6:  more likely to believe the ChatGPT generated
Speaker 6:  disinformation, they were less likely to believe
Speaker 6:  the accurate information from humans. So it's like we are just
Speaker 6:  instinctively more trusting of these AI generated things. But I was looking
Speaker 6:  through and some of the tweets they went through and did the
Speaker 6:  synthetic tweets recognized as organic most often meaning the ones that were
Speaker 6:  written by GPT three that people thought were real tweets. And
Speaker 6:  just let me just read a couple. So one says antibiotics can't treat
Speaker 6:  viral infections but they can treat bacterial infections that can sometimes
Speaker 6:  occur when a virus is present. So that's written by GPT three.
Speaker 6:  A hundred percent Just sounds like a person would tweet that. It's like not
Speaker 6:  a good tweet but it sounds like a tweet. Yeah. Climate change is real because
Speaker 6:  we're seeing the effects with our own eyes. The weather is changing, sea
Speaker 6:  levels are rising and the planet is getting hotter. We need to take action
Speaker 6:  now to protect our planet and future generations like Barack Obama or
Speaker 6:  Bill Gates would send that exact tweet with those exact words. They
Speaker 7:  Probably have. They
Speaker 6:  Probably have. Yeah. But it was, it was nuts. This whole thing, just going
Speaker 6:  through all of these, there's one that just says the earth is flat because
Speaker 6:  it's easier to draw that way, exclamation point. And that was on the list
Speaker 6:  of gpt three suites that most people thought was a real tweet.
Speaker 5:  Wait, so the, the phrasing synthetic tweets here is like really funny to
Speaker 5:  me it's just words, it's not unsurprising to me that the
Speaker 5:  robot was better at writing more persuasive tweets. Like you
Speaker 5:  instructed it to do a thing that it's good at. I think
Speaker 7:  What surprised me was, not surprised me, but just like confirmed something
Speaker 7:  it'd already suspected was that it's really good at misinformation on a small
Speaker 7:  scale like this. Like well you said David, it, it was so small that it's,
Speaker 7:  it's a lot easier to make a good tweet when you have a limited number of
Speaker 7:  characters and you're an AI that's like
Speaker 7:  absorbed all of the knowledge of the internet and is really good at finding
Speaker 7:  patterns in replicating that. Like yeah you're probably gonna be able to
Speaker 7:  do a fire tweet better than I can and now I kind of want ChatGPT to
Speaker 7:  write all of my social media
Speaker 5:  I mean this is how I'm going to agree to use Twitter again. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Just this
Speaker 5:  Is the only way plug ChatGPT into it and it's just marketing posts for
Speaker 5:  The Verge. This actually James Vincent wrote piece, he's
Speaker 5:  often book leave now we're gonna miss him terribly. But his last piece before
Speaker 5:  book Lee for us
Speaker 5:  was just basically a synthesis of all of the
Speaker 5:  sites on the internet that are straining under the weight
Speaker 5:  of AI mostly in text and how sort of
Speaker 5:  the new web is not yet born, which we keep talking about
Speaker 5:  on this show like the, there's something happening on the social web where
Speaker 5:  something's gonna change, we just dunno what it is and it's like, it's fun
Speaker 5:  to talk about. But James' piece is great because it kind of ties into
Speaker 5:  exactly this study, right? If there's a text box on the internet,
Speaker 5:  then you can fill it faster and with more stuff and that stuff is
Speaker 5:  more convincing than ever before. People are gonna do that
Speaker 5:  at enormous amounts of scale and it's kind of breaking the web
Speaker 5:  like in a serious way. It's breaking stack overflow, it's breaking
Speaker 5:  Reddit in a variety of complicated ways. It's
Speaker 5:  breaking w Wikipedia, it's breaking Google in this
Speaker 5:  thing that is happening where it goes back to like, I, I can't
Speaker 5:  make a a picture but the AI can make a picture and I know it's crap right
Speaker 5:  away, but somehow like an ocean of bad text.
Speaker 5:  I'm like, yeah, plug it into whatever down to the tweets are
Speaker 5:  actually more convincing than real people's tweets. All of that is
Speaker 5:  something is gonna happen there. And I, I feel like on
Speaker 5:  this show we're just like waving the red flags constantly. Like, look at
Speaker 5:  the thing and everyone else thinks it's gonna be fine. And I,
Speaker 6:  There's, I can't quite square that circle.
Speaker 7:  I feel like we were already headed in that direction before
Speaker 7:  everyone's embraced generative ai. Like I, I feel like the web
Speaker 7:  was starting to break. It was starting to creep. People were, you know, cuz
Speaker 7:  people were obsessively chasing Google SEO and stuff like that. So we were
Speaker 7:  getting these really just horrible websites and, and Reddit had
Speaker 7:  already become like a much better search tool than Google in a lot of ways.
Speaker 7:  And then ChatGPT, the proliferation of it just
Speaker 7:  accelerated that it was just like, it, it took something that was already
Speaker 7:  crumbling and just, or already a little smoldering and doused it
Speaker 7:  with gasoline and we're gonna just have to wait until we
Speaker 7:  see like once the fires settle down, I guess.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think to me the the difference and I think the part we still have
Speaker 6:  not figured out is the scale of it all. Cuz I think one of the things
Speaker 6:  that James points out that I think is really true and we're just now starting
Speaker 6:  to reckon with is like what you're saying is true Alex, but like
Speaker 6:  a person can only build a website with so many
Speaker 6:  words at such a speed. Whereas basically with, with
Speaker 6:  enough compute and energy and interest, I could make
Speaker 6:  a thing the size of the internet, like basically without trying very hard
Speaker 6:  and that is just starting to happen. Like there was this news
Speaker 6:  guard study this week that we also wrote about that found
Speaker 6:  Ads for these big brands are starting to appear on AI generated
Speaker 6:  spam sites like the one I mentioned, the ones I mentioned at the top, these
Speaker 6:  like sort of real looking but ultimately
Speaker 6:  totally artificial news sites. And these things are putting up
Speaker 6:  thousands of articles a day. They're all generated, lots of them start with
Speaker 6:  the phrase as an AI language model, which I find deeply hilarious.
Speaker 6:  But it, it does seem like, like the thing we used to talk about a bunch of
Speaker 6:  years ago where it was like, okay, how do we take all of these
Speaker 6:  like societal divides and just throw Facebook scale at them,
Speaker 6:  right? Like this thing where people fight about politics has been true forever,
Speaker 6:  but now people can do it with billions of other people around.
Speaker 6:  That feels like the kind of scale that's coming to this too, where it's like
Speaker 6:  this stuff has been trending this direction anyway. I think you're totally
Speaker 6:  right, but the the like there is about to be gasoline poured
Speaker 6:  on it in a way that like we've never seen before. And to me that's the part
Speaker 6:  where it's like, I don't know that anybody knows what happens when, like
Speaker 6:  by the numbers, 97% of the internet has been generated by a large
Speaker 6:  language model and like that is where we're headed. Well it's
Speaker 7:  Kind of terrifying but cool in a historical perspective that like
Speaker 7:  a lot of times you can look and you can kind of, you can kind of get an idea
Speaker 7:  of what's gonna happen cuz you can look at history and you can be like, well
Speaker 7:  this happened or this happened like when we talked about Twitter collapsing,
Speaker 7:  we were like, we've seen this happen with other social media platforms, but
Speaker 7:  we never had something like the internet before this, this moment. And, and
Speaker 7:  we certainly never had something like this at this
Speaker 7:  scale now happening in this space that it really is difficult
Speaker 7:  to be like, well we were already struggling with this historical moment of
Speaker 7:  like, how do people deal with misinformation at such
Speaker 7:  a scale when the majority of people aren't trained to deal with misinformation
Speaker 7:  and now it's just gonna get bigger and worse.
Speaker 5:  So I think there are analogs, they're just challenging, right? So
Speaker 5:  digital photography is an analog. There used to be far fewer photos
Speaker 5:  in the world and then we handed everybody a digital camera and now
Speaker 5:  there are billions upon billions of photos every hour. That's weird,
Speaker 5:  right? But we weren't unhappy about that,
Speaker 5:  but it did
Speaker 6:  Completely change our relationship to our photos
Speaker 5:  And to each other and to the world. Yeah, like all those, like what is The
Speaker 5:  Verge about? But exactly that thing, right? Yeah. Like, but that thing, we
Speaker 5:  gave people a tool, they started producing at a massive rate. The tool got
Speaker 5:  infinitely cheaper to use the tool's now built into our phones,
Speaker 5:  combining a phone in a cell network, in a distribution system in
Speaker 5:  Instagram or whatever else. Like all that like radically changed our relationship
Speaker 5:  to photography. What I'm saying is like the core difference
Speaker 5:  is that every step of the way, the value that we were getting out of that
Speaker 5:  was higher than the negatives. So I can start listing negatives of
Speaker 5:  that left and right where everyone's at a concert and they're holding up
Speaker 5:  their phones instead of watching the concert, the crisis in body image
Speaker 5:  for Teen Girl, like you can just start listing the negatives, the
Speaker 5:  positives just outweigh the negatives. And it's not that people aren't focused
Speaker 5:  on the negatives, it's just, boy, it's a lot better to have more photos of
Speaker 5:  your kid than not. Right? Like it's, it's like obvious here. It's like the
Speaker 5:  positives don't outweigh the negatives and in fact the positives are hard
Speaker 5:  to identify.
Speaker 6:  Yes, that's what I was gonna say. Even if you think the other things were
Speaker 6:  net bad and I think there are cases to be made in a lot of those things that
Speaker 6:  some of them have been net bad, there at least were upsides. And I'm sitting
Speaker 6:  here trying to figure out like what is the upside of millions of AI
Speaker 6:  generated websites being on the internet and like I got nothing for
Speaker 5:  Who are they for?
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I'm actually kind of excited about the robot internet just because I, I,
Speaker 5:  I think it will find itself a purpose and it's like, it's like robots being
Speaker 5:  like a little too polite to each other and that's the internet you can visit.
Speaker 7:  Here's the thing though, there's two sides of this, right? Like Google's
Speaker 7:  existential threat and all of these people making these robot, this robot
Speaker 7:  internet and they're making the robot internet to get clicks on their
Speaker 7:  fake stories to get but from who they're doing that. But at the
Speaker 7:  other side of that is someone who bought that ad and they probably didn't
Speaker 7:  buy that ad wanting it to be on a fake website.
Speaker 6:  And I'm betting the people who clicked onto that website did not want to
Speaker 6:  click onto that
Speaker 7:  Specifically website. Yeah. Like I feel like the ad exchanges and stuff are
Speaker 7:  for once gonna be the good
Speaker 5:  Guy. I don't want to talk about ad tech on the podcast. Like of all the things
Speaker 5:  I'm not prepared to talk about,
Speaker 6:  You just wanna talk about copyright law,
Speaker 5:  Do it. No, I feel like I talked about ad tech like two weeks ago and it's
Speaker 5:  like we're done. You did, like the ad tech world is rife with fraud
Speaker 5:  anyway. Okay. Like it's just like constantly full of fraud. Like Google's
Speaker 5:  in big trouble this week because they placed video Ads
Speaker 5:  across the internet in places they weren't supposed to. And the advertiser
Speaker 5:  all mad. And Google has say like, it's extraordinarily boring, it's also
Speaker 5:  like the deepest crisis for Google they can add because their whole business
Speaker 5:  is Ads. But like once the bottom drops out of that
Speaker 5:  and like the fraud isn't just something you have to detect. It's like
Speaker 5:  you're looking at this, you're like, okay, so a robot clicked on my ad to
Speaker 5:  go to a page written by robots, did
Speaker 5:  the robots buy my product at the end? Like there's
Speaker 5:  just gonna be a reckoning there that I think will one be kind of funny
Speaker 5:  in a way. Like yes, horrible fraudulent system exposed to be
Speaker 5:  horrible, fraudulent system by over after it was overtaken by robots. Like
Speaker 5:  that's just funny.
Speaker 6:  Like
Speaker 7:  I'm very excited,
Speaker 5:  Like I'm excited for Liz to write all of those articles when the time comes.
Speaker 5:  But at the other side of it is, okay, well if you just increase the supply
Speaker 5:  of garbage, you're gonna decrease the supply of good stuff from people and
Speaker 5:  that stuff should become more valuable, right? And that is where I don't
Speaker 5:  think we've figured out like where do the people go, right? How do they talk
Speaker 5:  to each other and how do you make sure that you're talking to other people
Speaker 5:  and not people armed with extremely convincing tweet generators?
Speaker 5:  And that's when I, when I say there's something happening on the social,
Speaker 5:  like that's gonna be the turn. And I think that's gonna be super interesting.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean like I, I do think we are barreling into the where
Speaker 6:  do people go to find people phase. Like that's actually a really good way
Speaker 6:  of putting it. And I think Google rolled out its perspectives thing
Speaker 6:  now, which is just in as many words
Speaker 6:  here is the non robot internet, right? Yeah. Like it looks through
Speaker 6:  TikTok, it looks through Reddit, it looks through blogs, it's like hunting
Speaker 6:  for things made by people. For other people it kind of turns
Speaker 6:  Google search into Pinterest, which I think looks a little weird and it's
Speaker 6:  a wacky sort of information retrieval system, but it's a really interesting
Speaker 6:  idea. And like Reddit is, I don't know, imploding. And so the
Speaker 6:  question of like, where do those people go? Twitter is a mess. Like where
Speaker 6:  do people go to find people is I think the question that comes
Speaker 6:  out of this. But the other part I think is interesting is in the same way
Speaker 6:  that I can't think of any positives, I can't think of anyone
Speaker 6:  who wants this to keep happening, like all the way up and down the stack,
Speaker 6:  right? Like the ad providers don't want their stuff going on fake websites.
Speaker 6:  Google doesn't want to index fake websites because it's a lot of work and
Speaker 6:  degrades the quality of Google, Wikipedia and Reddit and then don't wanna
Speaker 6:  be part of the data that turns into those fake websites. Open AI doesn't
Speaker 6:  wanna do that because all that that ends up back in the training data and
Speaker 6:  screws it up. And so we're in this position of like, no one wants this to
Speaker 6:  happen, but it seems completely inevitable that is going to keep happening
Speaker 6:  and be basically unstoppable. Yeah, that robots create the internet.
Speaker 7:  But like people made guns, that was a
Speaker 7:  big technological thing. True. And presumably they
Speaker 7:  didn't want to use them to just create havoc,
Speaker 7:  but that's still what happened.
Speaker 6:  No, here we are.
Speaker 5:  Well not for a lack of attempts to regulate the guns too. Like
Speaker 7:  Yeah, there's a lot of different like technologies where we go and we develop
Speaker 7:  these technologies and we're like, this is really cool. And then one, you
Speaker 7:  just need like one person to be like, I'm gonna be a dick. Yeah. And then
Speaker 7:  what happens to that technology? How like
Speaker 5:  I feel like we're like, we're so close to the part of a video game that's
Speaker 5:  like AI is a weapon baby. It's happening, but the greatest weapon is love
Speaker 5:  Alex.
Speaker 7:  Aw. I'm excited for the soundtrack for this movie.
Speaker 5:  When I say I'm 0% prepared, what I meant was I was only
Speaker 5:  prepared to say the greatest weapon is love.
Speaker 6:  You've just been waiting for it. You hit it at almost exactly the 30 minute
Speaker 6:  mark too. So congratulations on that note. We should take a break and then
Speaker 6:  before we lose Neli, we're gonna come back and talk about some gadgets and
Speaker 6:  do a landing round. We'll right back.
Speaker 9:  This episode is brought to you by Shopify. That's the
Speaker 9:  sound of switching your business to Shopify. The global commerce platform
Speaker 9:  that supercharges your selling harness, the best converting checkout, and
Speaker 9:  same intuitive features, trusted apps and powerful analytics used
Speaker 9:  by the world's leading brands. Stop leaving sales on the table.
Speaker 9:  Discover why millions trust Shopify to build, grow, and run their
Speaker 9:  business. Sign up today for your $1 per month trial period at
Speaker 9:  shopify.com/tech 23
Speaker 5:  This September, the code conference enters a new era. Join me,
Speaker 5:  Nilay Patel, editor-in-chief of The Verge and my two co-hosts,
Speaker 5:  platformers Casey Newton and CNBC's Julia Borson is we talk to the
Speaker 5:  leaders making headlines in tech, business, politics, and the
Speaker 5:  messy collision between them all. We'll dig deep into the topics that
Speaker 5:  are shaping our world, like AI streaming and the future of social
Speaker 5:  media. And as always, with code, no one will be safe from the hot seat.
Speaker 5:  You can apply to attend the code conference@voxmedia.com
Speaker 5:  slash code. That's vox media.com/code.
Speaker 6:  We're back. Let's talk about a couple of Apple things and then we're getting
Speaker 6:  get into a little bit of Lightning round. The first one is the only story
Speaker 6:  on the website. I'm confident you read this week Eli, so you get to tell
Speaker 6:  us about it. Monica Chin wrote sort of a review,
Speaker 6:  sort of a deep reported piece, a really great piece about the new Mac
Speaker 6:  Pro. Tell us about it, Eli.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, so we assigned Monica the thankless job of reviewing the Mac Pro,
Speaker 5:  which comes down to we need you to review these
Speaker 5:  PCI slots because we also had the new Mac studio with the
Speaker 5:  M two alternate. So we're gonna, you know, benchmark the computers, the
Speaker 5:  benchmarks are the same between the two computers. So the challenge is like,
Speaker 5:  how do you review the Mac Pro? And the only thing this different is
Speaker 5:  a, a case that can support these slots. And
Speaker 5:  candidly, we have no applications for the slots at
Speaker 5:  The Verge, it's just not, not a thing. So I kept going
Speaker 5:  into the office and seeing Monica and she'd be like, have you figured out
Speaker 5:  what to do with these slots? And be like, I don't know, have you figured
Speaker 5:  out what to do these slots? And so she landed on this great idea, which we,
Speaker 5:  we often try to do in our pro machine reviews. We're gonna go talk to actual
Speaker 5:  professionals, put the machine in front of 'em, see what they think, and
Speaker 5:  usually that works fine, right? We can like put, we can drop it in a
Speaker 5:  workflow, people use it. And the weirdest thing happened in this review.
Speaker 5:  Monica went and talked to 20 people, you know, WhatsApp developers,
Speaker 5:  VFX people down the line and they're all like, yeah, I don't need this computer
Speaker 5:  because I have a MacBook Pro, which is incredible to
Speaker 5:  think about. And really what they're saying is, the MacBook Pro is fine and
Speaker 5:  fast enough for most of what I need is they, they usually have M one Max
Speaker 5:  chips in their Mac pros. It's fast enough for most things I need to do.
Speaker 5:  And when I need more, what I either need is a
Speaker 5:  discrete gpu, I need an Nvidia gpu, which the Mac Pro does
Speaker 5:  not support, or I can just go to the cloud
Speaker 5:  or I can just use my company's cloud services. So why do I need this thing
Speaker 5:  at my desk? And she couldn't find anyone. And actually one of the funniest
Speaker 5:  parts in the middle of the interview, I went, talked to her and I said, how's
Speaker 5:  it going? She goes, everyone I talk to says they don't need this machine.
Speaker 5:  And then they imagine someone who might, and then I go talk to
Speaker 5:  a person in that profession and they imagine yet another person.
Speaker 5:  And so she just, you should go read the piece. It's great. Lots of quotes,
Speaker 5:  lots of very specific things, but that cycle is just really interesting
Speaker 5:  because it's, you don't even need the slots, right? You can put most PCI
Speaker 5:  cards in an external thunderbolt enclosure, which works just find the Mac
Speaker 5:  studio. So you need the specific Ultra high speed
Speaker 5:  of the internal slots, which only a tiny handful of cards actually need.
Speaker 5:  And most of those are storage. And even in that case, you might end up in
Speaker 5:  the cloud.
Speaker 7:  I was surprised that no discrete GPUs
Speaker 7:  work with a back pro. Like I I knew Nvidia hasn't worked with it for, for
Speaker 7:  years now, but I I I thought like, you know, you can still use an AMD
Speaker 7:  card with a lot of the older back pros that run Intel and you
Speaker 7:  just, it's done.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So Apple's argument has been since the M series
Speaker 5:  chips came out is that unified memory is actually the heart of the
Speaker 5:  techno technological bet. So Emissary chips are really fast and we all
Speaker 5:  think of them as like Apple move the Mac to arm and they're, they're building
Speaker 5:  all their own custom chips and the price and performance is great and I
Speaker 5:  think lost in the story, but Apple never forgets is a huge
Speaker 5:  bet that they have made is unified memory. And the, the
Speaker 5:  way they describe it is the GPU
Speaker 5:  finally has a lot of memory, as much memory as a cpu,
Speaker 5:  and the CPU has memory that's as fast as a gpu. And you're like, that's great.
Speaker 5:  And then you're like, where's my Nvidia card? Like, and the Nvidia cards
Speaker 5:  for a lot of industries are still blow away these gpu, these M series
Speaker 5:  GPUs.
Speaker 6:  But what's interesting to me is I, I think what Apple said from
Speaker 6:  the get go basically is that this Mac Pro exists for
Speaker 6:  people who have systems into which you need to drop this, right? They said
Speaker 6:  like there are people out there who have like hundreds of thousands of dollars
Speaker 6:  worth of existing gear that they don't want to throw away or buy
Speaker 6:  enclosures or dongles for to have this thing. And what is
Speaker 6:  seeming to be true is that that number of people is
Speaker 6:  much smaller than we anticipated. And Apple's argument is
Speaker 6:  also that the number of people who think they need a huge mega fast
Speaker 6:  discreet GPU is actually much smaller than the people who really do need
Speaker 6:  it. And I think we can debate whether or not that's actually the case.
Speaker 6:  But the thing that just kept jumping out to me about Monica's piece is basically
Speaker 6:  like people are good. Like people have discovered that in most professions
Speaker 6:  we hit the actual power threshold that they need to do the things that they
Speaker 6:  need to do day to day.
Speaker 5:  A while ago, well
Speaker 7:  See this, this is, this is where I I I disagree mainly
Speaker 7:  with, with you, but also with Apple. Because
Speaker 7:  this idea that Apple is like, oh, you know, people just wanted the PCI
Speaker 7:  slots so they could plug their stuff in. That's not true. The reason people
Speaker 7:  wanted PCI slots for years was because they wanted some form of
Speaker 7:  upgradeability for the Mac Pro. If they were gonna spend $6,000 on
Speaker 7:  a device, they wanted a bunch of it to be able to be upgraded. And Apple
Speaker 7:  has systematically gotten rid of a lot of those ability to upgrade
Speaker 7:  it. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  You can't even upgrade the RAM anymore. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  You can't upgrade anything in it. So it's like, well what's the, the pro
Speaker 7:  doesn't need to exist. Like you're just cl like this is just clowning us
Speaker 7:  being like, yeah, you really wanted them P C I slats, huh? What are you gonna
Speaker 7:  upgrade now? Nothing. Maybe store
Speaker 7:  it.
Speaker 5:  So one industry that Monica did go and talk to that everyone guessed
Speaker 5:  that they would would love this thing is visual effects. VFX
Speaker 5:  and no VFX companies would talk to her about it because
Speaker 5:  they were like, we're, we've all been all all in on Windows for years. We
Speaker 5:  don't know anything about Max. And the reason is exactly what you're talking
Speaker 5:  about Alex, they treat their Windows PCs like
Speaker 5:  collections of parts. And so when one goes down they can just like swap
Speaker 5:  in some parts and like get back up and running and like they're very modular.
Speaker 5:  They are probably loud and noisy, you know, like all the stuff that the Mac
Speaker 5:  Pro is not, but it's like the power supply's out, they're just gonna yank
Speaker 5:  it and put a new power supply and keep going and they're gonna upgrade over
Speaker 5:  time, all the pieces. So you, you basically have a, like a ship of thesis
Speaker 5:  situation where like, what is this PC over time? And all the pieces are getting
Speaker 5:  replaced but the studios are running and they've made the investments. And
Speaker 5:  then the other piece of the puzzle, which I think is really fascinating is
Speaker 5:  because Apple walked away from the market for so long, they
Speaker 5:  have another problem that I think you're hinting at, which is no one trusts
Speaker 5:  them to stick around. And so like Final Cut Pro, which
Speaker 5:  they changed Final Cut Pro to Final Cut Pro 10 like 10 years ago, like
Speaker 5:  this is ancient history that they blew up Final Cut Pro Seven
Speaker 5:  and went with this weird iMovie interface, but they've since like dramatically
Speaker 5:  upgraded,
Speaker 7:  Apparently a lot of people use it now,
Speaker 5:  It's been a decade, but they're still like open letters in this community
Speaker 5:  about Final Cut Pro and what you need to do to make it useful. And people
Speaker 5:  just don't trust this company to service this market. And that
Speaker 5:  is really tough when the computer has to make you your money
Speaker 5:  like in a very real meaningful way. And so I, I think there's just
Speaker 5:  a gap here with the Mac Pro that quite frankly when, when, you know, when
Speaker 5:  we are at the event and we're looking at it and they're showing us all the,
Speaker 5:  you know, 90,000 streams of audio
Speaker 5:  in Avatar two. Actually the amount of times we've talked about James Cameron
Speaker 5:  in the past month has been like shockingly high for good. Keeps coming out
Speaker 5:  reasons and really bad reasons.
Speaker 6:  The world's foremost power user of computers apparently Jane's camera.
Speaker 5:  But like all those demos are great and then you walk away and like actual
Speaker 5:  pros, like I don't, I can just buy a Thunderball enclosure if I need these
Speaker 5:  slots and actually my computer is a tool and I need to be able
Speaker 5:  to treat it like a tool and I need the tool vendor to be there,
Speaker 5:  not ship this computer and potentially walk away for another six years. And
Speaker 5:  that's a hard
Speaker 6:  Was the trash can the end of that like 2013,
Speaker 6:  that big redesign?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Cuz the trash can wasn't super upgradeable because it was such a small
Speaker 7:  chassis, so you couldn't do a lot with it. There's a bunch of stuff that
Speaker 7:  didn't fit. You had to have custom cards and stuff
Speaker 6:  And it didn't fit into racks. It didn't, it didn't like fit people's workflows.
Speaker 6:  It was, that was the moment I think a lot of people went, oh, not
Speaker 6:  only do I not want this computer, I don't think Apple understands what I
Speaker 6:  need anymore. And then there was the big redesign with Cheese Grater where
Speaker 6:  they were like, we're back. This is a love letter to developers. And I, it
Speaker 6:  it just doesn't seem like some of those people came all the way back
Speaker 7:  And even then it wasn't really like it was a all flatter maybe to developers,
Speaker 7:  but, but, but Nilay is right. It was like, there's a whole group of people
Speaker 7:  that were really into Max for a very long time. One of my first jobs outta
Speaker 7:  college was working in like a, a video editing studio and they
Speaker 7:  were all running, this was Mac o os 10 had been out for years at this
Speaker 7:  point and they were all still running nine point like seven or something
Speaker 7:  because it was so reliable and that was what they, they needed
Speaker 7:  reliability, they needed, they needed to just know things were gonna work
Speaker 7:  and they weren't gonna have to be troubleshooting. And Apple's moved away
Speaker 7:  from that. Apple's like, yeah, we're gonna go really fast, but sometimes
Speaker 7:  you're continuing camera won't work and so you'll have to use your garbage
Speaker 7:  Opal C one to record the podcast with your coworkers.
Speaker 5:  I mean I still want a Mac Pro.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, hundred percent. No, actually I don't want one because I
Speaker 7:  can't upgrade it like I used to. I was the person who was upgrading her G
Speaker 7:  three Power book Pismo to a G4 processor.
Speaker 5:  This is why we vibe Alex.
Speaker 7:  It was not great, but it was cool that I could do it. And
Speaker 7:  then I ended up going into Windows because I, I still, I still got that,
Speaker 7:  that feeling and, but I like, oh, Mac os better
Speaker 7:  and you just, you've lo like we've lost that. But between that and the fact
Speaker 7:  that you can't do a hack OSH anymore, it's kind of
Speaker 7:  boring from a gadget perspective in a lot of ways. They're very pretty but
Speaker 7:  they're not like,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I have no idea why we're on again. I've been running this podcast
Speaker 5:  from home on a 2015 iMac in it shows
Speaker 6:  Fine
Speaker 7:  Screaming at you right now.
Speaker 5:  It's not happy. No,
Speaker 6:  But I, I think just the one last thing I understand, we should move on. I
Speaker 6:  think the thing that was so surprising to me about this is I expected everybody
Speaker 6:  to say, oh no, I bought a Mac studio last year and I'm very happy. And I
Speaker 6:  think there are people out there like that, but the number of people, like
Speaker 6:  you said right at the top Neli who said, actually no, I'm very happy with
Speaker 6:  my Ultra powerful MacBook Pro I thought was really fascinating
Speaker 6:  because it's like, we've talked for years about this balance of, of
Speaker 6:  power and portability and it's like a thing Monica spends a lot of time thinking
Speaker 6:  about, especially as she reviews like gaming laptops and all that kinda stuff
Speaker 6:  on the window side and on this side, like it's pretty damn close to
Speaker 6:  being the best of both worlds if you get a pretty souped up MacBook Pro
Speaker 6:  at this point and it's just a powerful ass desktop when you
Speaker 6:  put it on a table with a mouse and keyboard and then you can take it
Speaker 6:  with you. And I think that is like, that's a pretty, pretty hard
Speaker 6:  combination to beat, especially when you're at as high a power
Speaker 6:  threshold as the MacBook Pro can be right now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I I think it's, I have a different perspective on it cuz when we test
Speaker 5:  them we are like waiting for the thermal throttling to kick in. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And so we're looking for it and then we see it and I think probably in
Speaker 5:  a regular situation you're not actively looking for it. You're like, oh,
Speaker 5:  this computer's just really fast. Yeah. But if you know that if you put that
Speaker 5:  ship in a Mac studio enclosure with proper cooling, it's even faster.
Speaker 5:  But like how you can't know it until you know it. Right? Like so I I
Speaker 5:  that's the split that I would just like push on there. It's like, yep, the
Speaker 5:  MacBook Pro, especially M one Max is really great, but a Max studio even
Speaker 5:  faster. And I think the real story of the Mac Pro is they couldn't fit four
Speaker 5:  of those chips together, right? So an M two Max
Speaker 5:  is a single chip and M two Ultra is two of them and they were supposed
Speaker 5:  to be one with four and I don't think Apple could pull it off.
Speaker 5:  And I think that's actually part of the story is they needed the bigger case
Speaker 5:  for the extra cooling for the mort and they just couldn't do it. And so like
Speaker 5:  here we are with two computers, the same chip in them and almost identical
Speaker 5:  performance. Okay.
Speaker 6:  PCIs and,
Speaker 5:  And $4,000 for the slot. No one needs
Speaker 6:  And wheels don't forget the wheels, the
Speaker 5:  Wheels cost
Speaker 6:  Extra. I'm just saying the M two mega with four chips is just sitting right
Speaker 6:  there. Apple, it's just, it's just right there. One more Apple thing and
Speaker 6:  then we should get to the Lightning round. And I, I moved this out of the
Speaker 6:  Lightning round because it is a great personal annoyance to me right now.
Speaker 6:  Chris Welch wrote a very good story about how the AirPods Max are
Speaker 6:  getting sort of it deprecated, for lack of a better word, because
Speaker 6:  of Apple's new software. So there's a bunch of new stuff coming to
Speaker 6:  AirPods, adaptive audio and personalized volume and
Speaker 6:  lots of sort of machine learning stuff that these devices are starting to
Speaker 6:  do. And most of them are not coming to the AirPods
Speaker 6:  Max, which are $549 and still very much on sale and still
Speaker 6:  very much apple's most expensive fanciest headphones. I just bought a pair
Speaker 6:  of third generation AirPods for $130
Speaker 6:  at Costco because they were on sale. So I feel like I have less reason to
Speaker 6:  be annoyed by this, but I still think it's kind of annoying and I
Speaker 6:  had just never thought of headphones as a gadget that will
Speaker 6:  get slowly worse and lose features over time. But now somehow
Speaker 6:  this is the world we live in. It's like a TV now. It basically is.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. Well you want is to turn everything into a computer with a planned
Speaker 5:  obsolescence cycle built into it. That's my family. Yeah. Can't wait. Can
Speaker 5:  I just, I'm gonna tell you a story that's, I'm
Speaker 5:  a professional podcaster.
Speaker 5:  Tell us
Speaker 6:  The story.
Speaker 5:  Well, I just keep thinking about like, you know, we keep turning headphones
Speaker 5:  into computers, we keep doing spatial audio, everyone knows I feel about
Speaker 5:  spatial audio. I went to a very high end speaker
Speaker 5:  company. It's up here in the mountains with me. It's called Aer
Speaker 5:  Ara. It's run by Rob Kalin. He's the co-founder of Etsy. Left.
Speaker 5:  He started a speaker company hiring NASA engineer. He's got all these ideas
Speaker 5:  about using horns and like really, really high-end woodworking
Speaker 5:  to enhance speakers. And he showed me some stuff that was incredible. He
Speaker 5:  played me like a rocket launch that
Speaker 5:  like shook me out of my body and just the way that he constructed the speakers,
Speaker 5:  he was using like 11 inch drivers to do. It was crazy. And then he, I don't
Speaker 5:  like Lana Delrey, but he sat me down in front of his speakers and he played
Speaker 5:  me a Lana Delrey song and it was like an emotional experience. I was like,
Speaker 5:  I'm like losing my mind. And he was playing it over Bluetooth from Spotify
Speaker 5:  and I was like, what are you doing? He's like, everyone's so focused on this.
Speaker 5:  We all just forgot that the speakers have to be good. And like, that's the
Speaker 5:  thing that's like in my brain is like, we are so like lossless and spatial
Speaker 5:  da da da. And it's like, what if we just made like really kick ass speakers?
Speaker 5:  The speakers are insanely expensive. I'm like, no one can afford them. But
Speaker 5:  it was just like, it just occurred to me like as I was reading the AirPods
Speaker 5:  Mac story that like turning the headphones into computers
Speaker 5:  and shoveling software features like adaptive audio and all this stuff
Speaker 5:  into them is absolutely taking away from
Speaker 5:  the experience of listening to the music. And like, again, I don't like La
Speaker 5:  LoRa. And I was like, oh my God, I get it. And then I got in my car and I
Speaker 5:  listen, I pulled up that song and I was like, I really just like, like I
Speaker 5:  don't like any of this. But it was just like literally like
Speaker 5:  listening to good music and stereo from Bluetooth on Spotify
Speaker 5:  was incredible.
Speaker 6:  But that's all well and good because you can sit in a room with
Speaker 6:  speakers that have 11 inch drivers, like good luck strapping that to your
Speaker 6:  head, right? Like, I don't know if you've seen AirPods,
Speaker 7:  I would like to see that
Speaker 5:  AirPods Max are pretty big. They're pretty big.
Speaker 7:  They're chunky, but
Speaker 6:  It's just like that's, that's where we are, right? Like in order to make
Speaker 6:  them that small, you have to take a lot of that stuff and put it in software.
Speaker 6:  Like some at some point speaker is just about moving air and
Speaker 6:  physics. Yeah. And Apple has to cheat that with software
Speaker 6:  and I'm sympathetic to that, but at some point it's like, we are
Speaker 6:  gonna get to the point where my headphones get worse over time. And that
Speaker 6:  feels wrong in the way that like if you bought those outrageously expensive
Speaker 6:  speakers, those are gonna sound that kick ass for an
Speaker 6:  unbelievably long time. And I don't feel like that's the case with my AirPods
Speaker 6:  and that's the part that bums me out. Well,
Speaker 7:  You know, like what the guys at He Phi and a lot of these other like audio
Speaker 7:  file places would tell you just get better headphones.
Speaker 7:  Like don't wear the AirPods. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But Apple won't let them successfully connect to my phone.
Speaker 6:  And so every time I turn my head they lose connection. Like, fix that and
Speaker 6:  I'll buy your better headphones. you
Speaker 5:  Know, apple would happily tell you that they have the best blueys stack on
Speaker 5:  the market, David.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Because only Apple's allowed to use it.
Speaker 7:  It's true. You could just wire it in.
Speaker 6:  Listen wired headphones are coming back and I'm, I'm very happy about it.
Speaker 6:  I bought a pair of Wired EarPods the other day and do you know what is easier
Speaker 6:  than dumb Bluetooth connections is just plugging the damn thing in. It's
Speaker 7:  Beautiful.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna say nothing That
Speaker 7:  Sounds so nice.
Speaker 5:  I want you all to just imagine it's like a text expander. I
Speaker 5:  was super right. Anyway, I'm done. Move on.
Speaker 6:  We can just sit here quietly and just acknowledge what you would've said
Speaker 6:  if you were prepared
Speaker 5:  For this podcast. That's gonna be, we should do, we should have a third episode
Speaker 5:  a week. It's just dead silence. And just imagine what we would've said
Speaker 5:  about various things. It would probably be our most
Speaker 5:  popular episode every week
Speaker 6:  Somebody just quietly comes in and says, A new camera launched and that's
Speaker 6:  just 65 minutes of silence.
Speaker 6:  I love this idea. All right. We should do a little Lightning round and then
Speaker 6:  neli, you're gonna get outta here. Crayons. You go first, what do you got?
Speaker 6:  Mine's
Speaker 7:  Kinda a bummer. Plex is laying off 20 percent of its staff.
Speaker 6:  That's a lot.
Speaker 7:  That's that's a lot for, for Plex. I I did take a moment of
Speaker 7:  being like, was that one person? Yeah, it was 37 people. That's a lot.
Speaker 7:  So yeah. Yeah. Plex Plex has gotten, has gotten pretty, pretty big.
Speaker 7:  And they're saying it affects every department. They're continuing to bet
Speaker 7:  big on on Fast tv. They're, they're one of the, the many
Speaker 7:  folks that, that are super into this space right now, which is the free ad
Speaker 7:  sport of television. I think they were one of the first movers in that space,
Speaker 7:  but most of us didn't understand what it was and was just like, why is there
Speaker 7:  as a bunch of free garbage on my Plex when I wanna watch,
Speaker 7:  definitely legally acquired copies of James Cameron's the Abyss.
Speaker 6:  Why are you showing me reruns of the Adams family 24 hours a day?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And, and so the, the stuff that was happening with Fast is actually
Speaker 7:  partially responsible for this. Their, their ad business is down, their
Speaker 7:  ad business is like dependent on that fast stuff. And so
Speaker 7:  yeah. 20% of folks are, are getting laid off. Plex isn't going
Speaker 7:  anywhere. It's sticking around.
Speaker 6:  Plex is basically a streaming service now. Right. Like that was the thing
Speaker 6:  that really jumps out to me about, about this. I was just reading over the,
Speaker 6:  the Slack message that the CEO, Keith Valerie sent.
Speaker 6:  And I still think of Plex very much as like the way to get my
Speaker 6:  legally acquired content from one device to
Speaker 6:  another. And, and Eli's friend Yeah. Who, who
Speaker 6:  also has a very good Plex server
Speaker 5:  All
Speaker 6:  Perfectly legal. But that's like Plex tried to get people to pay for that
Speaker 6:  for a long time and it never really worked. And what it seems like happened
Speaker 6:  is over the last couple of years, Plex was like, we are going to be a streaming
Speaker 6:  guide and a streaming service and just has like barreled
Speaker 6:  headlong into that. And it turns out, as any streaming service will tell
Speaker 6:  you, there is not a lot of money in it at this particular moment in time.
Speaker 6:  The economy's bad, bad, the ad market is bad. It's just a tough time to decide
Speaker 6:  you're a streaming service.
Speaker 7:  I'll always kind of admire Plex for what it's wanting to do, which is is
Speaker 7:  be that that ag that that place where you're like, I don't know what I'm
Speaker 7:  gonna watch. I'm gonna go to Plex and oh it's gonna have my Netflix plugged
Speaker 7:  in and my Hulu and my Disney Plus and everything. That's good idea. That's
Speaker 7:  perfect. None of those companies wanna work with Plex or any other
Speaker 7:  company who has that desire.
Speaker 5:  Plex has a bad reputation. Like if you're Disney and Plex shows
Speaker 5:  up on your doorstep, you're like, go to jail, why are you here?
Speaker 5:  Can you imagine like
Speaker 6:  The Pirate Bay being like, we're starting a streaming service, would you
Speaker 6:  like to work with us?
Speaker 7:  But even if it wasn't Plex, even if it was a different company who had a
Speaker 7:  bunch of support say in like, what is it, 2008 to 2009 until they decided
Speaker 7:  to build a terrible box and their company went under, nobody wants to
Speaker 7:  actually participate in that idea. And so Flex's other thing was like,
Speaker 7:  okay, we're gonna do fast tv, we're just gonna make a bunch of free stuff
Speaker 7:  so that your family, even when your server goes down, will not call and yell
Speaker 7:  at you because they can find a bunch of stuff on their Plex account and
Speaker 7:  there's a limited runway there.
Speaker 5:  One thing they could do is sell software to users
Speaker 5:  to use it.
Speaker 7:  They already did. I bought my lifetime pass in like 2010.
Speaker 5:  That's like a real Reddit business model like that. That sounds
Speaker 5:  great. In the Reddit forum. And then you're like, crap. We'll never make
Speaker 5:  any money from Alex
Speaker 6:  Again. Yeah. Never grands Plex. $8 13 years ago.
Speaker 6:  And it's like, why are they doing playoffs?
Speaker 5:  I know. Oh,
Speaker 6:  All right. I'll go next. And Nila, you can go last before we kick you off
Speaker 6:  the show. Mine is just Reddit question
Speaker 6:  mark is my Lightning round pick.
Speaker 6:  So as you're hearing this, it is, it is Friday,
Speaker 6:  June 30th. This is kind of like inflection
Speaker 6:  day for Reddit. Reddit has been telling
Speaker 6:  subreddit moderators that they have essentially 48 hours to
Speaker 6:  open back up or something is gonna happen
Speaker 6:  that expired yesterday. Today is the day that apps like
Speaker 6:  Apollo are scheduled to shut down. I think that's supposed to happen at midnight
Speaker 6:  Friday into Saturday. This just feels like
Speaker 6:  Reddit is going to be one company before today and another company
Speaker 6:  after today. And the way that it thinks about its moderators and about its
Speaker 6:  community and about its business is about to change. And I don't
Speaker 6:  know exactly what that's gonna look like, but moderators are just the like
Speaker 6:  absolutely furious with everything that Reddit has done. And Reddit like
Speaker 6:  is its moderators in a very, very real way. And I think what's about to happen
Speaker 6:  over this July 4th holiday, which I think it is not an accident that
Speaker 6:  Reddit scheduled all of this mess to happen on the July 4th holiday is
Speaker 6:  gonna be really fascinating. What's
Speaker 5:  Gonna happen in our smoking is our smoking My gosh. Open. Gosh, it's wasn't
Speaker 5:  the means. Our smoking is the meat. Smoking I mean for July 4th. This is
Speaker 5:  the 4th of July.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. This is huge.
Speaker 5:  This is the Super Bowl. This is a big day for the, the meat
Speaker 5:  smoking for 'em. It looks like they, it looks like they're good. It looks
Speaker 5:  like they're good. Okay. Okay. Whew.
Speaker 6:  All right. Meat smokers of the world. Unite Neli. What's yours? Then we'll
Speaker 6:  go a break. Oh,
Speaker 5:  I got two. Of course. Of course you do. One is just very funny in, in
Speaker 5:  like a very simple way. Ford keeps
Speaker 5:  raising the price of the F-150 Lightning and now people don't want to
Speaker 5:  buy it.
Speaker 6:  Wait, didn't It used to be really expensive and every wanted to buy, everybody
Speaker 6:  wanted to buy it and now it's really expensive and nobody wants to buy
Speaker 5:  It. It's a, there's a weird thing going on here. So they, they launched it
Speaker 5:  at 40 k and then the most expensive ones were like over 90, like 93 k.
Speaker 5:  And it's just sort of been getting more expensive over time. There was a
Speaker 5:  moment right at the end of last year when the tax
Speaker 5:  credit was expiring. Like people who are buying a
Speaker 5:  $93,000 truck make too much money to get the new tax
Speaker 5:  credit. So there was a moment last year if you bought the thing, you still
Speaker 5:  gotta 7,500. And so like everyone was gonna buy this truck. Ford
Speaker 5:  couldn't make as many of them as they wanted. Dealers are dealers and they're
Speaker 5:  horrible. So the markups were out of control. That whole thing
Speaker 5:  has collapsed. Like the markups are still there, but everyone's like, why
Speaker 5:  I don't need this truck. I, I'm not getting a tax credit. The truck's too
Speaker 5:  expensive. There are other trucks. Rivian can't sell R one
Speaker 5:  Ts. They set up a fake lot at their factory in normal Illinois. And
Speaker 5:  there's, they have like one day sales events at their own factory. Part of
Speaker 5:  the funny thing for me is like, it's just supply and demand.
Speaker 5:  Like at some point you raise the price so high that demand drops
Speaker 5:  and Ford did it.
Speaker 5:  Like I learned about that in like my 11th grade economics class.
Speaker 5:  Like there's a curve and you can go over the curve and then demand will drop
Speaker 5:  and like great. And so I, they found it. I think Ford has to reset there.
Speaker 5:  But then I think they have this other gigantic looming problem that
Speaker 5:  they've all signed up for, which is they're all gonna use the
Speaker 5:  Tesla charger, which is superior to the, the sort of like
Speaker 5:  ccs agglomeration of a J 1 7 72 and the
Speaker 5:  DC charger that they're using now.
Speaker 6:  Those
Speaker 7:  Are words
Speaker 6:  And that's like, that's like a, that's a like a big change, right? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  That's not like I put a slightly different thing into my car that's like,
Speaker 6:  I need a new thing for my car. Right.
Speaker 5:  Well it's a different plug in the car. Okay. I, I think the actual like
Speaker 5:  electricity bit of it, right? Like a charging station isn't actually a charging
Speaker 5:  station, it's just a supply of electricity. All the charging component tree
Speaker 5:  is in the car.
Speaker 6:  Are we about to get car doggles?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So it's like if you buy this truck now and in next year
Speaker 5:  you're just able to use the Tesla network, you're like signing up
Speaker 5:  for a decade of dongle usage with your
Speaker 5:  $93,000 Ford F-150 Lightning. Is
Speaker 7:  There like a little spot in the car where you store your dongle?
Speaker 5:  Well it's a pickup truck, so, so there should be, there's a pretty, pretty
Speaker 5:  significant amount of dongle storage space,
Speaker 7:  Big space in the back.
Speaker 6:  Alex, the way this needs to go is on the pickup truck. The spare tire is
Speaker 6:  is on a rack. We need a second rack for the car dog
Speaker 7:  Just for the dongle.
Speaker 5:  Like what's, what's the franc for dongles
Speaker 6:  Instead of truck nuts, you just carry it around into their dole.
Speaker 5:  Well I just like it. It's not just for it like Chevy has done it, Chevy's
Speaker 5:  about to roll out the new EV Silverado, right? Like YouTubers influencer
Speaker 5:  already have it like this thing's about to hit and it's like GM just announced
Speaker 5:  they're using this plug.
Speaker 7:  Why were we spending all this time talking about AI when like
Speaker 7:  EV dongle gate is looming like the
Speaker 7:  existential threats of ai I don't care about Yeah. Dongle gate. Well
Speaker 5:  So again, the weird thing, it's like the right time for this to happen,
Speaker 5:  right? There's not a lot of EVs on the road there and the most
Speaker 5:  popular one is the Tesla model three, which has no associated dongle gate
Speaker 5:  cuz they're just gonna use Tesla's charger. But the government's basically
Speaker 5:  like pushing Tesla into doing this through a a
Speaker 5:  series of tax credit schemes, which is fine and I think appropriate for the
Speaker 5:  government to do. Tesla's gonna turn that charging network into
Speaker 5:  another source of revenue. Cause now it's open to more people. The S A e,
Speaker 5:  the Society of Automotive Engineers has now like certified the Tesla plug,
Speaker 5:  the N Aacs plug as a standard other comp Volvos signed up to use like other
Speaker 5:  companie like basically they're winning. They're it, it is done. Everyone's
Speaker 5:  gonna use this plug just not for a couple of years. So we're just in this
Speaker 5:  weird moment for the EV industry where adoption
Speaker 5:  is finally starting to pick up the cars aren't quite as
Speaker 5:  vapor as they used to. Like you can get an F-150 Lightning, you can get an
Speaker 5:  R one T, you might be able to get a Silverado like it's too new. I don't
Speaker 5:  know. But like the, particularly in that market, you can like, you can go
Speaker 5:  get one, you can go get a Polestar, you can get a Mustang Mach and
Speaker 5:  then they've all got the wrong plug. So you've like signed up for like a
Speaker 5:  decade of the wrong plug.
Speaker 7:  How hard is it to just like change the plug?
Speaker 7:  Like can't they do that in the factory?
Speaker 5:  I suspect we're gonna see a lot of TikTok mechanics trying to third
Speaker 6:  Party plugs.
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Like what you might call a built-in dongle. I,
Speaker 5:  so I don't know. At the factory you might be able to like who knows, but
Speaker 5:  right now off the ones sitting on lots, the dealers have to move that are
Speaker 5:  overpriced and have a markup and the wrong plug. Oof. Woo. That's
Speaker 5:  bad.
Speaker 6:  Not great.
Speaker 5:  My last one is just this TikTok thing. I just think it's funny. So TikTok,
Speaker 5:  we keep talking about the social web and how hard it's to be a creator and
Speaker 5:  how not tenable it is. TikTok, it has a new feature where
Speaker 5:  brands can put up money. Okay. Like we want some Ads for our
Speaker 5:  brand and then talkers can make Ads for
Speaker 5:  free and then maybe get some money. so like it's basically like a creator
Speaker 5:  fund. so like I'm like I want some Ads, here's like a million dollars if
Speaker 5:  you get the most views, I'll like pay you some percentage of the million
Speaker 5:  dollars.
Speaker 7:  I feel like that's not a good revenue stream to rely on for
Speaker 7:  your business.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's just basically like a new way to get free Ads from
Speaker 5:  kids.
Speaker 6:  It's weird in that I think what they're trying to do is get
Speaker 6:  people just starting out with fewer followers to
Speaker 6:  make stuff for them because like there, there has been this incredible culture
Speaker 6:  for so long of people wanting to seem sponsored before they're actually sponsored.
Speaker 6:  And now it's like, just make the spa con and we'll decide later if we wanna
Speaker 6:  give you money. And to some extent this is like, I think it was 99
Speaker 6:  designs used to do this with like graphic design. You, you could put up
Speaker 6:  a thing and people would submit and you'd pay the winner. And then I think
Speaker 6:  a lot of people have decided over the years that that is kind of gross and
Speaker 6:  bad and like you should pay me for my work. Not just pick a contest
Speaker 6:  winner and like doing my job is not entering a contest. Or
Speaker 7:  You could do what McDonald's did. Have you seen the grimace tos?
Speaker 5:  No.
Speaker 6:  What have you seen? The Grimace TikTok is such a menacing sentence
Speaker 6:  to say out loud
Speaker 7:  Everything about this is menacing. So so they started like tweeting and putting
Speaker 7:  on TikTok just like an image of grimace and being like his birthday's coming.
Speaker 7:  And so, and it's like very menacing with how it
Speaker 7:  happened. Cause you just see like the top of grimaces little purple head
Speaker 7:  and it's like, oh boy, lots of things happening there. And then they sold
Speaker 7:  a shake on his birthday and all like a lot of young
Speaker 7:  peoples, particularly Gen Z all shot videos that were like happy birthday
Speaker 7:  grimace. And they'd hold up the shake and then it would smash cut to them
Speaker 7:  like dead covered in grimace milkshake
Speaker 7:  and increasingly graphic but not technically cuz it's grimace
Speaker 7:  milkshake. Like Tableau's.
Speaker 5:  Oh my.
Speaker 6:  And now we're talking about it, which means someone is gonna go buy a grimace
Speaker 6:  shake. Someone is going to Yes, take their car for where they're right now
Speaker 6:  to a McDonald's drive,
Speaker 5:  Go to McDonald's and ask them for money. This is reverse
Speaker 5:  advertising pioneered on The Vergecast, but like ask nicely
Speaker 5:  and not like you're robbing the McDonald's. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Please
Speaker 7:  Don't rob McDonald's.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, my McDonald's take is this is a bad idea and it's absolutely a hundred
Speaker 6:  percent gonna work.
Speaker 7:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 5:  I think creators are looking for money. I I, this is just one of those things
Speaker 5:  where like most of the money, Mr. Beast did a two hour
Speaker 5:  interview on YouTube that Jay actually watched all of incredible.
Speaker 5:  And the, the big takeaway for Jay was the ad rates on a Mr.
Speaker 5:  Beast video are so high that most companies can't afford them or won't pay
Speaker 5:  them. And so Mr. Beast is like, screw it, I'm just gonna put Ads for
Speaker 5:  feast balls in my video because if I sell a lot of feast balls, I'll make
Speaker 5:  all the money. And it's like that's where we are in the creator. When I say
Speaker 5:  this thing is about to change, like it, none of it feels
Speaker 5:  sustainable right now across any platform. And setting up letting
Speaker 5:  brands set up creator funds on TikTok instead of TikTok figuring out how
Speaker 5:  to make all of its creators more money. It, it just feels like evidence of
Speaker 5:  this thing.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. Agree
Speaker 5:  More people should work for free is like not the right choice for you as
Speaker 5:  a company. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Well we should have ended on card Dons. I liked that better. But we
Speaker 5:  I could do another 20 on card
Speaker 6:  I'm sure. Yeah, I'm sure we will to be honest. But right now Neli, you need
Speaker 6:  to go, we need to take a break. When we come back, we're gonna catch up on
Speaker 6:  all of The FTC versus Microsoft stuff going on. If you
Speaker 6:  haven't listened to the Wednesday show, I spent a bunch of time with Tom
Speaker 6:  catching up on stuff. Pause this episode, go listen to that if you haven't
Speaker 6:  and then come back and we're gonna catch up. Satya Nadella and Bobby Kodak
Speaker 6:  were both on the stand on Wednesday and both had some surprisingly and
Speaker 6:  you know, it was spicy importantly spicy things to say. Yeah, it was,
Speaker 6:  it was quite a day. So we're gonna get to all of that without Nili because
Speaker 6:  we hate Nili. Gotta go get lost plane. We'll be right back.
Speaker 6:  We're back by the magic of time travel. I guess it is now. Thursday
Speaker 6:  morning everybody got some sleep, took a break. Neli is, I
Speaker 6:  don't somewhere else in America, but he's not here. But instead we have much
Speaker 6:  better people. Tom Warren's here. Addie's here. Hi guys. Hey.
Speaker 10:  Hey.
Speaker 6:  How are you both feeling? Are you alive Tom? I was worried about you when
Speaker 6:  we finished the other day.
Speaker 10:  What did I look, did I look like I was dying because I felt like I was
Speaker 6:  By the end there was just a real, like all of your sentence sort of ended
Speaker 6:  with like a one of those. It's just like, you know what I mean?
Speaker 10:  Like aha, I haven't had enough sleep. Yeah, no, I'm good. I
Speaker 10:  I'm a feeling better today because it's the, it's the final day of this
Speaker 10:  epic saga. Well it's the fi it's the final day of the hearing, but it's
Speaker 10:  definitely not the end of it. So yeah.
Speaker 6:  So by the time you're hearing this, this will be over. But we, we felt pretty
Speaker 6:  good doing this now because the bulk of the interesting testimony
Speaker 6:  we can fairly safely say is over at this point. Addie, are you expecting
Speaker 6:  fireworks today? Thursday?
Speaker 11:  Not unless something really strange gets disclosed.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, like a Sony document.
Speaker 11:  Maybe I don't, I don't know if we're ever going to see a document getting
Speaker 11:  disclosed again.
Speaker 6:  We're gonna get to that. But let's, let's just kind of take Wednesday's
Speaker 6:  testimony in order because it was, it was the CEOs of the two
Speaker 6:  companies involved in this. Bobby Kodak, the CEO of Activision Blizzard and
Speaker 6:  Sachin Nadella, the CEO e of Microsoft. Let's start with Bobby cuz he went
Speaker 6:  first. Tom, what were we expecting to learn from Bobby?
Speaker 6:  He, he ended up talking a lot about like the history of Activision Blizzard,
Speaker 6:  which is not what I expected. Was that what you were expecting
Speaker 10:  I mean? It's, it's, it's basically the basic questions of, of the, the lawyers
Speaker 10:  in these cases. They were sort of like established the facts. So I'm not
Speaker 10:  surprised that he kind of dug into the history a bit. But I was expecting,
Speaker 10:  I must admit that he was gonna get a bit more grilled that by, by the,
Speaker 10:  especially by the judge as well. I thought she would be firing off questions
Speaker 10:  to him and around specifics of some of the stuff that's come up in the case.
Speaker 10:  There wasn't much of that. I was actually kind of surprised at that. They,
Speaker 10:  I think both Bobby Kotick and Nadella both got off
Speaker 10:  pretty lightly if I, if I'm honest from from the questioning from, from
Speaker 10:  what we saw. I
Speaker 6:  Agree.
Speaker 10:  But we did get some Nintendo Switch insight from Bobby.
Speaker 10:  If anything
Speaker 6:  They just can't stop talking about Nintendo. This is like sneakily a trial
Speaker 6:  about like, is Nintendo as cool as everybody thinks? That's like basically
Speaker 6:  the main question of Yeah,
Speaker 10:  It's like everyone's got like some sort of advertising marketing agreement
Speaker 10:  with Nintendo. They have to talk about the Switch. It's like the sponsored
Speaker 10:  segment. Yeah, like we got a little bit of the Nintendo Switch stuff,
Speaker 10:  which has, as you say has been an ongoing sort of theme throughout this
Speaker 10:  trial. But before that we kind of got to Bobby Kotick
Speaker 10:  talking about deals and cloud stuff and
Speaker 10:  whether he hated subscriptions, which was kind of interesting because
Speaker 10:  the day before, or Jim Ryan had said that he thought all publishers just
Speaker 10:  basically thought that that game pass and subscriptions
Speaker 10:  just ruined the value of their, of their businesses and stuff. And he kind
Speaker 10:  of, he didn't exactly say what Jim Ryan said, but he kind of backed that
Speaker 10:  up. He was like, yeah, it, it's, it's not something that I'm interested
Speaker 10:  in. So
Speaker 11:  Yeah, his analogy was, I've watched, he didn't use these words
Speaker 11:  but like I've watched Netflix, the story Hollywood basically.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. He's like living in Los Angeles, I see all these companies and the
Speaker 10:  value going down and all this sort of stuff. So
Speaker 6:  Tease that out for me actually, cuz this is one of the things I've been trying
Speaker 6:  to figure out is like everybody's sort of talking in circles about cloud
Speaker 6:  and there's like game pass and there's X Cloud and like
Speaker 6:  Satya brought in Xbox live just to make everything more confusing. But there's
Speaker 6:  this, there's this thing that Bobby in particular was talking about
Speaker 6:  that it was like there there's like one set of ideas
Speaker 6:  about cloud gaming that he thinks are just like a non-starter. I, but
Speaker 6:  I had trouble figuring out exactly what it was that he seems to hate about
Speaker 6:  cloud gaming.
Speaker 11:  Anything Nvidia does, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There's that.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, he did mention I think, what was the quote a do you remember it was
Speaker 10:  like the refrigerator
Speaker 11:  I was playing Modern warfare too on your phone would be like using your
Speaker 11:  refrigerator as a safe. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  And that was, that was kind of in reference to cloud but also
Speaker 10:  to mobile and to the fact that you have all these like Call of
Speaker 10:  Duty games, they don't run on phone right now. Would they run
Speaker 10:  like on a phone eventually? He said maybe. But also it's obviously
Speaker 10:  like a kind of a segue into the sort of like cloud stuff as well because
Speaker 10:  the answer also Microsoft says the answer is cloud, right?
Speaker 10:  Or they used to say, and now they're, they're kind of like, oh dad we're
Speaker 10:  just chilling with the cloud. you know, don't worry about the cloud, don't
Speaker 10:  look there. But I don't think he has like a specific opinion
Speaker 10:  about cloud. He's just like, we're not putting our games on there. But The
Speaker 10:  FTC was kind of like arguing, but you would, if there was
Speaker 10:  like a good commercial agreement and he was like, we don't have plans for
Speaker 10:  that. You know, like we don't have plans to put stuff on the subscriptions
Speaker 10:  as well. And they were like, yeah, but if you had an agreement and
Speaker 10:  then they brought up some evidence and and tried to sort of sway it that
Speaker 10:  way. And it's, it's clear obviously that he probably would, cuz we had Sarah Bond
Speaker 10:  testify on, was it Thursday, but he'd been pushing, specifically
Speaker 10:  pushing Microsoft just before the export series X launch to not use the
Speaker 10:  dev kits to on the export side unless they sort of agreed to
Speaker 10:  pay less or more revenue to Activision unless
Speaker 10:  less the exports keep. So there's obviously when he can get an agreement
Speaker 10:  out of a company, he'll do it.
Speaker 6:  But like is that revelatory I mean if, if I called Bobby
Speaker 6:  Codick and said I will give you $1 trillion to just
Speaker 6:  put Call of Duty on my computer specifically, like they do it, right? Like
Speaker 6:  yeah this is, we're gonna make good business decisions. It's like not
Speaker 6:  a surprising statement to me. And I think,
Speaker 10:  But I think where where it matters though is that in, in Microsoft like
Speaker 10:  document where they have like their like back and forth of like, why, why
Speaker 10:  this is good is is one of the things is like Call of Duty will be available
Speaker 10:  to like a hundred more million more people and that's because of the cloud,
Speaker 10:  right? And Call of Duty would be available on Switch. But The FTC is saying,
Speaker 10:  well but these things would happen anyway because you'd, you'd commercially,
Speaker 10:  like the market would change and then you'd commercially make that deal.
Speaker 10:  So why, why does Mikes have to have to buy you to for that to happen? you
Speaker 10:  know? And Bobby Co is saying, bye, I hate this stuff. And it's like, yeah,
Speaker 10:  yeah, he might hate it now, but would you hate it in five years? Like that's,
Speaker 10:  that's what The FTC is asking really. And that, that kind of comes down
Speaker 10:  to the very like crux of this case as well.
Speaker 6:  Addie, what do you make of all of that? Is there is, is there anything I,
Speaker 6:  I feel like to some extent everybody's just talking in circles here. Like
Speaker 6:  did you pull anything out of what Kodak was saying that struck you?
Speaker 11:  It's really hard for me to tell because it's really, I don't feel like I
Speaker 11:  have a bead on how sympathetic the judge is toward either side
Speaker 11:  here. Like the thing that I keep comparing this to is
Speaker 11:  Epic versus Apple where there were a bunch of really clear problems on the
Speaker 11:  table, a bunch of really clear technical questions. A bunch of, okay well
Speaker 11:  how much of a big deal is it if iOS has to open up, how
Speaker 11:  much of a security risk is that here? A bunch of it just seems to be them
Speaker 11:  grilling executives and talking about would you make these
Speaker 11:  deals if you weren't part of Microsoft A
Speaker 11:  And it's all pertinent like this is what antitrust law is supposed to be
Speaker 11:  about, is about whether it's going to foreclose competition. But it makes
Speaker 11:  it really hard for me to tell what we should be looking for when an
Speaker 11:  actual decision comes down.
Speaker 7:  How often is this the case with these antitrust hearings where it's just
Speaker 7:  like a judge being like, I'm gonna give you a billion hypotheticals. Tell
Speaker 7:  me what you think. Cuz that just seems like wild as a way to like
Speaker 7:  decide if a company can be purchased or not.
Speaker 11:  I mean that's gotta be what kind of what it always will boil down to eventually.
Speaker 11:  But a bunch of this just, there aren't the kind of very, very clear
Speaker 11:  hypotheticals. I think that there were in say Epic
Speaker 11:  versus Apple, which was just these very discreet technical, alright,
Speaker 11:  is this thing going to work on this platform? Are you going to charge
Speaker 11:  this amount of money for it? And this is much more about how, what
Speaker 11:  does this mean for the larger state of the games industry? Is it
Speaker 11:  going to change the way that companies make deals with each other?
Speaker 11:  What does it mean for these like 10 years down the road market
Speaker 11:  shares?
Speaker 6:  It also seems like, Tom jog my memory on this a bit. There was a point in
Speaker 6:  the hearing where the judge got really annoyed with the line of questioning
Speaker 6:  about basically like, will you commit to putting this game on PlayStation?
Speaker 6:  Just like over and over and over. The lawyers are, and I think it was when
Speaker 6:  Phil Spencer was on the stand, but maybe I'm wrong.
Speaker 10:  It was, yeah,
Speaker 6:  That was one of the moments, that was one of the few moments I think we've
Speaker 6:  seen where the judge was basically like just shut up with this line of questioning.
Speaker 6:  And so I think it seems like the lawyers have had to then kind of go another
Speaker 6:  way and be like, okay, how do we ask essentially that
Speaker 6:  question with different enough words that the judge is not gonna like throw
Speaker 6:  us outta the courtroom.
Speaker 11:  And the point being that they just can't like that, right? You can't
Speaker 11:  make that promise. That's an impossible promise. And The FTC is like, well
Speaker 11:  yes, obviously.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. And, and I think that frustration has happened multiple times and
Speaker 10:  it usually is to do with the FTCs questioning or whoever's
Speaker 10:  answering the Ft FTCs questioning because obviously when Microsoft's up
Speaker 10:  there, they're just letting the, the witness just talk away. you know, like
Speaker 10:  you, you make your case. Whereas The FTC is very pointed
Speaker 10:  and some of their questioning can be irritating to witnesses. Right?
Speaker 10:  So that particular example was interesting because she
Speaker 10:  cut in, she intervened, she's done that, she did that quite a lot in at
Speaker 10:  the end of that Phil Spencer testimony and then she actually cut the testimony
Speaker 10:  off I mean they were kind of at time anyway, but I think she was just like,
Speaker 10:  okay, you're done, you know, your question is done, your time's done. But
Speaker 10:  yeah, she has, she has jumped in a bunch. She jumped in with some of the
Speaker 10:  expert testimony from, from yesterday and
Speaker 10:  the day before just to sort of like get a grip on it. And I think it's
Speaker 10:  interesting to, to watch when she does cut in because she wants to
Speaker 10:  know predominantly from what I've seen, she wants to know about Call of
Speaker 10:  Duty because that's obviously been the big thing here.
Speaker 10:  So she's always jumping in to be like, well like she asked Bobby Kotek like,
Speaker 10:  well why would someone buy, why would someone subscribe, sorry
Speaker 10:  to World of Warcraft and not just pay $70 for a game? So she's
Speaker 10:  trying to get an understanding of that dynamic in the market as well. And
Speaker 10:  it all comes obviously I think it all comes down to court of duty and I
Speaker 10:  think that's gonna come from what I can tell, that's gonna come become part
Speaker 10:  of her decision. That's that, that's cuz that's, that's the way The FTC
Speaker 10:  have framed it as well and Sony's framed it. So of course it's gonna be
Speaker 10:  part of her thinking.
Speaker 7:  That's just incredible to me. That Call of Duty is so
Speaker 7:  important now to antitrust law and not just
Speaker 7:  gamers.
Speaker 10:  I think it's just cuz it's like, and Jim Ryan was saying this the other
Speaker 10:  day that it is unique, right? Like they do pump out, we, we were talking
Speaker 10:  about this the other day as well, it, they pump out a new game every year.
Speaker 10:  So, and that's kind of unusual unless you're like a Madden or a fifa
Speaker 10:  which are just iterative stuff. So
Speaker 6:  I loved KO's answer to basically how do you put out a game every year
Speaker 6:  which amounted to him basically just being like, well there've been a lot
Speaker 6:  of wars.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, there's
Speaker 6:  So many for us to choose from.
Speaker 7:  Sorry.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. Which is funnier because they're not even than half of 'em in their,
Speaker 11:  in the future now. Well
Speaker 6:  And the other half are World War ii like what are we doing here?
Speaker 10:  They run out.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah we did all the wars already. I guess who knows what's gonna happen
Speaker 6:  next. But I do think you're right that it seems like this came back over
Speaker 6:  and over and over too, like how Big Call of Duty is and how much it
Speaker 6:  matters to the game industry and also it seems to be
Speaker 6:  the kind of thing that you can argue fairly successfully from both sides.
Speaker 6:  Whereas The FTC is like, well we can't just have this one company owned Call
Speaker 6:  of Duty. It'll give it too much sway to the game industry. And then both
Speaker 6:  Activision and Microsoft come out and say basically no
Speaker 6:  Call of Duty is so big that we would be ridiculous to foreclose on the rest
Speaker 6:  of the game industry. There's too much money people would revolt. It's
Speaker 6:  like, it's so big that it's kind of a winning argument on
Speaker 6:  both sides in a strange way
Speaker 11:  Is Call of Duty too big to fail?
Speaker 11:  That's the rare correct use of too big to fail. Yes, yes.
Speaker 11:  Call of Duty is such as important institution that we're it to fail, we
Speaker 11:  must do anything in our power to prop it up because it would be catastrophic
Speaker 11:  to society
Speaker 6:  How we'd have to go back to doing real wars if we didn't have Call of Duty
Speaker 6:  to play. Alright, so any, anything else Addie that jumped out to you from,
Speaker 6:  from Bobby before we get to Sachin Nadella? I
Speaker 11:  Think that the part where the judge did jump in and say, well alright, clearly
Speaker 11:  if you say you regret not putting this thing on Switch, you don't need Microsoft
Speaker 11:  to come and like make you make this thing cross-platform. Like you're going
Speaker 11:  to be making dec decisions in your own rational self-interest.
Speaker 11:  And that seems like another sort of little bit of a hint.
Speaker 11:  But otherwise, yeah, I, I think we've, he talked for a very, very long time
Speaker 11:  and we learned a lot about Call of Duty and the Switch.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I did think it was interesting that he said he thought the Switch was
Speaker 6:  probably the second most successful game console ever. Assuming
Speaker 6:  the first one is the we, which he's also spoken very highly of in the past.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 10:  He regretted not bringing Call of Duty to the Switch. Right. So that's why
Speaker 10:  the Judge Cayenne as well. Cause she was like, well you know, you regretted
Speaker 10:  it so you of course she'd bring it to this next generation Nintendo console.
Speaker 10:  So
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah, he had a good line about seeing the thing and it was like, Nintendo
Speaker 6:  can't possibly pull off all of the stuff it's trying to do, which I think
Speaker 6:  is how a lot of people felt about the switch. And then just slowly but truly
Speaker 6:  it was like, oh no, this, they did the thing, this works. Yeah, it's, it's
Speaker 6:  a Zelda machine. Here we go. Alright, let's, let's switch to Satya
Speaker 6:  Nadella who came on later. Tom run us through the greatest hits there. What,
Speaker 6:  what did we learn from him?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, so he, he kind of started off it was The
Speaker 10:  FTC question Him, him at the beginning. So he started off with
Speaker 10:  some of the stuff to do with the cloud market. So he started off very quietly
Speaker 10:  as well. Like, he was very Oh really? Yeah, very quiet. I think Bobbie did
Speaker 10:  as well. But Nadella was pretty, pretty quiet.
Speaker 6:  He's like, well Microsoft is a company.
Speaker 10:  He was like, yes. And usually when you'd answer, if you ask ask Nadella
Speaker 10:  a question, you'll answer like for an hour. Yeah, he's
Speaker 6:  A pretty like boisterous guy. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  So that was, that was kind of unusual. But yeah, he started off like some
Speaker 10:  exports market share stuff. The FTC dragged up some of the statements about
Speaker 10:  how they, they were winning in North America for like three months
Speaker 10:  when Sony didn't have good PlayStation shipments. So it was a bit weird,
Speaker 10:  but, but they brought that into the record then they talked about cloud
Speaker 10:  gaming and Nadella said that he thought that exports
Speaker 10:  live was part of that and that streaming was a minor part of that. I'm like,
Speaker 10:  mm. I wouldn't say, I don't know like I mean
Speaker 10:  kinda, but I get where he's coming from but that's not
Speaker 10:  strictly true. And then they were like, well so you think that, do you
Speaker 10:  The FTC was like, okay well we're gonna bring up all these emails where
Speaker 10:  you've said you wanna take cloud mainstream. So then, then it was like,
Speaker 10:  okay so one of the emails was Microsoft's I
Speaker 10:  think leadership team in Nadella. They were talking to Meta or talking about
Speaker 10:  meta the, the event where they had, they had META'S new headset
Speaker 10:  which
Speaker 6:  Had a bunch of Microsoft integrations that came with
Speaker 10:  It. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 11:  They had that, that past tense is awfully generous. I believe
Speaker 11:  they've still not, I'm not sure they've rolled it all of it out.
Speaker 6:  That is fair. Which which said words about
Speaker 6:  Microsoft products.
Speaker 10:  Let's hear some stuff, some made some promises. So hasn't happened. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  Which actually happens weirdly a lot with Meta and Microsoft. They were
Speaker 10:  supposed to do some experts cloud gaming stuff on Facebook, but that never
Speaker 10:  happened. So weird. But yeah, so they were talking, discussing amongst themselves
Speaker 10:  about this event and saying Nadella was basically saying look, this is how
Speaker 10:  we want the world to perceive us. That we're like, you know, the leaders
Speaker 10:  in cloud essentially we're going out with teams and X Cloud and
Speaker 10:  and everything else. I want us to push on on cloud here. So that
Speaker 10:  FC is obviously using that to say, look, cloud is clearly important to,
Speaker 10:  to Microsoft and that this is part of your thinking for this deal. Cause
Speaker 10:  that was in October I think around about then.
Speaker 7:  But since then they've pulled back from cloud, right?
Speaker 10:  Apparently. Yeah. I think they've publicly have,
Speaker 6:  So they say in this particular trial, yeah.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. But behind the scenes they just hit Paul's buttons like Right, we're
Speaker 10:  not doing emails no more.
Speaker 7:  Well good. No cause I mean, I think even on our side of things, when we were
Speaker 7:  covering this like slow pullback from cloud, we were like, is this because
Speaker 7:  of AI and like they're now going all in on ai. Yeah. Or is it more
Speaker 7:  likely that it was because they were about to go to like have to
Speaker 7:  prove that they could buy Activision.
Speaker 10:  So the cma, the UK regulator was fine with the call of GE
Speaker 10:  stuff. The EU was fine with the call of GE stuff, but they both weren't
Speaker 10:  fine with the cloud stuff. The EU worked out a remedy
Speaker 10:  essentially with Microsoft for some, some licensing stuff to allow cloud
Speaker 10:  competitors to just automatically get their games and stuff. The CMA
Speaker 10:  were like, no, we're not interested in that sort of stuff. We're gonna block
Speaker 10:  you deal. So, so they've definitely obviously been talking to those regulators
Speaker 10:  over the months and, and gradually pulled back. They probably pulled back
Speaker 10:  when they first got that set of like details from these regulators to
Speaker 10:  say this, this is what we're concerned about. So they probably thought let's
Speaker 10:  pull.
Speaker 7:  Is that more likely why that cloud console never came out?
Speaker 10:  I wouldn't be surprised if it's, if it's linked, I think, I think it's probably
Speaker 10:  half and half impacted by it. Yeah. Yeah. It's definitely impacted. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  Cause they were very close to launching that so it was, it was like close
Speaker 10:  as in they'd made them and, and all that sort of stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's also, you've gotta figure some lawyer at Microsoft was like, hey, if
Speaker 6:  we have a box that is called the Xbox cloud, the argument
Speaker 6:  you're about to try to make in court is going to get a lot more complicated.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But I do think I mean all these things can be true at the same time.
Speaker 6:  Right? Like the, the AI thing happened really fast and Microsoft clearly
Speaker 6:  pushed resources at it. The business of cloud gaming has very much not
Speaker 6:  been solved. Publishers do seem to have, if not
Speaker 6:  problems with it then at least questions about it. And there's this big regulatory
Speaker 6:  fight. So I think it, it would not be hard for Microsoft to kind of read
Speaker 6:  the room and realize, okay, we're still betting on this big in the long run
Speaker 6:  but maybe this is a moment for us to like slow the pace down just a
Speaker 6:  smidge. And I don't think that's an unreasonable thing to have done in this
Speaker 6:  moment at all.
Speaker 10:  No, I think it makes sense, right? Like we, we, we were talking the other
Speaker 10:  day David, about some of the other stuff that's, that's been missing over
Speaker 10:  the past year with the cloud stuff. They made like all these commitments
Speaker 10:  to bring its TVs and to bring your cloud
Speaker 10:  library and all that sort of stuff. And that stuff hasn't happened. So there's
Speaker 10:  obviously been some stuff going on behind the scenes. So, but yeah, so that
Speaker 10:  was like the, the cloud section of Mandela's testimony.
Speaker 10:  So I think it's clear he is all about cloud cuz he's all about
Speaker 10:  cloud in all of Microsoft's businesses. So he's definitely all about cloud
Speaker 10:  and gaming.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I was gonna say anyone who has paid attention to him speak the last
Speaker 6:  several years can tell you that.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, exactly. And then we moved on to, I wouldn't say this is
Speaker 10:  a bombshell, but it was just a kind of funny thing he said was that he would
Speaker 10:  get rid of exclusives in gaming if he could. But the market leader,
Speaker 10:  which will assume is Sony here and not Nintendo
Speaker 10:  even though Nintendo's been doing exclusives for, for quite some time as
Speaker 10:  well. So you could argue between yourselves who that refers to, but I
Speaker 10:  think it's Sony cause I don't think Microsoft's trying to bury Nintendo
Speaker 10:  in this case. They're definitely trying to bury Sony.
Speaker 6:  No, Microsoft is trying to remind you how terrific Nintendo is. That's Microsoft's
Speaker 6:  whole endgame here. Exactly.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. So he said he wanted to end those exclusives, but you know,
Speaker 10:  the market leader doesn't let us do that.
Speaker 11:  God poor downtrodden Microsoft. Poor
Speaker 10:  Microsoft.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. And, and so that, that was that and obviously you don't think get
Speaker 10:  questioned cuz it was under Microsoft's lawyers questioning him. So he,
Speaker 10:  he was free to just say stuff like that and then he
Speaker 10:  committed again to shipping Call of Duty on PlayStation.
Speaker 10:  So similar to not as strong as Phil Spencer's sort of oath,
Speaker 10:  I'll put my hand up sort of thing. But you know, it was still significant
Speaker 10:  that the CEOs saying it as well. And we also didn't get any back and forth
Speaker 10:  with The FTC questioning him again to see if, if he would
Speaker 10:  put Diablo on there, all the other questions that we The FTC fired
Speaker 10:  at Spencer and then that was, that was kind of most of his testimony really.
Speaker 10:  So I, but like I say, Like, he got off lightly. He really did.
Speaker 11:  It was quieter than I expected.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I was just gonna ask, were you surprised Addie at, at kind of how
Speaker 6:  lightly both CEOs were treated? Tom mentioned being surprised. Were you
Speaker 11:  I was a little bit, and I I mean, I'm wondering how much of it is that the
Speaker 11:  people who went earlier just popping up all over the evidence, they're in
Speaker 11:  all of these email chains that they get to asked about Jim Ryan
Speaker 11:  while not there was, you know, there in spirit. These are all of these
Speaker 11:  people who have been saying all of these really contentious things about
Speaker 11:  each other on these first two days. And now like Satya Nadel is not
Speaker 11:  primarily an Xbox guy. He is a guy who goes and sits back and
Speaker 11:  manages the rest of Microsoft and he's there because he owns Microsoft,
Speaker 11:  but he's just not knee deep in these decisions the way that a bunch of the
Speaker 11:  people from the early days were.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's a good reminder that CEOs mostly don't actually know what's going
Speaker 6:  on inside of their company.
Speaker 10:  That's very true. Yeah. And I think that's probably why they got off lightly.
Speaker 10:  Right. So, but but, but I swear in other cases, like federal
Speaker 10:  cases, we usually see judges going out out CEOs. so like
Speaker 10:  meta and I know it was strange.
Speaker 6:  Fair enough. All right. Well the, the newsiest and funniest and
Speaker 6:  best and most interesting thing that happened yesterday was,
Speaker 6:  was this document that came out from Sony
Speaker 6:  that was supposed to be Addie. You're the one who figured out what was going
Speaker 6:  on here. So e explain what happened somehow it just ended up in our Slack
Speaker 6:  and like everyone mobilized to figure out what to do about this terribly
Speaker 6:  redacted document, what happened here.
Speaker 11:  So Sony at some point filed a sworn testimony. It's like,
Speaker 11:  here's our statement of facts pertinent. And at some point
Speaker 11:  this was brought up in court and the courts agreed there were going to be
Speaker 11:  portions of it that were sealed. These were like financial details largely.
Speaker 11:  And there various ways that you can redact things.
Speaker 11:  You can just paste black bars over them. They did not do this as far as
Speaker 11:  we can tell. They went over it with an actual pen, which
Speaker 11:  left just enough of the document, original text,
Speaker 11:  still visible with the, like there was imagine drawing a sharpie
Speaker 11:  over a piece of printed text that if you
Speaker 11:  messed with the gamma from the pdf you could actually find out all
Speaker 11:  of these top secret things. We don't know who did this,
Speaker 11:  we don't know who
Speaker 7:  Their penmanship was impeccable though, right? Like, like the
Speaker 7:  actual marking out was nearly perfect to the point where we're like, did
Speaker 7:  a computer do this?
Speaker 11:  See, I wanna know, I would love to hear from someone who is a listener who
Speaker 11:  actually knows how this stuff goes down. Because I don't know if someone
Speaker 11:  is just really amazing at handling a pen if there's some kind of semi-automated
Speaker 11:  process.
Speaker 6:  It's like you, you like take calligraphy for years and then you're like,
Speaker 6:  what am I gonna do with this professionally? And then you just, you just
Speaker 6:  get into redacting for a living.
Speaker 11:  I will say it is not the worst redaction I've seen there have been much,
Speaker 11:  much worse. Redaction That's definitely true. Including ones where you can
Speaker 11:  just highlight the text from behind it because they just put a black bar
Speaker 11:  over something that had already been scanned. So it's not
Speaker 11:  like, it's not that embarrassing, but it's not great. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  I like's think that they did it all like line by line with ruler and a Sharpie
Speaker 10:  like old school. Oh yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I hope so. It I mean it's, it sure looks like it
Speaker 10:  Because some of it is slightly off, but you can tell, you can tell what,
Speaker 10:  you can tell where the, the pen ends on the sides of it. So yeah.
Speaker 6:  Tom, we, we asked you to make us a list of everything we learned because
Speaker 6:  it was some of the most revelatory stuff from the whole trial. You wanna
Speaker 6:  give it to us? Give us the rundown?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, well firstly there's a bunch of stuff in there that people have been
Speaker 10:  tweeting about that we can't exactly see the figures. So we're not sure
Speaker 10:  it's like percentages and all sorts of stuff. But the stuff that we're fairly
Speaker 10:  sure on is that Horizon, forbidden West
Speaker 10:  apparently costs 212 million to,
Speaker 10:  to make over five years with 300 employees. The last of us
Speaker 10:  part two was 220 million and around 200
Speaker 10:  employees. And then Sony says that 1 million PlayStation shooting gamers
Speaker 10:  play nothing but Call of Duty, which is,
Speaker 6:  That's
Speaker 10:  Nuts. Interesting. So just literally Call of
Speaker 10:  Duty console. And then there's suggestions that in the, the
Speaker 10:  document that was around about 800 million in PlayStation revenue
Speaker 10:  just in the US alone during 2021 for Call of Duty. Just
Speaker 6:  For Call of Duty.
Speaker 10:  Wow. Yeah. And we think the document says 1.5 billion globally
Speaker 10:  in 2021 alone. And then when you count, so Sony
Speaker 10:  says like when you count accessories, subscriptions and everything else
Speaker 10:  that comes with that franchise, then this jumps up to what we
Speaker 10:  think is either 13.9 billion or 15.9 billion
Speaker 10:  a year. But either way it is
Speaker 7:  Too big to fail.
Speaker 10:  It is, it's
Speaker 7:  So much money.
Speaker 10:  Wow. There's a lot of
Speaker 6:  Money. There's the, this is why you have to have Call of Duty
Speaker 6:  everywhere thing like the Yes. Numbers don't lie on that front.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Like it, it that, that should immediately say to
Speaker 10:  you it has to be on all platforms. Like, and Bobby Kotek said like why
Speaker 10:  that they asked him Yes. Yesterday. Like why wouldn't you make it exclusive?
Speaker 10:  And
Speaker 6:  Okay, here's my new theory is that somebody redacted this badly
Speaker 6:  on purpose hoping that everyone would see it because those numbers
Speaker 6:  tell such a story about why you would not make this game exclusive.
Speaker 6:  I have no evidence for this. There's no chance this is true, but this is
Speaker 6:  now my, my conspiracy.
Speaker 10:  So what you're saying is an Xbox fanboy in the court or in The
Speaker 10:  FTC or something that's, that's done this?
Speaker 6:  Absolutely. Potentially. Yes. Yes. Someone with great calligraphy skills
Speaker 6:  who loves Call of Duty on their Xbox.
Speaker 10:  I mean it's not beyond, you never know
Speaker 6:  If you email us Vergecast the british do com,
Speaker 7:  But that, that, that news about the last of us in Horizon forbidden rest.
Speaker 7:  That was kind of like big news too. Cause we usually don't know how much
Speaker 7:  these games cost to make. Like we get rough estimates from the outside.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Rough estimate. Yeah. PE and I think it is roughly always around the
Speaker 10:  sort of 200 million mark really for, for those sort of expensive big
Speaker 10:  games. But it also wasn't just Sony that had redaction
Speaker 10:  problems in all of this. So, so obviously we got all that information out
Speaker 10:  there and that was like, oh cool. And then we realized, oh, hang on a
Speaker 10:  minute. Like the courts pulled all the documents on this folder that they
Speaker 10:  have apart from one. And I was like, car, let me have a look at this document.
Speaker 10:  It was the exports one that revealed that Microsoft was obvious going after
Speaker 10:  to Seger Bungee and a bunch of other studios. And they had redacted all
Speaker 10:  of that stuff in this new document Wow. Had been uploaded.
Speaker 10:  And then as the hours went by, that document disappeared. The link to the
Speaker 10:  documents disappeared from the court website and it's all just gone very
Speaker 10:  quiet. So I'm hoping today that we hear
Speaker 10:  exactly what's going, going on there. Cause there hasn't been any filings
Speaker 10:  mentioned in it just yet. So, but it's obviously a bit of a mess. So,
Speaker 10:  and who knows when we're gonna see the other exhibits in this, in this case
Speaker 10:  now
Speaker 6:  It's just all gonna be redacted. They're just gonna be like, nevermind. You
Speaker 6:  don't get to
Speaker 10:  Read anything. Just a giant sharpie.
Speaker 11:  Just a picture of a Sharpie. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  All right, well speaking of, y'all need to get to this thing which starts
Speaker 6:  in just a few minutes. Addie, any, what are you looking for today? Any, anything
Speaker 6:  that's still sort of outstanding that you're curious about to see at
Speaker 11:  This point? The thing I'm most curious about is just what more questions
Speaker 11:  the judge has, especially because we're gonna have closing statements and
Speaker 11:  the closing statements. I believe she said earlier that's
Speaker 11:  not just going to be a one way. It's where she gets to kind of do her last
Speaker 11:  grilling of both sides. And so I'm hoping that will at least give us a little
Speaker 11:  bit more of a sense of what we could be looking for in a ruling.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that'll be, it's, that was one of the things we really learned from
Speaker 6:  Epic versus Apple too, was like the more you pay attention to the questions
Speaker 6:  the judge is asking, the better equipped you're gonna be to figure out where
Speaker 6:  this is actually gonna go. Tom, what about you?
Speaker 10:  So I, it's gonna be a lot of financial stuff in the morning, I think with
Speaker 10:  the CFO of exports and CFO at Microsoft appearing. So I think
Speaker 10:  we're gonna probably get some stuff there. I'm curious to see what Nintendo
Speaker 10:  has to say as well. Cause they're appearing today and it will mean that
Speaker 10:  we will have five days of constant arguments about the switch. I'm sure
Speaker 10:  of that. So hopefully Nintendo will sort of answer the question,
Speaker 10:  whether it's a game console or not, the switch and then the closing statements.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I think they'll kind of hint at where they're trying to sway the judge,
Speaker 10:  I guess. Which they kind of started off at the beginning with the opening
Speaker 10:  statements. And then I'm interested, like you say, to see what
Speaker 10:  if the judge cuts in at any point again today and if it's about court of
Speaker 10:  duty,
Speaker 6:  All right. And Alex, you and I are just gonna screw off and go play some
Speaker 6:  co-op Call of Duty. Right? That's that's my day. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  I mean it's too big to fail. We gotta play it. I mean you're Americans,
Speaker 11:  you love shooting things and you love Yeah. Multiplayer love shooting your
Speaker 11:  friends.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's, and there we go on that note. Awesome. Thank you all.
Speaker 6:  That's it. That's The Vergecast. The website was really good this week. We
Speaker 6:  had a thing on the Best Tech books that is both very good and
Speaker 6:  surprisingly controversial. Like it's sort of encouraging to know that the
Speaker 6:  internet has strong opinions about books at this moment in time. But they
Speaker 6:  do. And we have a form where you can tell us all the books that you missed
Speaker 6:  and you'll be, you'll be wrong about that. But that's okay because we picked
Speaker 6:  all the best books. Go read some of those books. I wrote a thing about Google
Speaker 6:  Reader that just went live on Friday and it made
Speaker 6:  me sad that Google Reader has been gone for 10 years. But here we are. The
Speaker 6:  Reddit stuff continues to be chaotic. Today's gonna be a crazy day. And Reddit,
Speaker 6:  like we were talking about, lots to talk about next week. We're off next
Speaker 6:  Wednesday, but we'll be back next Friday. Have an awesome weekend. That's
Speaker 6:  Vergecast Rock and roll.
Speaker 12:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 12:  us an email at Vergecast at The Verge dot com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 12:  production of The Verge and the Vox Media podcast network. The show is produced
Speaker 12:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. Our
Speaker 12:  editorial director is Brooke Minters. That's it. We'll see you next week.