# Transcript
ID: 3c9593a0-b28a-11ed-ae04-43d9e92daa0e
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Solo Acts: Raluca Pop, founder of Hive Social
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6871875157024828157/8216485279392187672/s93290-US-2293s-1677054229.mp3
Description: This is episode one of our Vergecast mini-series "Solo Acts", which features people who are working independently to create great things on the internet, hosted by Ashley Esqueda.
Today, Ashley talks with Raluca Pop, founder of the social media app Hive Social, which was created when Raluca was only 19. Ashley and Raluca discuss the challenges of building a social media app from scratch in the world of Big Tech, what happens when you need to address problem like a mass influx of users and security issues, and working with such a small team.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (3 ads detected)
Speaker ?:  Welcome to the Verge Cast, the flagship podcast of
Speaker ?:  Twitter competitors. I'm your friend Alex Kranz. And today
Speaker ?:  we're starting a mini-series called Solo Acts, which will feature interviews
Speaker ?:  from people who work independently to create great things on the internet.
Speaker ?:  Most of the time we talk about tech in terms of a handful of big gigantic
Speaker ?:  companies like Meta, Twitter, Netflix, all of those
Speaker ?:  guys. But some of the most interesting stuff we find online is the product
Speaker ?:  of a single person. Sometimes even in their spare time in this series,
Speaker ?:  we'll get to know these people, the tech they use to get stuff done and the
Speaker ?:  obstacles they face trying to compete with the Giants. So for the next five
Speaker ?:  Mondays on the Vergecast, our friend Ashley Escada will be curating
Speaker ?:  and hosting these interviews and sharing with us what she's learned. Hello
Speaker ?:  Ashley. I have to learn something You've hopefully learned. I'm
Speaker ?:  gonna be learning stuff. I feel like you've learned a lot. I have. I really
Speaker ?:  have. These people are all so fascinating and delightful. Really.
Speaker ?:  You've Done a, a bunch of these interviews so far today. We're talking
Speaker ?:  to, you're talking to the folks at Hive? Yes, I am talking
Speaker ?:  to the founder of Hive Social, Roca Pop,
Speaker ?:  otherwise known as Cassandra Pop sometimes she goes by Cassandra
Speaker ?:  and she is a person who launched
Speaker ?:  a social media platform because she did not see the
Speaker ?:  social media she wanted to see in the world. Yes. She
Speaker ?:  decided to launch that when she was, she decided to learn to code and launch
Speaker ?:  a social media site at 19. Wow. So that's pretty amazing.
Speaker ?:  That is super amazing. And Hive, I feel like we talked about a lot
Speaker ?:  in those early days of the Twitter implosion. It got a lot of followers
Speaker ?:  then. Yeah, shortly after Elon Musk took over Twitter,
Speaker ?:  there was sort of an, I call it a pseudo exodus
Speaker ?:  because I feel like we're all still on Twitter. Yeah. I was like, I'm still
Speaker ?:  There. We're all still there. But everybody was kind of looking for
Speaker ?:  alternatives to at least try. And one of the ones that I had
Speaker ?:  stumbled upon amongst others was Hive Social. It feels like
Speaker ?:  a mixture of old school, MySpace, little, little
Speaker ?:  sprinkle of old school MySpace. Because you can set music
Speaker ?:  to your profile page Yes. To automatically play, which I know is like a feature
Speaker ?:  a whole bunch of people really liked, including myself. But it's also, you
Speaker ?:  know, you can post photos, you can post things that look like tweets. I
Speaker ?:  can just post text. And so it's kind of, you know, it kind of wants to
Speaker ?:  be a little bit of everything. Wants to give people a little bit of everything.
Speaker ?:  I mean I used it and then I stopped using it cuz it, it, it broke down a
Speaker ?:  lot. But it sounds like when you only have one, one or two developers
Speaker ?:  it's a little more of a challenge. I think at the time of that massive influx
Speaker ?:  of users, they had three, three people working there. So
Speaker ?:  it's, there were definitely some challenges and Roka talks about that in
Speaker ?:  the interview. Oh, well let's just go to the interview then and in a little
Speaker ?:  bit. I'm gonna be back to ask you some more questions. All right.
Speaker ?:  Hika, thanks for being here today. Hi Ashley. Thank you for having
Speaker ?:  me. I'm really excited to be here. Well I am excited
Speaker ?:  to talk to you because in the wake of some pretty big changes
Speaker ?:  across some of the most popular social media apps, users seem
Speaker ?:  to be seeking alternatives that better suit their desired
Speaker ?:  experiences like more and more. And one of those competitors is
Speaker ?:  your app Hive Social Roka. Can you tell our
Speaker ?:  listeners a little bit more about what Hive Social is and
Speaker ?:  also how it started? So Hive Social is a social media
Speaker ?:  app that I self coded and developed beginning in the
Speaker ?:  later part of 2019. So I started to teach myself how to code
Speaker ?:  in June of 2019 and the very first version was launched in October
Speaker ?:  later that year. So that's how it started. I was still working
Speaker ?:  full-time and I was also in college full-time. So it was definitely
Speaker ?:  a crazy balance to, to try and maintain. I ended up bringing
Speaker ?:  a developer on and a designer just to help out because it was just
Speaker ?:  so much to try and do by myself from the UX design, doing that
Speaker ?:  by myself to the coding by myself. So definitely having extra hands helped
Speaker ?:  a lot. And then I know a lot of people frame Hive
Speaker ?:  this competitor to Twitter now, but I think it's so much more
Speaker ?:  unique in a standalone app to just be a competitor in general because that's
Speaker ?:  why I ultimately made it. I just noticed that there was that downward market
Speaker ?:  trend with other apps and I wanted to fill that market demand. Now
Speaker ?:  just so everybody is aware of this, you, you started
Speaker ?:  learning how to code and you launched your very own social media
Speaker ?:  platform at 19 years old. Is that That's right. Right. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker ?:  Okay. I think some people would say including myself,
Speaker ?:  the audacity, the, the nerve, the the, it's just really
Speaker ?:  that is something to wake up one day and think to yourself,
Speaker ?:  I've had it with these social media sites, I'm just gonna make my own
Speaker ?:  w walk me through that thought process. I mean what, what prompted
Speaker ?:  you to do this? Well I actually started
Speaker ?:  noticing again that downward trend as a senior in high school.
Speaker ?:  But I hadn't started learning how to code or program or anything.
Speaker ?:  It was just something that I noticed that I started wishing that
Speaker ?:  certain apps had X, Y, Z and other people had similar
Speaker ?:  complaints and I was just waiting for that like next big social media app
Speaker ?:  that other people were also waiting for and I just got tired of waiting for
Speaker ?:  and was like, you know what? I might as well try and create my own. And so
Speaker ?:  I started very carefully looking through what exactly I wanted to be in
Speaker ?:  the app and I just went from there. And what do you think
Speaker ?:  feature-wise makes Hive unique or sets it apart from
Speaker ?:  other social media platforms that are out there right now? I think the customization
Speaker ?:  really sets it apart right now. Like you have your music feature that people
Speaker ?:  really love cuz you get to express your music taste in that way. And every,
Speaker ?:  every stream also counts towards your favorite artist
Speaker ?:  total for the year. You can do color themes, people love the Zodiac
Speaker ?:  science and the pronouns that they can have on the profile. I think the Discover
Speaker ?:  page is also super fun for people because you just get to find
Speaker ?:  all sorts of new content on there in your profile itself.
Speaker ?:  You can also have asks, which is also very personal for creators
Speaker ?:  because then it's like if you're on the platform for example and I wanna
Speaker ?:  ask you a question, then I can, and it's a direct interaction that's also
Speaker ?:  a lot more personal too. So I think those combined features make it super
Speaker ?:  fun for people. It does seem like there are a lot of
Speaker ?:  bits and pieces from previous social media platforms that
Speaker ?:  have either come and gone or that still exist that have found their
Speaker ?:  way into Hive social. Now I'm assuming a
Speaker ?:  lot of these features did not exist when you originally launched the app.
Speaker ?:  So what did that version of Hive look like compared to
Speaker ?:  today? That version was very bare bones
Speaker ?:  skeleton. I think if people saw the very first version compared to
Speaker ?:  today's, they'd be like, wow, like you actually had the balls to launch that.
Speaker ?:  I mean it, it was not as modern or
Speaker ?:  a clean cut or aesthetically pleasing as the design today. You
Speaker ?:  still had your music feature that was still a part of it. But things like
Speaker ?:  asks were just not there. Polls were not there. Again, it was just a very
Speaker ?:  bare bone skeleton app Compared to today's.
Speaker ?:  And because you launched this shortly after you
Speaker ?:  started learning how to code for yourself, tell me about the
Speaker ?:  actual process of building Hive. So my
Speaker ?:  process was literally trying to find coding tutorials online, which might
Speaker ?:  sound super silly but I found you Demi. Shout out to them. They
Speaker ?:  have a ton of tutorials and courses that other people make and then
Speaker ?:  you can buy them. And this is non-ad or sponsorship. It's literally what
Speaker ?:  I use cause I didn't have any other resources. I never took college classes
Speaker ?:  or anything for computer science. So oh, I did some research.
Speaker ?:  I knew I needed to use Xcode to code cause I was just making the i l
Speaker ?:  s version at first. And then the easiest language I guess to learn
Speaker ?:  with that was Swift. I was using Swift four at the time so I just typed in
Speaker ?:  Swift four and Firebase cause I was also researching
Speaker ?:  different databases. I settled on that one and a bunch of tutorials came
Speaker ?:  up. I bought a couple and then I would sit there and I would watch the video
Speaker ?:  video in like one end of the screen and then on the other I'd have Xcode
Speaker ?:  open and I would just literally, they would say something and then I would
Speaker ?:  code it. And I remember being super excited because I made my first text
Speaker ?:  box and I didn't do anything. It didn't even have like any words in
Speaker ?:  it to say like, oh enter your username or something. It was just a box. And
Speaker ?:  I remember taking a picture and I sent it to my sister-in-law and I was like,
Speaker ?:  look I made a rectangle, it's a box and it's there. You can't do anything.
Speaker ?:  You can't type in it but like I did it. So I think
Speaker ?:  that part was easy I guess. But again, I did
Speaker ?:  literally have guidelines that I was following. I did make a mistake though.
Speaker ?:  So after I brought my developer on board and he took a look at the code,
Speaker ?:  I still have his text message. He had said that it was
Speaker ?:  impressive because I had hardcoded everything. I didn't
Speaker ?:  know what the hell that meant. So I asked him the library, he like, well
Speaker ?:  most developers use storyboard. Like that's a lot easier cuz then you can
Speaker ?:  just, I guess attach functions to whatever you create visually. And
Speaker ?:  I was like, I done that this entire time because I was coding
Speaker ?:  every single line including the sizing, the the
Speaker ?:  the point sizes and and the colors and everything and input the assets when
Speaker ?:  this whole time I could have been using the storyboard and that would've
Speaker ?:  been so much easier, would've saved me so much more time. And the time spent
Speaker ?:  on it, I, I know some people wonder like, oh well you started coding
Speaker ?:  in and you launched it in October, right? And so that's the, from June to
Speaker ?:  October it's about four or five months they say it's such a short
Speaker ?:  time and and it really is. But because it was the summer, I
Speaker ?:  didn't have school at that time so I was just working full-time.
Speaker ?:  I'd get up around 7:00 AM come home by three 30,
Speaker ?:  4:00 PM and then I would code from
Speaker ?:  4:30 PM to literally three or 4:00 AM the next night or sometimes
Speaker ?:  I just wouldn't even sleep and then I would just go to work and like repeat.
Speaker ?:  So they were very long days and long hours coding every single day.
Speaker ?:  Right? My dad would have to remind me to eat or sleep or drink water and
Speaker ?:  it's like no I wanna do this. Cuz once you're in that zone and like you're
Speaker ?:  so passionately or obsessed with it, you don't wanna stop or like lose your
Speaker ?:  train of thought or anything. So that was my process was just locking myself
Speaker ?:  in my room that summer and just coding it every single night
Speaker ?:  and every single day. I think it's fair to say that when I
Speaker ?:  fall into an internet rabbit hole, it does not normally end in
Speaker ?:  a social media platform getting created. Usually I just have watched
Speaker ?:  too many videos on YouTube or read, read too many
Speaker ?:  articles or have fallen into some subreddit that I wasn't aware of previously
Speaker ?:  and I get obsessed with. So kudos to you for that.
Speaker ?:  We're gonna take a quick break here, but when we come back I'll talk to
Speaker ?:  Barca about what it was like when people started flocking to Hive
Speaker ?:  social, looking for an alternative to Twitter.
Speaker 2:  This episode is
Speaker ?:  Okay. And we're back with my interview with Roka Pop, the founder of
Speaker ?:  Hive Social.
Speaker ?:  So the real kind of change points for
Speaker ?:  Hive Social is October and November of this past year. So
Speaker ?:  Elon Musk takes over Twitter, everybody out there is
Speaker ?:  either super excited about it or super not excited about it and looking for
Speaker ?:  an exit. And one of the apps that people turned to
Speaker ?:  was Hive that could not have been
Speaker ?:  easy. That had to have been a challenge for
Speaker ?:  an app that at that time employed three people. Is that right?
Speaker ?:  Yeah, three people. I think we're up to five Threes of
Speaker ?:  people almost. Yes, you've got almost threes of people working on the app.
Speaker ?:  So you have this massive user rush and
Speaker ?:  there were some complications. I remember I signed up for
Speaker ?:  Hive and I remember seeing a lot of folks saying that
Speaker ?:  usernames could be doubled up and there were some, there were some bugs and
Speaker ?:  challenges because of the mass influx of users.
Speaker ?:  I would love to hear you walk me through your side of
Speaker ?:  that experience. Yeah, so that experience completely
Speaker ?:  caught us of guard. We've had some growth spurts in the past as well. And
Speaker ?:  normally it's from something going viral. Like if people take a screenshot
Speaker ?:  their profile and they share it somehow, I don't know how it just, it
Speaker ?:  goes viral. So that's exactly what happened this time. It just happened on
Speaker ?:  a such a larger scale, whether that was in direct correlation with
Speaker ?:  everything that was going on on Twitter or it just reached the right accounts,
Speaker ?:  I have no idea. But it really exploded and
Speaker ?:  we were not prepared for that growth or, or our server
Speaker ?:  wasn't, I guess you could say, because we gained
Speaker ?:  over 150,000 people overnight and everyone trying
Speaker ?:  to sign up and making their accounts. That was just so amazing
Speaker ?:  to watch it happen. I didn't sleep for days literally cause I was just so
Speaker ?:  excited and I wanted to respond to people. If you get a response from like
Speaker ?:  the hi social account on Twitter, that's most likely me. There's two other
Speaker ?:  people who have access to you. But I'm on there a lot of the time and I try
Speaker ?:  and respond to everyone. So that's what I was doing. I was trying to respond
Speaker ?:  to people and let them know, you know, if they have questions like for example
Speaker ?:  about the duplicate usernames or when the site went down and the
Speaker ?:  completely, you know, the servers crashed, that was a, a kind of
Speaker ?:  panicky moment at that time. No functions worked. So
Speaker ?:  that's actually how the duplicate username bug came to be because
Speaker ?:  since the server was down and no functions were working, so like
Speaker ?:  the function to catch that duplicate username and say, hey, like this is
Speaker ?:  a duplicate, you can't use it. That was down too. So then that ended up
Speaker ?:  being a bug and now I have like over a hundred Nicki mjs on the app when
Speaker ?:  I know none of them are her. But I mean that's just one of
Speaker ?:  the things that the server going down had done and we, we were working to
Speaker ?:  get it back up. So we were working with the Google team, we ended up bringing
Speaker ?:  on a different developer at that time and he's still with us, he's super
Speaker ?:  great. So we got it back up that Friday. It had,
Speaker ?:  I think it went down on Thursday and we brought it up Friday night and
Speaker ?:  then the wave just kept coming and we ended up going past 2
Speaker ?:  million users when I think we had 600 to
Speaker ?:  700,000 at that time. Oh wow. Yeah. That is a pretty big crush on your
Speaker ?:  systems. Yeah, it, it, it really was. I, I think that the post is still
Speaker ?:  up there. I had taken a screenshot of all the reads that were going
Speaker ?:  on within the, the server, which is like every, every time someone does something,
Speaker ?:  we had over, I think over 3 billion reads. So that
Speaker ?:  was, those were all the function calls going to the server and why it had
Speaker ?:  all come down. So those were really wild numbers to see, but I
Speaker ?:  was really excited about it because that kind of proved what I had
Speaker ?:  originally thought like all those years back that hey, there is this downward
Speaker ?:  market trend, there's this market demand, people are going to want a new
Speaker ?:  app and again, whatever correlation it has to anything else going a on
Speaker ?:  out there or if people just really want something new, I mean
Speaker ?:  they really showed out for the app and, and signing up and supporting it.
Speaker ?:  So it, it was just really awesome to see it come to life. Were there specific
Speaker ?:  communities that you noticed in the data
Speaker ?:  for users that really sort of helped bring in
Speaker ?:  more users? Because it feels like there are some like real key
Speaker ?:  communities in fandom that were
Speaker ?:  extremely excited about Hive. Oh yeah, the K-pop
Speaker ?:  communities, what actually kicked off those viral posts, so shout
Speaker ?:  out to them and then that just somehow turned into the gaming community
Speaker ?:  coming on board, which opened the doors for cosplay and then the beauty community
Speaker ?:  and then the Star Wars community and Star Trek community were huge
Speaker ?:  on there as well. I know some notable gaming
Speaker ?:  community specifically that gone on I think we're Call of Duty
Speaker ?:  and then Bungee, so, which was actually really funny because
Speaker ?:  maybe you can see, but I have an Xbox back there and I play Destiny myself,
Speaker ?:  which Bungee had created. So it was just kind of a
Speaker ?:  full circle moment for me to have love the game so much and then have the
Speaker ?:  actual community come on to Hive. So, so it was just really cool to connect
Speaker ?:  with those, with those, the people from that gaming community.
Speaker ?:  But I would definitely say those big three would be
Speaker ?:  at Ridgeland K-Pop and then Gaming Beauty Cosplaying. And I
Speaker ?:  think the fifth one I would have to say is music since you know, have
Speaker ?:  supports music artists like I I mentioned the streams from the profile
Speaker ?:  music accounts towards their overall total. That was
Speaker ?:  really big on there too. So we noticed a lot of hiphop, pop, anything
Speaker ?:  that's trending you would see or hear either on the radio or other
Speaker ?:  apps, it's very similar following those trends on Hive. For
Speaker ?:  listeners who are unaware of hives profile
Speaker ?:  features, one of them is the ability to, much
Speaker ?:  like MySpace used to have set a profile song that
Speaker ?:  plays whenever someone opens up your profile and then there is a
Speaker ?:  monetization ability to purchase additional
Speaker ?:  or unlock additional music slots up to four songs. And
Speaker ?:  so I thought that was a very interesting way for Hive
Speaker ?:  to monetize because it is a free app, it is free for users
Speaker ?:  to use and I am really curious about
Speaker ?:  the future of Hive in that regard. Becoming
Speaker ?:  profitable, being able to monetize in a way that will enable you
Speaker ?:  to hire additional developers to continue to work on
Speaker ?:  all of the things that Hive has going on, which I would love to hear
Speaker ?:  about Hive's plans in let's say the next year.
Speaker ?:  Like what does Hive look like in a year for you? Hive has
Speaker ?:  some really big things planned in the next year. We've partnered with a lot
Speaker ?:  of different brands that I'm really excited to talk about later, later
Speaker ?:  on as well. And the brands, the, the influencers, you'll
Speaker ?:  see those more. But Hives has always been an
Speaker ?:  authentic social media app. That's how I kind of refer to, because a lot
Speaker ?:  of the content that's posted on there is very genuine, it's raw, organic
Speaker ?:  or it could be very curated if you have a specific niche or community that
Speaker ?:  you belong to. So I think having a creator economy where we support
Speaker ?:  those creators is definitely in the works. For example, one
Speaker ?:  feature that's out there and actually the, the term
Speaker ?:  that our users or our our besties have called it
Speaker ?:  is hi streams, which is basically live streaming. We wanna introduce that
Speaker ?:  on the app and then allow users to much like TikTok
Speaker ?:  give gifts through that app that then those creators could convert to
Speaker ?:  cash and then withdraw that for themselves. And I think i's a
Speaker ?:  percentage from that would be lower than other apps because we understand
Speaker ?:  that. I mean, I was, I was, I used to be a micro influencer so I know how
Speaker ?:  important the, that money is, that cash flow is, we
Speaker ?:  wouldn't take a lot from them because it's their full-time job, it's what
Speaker ?:  they're trying to do and I want to support
Speaker ?:  them in that way. So I think live streaming would be one with those
Speaker ?:  in-app purchases, the gifts, and then also in-app
Speaker ?:  subscriptions to different members profiles. So if you've got exclusive content
Speaker ?:  you wanna show behind the scenes for the podcast, for example, then
Speaker ?:  you could put your account behind like a paywall. It's whatever price you
Speaker ?:  wanted, we'll probably have a limit. I don't think people are gonna be putting
Speaker ?:  like a $500 a month to see this profile. I
Speaker ?:  don't know, some people will pay a lot of money for access to certain people,
Speaker ?:  maybe We'll test it with like a small batch and we'll see. But that, that's
Speaker ?:  an idea that, that we've been toying around with because I think it is really
Speaker ?:  fun to see behind the scenes exclusive content and that's another way for
Speaker ?:  computers to get closer with their audience members. So those two
Speaker ?:  revenue streams are going to be coming to Hive. And again, the
Speaker ?:  those brand partnerships that I had mentioned, you'll see them throughout
Speaker ?:  the app because I think Hive will eventually have ads and before
Speaker ?:  anyone freaks out, hive did have ads before the shutdown
Speaker ?:  and all that. We used to have one ad every like
Speaker ?:  seven posts I think on the home feed. And now we're just kind of
Speaker ?:  reframing that since we do have these brand partnerships now they're, they're
Speaker ?:  very minimally invasive. They looked exactly like posts, so it never really
Speaker ?:  bothered people that that was the feedback that we got from the beta group.
Speaker ?:  So now with these brand partnerships instead of, you know, having
Speaker ?:  more randomized ads through Google Ad Mo because that's what we were
Speaker ?:  using, you'll probably see paid advertising from
Speaker ?:  these brands out there. So I'm really excited to bring those
Speaker ?:  campaigns onto Hive. I'm very picky with those as well. So nothing
Speaker ?:  low quality at all.
Speaker ?:  Okay, we're gonna take one more break and when we return I'll check in with
Speaker ?:  Alex Kranz and then more of my interview with Roca.
Speaker 1:  This podcast is sponsored by Toyota Crown. The all new Toyota
Speaker 1:  crown is breaking new ground when it comes to the premium sedan with an available
Speaker 1:  hybrid max powertrain. The Toyota Crown is the perfect combination of
Speaker 1:  power, style, and elegance, making it the car to glide in
Speaker 1:  from a driver focused interior that says you're always comfortable in the
Speaker 1:  spotlight to the stylish exterior that says I have arrived.
Speaker 1:  Toyota says, wherever you go in the all new Toyota crown, you make a
Speaker 1:  statement, the car that says so much, visit toyota.com/crown
Speaker 1:  to learn more. Toyota, let's go places.
Speaker ?:  All right, we're back from break. I've gotta, I gotta interrupt you. I'm
Speaker ?:  sorry. Okay, I got, I got questions. I'm, I'm enjoying this interview, but
Speaker ?:  I, I also have some questions because before the break,
Speaker ?:  Roca referenced this big shutdown and for those of us who don't
Speaker ?:  know, I've deactivated their servers temporarily
Speaker ?:  last fall after some researchers found what looked like some security issues
Speaker ?:  with the app. Ashley, can you kind of tell me more about that? Yeah,
Speaker ?:  so this group of researchers had basically posted
Speaker ?:  a report saying there are a ton of issues here. All
Speaker ?:  of these issues allow any attacker to access all data
Speaker ?:  on Hive. Oh boy. Which is not great. And, and that includes
Speaker ?:  private posts, private messages, shared media, even deleted
Speaker ?:  dms. Ooh, so sliding into the dms and
Speaker ?:  deleting Not gone forever. No, everything lives forever on the
Speaker ?:  internet. So yeah, it was a, it was a Berlin based security collective and
Speaker ?:  they said this also includes private email addresses, phone numbers enter
Speaker ?:  during login, so not great. And so they
Speaker ?:  took down the servers entirely. The app was still up,
Speaker ?:  you could refresh, but it would just refresh to the exact same place that
Speaker ?:  the app was in the, the place your app was in when you opened it,
Speaker ?:  when they shut down the servers. But the service was actually down for two
Speaker ?:  weeks to fix these security risks, which in the world of
Speaker ?:  social media is an actual lifetime it feels like. Yeah. You know,
Speaker ?:  that begs the question, and I think everybody knows the answer. It's a
Speaker ?:  rhetorical question, what do people do when something doesn't work? They
Speaker ?:  stop using it. Yeah. So it's a, it's definitely a really
Speaker ?:  difficult problem to have when you have such a small staff and the inability
Speaker ?:  to remain live while you fix all of these issues in a test
Speaker ?:  environment. And so how do you get those people back? Yeah. How, how
Speaker ?:  do you get those people back? Does, does Roca have an answer for That? I
Speaker ?:  think she does.
Speaker ?:  I'm curious about the decision to pull Hive
Speaker ?:  entirely offline for a period of time and
Speaker ?:  how you as the founder plan to sort of
Speaker ?:  regain those users because obviously there has to
Speaker ?:  have been some drop. Yeah, so regaining the users
Speaker ?:  and the momentum that's going to come from the brand that we've partnered
Speaker ?:  with, and then also influencers later down the line as well as those extra
Speaker ?:  features that are coming later this year. I, I think Hive is an
Speaker ?:  ever-evolving app with, again, very carefully selective features. I'm,
Speaker ?:  I'm the one that makes the final decision on that. So if anything launches
Speaker ?:  and you guys don't like it, blame me fully because I'm the one picking and
Speaker ?:  choosing what to put in the, in the app. So the decision though, to take
Speaker ?:  it fully offline was actually from that
Speaker ?:  security company that had posted the original article, SERFOR Shung.
Speaker ?:  I had actually been in communication with them prior to the article even
Speaker ?:  going live. And the decision that we originally came to
Speaker ?:  was that they wouldn't post it until the issues
Speaker ?:  were fixed and then they posted it anyway. And then we,
Speaker ?:  we had a phone call afterwards where I told them kind of flat
Speaker ?:  out that, Hey, are you guys going to reconfirm that
Speaker ?:  or just confirm that these vulnerabilities were fixed, you kind of threw
Speaker ?:  a grenade and then you ran away and you caused this huge uproar.
Speaker ?:  They did confirm that they would do that for us, but as
Speaker ?:  of, yeah, I haven't seen anything come out, so I, I don't really know what's
Speaker ?:  going on with that. I haven't been in contact with them recently.
Speaker ?:  So that definitely threw a wrench in there
Speaker ?:  because the reason they were going to wait for those vulnerabilities
Speaker ?:  to be fixed, like that's their standard when they report vulnerabilities
Speaker ?:  on a company, it's usually after they have fixed those issues for
Speaker ?:  the simple common sense reason that hey, if you disclose these vulnerabilities
Speaker ?:  out there to people, then there's black hat hackers out there that
Speaker ?:  are going to exploit those. And at that point it
Speaker ?:  was just mind blowing to me that they had posted it because now
Speaker ?:  everyone has like a how to guide on how to exploit those vulnerabilities
Speaker ?:  and it just wasn't safe for people. I mean, we took full accountability
Speaker ?:  and responsibility for it by fixing them and we weren't communication with
Speaker ?:  them. So for them to have made that decision, it, it was really kind of
Speaker ?:  devastating because you worked for so many years on an app and you try
Speaker ?:  to make everything as perfect as possible. And it was my fault
Speaker ?:  for the, the security vulnerabilities even existing. But the fact that
Speaker ?:  they posted and exposed it to those hackers specifically that are
Speaker ?:  reading those, they're trying to see which companies have a, a
Speaker ?:  weaker security framework or system and, and to steal
Speaker ?:  people's data. It was again, just devastating. So we decided,
Speaker ?:  you know, now that hackers out there around the world know
Speaker ?:  about all of this, we would rather just take it offline.
Speaker ?:  And again, I know that resulted in the momentum
Speaker ?:  slowing down because nothing was working within the app.
Speaker ?:  Everything was just completely locked down. But I decided that was the best
Speaker ?:  thing because I would rather have shut down the app and made that decision
Speaker ?:  versus having people's data actually stolen. So I
Speaker ?:  think that's another confusing point for people is some of them think it
Speaker ?:  was a security breach, but nothing was breached. There was no user data
Speaker ?:  stolen, nothing like that. It was just a security vulnerability report.
Speaker ?:  And we have fixed that. All of those since then. The Google
Speaker ?:  engineering team actually cleared that for us. We were on a call
Speaker ?:  with them back and forth and they gave us the green light and then
Speaker ?:  that's when we had brought it back online. I know a lot of people who had
Speaker ?:  initially tried Hive, obviously there was a, a
Speaker ?:  great clamoring for an Android app and then
Speaker ?:  also a desktop app and the process of those
Speaker ?:  things. I would love to hear a little bit about the process
Speaker ?:  of bringing Hive specifically to mobile only
Speaker ?:  at this point, and if you have any plans on your
Speaker ?:  roadmap for a desktop version of the app? Oh yeah, desktop is
Speaker ?:  gonna come later down the line. Right now we just want to focus on mobile
Speaker ?:  only because, you know, we, we did bring the service back online,
Speaker ?:  it's functional, but there's just certain bugs and there's features that
Speaker ?:  we wanna bring on that we really wanna dedicate all of our time of effort
Speaker ?:  and focus to before diverting that to a desktop app. Since
Speaker ?:  we're such a small team, we wanna use our
Speaker ?:  time and efforts wisely and we just don't think it's very feasible at this
Speaker ?:  time to add a desktop version onto our plate because
Speaker ?:  that's essentially rebuilding the entire app. So that is
Speaker ?:  gonna be tabled until later this year. And then right now we're just
Speaker ?:  focusing mobile only. Make that perfect, give everyone a seamless experience,
Speaker ?:  bring those new features on and then we can focus on desktop.
Speaker ?:  I am very curious about your view of
Speaker ?:  the current state of social media. Do you think that we
Speaker ?:  will see major disruption in that space and how
Speaker ?:  that might happen? Or will we see more subtle change over the next few years?
Speaker ?:  Like what's your, what's your take on the current landscape?
Speaker ?:  I think major changes are coming because of the current landscape. So
Speaker ?:  I'm a really observant person. I like to read patterns in different
Speaker ?:  trends out there and just from seeing everyone's reactions
Speaker ?:  to not just the, the Twitter buyout that happened, but
Speaker ?:  social media in general, I, I don't think they're happy with it. I see a
Speaker ?:  lot more complaints than not. A lot of people are very
Speaker ?:  exhausted, I think from social media because it's not really fun
Speaker ?:  anymore. There's, aside from the aesthetic part with like
Speaker ?:  outdated layouts, whatever, you also just have the culture and
Speaker ?:  environment that are on these apps. Like for example, you go on Instagram,
Speaker ?:  you know, you have to curate this personality. And I know I
Speaker ?:  say have to, you don't need to, but if you wanna be someone on that platform
Speaker ?:  or you wanna showcase a certain lifestyle, you have to curate that personality
Speaker ?:  and kind of become this whole different person. When people in real life
Speaker ?:  know you as someone else on Twitter, you get on there and you're just
Speaker ?:  angry all the time because you see so many heart-wrenching
Speaker ?:  hosts and news on there about different things around the world or different
Speaker ?:  political things that are going on and it infuriates you. So
Speaker ?:  you've got one on Instagram where you have to be essentially fake, then you
Speaker ?:  have Twitter or you have to be angry. And then TikTok, I mean, you just get
Speaker ?:  on there and you kind of rant about whatever you make videos and that when
Speaker ?:  you just scroll forever you laugh and stuff. But even there, there's that
Speaker ?:  pressure to, again, if you wanna be a creator on there, you have to
Speaker ?:  consistently post. So the algorithm is pushing you. And I think
Speaker ?:  with that landscape constantly changing, different apps
Speaker ?:  are popping up. I know there's other apps and I guess
Speaker ?:  alternatives like Hive, but I think what sets Hive apart is
Speaker ?:  that we're actually a social media app that's again, a
Speaker ?:  unique standalone app. We're not clones of anyone else. We have our own
Speaker ?:  different, carefully selected blended features that work really cohesively
Speaker ?:  in the app. And we're very focused on UI and the user experience. And I think
Speaker ?:  that's what helps us deliver that more raw, organic experience to our
Speaker ?:  users. It's just the fact that we caring, we're really trying to make an
Speaker ?:  app that people genuinely love. And on that note,
Speaker ?:  if there's someone out there who is not unlike
Speaker ?:  you when you were 19 years old thinking I would like
Speaker ?:  to break out of the systems that I currently
Speaker ?:  operate in and I wanna build something, I wanna found my
Speaker ?:  own social media platform or something else like that, what advice do
Speaker ?:  you have for them and how do you think that your advice
Speaker ?:  is unique to you? Especially because you
Speaker ?:  have, you have experienced quite a ride in a
Speaker ?:  very short period of time. So I have two pieces
Speaker ?:  of advice or or three really. The first one is just started, the
Speaker ?:  second one is do not have any fear. And the third one is just find
Speaker ?:  humor in everything and I'll, I'll kind of go through each of those
Speaker ?:  points. So the first one for just starting it, me personally,
Speaker ?:  I'm a perfectionist. I, I know if I'm starting something I'm going to be
Speaker ?:  completely obsessed with it, but I also have this kind of fear that links
Speaker ?:  to the second point where, well what if I start it and it just
Speaker ?:  sucks. Like, what if I'm not good enough? I, I don't wanna start something
Speaker ?:  and have to learn it, I wanna start something and already be good at it,
Speaker ?:  which is so, so strange. But if you just start
Speaker ?:  it, that is honestly going to be the biggest hurdle, at least that I've
Speaker ?:  experienced. Because you're kind of just sitting there with that trepidation
Speaker ?:  like, oh, should I really do it? What if it doesn't work? And you kind of
Speaker ?:  think about failure and all those, what if scenarios that are honestly more
Speaker ?:  pessimistic than optimistic Because I think as humans we tend to think of
Speaker ?:  just that pathway for ourselves, but if you just start it,
Speaker ?:  you're already leaps ahead of other people who are just sitting on the
Speaker ?:  couch just dreaming about it. My second point to not have any fear,
Speaker ?:  again from my personal experience, some people that I talk to
Speaker ?:  and my friends are like, you know, your competitors are Zuckerberg and Musk.
Speaker ?:  Like, aren't you kind of like afraid of that or what people are saying
Speaker ?:  about you? And I don't, I don't really have any fear
Speaker ?:  about that because I'm not focused on other people. I'm focused on myself,
Speaker ?:  I'm focused on Hive and I want it to grow. And it's like, yes, you should
Speaker ?:  always be aware of things that are going on on around you or
Speaker ?:  potential competitors, whatever it is. But be aware, don't be
Speaker ?:  concerned and don't be afraid. And my third point in finding
Speaker ?:  humor in everything, that's honestly what has gotten me to this point
Speaker ?:  because a lot of, I, I have seen a lot of comments if
Speaker ?:  he looks through Aaron Greenberg's posts on Twitter, when he, he had posted
Speaker ?:  an article, I think it was from Newsweek, they had used a profile
Speaker ?:  picture of me and a lot of people were saying that I was
Speaker ?:  either ai, that I wasn't real, that I was
Speaker ?:  secretly either a Chinese guy in a basement or some Russian
Speaker ?:  spy that was like making the app. So there's a lot of different
Speaker ?:  rumors out there about me and speaking to anyone listening to
Speaker ?:  this podcast, there will probably be a lot of rumors about you too. Whether
Speaker ?:  it's articles about you or if it's people in your real life that are saying
Speaker ?:  stuff about you as well. But you have to find humor in it. So for me
Speaker ?:  personally, when I heard the whole AI and then Chinese guy Russian
Speaker ?:  spy thing, I made a TikTok response, I made a TikTok video
Speaker ?:  response and I just had fun with it and it, it got a lot of laughs
Speaker ?:  for me. It was kind of stress free because so much was going on with the
Speaker ?:  app. I kind of just had that break and I was like, I'll just make a quirky
Speaker ?:  little response. And then everyone else loved it too. So as long
Speaker ?:  as you start it, you don't have fear and you find humor
Speaker ?:  and stuff, I think you'll get really far. So that's coming from my
Speaker ?:  own experience with, you know, hive and everything that's been going on with
Speaker ?:  it. I think that's really good advice. And if you are in fact
Speaker ?:  a digital creation and an ai, it's, it's a really
Speaker ?:  impressive one. It's a really impressive one. You can
Speaker ?:  also just say you built yourself, I built myself, I have programs
Speaker ?:  running in the background. You guys don't see, I have some wires in the corner.
Speaker ?:  It's hooked up to me as my little charging port. So I
Speaker ?:  appreciate this conversation so much and I can't wait to
Speaker ?:  see what is in the future for hives. So thank you Ruka for, for chatting
Speaker ?:  with me. Thank you for having me on here. It was super fun talking with you
Speaker ?:  and I'm glad we got some laughs too.
Speaker ?:  Okay, that is it for the Verge cast. Ashley, thank you
Speaker ?:  so much. I am so very excited for more episodes of
Speaker ?:  this because This is the first episode of our Solo Act series.
Speaker ?:  So everybody you're gonna have to tune in and listen to, to Ashley, talk
Speaker ?:  to people for the next few weeks. Every Monday I hear there's like a
Speaker ?:  Mick Rib situation that's gonna be happening. I will be talking to the founder
Speaker ?:  of the Mick Rib locator and it is a fascinating
Speaker ?:  and delightful interview. We're very excited. There you go.
Speaker ?:  This show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James and Brooke Mentors
Speaker ?:  is our editorial director of audio. The Vergecast is a Verge production and
Speaker ?:  part of the Vox Media podcast network. If you have thoughts, feedbacks, feelings,
Speaker ?:  you can always reach us at the vergecast@theverge.com or you
Speaker ?:  can call the hotline eight six six Verge
Speaker ?:  11, that's 8 66 11. We're gonna be back on
Speaker ?:  Wednesday, as I already said for an all new midweek episode of the
Speaker ?:  Verge Cast. Until then, stay classy.