# Transcript
ID: 7964779f-63a1-48bb-b65f-f96add21dd01
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Sonos loses to Google, and Threads takes on Twitter
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1786708506656383720/-336005802933198818/s93290-US-4906s-1697190394.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss the Meta Quest 3 review, Google gadgets, and Threads continuing to compete with X.
Chris Welch joins the show to discuss the result of Sonos' legal battle with Google.
Speaker 4:  I welcome the Rich Cast, the flagship podcast of c s
Speaker 4:  s Elements. Top, bottom, left right. We've got 'em all here on
Speaker 4:  Vergecast. That's good. This is, I I promise you that will be relevant. I'm
Speaker 4:  your friend Neela. David. Pierce is here.
Speaker 5:  Hi. I should confess that I don't know the difference between margin and
Speaker 5:  padding and C ssss. And if someone would please email and explain that to
Speaker 5:  me, that would really help a
Speaker 4:  Lot. If you just opened a door, my friend. They
Speaker 5:  Create more space. That's, they both do that
Speaker 6:  Very differently.
Speaker 5:  I I'm confident it is different.
Speaker 4:  You have to. Okay. Here are the two rules. You have to limit yourself to
Speaker 4:  500 words and you can't use chat G B T, but then you can email David the
Speaker 4:  difference between margin and padding and C s s and I
Speaker 5:  Will recite several of those emails on this podcast. Sounds
Speaker 4:  Good. Alex Tran is here.
Speaker 6:  I have a confession to make in that. I thought the phrase Big Naturals
Speaker 6:  came from a Oh no
Speaker 4:  GF already. Oh wait. Meme, did you just say Gandalf?
Speaker 6:  I thought it was a Gandalf meme. That's all I'm gonna say about it. I just
Speaker 6:  wanna get that out there. I thought it was a Gandalf meme.
Speaker 4:  I realized now that you've opened this horrible door, it this
Speaker 4:  is the most vir that's ever happened. We've gone from c s s, but
Speaker 4:  I realized now last week I said I had this bad idea of an example because
Speaker 4:  of a meme and I didn't say what the meme was. Was it
Speaker 6:  Also the Gandalf
Speaker 4:  Heme? It was Kevin James.
Speaker 6:  Similar. Very similar.
Speaker 4:  And you can just go back and listen to what I was talking about contextually
Speaker 4:  to understand why that is a horrifying idea. You can find it.
Speaker 4:  Casey posted it in platformer. I'm just saying it's out there.
Speaker 6:  Just dmm me. I'll send it to you.
Speaker 4:  Don't do that. All. right. Here's why I was talking about C ss ss. This is
Speaker 4:  a thing that just got fixed on our website. Yeah. I think is one of the funniest
Speaker 4:  things that has ever been fixed on our website. We have a lot to talk about.
Speaker 4:  There's some Threads news. David reviewed the Meta Quest three
Speaker 4:  we've Sonos got just blasted by a federal judge
Speaker 4:  for patent abuse. Chris Welch is gonna join us. Talk about that. Have a lightning
Speaker 4:  round. But there's a thing that happened on our website that
Speaker 4:  is so silly. It is my favorite bug that we have ever fixed.
Speaker 4:  So we had published articles in like one of our fancy layouts and
Speaker 4:  we'd get all these comments that we're like, how dare you have black text
Speaker 4:  on an orange background? And we'd be like, what are you talking about? Like,
Speaker 4:  that's just the headline. That's fine. And after
Speaker 4:  a while I was like, there's no way this many people are this mad
Speaker 4:  about the headlines being on an orange bat. Like yeah,
Speaker 5:  We should say the way it's supposed to look is there's like a, A colored
Speaker 5:  banner at the top. Yeah, a right behind like the image and the
Speaker 5:  headline and the subhead and the author's name. And it's like a, it's a banner
Speaker 5:  that says like big important story and then it ends. And then you
Speaker 5:  read the story, which is black text on a white background.
Speaker 4:  And we were getting all these comments that were like, how dare you? And
Speaker 4:  I was like, that's weird. But You know it's a redesign. Everyone's mad about
Speaker 4:  everything in the redesign. So for a while we were just like, people are
Speaker 4:  just mad that we picked this color or any color at all. Which is a real thing
Speaker 4:  that happens when you make a website. How dare you use a color? Fine. We
Speaker 4:  use some color, I promise. We ran the accessibility checkers. But after a
Speaker 4:  while the sustained anger that there was black text on an orange
Speaker 4:  background, we were just like, there has to be something going on here. And
Speaker 4:  we finally figured it out. It is the silliest bug in the entire
Speaker 4:  world. All of those people, as best as we can tell, were using the Brave
Speaker 4:  Browser, which has a number of tracking
Speaker 4:  blockers and it is implemented in the most
Speaker 4:  shotgun way you can imagine. They just block all
Speaker 4:  instances of the word bot, which in their
Speaker 4:  implementation just means the string. B o t
Speaker 4:  gets blocked. Oh no. Which means CSS bottom got
Speaker 4:  blocked
Speaker 5:  On our page. Which by the way, the fact that that works for brave
Speaker 5:  is deeply hysterical.
Speaker 4:  So all these users, like we just like imagine trying to debug
Speaker 4:  this so that all these users were in fact a
Speaker 4:  full page of an orange blackground with black text. We had, we couldn't tell.
Speaker 4:  But it was because of this approach to tracking prevention,
Speaker 4:  which is just brute force enforcement.
Speaker 5:  Wait, lemme just make sure I'm understanding this correctly. 'cause this
Speaker 5:  is amazing. So brave is just going in and anything that it's, it, anytime
Speaker 5:  it sees the letters b o t, it's just like, nah,
Speaker 4:  Kill it. That's the bot. Get rid of it.
Speaker 5:  And and we had, we had a thing meant to define the bottom
Speaker 5:  of Yep. The red. It was
Speaker 4:  Breaking our C ss s because it was blocking the word bottom somewhere in
Speaker 4:  there. Yeah. Both our product manager and our senior engineer are both named
Speaker 4:  Tara and I demanded just now in a meeting that they write about this 'cause
Speaker 4:  it's so silly 'cause they had to fix it. So good. So we fixed it. This
Speaker 4:  is what running a website in 2023 is like, it's great. Please
Speaker 4:  keep visiting our website no matter what browser you're on. But if you are
Speaker 4:  seeing something completely bananas, it might be
Speaker 4:  that your browser is doing something just maybe is what I've learned. Check,
Speaker 4:  check another browser. Always. Yeah, that's a goods, that's a web design
Speaker 4:  thing. That's why safari's there on your Yeah. On your computer.
Speaker 5:  I never use
Speaker 4:  It just but everyone's far to see if it's broken. Yeah. There's nothing more
Speaker 4:  powerful you can say in a product meeting than it's broken in Safari too.
Speaker 4:  Just that's
Speaker 5:  Real. Yeah. Done.
Speaker 4:  Alright, let's talk about some things. David, you just did a bunch of reviews
Speaker 4:  on the Wednesday show and then you just reviewed the Meta Quest quester.
Speaker 4:  You wanna talk about those quickly?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Well I'm, I'm mostly curious from the Pixel perspective, kind of what
Speaker 5:  you guys think of all this. We've been tracking this a lot. Neil, I you've,
Speaker 5:  you now had a week to sit with your, what is a photo feelings. I talked to
Speaker 5:  Allison a bunch about how she feels about this. She's a lot more, I would
Speaker 5:  say, normal human than you are about this. She's just like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, it's, it's, this stuff is complicated and weird and it doesn't always
Speaker 5:  work all that well. And I'm very aware every time I've edited these images,
Speaker 5:  that was one of the questions I asked her that I've actually gotten a surprising
Speaker 5:  amount of people responding to is this. Like, she was like, yeah, I,
Speaker 5:  my images look like normal images, but I know that I did something to them
Speaker 5:  and it sort of changes my relationship with it. Yeah. And I thought that
Speaker 5:  was really interesting. And a bunch of people have reached out and said,
Speaker 5:  not only do I feel that way with this stuff, but like it has changed the
Speaker 5:  way that I've edited all of my family photos forever. Because even when I
Speaker 5:  put the better face on, I remember and it changes
Speaker 5:  my relationship to that image when I change it. So, I've just been thinking
Speaker 5:  about that for like yeah. Days now. But I said on this show last
Speaker 5:  week that I was sort of disappointed in what the Pixel eight seemed to be.
Speaker 5:  And I feel like I have changed my tune now seeing Allison's review and other
Speaker 5:  people's reaction to it. People seem to be into this phone, like it seems
Speaker 5:  like they Google like did a good thing. I
Speaker 4:  Thought her framing of the review was really interesting and I encourage
Speaker 4:  people to read it. It's about whether or not you can trust Google, which
Speaker 4:  is where Google is. Like I, yeah. And I, I think the seven
Speaker 4:  years of updates that they promised, we got a bunch of notes. Why don't you
Speaker 4:  talk about the seven years of updates. I think people are excited about it.
Speaker 4:  It's, you can be of two minds about that One. You can be excited about it.
Speaker 4:  Google's finally gonna commit to a supporting a thing for seven years. Or
Speaker 4:  you can say, when will they break my heart? And I think we got a bunch of
Speaker 4:  notes on either side of that debate. I think that's a, a strange place
Speaker 4:  for Google to be in. Like people don't trust them to support their products
Speaker 4:  over the long term.
Speaker 5:  I mean, and with good reason. Why would they? I
Speaker 4:  They provided abundant evidence. So you, you make a promise, like we'll support
Speaker 4:  it for seven years and then you get a 50 50 reaction
Speaker 4:  to it, which is I think fascinating. And that's You know the
Speaker 4:  Pixel eight I think is just in that lineage of things. Like
Speaker 4:  are they gonna stay committed to all of these ideas or are they gonna walk
Speaker 4:  away from some of them? The assistant seems better and faster on this phone.
Speaker 4:  Will it work like that next year? We'll Google Flip the table and, and Android
Speaker 4:  15. Like there's just a lot of that embedded in this phone alongside,
Speaker 4:  oh, some ideas did iterate themselves to completion and it's
Speaker 4:  pretty good. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I think that's right. And I think the AI stuff is so tied up in that, right?
Speaker 5:  Because like the promise Google has been making about this push to AI is
Speaker 5:  you're gonna be able to buy a piece of hardware and as long as it is sufficiently
Speaker 5:  capable, it is going to get better over time. Like actually get better over
Speaker 5:  time, which is a thing we've been saying for years. Never buy a product based
Speaker 5:  on future promises, but like the promise of AI is
Speaker 5:  that it will get better over time. Literally as you use it, it will
Speaker 5:  get better. And that's compelling. But I think the, the Pixel
Speaker 5:  seven didn't really do that. And I think Alison wrote that
Speaker 5:  piece like six months after the Pixel seven came out being like, yeah, this
Speaker 5:  phone still pretty good. It's really not any better. Like
Speaker 5:  Google does the feature drops, it adds new stuff, the models get better,
Speaker 5:  whatever. But there hasn't been anything that sort of changed the game there.
Speaker 5:  And I like the reason to worry about this phone is
Speaker 5:  to worry that it is going to be exactly what it is right now, seven years
Speaker 5:  from now. And that is so not the promise Google wants you to believe in.
Speaker 5:  And yeah, I'm, I'm very torn between the two, but like Google at
Speaker 5:  least seems to have made a bunch of good decisions about where it could go.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's just about whether it chooses to keep going that way. When
Speaker 6:  Do we trust Google? Like, like I think that's the thing I keep
Speaker 6:  thinking about is it feels like I'm in like, like when you're in a relationship
Speaker 6:  and somebody breaks your trust and you're like, how do I go back to trusting
Speaker 6:  you? Right? Like in real life, it, it's a long journey. It's
Speaker 6:  not like you need to start doing these things. And that's usually when we
Speaker 6:  talk about companies, we wanna trust them again. We're like, you need to
Speaker 6:  do this, this, and this. But Google can't do that because it keeps
Speaker 6:  breaking promises. It's like a real Google killed
Speaker 5:  Pixel pass six weeks ago.
Speaker 6:  Right? Like, like how, how do I trust Google
Speaker 6:  again? Because I kind of like, this phone seems really cool. Like part of
Speaker 6:  me wants to, it's just like that best friend where I'm like, I wanna trust
Speaker 6:  you. How
Speaker 4:  I think the answer is, is really narrow. I think it's kind of what David
Speaker 4:  is saying, you're gonna buy this phone on the same cadence. Especially the
Speaker 4:  pro people who buy pro phones I think are on two year cycles,
Speaker 4:  maybe shorter. I think I, I know a lot of pro phone people who are on a one
Speaker 4:  year cycle. I'm on a
Speaker 6:  Three year
Speaker 4:  And, but I That's reasonable. I I think it's the seven years
Speaker 4:  where people are like really, like, it's hard to think of a Google
Speaker 4:  product except for search and YouTube that has lasted for seven years. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Gmail.
Speaker 5:  That's basically
Speaker 4:  True. Yeah. Like that's kind of what we're working with here. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Even we got, I got a note today about decoder being in YouTube music and
Speaker 4:  it's like, oh, because they shut down the podcast thing and moved it on.
Speaker 4:  Like even that, like even what you would think of as like basic stuff,
Speaker 4:  they, they just move around on. So the idea that this phone is gonna stay
Speaker 4:  fixed and relevant for seven years, I think it's really important. It's
Speaker 4:  Google saying, okay, the Pixel program is gonna be around for seven years,
Speaker 4:  but like David said, they canceled but Pixel passed six weeks before this.
Speaker 4:  So yeah, who knows?
Speaker 6:  So really it's just, it is that waiting game then It is like that that best
Speaker 6:  friend. Yeah. I just
Speaker 4:  Thought that was like in Allison's entire review, like that was the framing
Speaker 4:  that got me. Like it's the right framing. Like here's a bunch of betts Google
Speaker 4:  is taking, some of these thoughts are finished. That's really remarkable.
Speaker 4:  Google doesn't finish a lot of thoughts and some of the thoughts on the phone
Speaker 4:  are, are finished. But the fact that it's like a vessel of Google
Speaker 4:  services and Google AI means you have to believe Yeah. That that
Speaker 4:  stuff will persist for quite a long time. You have to believe that this ecosystem
Speaker 4:  is gonna get richer, richer and richer and richer for a long time in a way
Speaker 4:  that even the Samsung ecosystem is now that I have a, like a long train commute,
Speaker 4:  I gotta say I'm getting Seaford pilled. I'm like, what if I don't bring a
Speaker 4:  laptop and I have a Galaxy fold and then I use decks at the office. And I've
Speaker 4:  thought like I'm like, that ecosystem is, they just kept at it. What if
Speaker 4:  you bring in and now it's just waiting for me.
Speaker 6:  You do an iPad
Speaker 4:  Every time I get on this? No, no, no, no, no. No decks. It gotta be
Speaker 6:  It's gotta be decks. It's gotta be
Speaker 4:  Decks. No, 'cause what I want is to not carry a backpack. Okay. I just want,
Speaker 4:  I just wanna roll onto the train like a ninja You know. Like an
Speaker 4:  assassin. No backpack, no bag, nothing. Like who is
Speaker 4:  this guy in the morning commuting to New York City with nothing coffee.
Speaker 6:  At least maybe,
Speaker 4:  Maybe even that just like who what? Just because that is a power,
Speaker 4:  especially when it's warmer and you're not even wearing a coat,
Speaker 6:  You just flip the phone out as dramatically as
Speaker 4:  Possible. Everybody has something except for me. I've got a folding phone.
Speaker 4:  Would you like to see my tablet? It used to be my phone. And then I get to
Speaker 4:  the office, I still have nothing. You are the only person in the elevator
Speaker 4:  in our building without a bag. And you just like confidently
Speaker 4:  walk to one of our like weird rotating desk and you sit down, you're like,
Speaker 4:  boop, boop. I have a computer now. It's not a great computer.
Speaker 4:  It's not super functional.
Speaker 6:  The Slack experience is probably better.
Speaker 4:  Probably. Yeah. Because Slack hasn't been updated for decks. Yeah, you're
Speaker 6:  You. That's good.
Speaker 4:  We, we'll now spend the rest of the show complaining about the Slack redesign,
Speaker 6:  Get excited. But
Speaker 4:  Yeah, all I'm saying is Samsung like kept chipping away at that
Speaker 4:  ecosystem such that even if it's a bad idea,
Speaker 4:  it feels like a good idea now. Right? You're not like an early adopter of
Speaker 4:  this. You're like down the road with it and you can read all the blog posts
Speaker 4:  about how to make it work for you or talk to Dan. Two choices. I
Speaker 4:  with the Pixel, it's like everything is new all the time. Yeah. So that's,
Speaker 4:  that's the thing that really got me. It does seem like the camera sort of
Speaker 4:  divorced from the AI editing stuff. The camera is good. I think Allison
Speaker 4:  said it's a Pixel camera when it's great, it's great. And then when it fails
Speaker 4:  it, it's very predictable how it fails. I think these cameras year over year
Speaker 4:  are almost like imperceptibly different. Like didn didn't review the
Speaker 4:  iPhone 15 this year. So I tried to do a thing where I
Speaker 4:  tried to not pay attention to what was new for my 14 just
Speaker 4:  to see what jumped out. And it's nothing. It's nothing. And I, when I
Speaker 4:  go look, I mean I obviously know there's stuff I'm excited about U S P C.
Speaker 4:  Very cool. I had to buy all new cables. Very cool. But it's like, it's so
Speaker 4:  imperceptibly different. It's the Zoom lens is really nice in low light.
Speaker 4:  It's a little bit You know sweaters are a little more sweater moody. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So soft.
Speaker 4:  But I, I think it's the same way with the Pixel two. It it, both of these
Speaker 4:  phones I think are imperceptibly better year over year. I
Speaker 4:  just come back to the AI thing and I know I was like ranting and raving last
Speaker 4:  week and I received a lot of feedback. And the feedback is
Speaker 4:  uniformly in two camps, this is the end of all trusted
Speaker 4:  information and we should be more careful or you couldn't trust the information
Speaker 4:  anyway. Why do you care now? Yeah, that's it. There's like almost
Speaker 4:  no gray area.
Speaker 5:  Those aren't that different. Yeah. Like those might actually be on one side
Speaker 5:  of the story.
Speaker 4:  And I, I just think that's really interesting. I, again, you can say a lot
Speaker 4:  of people are like, he hates Google. It's like, no, it's, I'm just saying
Speaker 4:  if you can ship photos that demonstrably did not happen and no one knows
Speaker 4:  except for you. And as David pointed out, like a lot of the feedback is like
Speaker 4:  what I know when you have that feeling that something important is happening
Speaker 4:  there, right? The feeling is, oh, I'm lying to everyone. Like
Speaker 4:  that's the feeling. That's, there's not anything else. You're not being totally
Speaker 4:  honest and You know. That's all I'm saying like that something along
Speaker 4:  the way should quell that feeling just so you can communicate, oh, this
Speaker 4:  photo is in a metadata in a way that can't be stripped or don't
Speaker 4:  do. This is another choice. I will say I took on my Instagram,
Speaker 4:  there's, I took a photo of Max and I eating ice cream. You can go look at
Speaker 4:  it and there's people in the background and I thought to myself, boy, I'd
Speaker 4:  like to delete those people, but You know I didn't do it because
Speaker 4:  I, I can't then come back on the show. I
Speaker 4:  boxed myself into a non-AI generative corner. What if you'd heel
Speaker 4:  heel brushed them out? Yeah. Or just replace them fully. Yeah, just,
Speaker 5:  Just the whole guy in front of them. It just, for
Speaker 4:  Some reason David and Alex are in the background of all of my photos.
Speaker 4:  All. right. Tell me about the Quest three real quick. That's the thing I
Speaker 4:  really wanted to hear about
Speaker 5:  So. I had this really interesting experience with the Quest three, which
Speaker 5:  is like, it's two different headsets in one headset.
Speaker 5:  On the one hand it is like the third Quest, right? It's, it's a VR headset
Speaker 5:  that does VR headset things and it does them like
Speaker 5:  shockingly well. I had this experience the first time I put on the headset
Speaker 5:  of things looked right. I didn't have to spend half an hour like
Speaker 5:  dialing in the little things. I didn't have to move it around a bunch of
Speaker 5:  my head. It just like looked good. And it's crazy how much that
Speaker 5:  upgrade in display quality, which it has, it's the best looking Quest
Speaker 5:  by a mile ever, including the Quest Pro. And just like changes everything.
Speaker 5:  It's more fun to do things. It's more fun to look at menus. I find myself
Speaker 5:  like using the headset longer. It has more games, it has more processing
Speaker 5:  power. So like it's a better VR headset in all the ways you would want it
Speaker 5:  to be our VR headset. But then on the other hand, Meta is out here
Speaker 5:  being like, this is the first mainstream mixed reality headset. And I just
Speaker 5:  found myself the whole time doing this review of being like, what does that
Speaker 5:  mean? It has new pass through. It uses these cameras in a depth sensor to
Speaker 5:  like better map the world around you and see what's going on. And you can
Speaker 5:  interact with the world through your headset. That's all true and all cool.
Speaker 5:  And there is precisely one good mixed reality
Speaker 5:  experience I had on the whole thing. And it's the demo app that shows you
Speaker 5:  how to use mixed reality. Like it's called first encounter and it's
Speaker 5:  sick. It's so fun. There's like, like I played it mostly
Speaker 5:  down here and it's, it starts with coming from your ceiling, there's a little
Speaker 5:  alien craft and it actually makes a thing that looks like a hole in your
Speaker 5:  ceiling. And then aliens just blow holes in all your walls and you have to
Speaker 5:  fight them. It's so fun. It lasts like eight minutes and then it's like,
Speaker 5:  go have fun on your headset. And I'm like, I what else, what do I do here?
Speaker 5:  So I landed in this really weird place of like, and I, I argued about this
Speaker 5:  a bunch with Addie and Dan who have done a lot of these headset views for
Speaker 5:  us too. Like on the one hand it's a $500 very good VR
Speaker 5:  headset. Cool. Big upgrade over the Quest two a lot more
Speaker 5:  expensive than the Quest two. On the other hand it has this like amazing
Speaker 5:  new functionality that is essentially not for anything,
Speaker 5:  don't know what to do with that. And,
Speaker 4:  And that's how they're, they're marketing the product.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That was the same thing we saw with the PS five, right? Like
Speaker 6:  PS five comes out, Astros playroom really, really cool great
Speaker 6:  demos. You're like, oh wow, the controller's so cool. Every other game's
Speaker 6:  just like, yep, that's a controller You know a hundred percent. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But this is like, I feel like a bigger deal because mixed reality
Speaker 6:  is bigger than haptic feedbacks. Probably not a lot of people were buying
Speaker 6:  the PS
Speaker 4:  Five gimme the entire PS five for a metal gig game that never came.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And like dude left You know. Yeah. And like Kojima's gone and like
Speaker 4:  no one's ever gonna use this controller again. Haptic only Nintendo gets
Speaker 4:  to pull the controller trick. Yeah. By the way, I'm sure there are cool haptic
Speaker 4:  PS five games. I only play Madden in Grando in that fine All. right. Just
Speaker 4:  be fine with that.
Speaker 5:  Horizon
Speaker 6:  Is
Speaker 4:  Lovely. I get, I get what I want outta this console. It's awesome.
Speaker 4:  Grand Ismo. Let's just talk about, let's just talk about racing seats the
Speaker 4:  rest of the show we're
Speaker 6:  Pivoting.
Speaker 4:  No, I think there's that like the chicken egg problem. Like you need a cheap
Speaker 4:  good mixed reality headset Yeah. For developers to want to come and develop
Speaker 4:  for it. Fine. And the Vision Pro is coming and
Speaker 4:  presumably some of these concepts will grow and the market will grow. I guess
Speaker 4:  my question is that's what everyone wants, right? Everyone wants to do
Speaker 4:  augmented reality. I can't tell if we made the
Speaker 4:  best VR headset ever, but we want to talk about it as though it is not a
Speaker 4:  VR headset means the VR market has come to its logical conclusion.
Speaker 6:  I think it has.
Speaker 5:  I kind of think So I dunno too. I think I, I don't know if it's come to its
Speaker 5:  logical conclusion. I think it's very clear that it has a ceiling and that
Speaker 5:  that ceiling is fairly low. Like I, I don't think
Speaker 5:  this headset as much better as it is, is going to make people who never
Speaker 5:  wanted headsets, want headsets. Right. And like if you take the diagram
Speaker 5:  of headset people and all people,
Speaker 5:  it's headset people is like a teeny tiny sliver, right? It's like people
Speaker 5:  who had smartphones in like 2002
Speaker 5:  because I was one of those people and it ruled and my smartphone was
Speaker 5:  a piece of junk and I had it because like I am that kind of person. But it
Speaker 5:  took a long time for like the world to become smartphone
Speaker 5:  people. And then we're there with headsets, right? Where there's like, there's
Speaker 5:  this much market share for people who want
Speaker 5:  headsets to do VR things, right? It's like it's a gaming thing and it
Speaker 5:  is harder to use and access than a lot of gaming things. So it it's, it's
Speaker 5:  a small group. If you believe as a lot of people in tech do that,
Speaker 5:  the future is glasses that we are all eventually going to wear something
Speaker 5:  on our face. You are never going to get anywhere close to that with mostly
Speaker 5:  a VR product. I think you're right that Meta is just out here saying like
Speaker 5:  this is the start of it. Like this is the, the what the Oculus dev kit
Speaker 5:  was You know 11 years ago. This is now that
Speaker 5:  except they want you very badly to buy it. But the thing that really
Speaker 5:  confuses me is that at the very beginning when Meta decided
Speaker 5:  it was all in on vr, back when it was Oculus and Facebook was Facebook,
Speaker 5:  the company went way out of its way to like juice this ecosystem.
Speaker 5:  It bought every company it could think of. It had this like crazy
Speaker 5:  flood of content. It like single-handedly made the VR
Speaker 5:  ecosystem an ecosystem. I don't see any of that happening in mixed reality
Speaker 5:  now. Even all the cool stuff coming, there's a bunch of cool games coming.
Speaker 5:  There's an Assassin's Creed game coming. If
Speaker 4:  There's, if no game console shall exist No. Without Assassin's Creed. It's
Speaker 4:  illegal. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  If you don't get it in six months, just throw in the track.
Speaker 4:  Jeff. Ito's not stabbing you. Nothing is happening,
Speaker 5:  But all the stuff that's coming is VR games. Addie
Speaker 5:  kept making the case to me that maybe the problem here is that even Meta
Speaker 5:  is not sure what mixed reality is for, especially in a headset you're not
Speaker 5:  likely to like wear out into the world. And I think she's probably right
Speaker 5:  about that. So it's like, this is like a, a very cool VR headset with a tech
Speaker 5:  demo on top of it. And
Speaker 6:  That tech demo was also like, wasn't that a Magic Leap Tech demo years
Speaker 6:  ago? Or it was like it was part of their
Speaker 4:  Oh the Aliens. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  The Aliens. 'cause it was, but it was an office and you're like, ah, in the
Speaker 6:  office. And I was like, that's cool, right? So it's exciting. I can do that
Speaker 6:  now. Not with like glasses and a little backpack, but
Speaker 5:  It's something like, it's fun. The the first encounter thing is like legit
Speaker 5:  fun.
Speaker 4:  Would you say that it hacked the g p u of your brain, which is what Magic
Speaker 4:  Leap used to say
Speaker 5:  About the teeny tiny like sliver of field of view that you would
Speaker 5:  get in the Magic Leap headset? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I was just never, ever forget, I believe this was like a wired
Speaker 4:  covered story, right?
Speaker 5:  Kevin Kelly wrote about it.
Speaker 4:  It was like we, we used the Magic Leap and there were just a line in it
Speaker 4:  where they refused to describe how their technology worked. Magic.
Speaker 4:  Like the poor y reporter, like we asked how the technology worked and they
Speaker 4:  wouldn't say, they just kept saying things like, it hacks the G p U of your
Speaker 4:  brain. It was just incredible. Like if only I could
Speaker 4:  say things like that more consistently, right? You know it'd be great.
Speaker 4:  I mean
Speaker 6:  The Meta
Speaker 4:  Three The Verge, it hacks the g p U of your brain.
Speaker 4:  That's,
Speaker 5:  That's pretty good, honestly.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I So I agree with you about this VR thing. Every compelling demo even
Speaker 4:  of the Vision Pro, every compelling idea for these products is virtual
Speaker 4:  reality. Yeah. There, there just isn't one. The You know the,
Speaker 4:  the videos of the Vision Pro or the Quest Pro before it, where
Speaker 4:  you're at a table and you've put five giant monitors in front of you on
Speaker 4:  the table. It's like You know that requires an empty table.
Speaker 4:  Why? Why would you have, why like inside your house is a
Speaker 4:  bad mixed reality environment? 'cause it is likely that you don't just
Speaker 4:  have like empty rooms.
Speaker 6:  I got the idea,
Speaker 4:  The dystopian vision of Mark Zucker being like, here's what's gonna happen
Speaker 4:  in the future. People will live in gigantic empty homes and my virtual
Speaker 4:  objects will fill those homes and to move around your house and do anything,
Speaker 4:  you will wear my headset
Speaker 6:  And buy my NFTs.
Speaker 4:  But that's just like, is that, is that right? Is that why we're all chasing
Speaker 4:  it? So you can buy TVs from the, the Facebook store? I don't know like that.
Speaker 4:  You gotta give me some reason to wanna wear this thing in my house. And all
Speaker 4:  the reasons in the house are virtual reality reasons.
Speaker 6:  I got one, I got a mixed reality. It's
Speaker 4:  Grand Jury, Ismo and Supernatural,
Speaker 6:  They haven't released yet, but they got to like car and
Speaker 6:  computer repair mixed reality. Like you just put it on and you look down,
Speaker 6:  it's like, oh yeah, you no
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 6:  Fix it. Yeah, you you messed that up. Do that. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That's all it's gonna say is, boy, those screws are smaller than you thought.
Speaker 4:  Huh? Yeah. You didn't, you don't have a bowl, do you? You
Speaker 4:  forgot a bowl. You're just hoping they don't roll away and
Speaker 6:  It's just like a little thing up at the top showing you what actually you
Speaker 6:  need to do. Yeah. Versus whatever the instructions say. Like I would buy
Speaker 6:  a headset in a heartbeat if it did that for Ikea
Speaker 6:  furniture plumbing. I don't know how to plum
Speaker 5:  Alex. I have such good news for you. I'd like to tell you about a product
Speaker 5:  called Google Glass, which exists still in this world
Speaker 5:  I know today exists to do exactly the thing you're describing. It's not for
Speaker 5:  you, it's for like people who repair airplanes and stuff. It's not for people
Speaker 5:  who put together IKEA furniture, which to be fair would be sick. I
Speaker 6:  Want it for my house.
Speaker 4:  No, wait, hold on, hold on. Excuse me. I'm sorry. My Google clock
Speaker 4:  dinged. You are wrong. Google Glass has been discontinued.
Speaker 4:  No, may March 15th, 2023 Google Enterprise has stopped being sold.
Speaker 4:  That was their market. They pivoted into. Okay. But
Speaker 5:  People are still using it. Oh sure.
Speaker 4:  I'm sure Somewhere there's a mechanic being like, man I hope this airplane
Speaker 4:  database is up to date. Can you imagine you roll
Speaker 5:  Into Jiffy Lube and the guy's like, lemme take a look and just flips his
Speaker 5:  Google glass down all his
Speaker 4:  Head. Yeah. I will say the first ever HoloLens demo I took at
Speaker 4:  Microsoft, they made me wear a HoloLens and I replaced a spark plug in an
Speaker 4:  A T V by walking around in a room.
Speaker 6:  I I I fixed some plumbing.
Speaker 4:  Oh see issue that was, and my question to them, which in
Speaker 4:  retrospect was not as rude as it should have been, was if you are a mechanic
Speaker 4:  and you have a shop full of tools and someone has brought you
Speaker 4:  their a t v, wouldn't you already know how to fix the spark plug?
Speaker 6:  But that's why this is perfect for consumers because I would
Speaker 6:  not, I have a vague understanding, but you wouldn't,
Speaker 4:  You wouldn't be in a position where like you were perfectly ready
Speaker 4:  to replace a spark plug and your face computer was like,
Speaker 4:  now walk 30 steps to the left and get this wrench. Like if all
Speaker 4:  of that is ready to go and you've spent the time to set that up,
Speaker 4:  like, and you don't know how to fix the spark plug, like your, your priorities
Speaker 4:  are just upside down.
Speaker 6:  But that is exactly what I would do in real life.
Speaker 4:  That's true. It's true. It's like,
Speaker 6:  Like think a hundred percent. Yeah. I've got everything ready. I Google that.
Speaker 6:  I didn't Google how to actually do the thing. Right. I just googled the prep.
Speaker 5:  But luckily YouTube exists and I'm sure there is a middle-aged man
Speaker 5:  with boots on who will teach you how to do anything you can think of.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But I want him in mixed reality showing me and then being like, Alex, that's
Speaker 6:  terrible. What are you doing the other direction?
Speaker 4:  This is what, this is like the true promise of ai. Yeah. That's is synthesizing
Speaker 4:  YouTube fix it guy to look through your eyes
Speaker 4:  and he should be played by T-pain.
Speaker 6:  Never hire an AC repair guy. And
Speaker 4:  You say we don't have ideas in the Birch cast. This is how you hack the G
Speaker 4:  p U of the brain. We did it guys tpa, generative AI plumber.
Speaker 4:  Just being like, that's not how you fix a toilet. Alex.
Speaker 6:  Perfect.
Speaker 4:  It's true by the way that those enterprise products existed. They thought
Speaker 4:  that would be a huge market, right? You've got a, you're a a baby mechanic
Speaker 4:  for Delta, you gotta fix a thing. I don't
Speaker 6:  What you
Speaker 4:  And that that's what they thought. And none of them worked out. I just say
Speaker 4:  I I keep coming back to this basic idea. The thing they
Speaker 4:  all wanna build is glasses. And the thing they keep trying to sell is virtual
Speaker 4:  reality and glasses and virtual reality are non-compatible. Correct.
Speaker 6:  That's
Speaker 4:  True. And so it, it's when I say like, is this the end of the VR market?
Speaker 4:  Like you, you have to make the turn. You have to stop doing VR
Speaker 4:  games. You have to stop. Supernatural is entirely vr. You have to stop telling
Speaker 4:  people that you're gonna get on an airplane with your $3,500 vision pro in
Speaker 4:  a battery pack in your back pocket and you're gonna watch a movie in vr.
Speaker 4:  'cause if your eventual goal is to ship glasses, you won't be
Speaker 4:  able to do that anymore. 'cause you won't be able to block out the world
Speaker 4:  around you. And I, I Don, I, it just seems like
Speaker 4:  everyone knows this problem is there. It's not like a secret problem. This
Speaker 4:  is not some grand insight that they gotta solve. VR requires you to block
Speaker 4:  out the world around you. But like how are you gonna do it? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  They just gotta move headsets for, for the holidays. So so let's talk about
Speaker 6:  the VR part because that's what kids can actually use right now. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And sell it. And then I think that's always the plan is like vr, vr, vr.
Speaker 6:  And then one day they'll be like, okay, the glasses are ready, vrs over there
Speaker 6:  if you want it, you can get that. Or you can spend $4,000
Speaker 6:  on these glasses and t-pain will be in your ear and like
Speaker 4:  Confined. Finally, finally, someone has a killer app that does not require
Speaker 4:  facial recognition. See we did it. It's angry T-Pain the plumber,
Speaker 4:  we
Speaker 6:  Fixed
Speaker 4:  It by the way I I say this for maybe the a hundred times of her Chest T-pain
Speaker 4:  rules. And if he ever wants to come on the show, he's more than welcome.
Speaker 4:  Just putting that out there. We should talk about Threads really quickly
Speaker 4:  just before we move to a break. There's just Twitter and Threads news
Speaker 4:  in the world. There's a war going on between Israel and
Speaker 4:  Hamas. Twitter did not do great in that
Speaker 4:  circumstance. Every time Twitter does not do great. A flood of people comes
Speaker 4:  to Threads and then we all have to contend with Adam Ary
Speaker 4:  talking about news on Threads, which he should just stop doing.
Speaker 4:  I, that's just my free advice to Adam Sary. 'cause he keeps saying things
Speaker 4:  like, it's not that we don't want news, it's that we're gonna prioritize
Speaker 4:  everything else. Anything but news is my priority. Does that make
Speaker 4:  sense to you? It's not that we don't want it even though you keep asking
Speaker 4:  for it and doing it and boy do you keep doing it. It's just that I don't
Speaker 4:  want to prioritize it in any way, shape or form. And it's like You know
Speaker 4:  that that it silence.
Speaker 6:  Silence is good.
Speaker 4:  It's not that I don't want to turn up the volume on this channel, it's that
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna turn up all the other channels as loud as I can so that this channel
Speaker 4:  is effectively zero. Like that's what that looks like.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. He needs to just stop talking about news until he actually has some
Speaker 6:  news about this. I I don't
Speaker 4:  So I So I think he's sincere. I like Adam. Yeah. He's been on Decoder before.
Speaker 4:  I think he's even been on The Verge house before I I think he's sincere.
Speaker 4:  I think Meta got burned by what you might call the great
Speaker 4:  Facebook news experiment
Speaker 5:  And also like burned the world. He the world. It's useful to remember that
Speaker 5:  asking Meta to do more news has not historically been a good idea for like
Speaker 5:  the earth. Yes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. There's a lot of wreckage in what you might call the millennial media
Speaker 4:  ravine. Let's name some brands that don't exist. Buzzfeed news
Speaker 4:  mike.com, like generally vice in its previous
Speaker 4:  incarnation. It's just true. I mean like all the the, those are all huge
Speaker 4:  betts on Facebook news distribution or Facebook video distribution.
Speaker 4:  You can just go look at the Wikipedia page where the words pivot to video.
Speaker 4:  We all live through it and that was Facebook sent floods of
Speaker 4:  traffic, web traffic to publishers and then they stopped and they started
Speaker 4:  saying the future of the internet is video. Which I will grant them broadly
Speaker 4:  True. That was true. People like watching video who
Speaker 4:  knew you can get it from a streaming service.
Speaker 4:  You can get it from Alex's plex server. Yeah. Or you can get it from a social
Speaker 4:  platform and most people pick social platforms so that's fine. But, but Facebook
Speaker 4:  like led a bunch of companies off a cliff basically in terms of revenue.
Speaker 4:  And I think Adam doesn't wanna do that again. And he keeps saying, I don't
Speaker 4:  wanna overpromise and underdeliver cynically. What you might respond to that
Speaker 4:  with is then don't break your promises. That's just a thing
Speaker 4:  you could say. Well I think
Speaker 6:  It's important to remember what people are asking for isn't like give us
Speaker 6:  algorithms that control the news, which leads to all the things that
Speaker 6:  happen when Facebook did that. And they're not asking for pivoting to
Speaker 6:  video or any of the other things. They're just saying like give us better
Speaker 6:  hashtag support. Yeah. So if I wanna follow something
Speaker 6:  breaking in the world, I can And it doesn't have to be bad, it can be sports
Speaker 6:  and, and so like that's the really interesting thing that's happening
Speaker 6:  here to me is, is just co completing completely rolling all of
Speaker 6:  that in together. And I'm like, Adam, I promise you whatever's happening
Speaker 6:  in Marvel or
Speaker 4:  Like talking directly to Adam,
Speaker 6:  Sorry or N F L is not the same as whatever's happening in the
Speaker 6:  larger world with with conflicts and stuff like that. Like those are different
Speaker 6:  types of news. People just want a way to be like, oh something
Speaker 6:  happening. What?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I, but again, I think they've been burned by this idea in the past.
Speaker 4:  Right. And I think again, in no way is criticism of X the
Speaker 4:  company praise for criticism of the previous administration of Twitter
Speaker 4:  the company. But I think you can look at it and say maybe that horrible
Speaker 4:  clown car was the best it could ever be and we don't wanna do that. We wanna
Speaker 4:  build something bigger. I think they're sincere about that. All that said,
Speaker 4:  I don't think that they're ever gonna do news. I think that adversary says
Speaker 4:  that they're not gonna do news over and over again 'cause they don't wanna
Speaker 4:  do it. It's, and again his, he's not saying they want to or they're gonna
Speaker 4:  block it. Although they have some very restrictive moderation policies that
Speaker 4:  seem like they don't wanna do. Like you can't talk about Covid on Threads
Speaker 4:  really. It's just like not a thing you're allowed to do. Right. You know,
Speaker 4:  I think they're gonna prioritize sports coverage and fashion and culture
Speaker 4:  and whatever and they will accidentally build tools that are reasonably good
Speaker 4:  for news. But the idea that the way that Twitter was just sort of the
Speaker 4:  assignment editor for the media and the Trump era, I think they would prefer
Speaker 4:  Threads to not be that thing
Speaker 6:  That I'm okay with. Like that's the kind of thing where I'm like, okay, yeah,
Speaker 6:  we don't need that. There are other ways to get this. And frankly, having
Speaker 6:  all of your, your really good reports appearing in like
Speaker 6:  148 characters on a website is not the best way to deliver a
Speaker 6:  lot of news. And we need to move past that. That seems yeah,
Speaker 6:  fine. Let's do that.
Speaker 4:  This is the time in the broadcast where I start talking about ActivityPub.
Speaker 4:  This is the point. Yeah. Everyone's making a huge mistake. You don't want
Speaker 4:  Twitter again, it wasn't great. It just wasn't good. Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  just fundamentally
Speaker 6:  Bad. It
Speaker 4:  Was not, it was not a great time for a handful of guys
Speaker 4:  to be in charge of a handful of platforms that dominated our
Speaker 4:  information ecosystem. So the point, and I think that the,
Speaker 4:  the better thing to do is hold Instagram and
Speaker 4:  Meta to their promises around Federation and ActivityPub, which
Speaker 4:  they continually say they're gonna do like their engineers on the platform
Speaker 4:  saying they're gonna do it. Their representative to the W three Cs on there
Speaker 4:  saying they're gonna do it. Ari says they're gonna do it. Zuckerberg said
Speaker 4:  to Alex Heath a couple weeks ago, they're gonna do it. They keep saying they're
Speaker 4:  gonna do it, they haven't done it. So you gotta hold them to that promise
Speaker 4:  and then you have to build products that interoperate and allow you
Speaker 4:  to address the Threads audience with news products or allow you to build
Speaker 4:  news products that use content from Threads in new and interesting ways.
Speaker 5:  I agree with that. I also think you just made the exact case
Speaker 5:  why Meta wants to do this because Meta federating
Speaker 5:  lets it wash its hands of every complicated thing it doesn't feel like dealing
Speaker 5:  with. Right. And So I think it's just going to be true that
Speaker 5:  Threads is the biggest thing in the Fedi verse or the
Speaker 5:  open social web or whatever you wanna call it. Like the day it does, it will
Speaker 5:  be the dominant player on ActivityPub and probably will be for a
Speaker 5:  long time. And so it's still going to have this
Speaker 5:  same set of responsibilities. And I think just to be able to say it's like
Speaker 5:  Google saying you can use a different search engine, right? It's just like,
Speaker 5:  it's not, it's true but it's not the reality of
Speaker 5:  being alive. Most people are gonna be
Speaker 5:  on Threads doing this stuff and like Adam er and his team still have
Speaker 5:  incentives and I think responsibilities to get this stuff right.
Speaker 5:  But I think like what he means when he says we don't want to do news
Speaker 5:  is literally, it's like the the knob that says news that's on
Speaker 5:  his desk, he is going to keep dialing it down. Right? Like yeah, you, your
Speaker 5:  thing about turning up the volume is like a, I think a surprisingly real
Speaker 5:  metaphor. Like I don't think that's actually that far off from what's actually
Speaker 5:  going on. The question is do you care more about like evergreen stuff or
Speaker 5:  do you care more about real time stuff? Right. And Twitter a thing it did
Speaker 5:  right? Was it found that balance really, really, really well. It's
Speaker 5:  really hard to do the thing where you divide between what is good And, what
Speaker 5:  is now and and Twitter hit that balance better than I think any
Speaker 5:  other platform ever has. Which is why it was so good at that. You could even
Speaker 5:  go on the algorithmic timeline and it would still show you new stuff.
Speaker 5:  I don't think Threads is ever going to push as far down that
Speaker 5:  realtime road ever as Twitter did. Yeah. I just don't see it. I have
Speaker 6:  One question about all of this and it was something I actually saw on Threads
Speaker 6:  and I think it was maybe from you or maybe response to Adversary,
Speaker 6:  why are we focused so much on Threads and how it handles
Speaker 6:  news and not focused on TikTok, which by all accounts is a much more
Speaker 6:  widely used platform and it how it handles news because it has a lot
Speaker 6:  of the same kind of like concerns about like what you can and cannot say
Speaker 6:  on the platform, but it also has a much bigger audience
Speaker 6:  and it is actually actively algorithmically delivering that news.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Whatever it is to people, be it accurate or not. And it's kind of an
Speaker 6:  obnoxious, I found to like report when stuff is inaccurate on that platform.
Speaker 6:  Like do I just do a call out TikTok being like, everything this man has said
Speaker 6:  is wrong. Like I've thought about it. But like that
Speaker 6:  for me feels almost a bigger concern than what's happening at
Speaker 6:  Threads. And it's kind of interesting that I think we all talk about it here
Speaker 6:  and I know a lot of people in media talk about it Threads because Twitter
Speaker 6:  was very much like a media thing. Everybody on media used it. And
Speaker 6:  then a lot of people have migrated to Blue Sky to Mastodon now to Threads
Speaker 6:  and they're very much using it there. And a lot of the discourse, the conversation
Speaker 6:  around news is driven by the media on that platform. And it is kind of
Speaker 6:  interesting that we're driving it there and we're kind of ignoring TikTok
Speaker 6:  where the people are actually watching. Yeah. The news.
Speaker 5:  I also think there's something about those platforms that make
Speaker 5:  it feel more like everyone is having a similar
Speaker 5:  experience where I think like on TikTok there's no pretense that what
Speaker 5:  I'm seeing on TikTok is anything like what either of you are seeing on TikTok,
Speaker 5:  right? And so it, it makes this question of like, what is the
Speaker 5:  quote unquote TikTok experience really hard to talk about
Speaker 5:  in a way that these more like participatory
Speaker 5:  messaging things like Twitter and Blue Sky and now Threads, it just
Speaker 5:  feels more like everyone is in one place. Whereas these
Speaker 5:  other things, and I think YouTube falls in this category too. Like you
Speaker 5:  don't see on YouTube what I see on YouTube. So it's very hard for
Speaker 5:  us to actually talk about the way YouTube works because everyone's experience
Speaker 5:  of it is so different. But on a place like Threads, it
Speaker 5:  feels more like everyone is there just because it moves so fast that even
Speaker 5:  though the experiences are different it just makes people feel more like
Speaker 5:  they understand it, I think. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And there was like, there were universal experiences. We all got the
Speaker 6:  Sexy Ladies for like a week on Threads and we're like, why are you here?
Speaker 6:  Stop.
Speaker 4:  I was like, why aren't you here more often?
Speaker 6:  Neil like some sexy favorite app.
Speaker 5:  Mine was just the Nugget account. Yes. Like that was the most universal experience
Speaker 5:  of all was the Nugget account for like three weeks on Threads.
Speaker 4:  Well you didn't just actively interact with the sexy ladies of Threads to
Speaker 4:  bring 'em back more often. You know like crypto, you want it? Oh,
Speaker 4:  oh it's, this is happening, it's fine. I'm nothing but a
Speaker 4:  man. I'm just, the thing about news is like I, here's my other
Speaker 4:  metaphor. You ready? Here's what the media is. The news media
Speaker 4:  is on Threads. We're the mandolin players in a C D C, we All, right?
Speaker 4:  It's not to say there's not a mandolin player at AC d c, maybe there is,
Speaker 4:  you don't know. But there's also ac, C D C,
Speaker 4:  they're not kicking you out. You might, you might be jangling away on that
Speaker 4:  thing.
Speaker 6:  It's in the back behind the drum kit
Speaker 4:  And Adam and Sarah's like, look, we're just not gonna amplify the mandolin.
Speaker 4:  They
Speaker 6:  Don't get a mic. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That's, that's all that's happening there. And it's fine. It's a, it's a
Speaker 4:  way to be. But I'm just saying that
Speaker 4:  opportunity, especially when the big player is gonna do federation
Speaker 4:  again, you gotta hold 'em to it. That means you get to rethink all of web
Speaker 4:  distribution. You get to rethink content moderation and to be like, give
Speaker 4:  me trending topics, So, I can one-to-one replace Twitter is like,
Speaker 4:  that's just itty bitty thinking. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Everyone,
Speaker 4:  Everyone think bigger. If you want to, if you're out there building a cool
Speaker 4:  ActivityPub product, just like let us know we're gonna start over covering
Speaker 4:  that stuff just to show people that people are building new interesting products.
Speaker 4:  We'll see. I mean it has to be good. We can't just be sexy ladies in crypto.
Speaker 5:  And speaking of ActivityPub, we should say the one, the bit of ActivityPub
Speaker 5:  news this week was that WordPress now officially supports
Speaker 5:  ActivityPub on WordPress dot com accounts. Yeah. And like what
Speaker 5:  WordPress is is very confusing. WordPress dot com is only a subset of WordPress
Speaker 5:  and WordPress the company and WordPress. It's like, it's a lot, but a lot
Speaker 5:  of websites can now with one plugin and
Speaker 5:  checkbox interoperate with ActivityPub, which means you can actually push
Speaker 5:  your content to these other places and it's like, that's what this is
Speaker 5:  supposed to look like. Yeah. Right. Like that I think is very exciting and
Speaker 5:  yeah, right is a big start in this narrowly
Speaker 4:  It's, well Threads doesn't do it yet. So if you have a blog and you're like
Speaker 4:  running it, someone can follow you on Mastodon and
Speaker 4:  your post to your blog will show up in their Mastodon feed, right? And it,
Speaker 4:  if they hit like it'll come back to you. That's hugely powerful. You
Speaker 4:  could see how, for example, if a large technology website had a quick
Speaker 4:  posting format, it might make use of such a technology,
Speaker 4:  especially who is migrating toward WordPress in near future. Just an idea
Speaker 4:  that I have just a hypothetical for you all to think about. Okay. We should
Speaker 4:  take a break. I want to get David's perspective on his
Speaker 4:  time in the US versus Google courtroom and then Chris
Speaker 4:  Walsh is gonna join us and talk about another Google case, which
Speaker 4:  is handily winning. We'll be right back.
Speaker 8:  Welcome
Speaker 4:  Back to The Vergecast Legal Hour. Or we break down the
Speaker 4:  hottest action courtrooms around the country. We should just pivot
Speaker 4:  the show to True crime. Yay. Like that's what does the numbers, that is the
Speaker 4:  dream of the people who run this podcast network. Yeah, that we, we do a
Speaker 4:  tech true crime show.
Speaker 4:  They stole my battery bank and I spent the next five years tracking 'em down.
Speaker 4:  Well Chris Welch is here. Hey Chris. Hello. Pleasure to be here. Chris covers,
Speaker 4:  I would say Sonos in to the closest degree possible. I
Speaker 4:  think it's
Speaker 8:  Kind of interesting you're here and not currently in the events at Sonos.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I'll take a break here and there. Okay. So, I wanna talk about what's
Speaker 4:  going on with Google and Sonos. There's big Ruling in that that patent case.
Speaker 4:  It's like a remarkable Ruling, So, I wanna spend some time there. But first
Speaker 4:  there's actually another trial that's ongoing, which we keep talking about
Speaker 4:  United States versus Google. It is a trial claiming that
Speaker 4:  effectively the deals Google makes with other vendors, most
Speaker 4:  notably Apple provide an illegal benefit to its search monopoly.
Speaker 4:  And those deals are bad. David, you've been in and outta that courtroom this
Speaker 4:  trial. If you've been listening to the You know this trial's really hard
Speaker 4:  to cover there. There's no streams, documents and
Speaker 4:  transcripts are hard to come by. There's been drama around that stuff.
Speaker 4:  So we've just been, when we can sending David into the courtroom in DC to
Speaker 4:  watch things go down, watch the various witnesses.
Speaker 4:  This last turn, it made it very clear that as
Speaker 4:  goes Apple goes the search market and it, I think it's like
Speaker 4:  under reported on under noticed that that is like the heart of this whole
Speaker 4:  case.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And ironically, this turn really started with
Speaker 5:  Satya Nadella, the c e O of Microsoft who a lot of people give
Speaker 5:  testimony in these things and they're prepared by a lot of lawyers to not
Speaker 5:  really say anything interesting. And there have been a few witnesses so far
Speaker 5:  who I know have spicy hot takes.
Speaker 5:  Some of them I have written about on The Verge dot com in stories
Speaker 5:  that I'm happy to send you links to who clearly were trained to like sort
Speaker 5:  of do the least in the courtroom. Satya Nadella was not one of those people.
Speaker 5:  Like dude came out swinging and essentially
Speaker 5:  began to make this case that binging is bad. It's worse than Google, but
Speaker 5:  the only reason binging is worse than Google is because of the Apple
Speaker 5:  deal. And that sounds like this like wild impossible
Speaker 5:  to navigate thing. But essentially what the argument has come down to, and
Speaker 5:  a number of people have made this argument and even Google has sort of
Speaker 5:  acknowledged that it understands this in a lot of the evidence that we've
Speaker 5:  seen in the exhibits that are being published. It, it's essentially that
Speaker 5:  if you can be the default search engine in Safari, which Google
Speaker 5:  has been for 20 years, for as long as there has been a safari, you will get
Speaker 5:  such market share so quickly and so many more
Speaker 5:  searches. Like I I, I have like learned how things like
Speaker 5:  query flow work and basically the like flywheel of the
Speaker 5:  more searches you get, the better the searches are. Thus you can make more
Speaker 5:  searches, thus you do better, thus you get more search like on and on and
Speaker 5:  on. And if anyone could break in,
Speaker 5:  overwhelmingly the industry seems to think there would be real
Speaker 5:  serious competitors to Google
Speaker 5:  essentially overnight. And that by not getting out
Speaker 5:  of its deal with Google or letting anybody else in Duck, duck go apparently
Speaker 5:  was in negotiations to do it for private browsing, which Gabriel Weinberg,
Speaker 5:  the c e o said would've been absolutely game changing for their business.
Speaker 5:  It would've increased their mult, their market share. I think he said multiple
Speaker 5:  times over. But like Apple is the moat for Google,
Speaker 5:  right? Like Google has Chrome and it has Android and it turns out it's
Speaker 5:  not illegal to like have your own products on your own products. So there's
Speaker 5:  really no fight there. But this one deal
Speaker 5:  that Apple has, if it gave it to somebody else, the DOJs
Speaker 5:  argument is that it would essentially raise up a serious
Speaker 5:  Google competitor out of nothing. And because Google is so rich,
Speaker 5:  it is preventing that from happening. And that's like, that has become the
Speaker 5:  thrust of the argument and it's really fascinating.
Speaker 4:  What do you think?
Speaker 5:  I think it's true. I mean it's, it's hard to say
Speaker 5:  counter factually, right? Like one of the things that Judge Meta, who's,
Speaker 5:  who's presiding over this case asked Satya Nadella was could a startup
Speaker 5:  in search succeed? Right? And there's been a bunch of talk about how the
Speaker 5:  search market is considered like a no-fly zone for VCs. They don't even invest
Speaker 5:  in it because it's not worth it. And so we asked him, he was like, can a
Speaker 5:  startup win its search? And Nadella like, thought about it for a second and
Speaker 5:  then just goes, well, there's no evidence for that. And
Speaker 5:  his point over and over was, he was like, we, I, I'm willing to lose
Speaker 5:  $15 billion a year to Apple just to get
Speaker 5:  the query flow and the market share that comes with it for binging. Microsoft
Speaker 5:  at one point thought about selling part or all of binging to Apple
Speaker 5:  in order to fund a competitor that could actually stand up to Google in a
Speaker 5:  real way because they don't think Google being this powerful is valuable.
Speaker 5:  Like there are a lot of reasons to believe that
Speaker 5:  what Apple could essentially turn that on for somebody else.
Speaker 5:  But also we have no proof. Google has been the partner for 20 years.
Speaker 5:  Like it was in the very first press release announcing Safari,
Speaker 5:  which they showed while Eddie Q was on the stand a couple of weeks ago,
Speaker 5:  mentioned Google as a partner and has been a partner ever since. And the
Speaker 5:  terms of that deal have changed. And so we've just never seen it. Like one
Speaker 5:  of the things that has really blown my mind is we've only ever seen one version
Speaker 5:  of the search market. There's never even been in like the modern
Speaker 5:  internet. Another world,
Speaker 4:  Well, there is if you leave this country, right, sure. That's that's also
Speaker 4:  come out right? In other countries, apple partners with other search providers
Speaker 4:  in Safari, and those companies are fine. They like exist
Speaker 4:  in
Speaker 5:  Our competitors. The index is very successful. Yeah. Yeah. And to be clear,
Speaker 6:  Like one of the reasons that if you put something else on Apple
Speaker 6:  instead, part of it was, okay, everybody's using it on Apple. So
Speaker 6:  that's just automatically they use it, but it would also learn and get better
Speaker 6:  because more people would be using it. Right? So that's how it would compete.
Speaker 6:  Or is it just like more people using it because it's on Apple and it's the
Speaker 6:  natural, the default search?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So the, the sort of universal truth of searches that the best way to
Speaker 5:  make a search engine is to already have a successful search engine. And
Speaker 5:  the more people use it, like one way to think about it is a big
Speaker 5:  part of your job as a search engine is to know when somebody
Speaker 5:  spells something wrong, what they're actually looking for, right? Like that's
Speaker 5:  a, that's a big job of a search engine. And the way that you do that is by
Speaker 5:  seeing the queries that people get wrong and then where they go
Speaker 5:  and you can figure out, okay, well they, they typed this word, they didn't
Speaker 5:  get what they wanted, then they typed that word, which looks very similar.
Speaker 5:  We can put those two things together and the next time somebody searches
Speaker 5:  for this wrongly spelled word, we can get it right the first time. You've
Speaker 5:  just instantly made your search engine better, right? Like you just can't
Speaker 5:  do that if you don't have the searches. And everyone
Speaker 5:  acknowledges this. This is not like a secret fact, this is like how the search
Speaker 5:  engine world works, is that the more search queries
Speaker 5:  you get, the better your ranking gets, the better your personalization gets,
Speaker 5:  the better your spell check gets, the better your, they, they call it, there's
Speaker 5:  a better term for it than this, but it's essentially query rewriting. So
Speaker 5:  when you type in a query, what do you actually mean? Are you looking for
Speaker 5:  a shopping link? Are you looking for travel? They, they do this thing where
Speaker 5:  they take the words that you use and then sort of boil it down to a set of
Speaker 5:  words that can also be used in a bunch of different ways. All of that you
Speaker 5:  can only do with the data. And the only way to get that data is to get people
Speaker 5:  searching. And so like what Nadella was saying is he's like, I don't want
Speaker 5:  any of the money that comes out of an Apple deal because
Speaker 5:  I'm so convinced that the product will get so much better that we'll make
Speaker 5:  up the rest of the money elsewhere. And that like, I don't think he's
Speaker 5:  just spouting out of his ass. Like that is the deal that Microsoft
Speaker 5:  has offered to Apple and loss.
Speaker 4:  I will say there's a deeply funny Google presentation that has been
Speaker 4:  entered into the exhibits here about iOS eight.
Speaker 5:  Oh, it's so good.
Speaker 4:  I mean, again, this is how long this has been going. Yeah, so an iOS eight
Speaker 4:  Apple World out spotlight, so you could just like pull down and do stuff
Speaker 4:  and there's a deck and we'll link to it and it's in David's piece. It's linked
Speaker 4:  there, but the deck is called, it's a Google deck. It's called iOS
Speaker 4:  eight Revenue Impact. And the first heading on the first
Speaker 4:  slide bottom line, it's bad.
Speaker 4:  Like Yep. It's like it's not, they're just like,
Speaker 4:  they're doing less searches. It's bad. And then it goes into it and like,
Speaker 4:  here's all the searches that Apple's doing for itself now and says, instead
Speaker 4:  of sending people to us, it's the app store and maps and Wikipedia and all
Speaker 4:  this stuff. Yeah. And they're just like, yeah, we're just losing searches
Speaker 4:  and revenue because any amount of any amount of loss from
Speaker 4:  Safari is huge. Right? Bottom line. It's bad. It's, but it's like so
Speaker 4:  funny. Well,
Speaker 5:  And that has become one of the new stipulations in
Speaker 5:  Google's deal with Apple as of I think 2016, is that Apple
Speaker 5:  can't do more in search than it had been doing in
Speaker 5:  2016. Right? Like by the terms of this agreement, apple is not allowed
Speaker 5:  to build a Google competitor or else it's in violation of this deal.
Speaker 4:  This explains by the way, several years ago there was like, IO and
Speaker 4:  WWC were like kind of back to back and at WW d c Apple
Speaker 4:  announced like some more search things in some version of iOS. This
Speaker 4:  is post 2016. And then we went to IO like several days
Speaker 4:  later and all like all the Google people were like apples to and some
Speaker 4:  search stuff.
Speaker 4:  And I, and I was at the time, I was like, yeah, they should, but I didn't
Speaker 4:  realize, like, they were like, oh, are they in trouble? Like, are they past
Speaker 4:  the line? And you would, we wouldn't know, right? 'cause this deal was a
Speaker 4:  secret until this trial.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean we, we, we knew there was a deal, but like the, the
Speaker 5:  machinations of the deal and both how
Speaker 5:  profitable it is for Apple and how exclusionary it is
Speaker 5:  are definitely, they're, they're coming out in really new ways. It's really
Speaker 5:  interesting
Speaker 4:  Just to say it and we should move on and talk about Sonos. I'm aware that
Speaker 4:  people think that Google should be able to pay whatever money to Apple for
Speaker 4:  whatever Apple wants to buy. And that, yes, I'm aware that many retail
Speaker 4:  stores in America have their own products they put on shelves and they pay
Speaker 4:  for placement. And you can make all kinds of analogies. And I'm just telling
Speaker 4:  you that winning an argument through analogy is like kissing your sister.
Speaker 4:  Like that's just fine. I don't care. You know you didn't do anything. Can
Speaker 4:  I wait?
Speaker 5:  You don't care. Can I just tell you one very quick courtroom story that summarizes
Speaker 5:  this entire thing very well? At one point during Satya NA's testimony,
Speaker 5:  judge Meta, who I wouldn't say interrupts a lot, but he'll occasionally like
Speaker 5:  follow up on questions or ask to clarify and like he, he does a lot of sort
Speaker 5:  of drilling down on technical things that either he doesn't understand or
Speaker 5:  he wants in the record or whatever. He at one point looks over at Del and
Speaker 5:  says, okay, imagine you're Tim Cook. Why would you wanna switch to
Speaker 5:  Bing when it's a worst search engine? And that was the whole question. And
Speaker 5:  like you could like Google You know they have a table full of lawyers. Like
Speaker 5:  you could just feel the vibe in the room. Everybody at the Google table is
Speaker 5:  just like, yes.
Speaker 4:  Because that's the whole defense
Speaker 5:  Is that like Satya Nadella getting up there and saying binging is not as
Speaker 5:  good as Google is both a, a case against Google
Speaker 5:  and the entire Google defense, which is that it is not illegal to be the
Speaker 5:  best product and everyone is acknowledging that is the best, it is the best
Speaker 5:  product. It it's just, it's a very funny thing where like D O J
Speaker 5:  has to do this thing where they're saying Google is really good because no
Speaker 5:  one else is allowed to be and Google is just going to keep saying,
Speaker 5:  we're good. And that's okay. Yeah. And that's a really, really, really
Speaker 5:  compelling argument. Like being the best is not a
Speaker 5:  problem and Google is going to spend a lot of time when it turns and
Speaker 5:  becomes Google's chance to really give its argument. It's gonna spend a lot
Speaker 5:  of time telling us how terrific Google is. And I'm very much
Speaker 5:  looking forward to like that second half of this trial. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I think Google is too, to be perfectly honest.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  Alright. Speaking of Google on a, on a high in the legal
Speaker 4:  system. Yes. I mean this is, this is as
Speaker 4:  when it comes to the patent wars, this is as Slam
Speaker 4:  Donkey swagger off the court as it's gotten a while, Chris, what's going
Speaker 4:  on?
Speaker 15:  Sonos got its ass handed into it and in court had a
Speaker 15:  32.5 million judgment tossed out by Judge William Sup
Speaker 15:  one of the most high profile judges who, who's covered, who knows how many
Speaker 15:  tech cases. And
Speaker 4:  We profiled him. Yeah,
Speaker 15:  We profiled him. Profiled him. Yeah. And so he knows his stuff. He knows
Speaker 15:  what Sonos is, how long they've been around. And if you read this Ruling,
Speaker 15:  it's really like a super deep dive on zones and like different rooms
Speaker 15:  and overlapping zones. And so he knows this stuff. And so it comes down
Speaker 15:  to, he just said that Sonos took too long to really You know, come up
Speaker 15:  with these complaints and say Google was copying its technology. 13 years
Speaker 15:  is really the time between like their first application. And then when they
Speaker 15:  like said You know, hey, Google is stealing our ideas and trying to copy
Speaker 15:  multi-room audio. And so the patents that they
Speaker 15:  had included were rule to be said. They were, they're now invalid
Speaker 15:  and also unenforceable. And so
Speaker 5:  In like big bold letters in the Ruling, I very much enjoyed that. It was
Speaker 5:  like a different font for the word unenforceable, which I really liked. So
Speaker 15:  He calls Sonos a pretender and he says Google is the innovator, which is
Speaker 15:  is a little harsh man. Like, ooh, You know. Like Sonos is the company that
Speaker 15:  like has made this their whole brand You know So I feel like that was a
Speaker 15:  little, little mean what did, but what did
Speaker 6:  Google innovate in this space? Yeah.
Speaker 15:  I
Speaker 4:  Like, that's a really good question because
Speaker 6:  Honestly this whole case, the entire time we, we've heard about it and,
Speaker 6:  and we've been covering it and stuff, it always seemed like Sonos was kind
Speaker 6:  of in the right. Google used
Speaker 4:  Well no. So there this whole,
Speaker 6:  And then that all got thrown out and like yeah,
Speaker 4:  This case has a bunch of twists and turns. The heart of it is
Speaker 4:  like not patents. Yeah. And I, this has always been, and
Speaker 4:  we had Patrick Spence and at the time Sonos ISS chief legal counsel on
Speaker 4:  the show and we talked about why you would sue Google and like they're using
Speaker 4:  their patents because they're mad about something else. Yes. Which
Speaker 4:  many people have many feelings about. Yeah. Right. What are they mad about?
Speaker 4:  They basically like went to go work with Google and then Google like immediately
Speaker 4:  undercut them on business terms. They released,
Speaker 15:  Put out cheap speakers that cost $49.
Speaker 4:  Right. They like immediately undercut them with cheaper speakers that copied
Speaker 4:  their features. So they did the thing that every big company has always done
Speaker 4:  to small companies forever.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They pulled an
Speaker 4:  Amazon, you can, yeah, you can replace Google with Amazon and Sonos is just
Speaker 4:  as mad, but Amazon lets them use Alexa. Like it's, it's like they're
Speaker 4:  Sonos is in this weird position where they need access to
Speaker 4:  voice assistance or they, at the time they did and they just
Speaker 4:  ended up really upside down with Google. Yeah. Right. And they thought they,
Speaker 4:  they felt very strongly that Google taken advantage of them. So then they
Speaker 4:  said, well look, we invented a bunch of this technology, we've been around
Speaker 4:  for a long time. We're gonna sue Google for patent infringement that will
Speaker 4:  create some leverage and Google will inevitably settle because why wouldn't
Speaker 4:  they? And then we can't get along. And that was like more or less the story.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 15:  Three years later.
Speaker 4:  And then Google did not settle and Sonos won the judgment and then Google
Speaker 4:  appealed and now Alsip is like here, what's the quote? It is wrong
Speaker 4:  that our patent system was used in this way. This is from the Ruling
Speaker 4:  with its constitutional underpinnings. The system is intended to promote
Speaker 4:  and protect innovation here. By contrast, it was used to punish an innovator
Speaker 4:  and enrich a pretender by delay in slight of hand. It
Speaker 4:  has taken a full trial to learn this sad fact, but it long
Speaker 4:  last a measure of justice is done. Like it's, I mean it's
Speaker 4:  a good, it's a lot. Yeah. You would think that it was a murder trial,
Speaker 4:  right?
Speaker 6:  Like what did Sonos do to this judge?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So this judge is like, my fucking speakers keep disappearing. Like
Speaker 4:  that's what he's,
Speaker 6:  He had to do that transition from Sonos version one to two,
Speaker 15:  That S two, he was ready
Speaker 6:  Over
Speaker 4:  The line. He was super mad at play three. He is just sitting there and he
Speaker 4:  is like a measure of justice for the Sonos play three,
Speaker 4:  I don't know man it again for Google it's 30 million. Like Google
Speaker 4:  sneezes that money, we're just talking about like a $10 billion deal with
Speaker 4:  Apple. They paying money. But anyway, so now
Speaker 4:  Google's one, they put out a statement that is just,
Speaker 15:  Yeah, I was taking a victory lap and saying the patent system needs reform
Speaker 15:  and this and that. And Somos came back and said the same thing of course.
Speaker 15:  But also, also they still wanna keep on fighting Google because they're
Speaker 15:  trying to like trying to protect their patents and innovations and they're
Speaker 15:  trying to like get royalties, which I think is the main crux of this whole
Speaker 15:  thing is like they want all these tech companies to like pay them royalties
Speaker 15:  for their technology and like multi-room audio and And what whatnot. And
Speaker 15:  that's clearly not something that Google is, will budge on anytime soon
Speaker 15:  as we've seen. And so three years later there's no sign of a settlement,
Speaker 15:  there's no Google Assistant on the new Sono speakers still, which I think
Speaker 15:  is a worst experience for customers. Yep. Customers always, I, I won't buy
Speaker 15:  it. Always suffer. Yeah. And yeah, I think, I mean like Sonos was
Speaker 15:  concerned about these companies putting out cheaper speakers, but I feel
Speaker 15:  like Google and Amazon really don't care about audio as much anymore. You
Speaker 15:  know, like the Nest audio came out three years ago and like Google hasn't
Speaker 15:  put out a new speaker. That was good since
Speaker 4:  Then. Yeah. I don't even care about their voice assistants anymore. There
Speaker 4:  was just that new It's Marshall, right. That has both assistant on it at
Speaker 4:  the same time. I think it
Speaker 15:  Was jbl, L J B L. Sorry. But yeah, that is both, both things. Which
Speaker 15:  Sonos said once that like they wouldn't couldn't do that by Google's own
Speaker 15:  terms. They weren't allowed to do that. And so now we see it happening on
Speaker 15:  this other speaker. So You know, I think it's time to hopefully settle because
Speaker 15:  I think Sonos has its You know, oh
Speaker 4:  There's no way. I'm sorry.
Speaker 15:  Has its own place carved.
Speaker 4:  If you have a long last, a measure of justice is done in in your back
Speaker 6:  Pocket. Google's never settling,
Speaker 4:  There's no settling happening here.
Speaker 15:  Yeah. I just feel like Sonos You know like they're, they're safe. They have
Speaker 15:  their You know you just walk into like any Best Buy or Target and there's
Speaker 15:  like a Sonos section there. Like they're not a small company. Well,
Speaker 4:  Compared to Google. Yeah. Compared
Speaker 15:  To Google. Yes. But like You know, like small company like David versus
Speaker 15:  Goliath thing is like You know they're a pretty sizable audio company compared
Speaker 15:  to like Whim or Weem And what's that brand that Chris person loves a lot?
Speaker 15:  Like Yeah, that's a small company whim. Sonos Wim. Yeah. Sonos is
Speaker 15:  a bit larger than that. So I
Speaker 4:  Will say, Chris and I, earlier this week we went and visited a
Speaker 4:  studio where Dolby was showing off how they mix in Atmos
Speaker 4:  and their test product was at an era 300. Right?
Speaker 4:  Right. And it was actually really funny 'cause it was a prototype and it
Speaker 4:  had the word prototype like printed on it. And I was like, Chris had every
Speaker 4:  part of this scoop except a picture of a prototype with the word prototype
Speaker 4:  on it. But like, but that's it. Like the, the recording industry is like
Speaker 4:  in on Sonos, right? Like that is the test product. And Chris was like, do
Speaker 4:  you ever test on the home pod? And they're like, no, no, no, no, no we don't.
Speaker 4:  No thank you.
Speaker 15:  No home pod that.
Speaker 4:  And it's true. Yeah. I don't think the Amazon products are like huge successes
Speaker 4:  in the audio world. The Google products certainly aren't. Right. Yeah.
Speaker 15:  Like yeah, Sonos has like the move to which like none of these brands really
Speaker 15:  have their own version of So. I feel like Sonos as a business is pretty
Speaker 15:  secure. So like at least You know, like move towards some kind of resolution
Speaker 15:  here. Like for the benefit of people and customers who want Google Assistant
Speaker 15:  on their Sonos speaker and You know. And when
Speaker 6:  Originally sued Google, it was not as as secure Right
Speaker 6:  as it is now. Right. Like, like at the time it was very much we are fighting
Speaker 6:  an existential threat from Amazon and from Google and we
Speaker 6:  do not know how our company is going to continue. And if we don't
Speaker 6:  figure that out, we're screwed.
Speaker 4:  So that was a framing. I mean if I Lawsuit. Lawsuit,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It was our framing.
Speaker 4:  I believe it was at css. I think we were in Vegas when the lawsuit hit and
Speaker 4:  it was just before we assumed both companies would announce a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. And they announced a bunch of stuff. You know a theme of this
Speaker 4:  podcast is that like, Google products don't last a long time. And it's like
Speaker 4:  looking back we're like, oh were were they gonna stay committed to the Nest
Speaker 4:  audio or could you have just waited them out? Well I think
Speaker 6:  What that was a curiosity was like, okay, this is probably almost certainly
Speaker 6:  not gonna be as good as whatever Sonos does, but it'll cheaper. Is it gonna
Speaker 6:  be cheaper? And then push Sonos out that way. And so Sonos is
Speaker 6:  shrinks and shrinks and instead Sonos is like, feels like it's kind of turned
Speaker 6:  it or doing well, right. Apart from this. Well,
Speaker 4:  I mean I'm curious what Chris's take here, but it seems like they, they didn't
Speaker 4:  just become a patent troll. They invented a whole bunch of stuff, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Right. And Patrick Spence has been on the show a bunch of time being
Speaker 4:  like, the pace of innovation, we need to pick it up. We need to go faster.
Speaker 4:  They're on a yearly cadence now. Yeah. Before Patrick showed up, they were
Speaker 4:  on like a one decade cadence. Yes. You know, like,
Speaker 4:  so like I think they did the right thing there for sure.
Speaker 4:  I I this rule you should read the rule. It's like a fun read. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  To read this Ruling. 'cause it, he's just so mad, he's sad,
Speaker 15:  So angry that any
Speaker 4:  Of this happened. I I think there's like an
Speaker 4:  equal amount of mad at Google that you could be because they
Speaker 4:  didn't like 70, 80% of cases settle
Speaker 4:  and if your Google it is probably better to
Speaker 4:  settle and move on and also have Google Assistant be available on all
Speaker 4:  kinds of devices for what is peanuts in the scheme of Google.
Speaker 4:  Right. But it's a fun distribu and like a measure
Speaker 4:  of justice is done. It's, it's incredible for a, for a
Speaker 4:  a multi-zone audio patent lawsuit.
Speaker 4:  What's going on over there? Bill? You All right?
Speaker 4:  Still still pissed about the, the play three like air, three hundred's
Speaker 4:  out. It's a replacement.
Speaker 6:  Seems real nice.
Speaker 4:  It's, it sounds great. Chris loves it.
Speaker 15:  I do. I do like most of their products. You know Google and Amazon, their
Speaker 15:  speakers are fine. Like the Echo Studio is fine. It's been sitting there
Speaker 15:  like untouched for like three or four years now. So. But it sounds nice.
Speaker 15:  I just think tho those companies clearly don't care about audio as much
Speaker 15:  as they once to I think Apple, like if there's one company that someone
Speaker 15:  should be like pretty concerned about, it's Apple HomePod and like AirPods
Speaker 15:  You know like headphones if they ever get into headphones, obviously that's
Speaker 15:  gonna be a hard climb for Sonos to do And I think there will be like a
Speaker 15:  You know some kinda Apple soundbar at some point. It seems like they're
Speaker 15:  super interested in the computer. Do
Speaker 4:  You think Apple's gonna make a soundbar? Yeah. Oh
Speaker 6:  Yeah. With the home pods as as satellites, right?
Speaker 15:  Yeah, yeah. Something like that. Yeah. I think they're gonna
Speaker 4:  No way
Speaker 15:  Come into their territory at point
Speaker 4:  A bit. Way more.
Speaker 6:  No way. It's gonna be like the KU one. It's gonna have an Apple TV
Speaker 4:  Building unless can figure out how to sell you extra iCloud storage the product.
Speaker 4:  They will never make it. Well I go
Speaker 15:  With the trouble of like letting you use two home pods as like E Arc outputs
Speaker 15:  if they're not gonna like make a proper soundbar at some point
Speaker 4:  They did that. Like they did that under duress. They're like
Speaker 4:  God damnit You know like straight up like enough people just
Speaker 4:  annoyed them about this thing. Yeah. And then like probably Phil Schiller
Speaker 4:  and his house was like, why do I have other speakers? You know. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But actually a soundbar no way. 0% chance. I don't know.
Speaker 4:  They are not interested in that market Percent.
Speaker 15:  We can have a wager, we can have a wager,
Speaker 4:  A wager. Apple will release a cheap Vision pro before they release
Speaker 4:  a soundbar.
Speaker 15:  Okay. Wow. You're
Speaker 6:  Gonna make some money Chris.
Speaker 15:  I'm pretty proud.
Speaker 6:  I'm really excited for you.
Speaker 15:  Yeah, me too.
Speaker 4:  All, right? This is, this is an important prediction on it. You think they're
Speaker 4:  gonna make a soundbar?
Speaker 15:  I mean what's a cheap vision pro? We should really get into that. A
Speaker 4:  Thousand dollars, a thousand dollars dollars.
Speaker 6:  Ooh
Speaker 4:  That's cheap. I think that's, I think for a product of Vision Pro that's,
Speaker 4:  it's, I think you still have good odds significantly now
Speaker 15:  I think I'm, yeah I think I'm still feeling pretty good about some kind
Speaker 15:  of like Apple tv, four K, soundbar, HomePod, concoction, You know one of
Speaker 15:  those things all melted.
Speaker 4:  When I think of Apple, I think of Concoctions. It's
Speaker 5:  Feel, we'll see an important stipulation is you only win if Apple calls
Speaker 5:  it a soundbar, which is never ever, ever, ever, ever
Speaker 5:  will
Speaker 4:  Not single, what would it call it?
Speaker 5:  Not a single chance. Who knows? There's
Speaker 4:  A 0% chance Apple. I just wanna be so
Speaker 5:  Clear about this. Yeah, I'm with Neli on this. Like that's, it's never gonna
Speaker 5:  happen. I don't know, one thing I've been thinking about a lot with this
Speaker 5:  is it seems like one of the things that happened from when this
Speaker 5:  Ruling star or from when this trial started to today is that the
Speaker 5:  stakes for audio seem like they've gone way down. Like if you
Speaker 5:  rewind a bunch of years to when this all started, we were in this phase where
Speaker 5:  like voice assistance were gonna be the next big thing. Everybody was gonna
Speaker 5:  use them, they were gonna be huge businesses. Sonos was under pressure to
Speaker 5:  like be part of this because the idea was you were gonna have speakers all
Speaker 5:  over your house and you were gonna talk to them and that was your gonna be
Speaker 5:  your main interface with technology. And like that idea is
Speaker 5:  not dead but like not alive anymore. And so
Speaker 5:  now we're back to this speaker business and Google and Amazon have no
Speaker 5:  interest in being in the speaker business. They're in the, they're in the
Speaker 5:  business of getting you to use their assistance but they're even getting
Speaker 5:  out of those businesses. Like Amazon is shedding the Alexa team in a big
Speaker 5:  way. Google is gonna put borrowed into assistant but is already like pretty
Speaker 5:  clearly pivoting the way that it thinks about that as a tool. Like
Speaker 5:  we're just out of this phase where speakers are going to be the centerpiece
Speaker 5:  of your home and they're back to being speakers. And I think if we're gonna
Speaker 5:  go back to being speakers, that's probably good news for Sonos, right? Because
Speaker 5:  these other companies just aren't gonna care that much about it.
Speaker 15:  Yeah. Right. So then it's like why keep fighting this battle? You know,
Speaker 15:  like just You know.
Speaker 5:  I think at some point if you're Google you're like, we, we can't go down
Speaker 5:  this road because then we're gonna end up paying royalties on everything
Speaker 5:  every time we screw over a small tech company and we're hosed. Like the
Speaker 5:  fight for them seems like it's on like patent principle rather than
Speaker 5:  the specifics of this case. Right? Whereas Sonos like needed
Speaker 5:  this win a lot more back then. But at this point, I
Speaker 5:  don't know, like I don't know how big Sonos loses here.
Speaker 6:  Sonos has gotta fight 'cause they got owned so hard
Speaker 6:  in this judgment like
Speaker 5:  Oh sure they did. Yeah, for sure.
Speaker 6:  If I got owned that hard I would fight. Even if I knew I was gonna lose,
Speaker 6:  I'd be like, no, I'm still going.
Speaker 4:  Well to be clear, so they lost it. This court. Okay, they need to appeal
Speaker 4:  to an appeals court, right? Yeah.
Speaker 15:  And so there's this case and there's still several others. There's one at
Speaker 15:  the I T C where they've won a few times to ban like very old
Speaker 15:  Google products that you can't even buy anymore. As is usually the case
Speaker 15:  with those lawsuits, Neil. And so yeah, there's other counter
Speaker 15:  suits from Google and several countries. So it's still just like a very
Speaker 15:  like very angry feud that seems to have no sign of
Speaker 15:  cooling down anytime soon. Which seems a bit silly at this point.
Speaker 4:  Well now that a measure of justice has been done, I don't know why you don't
Speaker 4:  say that All. There's a long road you can, there's an appeals court. I love
Speaker 4:  the idea of our current Supreme court being made to cons deeply consider
Speaker 4:  multi-room audio. That's
Speaker 6:  All I want. David just sitting in the,
Speaker 4:  Oh my god. A pile of soundbars has arrived at Justice Clarence Thomas' house
Speaker 4:  and he didn't refuse them. Oh no,
Speaker 4:  I can't help it if my friends own a jet and love surround
Speaker 4:  sound. All. right. We gotta take a break. We'll do a lightning round and
Speaker 4:  then we'll get outta here. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  All. right, we're back. Lightning around time. Alex, you wanna start? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  There's a new piece.
Speaker 4:  Oh by the way, a number of people have told us that we need to change the
Speaker 4:  lightning around to U S P C round 'cause You know
Speaker 6:  It's not as pow sounding. It's
Speaker 4:  It also, it's not named after the port.
Speaker 4:  I don't know how to, it's
Speaker 6:  Just a lightning
Speaker 4:  Round. We have multiple that's just a noun. This is
Speaker 5:  The P C I round. Get ready everybody.
Speaker 4:  It's the Thunderbolt four round. Okay, go ahead. Alex
Speaker 6:  Sponsored by Intel. Oh my gosh. Oh sorry.
Speaker 4:  You gotta pay us money for that.
Speaker 6:  Me or Intel someone. Someone
Speaker 4:  If you wanna pay us to sponsor the Thunderbolt fore round,
Speaker 4:  I'm not gonna say no All. right, go ahead. There's some journalistic integrity
Speaker 4:  there. I'm, there's transparent disclosure. I will accept money if
Speaker 4:  it's funny.
Speaker 6:  All, right, so the Sony PS five, it's got a new Sony PS five.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, just like now. Now you can go buy one and that is a perfect time to
Speaker 6:  be like, no, we got new ones coming. It's been rumored for a while. It's
Speaker 6:  smaller, it's slimmer. It should actually fit in most home
Speaker 6:  theater setups, which the current one doesn't.
Speaker 5:  Okay, I I would like to quibble with that particular assessment. Yeah. This
Speaker 5:  thing is Jake, you
Speaker 6:  Probably have an ugly home theater setup. This thing
Speaker 5:  Went from being preposterously humongous to very
Speaker 5:  slightly less preposterously. Humongous.
Speaker 15:  Yeah. I think there's a piece on the side actually by JP Peters that says
Speaker 15:  the Slim PS five is still huge. So it's, it's a
Speaker 15:  chunk,
Speaker 5:  It's it's smoother now it's much more like straightforward i f R on Lord
Speaker 5:  of the The Rings now than it was. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  No, no, but it's 24% lighter, which I think is very
Speaker 6:  important. People, my
Speaker 5:  Home Peter system will be psyched about that. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  This is the thing that you put down once and never, never touch again. Right.
Speaker 6:  I'm just, look, these are the specs they gave us and this is what they're
Speaker 6:  proud.
Speaker 4:  Have you seen, have you seen the stand for horizontal mode? I didn't know
Speaker 6:  You're supposed to use the current one with the stand and
Speaker 4:  So you just had your current one horizontal the whole time. Yeah. Oh
Speaker 6:  Boy. To fit in my home theater system, I had to clear a whole
Speaker 4:  Shelf. I'll say that Sony picked and then picked another shape that
Speaker 4:  incompatible with most furniture. Yeah. Yes. They're just like, oh this is
Speaker 4:  for a rectangle to hell with you.
Speaker 4:  But the little stand to be horizontal is not a stand. It's just like a little
Speaker 4:  peg. It's like a little peg leg.
Speaker 6:  I know. I just like stuck in like a something under there. There's the
Speaker 15:  Stand you can detach the optical drive, which is truly wild. That's
Speaker 6:  Wild. Yeah. Yeah. The the optical drive I think is most interesting. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  this is the part like Tom Warren, when he was looking at the news, he was
Speaker 6:  like, oh my God, that's so cool. And like yeah, it
Speaker 6:  is cool. It, it, it looks, it's, it seems fairly elegant way to,
Speaker 6:  to do it. 'cause you can now go same price,
Speaker 6:  24% lighter, 30%
Speaker 6:  smaller by volume.
Speaker 4:  Hey, that's, those are how people consider game consoles. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Xbox or PS five. I'm going with 30% smaller by volume.
Speaker 6:  That's what you should have listed on like the the Costco website. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  The Best Buy website.
Speaker 5:  My water displacement is gonna go so far down when I read it.
Speaker 15:  Still feel like physical media is like slowly dying here. Like this is like
Speaker 15:  an optional like optical drive. You can have it if you want it, if you wanna
Speaker 15:  watch four K of Blu-ray, like that new Xbox that leaked has like has no
Speaker 15:  more drive in there anymore. So, I feel like we're slowly inching towards
Speaker 15:  like a gaming world where it's like all digital.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah, yeah. We're getting rid of the, the, the drives. But the drives
Speaker 6:  are actually important. They're good. If you wanna watch
Speaker 6:  DVDs and, and U h d Blu-rays and everything, like only three
Speaker 6:  people in the world and they're all in this room. Yeah, would do. But
Speaker 6:  it's a little cheaper, right? Like it's four 50 starting for the digital,
Speaker 6:  the the disc free one and previously it was 4 99 for, for the
Speaker 6:  digital free one and then the, the new base like
Speaker 6:  model with the drive already installed is gonna be 4 99, which
Speaker 6:  was the old price for the disc free one. So that's kind of nice. And
Speaker 6:  then there's gonna be the display which is 80 bucks additional and
Speaker 6:  integrates kind of neatly. You can go look at it on the website. It's, it's
Speaker 6:  cool, there's like a little video. It shows the integration and it is cool.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But like you should also go look at Jay's story about how much
Speaker 6:  smaller it is because like 30% volume does not actually track
Speaker 6:  to dimensions. Yeah.
Speaker 15:  You still don't wanna measure your cabinet and make sure it'll, it'll fit
Speaker 15:  in
Speaker 4:  It again. It is also a shape that is incompatible with most things. You can't
Speaker 6:  Stack on it then you just slide off. It's horrible.
Speaker 4:  I think that yeah, yeah. All right Chris what you got
Speaker 15:  My pick of the week is the speakers on the Pixel eight Pro.
Speaker 15:  If you've owned a Pixel over the last few years, you've known that Google
Speaker 15:  for some reason has put like terrible out speakers in their phones. This
Speaker 15:  started with the Pixel five. They had some weird like vibration motor that
Speaker 15:  like made sound and then they went back to like standard speakers for the
Speaker 15:  Pixel six and Pixel seven. But they were tinny and hollow and just sounded
Speaker 15:  like absolute trash. And so since the Pixel eight
Speaker 15:  pro now costs a thousand dollars, you would hope and pray that the speaker
Speaker 15:  is decent. Like I don't use my speaker a ton, but if I'm in bed and You
Speaker 15:  know playing a podcast or watching a video, I want it to sound decent. I
Speaker 15:  don't wanna spend a grand on a phone and have it sound like absolute garbage.
Speaker 15:  And so finally Google, I'm happy to say has a speaker that sounds
Speaker 15:  comparable to the iPhone. Not quite. Okay. The level of the iPhone 15 Pro
Speaker 15:  Max but You know it's in that ballpark, which was certainly not the case
Speaker 15:  last year. Yeah. Or the year before that. Or the year before that.
Speaker 5:  My wife has a Pixel six and I mean just by virtue
Speaker 5:  of like what I do for a living, I have 400,000 speakers in this
Speaker 5:  house. She steadfastly refuses to use any of them and
Speaker 5:  just plays everything out of her phone. And the rage it has filled me with
Speaker 5:  in the last two years as she has had this phone of how bad it sounds all
Speaker 5:  the time. She's just like, oh we're gonna like put on some music while we
Speaker 5:  have dinner. And I'm like, there's a Sonos like you're connected to this
Speaker 5:  Sonos. And she's like, no, I'll just, I'll just put it on my phone. It'll
Speaker 5:  be fine.
Speaker 4:  This is podcast through Becky's phone. Yes. I'm like, Hey what kind of speaker
Speaker 4:  should I get? Should I put speakers in the ceiling in your house? She's like,
Speaker 4:  I don't know. I listen to podcasts in my phone. I'm like, but there's
Speaker 4:  a world of possibilities exist for you. No, no podcast in my phone.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So like to me the speaker upgrade might be the single most important thing
Speaker 5:  about the Pixel eight. And I will probably be buying Anna one as a result.
Speaker 5:  It's very exciting for me.
Speaker 15:  It's a good phone and it doesn't get that hot anymore. Which was pretty
Speaker 15:  concerning about the past.
Speaker 4:  That's a real part of this generation of phones is boy they get real hot
Speaker 4:  when you first buy 'em.
Speaker 15:  Gotta be careful that Instagram, it's a heavy resource intensive app. All.
Speaker 15:  right.
Speaker 4:  I'll make mine quick. There's another trial that's happening right now. Sam
Speaker 4:  Bankman Free is on trial for the F T X. We'll just call it fraud. I mean
Speaker 4:  I think it's like fairly obvious what happened here. And Liz Lipato
Speaker 4:  is here in New York. She's been at the courthouse filing reports every day.
Speaker 4:  It is some of the funniest coverage we've ever had on the site. It is Liz
Speaker 4:  at Full Force in terms of being a writer. Some just the funniest
Speaker 4:  writing we've had on the site. Her last headline is Sim Bankman. Fried
Speaker 4:  was a terrible boyfriend. I mean perfect. Just like perfect. Just go read
Speaker 4:  it, go read it. All it. She's doing it basically every day. There's like
Speaker 4:  an army of people waiting, just like waiting for her edits at the end of
Speaker 4:  like the courtroom day. It's all very funny and the dude did
Speaker 4:  it. I don't like, I don't want to turn this into too much of a true crime
Speaker 4:  podcast, but after extensive investigation I can
Speaker 4:  exclusively reveal that F T X was a scam
Speaker 4:  and it was obvious the entire time in crypto was a fraud. Just Michael Lewis
Speaker 5:  Is gonna find you and fight you.
Speaker 4:  That dude we do have another hour.
Speaker 4:  Did he see the thing Michael Lewis, he wrote the blindside that book, which
Speaker 4:  is now in a substantial amount of controversy. But he had a state, I think
Speaker 4:  he gave an interview time this week. He's like, I wrote my book for the jury.
Speaker 4:  They should read my book. And it's like, no, they should do the trial.
Speaker 4:  I think that might be a substantially better use of their time. They should
Speaker 4:  watch Money Ball Base
Speaker 15:  There.
Speaker 4:  Such that. Pretty good. Okay. Read Liz's coverage. It's great.
Speaker 4:  It's really fun. All right? That was mine. David, what's yours?
Speaker 5:  I would just like to very quickly appeal to Samsung and Google to
Speaker 5:  stop being so embarrassing trying to convince Apple to support
Speaker 5:  RCS.
Speaker 4:  Oh no. Do we have to disclose that Dieter Bone, former host of The
Speaker 4:  Vergecast regularly tweets at Apple about
Speaker 4:  RCS. Sure.
Speaker 5:  There you go. Done. Disclosed Dieter is right to be clear, Google is
Speaker 5:  right. Samsung is right. Apple should support RCS. It is a, it is
Speaker 5:  a better system. S m s is like a technological disaster that should no longer
Speaker 5:  exist and we should stop using it. Silly YouTube videos
Speaker 5:  from major competitors are not going to
Speaker 5:  convince Apple to do anything. In fact, I would argue
Speaker 5:  that every time Samsung and Google say to Apple,
Speaker 5:  do RCS or you won't be cool anymore, Tim Cook just like,
Speaker 5:  I don't
Speaker 4:  Know, buy your mom an iPhone
Speaker 5:  Throws the cat out the window and like Cackles, I don't know, whatever he
Speaker 5:  does throws
Speaker 4:  A cat out the window. I dunno. He's like, bring me another cat.
Speaker 4:  Samsung's at it again. Open the cat room.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And like, and now Samsung's whole thing is like, we're bubbles
Speaker 5:  too and it's just like, it's not gonna work. Yeah. Go
Speaker 5:  go pick the a fight with carriers. Go try to like
Speaker 5:  covertly destroy s m s from the outside. Like pick,
Speaker 5:  pick any fight you want or just like wait for the EU to make Apple You know
Speaker 5:  interoperate with all of the other messaging apps and it'll be fine. But
Speaker 5:  like, it
Speaker 15:  Just seems kind of sad. It's like all the teens are leaving our phones.
Speaker 15:  We have to like come up with these ad campaigns to put
Speaker 5:  Up a fight. Like I want this to happen and they're doing it wrong
Speaker 5:  and I would like them to stop.
Speaker 4:  It's real cringe. Here's, here's what Google can do. Have a messaging app
Speaker 4:  that people like to use.
Speaker 6:  Stick with it for longer
Speaker 4:  Than you should call it Gchat, an app. Which people
Speaker 4:  firmly believed that they used and loved but which Google never made.
Speaker 15:  I don't mean I think Alo was the way that was the,
Speaker 4:  My God,
Speaker 6:  It's all about do
Speaker 4:  All right? I'm just saying, and Google has enough money. You just got your
Speaker 4:  $30 million back. Just give everybody five bucks
Speaker 4:  is fine. Just do it. You'll, you'll, you'll get a substantial
Speaker 4:  user base just five bucks at a time. That's how the D
Speaker 4:  VCs did it.
Speaker 6:  Couldn't they just put it into their
Speaker 4:  Next for while
Speaker 6:  What search deal with iOS. Just be like, okay, we'll let you use
Speaker 6:  our search. But also
Speaker 4:  Tim Cook is gonna throw so many cats out the window if they bring that up.
Speaker 4:  Just bring me a Tiger
Speaker 4:  All. right? He's he's he's a fit man. Yeah, he is.
Speaker 4:  He can lift a large cat. That's all Im saying. He could, he could throw a
Speaker 4:  large tiger. Okay. Please send us a note with your thoughts on how large
Speaker 4:  of a cat Tim Cook can lift. Doesn't he go to the gym at like
Speaker 4:  5:00 AM every day? Yeah. I'm saying it's a, I think it's a larger cat than
Speaker 4:  you expect. Expect it's a big cat. Yeah, I agree. All, right? That's, we
Speaker 4:  gotta end it here. I would also accept AI generated images of Tim
Speaker 4:  Cook lifting a large cat just putting up in the world. You
Speaker 4:  gotta manifest what you want. You know and that's what I want. Send 'em to
Speaker 4:  us at The Vergecast. we love hearing from you. Monday Connectivity miniseries
Speaker 4:  comes back with beeper co speaking of messaging app
Speaker 4:  Beeper co-founder Eric Majkowski, who is a longtime friend of The Verge.
Speaker 4:  That's gonna be really exciting. David's got installer, which can I reveal
Speaker 4:  this stat, David? Sure. I
Speaker 18:  Don't. Sure. Maybe.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You're just well over 10,000 subscribers now. Oh yeah. It's like zero
Speaker 4:  to 10,000. Amazing people love it. Subscribe to that. And then I'm
Speaker 4:  not gonna tell you what's happening on Decoder 'cause I don't know, but I
Speaker 4:  think something very exciting is gonna happen in Decoder very soon. That's
Speaker 4:  what I got for you. All, right? That's it. That's Vergecast Rock Home.
Speaker 18:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 18:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The Vergecast is a
Speaker 18:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 18:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. We'll see you next week.