# Transcript
ID: 0c0bf5cb-c1b2-43f2-9d0d-f09b37cbeedc
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The Verge guide to holiday shopping
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/3196430261313802934/346210007668421802/s93290-US-3646s-1701859373.mp3
Description: The Verge's David Pierce, Victoria Song, Dan Seifert, and Jennifer Pattison Tuohy answer questions from the Vergecast Hotline about what to buy for your loved ones this holiday season.
Keep emailing us at vergecast@theverge.com or leave a voicemail at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (1 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of using gift cards to buy
Speaker 2:  other gift cards. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am seemingly as
Speaker 2:  always these days on a walk home from dropping my kid off at daycare. Do
Speaker 2:  you remember how a few weeks ago I told you that I was trying to like be
Speaker 2:  a person who walks and go on idea walks and get the blood flowing
Speaker 2:  and get out in the world? It turns out that was a super fun,
Speaker 2:  good plan until it got to be cold. And now
Speaker 2:  I have settled into the routine that I forget about every year, but always
Speaker 2:  settle into again about this time, which is where I only go outside when
Speaker 2:  absolutely a hundred percent necessary. And right now that is basically
Speaker 2:  to walk the dog or take my kid to daycare. And so
Speaker 2:  I'm outside right now and this is the last time I'll be outside potentially
Speaker 2:  until this time tomorrow. It's a life. But this is what happens to me
Speaker 2:  every year when it gets cold. So you know, I'll see you in April or something.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, we have an awesome show coming up for you today. We are gonna spend
Speaker 2:  the whole hour answering your questions at least to the best of our ability
Speaker 2:  about buying stuff. It's the season for buying stuff, right? It's deals,
Speaker 2:  it's presents, it's weird gift exchanges with your
Speaker 2:  coworkers. It's just a time of year you have to buy a lot of stuff and also
Speaker 2:  you're trying to tell people what to buy you. So we figured we might be able
Speaker 2:  to help. And whether you have questions about which laptop to buy
Speaker 2:  or which MacBook to buy or which Smart home gear you should get into
Speaker 2:  or what odd gaming console you're excited about, we
Speaker 2:  took all of your questions, some of them super broad, some of them like
Speaker 2:  hilariously impossibly specific and we're gonna answer as
Speaker 2:  many of them as we can on the show today. We grabbed a couple of our best
Speaker 2:  reviewers and smartest folks on the team and we're gonna go through as much
Speaker 2:  of it as we can. Thank you to everybody who's sent in questions. It's gonna
Speaker 2:  make this super fun and I have no idea if we're actually gonna help anybody
Speaker 2:  but boy are we gonna try All, right? All of that is coming up in just a second,
Speaker 2:  but first I gotta get home. I gotta, you know, get warm. I gotta take some
Speaker 2:  cold meds. I don't know if you can hear in my voice, but my kid got sick
Speaker 2:  and then my wife got sick and now I'm sick. It's great times all around then
Speaker 2:  we're gonna get to it. This is the first cast, we'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Nearly 24,000 kids had their identity stolen in
Speaker 3:  2022 In the age of social media and phishing schemes.
Speaker 3:  It's more important than ever to protect your family's personal data.
Speaker 3:  Microsoft Defender helps keep your personal information safer online
Speaker 3:  with identity theft monitoring for the whole family, giving
Speaker 3:  you real-time alerts, expert guidance, and even
Speaker 3:  hands-on restoration support. When you need help, you get
Speaker 3:  personal data plus device protection all in one
Speaker 3:  easy to use app. Maximize your protection with Microsoft
Speaker 3:  Defender available with a Microsoft 3 6 5 personal or family
Speaker 3:  subscription.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. We have a panel of stuff buying
Speaker 2:  experts, which I believe is all of our titles here. Jen Tui,
Speaker 2:  welcome back to The Vergecast. It's been a while.
Speaker 4:  Thank you David. It has been, it's lovely to be here. I'm sad we missed
Speaker 4:  cooking our Thanksgiving Turkey together this year.
Speaker 2:  We spent a lot of time trying to figure out how to one up that episode and
Speaker 2:  never figured it out and so we never did a Thanksgiving episode. It's still
Speaker 2:  one of my favorites we've ever done. If you haven't heard it, go find it.
Speaker 2:  Dan Siffords here. Hi Dan. Hello and in the studio with Dan V
Speaker 2:  Song. Hello.
Speaker 5:  Hey, what's up?
Speaker 2:  We have a lot of things to get through. I've assembled all of you because
Speaker 2:  you each have, I would say both like good expertise but also
Speaker 2:  just like broad knowledge of cool stuff and we need broad knowledge of cool
Speaker 2:  stuff. So let's just dive in. We got a bunch of stuff to get to. I've set
Speaker 2:  this up, we're gonna do some like general questions at the beginning
Speaker 2:  and then we have a couple of categories in which we got a bunch of questions.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna go through those and then we have my favorite question that
Speaker 2:  we got through this whole process to do at the very end. So we're gonna get
Speaker 2:  into that. But let's start with a couple of just kind of grab baggy questions.
Speaker 2:  The first one we got is, I'm gonna butcher everyone's name here and I'm very
Speaker 2:  sorry in advance. I believe it's from Coine in The Vergecast email
Speaker 2:  who says, are there any good options if I want to swim and listen to music
Speaker 2:  or dare I even say listen to podcasts. It seems to me that they all require
Speaker 2:  me to have MP three files, which I don't even know how to obtain in today's
Speaker 2:  streaming world. Ideally I'd like to keep my phone in the locker room and
Speaker 2:  somehow stream music and podcast via the Apple watch. Also our bone conduction
Speaker 2:  headphones the way to go or is the quality horrible? Let's break that into
Speaker 2:  two parts. VI want you to go first because we brought this up Chris WeCh
Speaker 2:  and I had a long chat about MP three players a couple of weeks ago on this
Speaker 2:  show that made a lot of people feel a lot of feelings. But I wanna know first
Speaker 2:  if you have a good answer to our friends' question here.
Speaker 5:  My main answer is that there are a lot of trade-offs and there is
Speaker 5:  nothing yet out there that's going to kind of be everything
Speaker 5:  that I think this person is looking for because Bluetooth and
Speaker 5:  water, not really great friends. There's a
Speaker 5:  reason why you're having a hard time finding things that aren't MP three
Speaker 5:  based and it's because Bluetooth is not meant to send things
Speaker 5:  through water. It's just not, I'm not a swimmer, I'm gonna caveat
Speaker 5:  that I stick primarily to running because I should not be
Speaker 5:  let on a bicycle and I had to take swim gym in high school and that should
Speaker 5:  tell you everything about my swimming skills. But that being said, I have
Speaker 5:  a lot of friends who swim and the Apple watch, do
Speaker 5:  you want the Apple watch to actually track your swim? Because if you want
Speaker 5:  it to track your swim and play content, you're out of luck.
Speaker 5:  But if you just want it to be like a media player, there is something from
Speaker 5:  H2O audio called the interval and it's, it's a
Speaker 5:  wild device. If you look at it, it's like this little framework
Speaker 5:  thingy and you like snap it onto your goggles
Speaker 5:  and it's on the back of your head. So you just have the apple watch on the
Speaker 5:  back of your head and it attaches to either bone conduction or ear ear
Speaker 5:  earbuds and it's not streaming. You have to
Speaker 5:  like download offline playlists And technically
Speaker 5:  It works though, you know, I will say I have doubts about whether
Speaker 5:  this thing will last long term just because
Speaker 5:  you really want a waterproof wearable. Most
Speaker 5:  of the advanced ones are not particularly strong at that.
Speaker 5:  Like the Apple Watch is waterproof up to five ATM, which
Speaker 5:  is what we consider swim proof. But that doesn't mean, it doesn't mean that
Speaker 5:  if you're diving to the depths of your pool a lot there,
Speaker 5:  there's still a risk there. There's an inherent risk. So that's one
Speaker 5:  option. And the other one is, is stuff like the Zy igo
Speaker 5:  that one technically allows you to stream, but it's just because it has
Speaker 5:  a radio frequency transmitter on it so that it takes
Speaker 5:  the Bluetooth playing from a source like your phone, which is you want it
Speaker 5:  to be in your locker room. So this might not actually work out for you,
Speaker 5:  but it's taking it from a Bluetooth source and then there's like a
Speaker 5:  frequency transmitter that converts the Bluetooth into something else
Speaker 5:  that does work in water and that's a little pricier. So
Speaker 5:  you know that's the
Speaker 2:  Hackiest thing I've ever heard in my life.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, so these are like, these are the, you know, swimmers Got it. Rough
Speaker 5:  runners and cyclists. We can just use our regular Bluetooth headphones and
Speaker 5:  like Bluetooth works fine in air but water just adds a different
Speaker 5:  layer of physics to the problem so that there is a reason why most
Speaker 5:  of the players you're finding are MP three based and and
Speaker 5:  also another reason why they are bone conduction based too because you know
Speaker 5:  like the earbuds, if if the earbud falls out
Speaker 5:  are you going to be able to dive to the bottom of the pool to pick it up?
Speaker 5:  So that's why like most swimming headphones you see they are gonna be the
Speaker 5:  type that goes around your, goes around your head or you know has a little
Speaker 5:  like string attached to them. You're not gonna really get any true earbuds
Speaker 5:  for for underwater use. So you know things to think
Speaker 5:  about. And to the second part of your question, are bone
Speaker 5:  conduction headphones good? No,
Speaker 5:  they're fine. They're fine if if you like base
Speaker 5:  they're not great And so like as a runner, you know there's a lot of
Speaker 5:  reasons and like there's time and place for using bone conduction headphones
Speaker 5:  as a runner, I really like them when I am in an area and I'm worried that
Speaker 5:  a truck is gonna run me over if I've got like noise canceling headphones
Speaker 5:  on. But I really like bass heavy music for running just
Speaker 5:  to like drown out my thoughts of I want to quit, I want to quit, I want to
Speaker 5:  quit. So if that's you bone conduction isn't really gonna be all that
Speaker 5:  useful. And then podcasts is another problem
Speaker 5:  because not every platform is gonna support
Speaker 5:  podcasts. So like if you wanna listen to podcasts but you're primarily on
Speaker 5:  Apple music and that's how you're downloading your offline playlists, well
Speaker 5:  you're gonna need the Spotify if you wanna listen to audio books, audio books,
Speaker 5:  you're gonna have to find something that supports audio books 'cause those
Speaker 5:  files are encoded in a specific way. So there's
Speaker 5:  just no easy way to do it. You can do it, there are people who do it. It's
Speaker 5:  just you might have to learn how to get those MP three files or find
Speaker 5:  an option that lets you download offline playlist from your
Speaker 5:  streaming service of choice.
Speaker 2:  It's tough. I will say I'm looking at the Zy Igo website right now and it
Speaker 2:  both looks like the hackiest thing in history and also like it might
Speaker 2:  be kind of a magical thing like if it's as good as the reviews say
Speaker 2:  it seems like kind of the perfect answer. But I am curious about bone connection
Speaker 2:  headphones in part because I feel like Dan, I swear like
Speaker 2:  the third day of The Verge you and I had a conversation about like when are
Speaker 2:  bone conduction headphones gonna be the thing? They seem like a good idea.
Speaker 2:  It's been so long they see like remember when like aftershocks was out here
Speaker 2:  being like bone conduction headphones are the future. They're still around.
Speaker 2:  They are still around and I feel like they are perfectly suited for
Speaker 2:  when you just want to hear sounds and
Speaker 2:  and that's all. You don't care about audio quality, you're just like, and
Speaker 2:  swimming is actually a good example of this. Like you don't really wanna
Speaker 2:  plug your ears but you want to be able to like kind of hear music
Speaker 2:  which sounds like damning with faint praise but I kind of mean it don don't
Speaker 2:  know where are we with bone conduction headphones? Is it as bad as V says?
Speaker 6:  No, I know I think there are people who really swear by them and really like
Speaker 6:  them but I think that outside of swimming the other use cases for bone
Speaker 6:  conduction headphones are running and cycling where you need spatial awareness
Speaker 6:  for safety reasons. And I honestly think that the advancements
Speaker 6:  in ambient modes on true wireless earbuds
Speaker 6:  have kind of made it so that you can wear standard earbuds
Speaker 6:  and use the AirPods active noise, not the
Speaker 6:  noise canceling mode but the new one which is slipping my mind right now,
Speaker 6:  which kind of like automatically adjusts the, the cancellation to give you
Speaker 6:  awareness of noises and the general ambient mode
Speaker 6:  of AirPods is very good where you can still hear your music with a good audio
Speaker 6:  quality and still hear everything around you for safety reasons. So I think
Speaker 6:  for most people, unless you're really specific and you want bone
Speaker 6:  conduction for very specific reasons, I don't know that I would recommend
Speaker 6:  bone conduction for, for most people looking to use them outside of like
Speaker 6:  swimming, which is like obviously you don't want, you can't put AirPods in
Speaker 6:  in a pool and and you don't want them plugging up your ears anyways.
Speaker 2:  Jen, what do you do when you exercise? Are you a headphones while exercising
Speaker 2:  person?
Speaker 4:  I bought the Beats ones that stick in your ear. Beats Fit Pro.
Speaker 4:  The purple ones? Yes, the purple. Well I did buy the purple ones, we both
Speaker 4:  got the purple ones and then my daughter lost them so now I have boring gray
Speaker 4:  ones but I loved those.
Speaker 6:  I have the gray ones.
Speaker 4:  I bought boring gray ones 'cause I got renewed 'cause I'm like I'm not spending
Speaker 4:  this much money again but I'm, I'm not thee is the
Speaker 4:  fitness girl here. I I'm the walk slowly around the block girl.
Speaker 2:  Same. Alright, let's get to the next question. Oh, which is actually
Speaker 2:  another headphones question. This is a good one. This one came from the
Speaker 2:  Hotline and it's from Daniel.
Speaker 7:  Hi, my name is Daniel. I've become a bit obsessed with trying to keep
Speaker 7:  a clean minimalist bag. I'm a remote worker and I
Speaker 7:  constantly have to take, you know, meetings from coffee shops and I've
Speaker 7:  been like mostly satisfied with my setup where I have a pair
Speaker 7:  of quiet Comfort 40 fives or Donny XM fives that do a
Speaker 7:  decent enough job of letting people hear me. But occasionally they
Speaker 7:  just stop working like there's a critical threshold of noise in a coffee
Speaker 7:  shop where the directional mics just don't do the job anymore. And
Speaker 7:  so now my bag has like a backup solution because I couldn't take the anxiety
Speaker 7:  of not being able to do my job occasionally and that
Speaker 7:  it's clunky. Like I don't want have two pairs of headphones in my bag, but
Speaker 7:  I also want to have like good noise cancellation for when I'm listening to
Speaker 7:  music and I want to have a good microphone for when I'm doing my job and
Speaker 7:  I want a little help answering the question of what is the best way to do
Speaker 7:  this. Thank you for your time.
Speaker 5:  Just use the wired apple headphones.
Speaker 2:  Yes, that's exactly what I was gonna say
Speaker 5:  Because it's totally gonna save space in your bag and you know,
Speaker 5:  Becca's done what, 5,000 videos at this point showing how good the quality
Speaker 5:  is on them. So I mean that's what I do. I just always have a wired
Speaker 5:  pair in my bag. Actually Becca made me buy a pair for,
Speaker 5:  for work reasons. So I. I would just say those are super easy to stash
Speaker 5:  and a lot cheaper than a lot of the other options out there.
Speaker 6:  I I agree this was gonna be my recommendation as well. The only caveat is
Speaker 6:  they're not gonna do any noise canceling for you. So basically you just have
Speaker 6:  to be willing to carry around both. I love the inclination to have
Speaker 6:  redundancy, I love redundancy. I'm the same person. but it does mean that
Speaker 6:  like you're, you're likely gonna have a set of over your headphones for your
Speaker 6:  noise canceled focus time and then when you need to hop on a call you just
Speaker 6:  switch to the wired ones. I
Speaker 2:  Think that's right. Every bone in my body wants to
Speaker 2:  scold anyone who gets into a loud coffee shop and
Speaker 2:  then tries to take calls. Like it's just, it's the worst for
Speaker 2:  everyone involved when people do that. But it's the holidays and so
Speaker 2:  I'm not going to scold our friend Daniel for just trying to do his job while
Speaker 2:  irritating every single other person in this coffee shop by shouting into
Speaker 2:  his microphone. Well
Speaker 5:  You don't know what Daniel's home life is.
Speaker 2:  Daniel's gotta do what Daniel's gotta do. I get it. I do think like
Speaker 2:  we've spent a lot of time talking about and testing various microphones
Speaker 2:  in various coffee shops on the show and what we have discovered is that you
Speaker 2:  just can't beat the microphone on a big ass boom
Speaker 2:  arm that comes all the way down to your mouth and you're just either going
Speaker 2:  to have to get apple's wired headphones like we've been talking about or
Speaker 2:  whip out the gamer headset and there just is no good third
Speaker 2:  option. There's
Speaker 6:  A reason Pilots headsets look the way that they do. Yeah when they're
Speaker 6:  flying a helicopter.
Speaker 5:  I mean if the, the RayBan Meta Smart Glasses could
Speaker 5:  actually pair with your laptop, I might've recommended that because
Speaker 5:  the mic is right on your nose and like you could watch our video review,
Speaker 5:  Becca did a mic test. It is like on par slash almost
Speaker 5:  slightly better than the wired apple headphones
Speaker 5:  but they don't really pair easily with your
Speaker 5:  laptop. So that was like one of the things that she pointed out as being
Speaker 5:  kind of a miss there and then just smart glasses in general, you know
Speaker 5:  that that is the thing that they're saying, right? You can use these for
Speaker 5:  calls. They're not good enough for a coffee shop. Like just anytime you have
Speaker 5:  any kind of ambient noise you have to crank the volume on them so loud that
Speaker 5:  it kind of defeats the purpose. And you know, I've never heard anyone besides
Speaker 5:  the ray bands tell me that I sounded good while wearing those so
Speaker 5:  eh, you know?
Speaker 2:  Yeah like really the, it is just the closer the microphone is to your mouth,
Speaker 2:  the better it's going to sound is like basically all you
Speaker 2:  need to know about all of this stuff. And the problem with the noise caning
Speaker 2:  headphones generally is that your ears are not that close to your mouth.
Speaker 2:  That's a fun fact about how the world works. And I think like
Speaker 2:  if there is a thing, and you all should tell me if this exists, that is like
Speaker 2:  a normal pair of noise canceling headphones onto which you can attach like
Speaker 2:  one of those boom arms that is a microphone.
Speaker 6:  So those things do exist. I forget the name of it right now but it,
Speaker 6:  you did just remind me of there's a a device that you can literally
Speaker 6:  stick to the outside cup of any pair of headphones
Speaker 6:  and then it has its own Bluetooth connection or dongle connection to your
Speaker 6:  computer and it's basically a boom arm that goes across your mouth. It
Speaker 6:  is one of the jankier setups but basically it's like if you've
Speaker 6:  got a pair of headphones that you really love the sound or comfort or whatever
Speaker 6:  features of, and they just don't have a mic or don't have a great mic, it
Speaker 6:  allows you to retrofit a mic to it. I think that you are still gonna run
Speaker 6:  into the same similar problem. So even with a boom arm on that,
Speaker 6:  you're dealing with Bluetooth connections, you're dealing with other, you
Speaker 6:  know, factors. It's just another thing for your to manage and deal with
Speaker 6:  instead of just plugging in the wired headphone, which is always gonna be
Speaker 6:  the most rock solid connection.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah, that's fair. Just
Speaker 5:  Carry your Yeti to the coffee shop, your Yeti
Speaker 5:  or your Sure. Just carry that. That's totally, no don't do that. That's,
Speaker 2:  That might be worse. No, I think truthfully the like if you just want to
Speaker 2:  carry one thing I think like Jabra has pretty good headsets. They
Speaker 2:  all have the boom arms, you're gonna look a little silly but at least folds
Speaker 2:  up and has a decent set of headphones. That's probably the best. I think
Speaker 2:  they're called like the evolves or something and they're actually pretty
Speaker 2:  solid. They're expensive but they, they are the best kind of
Speaker 2:  headphone looking headset working thing. You,
Speaker 6:  You look like you are in a call center but that's why they
Speaker 6:  work because that's what they're designed for.
Speaker 2:  A hundred percent because you are in fact in a call center. Yeah. Okay,
Speaker 2:  that's enough headphone questions. Please leave me alone at the coffee shop
Speaker 2:  and everything will be fine. We're gonna take a quick break and then we're
Speaker 2:  gonna go back and we're gonna answer some computer questions and then we're
Speaker 2:  gonna get into the really tough stuff, which is the smart home. We'll be
Speaker 2:  right
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. We got a bunch of questions from people that essentially
Speaker 2:  just want to know what computer they should buy. So let's help people buy
Speaker 2:  computers. The first one we got is a voicemail from Benjamin. Let's hear
Speaker 2:  it now.
Speaker 7:  Hey Vergecast, it's Benjamin. I've got a classic form over function
Speaker 7:  dilemma I'm hoping you can solve for me. I'm looking to buy my partner a
Speaker 7:  new laptop for the holidays but she has her eye on the 15 inch surface
Speaker 7:  laptop five specifically because of the all aluminum chassis. I
Speaker 7:  don't feel good about getting her a laptop with last year's mid-range specs,
Speaker 7:  especially for such a premium price. Maybe I would feel different
Speaker 7:  if the surface laptop six had actually come out this year. But
Speaker 7:  I'm looking for recommendations for Windows laptops with an all metal chassis
Speaker 7:  and modern specs So I can steer her towards instead. She'll
Speaker 7:  mostly be doing light tasks like web browsing and streaming, but I wanted
Speaker 7:  to have enough muscle holdup for a long time. She's also in grad
Speaker 7:  school so great battery life would be a bonus. Is a MD still
Speaker 7:  the efficiency champ for laptops? Any advice is appreciated
Speaker 7:  before? I'm sure I'll ultimately buy her the Surface 'cause you know, happy
Speaker 7:  wife, happy life. Thanks
Speaker 2:  Dan Seifert help this person. What should Benjamin buy? It's not
Speaker 2:  the surface laptop. I just wanna put that out in front here.
Speaker 6:  Well hold on. We we let's, I'm gonna give him two recommendations. Okay.
Speaker 6:  He should ignore both of them and just buy the surface laptop. He specifically
Speaker 6:  said this is the one his wife wants.
Speaker 2:  That's a fair point. And so
Speaker 6:  He should just buy the one she wants. That's a
Speaker 2:  That's what
Speaker 4:  I was gonna say. I know nothing about the laptops but buy her
Speaker 4:  what she wants.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean there's, there's a lot of nice things about the Surface laptop.
Speaker 6:  It is aging as he mentioned, it's not really super new. I think it came out
Speaker 6:  in 2022 but it's got a great screen, great keyboard and
Speaker 6:  it's a surface design so it's, it's a really nice premium design as I think
Speaker 6:  are all the things that she likes. If we were to buy something else. I've
Speaker 6:  got two recommendations. one of 'em is a little bit less expensive. It is
Speaker 6:  the a Zen book 14 x. This
Speaker 6:  is a 14.5 inch screen so it's a little bit smaller than the surface laptop
Speaker 6:  but it's an ole display. So really awesome screen. It's got the latest
Speaker 6:  13th gen Intel processor. It's like comes with 16 gigs ram, half
Speaker 6:  a terabyte of storage and you can get it for like 750 bucks, maybe even less
Speaker 6:  if you're shopping around. So it's a very up-to-date current model,
Speaker 6:  it's still metal, it's not quite up to the build quality of the surface
Speaker 6:  laptop but it's still, it's not a plastic piece of junk, it's still a a high
Speaker 6:  quality laptop. The other option is a larger
Speaker 6:  one and since they mentioned that they want a 15 inch surface
Speaker 6:  laptop and they like the aluminum chassis, I would suggest taking a
Speaker 6:  look at the LG gram 16, the things to like about the LG gram
Speaker 6:  16 is you got that 16 inch screen, it's huge. It's a 16 by 10
Speaker 6:  aspect ratio so you got a lot of room on there. It's a very thin and light
Speaker 6:  design, which is a signature of the Gram series and it has tremendous battery
Speaker 6:  life. Comes with the latest 13th gen processors 16 gigs, gram a
Speaker 6:  terabyte SSD Best Buy selling this for about 1700 bucks. So it's on the more
Speaker 6:  expensive scent end here but the Surface laptop's not a cheap
Speaker 6:  computer. So those would be my recommendations but at the end of the day,
Speaker 6:  go buy your wife a Surface laptop. Five.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I mean you said it yourself. Happy wife, happy life.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, don don't know about you guys but when I first started dating my now
Speaker 2:  wife, she like the first Christmas we were together, she like literally gave
Speaker 2:  me a list of like links and was like buy me one of these for Christmas. And
Speaker 2:  I took this as a test to be like, okay, what cool thing can I buy that
Speaker 2:  isn't on the list but shows that I read the and I did that and she was like,
Speaker 2:  why didn't you just buy me a thing on? She's like, I literally, I sent you
Speaker 2:  a link of the thing and the color that I want. And So I learned very quickly.
Speaker 2:  She sends me a list of links, I click on one of them and I click by and I
Speaker 2:  give it to her for Christmas and she's very happy and it has been a winning
Speaker 2:  move ever since. And it makes Christmas shopping the easiest thing in the
Speaker 2:  world. And So I, I have learned the hard way that when they tell you what
Speaker 2:  they want just just roll with it. So I think that's good advice.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, buy your Spouse what they ask for.
Speaker 2:  But also if you, if you want her to call in and us to talk her out of
Speaker 2:  the Surface laptop five because it is an old computer with old specs, I'm
Speaker 2:  also happy to do that All. right. One more computer question, it's an email
Speaker 2:  from Nathan. It says, hi friends, I have a 2020 Intel MacBook Pro right now
Speaker 2:  and it is the base level which means it has some trouble when I use Excel
Speaker 2:  and PowerPoint. I'm looking into starting graduate school in the fall and
Speaker 2:  would like for a Mac to be my main driver but I don't love the idea of spending
Speaker 2:  a bunch of money on the soup up MacBook Pro. I also find myself needing software
Speaker 2:  that is only available on Windows, which leads me to believe that maybe I
Speaker 2:  should buy a Power full Tower PC to keep at home and buy a lower
Speaker 2:  end M two MacBook Air and remote access the Windows computer when they need
Speaker 2:  to do more processing. Does that make any sense or should I go for a more
Speaker 2:  expensive MacBook Pro and not be it VI wanna know what you think having
Speaker 2:  used the newest fanciest best MacBooks
Speaker 5:  Ah yes, the, I still can't believe that the MacBook Pro
Speaker 5:  16 inch that they sent me was $7,200.
Speaker 5:  That configuration was just absolutely absurd.
Speaker 5:  So like the one thing that I would have a question for Nathan is like what
Speaker 5:  is his workload like? Just because you know, he
Speaker 5:  mentions using that he needs Excel and PowerPoint but then also
Speaker 5:  programs that are only available on Windows. So like
Speaker 5:  if you have programs that are only available on Windows,
Speaker 5:  maybe you do want the, the Powerful Tower pc. But
Speaker 5:  having used the very, very souped up MacBook Pros and
Speaker 5:  having an M two MacBook Air as my personal computer
Speaker 5:  right now, you know the MacBook Air is, is good enough for
Speaker 5:  most of your like daily, you know, productivity type software.
Speaker 5:  So long as you don't do what I did and get an eight gigabit, eight gigabits
Speaker 5:  of memory, that was a dumb choice on my part. You need at least 16
Speaker 5:  so you have to factor that into the price. So yeah, like
Speaker 5:  the, the one thing I'm hung up on is like needing programs that are only
Speaker 5:  available on Windows So.
Speaker 2:  I believe there is a solution to this problem, which is the Windows app,
Speaker 2:  which is now a thing that exists as of just a couple of weeks ago and
Speaker 2:  I confess I have not used this at all personally, but
Speaker 2:  the idea is you can now download Windows as an app and run what
Speaker 2:  amounts to a virtual computer on your Mac computer. I
Speaker 2:  do not believe that you should buy a computer and also another computer and
Speaker 2:  then use the one computer to access the other computer. Like yeah
Speaker 2:  that way lies madness. Dan is the like
Speaker 2:  bootcamp exists, parallels exists, there's like, yeah
Speaker 2:  kind of strategies here. Like what what do we do?
Speaker 6:  Well first off I'll start with saying I don't think you need a MacBook Pro.
Speaker 6:  I think a MacBook Air like V said is entirely capable of running the
Speaker 6:  workloads of Excel and PowerPoint, particularly compared to an Intel MacBook
Speaker 6:  Pro. Like the jump going from Intel to an M series processor is
Speaker 6:  just enormous and you are gonna have Power des spare so long
Speaker 6:  as you equip it with at least 16 gigs of Ram and I would recommend
Speaker 6:  probably five 12 to a terabyte of storage for this next half of the recommendation.
Speaker 6:  And So I think Go MacBook Air is my my first recommendation.
Speaker 6:  The second thing is buy the MacBook and then explore these
Speaker 6:  options for running your Windows apps on the MacBook. Whether that is the
Speaker 6:  Windows app, whether that is Parallels Bootcamp might be a little weird that
Speaker 6:  actually like requires you to use a Windows on arm build and it's a little
Speaker 6:  wonky on the arm max. I think Parallels is a little bit more
Speaker 6:  straightforward of a solution, but again, I personally have not directly
Speaker 6:  used it, but you should try it out and see if it allows you to do the things
Speaker 6:  that you need to do. And if it doesn't then you might have
Speaker 6:  to go your route of setting up a tower PC or, yeah, I
Speaker 6:  don't even think you really need to go a tower pc. I think you could go a
Speaker 6:  pretty simple PC and that's, that's always plugged in at home and you can
Speaker 6:  just remote desktop into it and and go from there. You know, Nathan's not
Speaker 6:  the only one with this problem. I know Eli's been on the show many times
Speaker 6:  talking about how his lawyer wife has to deal with very weird
Speaker 6:  Windows based programs and trying to use him on a Mac is a huge pain.
Speaker 6:  He, he's not the only one with this problem. And so that means there are
Speaker 6:  people who are trying to solve it and So I, that would be my recommendation.
Speaker 6:  Go get a good MacBook Air equip it well enough. You are still probably going
Speaker 6:  to be spending close to $2,000 on this, but it's not 3000.
Speaker 6:  And see if you can get your Windows applications to run and if not then
Speaker 6:  go to the next step. And if
Speaker 2:  It's the kind of thing that it's, it's like old outdated software that just
Speaker 2:  only runs on Windows. Odds are that if you buy one of those like little
Speaker 2:  $200 mini PCs things, it'll work fine for
Speaker 2:  the occasional times you need to use it. So that, that would be my recommendation
Speaker 2:  is that if you do end up buying two computers,
Speaker 6:  Unless Nathan is saying these quote needing
Speaker 6:  software that's only available on Windows is AAA games that he wants to stream
Speaker 6:  to.
Speaker 5:  Oh good, no, no his Mac no
Speaker 6:  The game then like then you do need that big power tower or you should just
Speaker 6:  buy a gaming laptop. But I don't think that's what he was referring
Speaker 5:  To. Just get a console. If you're gonna, if you really wanna be a Mac user
Speaker 5:  and play AAA games, the console is just gonna be so much easier for you.
Speaker 5:  Like just, just just do it.
Speaker 2:  There's so many PC gamers furiously sending you emails right now.
Speaker 2:  VI just want you to know
Speaker 5:  Don, don't just, just don't, just don't do it like, so like my spouse
Speaker 5:  is a gamer or was a gamer and they had this problem too and they have just
Speaker 5:  like thrown up their hands in the air and gone like f it of a PS five and
Speaker 5:  an Xbox. That's just, just it. And you know, for their
Speaker 5:  purposes, like are you really gaming on the go that you want it to be
Speaker 5:  on your, your pc or do you want in their case a giant
Speaker 5:  65 inch LG ed
Speaker 5:  to to sit like two feet in front of 'cause they move up their chair
Speaker 5:  to two feet in front of the, the the so that all the racing games can go
Speaker 5:  directly into their eyeballs. I I don don't know, I just think just do the
Speaker 5:  console and use the Mac for work. That's if, if if we
Speaker 5:  are talking AAA games here
Speaker 2:  I'm just saying MacBook Air Mini PC Steam deck
Speaker 2:  and you were just living your best life. Like that's the, that's the way
Speaker 2:  to do it. Happy holidays to everybody. It's a huge victory. All right. Let's
Speaker 2:  move on. Jen, I have terrible news for you. It's time to talk about matter.
Speaker 2:  I'm so sorry we have to do this one more time. Before the year's over we
Speaker 2:  got a bunch of smart home questions I would say, all of which I can distill
Speaker 2:  into this voicemail from Chris.
Speaker 10:  Hi, this is Chris from Los Angeles. Gotta ask going into buying season,
Speaker 10:  what's up with Matter? What home tech am I allowed to buy? What home tech
Speaker 10:  should I absolutely not buy? Is it the year for matter? Thanks
Speaker 10:  Chris.
Speaker 5:  I also wanna know the the question because I'm buying a house, yay,
Speaker 5:  my first house and I'm gonna go straight into the smart home.
Speaker 5:  So, I need, I need this for
Speaker 2:  Me too. Yeah, we got a lot of versions of this question because I think
Speaker 2:  this is the time of year to buy all this stuff, right? Like they're
Speaker 2:  fun stocking stuffers, they're fun gifts to buy people and
Speaker 2:  every version of this question we got is essentially am I a
Speaker 2:  moron for buying smart home stuff right now as we've talked about many times
Speaker 2:  we're in the middle of transitioning to matter. Matter is kind of here, it's
Speaker 2:  also kind of not here. Jen, talk us through it, it give us a gift guide here.
Speaker 2:  What are we doing?
Speaker 4:  Well, two points. The first would be friends, don't buy Friends Matter
Speaker 4:  devices for Christmas.
Speaker 4:  Okay? Just, just don't put that paint on them.
Speaker 4:  And the second would be V can you wait a couple years to move in to your
Speaker 4:  new house? No,
Speaker 5:  My lease is up at the end of this month.
Speaker 4:  Oh. So I know Eli's been going through this same issue with his house.
Speaker 4:  You know, this is a tricky time and I would like to say it's unique in
Speaker 4:  the smart home to be in this awkward situation where you are between protocols
Speaker 4:  and between devices and technologies. But no, this has been happening
Speaker 4:  since I got into the smart home a decade ago. The smart home
Speaker 4:  is continually changing. It's never in a place where you're like,
Speaker 4:  okay it's, it's here. This is right, this is the way to do it,
Speaker 4:  I'm happy. So really it's kind of like any tech, you know, I
Speaker 4:  do always encourage people to buy, you know I, I think we do this
Speaker 4:  a lot with our reviews. You know, the best you can afford that fits
Speaker 4:  your need and that's still where it sits with Smart Home. I
Speaker 4:  think Matter is going to help but it is not helping
Speaker 4:  yet. And right now my number one recommendation about my matter
Speaker 4:  devices would be only by matter devices that also work on other
Speaker 4:  platforms, which is to, to sort of break that down a
Speaker 4:  little bit. So Mat itself obviously not a platform but it does support
Speaker 4:  all the major platforms and that's its biggest selling point And that's the
Speaker 4:  one thing that I feel is good about MAT devices. If you want to buy a cheap
Speaker 4:  smart switch now for your Apple Home setup, you can go and do that.
Speaker 4:  You really didn't have the option before matter and that's an area where
Speaker 4:  Matter has succeeded. Yay. Where it has not succeeded
Speaker 4:  is in being able to pair to multiple smart home systems. So
Speaker 4:  I have spent the last month tearing my hair out trying to
Speaker 4:  pair my Phillips Hu platform, my Phillips Hu Bobs in my
Speaker 4:  house, which I have had for over a decade 'cause that's one of those systems
Speaker 4:  that's been around for a long time and it's been, it's been
Speaker 4:  something of a, a complicated process and basically there there are
Speaker 4:  still problems with that interoperability. So it's great if you want to
Speaker 4:  buy a device and pair it to one smart home platform. But if you are one
Speaker 4:  of the few, and I'm guessing there aren't a ton of people out here that wanna
Speaker 4:  use two, three or four smart home platforms. But I'm also guessing
Speaker 4:  that if there are people that want to do that, they are listening to their,
Speaker 2:  There are people yes welcome.
Speaker 4:  So, and that's where things go sideways fast. So
Speaker 4:  I paired my Hue bulbs all, all 40 bulbs I have in my house, 40
Speaker 4:  and slowly collected over the years to Apple Home, worked
Speaker 4:  great through Matter, paired them to Alexa, worked great next day
Speaker 4:  left they'd gone from Apple Home, they weren't there anymore and they weren't
Speaker 4:  working anymore so they weren't responding which anyone that uses Apple Home
Speaker 4:  will be familiar with. And then vice versa, the same thing happened with
Speaker 4:  Alexa. It stopped working and So I have literally been tearing my hair out.
Speaker 4:  It's not been fun. So Matter right now is still in
Speaker 4:  its early stages. I remember when we first went to the launch party launch
Speaker 4:  event for it, the, the head of the CSA, the organization behind it said
Speaker 4:  Matter is a journey. It's going to take a long time and
Speaker 4:  if matter is a journey, I would say we're right about the stage where we've
Speaker 4:  just stopped at the gas station to fuel up. So it's gonna be a really long
Speaker 4:  time until we get where we need to be in terms of that
Speaker 4:  solid interoperability. So right now, number one takeaway, if
Speaker 4:  you're gonna buy a device and you want it to work with a specific smart home
Speaker 4:  platform and It works with Matter, that's great. But also make sure you have
Speaker 4:  a backup so that it also works with Amazon Alexa over
Speaker 4:  the cloud or Apple Home Kit as a home kit device because
Speaker 4:  there are still a lot of interoperability problems. Unfortunately
Speaker 4:  it is not the salvation of the smart home that we were all hoping,
Speaker 4:  but there's still potential. And the most important part about Matter right
Speaker 4:  now I would say is future proofing. So having a device that works
Speaker 4:  with matter now is a good thing for the future of your smart home,
Speaker 4:  but it's not gonna solve your problems. Most of your problems today unfortunately.
Speaker 4:  So one of the things they promised us or quite loudly said at the beginning
Speaker 4:  of all of this was all your smart home devices that you currently have will
Speaker 4:  work in matter going forward. So yay you don't have to go out and buy
Speaker 4:  new stuff that does not seem to be really happening.
Speaker 4:  And you know, Philips Hugh example, I just just
Speaker 4:  gave, I mean it does work with Matter but, but not well So, I've just reverted
Speaker 4:  to using it the way it always worked, which it worked brilliantly. It has
Speaker 4:  for many years and what's not broken in the smart home you should not
Speaker 4:  try and fix
Speaker 4:  'cause you always run into problems. So backwards compatibility has been
Speaker 4:  one of the sort of real letdowns here. We've really hoped that a lot of our
Speaker 4:  current devices would get upgraded to support matter and
Speaker 4:  either over wifi or Thread, which is the one of the main protocols that
Speaker 4:  matter runs over. And it seems like from talking to companies out there that
Speaker 4:  the, the kind of load that matter requires for
Speaker 4:  their products is just, it's much heavier than they had expected.
Speaker 4:  So they're not able to update these devices necessarily with
Speaker 4:  firmware. And if they do, sometimes that actually takes away function,
Speaker 4:  which is one of the issues that Eve had with some of its devices. So
Speaker 4:  it's smart plugs, they updated to matter and
Speaker 4:  there was a potential that it was gonna take away the function for energy
Speaker 4:  monitoring, which was one of their best features. So they managed to get
Speaker 4:  around that. But yeah, there's problems there. It's, it's not as easy as
Speaker 4:  people had hoped. So VI think you should probably wait.
Speaker 4:  Oh no.
Speaker 2:  One of the things that I believe strongly about gift giving is that you should
Speaker 2:  never give someone a to-do list. And I think one of the things that
Speaker 2:  happens when you give somebody like a, a smart home gift in a lot of cases
Speaker 2:  is like I've, I've now signed you up to make 10 phone calls and rewire your
Speaker 2:  entire house. But so here's what I wonder and I'm curious
Speaker 2:  kind of for everybody's perspective on this, this 'cause we're all sort of
Speaker 2:  dealing with smart home stuff at various stages of, of installation.
Speaker 2:  What is a good and not to-do Listy
Speaker 2:  Smart Home gift you can give someone at this point in time
Speaker 2:  a plug A plug. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You know, individual components are actually tough to recommend because you
Speaker 6:  don't know what platform, unless you know you're this recipient
Speaker 6:  very well, you might not know what platform they are using or prefer. That's
Speaker 6:  true. So if you are going to do individual components, something like Jen
Speaker 6:  said that works on all of them is obviously the way to go. So
Speaker 6:  smart plugs like for Miros, they work on all the major platforms,
Speaker 6:  very reliable, we like them a lot, they're very inexpensive Hue bulbs are
Speaker 6:  very, are are very reliable work on all the platforms.
Speaker 2:  Hue Lights I have found by the way are are almost always a hit gift
Speaker 2:  because they like, they set up really fast and they're like, they're fun.
Speaker 2:  So like in three minutes you're just changing the lights in your house. Like
Speaker 2:  yeah I have found I don, I don't know that anyone I've given them to as a
Speaker 2:  gift has actually used them for very long, but they're a fun like, but
Speaker 6:  They haven't complained about them. So yeah, so like there's, there's things
Speaker 6:  like that I I think that for a few years everyone was given everyone smart
Speaker 6:  speakers and smart displays. I think we're kind of past that point and
Speaker 6:  not everyone wants a smart speaker. If they did want one, they probably have
Speaker 6:  it already. And so there that's a little tougher. I just think that like
Speaker 6:  too, kind of like what Jen was saying, I think smart home
Speaker 6:  products make a great gift for yourself and less
Speaker 6:  of a great gift for someone else. Unless you know this person is
Speaker 6:  already a smart home person and they've given you the list
Speaker 6:  of things they want and there's smart home things on there and you just go
Speaker 6:  buy them on that. I, I I think that like you are
Speaker 6:  introducing a project to, to the uninitiated. My only
Speaker 6:  caveat there is if you are going to be the project
Speaker 6:  maintainer then maybe that's okay. An example my
Speaker 6:  in-laws, I gave them a Google fa Google Home Hub
Speaker 6:  or Nest hub, whatever it's called these days, the smart display a few years
Speaker 6:  ago and I linked it up to Google Photos and now they automatically get photos
Speaker 6:  of the grandchildren on their kitchen counter. I installed it, set it up
Speaker 6:  on their wifi, they don't ever have to touch it, it just shows them pictures.
Speaker 6:  And then I saw that my father, my father-in-law said it to a a five second
Speaker 6:  changeover between the the images. So it's just speeding my images when I
Speaker 6:  was over there, So I set it back to a minute. Everyone's happy but like you
Speaker 6:  have to be prepared for that otherwise you are kind of introducing a project
Speaker 6:  to them and, and and, and maybe that's not the best gifting type of
Speaker 6:  thing.
Speaker 2:  Photo frames are a good one. My mother-in-law loves them.
Speaker 4:  That's the nice thing about the smart displays is being able to set up that
Speaker 4:  feature and there are ones that aren't smart displays if if people don't
Speaker 4:  want the speakers and microphones as well, like Skylight and Aura. But
Speaker 4:  in terms of yes actual smart home devices, it's kinda like, I mean would
Speaker 4:  you buy someone a a tap a faucet for for Christmas?
Speaker 4:  You know it's like those types of, you know, I'd love a smart tap,
Speaker 4:  a smart faucet myself but so it's my English, my English is in,
Speaker 4:  it's just, there's slightly odd things. Oh here's a smart switch. Go wire
Speaker 4:  it into your house as much as as you used to gonna get
Speaker 4:  out of it. I think the one area that perhaps I would say, okay this would
Speaker 4:  be kind of cool is when you know they have a problem and there is a
Speaker 4:  smart home device out there that will solve it. For example, like a smart
Speaker 4:  garage door opener or you know if your granddad or your
Speaker 4:  neighbor is always leaving their garage door open, you're like look here's
Speaker 4:  a smart garage door controller this look how you can do this. And every
Speaker 4:  time you give someone a smart gift like that, you should have a little coupon
Speaker 4:  next to it that says I will come and install it and set it up for you.
Speaker 2:  That's good. Yeah and then I will not maintain it over
Speaker 2:  time. Like this comes with seven days of service and then and then
Speaker 2:  no more beyond that. That's long your warranty lasts. V if are you thinking
Speaker 2:  about smart home gifts? What are you, what are you gonna give or receive
Speaker 2:  this year?
Speaker 5:  No So I. Think I'm going to follow everyone's advice and do all
Speaker 5:  the research ahead of time. AKA Jen, I'm sliding into your DMM
Speaker 5:  sometime soon and then I'm gonna make a list and then send that
Speaker 5:  list to everyone and say only buy the things on this list
Speaker 5:  for me. But yeah, I'm basically, I wanna thermostat is like number
Speaker 5:  one on my list just to, you know, lower my utility bills
Speaker 5:  and then you know, further down the line I'm gonna get one of those
Speaker 5:  toto toilets in the bidet So I. It's further, further down the
Speaker 5:  line.
Speaker 2:  That's a good gift. That's like a slightly awkward thing to talk about
Speaker 2:  potentially at the holidays but if, if you're that kind of family, like get
Speaker 2:  after it. I
Speaker 6:  Bought one last year for the fans like the family gift or for
Speaker 6:  like my wife and I to use and I love
Speaker 5:  It. Yeah you know you will change someone's life by introducing them to a
Speaker 5:  toto that that is true I
Speaker 2:  Don Dunno if that counts as smart home but it's high tech So. I'll take it.
Speaker 2:  This will do All right? We gotta take one more break and then we have a few
Speaker 2:  more questions and we'll get out here. We'll be right back.
Speaker 11:  Fox Creative,
Speaker 8:  This is advertiser content from Microsoft 3 6 5
Speaker 9:  In the first six months of 2023, more than 200,000
Speaker 9:  cases of identity theft were reported. Credit card fraud,
Speaker 9:  bank fraud, the ominous category of other.
Speaker 9:  There are a lot of categories that fraud can fall into and there are ever
Speaker 9:  evolving strategies that thieves use to take advantage of unsuspecting
Speaker 9:  people even if the odds are relatively low. The stakes
Speaker 9:  are high and there are simple ways to protect against all kinds of identity
Speaker 9:  theft. Never repeat passwords, never click on a
Speaker 9:  link sent from an unknown contact And use tools like Microsoft
Speaker 9:  Defender.
Speaker 9:  Microsoft Defender helps keep your personal information safer online with
Speaker 9:  continuous monitoring of threats to your identity and credit.
Speaker 9:  Get timely alerts, monthly credit reports, expert guidance and even
Speaker 9:  hands-on restoration support when you need help all in
Speaker 9:  one easy to use security dashboard, maximize your
Speaker 9:  protection with Microsoft Defender available with a
Speaker 9:  Microsoft 3 6 5 personal or family subscription
Speaker 2:  All. right, we're back All, right Jen, one more smart home question before
Speaker 2:  we get out of this matter. Chaos. This is an email
Speaker 2:  from Alec and this is like not specifically a
Speaker 2:  Christmas holiday question but this is actually a thing I've heard a bunch
Speaker 2:  of people buy for the holidays so I'm gonna, we're gonna do it anyway. The
Speaker 2:  email says last spring Google announced that it will be getting rid of the
Speaker 2:  Nest security products that it support in April, 2024 and that Nest customers
Speaker 2:  can get a free set of a DT hardware to replace it. Problem is the A DT hardware
Speaker 2:  doesn't seem very good to me and I'd rather have a better alternative. It
Speaker 2:  can work with my remaining Nest products doorbell, smoke detector, et cetera,
Speaker 2:  as well as Apple Home and Google Home. I'm left wondering what a good alternative
Speaker 2:  is to nest security that isn't a DT lots of options but no clear good direction.
Speaker 2:  This definitely falls under the do not buy someone a whole security
Speaker 2:  system for their house unless you know what they're doing. But if you want
Speaker 2:  to give this to you know yourself or your partner or your family for the
Speaker 2:  holidays seems like a reasonably good gift. Can we help this person? This,
Speaker 2:  this sort of sunset setting of nest thing has been going on for a while and
Speaker 2:  does sort of seem like a lot of people might just be left in the lurch. Is
Speaker 2:  there a good way out of this?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's a tricky one. This, it's such a shame. The Nest secure system
Speaker 4:  actually was, was a pretty neat system. I was very sad when it went away,
Speaker 4:  what it did so well and which I do have some
Speaker 4:  alternatives for. So hopefully we'll have a good solution here. But what
Speaker 4:  it did so well was it took home security,
Speaker 4:  which is full of tiny little white plastic things you have to stick around
Speaker 4:  your house and digest it all into one tiny little sensor
Speaker 4:  and a nice little central hub. So it was a beautiful
Speaker 4:  product in that respect. It was overpriced and it had a, a fair
Speaker 4:  number of other flaws but you know, that core functionality was really good.
Speaker 4:  And then also the NFC tag so you didn't have to worry about running in and
Speaker 4:  like pressing the keypad thing, which still gives me nervous sort of hives
Speaker 4:  when I have to do because I do it all the time when I'm testing these devices
Speaker 4:  like oh no, the police is gonna show up. But anyway, so
Speaker 4:  it, it had some great solutions there and this is what I like about the smart
Speaker 4:  home when it takes a sort of legacy product and does makes
Speaker 4:  it smart, makes it, oh wow, this is so much better than it was before. And
Speaker 4:  there are a couple of solutions out there that will fill that Nest
Speaker 4:  secure shaped hole. Unfortunately not entirely precisely.
Speaker 4:  There's a few sort of caveats and you know, choices you have to make.
Speaker 4:  So you're not gonna get some of the, the benefits that Nest Secure had. But
Speaker 4:  one, what I love about these two is that they both offer that, that all in
Speaker 4:  one sensor product. So the two options that I really like are
Speaker 4:  Arlo Secure and then the Eco B security system. So they
Speaker 4:  both have these all in one sensors and Arlo Secure is
Speaker 4:  probably gonna be the best solution for our caller here because it's
Speaker 4:  very well integrated with Google. It integrates with
Speaker 4:  into the Google home system really well. The cameras and such, like
Speaker 4:  the actual security system integration, it gets a little tricky when you
Speaker 4:  integrate security systems into other systems because you want
Speaker 4:  them to be secure. So there's a lot of sort of caveats about making,
Speaker 4:  giving other platforms access to your security system. But in terms
Speaker 4:  of using, you know, like your Google Home app and integrating with your cameras,
Speaker 4:  Arlo Secure is probably gonna be your best solution and it's really relatively
Speaker 4:  inexpensive. It's like $200 to get started with the keypad and two
Speaker 4:  sensors and these sensors are awesome. They're all in one multisensor and
Speaker 4:  they do eight different things, which is kind of impressive. Wow.
Speaker 4:  So their contact sensors, motion sensors, ambient light
Speaker 4:  sensors, temperature sensors, they can also, the system itself can
Speaker 4:  also listen for smoke and co alarms. So you don't need, you know, all
Speaker 4:  the other sensors that most security systems come with and
Speaker 4:  also they're leak detectors. You can't use them as a leak detector
Speaker 4:  and a contact sensor at the same time but you can, you know, you can
Speaker 4:  choose, pick and choose what you want them to do, which is really neat. And
Speaker 4:  if you use Arlo cameras you actually can get video
Speaker 4:  verification, which is a pretty key part of any kind of security system these
Speaker 4:  days if you sign up for professional monitoring and that was something that
Speaker 4:  Nest Secure didn't offer. So that's where police will only come to your
Speaker 4:  house if they can actually verify that something's wrong and not that you
Speaker 4:  just forgot You don, you forgot to know how to disarm the system. Right.
Speaker 4:  Pressing the buttons. So the Arlo secure is, is a good one. And
Speaker 4:  then the Eco B secure system, very similar. It also has
Speaker 4:  these sensors that are contact and motion in
Speaker 4:  one but they don't do all the other stuff. But what they do, and this is
Speaker 4:  something that V might be interested in, is they do sync with your thermostat
Speaker 4:  and so if you leave your door open it will, you can
Speaker 4:  set it to automatically turn your heating or AC off
Speaker 4:  when the door's left open just so that you're not, you know, yeah, that's
Speaker 4:  neat. Accidentally cooling the outdoors or heating or as
Speaker 2:  My mom used to say, we're not heating outside here.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So that's a neat sort of extra feature, which I really
Speaker 4:  like. And that's the kind of thing, you know, security systems are boring,
Speaker 4:  they're kind of expensive. You're paying monthly for them most of the time
Speaker 4:  and especially if you have professional monitoring. So it's kind of cool
Speaker 4:  when they can do something else useful and helpful and all of these
Speaker 4:  both on Arlo Secure and e be, you can use as motion sensors and contact
Speaker 4:  sensors in your smart home. So you, the door opens, the lights can
Speaker 4:  turn on, you can set motion automations and those types of
Speaker 4:  home automation setups, which you know, are really useful in your house
Speaker 4:  as well as also protecting you potentially if someone comes and tries to
Speaker 4:  break in. So those are both good options. The other one would be Abode,
Speaker 4:  which has, they're a bit more like traditional security
Speaker 4:  system. They have all the different sensors, but they also work as a
Speaker 4:  Z-Wave hub. So if you want to connect to a broader smart home with
Speaker 4:  Z-Wave devices, the, and all three of these do work with Apple Home.
Speaker 4:  They all work with Google to some extent and they all
Speaker 4:  work with Amazon Alexa assistant too. So you have
Speaker 4:  kind of broad support there on the platforms. They all also have cameras
Speaker 4:  with them. So it does, our caller does mention he already has some Google
Speaker 4:  cameras, but if you wanted to add more cameras, you can use cameras
Speaker 4:  from all three of these systems in there. The, the E could be cameras and
Speaker 4:  the other cameras are, are really quite good. The abode cameras I would maybe
Speaker 4:  stick clear of, so there's some three good options there and three
Speaker 4:  good price points too. They all, I think the cheapest actually is the abode,
Speaker 4:  which starts $160. The A DT stuff unfortunately
Speaker 4:  just really wasn't very impressive. I read a lot of people
Speaker 4:  complaining about that when it came out, but we did actually report a couple
Speaker 4:  months ago that it looks like a DT is working on another
Speaker 4:  system where they're more tightly integrated with the Nest devices
Speaker 4:  and have some slightly nicer looking hardware. So if you can wait, you
Speaker 4:  might wanna wait and see how that pans out. But otherwise I would look into
Speaker 4:  one of those three options that I mentioned. I think you'll probably find
Speaker 4:  something there that you'd like.
Speaker 2:  I feel like our takeaway so far is that holiday season 2027
Speaker 2:  is gonna be like sick for the smart home. It's gonna be so good
Speaker 2:  and until then just, you know, close your eyes and point at something and,
Speaker 2:  and we'll try. No, I think that's, that's super helpful. I'm actually gonna,
Speaker 2:  I think go probably by one of those this holiday season stuff's on good sale.
Speaker 2:  I guess that's part of the reason everybody buys stuff is just everything's
Speaker 2:  on sale right now. Alright, a few more questions then we're gonna get outta
Speaker 2:  here. We got a couple of questions about gaming, specifically handheld gaming.
Speaker 2:  This first one is voicemail from Sean.
Speaker 7:  Hey, this is Sean from Ohio. Christmas is coming up and I
Speaker 7:  have a 7-year-old son at home that I've is really in the video games.
Speaker 7:  I've been noticing on TikTok a lot of these handheld,
Speaker 7:  almost Game Boy esque video game emulators.
Speaker 7:  I'm wondering if those are any good if emulator
Speaker 7:  handheld gaming is very good. I've heard of the steam
Speaker 7:  deck and we own a switch, but I'd love to get him something that I can just
Speaker 7:  load up a bunch of games. Also, I'm a Mac user, So I. Don't know
Speaker 7:  if that prohibits me or kind of
Speaker 7:  detracts from being able to do that anyways. Looking for a game device
Speaker 7:  to buy for my son. Love to know your thoughts. Thanks.
Speaker 2:  There are two correct answers to this question. I would say one
Speaker 2:  is a device called the Retro Pocket, which is one of those things that comes
Speaker 2:  from Amazon and ships with like a million built-in games that you can play.
Speaker 2:  Some of them don't work very well, some of them are like
Speaker 2:  porny and weird on a lot of these emulator devices, but it's also,
Speaker 2:  there are some very good games. So that's a good like all in one emulator
Speaker 2:  kind of system. How old is your son if they're Porny
Speaker 2:  seven, you know, whatever. I'm not here to litigate. Oh okay. I'm not, I'm
Speaker 2:  I'm not, I'm not in charge. No, I think it's, it's the, you can basically
Speaker 2:  either do the, like a system like the analog pocket which is like an
Speaker 2:  amazing piece of hardware but requires you to kind of bring your own games,
Speaker 2:  which is the more legally upstanding thing as we've talked about in the show
Speaker 2:  in the past, but also more expensive and more complicated. Or you
Speaker 2:  can buy the things that you see all over Amazon from companies like Annick
Speaker 2:  and Retro and others that are just the, we downloaded every
Speaker 2:  rom we could find on the internet. Put it onto a device and we'll ship it
Speaker 2:  to you from Amazon. Those are very fun. They come with some weirdness.
Speaker 2:  Some of the games don't work, some might be games you don't like very much.
Speaker 2:  They require some extra management but they work. The retro pocket is very
Speaker 2:  good. It's the one people seem to like So I would steer you that way if
Speaker 2:  that's what you want. But if you wanna like be a gaming purist, the
Speaker 2:  Analog Pocket is is the one. Then we have a question that is another
Speaker 2:  one we've gotten a bunch of, which is a voicemail from Hillary.
Speaker 12:  Hey this is Hillary. My husband and I are
Speaker 12:  expecting our second child in May and my husband
Speaker 12:  wants to get a handheld gaming device to go with
Speaker 12:  those long sleepless nights. I think it's a little bit silly too
Speaker 12:  because he's not actually gonna have time to play it, but pretending that
Speaker 12:  he does, he's trying to choose between a steam deck and an Nintendo
Speaker 12:  Switch. Which would you recommend for using while caring
Speaker 12:  for an infant? Thanks.
Speaker 4:  Neither of them are very good as nannies. I would say
Speaker 2:  So I. Think why I like this question is this is less what can I do
Speaker 2:  for the child and more like how do I occupy myself while my child sleeps
Speaker 2:  on top of, yeah, having just had an infant, I had
Speaker 2:  terrible luck with this. I found that anytime I put a screen up
Speaker 2:  sort of behind his head he would wake up and it would go sideways. But
Speaker 2:  I will say between these two the switch is, is the choice for me
Speaker 2:  at least. Yeah, same. The games work super well
Speaker 2:  offline. The thing is really simple and straightforward. You
Speaker 2:  can put it on a table and just use the joycons in your hands or you can hold
Speaker 2:  it or you can plug it in. It'll end up being a thing your kids can use when
Speaker 2:  they go to like I just think it it, I lean way towards Switch
Speaker 2:  as the more sort of, I have a kid on my lap and also
Speaker 2:  wanna play video games kind of device.
Speaker 6:  I totally agree and I think that the challenge with the Steam deck while
Speaker 6:  a phenomenal gaming device is that you will spend a lot of time tinkering
Speaker 6:  with it and if you do have limited amount of time to play
Speaker 6:  because you are also caring for a new infant, the Switch is the one that
Speaker 6:  you'll be able to just pick up, start playing, put it down when you need
Speaker 6:  to and like, like David said, it is convertible to
Speaker 6:  tabletop or TV playing very easily and stuff like that. So I would
Speaker 6:  recommend the Switch as well.
Speaker 4:  The best device for one-handed entertainment while you're caring for a
Speaker 4:  child because generally you're only gonna have one hand is a Kindle.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah, just press the button and you can turn the page. Yep. It's the only
Speaker 4:  one that you don't need two hands for.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, my gaming strategy was to get weirdly into this game called Hold
Speaker 2:  Down on my phone, which is just a game where you
Speaker 2:  shoot a ball at things and try to knock them down and get as far down as
Speaker 2:  you possibly can. Have I ever spent six straight hours playing that game
Speaker 2:  while a child slept on top of me? Yes. I absolutely have So I truthfully
Speaker 2:  I would say like an Apple Arcade subscription is like the the better
Speaker 2:  infant care strategy than either of these devices. But yeah, I
Speaker 2:  would, I would lead a Nintendo Switch if that's where you're going. Alright,
Speaker 2:  one more question and then we're getting outta here. This is a much broader
Speaker 2:  question, So I, everybody has to answer. We can go any direction you want.
Speaker 2:  It's an email from Charles. It says, I think niche, small batch hardware
Speaker 2:  products make great gifts. Things like the panic play date, handheld console,
Speaker 2:  the Dirty Wave M eight synth tracker or the paper shoot camera. The problem
Speaker 2:  I run into is finding these products in the first place. Usually the marketing
Speaker 2:  relies on word of mouth referrals, so they're hard to find if you're not
Speaker 2:  deep into the specific community or hobby these products are made for. I'm
Speaker 2:  curious to know what your favorite small batch bespoke hardware is. I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  broaden this question very slightly, which is just to say we each have to
Speaker 2:  recommend one thing that is like thoroughly non-obvious. Something that you
Speaker 2:  wouldn't find on like a gift guide that is like, here's
Speaker 2:  the cool Bose headphones and AirPods and this iPhone and
Speaker 2:  that laptop.
Speaker 6:  I've got one and I will caveat that this might might appear on one of our
Speaker 6:  gift guides 'cause our gift guides are very good and you know, I, I
Speaker 6:  consider this a niche, small batch hardware. I'm not sure if Charles will
Speaker 6:  agree, but I love the pine sill. It is a very cool
Speaker 6:  little tool if you are into tinkering at all or if you want to
Speaker 6:  like explore it. Like my personal experience, I've, I've never soldered anything
Speaker 6:  before I bought a pine sill and now I'm soldering. Like that's like
Speaker 6:  how it goes. And it was very easy to get into. It's very easy to use. It's
Speaker 6:  very small and lightweight. It's inexpensive, it's a small company. Open
Speaker 6:  source hardware. That would be my recommendation.
Speaker 2:  That's a good one that counts. I'll give you that. V what do you got?
Speaker 5:  One of the things I tested this year that is completely stupid but that I
Speaker 5:  kind of enjoyed the concept of was the Now watch,
Speaker 5:  okay, you're not gonna find this anywhere, but it is like a stress
Speaker 5:  tracker device thing, but it has these little discs.
Speaker 5:  There's no display, it's one of these no display type trackers. It just,
Speaker 5:  it just buzzes whenever you're stressed and it has these like
Speaker 5:  gemstone faces that you take in and out with a little magnet
Speaker 5:  and that thing was fun. I would not recommend it to most people to be
Speaker 5:  clear who actually care about their health tracking. But for people who
Speaker 5:  are just like, I want something that's unique, I want
Speaker 5:  something that's very stylish, I want something that's going to alert me
Speaker 5:  when I'm really stressed out because I'm the type of person who caress and
Speaker 5:  wants my tech to tell me to cool down. Then that one, it's
Speaker 5:  weird and kind of fun. And then I thought of the other one that's really
Speaker 5:  niche and something that I bought for myself this year is the
Speaker 5:  Medi Cube
Speaker 5:  booster h and it's a little wand that you zap your face with
Speaker 5:  so that your skincare goes into your skin more deeply. It
Speaker 5:  uses electroporation, it's all over TikTok,
Speaker 5:  but if you're not in the skincare community you ain't gonna know about this
Speaker 5:  thing. So there you go. That's good. The Mecu Booster H
Speaker 5:  it's on sale for like 50% these days. So I would do it. Hailey
Speaker 5:  Bieber uses it. So there you go.
Speaker 2:  All, right? Chen you got one.
Speaker 4:  Well, I'm not sure it quite fits with the niche small batch
Speaker 4:  hardware but Maybe it does. But Home Assistant,
Speaker 4:  the Home assistant Green if you wanna, you know, be Budget,
Speaker 4:  which is their, their new budget version of getting started with
Speaker 4:  Home Assistant. But as we started the smart home discussion with
Speaker 4:  all the problems with Matter and how you should buy a device that also works
Speaker 4:  with other platforms, home assistant would be your friend here because
Speaker 4:  it can help you get any device into any platform and also will
Speaker 4:  offer matter support going forward. It has matter support in beta
Speaker 4:  right now as everyone else does. Everyone's in beta right now,
Speaker 4:  so yeah, it's, it's a, every time I write a review on The Verge,
Speaker 4:  one of the comments will be, but you can already do this with Home Assistant.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it is, it is a great powerful tool. It
Speaker 4:  it's one of those devices that if you give to a friend you are going to then
Speaker 4:  become their backup IT person,
Speaker 4:  but you will know the right friend to give this to and if you give it to
Speaker 4:  the right friend they will be very, very grateful.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, the, the home assistant people are a little like the Linux people but
Speaker 2:  Home Assistant is much more of a product that regular people can actually
Speaker 2:  figure out and
Speaker 4:  It's gotten that way a lot over this last year or two. Yeah, they've really
Speaker 4:  put a lot into making this a lot a much easier proposition than,
Speaker 4:  than it once was.
Speaker 2:  I, I agree. Mine I have two. One is a gadget
Speaker 2:  and one is not, but it's close enough. One is the one I've already mentioned,
Speaker 2:  which is the Analog pocket, which I think as like a little
Speaker 2:  Game boy thing for the modern age is just one of the like best made
Speaker 2:  pieces of hardware out there. It's the kind of thing that like if you're
Speaker 2:  in the gaming world, you know this and you're like, David, the analog pocket
Speaker 2:  doesn't count in this game, but if you're not, you've probably never heard
Speaker 2:  of it. It takes cartridges. It's a very fun thing. If you wanna like play
Speaker 2:  retro games in a new way, it, it rules and they're also building a thing
Speaker 2:  for the N 64 that is not coming out this year, but it is probably coming
Speaker 2:  out next year and I'm confident I'm going to do whatever it takes to buy
Speaker 2:  one whenever that happens. So if you wanna just like wrap up a piece of paper
Speaker 2:  that says I'll buy you the N 64 thing, that works fine. The other one
Speaker 2:  is I've gotten back into a kick with notebooks as
Speaker 2:  Dan can attest, I spend all of my time switching between to-do list apps
Speaker 2:  and recently I have given up on to-do list apps and I'm back to writing
Speaker 2:  on paper like a, like our ancestors did and the
Speaker 2:  team from Cortex, which makes very good podcasts over Relay fm, they made
Speaker 2:  a thing called the Sidekick ePad that is this big wide
Speaker 2:  notebook that is part like lists on the right and just sort of empty space
Speaker 2:  to right on the left and it sits on your desk and is a perfect like day
Speaker 2:  planner thing and I love it very much. It's a
Speaker 6:  Great wrist rest for your keyboard too. It's like, it's specifically designed
Speaker 6:  to be the width of your keyboard, which is very
Speaker 2:  Cool. Yeah and it sort of sits in front of it and you can like write on it
Speaker 2:  and then go back to typing. It's, it's lovely and I have enjoyed it very
Speaker 2:  much so that's my recommendation. Alright, thank you all. We should
Speaker 2:  get outta here. I hope we have spent a lot of people's money and if you wanna
Speaker 2:  buy us nice things to, to tell us, send Jen
Speaker 2:  all of your matter compatible gadgets and she will somehow figure out how
Speaker 2:  to install them in her home All. right. Thank you guys. Appreciate
Speaker 2:  it as always. Thanks.
Speaker 3:  Bye
Speaker 1:  Bye.
Speaker 3:  Having your identity stolen can be devastating financially
Speaker 3:  and emotionally and it feels like identity thieves are constantly
Speaker 3:  embedding new ways to take advantage of unsuspecting people. Now you can
Speaker 3:  stay one step ahead with Microsoft Defender. Microsoft Defender
Speaker 3:  helps keep your personal information safer online with continuous
Speaker 3:  monitoring of threats to your identity and credit. Get timely
Speaker 3:  alerts, monthly credit reports, expert guidance, and even hands-on
Speaker 3:  restoration support when you need help all in one easy to use
Speaker 3:  security dashboard. Maximize your protection with Microsoft Defender.
Speaker 3:  Available with a Microsoft 3 6 5 personal or family
Speaker 3:  subscription.