# Transcript
ID: d0086167-48d5-4dcf-9da1-f4ed77c05cb4
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Nothing’s gadget renaissance, and our favorite TV remotes
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8494732846201188191/-4305024782947661299/s93290-US-5419s-1689752962.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of sustainable supply chain economics:
03:27 - CEO of Nothing Carl Pei sits down with The Verge’s David Pierce to discuss the new Phone 2, Carl’s vision for the company, his thoughts on AI, foldables, VR, and much more.
Nothing Phone 2 review: the vibes abide
Nothing CEO Carl Pei on the Phone 2, AI, and the future of gadgets (video version of interview here)
50:02 - Later, Vergecast producers Andru Marino and Liam James debate with David the best and worst TV remotes, and what makes a good remote design. Watch the YouTube version to see all the remotes we talk about.
3 Kinds of Simplicity :: UXmatters
Philips Design - Simplifying TV remote (UX Case Study)
1:25:19 - Keep listening for the Vergecast Hotline question of the week.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Sustainable Supply Chain
Speaker 2:  economics. I'm your friend, David Pierce. And I am currently packing up to
Speaker 2:  go on vacation. I'm off next week and we're gonna go visit some family and
Speaker 2:  spend some time relaxing. So I'm getting everything ready. I dunno if you're
Speaker 2:  like me in this way, but I realized for the first time in getting ready for
Speaker 2:  this trip that my packing strategy is to basically just like
Speaker 2:  randomly heave a bunch of shirts and pants into a bag without even looking
Speaker 2:  at it. And then spend three days carefully curating all of my
Speaker 2:  technology. I might have my priorities wrong here. I have my laptop,
Speaker 2:  I have my phone, an iPad and a Kindle. All of which I'm gonna spend
Speaker 2:  the next several days making sure are perfectly charged. The iPad
Speaker 2:  has like 9,000 hours of TV and movies downloaded, even though
Speaker 2:  I'm driving And I have no idea when I'll watch them. But anyway, I did that
Speaker 2:  and they're there now. I bought three new books in addition to the several
Speaker 2:  dozen I already own that I haven't read yet. I have Chargers and
Speaker 2:  backup chargers with me. I even have an SD card reader in this little
Speaker 2:  bag here, despite the fact that nothing I'm bringing uses an SD card.
Speaker 2:  I have wired headphones, I have wireless headphones, And I, have a pair of
Speaker 2:  Bose headphones that is both wired and wireless. I might have
Speaker 2:  a problem y'all, but I guess if our car breaks down and we have to spend
Speaker 2:  an entire day waiting and watching all of season two of the Bear on Hulu
Speaker 2:  when there's no service, I, I guess I'm good to go. So
Speaker 2:  there's that. Anyway, I have a lot of stuff left to do. Somehow
Speaker 2:  it's gonna be a scene. Anyway, we have a great show for you today. First,
Speaker 2:  we're gonna spend some time with Carl Pay the CEO of Nothing, talking about
Speaker 2:  the Nothing Phone two, but mostly talking about the tech business in general
Speaker 2:  and why it's So Hard to build great hardware. Then we are
Speaker 2:  going to finally get on the mics and hash out a debate that The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  team has been having for months. What makes a great TV remote
Speaker 2:  and which one is the best one? All that's coming up in just a second. But
Speaker 2:  first I gotta run upstairs and find my U S BBC to H D M I cable
Speaker 2:  because I always bring that with me in case, I don't know, I guess I need
Speaker 2:  to connect my computer to my TV and do a slideshow or
Speaker 2:  something. I realize now this is insane, but this is the life I've
Speaker 2:  chosen. This is The Verge cast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  You've probably heard about the job of an intimacy coordinator,
Speaker 3:  but do you know what they actually do?
Speaker 4:  And every intimacy coordinator's kid is gonna be some form of mint of really,
Speaker 4:  I think most of the time Wait. Oh, a hundred percent, huh? Then we add in
Speaker 4:  the full retro Listerine breath strip, which is crucial
Speaker 3:  Several years into the era of the intimacy coordinator.
Speaker 3:  We ask what they've changed for the better in Hollywood
Speaker 3:  and what still needs work. This week on Intuit
Speaker 3:  Vultures Pop Culture podcast
Speaker 5:  On criminal, we bring you true crime stories told by
Speaker 5:  people who know them best.
Speaker 6:  We didn't believe in setting fires cause that was too dangerous. We were,
Speaker 6:  you know, a kind, a gentler kind of crooks, so to speak.
Speaker 5:  So the best plan you had was that you'd LaSow it?
Speaker 7:  Yes. Never imagined I'd use it for a camel.
Speaker 5:  I'm Phoebe Judge and this is criminal. Did you have to say
Speaker 5:  what was in the box,
Speaker 9:  Phoebe? We told lies,
Speaker 5:  Listen to criminal every week, wherever you get your podcasts.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Everything's charging. All my cables are packed. I'm
Speaker 2:  gonna crush this vacation. So we are already
Speaker 2:  in the thick of phone season. It's mid-July and it is just coming
Speaker 2:  fast. Google launched the pixel fold the other week. Samsung has new
Speaker 2:  foldables and flippable coming later this month. We're gonna get new stuff
Speaker 2:  from Apple in September. The new Zen phone is pretty good. It's
Speaker 2:  all happening really fast. But one of the most interesting phones of the
Speaker 2:  year to me is the Nothing Phone two.
Speaker 10:  Introducing phone two, meet the Glyph interface,
Speaker 10:  a more thoughtful way to interact with a smartphone where lights on the
Speaker 10:  back of your device tell you all you need to know. Nothing
Speaker 2:  Is one of the few startups, true startups, trying to make it
Speaker 2:  in the phone business and has been doing some pretty interesting stuff over
Speaker 2:  the last couple of years. The verges, Allison Johnson reviewed the phone
Speaker 2:  too. I'll link to it in the show notes. It's a great review and her takeaway
Speaker 2:  was essentially that it's a good phone with some strong opinions
Speaker 2:  about how phones should work and how you feel about those opinions.
Speaker 2:  Like a monochrome UI and that light up interface on the back that
Speaker 2:  can alert you when your phone is face down and nothing's cool,
Speaker 2:  transparent design language, all that stuff will determine
Speaker 2:  how you feel about the phone. Otherwise it's just a good phone. And actually
Speaker 2:  that's the kind of stuff I want to talk about today. Nothing specifically
Speaker 2:  at CEO Carl Pay has spent the last couple of years running around
Speaker 2:  talking about how tech is boring and the world needs more exciting
Speaker 2:  tech companies and how nothing is going to bring back the glory days of
Speaker 2:  gadgets and then it makes the pretty good smartphone.
Speaker 2:  I just have trouble squaring those two things sometimes. So right
Speaker 2:  around the launch of the phone too, I brought Carl into the studio to talk
Speaker 2:  about nothing in the company, the phone too. His thoughts on everything from
Speaker 2:  gadgets to AI to AR glasses and what it really takes to
Speaker 2:  make it in the phone biz. I thought it was fascinating. So let's get into
Speaker 2:  it.
Speaker 2:  Carl, pay Welcome to The. Vergecast.
Speaker 8:  Thanks for having me.
Speaker 2:  You've been trying to do this forever.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, we, this is very exciting. We said seven years, right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, God, several lifetimes ago
Speaker 8:  At this point. Lifetimes ago.
Speaker 2:  So you just launched a phone. Congrats.
Speaker 8:  Thank you. You're, you're
Speaker 2:  Like at the end of true chaos hopefully of launching
Speaker 8:  A phone. There's still a lot of work. Yeah. In the next couple of weeks,
Speaker 8:  but yeah, at least we've, we've launched the phone now. That's
Speaker 2:  Good. And I. Wanna get into that? We both have the phone phone sitting here
Speaker 2:  and we're gonna talk about it a little bit. Yours looks more like a storm
Speaker 2:  trooper than mine, which is very cool. But you've never been on the show.
Speaker 2:  And, I wanna talk about nothing as a thing and sort of you, you launched
Speaker 2:  this company a few years ago with this like big grand theory about the state
Speaker 2:  of technology. And, I have lots of questions about it. I guess maybe the
Speaker 2:  easiest place to start is just like I, I've sort of heard this mantra in
Speaker 2:  a bunch of different forms, but how do you talk about it now? Like what did,
Speaker 2:  what does nothing exist to do?
Speaker 8:  We're trying to make tech more fun again because I think a lot of people
Speaker 8:  can resonate with this, but personally, when I was young, I was super excited
Speaker 8:  about tech. I felt really inspired both on the hardware side and the software
Speaker 8:  side. When I was younger, apple used to have these epic product launches
Speaker 8:  that I grew up in Europe, so I had to stay up over the
Speaker 8:  night to watch and it was worth it because each product was such a big leap
Speaker 8:  forward compared to the last one. And you just made you feel like everything
Speaker 8:  was heading towards a really exciting trajectory. And it was also the time
Speaker 8:  where a lot of these social media and consumer
Speaker 8:  internet companies were being created. So you had a lot of innovation on
Speaker 8:  hardware but also a lot of innovation on software and and services. So
Speaker 8:  it felt like back then, you know, 10 years ago, society as a whole was way
Speaker 8:  more optimistic about where technology was going. But in the last couple
Speaker 8:  of years that sentiment, at least for me, has
Speaker 8:  pretty much disappeared. And when when we speak to other people, be it consumers
Speaker 8:  or investors, I think it kind of resonates. So
Speaker 8:  we're thinking like how can we kind of get back to that
Speaker 8:  original state where things just felt like it was getting better and better
Speaker 8:  and hopefully also inspire others to, to be a part
Speaker 8:  of this journey, be it our community or even our competitors. So I guess
Speaker 8:  that's why we, we started this.
Speaker 2:  I like the theory of that a lot. And I think that change you're
Speaker 2:  describing is something we talk about a lot on this show. And I think there
Speaker 2:  are sort of two responses I have to that idea and one
Speaker 2:  is that I think one thing that has happened in the last 10 years is that
Speaker 2:  all those things became super successful to the point where now like
Speaker 2:  most people's smartphones are not exciting, right? Like they're appliances,
Speaker 2:  And, I think to some extent that's fine. Like they do a lot of things really
Speaker 2:  well. They're very successful. But we, we got past the point of
Speaker 2:  being really excited about every single spec upgrade because they don't matter
Speaker 2:  that much.
Speaker 8:  The marginal utility is not that high.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I think you can, you can have interesting debates about whether
Speaker 2:  that is a total lack of imagination and innovation or it's just the fact
Speaker 2:  that everybody got phones, we all got used to them and that's fine. And like
Speaker 2:  our phones fridges or washing machines now, like it
Speaker 2:  maybe. And then I think the other thing that happened is a lot of that stuff
Speaker 2:  we were really optimistic about turned out to have huge problems. Some of
Speaker 2:  which we should have known going in, some of which we didn't know going in,
Speaker 2:  but like we've been talking a lot about this with Instagram threads. This
Speaker 2:  like beautiful world we used to live in where you could just like talk to
Speaker 2:  all your friends on Facebook before. We all knew all of the costs that came
Speaker 2:  from that. And so part of what I wonder And I suspect you spend time
Speaker 2:  thinking about is like, is that era of how we
Speaker 2:  felt about technology ever gonna come back? Or do we just know things now?
Speaker 2:  We didn't then. And our experience of it has sort of changed that forever.
Speaker 8:  I don't think anything is forever And I if, I think if you zoom out and look
Speaker 8:  at history, history kind of ebbs and flows. Sure. So I think
Speaker 8:  there will be kind of periods in history where technology doesn't advance
Speaker 8:  that much and there will be other periods where a lot, a lot is happening.
Speaker 8:  I think we're in one of those slow periods. But what you said, if you look
Speaker 8:  at it from the company's perspective, I think a lot of innovation happened
Speaker 8:  when there were many small and medium sized companies trying to compete
Speaker 8:  with each other. And I think one of the reasons why we feel like
Speaker 8:  innovation has slowed down is because a lot of these companies have won already.
Speaker 8:  They become really big, they have, you know, very defined business model,
Speaker 8:  very defined type of consumer and it works. So
Speaker 8:  why, why risk it with something new At the same time? It feels like they've
Speaker 8:  all created really strong moats. So it's really hard for a new entrant to,
Speaker 8:  to get in. you know, we talked about the fact that we're launching our second
Speaker 8:  phone. There's a bunch of people that try to make smartphones in the last
Speaker 8:  10 years who never got got around to launching their, their second phone
Speaker 8:  or
Speaker 2:  Even their first phone in a lot of cases. Yeah. I have a lot of prototypes
Speaker 2:  that never hit the market sitting in my basement somewhere.
Speaker 8:  So, so the, the barrier to entry is, is just way too high for, for smaller
Speaker 8:  companies to come in? I think so. I think that from the company side, that's
Speaker 8:  kinda what we're seeing. you know, these small companies got really big and
Speaker 8:  they built these moats. I think we're probably one of the only smaller companies
Speaker 8:  that are that's able to experiment and, you know, try our own ideas
Speaker 8:  because we have accumulated the right type of resource
Speaker 8:  competence to at least give it an honest shot.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. And I think to some extent, I would imagine coming out of
Speaker 2:  what you were doing at OnePlus, which is like a, a small thing inside of
Speaker 2:  a large company with lots of infrastructure and lots of, you know,
Speaker 2:  backing resources. You were sort of a, a startup without
Speaker 2:  all the like scary cliffs of being a startup in a lot of ways. Then
Speaker 2:  you should just show up on your own and you're like, okay, now it's, it's
Speaker 2:  just like me and a dream. Yeah. And I I was in in
Speaker 2:  preparing for this was like listening to other interviews and stuff that
Speaker 2:  you've done and you've basically talked about just like walking into factories
Speaker 2:  being like, please, please build my phone. And all these companies are like,
Speaker 2:  we've built other people's phones and they died and those companies went
Speaker 2:  outta business and like there are a million failed, really good
Speaker 2:  Kickstarter ideas out there. Are you sure you're not just like totally insane
Speaker 2:  to try this? Is there a possibility that you are
Speaker 8:  I think we underestimated how hard it would be. Okay. Maybe that was a good
Speaker 8:  thing. We're kind of like you said, in more of a protected environment coming
Speaker 8:  out in the real world. It's a lot more difficult when we are approaching
Speaker 8:  the factories in the beginning, as you say, they, they, a lot of them have
Speaker 8:  been burned before by other entrepreneurs even more with more resources
Speaker 8:  than, than us. And the factories got a lot smarter now because before the
Speaker 8:  factory took all the risk. So they would procure all the components and
Speaker 8:  they would make everything. And if the entrepreneur or the company couldn't
Speaker 8:  sell the product, the factory would be sitting on everything. But with us,
Speaker 8:  when they eventually agreed to work with us, which they didn't in the beginning,
Speaker 8:  we had to pay everything not even upfront, but months in advance
Speaker 8:  of getting the product. So it got much harder from a funding perspective
Speaker 8:  and a cashflow perspective for us compared to the guys before because the,
Speaker 8:  the SU supply chain had just lost so much money with these other
Speaker 8:  startups in the past.
Speaker 2:  And in thinking about like how do we push all this stuff into the future,
Speaker 2:  I feel like there's a version of nothing where you tried to do something
Speaker 2:  super different and you ended up doing like what Humane is
Speaker 2:  doing with the, the AI pin or what Snap did with spectacles a bunch of years
Speaker 2:  ago and you're like, we think we know what's next and we're gonna, we're
Speaker 2:  gonna try to build it in public and get everybody really excited and move
Speaker 2:  everybody into the future. You decided to go with
Speaker 2:  headphones and smartphones, which I think you could argue are
Speaker 2:  two of the most like mature mainstream hard to
Speaker 2:  crack markets that exist. Yeah. Why if, if the goal is like
Speaker 2:  make technology exciting again, why build those things?
Speaker 8:  I think you have to exist to be able to make
Speaker 8:  things more exciting. I think of it as kind of like the Apple analogy.
Speaker 8:  So Apple started with computers, but computers is not what made
Speaker 8:  Apple really big. The iPod was what made Apple really big and then they had
Speaker 8:  successes with iPhone and other products after that. I think our
Speaker 8:  entry into the smartphone industry is similar to Apple's entry into the computer
Speaker 8:  industry. It's a mature market through being different, we can find
Speaker 8:  our group of consumers and eventually build a business that is self-sustaining.
Speaker 8:  We can make some profits and then we can take those profits and
Speaker 8:  reinvest those into imagining what a future form factor could be.
Speaker 8:  I think we need that iPod moment in the future as well. But if we
Speaker 8:  started with that really crazy idea, what if it didn't have product market
Speaker 8:  fit then you know, we don't have an opportunity to try and create
Speaker 8:  the future anymore. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I mean, it's an interesting analogy, right? Cuz I do think the computer market
Speaker 2:  was substantially less mature in the seventies when Apple came
Speaker 2:  in than the smartphone market is now. Which I think just like kind of makes
Speaker 2:  that road for you even harder in a lot of ways. It's like there
Speaker 2:  was no sort of apple of the computer industry at that time. But the thing
Speaker 2:  that's interesting is like, I think about sort of what is, what is at the
Speaker 2:  point right now that the MP3 market was when the iPod came
Speaker 2:  out and it's like there really isn't one, I kind of feel like the closest
Speaker 2:  thing is maybe headsets in the sense that like some exist but it's
Speaker 2:  pretty clear that nothing has gotten it right. But I also think we're like
Speaker 2:  several massive technical breakthroughs from being able to make, you know,
Speaker 2:  the iPod of headsets or whatever. I don't think the Vision pro is that thing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And so it's, it's just sort of a tricky moment where it, it does feel
Speaker 2:  like your only options are things we're totally not ready for
Speaker 2:  or things that may be kind of at the other side of the curve of being super,
Speaker 2:  super exciting to everybody.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think our strategy is to start with really mature categories
Speaker 8:  that are big. So for smartphones, over a billion are sold every year for
Speaker 8:  wireless headphones. Over 300 million are sold every year and try and be
Speaker 8:  different there. At least carve out a niche for ourselves and then gradually
Speaker 8:  take it step by step to a more, more innovative
Speaker 8:  part of the curve.
Speaker 2:  So You don't have to win the phone market, you just have to get enough of
Speaker 2:  the phone market to put yourself in a position to win the next thing.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think, you know, apple in the computer industry, although Dynamics
Speaker 8:  were not exactly the same, but today there's still kind of not a dominating
Speaker 8:  player in terms of market share. I don't think that we're gonna be a dominating
Speaker 8:  player if we're around in 10 years in smartphones. I think the, the p
Speaker 8:  like the turning point will be a new form factor definitely. Is it glasses?
Speaker 8:  You know, I've been thinking a lot about software. I think
Speaker 8:  a lot of the smartest people they went out to making apps. So in
Speaker 8:  2008 the app store was invented. I think that was like the major,
Speaker 8:  the last major innovation in mobile os before the app store,
Speaker 8:  whatever features you got with the phone were the features you had throughout
Speaker 8:  the entire lifecycle. Unless you sideloaded something after the app store,
Speaker 8:  you could basically extend your phone with infinite capability. Like whatever
Speaker 8:  other people could dream up, you could download, right? So I think a lot
Speaker 8:  of the smart people, they went on to making apps around 2008
Speaker 8:  and then it got to a point where people were just optimizing for time spent
Speaker 8:  or trying to make whatever metric was important to them. And, I think the,
Speaker 8:  the major platforms like app apps were there. They were bought into this
Speaker 8:  because whenever the app developers make money they also make money.
Speaker 8:  So I think there's a vested interest in not doing that much on the, on the
Speaker 8:  mobile OS side. Maybe that's where we, you know, should be exploring
Speaker 8:  what what could be done. Okay. Like one of the things we've done with the
Speaker 8:  phone too is we feel like apps have gotten too powerful. Like,
Speaker 8:  you know, sometimes I know I have to do something on my phone work related.
Speaker 8:  So I unlock my phone, I go into TikTok or Instagram, I
Speaker 8:  scroll for, I just wanted to scroll for like one minute to see what's, what's
Speaker 8:  new, what notifications are important. But I actually just end up scrolling
Speaker 8:  for five minutes and then I forgot what, what my original task was. Yep.
Speaker 8:  So we feel like apps have gotten too powerful and with the phone
Speaker 8:  too, both on the hardware side with the cliff but also on the software side,
Speaker 8:  we're trying to at least give users options to take
Speaker 8:  some of that power back.
Speaker 2:  I mean now you're just bringing up my like pet favorite thing to talk about.
Speaker 2:  I've been obsessed with this world of these like slightly dumber smartphones
Speaker 2:  for forever. The the light phone and there was the the punk a few years ago
Speaker 2:  and this idea about like what if you had a phone that did all the things
Speaker 2:  you needed it to but didn't take over your entire life. Which I think
Speaker 2:  is a really good thing. And I think a lot of people intellectually want that,
Speaker 2:  but I think figuring out how to make the case for what amounts to like a
Speaker 2:  slightly worse smartphone is really complicated.
Speaker 8:  It it is. And
Speaker 2:  You're better at marketing in this space than most And I think even for you
Speaker 2:  that story is gonna be hard to tell. Like we are going to make it harder
Speaker 2:  for you to find the Instagram icon because that's good for you. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  I think that's right. And. I just, I don't know how to get over that bridge.
Speaker 8:  I think it's going against human nature Yeah. Is really difficult
Speaker 2:  And tens of thousands of engineers who have spent the last decade building
Speaker 2:  really, really good apps that I am sort of drawn to spend hours in
Speaker 8:  All day. Yeah. So I think we gotta start with a niche. I think there's a
Speaker 8:  certain type of consumer out there who's, who really resonates with features
Speaker 8:  like this. It's really gonna be hard to convince the mass to adopt something
Speaker 8:  like this. It's hard to go against human nature. Like we're hardwired to
Speaker 8:  want to use things that are addictive. So I think it's,
Speaker 8:  it's, it's one step but it's not gonna take us to the, to the mainstream.
Speaker 8:  Definitely. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's fair. So tell me about the phone too. So by the time this comes out
Speaker 2:  the reviews will be out, a lot of folks will have seen it, but I think based
Speaker 2:  on kind of what I've heard and what you said in the launch and stuff, you,
Speaker 2:  you learned a lot from the phone. One, building phones is hard. You,
Speaker 2:  you got better at it, you got a better team. You've like convinced some of
Speaker 2:  these partners that you're actually doing this for real and you're not just
Speaker 2:  gonna leave them in the lurch with a bunch of unused product and you're in
Speaker 2:  a position where you can like push a little harder towards the stuff you
Speaker 2:  wanna do. So when you look at the phone too, where does that most
Speaker 2:  show up? What is the like you're like this is now the stuff we're able to
Speaker 2:  do because we're better at this now.
Speaker 8:  So if you look at the hardware design or the hardware side, we
Speaker 8:  had the Cliff interface with the phone one. We got a lot of negative feedback
Speaker 8:  on the, from comments on the internet saying it's like a gimmick. Okay it's
Speaker 8:  just a nice phone with some funky lights on the back, but it's not really
Speaker 8:  useful. It wasn't that we didn't have those ideas of how to make it useful
Speaker 8:  and what features it should have. We just didn't have the engineering capability
Speaker 8:  to deliver all of that. So now with the phone too, on
Speaker 8:  the glyph interface side, there's a whole lot of features. There's a timer,
Speaker 8:  there's a progress bar. So when you're like waiting for your food delivery
Speaker 8:  or waiting for a Uber, you can see where it is. We created a
Speaker 8:  Glyph composer so you can have fun and kind of create your own gly segment,
Speaker 8:  share with your friends. And we're working with artists like Swedish House
Speaker 8:  Mafia to make sound packs. Nice. Yeah. So it's just more fun. So
Speaker 8:  a lot more on the utility but a lot more fun as well.
Speaker 2:  That reminds me of, I don't know even know if this is still a thing, but
Speaker 2:  for a while you could customize the vibration patterns on certain phones
Speaker 2:  so that like if you had an in your pocket and it was like, oh if my wife
Speaker 2:  is calling it does sort of three quick pulses and if it's anybody else it's
Speaker 2:  like too long. Pulses. Yeah, And, I. Remember spending so much time trying
Speaker 2:  to dial that in only to discover that I could never get it quite right and
Speaker 2:  could never remember what was what. But I feel like the gly thing kind of
Speaker 2:  vibes with me
Speaker 8:  In that. Yeah, I think we should simplify it. Right? So now we also introduce
Speaker 8:  something we call essential glyphs. So for things that are really
Speaker 8:  essential for you, it's just always on. It doesn't flash and go away.
Speaker 8:  So you could assign this one to somebody important as an example. So I think
Speaker 8:  that's easier to, to recognize than some vibration or, or
Speaker 8:  a light that flashes in and disappears. So the hardware side, I think
Speaker 8:  Cliff is a lot more useful. I know that the creativity within
Speaker 8:  our company cannot be compared to the creativity of the entire internet.
Speaker 8:  So we're creating SDK for this interface. Other app developers can also
Speaker 8:  tap in and, and it'll be exciting to see what they build with this.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I, I noticed in using it there's definitely like, you can tell the
Speaker 2:  team is bigger, there's just more stuff going on on the phone than there
Speaker 2:  was before. It feels like you've, you've touched more of the menus, you've
Speaker 2:  touched more of the icons, there's more going on kind of in the nothing os
Speaker 2:  people built new widgets. It's just like there was just yeah, human power
Speaker 2:  to build some of this stuff. But it does make me wonder not to keep going
Speaker 2:  back to the Apple analogy, but like the thing Apple did very
Speaker 2:  early on that worked out really, really well for Apple was basically try
Speaker 2:  to own as much of the thing as it possibly could. And you're in a position
Speaker 2:  with smartphones where that's very hard. Like building your own Os right
Speaker 2:  now is is suicide. Yeah. Like it just, it just is if you, if you weren't
Speaker 2:  running Android, people would be like, that's stupid and just move on to
Speaker 2:  their last, they need
Speaker 8:  Apps,
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. And and so you're in this position where there is at some
Speaker 2:  point sort of a wall on how much you can do. I would think in part because
Speaker 2:  apps are made to run on specific kinds of devices with specific size
Speaker 2:  screens with specific kinds of resolutions. Like how far do you feel
Speaker 2:  like you can push in the smartphone world before you either like lose
Speaker 2:  users or just build something nobody wants?
Speaker 8:  I think taking a step-by-step approach and reacting to user feedback for
Speaker 8:  every generation we could probably do something really interesting. Okay.
Speaker 8:  And wait for that leapfrog moment. You mentioned that it's
Speaker 8:  our hands are kind of tied right on multiple fronts and even within
Speaker 8:  Android, if you look at the market share globally, but in particular in the
Speaker 8:  US like iOS is creeping up year on year. I think today
Speaker 8:  is already in general population of the US it's like
Speaker 8:  55%. Yeah. iOS already
Speaker 2:  And climbing pretty fast and
Speaker 8:  Climbing. Yeah. And for people under 18 it's like 90%. So what happens
Speaker 8:  when these people grow up I mean is Android still gonna be around? So that's
Speaker 8:  something that, you know, really worries us, us as well. Like if we're able
Speaker 8:  to be successful with the next few generations of products. But at the same
Speaker 8:  time, if the door for Android is, is slowly closing, then what do
Speaker 8:  we have to build a company on? Right?
Speaker 2:  So, but the thing I take away from that is like, I, I swear the whole reason
Speaker 2:  for the iOS thing is just blue bubbles. Like it's just, it's just blue bubbles
Speaker 2:  and it's like there there are people out there who it's like, you know, what's
Speaker 2:  the, what's the biggest turnoff in a possible dating partner in people like
Speaker 2:  Green Bubbles? Yeah. And it's like that is like objectively insane. But this
Speaker 2:  is the world we live in. Are there blue bubbly things you feel like you
Speaker 2:  can do in this space without being sort of the
Speaker 2:  dominant player? Like if I'm, yeah, if you're, if you're running Samsung,
Speaker 2:  you have some moves right there, you can, you can start to sort of enclose
Speaker 2:  the ecosystem in some interesting ways. You're too small to do that right
Speaker 2:  now in a way that would sort of blow up. Maybe that changes over time. But
Speaker 2:  are there, do you have moves like that?
Speaker 8:  My view on this is that, you know, apple, they used to really compete on
Speaker 8:  making the best product, the best user experience, the best software, the
Speaker 8:  best hardware, the best interplay between hardware and software. But today
Speaker 8:  they build so many moats that are beyond that, right? So they don't have
Speaker 8:  to compete as hard on pure product cuz they have these blue bubble
Speaker 8:  moats and ultimately that's gonna be really bad for the
Speaker 8:  consumer because there's just gonna be fewer and fewer options. If you look
Speaker 8:  at our industry, there's fewer and fewer brands over time it's getting more
Speaker 8:  and more consolidated and Apple is slowly gaining market share every single
Speaker 8:  year. So I think ultimately the only way around this
Speaker 8:  is, is, is if the government steps in, and I've seen in Europe that things
Speaker 8:  are already happening with a USB C standard. But also I think
Speaker 8:  next year the protocol iMessage has to be opened up in Europe
Speaker 8:  based on my understanding. But I'm not sure how they're gonna phase it. And,
Speaker 8:  I'm sure Apple is gonna try and make it difficult. That's,
Speaker 2:  That's gonna get messier before it gets better I
Speaker 8:  Think. I think so as well. So what can we do? We can't wait. Okay. We can
Speaker 8:  communicate on, on kind of how, how unfair the some of the practices are
Speaker 8:  and how it's really hard to break in and innovate in this market. We can
Speaker 8:  probably not I mean if we build our own social features, it's probably not
Speaker 8:  gonna do that much, right? Cuz we're, our user base is still quite
Speaker 8:  small. Maybe we can do some really naughty stuff like reverse
Speaker 8:  engineer iMessage and Yeah. And have support on our
Speaker 2:  Phones. Sure. I mean, but even that, it's sort of an interesting thing to
Speaker 2:  think about how to sequence, right? Because if you wait until you're huge
Speaker 2:  to build that stuff, you've kind of missed a chance to bring people
Speaker 2:  along with you. But if you do it at the beginning, it's gonna be so
Speaker 2:  sort of limited in its utility. But I just think about like, I
Speaker 2:  mostly use an iPhone and my wife mostly uses a Pixel and there's just a
Speaker 2:  series of things that are more annoying in our relationship as a result.
Speaker 2:  And so I'm at a point now where it's like one of us is gonna switch phones
Speaker 2:  because it's just gonna make life easier for us to like send each other pictures
Speaker 2:  airdrop, right? Because trying to send pictures between devices is awful
Speaker 2:  when you're on different platforms.
Speaker 8:  So what, what do you guys do now? Email or
Speaker 2:  She just texts me everything. Links and the, the videos come in like tiny
Speaker 2:  little postage stamps. I mean it's bad, it's a crappy system. We have shared
Speaker 2:  Google photos albums that kind of work. It's just not good is the point.
Speaker 2:  And so I think for me it's like okay if I go out and buy
Speaker 2:  us the same thing, if I'm buying two nothing
Speaker 2:  phones, should that be better than if she has a Pixel And? I have a
Speaker 2:  Nothing Phone
Speaker 8:  Today it's probably the same. Okay. Android is also building interoperability
Speaker 8:  between Android devices. So instead of Airdrop, Android has something called
Speaker 8:  nearby share. Right? It works in a similar way. I don't think it's the right
Speaker 8:  time yet to make the experience between nothing devices way better than nothing
Speaker 8:  and other Android devices. Okay,
Speaker 2:  That's fair. I think that's probably right. And it does seem like Android
Speaker 2:  has at least gotten better enough in that regard that you're not,
Speaker 2:  you're not missing. There's
Speaker 8:  Too, too much.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The iOS to Android dinner play sucks really bad. Yeah. But with things
Speaker 2:  like RCS and nearby share and that kind of stuff, it seems like the blue
Speaker 2:  bubbles of Android at least are coming along a little bit.
Speaker 8:  I don't think it's enough. Okay. It's not stopping the market share increase
Speaker 8:  or the market share decrease. Right? So it's something that's kind of worrying
Speaker 8:  but you know, hopefully some, something good happens. What
Speaker 2:  Do you make of that? Like the looking at the fact that especially in the
Speaker 2:  US the iPhone is just dominant. Like what, what's the takeaway
Speaker 2:  there? Is it just that Apple is better at marketing this than everybody?
Speaker 8:  I think Apple had the best product and now that they built the
Speaker 8:  moats, they can focus less on innovating on the product. They can just
Speaker 8:  keep defending their their pie. So that's my take. So if we want innovation
Speaker 8:  to speed up, again, somebody has to do something about all these modes
Speaker 8:  because like messaging is almost like infrastructure. Like how can you
Speaker 8:  give monopoly to one company? File sharing is kind of like
Speaker 8:  basic in infrastructure. Would you give water system or
Speaker 8:  plum like water, plumbing and electricity to one company? I don't know. But
Speaker 8:  that's kind of what's what's happening.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Do you buy that hardware can kind of lead that cuz I think a lot of
Speaker 2:  it also is, I think the app ecosystem on iOS is pretty
Speaker 2:  definitively better than on Android. But I think, like I remember talking
Speaker 2:  to the Pixel team years ago when they were starting the Pixel and one of
Speaker 2:  the things that they said is we need to make what we believe is like a truly
Speaker 2:  terrific Android device to make developers excited to build stuff for this
Speaker 2:  device. And I think to some extent that has worked and that's what they've
Speaker 2:  tried to do with Chromebooks. That's what they've tried to do with tablets
Speaker 2:  and kind of to, you know, mixed effect on some of those. But you've been
Speaker 2:  in this business a long time. Do you buy the idea that like if you make really
Speaker 2:  great hardware, you can get people to kind of wanna be part of it? I guess
Speaker 2:  the, the same question goes for like the glyph interface
Speaker 8:  I think with scale. Okay, great hardware and a lot of scale because the app
Speaker 8:  developers, they're, a lot of them are also businesses. So they have to figure
Speaker 8:  out the roi. If I invest engineering resource, am I gonna make the money
Speaker 8:  back or not? So it's easier when you have scale. I think we're lucky because
Speaker 8:  we have a very, cause we're quite small, so we have a very enthusiastic community.
Speaker 8:  They're very technical. So there'll be a lot of kind of hacking going on
Speaker 8:  once we're released. Sdk, maybe something interesting comes out of that.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. But I don't expect the, the metas or you know, the largest
Speaker 8:  tech companies in the world to use our glyph SDK
Speaker 2:  Is the only way to do that. To just, if volume eventually gets so big, they
Speaker 2:  can't ignore you. That's the only move.
Speaker 8:  That's the only way. Okay. I think
Speaker 2:  You don't think you can like sneak one into, into Adam ER's office
Speaker 2:  and be like, hey, here's a, here's a cool thing that might work for Instagram
Speaker 2:  just to
Speaker 8:  Get him off. I think he might really love the product, but it still doesn't
Speaker 8:  make sense for him to commit resources to, to doing anything at this moment
Speaker 8:  unless it can can really benefit his product somehow.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. I I can understand that Adam build it. If you're listening,
Speaker 2:  I don't know what it would do, but every time you get an Instagram, just
Speaker 2:  cliffs everywhere. All right, we're gonna take a break, but we have
Speaker 2:  lots more to talk about including what comes after phones. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 11:  Unexplainable has got a new two-part series we're calling the black box.
Speaker 11:  It's all about the mysterious hole at the center of modern artificial intelligence.
Speaker 12:  I've built these models, I've studied these models, we just don't understand
Speaker 12:  what's going on here.
Speaker 11:  Even the experts don't really know how these systems work or what they can
Speaker 11:  do
Speaker 12:  If we open up PGE or a system like it. You just see
Speaker 12:  millions of numbers flipping around and we just have no
Speaker 12:  idea what any of it means.
Speaker 13:  We are rushing at breakneck speed towards
Speaker 13:  more and more advanced forms of ai.
Speaker 14:  You know, when I see something that is well beyond my understanding,
Speaker 14:  I'm scared. And that was something well beyond my understanding.
Speaker 11:  I'm know I'm hassenfeld, but this isn't my voice and it hasn't been the
Speaker 11:  whole time. It's just an AI made that sounds sort of like me. An
Speaker 11:  unexplainable new series starts July 12th, wherever you get your podcast.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back with Carl. Pay the CEO of nothing. Talk to me about
Speaker 2:  price, cuz I think this is something you've been through now at a couple
Speaker 2:  of different companies trying to figure out how do I sell good stuff at the
Speaker 2:  lowest possible price. And you're kind of doing the same thing you did at
Speaker 2:  One Plus, which is like one of the things that most impressed people about
Speaker 2:  the phone one was how cheap it was. And I think with this next one, the phone
Speaker 2:  is, seems to be significantly better but also significantly more expensive.
Speaker 2:  It's gone from 3 99 to 5 99. Yeah. How do you balance
Speaker 2:  making a phone at the, at the cheapest possible price with trying to do
Speaker 2:  all this other stuff you're trying to do?
Speaker 8:  It's quite complicated. We can't just think about what consumers are gonna
Speaker 8:  think, although consumers are the most important ones. We also have to think
Speaker 8:  about the suppliers because our industry doesn't really support
Speaker 8:  small companies. It just costs like 30 to 50 million
Speaker 8:  for each new product we develop. Wow. So if we sell one
Speaker 8:  unit, it's still that amount of money. If we sell a million units, it's still
Speaker 8:  that amount of money. Right? So we just have to reach scale and it also,
Speaker 8:  it's quite, quite costly for our factories and our suppliers to work with
Speaker 8:  us. So unless they feel like we can become a big company one day, it
Speaker 8:  doesn't make sense to, to collaborate. So in the beginning
Speaker 8:  with the phone one, we had to sacrifice and make it a
Speaker 8:  loss leader just to get to some level of volume that's enticing for,
Speaker 8:  for supply chain to wanna work with us.
Speaker 2:  So at that point, it's actually more useful to be sort of cool and
Speaker 2:  zeitgeisty than it is to be per unit profitable in, in that first
Speaker 2:  run.
Speaker 8:  We need to get the volumes up. Sure. That's, that's like the key. Okay. So,
Speaker 8:  but as a company we can't keep making a loss on everything we sell. Sure.
Speaker 8:  So over time we have to become profitable and we,
Speaker 2:  We should've just made the phone 50 bucks you would've sold a ton of them
Speaker 2:  would've
Speaker 8:  Been great. Exactly. And would've been bankrupt by now. So it's
Speaker 8:  about finding the right balance. So with the phone two, we're not losing
Speaker 8:  money on every device sold. We're making a small margin, but after all
Speaker 8:  the costs this year, we're still gonna be lose quite a bit of money.
Speaker 8:  But we have to make that step so that, you know, eventually maybe next year
Speaker 8:  or the year after we can break even The economy right now is not the best.
Speaker 8:  So funding, although it's available, it's much harder than before.
Speaker 8:  So we gotta try and run a more, get to profitability quicker than
Speaker 8:  before.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I have no evidence for this and it's possible, I'm totally wrong. And
Speaker 2:  I. Hope you tell me if I am. But it seems to me that especially in the US,
Speaker 2:  $600 is kind of an awkward price for a phone. Yeah. Like I, I
Speaker 2:  almost think it's easier in some ways to make the case for like an eight
Speaker 2:  or $900 phone than it is for a $600 phone. Because
Speaker 2:  especially in the US where people are paying it off over the course of a
Speaker 2:  couple of years, it's, it's a couple of dollars a month people don't really
Speaker 2:  notice. But then if you say, okay, I can buy the iPhone for a thousand dollars,
Speaker 2:  right? That is just sort of the, the assumed price of a very good phone.
Speaker 2:  You come in and say, no, we've made a very good phone for $600 and there's
Speaker 2:  just a thing that lodges in people's brains that's like, well what's the
Speaker 2:  catch And I think? Right? If it's like, yeah, if it's $200, I understand
Speaker 2:  that I'm making trade offs and I'm clearly a a cost conscious person, but
Speaker 2:  you get to this middle ground, And, I think lots of companies have found
Speaker 2:  this in the US that the price sensitivity is really different here.
Speaker 2:  And so it's like at some point if you're gonna ca if you're gonna charge
Speaker 2:  $600, you might as well just charge $900.
Speaker 8:  The market is like a barbell shaped. Yeah. So you got a lot of volume
Speaker 8:  at the low end and a lot of volume at the high end. But I think that's like
Speaker 8:  when you're looking at the market as a whole, like the general market in
Speaker 8:  the US looks like that. However, we're not catering to the general market
Speaker 8:  today. We're not even available for sale inside of the carrier stores. Sure.
Speaker 8:  I think the first step to our entrance into the US
Speaker 8:  is we gotta target to the tech enthusiasts
Speaker 2:  Who are even less price sensitive. These are the people who are out there
Speaker 2:  buying $1,800 crappy foldable phones.
Speaker 8:  I think a lot of them actually look at what you get and what you pay. Okay.
Speaker 8:  And can be really smart about that. So at least that group of people are
Speaker 8:  gonna be, I think it's gonna, this phone is gonna speak to them. I think
Speaker 8:  us is really, really complicated as a market. We gotta take a step-by-step
Speaker 8:  approach, start by building a loyal fan base, people really knowledgeable
Speaker 8:  with people, really know knowledgeable about technology, have their endorsement
Speaker 8:  first, you know, collaborate with them to make the product really, really
Speaker 8:  good before we go to the next step. you know, us is, it's
Speaker 8:  like one of the freest economies in the world, but actually our industry
Speaker 8:  in the US it's one of the most difficult ones.
Speaker 2:  Oh, it's a disaster to
Speaker 8:  Break into. Yeah. Like the barrier to entry is so high. There's basically
Speaker 8:  only three sales channels. Right? The three carriers, the three big carriers.
Speaker 8:  And it just makes it a lot more complicated than compared to other markets
Speaker 8:  where everything is unlocked. When, when everything is unlocked, you can
Speaker 8:  just speak to the consumer and as long as you have a great product and a
Speaker 8:  and a a brand that consumers love, that's all you need to worry about. But
Speaker 8:  here it's, it's it's way more complicated.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean that sort of mid-range phone graveyard is
Speaker 2:  littered with phones who thought they could crack unlocked phones in the
Speaker 2:  US Yeah. And they just were all wrong. It's really hard to do.
Speaker 8:  And then you see the market share for iPhone keep increasing as well. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Exactly. Yeah. People like walk into stores and say, what should I buy? And
Speaker 2:  they say, here's the new version of your old phone. Yeah. And that's in the
Speaker 2:  US especially, that just is what happens. so like I had a, I had a Samsung
Speaker 2:  phone or I had an iPhone and you use your phone
Speaker 2:  until it dies, then you upgrade it to whatever the newest one of those things
Speaker 2:  is. And breaking that chain
Speaker 2:  strikes me as maybe the hardest challenge of breaking into the us
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I've spoken to carriers in the us it's not that we can't be
Speaker 8:  arranged, but I think it's just not the right timing. But something that
Speaker 8:  came out of those conversations was that they're also really worried about
Speaker 8:  the situation because they're seeing, you know, after these
Speaker 8:  big launches, they would measure the footfall into their stores and now the
Speaker 8:  footfall is getting less and less ing after the launches because there's
Speaker 8:  not much new to, to go and check out in person anymore. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I mean that tracks I mean. We even see that covering these things like the,
Speaker 2:  the sort of day of enthusiasm for one of these new devices is definitely
Speaker 2:  not what it once was.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So hopefully we can do something about it, but it'll it'll take a bit
Speaker 8:  of time. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's fair. So, and speaking of that, actually, one of the things I've heard
Speaker 2:  you talk a bunch about is thinking about how to do all this stuff over
Speaker 2:  time. Right? You, you clearly have a long roadmap. You didn't answer my question
Speaker 2:  about glasses, so I'm gonna make you answer my question about glasses here
Speaker 2:  at some point. But you also are in a position of You
Speaker 2:  don't have unlimited money. You're not a trillion dollar company that can
Speaker 2:  just pour money into the metaverse until it becomes a thing.
Speaker 2:  You have a a small number of shots at this in a pretty real way.
Speaker 2:  Like I've talked to a lot of companies over the year who are like, we we
Speaker 2:  got one hardware order wrong because it didn't launch
Speaker 2:  to as much excitement as we hoped and it bankrupted the company and that
Speaker 2:  was it. Yeah. We ended up with a warehouse full of phones and no company.
Speaker 2:  How do you square those two things? You're like, okay, this is the thing
Speaker 2:  that gets us to the thing. We want to be big, we have this long
Speaker 2:  roadmap, but we also have to keep being an ongoing
Speaker 2:  concern. Yeah. To get there.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. You got kind of have to have a dream, but you have to be very practical
Speaker 8:  and reaching it. I think this business is one of the most challenging ones
Speaker 8:  to build because there's just so many things you gotta think about. You gotta
Speaker 8:  think about everything from supply chain to manufacturing to
Speaker 8:  hardware engineering, software engineering, hardware design, software design,
Speaker 8:  sales, marketing, distribution around the world. It's different in every
Speaker 8:  country. Marketing is different in every country then
Speaker 8:  supporting the products, software updates and you know, fixing,
Speaker 8:  repairing the products when they're broken. So the chain, the, you know,
Speaker 8:  the value chain is just so long compared to if we're just making an app
Speaker 8:  Right. It'll be much, much simpler. Sure. So I think,
Speaker 2:  Or the reverse, like the one of the companies that I know you've thought
Speaker 2:  about in, in building this company is Tesla, And, I. Think the smart thing
Speaker 2:  Tesla did was say our first car is gonna cost $250,000. We're not gonna
Speaker 2:  sell very many of them, but we're gonna make a bunch of money on the ones
Speaker 2:  that we do sell. And that's gonna start to pay as we kind of trickle down.
Speaker 2:  So for you that, I don't know, you, you could have started with like a, a
Speaker 2:  foldable phone that cost $2,000 and some people would've bought it, some
Speaker 2:  people would've not bought it, and then you can sort of slowly scale up.
Speaker 2:  But you, you tried to do kind of the, a small version of the mainstream
Speaker 2:  thing. Yeah. From the very beginning.
Speaker 8:  I thought about the Tesla model, but I think Tesla was so ahead of its time
Speaker 8:  against their competitors. That's fair. Yeah. To make an electric vehicle,
Speaker 8:  a foldable phone does not have the same headstart as
Speaker 8:  as
Speaker 2:  That's fair. You would've had to launch that in like 2012 and then you would've,
Speaker 2:  you
Speaker 8:  Would've had, and also the utility of electric car is so easy to understand
Speaker 8:  versus a foldable phone. I think that's fair. So maybe when we,
Speaker 8:  you know, go to our iPod moment, that's where we start from the high end.
Speaker 8:  I don't know.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no, I I that's, that's fair. And I think, I just think that pace is
Speaker 2:  really interesting and we've seen so many companies, like Snap has been going
Speaker 2:  through this in a big way where they, they started the spectacles. They're
Speaker 2:  like, here's the road to true augmented reality. We think we're gonna get
Speaker 2:  there. And that road has gotten weirder and longer than anybody expected
Speaker 2:  and has been really hard for that company. And Meta is going through the
Speaker 2:  same thing with Oculus, like that's getting better, but not as quickly as
Speaker 2:  we would hope. Apple's having trouble with Division Pro. It's like these
Speaker 2:  roads are long and complicated and those are companies, those are like public
Speaker 2:  companies with billions of dollars to lose on this problem. It's
Speaker 8:  A cliche, but I I mean timing is key. So we're trying to do the right thing
Speaker 8:  at the right time. Yeah. And, and have a more patient approach.
Speaker 2:  So speaking of that, what do you look at right now? It feels like we're in
Speaker 2:  this crazy moment of change. All anybody talks about is ai,
Speaker 2:  wearables are like kind of a thing. Glasses are becoming the thing.
Speaker 2:  Like what's, what do you make of the transition we're in right
Speaker 8:  Now? I think for us, like at where we are, we are,
Speaker 8:  what's really important is to get to profitability. If we don't, then there's
Speaker 8:  a risk, again,
Speaker 2:  You're talking like a big company here. Like we have to be fiscally responsible
Speaker 8:  Because we, if we are not profitable then we don't have the opportunity to
Speaker 8:  build the next thing. And that that's, that's a reality. Yeah. A lot of these
Speaker 8:  big companies, they have a lot of free cash flow like Google and Face and
Speaker 8:  Meta. They make a lot of money on ads so they can use that business to kind
Speaker 8:  of subsidize or take, take larger risks elsewhere. We don't have that. So
Speaker 8:  we need to make sure we're at least safe and we survive and then we can figure
Speaker 8:  out the, the really interesting products. Is
Speaker 2:  That hard for you as the CEO to move sort of deliberately
Speaker 2:  in that sense? Because I would think also if you're sitting there thinking
Speaker 2:  like, okay we, here is the, the thing that is going to make
Speaker 2:  us the company we want to be, to not just
Speaker 2:  pour everything into racing there as quickly as you possibly could and actually
Speaker 2:  be sort of methodical on the way. Seems like it would be a really hard thing
Speaker 2:  to stay disciplined about over
Speaker 8:  Time. There's no other option. I mean it's like a, a game with no other,
Speaker 8:  other path. So I think it's, it's quite easy to, to be on this
Speaker 8:  path apart from reaching profitability, I think it's really important to
Speaker 8:  build a really solid team and really solid processes so we can run
Speaker 8:  like clockwork for when that opportunity comes. We'll be much more,
Speaker 8:  it'll be much easier for us to capture the opportunity. It's like during
Speaker 8:  winter let's train our body to be really strong so that when summer comes,
Speaker 8:  when spring, when spring comes, we can run really quickly.
Speaker 2:  So do you think the phone keeps being the thing for a long time? Both for
Speaker 2:  you and kind of for the world?
Speaker 8:  I think so, yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like if you fast forward out five years from now, is the phone still the,
Speaker 2:  the primary thing that everybody has with them all the time.
Speaker 8:  A computing device made up of a large screen with some camera capability
Speaker 8:  I think is gonna be the dominating form factor for Okay. A long time
Speaker 8:  people have said voice might be taking over or kind of
Speaker 8:  immersion into virtual reality. But I, I think those are more like
Speaker 8:  in addition to the main form factor, you can't get the
Speaker 8:  same level of utility through just audio or it, it
Speaker 8:  doesn't feel that good to always be in a virtual environment. So
Speaker 8:  I think this form factor will be really key. But I think maybe what happens
Speaker 8:  on the OS side and the software side could change with all the
Speaker 8:  improvements we're seeing in AI today.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. What does that look like do you think as, as you cast out a few years?
Speaker 2:  I think the thing I keep hearing is basically like how do we take your phone,
Speaker 2:  how of being kind of an app machine, right? That all your
Speaker 2:  device does is provide a bunch of icons that you tap on to go into sort of
Speaker 2:  individual worlds that are apps and how do we kind of stitch it all back
Speaker 2:  together in a way that makes more sense And that's what like Alexa and Google
Speaker 2:  Assistant were supposed to be. That's what everybody's talking about with
Speaker 2:  the AI chatbots. Is that where you think we're headed or do you see something
Speaker 8:  Else? I think so. I think there's not a lot of dumb people. I think everybody
Speaker 8:  sees a similar kind of long-term vision but everybody might have
Speaker 8:  a different solution or how hypothesis on how to get there.
Speaker 8:  If we take one step back and just think about what it means to be a tech
Speaker 8:  company, I think we need to either, not just our company but
Speaker 8:  the tech company community. We either have to enable
Speaker 8:  consumers to do something they weren't able to do before or we, we need to
Speaker 8:  enable them to do it. Something they can already do, but much faster or much
Speaker 8:  cheaper. So I think that's, those are the guiding principles for how we evolve
Speaker 8:  the OS as well. Like okay, it's an app machine right now. It's an app
Speaker 8:  launcher that actually hasn't changed since the Symbian days, right? Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Symbian was also home screen or lock screen with, with a bunch of apps that
Speaker 8:  you open. It took up the entire screen, you went back to home screen and
Speaker 8:  launched something else. So I think if you want to remove that metaphor,
Speaker 8:  you need to create a new metaphor that's way more efficient than before and
Speaker 8:  easy to understand and easy to use.
Speaker 2:  Do you have a theory about what that metaphor looks like? Is it just a text
Speaker 2:  box? Like is the chat g p t bot how
Speaker 8:  You do everything? I think some, some text, not all text. Probably some
Speaker 8:  buttons because writing is still slower than just pressing something
Speaker 8:  and some augmentation via, via voice. I think it needs
Speaker 8:  to slowly augment away the apps. Like
Speaker 8:  today we're using some really simple apps like mindless scrolling apps, right?
Speaker 8:  What if we wanted to accomplish more complicated tasks like 3D modeling or
Speaker 8:  photo editing or I don't know what, what other use case there might be.
Speaker 8:  It's actually quite difficult to learn how to use these new apps, but maybe
Speaker 8:  we can just tell the phone what we need to do and it would use those apps
Speaker 8:  for us without the apps even being visible in the foreground. I think that
Speaker 8:  could be like enough utility to transition to a new
Speaker 8:  metaphor.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean that is like my favorite sort of UI game to
Speaker 2:  play. It's the, it's the plane ticket example, right? Like I need to go to
Speaker 2:  San Francisco. And I would like to buy a plane ticket to get to San Francisco.
Speaker 2:  It turns out that doing like a back and forth with a voice assistant to do
Speaker 2:  that is terrible. Doing a a back and forth with the chatbot is
Speaker 2:  terrible. But also the way we have it now where I'm in six apps, I'm comparing
Speaker 2:  a bunch of different things. Like also terrible. So this question of like
Speaker 2:  what is actually a better structure for doing something like that
Speaker 2:  feels like sort of the next big question of the next, you know, five
Speaker 2:  years and there's a million versions of that, right? Yeah. Where it's like
Speaker 2:  I just wanna, I wanna find something to watch on my TV or I wanna book
Speaker 2:  a reservation to go to dinner. These things that we've all learned how to
Speaker 2:  do in these really specific, not that good ways we have to invent
Speaker 2:  something better for and like the underlying tech is getting there, but the
Speaker 2:  products don't seem to have quite solved it yet.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think everybody sees what the future needs to be, but I think the
Speaker 8:  trick really tricky part is finding the right user interface that's easy
Speaker 8:  to understand and can get adoption from consumers. you know, as we
Speaker 8:  scale our these products into the hands of millions of consumers, we also
Speaker 8:  have a shot at implementing our version to see if it sticks or not.
Speaker 8:  But who knows, right? Cuz the, I don't think it's the underlying technology
Speaker 8:  that's gonna be the most challenging part because it's maturing. It's gonna
Speaker 8:  be the, the right user interface.
Speaker 2:  I have two more questions then I'm gonna let you go. The first is, one of
Speaker 2:  the things that has happened is that this sort of transparent design
Speaker 2:  that you guys have bet really big on is starting to percolate out
Speaker 2:  there. Like Beats has a pair of headphones that looks suspiciously like somebody
Speaker 2:  at Apple got ahold of the nothing headphones and made those for, but
Speaker 2:  for Beats. The, the transparent look is you guys didn't invent it, but
Speaker 2:  I think it, it restarted a bit as nothing started to come out. You're gonna
Speaker 2:  be in a position where like any good startup, there are these big companies
Speaker 2:  that have infinite resources and are gonna copy every cool thing you do
Speaker 2:  really fast. How do you stay out in front of that?
Speaker 8:  I think Apple won't I mean big companies won't really copy
Speaker 8:  us because they already have a much more mass market
Speaker 8:  consumer base. By copying us, they actually limit the amount of users that
Speaker 8:  they can potentially talk to. Cuz our design is more niche.
Speaker 2:  But at the, on the flip side, they have a hundred thousand engineers and
Speaker 2:  they can just throw a thousand of them at any specific problem for a small
Speaker 2:  number of
Speaker 8:  People and, and they can use their sub-brands like what you just mentioned,
Speaker 8:  to do something more niche. Sure. But actually also committing to creating
Speaker 8:  something transparent is actually, it's a lot of work. I don't know if you've
Speaker 8:  seen some of my tweets on how we accomplished this design. I mean it's very
Speaker 8:  easy to make the glue look very ugly
Speaker 8:  because everything is visible now. It's very easy in the manufacturing process
Speaker 8:  for there to be dust. So it actually adds a lot to our costs
Speaker 8:  of making the product transparent. I don't think it's something that
Speaker 8:  like these big companies with a lot of resource, of course they can do it,
Speaker 8:  but I don't know if the economics make sense for them to increase the cost
Speaker 8:  of all their products just to make it look a little bit different. I think
Speaker 8:  it's a good strategy for us because we need to find our niche and wedge
Speaker 8:  ourselves into the market. So I'm not that worried about other people
Speaker 8:  copying. Also, if our, if our vision is to make tech fun again,
Speaker 8:  if we can inspire other people to do more interesting things, that it's still
Speaker 8:  okay. However, if they go straight for some of the user
Speaker 8:  interfaces that we create, like for me, I see the Cliff interface as
Speaker 8:  a UI that we're trying to create. I think that's when we're gonna start defending
Speaker 8:  ourselves. Okay.
Speaker 2:  So do you think about it that ruthlessly in thinking about products,
Speaker 2:  like is is one of the sort of check boxes for new products, is this
Speaker 2:  something that these big companies can't or won't do?
Speaker 8:  I don't think we're, that we weren't that kind of structured about,
Speaker 8:  about this. It just happened. But we realized throughout the process how
Speaker 8:  difficult it was to actually make these products, which kind of alleviated
Speaker 8:  our worry that people would aggressively go after this.
Speaker 2:  Okay. All right. So last thing and then I'll let you go. The phone two is
Speaker 2:  I think in a lot of ways a much better phone one. Is that the right
Speaker 2:  path to be on in this space where you're trying to sort of build something
Speaker 2:  like just keep getting a little better every year? Or do you think there
Speaker 2:  is room for you in this industry to try something
Speaker 2:  wildly different and new?
Speaker 8:  I think both. I think if you keep getting a little bit better every half
Speaker 8:  a year or every year, it really compounds. Right? So you,
Speaker 8:  you end up like maybe,
Speaker 2:  I don't know, I think, I think Apple would say that's what they've been doing
Speaker 2:  for the last decade and then you show up saying everybody's super boring
Speaker 2:  cause they all just get 10% better every year.
Speaker 8:  I don't know. I I feel like this, the changes between the phone one and
Speaker 8:  phone two and how different it is, is a lot bigger than
Speaker 8:  some of these bigger companies. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Like, gimme an example of what, what on there feels,
Speaker 8:  I think the, the software looks completely different as an example. So when
Speaker 8:  we launched the phone one, we, we were only able to make stock Android
Speaker 8:  stable, right? That's the extent of our engineering resource. Now we can
Speaker 8:  start experimenting with our own ideas, our own widgets, our own
Speaker 8:  monochrome ui, et cetera. So I think at least that looks very different
Speaker 8:  and we have a very exciting roadmap for where to take that in the future.
Speaker 8:  So at least the next few generations or next couple of years, there'll be
Speaker 8:  a lot of exciting stuff happening on the software side.
Speaker 2:  What about on the hardware front? Is there a, I know you've, you've said
Speaker 2:  somewhat controversially. I read a thing this morning that said like, Carl
Speaker 2:  pays reality distortion field put Steve Jobs to shame. After you said
Speaker 2:  you're not into foldable phones as an idea. I'm very bullish on flip phones
Speaker 2:  personally. And, I'm happy to give you a long speech about why I love flip
Speaker 2:  phones if you'd like, but you have not seemed all that interested in that.
Speaker 2:  You're, you're still on this kind of like most people's experience of a smartphone.
Speaker 2:  What else can we add to it? Do you think there's big new ideas to be had
Speaker 2:  there?
Speaker 8:  The thing for us is every product needs to be profitable and every product
Speaker 8:  needs to be a hit because we don't have infinite resource. So
Speaker 8:  foldables and flip phones are not that exciting yet, over time as the
Speaker 8:  category matures, as the crease starts really disappearing as apps
Speaker 8:  are being tailored to this new form factor, I think, you
Speaker 8:  know, it's something we we could consider. We're not saying no, but I don't
Speaker 8:  think it's the thing that's gonna really change the paradigm. It's, I don't
Speaker 8:  think it's the thing that's gonna make Android win over iOS. I don't think
Speaker 8:  it's what's gonna make us go from a, a niche smartphone maker
Speaker 8:  to the next big tech company. So it's, it's okay. We
Speaker 8:  just gotta build a really solid base of products and we keep getting
Speaker 8:  better. Hopefully we build up some, some cash
Speaker 8:  to try and invent the next thing.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. All right, well when either the next thing happens or the
Speaker 2:  phone three like flips and folds and you've just been lying to me this whole
Speaker 2:  time, you're gonna come back and we're gonna talk about it. Okay,
Speaker 8:  Sounds good.
Speaker 2:  Thank you Carl. Really appreciate it.
Speaker 8:  Thank you.
Speaker 2:  All right, one more break and then we are going to get deep into our feelings
Speaker 2:  about TV remote.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Andru. Marino is is here. Andru, you have told me
Speaker 2:  very little about what's about to happen to me and to us in the
Speaker 2:  universe, except you told me you wanna talk about TV remotes.
Speaker 16:  Yeah. Yeah. We have a lot of opinions about TV remotes in this
Speaker 16:  Vergecast Producers club here. And I wanted to share
Speaker 16:  that discussion with the audience. Cause I think it's worth talking about.
Speaker 2:  I should say in preparation for this, I went around my house and found every
Speaker 2:  single remote that I have. It turns out there were seven, three of them.
Speaker 2:  I could not tell you what they go to, but I have four functioning remotes
Speaker 2:  and three others in my house. Liam James is also here. Liam who
Speaker 2:  usually refuses to be on the podcast, demanded to be on the podcast.
Speaker 16:  Well someone has to counter your terrible opinions on remote controls.
Speaker 2:  So I mean that's fair. We've been talking about this segment and this issue
Speaker 2:  for a very long time. This might be six or seven hours long. So buckle up
Speaker 2:  everybody. Andru you, you have been talking to some people and and
Speaker 2:  doing some research. Where would you like to start here?
Speaker 16:  Okay, I wanna start with one of the most frustrating remotes I've ever
Speaker 16:  used, which kind of started this conversation about how remote
Speaker 16:  design is kind of an afterthought. So I have this remote
Speaker 16:  and it is one of the novelty remotes cuz I needed a universal remote for
Speaker 16:  my tv. Okay. And it's shaped like a fishing reel.
Speaker 16:  What it looks like a fishing reel has a little like
Speaker 16:  crank on the side. Oh boy. So it actually works
Speaker 16:  with the remote and I'll get to that.
Speaker 2:  You know what this looks like to me is like an old timey like Nintendo video
Speaker 2:  game controller. Like you know the the gun that you had for duck hunt on
Speaker 2:  like the old Nintendo,
Speaker 16:  There's a Dreamcast fishing remote that is a like that.
Speaker 16:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Exactly.
Speaker 16:  It's shaped like a phish fishing reel. There's a skinny handle and
Speaker 16:  there's like a bulbus spool shaped end to it. The
Speaker 16:  first problem is there's absolutely no way to lay this flat on the table
Speaker 16:  because there's a little trigger on the back and if you lay it on the table
Speaker 16:  it just kind of goes to the side. Also there's a gigantic
Speaker 16:  button on the side of the remote that makes this very loud
Speaker 16:  noise.
Speaker 16:  Oh no like sounds like a fishing reel being yanked
Speaker 16:  pressing. This button also turns on the sounds for the remote
Speaker 16:  so I can be like I'm reeling it right now. Is
Speaker 16:  this marketed to children? It's this
Speaker 2:  Is marketed just to you Andru like this. I'm not convinced this is
Speaker 2:  a real product. This is something someone made and conned you into buying
Speaker 2:  on the internet.
Speaker 16:  It's probably like a Father's Day present kind of thing. So obviously
Speaker 16:  you don't want a knowing sound every time you use the remote. So you can
Speaker 16:  turn it off by pressing the button again, but if you put it on the couch
Speaker 16:  it's gonna hit that button again. It's really annoying. And then all
Speaker 16:  the other buttons are so tiny and hard to find. The volume up
Speaker 16:  button is like two little triangles on the left. The
Speaker 2:  Thing you're holding up looks like a slightly bigger like calculator. Watch
Speaker 2:  where all the buttons are the same and tiny and like God help you trying
Speaker 2:  to figure out what any of them are.
Speaker 16:  So obviously this is like a dramatic version of a bad remote
Speaker 16:  design but there are similar kind of problems with remotes.
Speaker 16:  Like my least favorite is that Comcast Silver remote?
Speaker 16:  This one? Oh yeah, David has it here.
Speaker 2:  This is one of the seven that I have in my house. I don't have a Comcast
Speaker 2:  box anymore but I have this remote which means there's like a 60% chance
Speaker 2:  I'm paying Comcast $10 a month for this remote at some point. But I
Speaker 2:  agree this is one of the all time worst remotes and it has the same problem
Speaker 2:  that you were just showing. It has a million buttons, they're all basically
Speaker 2:  the same. You can't find anything just like with your fingers. I agree. This
Speaker 2:  is like one of the worst remotes of all
Speaker 16:  Time. Yeah, this is one of the remotes that's like notorious for being taped
Speaker 16:  off for certain areas. so like you give to your grandparents, it's like
Speaker 16:  here are the three buttons you need to know use,
Speaker 17:  Do not touch the input button.
Speaker 2:  This remote, I'm sorry, I'm just now obsessed with this remote. I'm looking
Speaker 2:  at this remote now. It has five buttons just to control picture
Speaker 2:  and picture mode, which no one ever uses on their Comcast box. And
Speaker 2:  overwhelmingly their Comcast box probably doesn't support it has buttons,
Speaker 2:  marked guide, info, menu, exit help. And last
Speaker 2:  there's an A, B and C. Like what are we, what are we doing? This is out.
Speaker 2:  There are five buttons that you use to turn things on at the top of this.
Speaker 2:  This is, yeah, this just makes me angry to look at.
Speaker 16:  Right? So I wanted to know how did we get to this point? Why
Speaker 16:  are remotes so poorly designed? So the first person I talked
Speaker 16:  to was Steve Turk, he's a designer in Brooklyn.
Speaker 18:  One of the biggest things I've worked on is how to like explain to people,
Speaker 18:  normal people what design is.
Speaker 16:  He wrote this really great blog about the design of remote controls
Speaker 16:  and the different levels of Simplicity. He pointed out
Speaker 16:  the obvious reason why a lot of remotes are quote unquote bad.
Speaker 16:  The
Speaker 18:  Key thing about remotes is though, even though they're the most important
Speaker 18:  thing to the user, they're the last thing that the company thinks about
Speaker 18:  making and generally speaking they're trying to make them as cheaply as
Speaker 18:  possible. And so that often means using a bunch of stock remotes
Speaker 18:  that are kind of manufactured in a hundred different places and yet like
Speaker 18:  the actual, the thing that you hold in your hand for a good five to 10 years,
Speaker 18:  it doesn't seem to be that important. So I think it's more of a cultural
Speaker 18:  thing rather than an engineering problem.
Speaker 2:  I guess that's true. That also explains right why like your cable box looks
Speaker 2:  like crap. It's just not the thing people ultimately at the end of the day
Speaker 2:  care about. Yeah, but it's the least satisfying answer. It really is,
Speaker 2:  but it's probably right. That
Speaker 17:  Makes sense. But also, yeah requires me to accept that people
Speaker 17:  don't care about things that they should.
Speaker 16:  Yeah, exactly. So I talked to someone else who actually
Speaker 16:  has designed remotes, his name is Sajid. He worked on
Speaker 16:  the Phillips UX design.
Speaker 19:  The whole effort was called one UX, which is basically
Speaker 19:  one user experience across all of Philips products. Not only doing
Speaker 19:  the the digital interface designs, remote controls were are an
Speaker 19:  integral part of using a product like a television. So naturally it became
Speaker 19:  part of the process to take a look at the remote controls and
Speaker 19:  make that entire experience end-to-end experience more pleasant for our
Speaker 19:  users.
Speaker 16:  Something immediately when I asked like why can't we just have like a simple
Speaker 16:  remote design? He alluded to the
Speaker 16:  obstacles and red tape and a lot of this kind of stuff.
Speaker 19:  When you try to do something totally divergent and let's say okay, let's
Speaker 19:  remove the buttons, let's introduce a track pad and then there will be a
Speaker 19:  lot of pushback because that demands new engineering,
Speaker 19:  new product in industrial design, new testing
Speaker 19:  and there is skepticism around whether this will work or not. So you have
Speaker 19:  to convince a lot of stakeholders to be able to adopt anything
Speaker 19:  that's diverging from the traditional way of doing things.
Speaker 16:  And this is kind of like an overall tech design problem, not
Speaker 16:  specific to TV remotes. That's a reason why a lot of TVs look
Speaker 16:  exactly the same and a lot of laptops and mice and and all that.
Speaker 16:  Well And
Speaker 2:  I think, I wonder if that also explains these kinds of, you know, every
Speaker 2:  imaginable button and idea thing like this just made me think of for
Speaker 2:  some reason I was talking to somebody years ago who was making an email app
Speaker 2:  and they were like pull up gmail.com And, I'd like to tell you
Speaker 2:  about the product manager for every single pixel on this website.
Speaker 2:  And it's like there's a reason that there's something in this corner and
Speaker 2:  there's a reason that there's something in this corner and on this sidebar
Speaker 2:  and up here and there's a person who is in charge of all of this and they're
Speaker 2:  sitting in meetings demanding that their thing be front and center. So ultimately
Speaker 2:  they make everything front and center, which makes everything a total nightmare.
Speaker 2:  And I'm sitting here looking at both this Comcast remote with a billion buttons
Speaker 2:  and my old VIO remote which has a million buttons on one side and then a
Speaker 2:  full keyboard on the back.
Speaker 16:  Oh I love that one.
Speaker 2:  I actually, to be honest, there's like something very good about this particular
Speaker 2:  remote but you can just see it too, right? There's a million
Speaker 2:  different products inside of this. Exactly. This one remote and they
Speaker 2:  all just shove it all together because it seems easier than like having
Speaker 2:  opinions about things.
Speaker 16:  Yeah, both designers talked about this like over time there's been so
Speaker 16:  many iterations of the TV
Speaker 16:  remote controlling the DVD player, the home theater system,
Speaker 16:  the vcr, your music devices, your computer,
Speaker 19:  All of these interfaces that you're trying to control kind of are hidden
Speaker 19:  behind something that you need to access and to access
Speaker 19:  those is the remote control and that makes it, you need to expose all
Speaker 19:  of those functions and features on the remote control so that you can have
Speaker 19:  a one click access to them. Right? So then you add up adding buttons and
Speaker 19:  functions
Speaker 16:  So you can tell when there's not a lot of research and development being
Speaker 16:  put into remote. So how would you test a good design
Speaker 16:  is what I asked them. Mm. Steve had a lot of ideas on how we
Speaker 16:  can get to that place.
Speaker 18:  You have, every designer has a way that they think about doing it, but it
Speaker 18:  turns out a lot of our ideas are not that great and so I'm more of a kind
Speaker 18:  of user experience designer where you design stuff and then you test it
Speaker 18:  and if, if your ego is strong enough to sit through like hundreds of people
Speaker 18:  going through your device, you end up in a much better place.
Speaker 16:  And that is what Sage's team ended up doing was
Speaker 16:  testing out this stuff in people's homes versus them coming to
Speaker 16:  a lab.
Speaker 19:  That's the best way to kind of understand what you are designing is getting
Speaker 19:  used in the real world. Like it could be somebody in their home
Speaker 19:  trying to use a TV while attending a kid and
Speaker 19:  something they are doing on the side. Like how do you juggle your
Speaker 19:  day-to-day life around the products that you are de because your product
Speaker 19:  is going and sitting inside their home, it's becoming part of their life.
Speaker 2:  Well my question on that is how do they test this? Because I think part of
Speaker 2:  the challenge here is that everybody is used to a giant slab full of
Speaker 2:  buttons and there's something awful but something sort of familiar about
Speaker 2:  that. So if you do have this like big divergent idea, how do you test
Speaker 2:  to see if it's working? Like what, what are they looking for? What is, what
Speaker 2:  does a better remote even look like?
Speaker 16:  So the best scenario that people want, which I think kind of
Speaker 16:  is a flaw in TV remotes, is everyone wants something to be like
Speaker 16:  one click away.
Speaker 19:  We have wanted to understand like what are some of those
Speaker 19:  priorities for the users. Like most of them don't want to be looking
Speaker 19:  down at the remote control while trying to experience the content
Speaker 19:  they're trying to enjoy. One of the big insights was like
Speaker 19:  make this a non interruptive process. Like remote control should not be
Speaker 19:  interruptive to the experience of enjoying the content
Speaker 19:  and at the same time it things should be one click away.
Speaker 2:  Can I tell you my crazy theory? I wonder if the problem is that we
Speaker 2:  conflate those two things that I can do it easily without looking
Speaker 2:  down And. I have to be able to do it in one click. Yep are the same thing
Speaker 2:  because they're not the same thing. Like for me it's all,
Speaker 2:  every time I have to look down at my remote we have failed but I'm happy
Speaker 2:  to like do two or three things as long as I kind of understand how to get
Speaker 2:  there quickly and don't have to look down. I am much
Speaker 2:  more in favor of like if I had to like do the kmi code every time
Speaker 2:  to do something but I like knew it and didn't have to look it up every single
Speaker 2:  time, that still feels like a victory to me. But maybe I'm not all people.
Speaker 16:  Yeah, I I mean I'm pretty satisfied with like the Netflix button and the
Speaker 16:  Hulu button. It's like multiple streaming service buttons and on one remote
Speaker 16:  fair that's I mean that works for me. But what Sage's team ended up
Speaker 16:  going with is kind of more, I don't wanna say minimalist but like
Speaker 16:  a smaller design with just like focusing on a track pad.
Speaker 19:  It is like a smaller in size. The track pad was like the major
Speaker 19:  portion of the design and the interface. So track pad can be just
Speaker 19:  a track pad but then track pad can be with clickable areas. So we had like
Speaker 19:  top right top bottom left and right edges of the track
Speaker 19:  pad as clickable so you could do multiple interactions And then we
Speaker 19:  also, because we had to do incorporate so much into one track pad, so we
Speaker 19:  said okay, how can we increase more functions within a track
Speaker 19:  pad? So you have a single click, you have a long press, you have a long
Speaker 19:  press and a slide. So we kind of use all those gestures to
Speaker 19:  increase the amount of things that you can do with just a square
Speaker 19:  surface.
Speaker 16:  I saw Liam really shaking his head. This is, this is my
Speaker 16:  biggest frustration
Speaker 17:  With modern remotes. you know I completely agree with what Steve said, right?
Speaker 17:  Most of our ideas are bad. I think Johnny Eve's worst
Speaker 17:  contribution to technology design in his entire career was putting
Speaker 17:  a touch surface on a remote control. It's a terrible
Speaker 17:  experience. I've never seen anybody do it right. If anyone should be able
Speaker 17:  to do it, it's Apple and their remote is a joke.
Speaker 2:  Yes. I could not agree more with this. The like true
Speaker 2:  torturous of trying to figure out how to even hold that Siri
Speaker 2:  remote in your hand was such a gigantic disaster
Speaker 2:  to me. It's like Liam listening to you talk about it just made me think of
Speaker 2:  the the keyboard that used to be in the Apple TV where you had to swipe from
Speaker 2:  letter to letter and it was so fine in order to make
Speaker 2:  it quick to swipe between things that actually landing on the letter you
Speaker 2:  wanted to click on was like borderline impossible. It was awful. I will say
Speaker 2:  the things that SJ is talking about about having these kind of
Speaker 2:  different interactions built into the same thing, the single press, the long
Speaker 2:  press whatever, I like that in theory I just have never seen
Speaker 2:  anyone do it. Well I don't think
Speaker 17:  Even the second version of this, this improved version of
Speaker 17:  this remote still has a touch surface on it that's prone to
Speaker 17:  like spurious inputs. Like you just accidentally do things
Speaker 17:  while you're watching a movie that takes you outta the moment.
Speaker 17:  And sorry, who thought putting this fucking Siri button on the side of the
Speaker 17:  remote was a good idea? It's just like every time you try to take a screenshot
Speaker 17:  on your iPhone, you accidentally turn it off or do some weird thing. It's
Speaker 17:  like, it's like
Speaker 16:  The screech on the phishing reel.
Speaker 17:  It's like they're trolling us. It's like let's just See how crazy we can
Speaker 17:  drive people.
Speaker 2:  I would get more use out of the real spinning thing than I
Speaker 2:  do with the Siri button because at least that's like a fidget spinner I can
Speaker 2:  play with while I'm watching tv.
Speaker 16:  What you can do is you can hold the trigger on the back of the
Speaker 16:  remote and then use the
Speaker 17:  Reel, oh my god.
Speaker 16:  And it will put the volume up on the
Speaker 17:  That
Speaker 2:  Incredible remote
Speaker 17:  That should be marketed as guaranteed divorce. Just
Speaker 17:  pop this out next to your spouse and give it a go.
Speaker 16:  So we we're talking a lot about what bad remote design is, but I wanna
Speaker 16:  talk about what everyone thinks is good TV remote design.
Speaker 16:  Okay, Liam, you go first.
Speaker 17:  So this isn't the remote I use every day unfortunately, but my
Speaker 17:  favorite remote of all time is the Xbox One media remote
Speaker 2:  Of
Speaker 17:  All time. Of all time. This
Speaker 2:  Is what you want to really,
Speaker 17:  This is the sword I'm gonna die on. I'm ready, willing and able hear me
Speaker 17:  out. The Xbox One was a terrible product but from
Speaker 17:  it came a great input device and if you've ever used a
Speaker 17:  Microsoft input device, like go back to the Intelli Explorer
Speaker 17:  Mouse from the nineties to their ergonomic keyboards. Microsoft knows
Speaker 17:  how to make a good input device. And I think this is
Speaker 17:  just like peak remote design. It's not made out of a slab
Speaker 17:  of aluminum or any sort of fancy material, it's just a
Speaker 17:  plastic remote with buttons on it. But what I like about it is the
Speaker 17:  way it feels in my hand because it has a rounded back.
Speaker 17:  However, even though it has a rounded back when you put it on your coffee
Speaker 17:  table, it's still stands up straight, which is just kind of like a cool
Speaker 17:  gimmicky bit. But I just, it makes me smile every time I see it.
Speaker 17:  It has back lid buttons which are necessary only because
Speaker 17:  all the buttons are black and it is a black remote, which I admit
Speaker 2:  Right, it needs back lid buttons because it's a bad remote that you can't
Speaker 2:  use without having to look down at it and blind yourself in the dark. This
Speaker 2:  is, this is great. This is what I was hoping for too.
Speaker 17:  Oh yeah, I hard disagree. It is definitely concession of the design to have
Speaker 17:  it all black, but every design has compromises, right? You want something
Speaker 17:  that doesn't look ugly on your coffee table that has like a giant Netflix
Speaker 17:  logo and an Amazon logo and whatever else on it, right? This
Speaker 17:  is a really nice looking design but is also really
Speaker 17:  ergonomic. It feels really nice to use even though the buttons are
Speaker 17:  covered with a layer of like soft touch plastic over the top
Speaker 17:  to make it water resistant. They feel really nice when you click them
Speaker 17:  up, down, left right are very easy even even though
Speaker 17:  they're set inside a circle, they're very easy to distinguish with your
Speaker 17:  thumb without looking at the remote. And then this is for me the most important
Speaker 17:  thing and this is what makes this remote stand out to me. So
Speaker 17:  most of our like media streamer remotes nowadays have about
Speaker 17:  like 12 or 13 buttons on them, right? This new Siri remote or
Speaker 17:  whatever it's called has I think 12 buttons if you count up, down, left,
Speaker 17:  right as separate buttons. This has those same 13 buttons that you
Speaker 17:  would normally have, but then it has for serious
Speaker 17:  video watchers, some dedicated video control buttons at the bottom.
Speaker 17:  So you can scrub forward back play pauses or let's say
Speaker 17:  you're inside of a video playlist. This one in particularly I love
Speaker 17:  you can skip to the next track. There isn't a button on most media
Speaker 17:  streamer, actually I can't think of another one that has that button. So
Speaker 17:  if I'm queuing up a playlist of my favorite must see TV
Speaker 17:  sitcoms from the nineties on shuffle and you know,
Speaker 17:  I've seen a couple too many episodes of Frazier, I can click this next
Speaker 17:  track button and get there. So I just love it. It feels nice. It's not
Speaker 17:  too heavy, it's not too small, it doesn't get lost in a couch
Speaker 17:  regardless of what David might say. And yeah, I just love
Speaker 17:  it. It's
Speaker 2:  A good remote. Best of all time is is a truly wild take.
Speaker 17:  All right, what do you got? What's better than this remote? I just
Speaker 2:  Mostly feel like the thing you're controlling with it is your Xbox One,
Speaker 2:  which immediately removes it from all contention forever and ever
Speaker 17:  And ever. Oh okay. That's a really good point. This remote is
Speaker 2:  Really good for operating a device that makes me want to
Speaker 2:  throw it out the window 450 times a
Speaker 17:  Day. Totally fair, totally fair. I should have started
Speaker 17:  this whole thing with the Xbox One Media remote is
Speaker 17:  using standard like media streamer IR encodes
Speaker 17:  and you can get this to work on. I've, I've had it work on an
Speaker 17:  Nvidia shield, I've had it work on an Apple tv, I've had it work on an Xbox
Speaker 17:  series X, which it's so supposed to not work with. That's
Speaker 2:  It's fair. I will say this is the kind of remote that I think like if Logitech
Speaker 2:  made it and sold it as like a use it for all of your other kinds of
Speaker 2:  devices remote, it would've done very well. My answer,
Speaker 2:  I have two and ultimately I'm just gonna pick one, but I want to quickly
Speaker 2:  honorable mention to the only remote that I have ever paid money for on
Speaker 2:  purpose, which is the, the Roku. I have four
Speaker 2:  Roku remotes on my desk right now. Like this is, this is the life I lead.
Speaker 2:  I believe this is the Roku Voice Remote Pro. Yeah, this is a
Speaker 2:  very good remote and it's very good for two reasons. One is because it's
Speaker 2:  a little bigger and sort of, you know, heftier than the other Roku
Speaker 2:  remotes, it's like feels better to hold, feels like a thing instead of the
Speaker 2:  plastic nonsense that Roku mostly ships. But it has two things that are
Speaker 2:  very good. One, it has integrated voice search, so you just press the microphone
Speaker 2:  button, hold it up to your face and voice search. And two, it has a headphone
Speaker 2:  jack and private listening on the Roku is like
Speaker 2:  the single greatest streaming box innovation of the last decade
Speaker 2:  as far as I'm concerned. I love it very much and Roku deserves huge credit.
Speaker 2:  So feature-wise, I think this is my favorite remote ever. But in terms of
Speaker 2:  like just the thing to hold in my hand and use, it's the Nvidia Shield remote.
Speaker 16:  Oh,
Speaker 17:  The Toone.
Speaker 2:  Wow. It's a toone, it's a weird shape. Which is weird
Speaker 2:  because it doesn't sit sort of pleasingly flat on my coffee table
Speaker 2:  but I, I can pick it out from all the other remotes that I have. So it's,
Speaker 2:  it's like unique. It feels really good to hold, which I think is important.
Speaker 2:  Are you guys, when you're sitting on the couch watching something, are you
Speaker 2:  holding the remote or is the remote on the couch next to you? Or is the remote
Speaker 2:  on the coffee table?
Speaker 17:  50 50?
Speaker 16:  Yeah, as an audio engineer I am constantly moving the volume up
Speaker 16:  and down on the tv
Speaker 16:  so I, I love the Roku remote also, so I'm constantly like
Speaker 16:  moving the buttons on the side of the Roku remote up and down
Speaker 2:  Side. Volume controls also a good innovation of focus. Agree. Yeah, well
Speaker 2:  done on that. But I, I will stop with the shield shortly here. But
Speaker 2:  it, it is another one that has nice buttons. Kinda like you're talking about
Speaker 2:  Liam where they're not super separated but you can kind of feel the difference
Speaker 2:  between all of them. And Nvidia did a thing that I really like where it has
Speaker 2:  a customizable button that you can like aggressively customize.
Speaker 2:  It can do almost anything. It can launch almost anything. It can get to menus
Speaker 2:  and you can have it do different things for one press, two presses, three
Speaker 2:  presses. So it becomes a thing that's like I can hand this remote to somebody
Speaker 2:  and they're gonna be able to figure out how to use it, but if I have it I'm
Speaker 2:  better at it. And, I actually feel like that's sort of the sweet spot where
Speaker 2:  like most of these kind of macro e remotes like s was talking
Speaker 2:  about are going to have a huge learning curve. But I like these ones where
Speaker 2:  it's like most people could just sit down and figure it out. But I have these
Speaker 2:  like power tools on top of it and for that reason I feel like Nvidia really
Speaker 2:  got this right.
Speaker 17:  Okay, so the Nvidia Shield Toone is a gray
Speaker 17:  remote. I have to agree. It's actually my half daily driver.
Speaker 17:  So I watch movies using the Nvidia Shield and everything else on my Apple
Speaker 17:  TV for the Nerds, it's just because I, I want pass through audio
Speaker 17:  and Plex can do pass through audio on the video shield. But I do
Speaker 17:  have a couple comments about this remote. One you just knocked my
Speaker 17:  baby for having black on black buttons. Same thing also
Speaker 17:  that remote's back lit.
Speaker 2:  You can turn the back light off, you
Speaker 17:  Can turn the back light off. But then it's really hard to see at night my
Speaker 17:  one other knock on that remote and maybe this, maybe I just got a bad one,
Speaker 17:  but I find the up down left right to
Speaker 17:  be like I just, it doesn't feel like it's gonna last
Speaker 17:  forever. Do you know what I mean? Like I've had it since the
Speaker 17:  Nvidia Shield Pro came out. So what does that couple years, it just feels
Speaker 17:  like it's not the way it was when I got it and it, it's starting to
Speaker 17:  get a little less satisfying to click.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. A lot of these like I have a couple of fire TV ones too that
Speaker 2:  have the same kind of all one piece wheel and they all feel
Speaker 2:  a little bit like they're one grain of dust away from
Speaker 2:  just totally breaking. But I've been using the shield one for a long time
Speaker 2:  and it's still fine. So I have high hopes Andru, I wanna know, I wanna know
Speaker 2:  what yours is. Is it, is it the fishing rod? Please tell me. It's the fishing
Speaker 2:  rod.
Speaker 16:  It is not the fishing rod. I have to agree like I love the
Speaker 16:  Roku remote and there's different reasons I think than what you said.
Speaker 16:  Really like the play state, the way we watch TV now is not like
Speaker 16:  dialing numbers and we don't go up and
Speaker 16:  down usually on channels. So what this prioritizes
Speaker 16:  is the play and pause. so like right where you're, when you're holding the
Speaker 16:  remote, right where your thumb is is the play and pause button and that
Speaker 16:  is the most important thing to do while you're watching tv, right?
Speaker 16:  Yep.
Speaker 2:  And it's a little like concave too. So your, your thumb just kind of nestles
Speaker 2:  on it. It's they did it, it's, it's very nice.
Speaker 16:  And then there is a home button and a back button
Speaker 16:  and those are right at the top of the remote and you know, if you need to
Speaker 16:  go back, just put your thumbs up to the back and it's
Speaker 16:  just like a really flexible remote that's a product of like us being
Speaker 16:  in the streaming world and they started to get it right during the
Speaker 16:  TiVo days. I have this TiVo remote here and if you see
Speaker 16:  this yellow button in the center of the remote is a pause button.
Speaker 16:  And it is like they clearly understood that this was the most important
Speaker 16:  part of the remote and it's like right where your thumb would be when you
Speaker 16:  hold it. Anything that prioritizes the play and pause,
Speaker 16:  that's where we should be going towards right now.
Speaker 2:  I I had never thought about this until you said this, but now I'm looking
Speaker 2:  at all these other remotes and almost none of them do. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  like on this horrible Comcast remote. I couldn't even tell you what it's
Speaker 2:  prioritizing but the play pause buttons are actually
Speaker 2:  up from where you naturally hold it. So you have to like shimmy it in your
Speaker 2:  hand just to get to the pause button. This Vizio remote, it really wants
Speaker 2:  you to launch the Vizio Smart apps cuz that's cool and the thing people wanna
Speaker 2:  do and most of them the volume is actually where your finger goes and
Speaker 2:  that sort of makes sense. But I think you're totally right that play pause
Speaker 2:  should be like naturally as you hold the thing, that's where your
Speaker 2:  thumb should sit.
Speaker 16:  Yeah. And while you're holding the remote you can hold pause and then
Speaker 16:  do the volume up and down with your other finger at the same time. True.
Speaker 16:  So you can really, it's really flexible. Yeah. And my LG
Speaker 16:  remote that it comes with my TV has a Netflix button
Speaker 16:  and Amazon Go button acknowledges that streaming is important.
Speaker 16:  The play and pause button are all the way tiny at the bottom
Speaker 16:  and it's so tiny you can't even tell like they're just next to each other.
Speaker 16:  There's no prioritize of what
Speaker 2:  Yeah's terrible is. Like
Speaker 16:  How often am I going fast forwarding, you know, it's the same size as the
Speaker 16:  play and the And the play and the pause button are separate buttons.
Speaker 2:  I was just about to say we can, we can agree that play and pause should be
Speaker 2:  the same button. Yeah. Right? Yeah absolutely.
Speaker 16:  Okay and then can I just give an honorable mention please. Which is
Speaker 16:  the Zenith space command remote,
Speaker 16:  which is a very old TV remote from the
Speaker 16:  sixties, seventies. All it is is just a tuning
Speaker 16:  fork and you press the buttons, there's four buttons. One is channel
Speaker 16:  lower volume mute on and off and channel higher.
Speaker 16:  Can
Speaker 2:  You press the buttons near your microphone? Cuz I suspect they make great
Speaker 2:  noises.
Speaker 16:  Yes,
Speaker 2:  That's what I'm talking about right there. Yeah, that's a button.
Speaker 16:  There's a really high frequency that is chiming with this
Speaker 16:  tuning fork in the remote. Then the TV picks it up and And
Speaker 16:  does that command And? I just love it because it is just stays
Speaker 16:  flat on the table. It is just a chocolate bar
Speaker 16:  basically and it has four big buttons.
Speaker 16:  And I. Just want a remote like this again that's just a thing with four
Speaker 16:  big buttons.
Speaker 2:  So that doesn't use infrared,
Speaker 16:  It uses sound correct? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Incredible.
Speaker 16:  It does not use any electronics. It is just you press
Speaker 16:  a button and it makes an actual sound with a tuning fork that changes the
Speaker 16:  tv.
Speaker 2:  This would absolutely not work in 2023.
Speaker 2:  But no I love it.
Speaker 16:  There should be an adapter that you could plug your TV into to use this
Speaker 16:  thing.
Speaker 2:  Andru this, this brings me to a big picture question that I've been wondering
Speaker 2:  about. And, I. Wonder if you talked to Steven and Sge about it too, which
Speaker 2:  is that it seems like the world should go in one of two directions. Either
Speaker 2:  all of these companies need to care about and design and build better
Speaker 2:  remotes that work for everybody. And, I wonder if that's even possible. Especially
Speaker 2:  because all this stuff is so mainstream now that like if Roku radically redesigned
Speaker 2:  their remote, I kind of feel like it would go badly. The Apple TV is a perfect
Speaker 2:  example, right? But then on the other side there have been various
Speaker 2:  attempts at like making of remote industry. Logitech sold the harmony.
Speaker 2:  There was like the Cavo was a thing for a minute there. Like people have
Speaker 2:  tried to do universal remotes and even when do you guys remember when everybody
Speaker 2:  was like, oh we're gonna make a universal remote that's also a smart home
Speaker 2:  controller. And that had a moment Google was like just
Speaker 2:  screw that user smartphone. Now they have a remote that's kind of like everybody
Speaker 2:  else's remote. Can we make an accessory industry out of this?
Speaker 2:  Can TV makers do this or are we just sort of stuck in
Speaker 2:  this crappy world of mediocre remotes forever?
Speaker 2:  What's your sense coming out of all this?
Speaker 17:  Well I talked to Sge a little bit about the future of this
Speaker 19:  Now with virtual reality and AR and all of that coming in. Maybe there's
Speaker 19:  something else. I don't know, we won't be even looking at each other.
Speaker 19:  So remotes are like maybe a small part
Speaker 19:  of the larger problem that the technology revolution
Speaker 19:  is going to kind of bring us. And now there are like TVs you can
Speaker 19:  control with your phones. So You don't even actually need a remote control.
Speaker 19:  Phones in some cases have also become a second
Speaker 19:  screen for televisions for example. There are
Speaker 19:  ways things you can do with second screen. You're watching something on
Speaker 19:  let's say Amazon Prime on your TV and
Speaker 19:  there is a product that you saw. Your phone could tell you
Speaker 19:  what that product is and you can buy it from Amazon.
Speaker 2:  I think the phone remote idea is horrible. And I hate every phone
Speaker 2:  remote cuz you have to look at it. It's like it's the opposite of what I'm
Speaker 2:  looking for in a remote, which is like a thing that I can hold in my hand
Speaker 2:  that doesn't light up like Liam's stupid remote and doesn't make me
Speaker 2:  look at it like Liam's stupid remote and doesn't get lost in the cushions.
Speaker 2:  Like Liam's stupid remote. I just want like a little brick
Speaker 2:  that I can feel. This is like, I just keep thinking about like Apple's Vision
Speaker 2:  Pro where it's like the sort of look and click your fingers and I'm like
Speaker 2:  that's the closest thing to a sort of virtual remote interface that I'm
Speaker 2:  interested in. I hate the smartphone as remote thing. It's fine in a pinch
Speaker 2:  when I lose Liam's stupid remote in the couch cushions. But it
Speaker 2:  is not what I'm looking for like day to day at all.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. I absolutely hate the reliance on
Speaker 17:  a smartphone to control things. And, I think it's becoming a problem in
Speaker 17:  like the home theater world. Like if you buy a soundbar, a lot of times
Speaker 17:  there's functionality locked behind the app.
Speaker 17:  So they give you one of these cheap pack and remotes. But if you want to
Speaker 17:  change how it's processing atmos or something like that, you gotta
Speaker 17:  download the app and link it up to this box. And is this company going to
Speaker 17:  continue to develop this app? Because we know you can't just make an app
Speaker 17:  and put it on the smartphone and expect it to just continue working forever,
Speaker 17:  right? You have to continue to develop it to make sure it continues to work.
Speaker 17:  So every time I see TV companies saying something like that
Speaker 17:  or home theater companies, it's like you've already proven to us that you
Speaker 17:  make terrible software. Just, just the worst imaginable.
Speaker 17:  I like yeah, only the audio industry can eclipse you in making terrible
Speaker 17:  software. And you want me to use your iOS app to
Speaker 17:  actually control your device? No, thank you. I don't get my iPhone out to
Speaker 17:  control my TV unless I have just absolutely given up.
Speaker 2:  Because you've lost your Xbox remote in the couch cushions again.
Speaker 17:  Yes. J just to be clear back check here David.
Speaker 17:  Your remote lights up is also hard to see in the dark and
Speaker 17:  is smaller than mine by thickness. So is easier to get lost on the couch.
Speaker 17:  So you know, just point that out.
Speaker 2:  That's outrageous. My to lone sticks out when it falls into the couch. And
Speaker 2:  I just yank it right out. It's like the sword and the stone style. I just
Speaker 2:  pull it outta the couch, get back to it.
Speaker 16:  You know something I liked And I know you guys are gonna have some feelings
Speaker 16:  about the Weu controller with the whole
Speaker 16:  screen on it. Oh, if I have a TV with a second
Speaker 16:  screen controller, Ooh, what do you think about that?
Speaker 2:  So basically what if my Nintendo switch was also my TV
Speaker 2:  remote?
Speaker 16:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I love this. I'm in, that's the most impractical thing I've ever heard. And,
Speaker 2:  I love it already.
Speaker 17:  I'm no, absolutely. I don't want software and screens to control my
Speaker 17:  viewing experience. Yeah.
Speaker 16:  One more thing before we go. I want to talk about voice
Speaker 16:  control. Mm. And whether you think we can rely totally on
Speaker 16:  that or is this an added feature or we should just not use
Speaker 16:  it at all? I don't like it.
Speaker 17:  I find it really handy for search when you're looking for something with
Speaker 17:  like an obnoxious title to type out. But I very rarely use
Speaker 17:  it.
Speaker 2:  That's interesting. I use it a lot, but only for search. I think the idea
Speaker 2:  that it's gonna be easier to lift my remote to my mouth and say open
Speaker 2:  Netflix than it will be to just press the Netflix button is just never
Speaker 2:  gonna be the case. But search on screens is
Speaker 2:  awful and you know, going left, left, left, right, right, right up, down,
Speaker 2:  up, down to get to the letter is just sucks. And that's also a place I use
Speaker 2:  my smartphone a lot. Like Roku has the thing where you can type with your
Speaker 2:  phone keyboard into the text box on the screen.
Speaker 2:  Love that. But I use voice pretty regularly if I know what I
Speaker 2:  wanna watch, that's almost always the fastest way for me to get there.
Speaker 2:  But I don't, if that was my only remote, it would drive me and everyone else
Speaker 2:  in my home. Crazy. Right. I mean. I just think about all the times that like
Speaker 2:  Siri activates because of something it hears on my television and
Speaker 2:  like good God, if it could control the TV in the process, I'd be, I'd be
Speaker 2:  screwed.
Speaker 16:  Yeah. The only time that has worked really well for me is in like
Speaker 16:  2018 when I asked my Google Home play
Speaker 16:  Stranger Things in my living room. And that has only, the
Speaker 16:  only time it's ever worked is specifically watching Stranger Things on Netflix,
Speaker 16:  but
Speaker 2:  It probably felt like magic.
Speaker 16:  Yeah, it felt like magic. It felt like the future. And ever
Speaker 16:  since then nothing has really worked as well with voice for me.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that sounds about right. So, okay, I know, I know we have to go here,
Speaker 2:  but did you ask them about the grandparent thing where you have to cover
Speaker 2:  80% of the buttons and and then hand it to them? It's like the
Speaker 2:  babysitter test was always the one that I I think of too, right? Because
Speaker 2:  these are like social objects, right? Lots of people use them. Do they look
Speaker 2:  at this and think, okay, the fact that you have to like sharpie an
Speaker 2:  arrow to the play button and the guide button because those are the only
Speaker 2:  ones that people should touch. Is that like a miserable design failure of
Speaker 2:  anyone who has ever tried to make remotes?
Speaker 16:  Yeah. Steve in particular called this out.
Speaker 18:  Most designers, especially remote controlled designers, we're in a funny
Speaker 18:  position. Like where we have I think a certain responsibility to try and
Speaker 18:  push the state of the art to be a little bit better, even if that's
Speaker 18:  means you're just putting a little bit more work into your onscreen menu
Speaker 18:  design or whatever it is. Or advocating in that critical meeting to
Speaker 18:  spend another 10 cents per unit or something like that. But because I think
Speaker 18:  a lot of people are, they're given the remote and they have no choice. And.
Speaker 18:  I feel like we have a little bit of responsibility to kind of tip the
Speaker 18:  balance to them. And if you see these little photographs of people
Speaker 18:  saving, like taking their grandparents remotes and covering over all the
Speaker 18:  buttons except for the volume and the PBS button or something like that.
Speaker 18:  But it's a little bit of failure in it. I feel like we could do a little
Speaker 18:  better there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, like I, I would like fewer buttons on remotes in general, but
Speaker 2:  I also think like clarity above all things, right? Even if you're gonna hand
Speaker 2:  me a remote full of buttons, most people are relatively smart. They should
Speaker 2:  be able to figure out what is going on. I was looking while you were talking
Speaker 2:  and speaking of the back button on the Roku remote, I'm back on my Silver
Speaker 2:  Xfinity remote and there are six things on here that you could
Speaker 2:  plausibly think are the back button. Like if I just wanna go back one.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. There are literally six things that I think I could plausibly argue
Speaker 2:  are the right one. I'm pretty sure I know what the right one is, but I genuinely
Speaker 2:  don't know for sure. And it's like, let's fix that problem and then then
Speaker 2:  we can worry about having a million buttons for a million streaming services.
Speaker 2:  Like just teach me where back is and And then we can go from there. Exactly.
Speaker 2:  Can you, can you play us out with the fishing rod? We should take a break,
Speaker 2:  but I just want to hear from the fishing rod one more time before we go.
Speaker 2:  And with that he launches Hulu. All right, thank you both.
Speaker 2:  You listening should email us all of your thoughts about your favorite remotes
Speaker 2:  ever, Vergecast of The Verge dot com. Send us your favorite remote ever,
Speaker 2:  ideally with a picture, and we'll talk about as many of them as we can on
Speaker 2:  the show. This is delightful. Andru Liam, thank you both. Again. Let's
Speaker 2:  do the hotline, wrap the show up
Speaker 2:  As a reminder, the hotline number is eight six six Verge one, one call and
Speaker 2:  ask us all your deepest, darkest, weirdest tech questions. We
Speaker 2:  love them all. Before we get into this week's question, let me just play
Speaker 2:  you a voicemail we got from Sean who called in to respond to last week's
Speaker 2:  question about how to keep your battery healthy for longer.
Speaker 22:  Hey, hey, this is Sean from Clearwater, Florida talking about phone
Speaker 22:  batteries. I drive for a living, so I have apps that track me
Speaker 22:  and take up a bunch of my battery life. So I
Speaker 22:  found out that it overheats really bad doing that. So what
Speaker 22:  I've done is clip my phone to an air conditioner vent
Speaker 22:  in my truck and that will keep that phone battery. Nice
Speaker 22:  and cool. Not using as much electricity. Okay. Hope it helps.
Speaker 22:  Bye.
Speaker 2:  I love this. These are our people. Thank you Vercast listeners for being
Speaker 2:  as weird about technology as we are. All right, this week's question
Speaker 2:  more on tv. It comes from Rahul.
Speaker 23:  Hi David and Verge team. My name is Rahul,
Speaker 23:  I'm in San Antonio, Texas. I'm calling to ask you guys
Speaker 23:  about TVs, particularly devices for TVs
Speaker 23:  cuz I'm tired of the crappy software on my lg OLED
Speaker 23:  tv. And I. Refuse to get an Apple tv. That seems to be the only decent
Speaker 23:  option out there. What does Google have nowadays? I had an Android
Speaker 23:  TV years ago. I had other products. I know the shield
Speaker 23:  exists, but it's, it's old now. So is there anything
Speaker 23:  newer, anything updated since the Shield TV for an Android
Speaker 23:  user to watch since streaming on their tv? I appreciate
Speaker 23:  you answer this. Thanks.
Speaker 2:  All right. First of all, I love this question because Rahul, you
Speaker 2:  feel the pain that I feel with set top boxes, which is that they're mostly
Speaker 2:  all very bad. The Apple TV has some stuff going for it. The shield, like
Speaker 2:  you said, has some stuff going for it, but I want there to just be one that
Speaker 2:  is like the one you should get and there just really isn't. But I think there
Speaker 2:  are really two answers to your question. One is the Nvidia
Speaker 2:  Shield, which just from a pure raw power perspective is still
Speaker 2:  probably the best Android thing on the market. It's a little
Speaker 2:  overkill for a lot of things and some people aren't gonna love the way that
Speaker 2:  you have to kind of maintain the interface and all that stuff, but it's
Speaker 2:  still very good. It's pretty expensive, but it's very good. But I would say
Speaker 2:  for my money at this moment, Google's latest
Speaker 2:  Chromecast, the one with Google TV is probably the one
Speaker 2:  to get, you can get the new Chromecast for as little as 30 bucks. It
Speaker 2:  comes with a remote now, which is great cause you don't have to just use
Speaker 2:  your phone, but it's still just a dongle that plugs into your tv. The $30
Speaker 2:  one is just 10 80 p and the $50 one
Speaker 2:  does 4K and HDR and all the rest of that stuff. I would
Speaker 2:  direct you to the $50 one for all those reasons, but
Speaker 2:  also because it comes in more colors. The $30 Chromecast just comes in. White
Speaker 2:  And, I don't care for the dongle, but that white remote is gonna
Speaker 2:  get gross really, really fast. Maybe your less gross
Speaker 2:  about like eating Cheetos and then using your TV remote than I am, but
Speaker 2:  that's just what happens. My remote would be truly disgusting if I had
Speaker 2:  that white one around. But the the new Chromecast is good. It has Google
Speaker 2:  tv, which does a really good job aggregating content and recommendations
Speaker 2:  and finding all that stuff. The remote works pretty well. It's not my favorite,
Speaker 2:  but it's like eight buttons in a D pad. It's pretty simple and straightforward.
Speaker 2:  You'll figure it out. The Chromecast has all of the apps you probably
Speaker 2:  want, including Apple tv, which was a late addition to the Google TV stuff.
Speaker 2:  But it's there now. It just does a good job of being content first in the
Speaker 2:  way that some others aren't. So that's where I would start you.
Speaker 2:  It's not terribly expensive. Works pretty well. It's a boring answer, but
Speaker 2:  just buy a Chromecast. I think that's the one. All right, that's it for The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast today. Thank you to everyone who came on the show today and especially
Speaker 2:  as always, thank you for listening. There's lots more on all of this at The
Speaker 2:  Verge dot com. If you wanna see all the remotes we talked about, you should
Speaker 2:  watch this episode on YouTube. We'll also put some links in the show notes,
Speaker 2:  but also, you know, read The Verge dot com. It's cool website. If you have
Speaker 2:  thoughts, feelings, questions, or TV remotes you desperately want to talk
Speaker 2:  about, please email us Vergecast at The Verge dot com. Tell us
Speaker 2:  everything or keep calling the hotline. 8 6 6 Verge 11. We're trying
Speaker 2:  to answer at least one question on the show every week, but I think we're
Speaker 2:  gonna do a whole hotline episode soon. Keep sending all your thoughts and
Speaker 2:  feelings. It's super fun to hear from you. We really love it. Thank you to
Speaker 2:  everyone who was called in so far. This show is produced by Andru Marino
Speaker 2:  and Liam. James Brooke Minters is our editorial director of Audio The.
Speaker 2:  Vergecast is Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network.
Speaker 2:  Neli Alex, And I will be back on Friday to talk about Reddit threads,
Speaker 2:  Barbie, Oppenheimer, everything else going on this week. We'll see you then.
Speaker 2:  Rock and roll.