# Transcript
ID: 2cda7b2e-ff74-458f-b2d8-5aed4608f9a5
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: iPhone 15: the good, the bad, and the titanium
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2958410269336735380/2986704340782789758/s93290-US-5995s-1694996835.mp3
Description: After attending Apple's fall hardware event, The Verge's Nilay Patel, Allison Johnson, Dan Seifert and Victoria Song break down the biggest announcements: the iPhone 15, 15 Pro, the new Apple Watch Series 9 and the Ultra 2.
Further Reading:
All the big conferences and events in tech, entertainment, and automotive coming this fall
iPhone 15 event live blog: all the news from Apple's keynote
Apple iPhone 15 event: the seven biggest announcements
Apple announces iPhone 15 with USB-C, a camera upgrade, and the Dynamic Island
Apple iPhone 15 Pro and Pro Max announced with titanium bodies and an Action Button
iPhone 15 Pro and Pro Max hands-on
A first look at the new iPhone 15 with USB-C and a big camera upgrade
Apple's cheapest iPhone 15 Pro Max now costs more — but also has double the storage
Apple is releasing iOS 17 and iPadOS 17 on September 18th
Apple announces Apple Watch Series 9, and it has a handy double-tap feature
Apple Watch Ultra 2: price, release date, and features
Apple is switching the AirPods Pro charging case to USB-C
Apple’s USB-C AirPods Pro will support lossless audio with the Vision Pro
Apple's Lightning connector was the first great port — and USB-C might be the last
Post-process: why the smartphone camera changed photography forever
The iPhone 7 Plus vs. the original iPhone: a camera showdown
The iPhone 15 Pro and Pro Max are the first smartphones with Thread
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  Support for this show comes from American Express Business If. you
Speaker 1:  are a small business owner. you wanna partner with someone that can help
Speaker 1:  make your day to day a rewarding experience. That's where American
Speaker 1:  Express can come in. American Express business cards are built for
Speaker 1:  your business with features and benefits like the ability to earn membership
Speaker 1:  rewards, points on select cards, the power to pay for big business
Speaker 1:  purchases, and 24 7 support from a business specialist
Speaker 1:  built for your business. Amex business terms apply.
Speaker 1:  learn more at American Express dot com slash business cards.
Speaker 3:  Support for this show comes from Global Citizen. on September
Speaker 3:  23rd, the Global Citizen Festival will gather thousands of people who
Speaker 3:  took action to end extreme poverty. Join the Red Hot Chili Peppers,
Speaker 3:  Ms. Lauren Hill, Jung, and Anita as they take the stage with
Speaker 3:  world leaders and activists to demand action for equity
Speaker 3:  for the planet, for food and for jobs. Download the Global Citizen
Speaker 3:  app today and earn your spot at the festival. learn more at Global
Speaker 3:  Citizen dot org slash box.
Speaker 4:  Hello and welcome to the British Cast, the flagship podcast of USB C.
Speaker 4:  It's finally here. The USB c puns are here in force. I heard
Speaker 4:  so many of them today, including from this group of people.
Speaker 4:  Hi, I'm your friend, Neli. I am back after several weeks of not being on
Speaker 4:  the show. I hope you'll have me. We were all at the Apple event today. Dan
Speaker 4:  Seaford ISS here.
Speaker 5:  Hello.
Speaker 4:  Victoria's song is here. Hi, Allison Johnson's here. Hello. We did it. We
Speaker 4:  went to an Apple event at the Steve Jobs Theater. We saw new
Speaker 4:  iPhones and new Apple watches and nothing else.
Speaker 5:  Well, we did watch a video.
Speaker 4:  We did. We watched a video with Octavia Spencer. We'll get into it before
Speaker 4:  we get into the Apple event. That's what we're gonna talk about on the entire
Speaker 4:  show today because we are all just there. We, we played with the new iPhones,
Speaker 4:  new Apple watches. I would say, this day Marks the beginning of just
Speaker 4:  a bonkers fall tech season. So September
Speaker 4:  is full. October is full. The end of September is the code conference for
Speaker 4:  me that that's just, it's the bomb in the middle of my
Speaker 4:  calendar. But there is this Apple event. There's the Amazon event. There's
Speaker 4:  a Microsoft event. There's a Google event. Oh,
Speaker 5:  You've forgotten meta.
Speaker 4:  There's a meta event. It's just, it's all happening. There's
Speaker 5:  Also a one plus event. Mm. There's a Qualcomm event. Everybody
Speaker 4:  Loves a Qualcomm event. Yeah. Who?
Speaker 5:  Who?
Speaker 4:  Who doesn't love it? Qualcomm's like five G's, right?
Speaker 5:  Love five G's on the beach, baby.
Speaker 4:  You love it. We've patent moat. You can anything you want, just pay us the
Speaker 4:  money. And they make everybody go to Hawaii. Yes, modems,
Speaker 4:  they love it. But just a like literally every week. So much so
Speaker 4:  that we made a calendar you can subscribe to on our website. It'll
Speaker 4:  just give you alerts and you can just like come look at events as this month
Speaker 4:  goes on. It's the O oldest school. We're like, how do
Speaker 4:  we make calendars? I cal. We did it. So just a
Speaker 4:  bonkers month, including today, the
Speaker 4:  antitrust trial of our lives like kicked off us
Speaker 4:  versus Google illegal monopoly
Speaker 4:  claims about the search engine and its dominance. The parallel is to us
Speaker 4:  versus Microsoft, which is 25 years ago.
Speaker 5:  Which to be clear, I was alive for.
Speaker 6:  I think we all were.
Speaker 4:  I mean, I hope so.
Speaker 5:  I just wanna say like it Is this the trial of our lives? It could be.
Speaker 5:  Or was Microsoft
Speaker 4:  Mic. So the end of the Microsoft trials, what created Google and like created
Speaker 4:  the opportunity for Google to exist. I just, whatever that all happened,
Speaker 4:  it's all in the past. Addie Robertson was in the courthouse today listening
Speaker 4:  to opening arguments. It immediately got very technical. What is a search
Speaker 4:  engine? A real question our government is currently grappling with. We will
Speaker 4:  have Addie on the show on Friday. Obviously I'm very interested in this.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna focus on Apple today. But just a bonkers month has
Speaker 4:  kicked off with this Apple event and with this Google trial. Google trial
Speaker 4:  by the way, is for 10 weeks. So we'll be talking about this for the next
Speaker 4:  two and a half months. But we're not gonna talk about it today. Today we're
Speaker 4:  gonna talk about Apple Degreed.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  No one wants to define what a search engine is today. Not
Speaker 6:  Is the in the slightest
Speaker 4:  Is. I have a lot to say about this, but we'll talk about it on Friday. Let's
Speaker 4:  talk about this Apple event. It, we were all recently here for Apple Vision
Speaker 4:  Pro. The vibes that one were excited. They were,
Speaker 4:  everyone was like kind of on edge, like they didn't know how it was would
Speaker 4:  go. There was a lot of expectations. They built a big structure in the middle
Speaker 4:  of campus and we had to go to it and there was like
Speaker 4:  new age music playing and then you ascended in a headset, whatever it, but
Speaker 4:  You know. It was that thing where it was like everyone wanted to know how
Speaker 4:  it would go. There was just a lot of curiosity in every direction. This event
Speaker 4:  was not that.
Speaker 5:  We kind of knew what was gonna happen.
Speaker 4:  We, we knew it was gonna happen. It was an iPhone. We know how to cover
Speaker 4:  new iPhones. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  We've done a few. Right.
Speaker 4:  There was just like an element of this where it was like, it was comfy. Like
Speaker 4:  everyone was just like back home. You know. So the vibes I think were just
Speaker 4:  like different because of that. And even to me, apple
Speaker 4:  like started off by saying like, this is our biggest event of the year. And
Speaker 4:  I was like, really?
Speaker 6:  I don't wanna say it was chill, but I feel like I was
Speaker 6:  chill in a way that I'm normally not for these events. I was just like, okay,
Speaker 6:  I can go into V Auto V mode. Yeah. Where it's just like,
Speaker 6:  I know what I'm doing. I'm not gonna freak out. I'm not on autopilot.
Speaker 6:  But like there's no like, oh my God.
Speaker 6:  Like last year when they called it the Ultra, I was like, oh my God, I have
Speaker 6:  to do so many find and replaces in this moment. My stress levels are through
Speaker 6:  the roof. This was like, nah, no, I'm chill and cool. I know what's going
Speaker 6:  on.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And they had us in the Steve Jobs theater, which is like an easy place
Speaker 4:  to kinda like do this work.
Speaker 5:  It's very comfortable. It's
Speaker 4:  It's comfy. That's right. Nice. The vibes of this event were comfy. It was
Speaker 4:  a video event again, which kind of made me sad. I was hoping that they would
Speaker 4:  come out on stage and actually do it. We all, all watch the video together.
Speaker 4:  Again, the point of this is actually us holding the phones in devices at
Speaker 4:  the end, not the presentation, but it's really weird to be
Speaker 4:  just watching TV with like a bunch of other people and Dan sitting next to
Speaker 4:  me taking pictures of the tv. Yeah, it's,
Speaker 5:  It's a very odd experience to spend an hour and a half taking photos of a
Speaker 5:  tv. It's a nice
Speaker 4:  Tv. It's a very nice tv. Yeah. So it opened with a video
Speaker 4:  of people celebrating their birthday and it was revealed that all the people
Speaker 4:  in the video had their lives saved by an Apple device. Fine.
Speaker 4:  This is great. I'm happy all these people are alive. I'm dying to know
Speaker 4:  if Apple staged all those birthday parties.
Speaker 6:  It had to have been, the angles were too crisp. Right?
Speaker 4:  Like you watched that video was, and you're like, here, like at some point
Speaker 4:  the richest company on earth descended on this person. Yeah. And I was like,
Speaker 4:  here's what we'd like to do. We'd like you to have a birthday party.
Speaker 5:  I have three kids, we have a lot of birthday parties. I've taken photos and
Speaker 5:  video at a lot of birthday parties and they never go that smoothly. No. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  As like You know that they came out with the cakes. With the candles.
Speaker 5:  Everyone had remembered to turn off the lights and didn't turn them back
Speaker 5:  on. I'll, I'll tell you also,
Speaker 4:  They were in, they were with them when they were waking up in the morning.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  And I'll tell you one little side weird story. I got a lot of
Speaker 5:  dumb smart home stuff in my house, including like motion sensors. And what
Speaker 5:  happens is every time we go to like sing happy birthday, we'll turn off
Speaker 5:  the lights and then two words into happy birthday, the lights come back on
Speaker 5:  and So, we fight with the
Speaker 4:  Lighting switch. That's pretty good.
Speaker 5:  None of this happened in Apple's birthday parties. Yeah, I'm just saying
Speaker 5:  that and
Speaker 4:  All, and all the homes are beautiful. I was just like watching this. And
Speaker 4:  again, I think it's great that the features are helping real people. Apple's
Speaker 4:  obviously very proud of this. I was just watching this ad and I was like,
Speaker 4:  they had to, they had to do this. Like there were like a lot of cameras
Speaker 4:  up in these people and they had to like feel the emotions. It was just a
Speaker 4:  weird way also to enter this event for me. They
Speaker 5:  Had to produce it in a time span. And I don't know if you all know this,
Speaker 5:  but not everyone has the same birthday at the same time. So I'm guessing
Speaker 5:  that a lot of these are just fake.
Speaker 4:  I have the most questions about the birthday party video of almost any product
Speaker 4:  here. Like I, there's, we'll get to it. I have one big question about the
Speaker 4:  iPhone 15 Pro. It's huge. But the birthday party video,
Speaker 4:  the more you consider it, the more you're like the production of this had
Speaker 4:  to have been so weird. I
Speaker 6:  Like, if you think about, you always do it once for safety too, when you
Speaker 6:  do any video. Yeah. Like that's like the kind of behind the scenes thing.
Speaker 6:  So you had to have someone light this cake multiple times and bring it out
Speaker 6:  and be like, yeah, do it
Speaker 4:  Again. Did you notice the one? She's like, can I blow out these candles out?
Speaker 4:  And I was like, she said that for real. That was real. Oh, she was what?
Speaker 4:  Anyway, so that was like the opening of it. And then Tim Cook You know, it
Speaker 4:  was like, I wanna give you an update on the Vision Pro, which they just announced.
Speaker 4:  And he said, we're on track. The developers love it. I don't know what else
Speaker 4:  you would've said. Developers are deeply confused about our new product,
Speaker 4:  we're excited about the things we're seeing. It's on track to ship early
Speaker 4:  next year.
Speaker 5:  That's it.
Speaker 4:  That's, and that's all we got from Vision Pro. There are some stuff with
Speaker 4:  the iPhone where the, the pros can shoot spatial video for Vision Pro.
Speaker 4:  Some stuff with AirPods, which we'll get to that. That was all the updates
Speaker 4:  on the, on the Mac and Vision Pro. The Mac update was like, they're great.
Speaker 5:  People love the Mac.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You know, like we continue to manufacture Macintosh's. And then
Speaker 4:  the other, just other video that we should talk about before we talk about
Speaker 4:  the products. They did a big skit in the middle of the Apple Watch
Speaker 4:  segment with Octavia Spencer, who was a great actress in the skit. Was
Speaker 4:  funny. Although it was cringey but funny. Yeah, it was, well it was well
Speaker 4:  done if you like that sort of thing. That's about
Speaker 4:  Apple's environmental efforts. They've announced a lot of
Speaker 4:  stuff. Elisa Jackson, by the way, used to run the E p A. She's their VP of
Speaker 4:  environment there. The series nine has recycled cobalt in the battery.
Speaker 4:  The sport loop is 82% recycled yarn. The manufacturing is carbon
Speaker 4:  neutral, on and on and on. There's a whole list. And then
Speaker 4:  they announced that the Apple watches its first carbon neutral
Speaker 4:  product with a logo on the side if you buy it with certain bands.
Speaker 6:  Yes. It has to be specific bands. It's like the
Speaker 4:  Ocean band will instantly harm the ocean. Yes.
Speaker 6:  That floral elastomer. It's not, it's not
Speaker 6:  biodegradable. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  The video is, it was fine. It's like, this is, if you're gonna announce a
Speaker 4:  litany of environmental accomplishments, that's like the
Speaker 4:  best way to do it. Like it was worth paying attention to. Yeah. But it was
Speaker 4:  also just like,
Speaker 4:  there's no reference frame for anything They were saying. They're like, other
Speaker 4:  companies plant trees. We plant forests and it's like, does Google Plant,
Speaker 4:  I don't know.
Speaker 7:  But they, I was like, okay, this is a clever way to stay all this and
Speaker 7:  like keep us engaged. But then they went and like repeated everything
Speaker 7:  that was said in the video in like a less funny, serious way. After
Speaker 7:  that, I was like, oh, I, I don't need to hear this again. It's,
Speaker 6:  It's also weird because it felt like the whole premise of the video was
Speaker 6:  skepticism and them answering that skepticism. So obviously if You know
Speaker 6:  anything about the environment, you're gonna be like, okay, how much of this
Speaker 6:  is greenwashing? Half of us have watched John Oliver talk about like
Speaker 6:  credits then why those aren't like real things, but they're like, no,
Speaker 6:  we have the answers here. Mother Nature is like kind of happy with
Speaker 6:  our answers. We're gonna have this really funny stare down that
Speaker 6:  is, I don't know, it was funny. It was funny. I just don't know. Like
Speaker 6:  You know. You're supposed to have Tim Cook in this video and I was like,
Speaker 6:  You know what Tim Cook can act, he can act like he's afraid of Octavia Spencer
Speaker 6:  and like as if he's on the spot. But at the same time, You
Speaker 6:  know back in your head that Apple is just doing that to kind of head off
Speaker 6:  the criticisms about greenwashing.
Speaker 4:  Right. This is like the frame of the video. That's what I mean. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  By the way, Tim Cook spent years pretending to be afraid of Donald Trump.
Speaker 4:  So like, I mean like this is his greatest accomplishment is like
Speaker 4:  China Trump politics. Like he navigated Apple through, he is
Speaker 4:  a good actor, but it was just, it was, it's worth talking about. Like that
Speaker 4:  was a long video in the middle of this event, like really long.
Speaker 4:  And I think it speaks to sort of, again, just the general vibe of the whole
Speaker 4:  show was like, we have a lot of time to bring out Octavia Spencer
Speaker 4:  and do a skit about the environment. Like a long time. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I just want, I wanted to start with that stuff because I think if you understand
Speaker 4:  that stuff, I think it puts the products in the context because the
Speaker 4:  products themselves are inherently iterative in like
Speaker 4:  meaningful ways. I think they're good. Like they seem cool and,
Speaker 4:  and again, big question about the 15 Pro, which we'll get to. Like there's
Speaker 4:  a mystery in the iPhone 15 Pro, which I'm obsessed with, but the vibe of
Speaker 4:  the event was like, we have enough time to do comedy.
Speaker 4:  All right, let's talk about the phones. iPhone 15
Speaker 4:  or the iPhone 14 Pro remix. Yes.
Speaker 5:  The iPhone 14 Pro two.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. But not quite two. It's like, yeah, negative
Speaker 4:  0.5. Yeah, it's missing a camera and some stuff.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Missing some promotion. But basically it is just like
Speaker 5:  last year's iPhone 14 was a remix
Speaker 5:  of the 13 Pro. The 15 is a remix, or a
Speaker 5:  repackaging is probably a better way to say it, of the 14 pro from last year.
Speaker 5:  So you get a 48 megapixel camera, you get the dynamic
Speaker 5:  island. What else?
Speaker 7:  Slightly brighter throw the,
Speaker 5:  The ac the A 16 processor. Yeah, they did update the screen. It's a little
Speaker 5:  bit brighter. And of course they added a USB C port, which was not on last
Speaker 5:  year's phone. So that's like the new thing. And they rounded the sides. It's
Speaker 5:  a little more comfortable to hold and the the glass is matte now. What do
Speaker 5:  you think, Allison?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it feels like last year was very much like a skip
Speaker 7:  the upgrade year. And this is the one that like my husband
Speaker 7:  bless him, is still holding onto the iPhone 10 R. I'm like, wow,
Speaker 7:  wow. This would be the one, like there are enough things here that are different.
Speaker 7:  You're gonna get the dynamic island, which like every, I don't know,
Speaker 7:  app developer's gonna consider going forward. So yeah,
Speaker 7:  it's, it's not exciting. It's like we've seen all this before, but it's
Speaker 7:  just the Right, it seems like a smart kind of like
Speaker 7:  packaging of everything. I
Speaker 5:  I, I'm, I just don't know if Apple's ever going to make this phone, whether
Speaker 5:  it's the iPhone fifteen, sixteen, seventeen or whatever. Exciting. Right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like it's, it's, it's, it's never going to be the one where they really
Speaker 5:  introduce new stuff to. It's never gonna be the one where they're pushing
Speaker 5:  the envelope on anything. But it is the mainstream one that most
Speaker 5:  people will buy or a lot of people will buy at least. And if you've had a
Speaker 5:  phone like the tennis or the 10 R or whatever, then
Speaker 5:  11 and you're upgrading now four or five years later, it will be
Speaker 5:  a meaningful upgrade for you. But it's hard to get excited about it because
Speaker 5:  we saw so much of this last year. Are
Speaker 6:  You telling me that you are not jazzed about color injected glass?
Speaker 5:  I will
Speaker 4:  Say the atomic level, Daniel, the glass
Speaker 5:  Felt nice. Like the, the, the, my main takeaway from touching these phones
Speaker 5:  today is they felt nice. They did,
Speaker 4:  They felt really, really nice. Like, like the,
Speaker 5:  The, the, even the, the pro models and the regular models less so, but
Speaker 5:  they, they like, for the past few years they've been so heavy and the edges
Speaker 5:  are sharp and like the stainless steel is nice, but like it's kind of
Speaker 5:  sticky and shows your fingerprints and stuff. These you pick up and they
Speaker 5:  just feel soft. Yeah. And they feel nice in your hand. We did,
Speaker 4:  We ran into people there who said that made them feel cheap, which is fascinating.
Speaker 5:  Yes, yes. They didn't have the perceived value because it wasn't as heavy.
Speaker 5:  And I was like, ah, yeah, I'll take the lighter phone. But You know, they,
Speaker 5:  they rounded the corner, the edges of the frame. It's still aluminum with
Speaker 5:  the iPhone 15, but it, it is nicer to hold. And the, the glass is
Speaker 5:  a soft mac glass in my experience that makes things slippery.
Speaker 5:  So. We'll see how that goes.
Speaker 6:  I mean, if you use a case, you're
Speaker 5:  Fine. You know, most people will use a case. So
Speaker 4:  You know, obviously the big news here is they, again, it's the iPhone 14
Speaker 4:  Pro minus. That's, that's how I think about this phone. So you're,
Speaker 4:  you're losing a camera, you're losing the Zoom camera. Yeah, the Ultra wide,
Speaker 4:  the telephone. Yep. But you, you get the main camera from the 14 pro, which
Speaker 4:  is a 48 megapixel. They're pixel bending. It kind of an interesting way.
Speaker 4:  Right. They're doing 24 megapixels by default. You can switch it to 12 in
Speaker 4:  the settings, which is interesting. Then you can crop it in different ways
Speaker 4:  to get two x. And then they've changed portrait mode,
Speaker 4:  which seems like a big deal. But I also, so much of the
Speaker 4:  hands-on area is just panic, but like
Speaker 4:  beautifully lit panic. And you're like, well that looks fine. And you're
Speaker 4:  like, like the light of heaven is, is up upon me. Everything
Speaker 4:  looks good in this. But they are capturing the depth map when you take
Speaker 4:  a photo now and you can go in a portrait mode later, which is cool.
Speaker 7:  And you can change the focus point later, which is like, isn't it
Speaker 7:  the dream of like digital photography
Speaker 5:  Tro baby. Yeah, I
Speaker 4:  Know. Yeah. It's been 10 years since we've been covering this idea. If you
Speaker 4:  don't know what Lightro is, Lightro is a a, you can go look at it on The
Speaker 4:  Verge from a million years ago, they shipped a, a whole camera
Speaker 4:  with like 50 lenses on the front.
Speaker 5:  Well, no, the the, the lightro that let you change the focus point was
Speaker 5:  that weird rectangular thing with one lens. Oh yeah. And
Speaker 5:  it allowed you after the fact to choose different focus points, which is
Speaker 5:  this, what is the iPhone's allowing you to do? Now what you're thinking of
Speaker 5:  is the light phone or the light camera that had
Speaker 5:  the, the spider's, I a of, of of lenses
Speaker 5:  switch cheese on the front quickly checking this and checking it. But yeah,
Speaker 5:  that, yeah. Which also I believe tried to accomplish a similar thing. But
Speaker 5:  Lightro was first. Yeah. The problem with the lightro was a, it took terrible
Speaker 5:  photos. B it was expensive and C like you couldn't do
Speaker 5:  anything with those photos. Yeah. Oh yeah. So it was a weird
Speaker 7:  Format. Right?
Speaker 4:  It
Speaker 5:  Was a weird format. Yeah. The only thing, I mean, I think the whole reason
Speaker 5:  it existed was to like try and get that technology into other things and
Speaker 5:  sell it to bigger companies, but it kind of fell. So David
Speaker 4:  Pierce wrote our Lights Review in 2012 and it is so broken now.
Speaker 4:  It is not even worth a year.
Speaker 5:  Pullover. Look it up.
Speaker 4:  But yeah, 11 years ago we, we covered a camera that could refocus The new
Speaker 4:  portrait mode can just do it. I will say Dan and I were playing with it at
Speaker 4:  the event. It got a little confused sometimes. But again,
Speaker 4:  it's the event. There's like 900 faces at, it's like, it's not a fair
Speaker 4:  testament. I
Speaker 5:  Think. I think this the feature of the, the main thing that I think
Speaker 5:  people would get from this is the ability to make a non
Speaker 5:  portrait photo portrait Yes. After the fact. And so like
Speaker 5:  so many times, like You know, I think of my wife taking photos of our kids.
Speaker 5:  She uses the normal camera mode and, and I, I always like switch it to portrait
Speaker 5:  or whatever, but she never does that switchover. But now if she doesn't do
Speaker 5:  the switchover, it doesn't matter. It captured the data and I can like turn
Speaker 5:  on the portrait mode after the fact. Yes.
Speaker 4:  It's unclear whether you get live photos at, at the same time
Speaker 4:  as the portrait capture. Oh yeah.
Speaker 5:  We'll have to follow up with that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So there again, lots of questions there, but basically you've got
Speaker 4:  what should be the 14 pro camera. I'd be shocked if
Speaker 4:  it was meaningfully different. I don't
Speaker 5:  Know that it's the exact same camera sensor. It's the same resolution
Speaker 5:  that we know. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And you get the two times lossless crop.
Speaker 5:  Right. 'cause you can, it can go into the center of the sensor. And then
Speaker 5:  the, the Benning, as you were saying earlier, is kind of doing a unique thing
Speaker 5:  where it's going to 24 megapixels as opposed to normally.
Speaker 5:  And what the iPhone has done in the past with the Pro Max or the 14 Pro
Speaker 5:  is it just takes four of the 48 megapixels and turns 'em into one,
Speaker 5:  which produces a 12 megapixel image. Yeah. So this 24 is kind of
Speaker 5:  a strange way to do it. Like I'm not sure how they're calculating the data
Speaker 5:  there, but it does give you a meaningfully more resolution without like
Speaker 5:  blowing up your storage.
Speaker 4:  But
Speaker 7:  Does anyone need 24 megapixels? Like on the regular, like
Speaker 5:  People zoom a crop all the time, I think. Yeah, but I think so. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  T 12 of is a good
Speaker 5:  Amount. This is why I, my my opinion on, on phone cameras is that telephoto
Speaker 5:  is always more useful than Ultra wide because I watch people go like this
Speaker 5:  with their phones and then pinched zoom
Speaker 4:  To
Speaker 5:  Death and they take four pixels and snap that photo. Painful.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And like I see 'em do that all the time. And then the Ultra wide is like,
Speaker 5:  oh cool, we got this really cool architectural shot. It's like, I mean it's
Speaker 5:  good for like getting a group of people.
Speaker 4:  Oh man, I love the Ultra wide. I don't what what you're talking about. You
Speaker 4:  are, you
Speaker 6:  Are not watching the,
Speaker 4:  It's so Moy, how are you take a band photo
Speaker 6:  Where you, you flip the, the TikTok photographers are always like flip your
Speaker 6:  camera upside down. Yeah, yeah. Get really down and then put it into Ultra
Speaker 6:  wide. And then you have like this, I don't know, this insane
Speaker 4:  Shot. Basically what you're saying is no matter what people will find a way
Speaker 4:  to make a great camera look like shit. Yes. No matter what.
Speaker 4:  Interestingly, we, there's some modes in this camera that are new. So you
Speaker 4:  can shoot 48 megapixel pro raw. You can shoot
Speaker 4:  24, you can shoot 12 and then you can shoot 48
Speaker 4:  megapixel compressed in Apple's format. Which
Speaker 4:  they revealed that as a company. They
Speaker 4:  pronounced Heif Heif. So H E I F, which I
Speaker 4:  get why you would head towards Heif. But they said it on
Speaker 4:  stage and then they were all saying it. It's been like the iPhones have
Speaker 4:  shot in he e f for a long time. Yeah. This is the first time I've heard anybody
Speaker 4:  call it Heif. It was deeply confusing. And
Speaker 4:  they're like, this is what we've been calling like I, I
Speaker 5:  I think we need to have Vergecast listeners call in or
Speaker 5:  hit up Neli online and say, how do you pronounce Heif? And do
Speaker 5:  you say Heaf?
Speaker 4:  No one says Heif. People say, I'm sw I'm pushing the button that says
Speaker 4:  maximize compatibility and shooting in jpeg. That's what everybody says.
Speaker 4:  They
Speaker 7:  Say What is this and why doesn't it work? Why
Speaker 4:  Doesn't does it work anywhere? Yeah. But it's, I think it's fascinating that
Speaker 4:  you're letting, they're letting consumers and the iPhone 15 shoot
Speaker 4:  48 megapixel compressed photos, which
Speaker 4:  I have no idea how these are gonna look. Yeah. Just none at all.
Speaker 4:  Again, in the, in the demo area with beautiful light, like
Speaker 4:  some of the most beautiful light I've ever seen in any room is in that demo
Speaker 4:  area. Looks great.
Speaker 4:  Very curious how it'll look anywhere else. And then it's also fascinating,
Speaker 4:  they're letting consumers shoot 48 Megale Pro raw, which
Speaker 4:  they shouldn't do from, from everything. I know
Speaker 4:  very few people should do this. Allison. Anything else catch your eye about
Speaker 4:  this camera? Yeah,
Speaker 7:  I don't know. I think like, I think the two times crop zoom
Speaker 7:  makes a lot of sense here. 'cause you don't have the telephoto and you're
Speaker 7:  kind of like getting something for like two lenses
Speaker 7:  for the price of one. And then when on a phone where you already have a three
Speaker 7:  times lens, it's sort of like, well what was the point of this? So yeah,
Speaker 7:  having, having the big one move up to five times
Speaker 7:  You know makes sense. And then having this, this two times option is nice.
Speaker 7:  It's nice for portraits. Yeah. I like it in portrait mode. So that's what
Speaker 7:  I'm jazzed about.
Speaker 4:  And then, then there's the thing, they switched the port to USB C
Speaker 5:  But at USB 2.0 speeds very
Speaker 4:  Confusing. They
Speaker 6:  Took forever. They took forever to get to that. Oh yeah. I feel like everybody
Speaker 6:  was waiting for it. And it's like, okay, okay. This
Speaker 5:  Big reveal,
Speaker 4:  They did it in two parts. They said, let's talk about connectivity. And they
Speaker 4:  said, let's start with wireless and you can, the whole room was like, no
Speaker 4:  one cares.
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 4:  We, you talk about five G again, you're gonna do this test again. But yeah.
Speaker 4:  So it's USB C the You know the word from Apple
Speaker 4:  basically is like the Europeans made us do it,
Speaker 4:  but it's time and we think people aren't gonna freak out. And to, to be clear,
Speaker 4:  there was applause in this room.
Speaker 5:  I mean also from
Speaker 4:  Apple's employees, that's also
Speaker 5:  Yes. Yes. This room full of Apple's employees clapped for apple's announcement.
Speaker 4:  Well there were some influencers there.
Speaker 4:  This inside baseball as journalists, we are not supposed to clap. So there's
Speaker 4:  It's like a big thing. Yeah. 'cause people assume the room is full of media
Speaker 4:  and they hear the clapping and it's like the media's clapping and it's like,
Speaker 4:  no, we're sitting on our hands. We're
Speaker 5:  Trying to type. Yeah, we're
Speaker 4:  Like typing as we can. It's like Apple employees. They're partners and
Speaker 4:  some people who don't have to play those same rules, but they clapped, they
Speaker 4:  clap for iCloud storage increasing the six and 12 terabytes. That
Speaker 6:  And who needs that much? Who needs 12 terabytes
Speaker 4:  Candy crush whales.
Speaker 4:  I don't, I I'm just guessing. I don't know. Because
Speaker 6:  Like I have, I have the plan where it's two terabytes and You know. I
Speaker 6:  I I feel for all my friends, I share it with six of my friends. Wow.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Wow. You're generous.
Speaker 6:  I I am. And I use most of it. Yeah. And we still have like 1.5
Speaker 6:  terabytes
Speaker 5:  Left. So, well, if you go buy an iPhone 15 and take 48 megapixel pro
Speaker 5:  raw images, you'll you'll soak up that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. What I know every professional is dying to do is have their phone instantly
Speaker 4:  and immediately choke their bandwidth out by offloading their 48
Speaker 4:  megapixel stills to iCloud. But so USB C we did it, we just
Speaker 4:  did the same thing. I said we're gonna talk about USB C Yeah. We talked about
Speaker 4:  wireless concept and iCloud great. They
Speaker 4:  added it to the phone. The, the, the vibe very much was like, well, we had
Speaker 4:  to do it, but we think it's gonna be fine. And no further discussion
Speaker 4:  was had
Speaker 5:  No, yeah,
Speaker 7:  They moved on pretty quickly.
Speaker 4:  There is a was is it $29?
Speaker 5:  It's $29 dongle. Oh my God. If you wanna convert your Lightning cable
Speaker 5:  to USB C Absolutely not. Why you would wanna do this When you can buy an
Speaker 5:  Apple branded USB c cable for $19 is beyond
Speaker 5:  me. But s Neli and I were trying to figure out why you would buy this earlier
Speaker 5:  today. Ah, maybe you have a Lightning accessory.
Speaker 4:  What Lightning access like a
Speaker 5:  Battery? I don't know man.
Speaker 4:  Because it's a cable. So like docks are out.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, docks are out because
Speaker 4:  You just, your phone will be flopping. It's not even a long, it's, it's just
Speaker 4:  a little wi of a cable. It's
Speaker 5:  Just, it's just like their USB A to USB C dongle except it goes from Lightning
Speaker 5:  to USB. So, so it's
Speaker 4:  Floppy. So your phone's gonna flop right outta your dock. Yeah. So that's
Speaker 4:  not it.
Speaker 4:  I, my answer was built-in Lightning cables and cars,
Speaker 5:  Which I don't think are a thing,
Speaker 4:  Which Dan doesn't believe that they exist, but some
Speaker 4:  things have built-in Lightning cables. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Some really weird obscure accessories that like four people bought.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And now those people have to pay $20. The outrage
Speaker 4:  in general, I think it's like a great move. Like I don't Yeah, I think Apple
Speaker 4:  held out. I think the Europeans made 'em do it. I
Speaker 5:  I will say, I was thinking about this 'cause last week, the show, I
Speaker 5:  said I really don't plug in my phone for anything. This is not gonna impact
Speaker 5:  me much at all. I use why I was charging, but the one time I do plug my phone
Speaker 5:  in is when I'm in the car and I use CarPlay and I'm going to upgrade my phone
Speaker 5:  and have a USB C port. And my wife is not going to upgrade her phone and
Speaker 5:  she's gonna have a Lightning port. And now I'm gonna have to deal with the
Speaker 5:  fact
Speaker 4:  Nobody one. You're gonna buy the dongle. Buy Don. Don
Speaker 4:  buy the Don.
Speaker 7:  We have, we have dueling cables in our car. And anytime, because I'm usually
Speaker 7:  on an Android phone and when I switch back to iPhone, my husband's like,
Speaker 7:  thank God.
Speaker 4:  Oh my God.
Speaker 7:  Put this away. We can use one cable like
Speaker 5:  God intended. Yeah. My, my wife will get in the car and it's set up for Android
Speaker 5:  Auto and she'll be like, and I have to like go through the settings menu
Speaker 5:  to turn on CarPlay.
Speaker 4:  It's very obvious. Who, who's gonna have to buy the dongle and it's you.
Speaker 4:  That's how that goes. Look, I think it's great. They, they didn't lock it
Speaker 4:  down. They didn't do any weird made for iPhone stuff. They, they're not nerfing
Speaker 4:  the cables at slower speed. Well they nerfed the entire phone to run a USB
Speaker 4:  two. But charging speed should be fine over USB C
Speaker 4:  15 watts. We think no matter what the cable, assuming you have a good cable
Speaker 4:  that doesn't light itself on fire. Yeah. A real part of the USB C experience
Speaker 4:  transfer speeds on the pros USB C It's a standard they can do. Like they
Speaker 4:  did it right? They did the thing they should've
Speaker 5:  Done. They could have put actual us like faster USB in it and
Speaker 5:  they could have like done more video out or whatever. But
Speaker 4:  For what? For 15?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Why not? It's an $800 phone. They couldn't put USB
Speaker 5:  three in there. How long has you spent three three been around? You could,
Speaker 4:  You could say it a different way. It's an $800 phone. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  they, that's how Apple would prefer you to say it. This is the
Speaker 4:  garbage phone for 800 people. $800. Yeah. U USB two. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  But you're right. It does, it does mean that you can now travel with one
Speaker 5:  charging cable, which I know on a lot of people are excited
Speaker 4:  About. I was on my way here and I was packing my bag full of cables. The
Speaker 4:  one that routinely gets me stopped at the airport as a brown man. You ever
Speaker 4:  fly on September 11th as a brown man, the bag full of wires and
Speaker 4:  batteries? Oh, it was great. I loved every minute of it, but I was packing
Speaker 4:  my wires You know U S P C for everything. And then my one
Speaker 4:  sad little Lightning cable and I was like, oh buddy. Which
Speaker 5:  Now you'll just need for your AirPods Max. I was like, this is
Speaker 4:  Your last trip little guy. You're coming with me and
Speaker 4:  then you're never gonna be seen again. It's interesting. They didn't upgrade
Speaker 4:  the AirPods Max. They did not.
Speaker 5:  They don't
Speaker 4:  Even talk about those things
Speaker 5:  Anymore. No, no. The rumors were as of last week, according to
Speaker 5:  Mark Erman, that we will see upgrades for them next year with
Speaker 5:  the USB C port on it. But yeah, no, no word to the USB.
Speaker 5:  The AirPods Max. There's like the other, we talked about this last week as
Speaker 5:  well, but like the other Lightning products in Apple's lineups will remain
Speaker 5:  though. They, today they did quietly take off
Speaker 5:  the, their store the MagSafe Duo charger, which had a Lightning port on it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And the MagSafe battery, which also had a Lightning port, which were
Speaker 5:  taken off the store not to be spoken of. They did not talk about
Speaker 5:  upgrading those to USB C or anything because they
Speaker 4:  Suck.
Speaker 5:  But you can still buy AirPods mags for 549.
Speaker 4:  You can still buy an 10 a nine gen iPad for 3 29. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Which is the iPad most people should buy.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I bought it. Yeah. We, we just were like children.
Speaker 4:  You have this iPad, you cannot hurt it in any meaningful way.
Speaker 4:  It's encased in rubber. I I look, I think on the 15 the port is
Speaker 4:  there for charging. Yeah. That it's not, it is not. No one who
Speaker 4:  buys an iPhone 15 is worried about their data transfer speeds.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  No. It just doesn't seem like a thing that's
Speaker 5:  Happening. Oh, they did? Oh, they also came out with USB C EarPods
Speaker 4:  Wire ear pods. Oh, the wire ear pods.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Which, which I think people would more likely use on a 15 than a 15
Speaker 5:  Pro.
Speaker 4:  Here's a question. Are they gonna work on your Mac? Hmm. 'cause
Speaker 4:  that would be great.
Speaker 5:  I mean, your Mac has a headphone jack, but Sure. If you wanna use crappy
Speaker 5:  EarPods, do You
Speaker 4:  Know? You know how they That's true. Well, I just like a lot of people
Speaker 4:  carry the warrant for their phones. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And
Speaker 4:  If it would be nice, it's unclear if that would happen. I bet it doesn't.
Speaker 4:  And if it, if it does work, like next year is Max don't have headphone track
Speaker 4:  anymore, right? Oh man. It's just coming. So that's a 15 I gr
Speaker 4:  a solid upgrade. Nothing spectacular
Speaker 5:  Comes in five colors. They all have normal names. Yeah. There's no dumb
Speaker 5:  marketing names on 'em. It's just pink, yellow, green, blue and black.
Speaker 8:  I love it.
Speaker 6:  Well you didn't want it to be like Barbie, lemon grass,
Speaker 4:  Sky. You did. You can, you can go black. Black. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You got it. Obsidian. Pure.
Speaker 5:  It's not space black. It's not obsidian. It's black.
Speaker 4:  Before we break, we should talk about the prices real quick. Yeah. iPhone
Speaker 4:  prices are, eh,
Speaker 5:  Same. So most of them are the same. the iPhone 15, the 15 plus are the
Speaker 5:  same as the 14 and 14 plus from last year. So we're talking 7 99 to start
Speaker 5:  8 99 to start on those a hundred bucks more to, if you upgrade the storage,
Speaker 5:  the 15 pro comes with 128 gigs of storage.
Speaker 5:  Starts at 9 99. Same price as before. Where it gets weird is with a
Speaker 5:  15 pro Max, which is now 1199. A hundred
Speaker 5:  dollars more than starting price of last year. But it comes with
Speaker 5:  256 gigs of storage, which is twice as much as last year.
Speaker 5:  And the same price if you got this 256
Speaker 5:  gig model last year. So it's like kind of a sneaky price increase.
Speaker 5:  Like yes. You are getting a little more. One can argue that a hundred
Speaker 5:  dollars is a lot of money to charge for 128 gigs of storage in this one
Speaker 5:  could argue the 2020 third year for Lord, but it is
Speaker 5:  more expensive. So like if you want the pro Max with the five x telephoto
Speaker 5:  lens, you are going to pay more for it this year
Speaker 5:  than last year.
Speaker 4:  Amortized over your phone plan. Am you're already getting scammed.
Speaker 4:  Yes. Like you've signed up with a major American
Speaker 5:  Wireless carrier. Apple loves to talk about the trade-ins. They love to talk
Speaker 5:  about how your iPhone holds value and that you can recoup a lot of value
Speaker 5:  and things like that. They, it's, they put it on a slide now. The carrier
Speaker 5:  promotions. Yeah. Like that's how much they wanna talk about because they
Speaker 5:  wanna deflect the fact that they are now charging a $1,200 starting price
Speaker 5:  for a phone. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's what I'm just saying. You're, you're signed up to American Wireless
Speaker 4:  carrier like You know. You know what you're in for. They're just coming to
Speaker 4:  your ass. They're just, they're one of your kids keys to your car at
Speaker 4:  $1,200 out the window. All right. So that's the 15.
Speaker 4:  We should take a break. I, I need to emotionally prepare myself for the mystery
Speaker 4:  of the iPhone 15 Pro. There's a lot I'm dying
Speaker 4:  to know. We'll be right back.
Speaker 10:  Fox Creative.
Speaker 8:  This is advertiser content from Zelle. So
Speaker 8:  you are a freelancer looking for your next gig. You get an email saying you
Speaker 8:  should apply for this amazing job, but it's competitive. So you need to apply
Speaker 8:  right now. Oh. And send them money to cover a few application
Speaker 8:  fees. Seems weird, but you really need this job.
Speaker 11:  Once you think critically, you realize it's a scam.
Speaker 8:  Cybersecurity expert Bruce Schneider says, scams like this can take
Speaker 8:  many forms, including employment scams that trick people into paying
Speaker 8:  bogus fees to apply for jobs that don't actually exist.
Speaker 8:  Scams like this are nothing new. But now money can be transferred easier
Speaker 8:  than ever.
Speaker 11:  Even though it's easy, don't lose sight of the fact that it's money.
Speaker 11:  And when you send money to someone you don't know, that's always a
Speaker 11:  risk. So think twice and be careful. If it seems too good to be true,
Speaker 11:  it probably is.
Speaker 8:  Zelle wants you to pay it safe. Treat every transaction like
Speaker 8:  cash and only send money to people You know and trust.
Speaker 8:  learn more safety tips@zellepay.com.
Speaker 12:  Support for this show comes from SoFi. Traditionally
Speaker 12:  access to IPOs has been aimed at institutional or high net worth
Speaker 12:  investors. Not anymore. With SoFi Invest, you can get
Speaker 12:  in on the I P O action at I p o prices before they're listed on
Speaker 12:  an exchange. Visit sofi.com/ipo
Speaker 12:  to see what IPOs are available. Now that's not all.
Speaker 12:  You can also trade stocks, ETFs, and options on an
Speaker 12:  intuitive platform that's easy to use. You'll even get a chance to up to
Speaker 12:  $1,000 in stocks when you fund a new active invest
Speaker 12:  account with at least $10. For full offer terms,
Speaker 12:  visit sofi.com/invest. Here's to making investing
Speaker 12:  more accessible. For the rest of us, investing in IPOs comes with
Speaker 12:  risk, including risk of loss. Please visit
Speaker 12:  sofi.com/ipo. Risk offered via SoFi
Speaker 12:  Securities. L L C member Finra, S P I C.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. The Apple event. We talked about the 15. Obviously
Speaker 4:  the, the interesting phone is the 15 pro in this
Speaker 4:  lineup. They made it out of titanium this time. It's a very, I like it. It's
Speaker 4:  very nice.
Speaker 5:  It's some titanium.
Speaker 4:  Some titanium.
Speaker 5:  There's a titanium frame, but that also connects to an aluminum frame
Speaker 5:  on the inside. So it's like the part you touch is titanium, but then
Speaker 5:  inside of it isn't aluminum
Speaker 4:  Frame thermo mechanically bonded. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Doesn't that
Speaker 8:  Just mean melted? Turned
Speaker 4:  Pushed? Yeah.
Speaker 8:  It sounds cooler
Speaker 4:  If you say thermo. Okay. Have you ever bumped into anyone in a sauna? You've
Speaker 4:  been thermo mechanically welders gross. I don't,
Speaker 4:  but that's how metals work is my understanding. It's the lightest one ever.
Speaker 4:  Same size as before 6 1 1 6 0.7 inches. They're very proud
Speaker 4:  of titanium apple, by the way, famously used titanium and another product,
Speaker 4:  not the Apple Watch Ultra, the titanium power book. The single coolest power
Speaker 4:  book ever made, which
Speaker 5:  Lasted about six months before it looked like garbage because they painted
Speaker 5:  the titanium and it all F
Speaker 4:  Flaked off. And also the hinges broke. Let's not talk about it at this time.
Speaker 4:  They said it's more repairable, which is really a big deal for Apple. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's carrying on from the iPhone 14 from last year. So now it's with the
Speaker 5:  pro line as well is,
Speaker 4:  But they're, they're saying this word out loud. They're saying repairable
Speaker 4:  out loud. They're basically giving into regulators, right? The Yeah. California
Speaker 4:  regulators want things to be repairable. This is
Speaker 5:  The big capitulation show for Apple. They gave in on USB C to the Europeans.
Speaker 5:  They gave in to California on repair
Speaker 4:  Big a 17 pro processor. It's three in animators, which is the industry
Speaker 4:  first. That's A T S M C, extreme
Speaker 4:  ultraviolet chip. Like Yeah, that's a big deal.
Speaker 5:  And rumors are the Apple bought out T SMCs entire capacity for the three
Speaker 5:  nanometer chips. So I would not expect to see three nanometer chips from
Speaker 5:  anybody else anytime soon.
Speaker 4:  And then they said it's a breakthrough new G P U design for Apple, their
Speaker 4:  first new one. It's like, guys, you, you're on the M two chip.
Speaker 4:  So, but they're very proud as new G P U. What's a
Speaker 4:  20% faster new shader architecture. They
Speaker 4:  have a new neural engine that's supposed to be faster. Basically it's a,
Speaker 4:  it does
Speaker 5:  Hardware Ray tracing games. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Games. They games a lot about games. Yeah. They talked a lot about games
Speaker 4:  at this
Speaker 6:  Thing. Just, just No, I'm just, listen, my phone is especially is like,
Speaker 6:  especially made for stupid games. If I wanna
Speaker 6:  play good games, it's not gonna be on my phone.
Speaker 4:  You this mobile gaming
Speaker 5:  System in the world, there a lot of stupid games on consoles too.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Fancy stupid games. Get to be on the console. I am not
Speaker 6:  playing Resident Evil on my phone because as I said, the phone is gonna
Speaker 6:  get chucked the second there's a jump scare and then my
Speaker 6:  expensive phone is going to be in pieces and AppleCare Plus or
Speaker 6:  whatever the, the thingy is, is not gonna cover. Oh, you were scared by
Speaker 6:  Resident Evil and you chucked your phone at the wall. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Well their, their, their whole big claim is that this is the first time a
Speaker 5:  full console game experience is available on a mobile device. What was the
Speaker 5:  name of the other game began with the D
Speaker 4:  Division? I just remember. Oh yeah. Division
Speaker 5:  Is like the full console experience.
Speaker 4:  Assassin Creed is there because there's no not a console in the world that
Speaker 4:  Esof won't put Assassin's Creed on. Like if you can play a game on it,
Speaker 4:  Assassin's Creed will be there. You'll be doing stabs on just
Speaker 4:  IO will be there and he'll be stabbing. But this was like a really weird
Speaker 4:  dichotomy in how they were talking about the Pro first. They said it's the
Speaker 4:  most pro phone ever, which is an incredible phrase, just a deeply
Speaker 4:  incredible phrase that means whatever Apple wants it to mean.
Speaker 4:  Like their answer to us was, we think pro features or aspirational.
Speaker 4:  It's the camera, it's the display and we just want this be the, and it's
Speaker 4:  the best that we can do. And by definition, that means every new pro
Speaker 4:  iPhone is the most pro phone ever made.
Speaker 5:  Well every new iPhone is the best iPhone ever. Right.
Speaker 4:  Be because they don't make worse iPhones. Like that's
Speaker 5:  Amazing how that works.
Speaker 4:  It's just, it's just really something to be the most pro phone ever. And
Speaker 4:  we've defined Pro in a way that we will never not make
Speaker 4:  the most pro phone ever. And then right next to it they're like, and
Speaker 4:  I, I believe they actually said out loud, this is the best mobile gaming
Speaker 4:  device ever made.
Speaker 5:  And you can also spend 14 hours in a row playing gun engine impact on it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And it's like, well then one, the Nintendo Switch exists,
Speaker 4:  which a deeply important mobile gaming device with maybe
Speaker 4:  two of the best games ever made in the Zelda games on there.
Speaker 4:  I don't think they're coming to the iPhone at this time. No, I'm
Speaker 4:  confident the iPhone is more powerful. The Nintendo Switch,
Speaker 5:  It's got a nicer screen too. It's got,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, like everything on the iPhone is nicer than my Switch and I have like
Speaker 4:  an original switch. But it's like that, that's the best one because it has
Speaker 4:  the best games on it then mobile games are not those games.
Speaker 5:  No, I mean that said, I You know, I, I'm not a mobile gamer, but I
Speaker 5:  know that there's an enormous market of mobile gamers out there.
Speaker 4:  Candy Crush Whales, candy Crush
Speaker 6:  Whales. It's mes
Speaker 4:  I spend too much. But there's You know she's a Candy Crush whale. There's,
Speaker 5:  There's the, the Ganon impact players and there's a lot of mos
Speaker 5:  played on mobile and stuff like that. So like there's definitely a market
Speaker 5:  here and like Apple is speaking to that market and they, this market
Speaker 5:  will also pay more for better performance, which
Speaker 5:  is what they are trying to like make the case for with the 15 product.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 6:  Just don't need Ray tracing for my beed knockoff.
Speaker 4:  You don't Yeah. The one that like gets your phone super hot and destroys
Speaker 4:  your battery. This is why your battery health is down to like 87%. Like
Speaker 4:  you're running a, like a Bitcoin botnet in the background of like a Beed
Speaker 4:  clone.
Speaker 6:  Listen, I You know I do. I need Ray tracing on Sudoku
Speaker 6:  Sudokus a middle, a mobile game. No I don't. Although, but you have I would
Speaker 6:  like to see what Ray tracing on Sudoku looks.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, that's what I'm
Speaker 4:  Saying. This is like Ultra realistic Minecraft. Yeah. Like those come out
Speaker 4:  like blow your mind. Look, there's somebody who said for the,
Speaker 4:  the fact like it's weird that they did a ray tracing explanation. Yeah. In
Speaker 4:  2023, like on the other side of the house, PC gamers had
Speaker 4:  ray tracing for a long time. That cost curve is all the way down. And then
Speaker 4:  you're like, oh this is a phone. Yeah. This is actually bonkers that they're
Speaker 4:  like doing it on a phone at this scale. But I have asked
Speaker 4:  people who use Android gaming phones to email us on the
Speaker 4:  show for years. Well,
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 4:  Mean we have never gotten one email. We've gotten emails from people who
Speaker 4:  think they might know someone who plays games on an Android
Speaker 4:  phone and needs a gaming Android phone because
Speaker 5:  They're all playing them on iPhones. So I,
Speaker 4:  I mean that's, that's it. I say to you audience, I look at you
Speaker 4:  directly and say if you are a hardcore iPhone gamer who's gonna
Speaker 4:  buy a pro iPhone to play games?
Speaker 4:  'cause you, this is how you want to play Assassin's Creed. So lemme know.
Speaker 4:  I'm, I'm just dying to hear from you. I just wanna know what it's like in
Speaker 4:  your life in your brain. You're like, You know what Ganion impact.
Speaker 4:  That's that's it's
Speaker 5:  A popular game. That's
Speaker 4:  $1,500 for me
Speaker 5:  That's a popular game. I don't know what to say man.
Speaker 4:  I know it's a popular game but it's just like, and it's, it's clear the clean
Speaker 4:  deck exists. Like
Speaker 5:  Chen Impact is one of those things where it's like very clear that their
Speaker 5:  gaming audience is on the iPhone because it runs so much better
Speaker 5:  on iOS devices than on Android. And they put so much more development work
Speaker 5:  into Android. Allison can speak to how annoying it is to test Genin
Speaker 5:  impact on new phones and devices. 'cause it's like a 30 gigabyte download
Speaker 5:  on a mobile phone
Speaker 7:  Like four hours before I wanna play it. I am like I better start
Speaker 7:  downloading Genin Impact now
Speaker 5:  So, we we test it. We stress test devices with it all the time because it
Speaker 5:  is such an intensive thing and the iPhones and the iPadOS just run
Speaker 5:  circles around it and they have better silicon. But it's a lot of the fact
Speaker 5:  that the developers put all their work into it because that's where their
Speaker 5:  audience is.
Speaker 4:  What And because in-app purchases are the money for all
Speaker 4:  of these games. Yep. And 30% of those in in-app purchases are
Speaker 4:  the money for Apple like Apple's entire services revenue chunk
Speaker 4:  that the thing that's growing while iPhone sales are going down
Speaker 4:  the line of business that's growing for Apple's services and the biggest
Speaker 4:  chunk of services is in-app purchases and games. Of
Speaker 4:  course they want the iPhone to be an incredible gaming device
Speaker 4:  because if they can sell you more Ian impact stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I mean there's that side of it. But I think that like part of the reason
Speaker 5:  that they spent so much time explaining Ray tracing and showing off all these
Speaker 5:  capabilities and stuff is like this is where you can see the most
Speaker 5:  impact of a three nanometer cutting edge processor there. It's not
Speaker 5:  like You know if they didn't talk about that, they would be like, what your
Speaker 5:  email opens faster or like the brow you can switch between the browser. Like
Speaker 5:  we've hit the point where like I can use a phone from five years ago and
Speaker 5:  be just fine for my daily day-to-day work because I'm doing those kinds of
Speaker 5:  tasks. Whereas gaming is one area where they can push the envelope, they
Speaker 5:  can continue to show development and like we've made this huge investment
Speaker 5:  on this three nanometer a 17 Pro processor. I think they dropped Bionic
Speaker 5:  Bionics gone. Am I right? Yeah. It's
Speaker 4:  A 17
Speaker 5:  Pro. But You know and like the, they, they talked
Speaker 5:  about its ability to shoot pro as video and decode a V one video
Speaker 5:  and all this kind of stuff. But really it's the games. That's where you're
Speaker 5:  gonna see the notice. Notice the difference. People can buy an iPhone 15
Speaker 5:  that has the A 16 from last year and not skip a beat because
Speaker 5:  it's just fine. But if you want the best gaming things, which as we know,
Speaker 5:  PC gamers will literally spend thousands and thousands of dollars to get
Speaker 5:  the best ultimate actual, maximum performance for their games.
Speaker 5:  If you are a mobile gamer, best maximum performance I guess is gonna be spending
Speaker 5:  big on the iPhone.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I'm just saying Candy Crush whales, candy crush whales. Like they
Speaker 4:  are, I I understand what you mean. The demos are good and they do have a
Speaker 4:  giant new spatial computing platform coming out.
Speaker 4:  There's a lot of graphics stuff they're
Speaker 5:  Gonna, which has an M one chip in it.
Speaker 4:  It
Speaker 4:  very confusing all the way around. We
Speaker 5:  Just, we skipped the most important part of the new iPhone pros thinnest
Speaker 5:  borders ever.
Speaker 4:  That's true. They're a little bit thinner. It makes the screen look a little
Speaker 4:  bit bigger. Yes.
Speaker 5:  It looks a little like I, I put it next to my 13 pro and like
Speaker 5:  I don't think it's any smaller, but it looks smaller.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it looks a little smaller. That screen by the way. Promotion. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Up to one 20 hertz. That's pretty normal. Can get brighter, can go up to
Speaker 4:  2000. It's of brightness. Which is pretty cool. In bright sunlight. In
Speaker 5:  Bright sunlight. We'll see how long it'll hold that brightness.
Speaker 5:  Lots of phones will juice their brightness and then 15 seconds later dimmed.
Speaker 5:  Unreadable. Yeah. My 13 pro does that all the time. So we'll see. But like
Speaker 5:  You know brighter is better. So that's, that's moving forward I guess.
Speaker 4:  And then obviously USB C three with camera
Speaker 4:  tether mode, USB USB three speeds up to
Speaker 4:  10 gigabits. Yeah. Which
Speaker 5:  Is actually,
Speaker 4:  They're very
Speaker 5:  Proud of this thing. They, they talked a lot about the things you can do
Speaker 5:  with that, which we saw some very comical studio setups of
Speaker 5:  people using iPhones to tether to much more powerful
Speaker 5:  computers. But the rumor mill was expecting Thunderbolt here,
Speaker 5:  which is four times the bandwidth of what it actually gets.
Speaker 5:  So it's USB three at 10 gigabits if you
Speaker 5:  know your USB. There's also USB three at
Speaker 5:  20 gigabits, which this is not. And then there's SB four which does
Speaker 5:  20 or 40 gigabits. And then also today Intel
Speaker 5:  announced Thunderbolt five, which does
Speaker 4:  120
Speaker 5:  Gigabits. So this is like, this is USB C, but it's like, or USB three.
Speaker 5:  But it's like one of the slowest tiers of USB three where
Speaker 5:  they could have, or there's potential for much faster ones. I don't know
Speaker 5:  if they're just setting themselves up to upgrade it later in the future or
Speaker 5:  if this is a limitation of the chip. It's kind of weird that You know we
Speaker 5:  have Thunderbolt on the iPadOS and all the Macs and things like that,
Speaker 5:  but it's not on the iPhone for whatever reason.
Speaker 4:  I think they're just managing battery life and heat. Right. It's a much smaller
Speaker 4:  chassis. All that stuff requires power, generates
Speaker 4:  heat. Yeah. And they don't know if anyone's gonna actually use the ship.
Speaker 5:  Well they aren't gonna use it outta the box. 'cause it doesn't come with
Speaker 5:  a USB three cable in the box.
Speaker 4:  But a USB three, USB C cable is like relatively inexpensive. They're
Speaker 5:  Relatively inexpensive. But this is the problem with USB C is that you do
Speaker 5:  not know looking at a cable unless it specifically says on there or you've
Speaker 5:  tested it yourself. What its capabilities are. Thunderbolt is the, the
Speaker 5:  Thunderbolt is annoying in a lot of ways. Mostly because it's expensive.
Speaker 5:  The cables are thicker, they have larger ends and stuff. But if it has the
Speaker 5:  Thunderbolt logo on there, You know what that cable is capable of. I have
Speaker 5:  a bag full of USB C cables right now that I do not know if it
Speaker 5:  charges at 60 watts, a hundred watts,
Speaker 5:  240 watts, I don't know. I don't know if the data supported is
Speaker 5:  480 megabits per second, which is USB two or is
Speaker 5:  it 40 gigabits per second, which
Speaker 4:  Which is Thunderball. So you take 'em all back to Apple so they can recycle
Speaker 4:  them into watches or whatever they're gonna do. And then you just buy good
Speaker 4:  cables.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean you could do that, but you will inevitably end up with cables
Speaker 5:  that you do not like they C So many things come with a charging cable. You
Speaker 5:  don't know what it's capable of.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And you just drive those directly to the Apple store. You increase
Speaker 4:  your carbon emissions and then you offset them by recycling the garbage cable.
Speaker 4:  That's how you do it. Look, I think this is, I think it's weird that when
Speaker 4:  you plug a cable into an iPhone, it doesn't tell you anything about the cable.
Speaker 4:  Yep. Like with with a Mac, you can like go and a system profile and like
Speaker 4:  at least suss out what's going on. This is like you're gonna plug a cable
Speaker 4:  with an iPhone and it's gonna tell you nothing. Just like stuff is gonna
Speaker 4:  start happening and it's like,
Speaker 5:  Or not happening.
Speaker 4:  The dynamic island should just be like garbage cable or like get
Speaker 4:  outta here. It would be really useful. Like they can do it. They have that
Speaker 4:  layer of information on the screen. I think Apple is just waiting to see
Speaker 4:  what people do with these USB C ports. But with capture one,
Speaker 4:  you can shoot 48 megapixel raw photos and tether
Speaker 4:  immediately, which is cool. You can shoot video directly to external storage,
Speaker 4:  which is cool. Yeah. Those are their big ideas basically. Camera
Speaker 4:  stuff.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Because I mean, what else are you gonna do with it? Charge your
Speaker 4:  Phone. Charge your phone at 15. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Lot. I mean like in a perfect world you would plug your USB C
Speaker 5:  iPhone into a studio display and get like a
Speaker 5:  desktop interface
Speaker 4:  With your a 17 Pro
Speaker 5:  With an A 17 Pro and the A 13.
Speaker 4:  This is why I need to talk about, Dan actually uses Samsung decks. I
Speaker 5:  Love ds.
Speaker 4:  He's like, he's serious about it. Talk about the action button or the, the
Speaker 4:  camera section. Let's do the action button quickly, I think. Okay. It's there.
Speaker 4:  You don't like it?
Speaker 6:  No, I like the action button on the Ultra. I think it's one of the cooler
Speaker 6:  things about the Ultra, but what I'm gonna say is, is that I use the
Speaker 6:  action button to do exactly one thug on my Ultra, which is to launch my runs.
Speaker 6:  And what I've noticed is that even though you can program
Speaker 6:  the action button on the Ultra using shortcuts, ain't nobody got time for
Speaker 6:  that. Ain't nobody got time to think about, well, some
Speaker 4:  People do that stuff.
Speaker 6:  Some people have that time. Pro
Speaker 5:  Users,
Speaker 6:  Most people ain't nobody got time for for thinking about how they're
Speaker 6:  gonna do that. So for me, the problem with the action button on the Ultra
Speaker 6:  is that it has so much potential, but it's really for the average
Speaker 6:  person, kind of hemmed in by what the presets are. So if
Speaker 6:  the presets for this action button on the phone aren't great, you're just
Speaker 6:  gonna be like, well, I miss my old Well,
Speaker 5:  I think I, I, I, I hear you. I, I feel the same way about the, the, the button
Speaker 5:  on the watch. I think it's, it's neutered by the fact that it's on the watch
Speaker 5:  and the platform of the watch the phone. I think it is more
Speaker 5:  practical to use it to launch a shortcut, which is one of the preset options.
Speaker 5:  The others are, by default, it will just control your
Speaker 5:  ringer. And it's always a long press. So you long press it to switch between
Speaker 5:  silent and ringing modes. You can also launch the camera with it.
Speaker 5:  You could launch the flashlight with it. You can launch an accessibility
Speaker 5:  shortcut. So if you use the back tap thing to pull down your notification
Speaker 5:  sheet, you can program that to the action button, which seems pretty neat.
Speaker 5:  And there, there's, you can run shortcuts with it. And I think there's one
Speaker 5:  more that I'm not remembering right now, but I could see like You know really
Speaker 5:  quickly, easily making a shortcut to launch Hali and then
Speaker 5:  using the action button to launch Hali as my camera. The
Speaker 5:  other thing you can do with it is you can take photos with it in the camera
Speaker 5:  app.
Speaker 6:  So I think the camera app launching is gonna be the thing that most people
Speaker 6:  use. Yeah. Because like, well,
Speaker 5:  To be clear, most people will use the default and they will not change it.
Speaker 4:  Yes. But if you do change the default, you
Speaker 5:  Are probably launching the camera
Speaker 6:  Are gonna change the default. Like I always, I know that you can just go
Speaker 6:  from the lock screen and go into your camera, but by the time I've done that,
Speaker 6:  my cat has moved. Yeah. The cute picture is gone. So,
Speaker 4:  I mean, well, I think the amount of time between that flow versus holding
Speaker 4:  the button down.
Speaker 5:  No, I think, I think it's, it's smoother to use the button. Like Allison
Speaker 5:  knows this with the Android phones for years, you double press the power
Speaker 5:  button to launch the camera and you're in it and you don't like, it's one
Speaker 5:  motion. You pull your phone up, you're double clicking. And, and you can
Speaker 5:  do that same thing with the action button, with the current system of,
Speaker 5:  you have to like wake the screen up, you have to put your finger on the screen,
Speaker 5:  which is almost always your other hand. And you have to hold it there for
Speaker 5:  a few seconds as it a second or whatever as it launches. That's like kind
Speaker 5:  of cumbersome and clumsy. I, I think the action button would be,
Speaker 7:  I have so much trouble with it. I don't know what is wrong with me, but like
Speaker 7:  swiping that camera icon is like, I'll, I'll like miss it or
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I don't know. I am jazzed about that action
Speaker 5:  Button. I always open the camera when I'm trying to swipe a notification
Speaker 5:  away, like just
Speaker 4:  Opening
Speaker 5:  The
Speaker 7:  Camera and drives me kind box. That's nice too. Yeah. And and the, the action
Speaker 7:  button, the camera, the like shortcut, you
Speaker 7:  can customize it to go into like a certain mode. So if you wanna
Speaker 7:  get in a portrait mode really quickly or a video, I think that's nice.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I think it just has more potential on the phone than I watch
Speaker 4:  In the UI for customizing this button is the funnest ui. It's wild that Apple
Speaker 4:  has shipped in a,
Speaker 5:  You go into the settings app, like just any other like thing you might change
Speaker 5:  on your iPhone and then you're taken into this like
Speaker 4:  There's a three render of the side of that we've never seen before,
Speaker 7:  Like turns and you see a different side of the phone. Yeah. It's
Speaker 4:  Wild.
Speaker 6:  I'm kind of mad as a watch user. This, this, this.
Speaker 7:  We're having more fun over here. Yeah. This
Speaker 4:  Boo. Yeah. Big ass screens. Huge battery gen. An impact action
Speaker 4:  button. That's good. Okay. The day they bring whatcha doing retracing against
Speaker 4:  You got an iPhone 10 Strapp to your wrist.
Speaker 4:  Well why? I mean, I have the same, I have the exact same watch I,
Speaker 4:  but the UI for this settings menu is so cool. Like Yeah, go look at our
Speaker 4:  pictures. Go look at the videos. It's so cool. It's
Speaker 5:  So just, it's cool but it's also just like so weird to go into.
Speaker 5:  I love it. Like normal iOS.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And more iOS.
Speaker 5:  It does not look like Apple's other us
Speaker 4:  More iOS should be wacky. Yeah, sure. Like if they, they
Speaker 4:  could do all of settings and all of settings would be fun. Instead of right
Speaker 4:  now the sort of impenetrable list of radio buttons and toggles. That's the
Speaker 5:  Nightmare. The nightmare of the settings
Speaker 4:  App. Yeah. This is just like cool as hell and it's like fun to use and it
Speaker 4:  makes you want to use it, which is neat. I am, I just don't know that
Speaker 4:  Long Press. I think they should have had double tap and Long press.
Speaker 5:  So this is the same argument that you made for with the Dynamic
Speaker 5:  Island last year, right? Like they, they have a long press and they have
Speaker 5:  like a short press and they
Speaker 4:  Be
Speaker 5:  Backwards. They invert, they should be backwards,
Speaker 4:  Right? I'm no here I'm saying there's only Long Press, right? Well there
Speaker 4:  is. So you tap it once, it'll just tell you what a long
Speaker 5:  Press will be. Yeah. It'll give the status. It'll
Speaker 4:  Pop up a thing that says like if it's in the default, if you tap it once,
Speaker 4:  it says hold down for silent and then you tap it when it's in silence says,
Speaker 4:  hold on for a ring. And it's like, okay, that's great. But
Speaker 4:  so everything by the default is a long press in this button. I
Speaker 5:  Think they're doing that because you could accidentally hit it. Oh
Speaker 4:  Sure. That makes sense. And
Speaker 5:  Then you don't wanna turn your ringer
Speaker 4:  On actually. But I'm saying they should, they should have left ring at two
Speaker 4:  clicks. So you double click it to switch ring modes
Speaker 4:  and then you long press it and that's your custom action. That
Speaker 5:  Would be cool. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And I, I hope that comes, it just seems very, it seems very obvious they
Speaker 4:  could do lots of things with this button. Yeah. Beyond just long pressing
Speaker 4:  it. And I, I think the long press is gonna throw a lot of people off. 'cause
Speaker 4:  you click it and it's like hold for ring and then your natural instinct is
Speaker 4:  to push it again and it just says it again. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It gives you haptic feedback though. Like, it, it, it vibrates and it like
Speaker 5:  buzzes as you're holding itself to kinda give you an indication of what
Speaker 5:  it's doing.
Speaker 7:  I think they did that 'cause they wanted to head off people being like, well
Speaker 7:  how am I supposed to know if my phone's on mute? Yeah. I can just like reach
Speaker 7:  into my pocket and mess with the mute switch or whatever. Or
Speaker 5:  Or the people that insist they can feel when it's in mute Yeah. Without looking.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. What, yeah, there's people that can insist they could feel the mute
Speaker 5:  switch. Yeah. So
Speaker 7:  You,
Speaker 5:  Which position is' in
Speaker 7:  Push it once and you're like a bullshit.
Speaker 5:  Sorry. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I just don't, well it, it also just occurs to me that if anybody with an
Speaker 4:  Apple watch like does not need the mute switch anymore because if, unless
Speaker 4:  you're a sociopath, your phone should always be on mute because your, your
Speaker 4:  watch is buzzing you and you're fine. Right. Like,
Speaker 4:  you're probably fine. So we'll see. I'm, I'm excited about it. I'm excited
Speaker 4:  about the camera stuff. I think the, the shortcuts people are gonna make
Speaker 4:  for this are gonna be bananas. I hope somebody that does like an iPhone action
Speaker 4:  button shortcuts website with all the best ones there already. Already some
Speaker 4:  do that. There are already some cool shortcuts out there. But yeah, I, it
Speaker 4:  it's a, it's a good change along with u s pc. I think the action buttons
Speaker 4:  like a good change to the phone. Okay. Then there's the camera,
Speaker 4:  which seems all new kind of bananas, Allison and go through it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So they're saying that the main camera is 48
Speaker 7:  megapixels again, but they're saying it's a bigger sensor.
Speaker 7:  And then You know you have the Ultra wide, which had some like new
Speaker 7:  coatings or something. But the big story is the five times
Speaker 7:  telephoto lens, which they would not, they did not say
Speaker 7:  periscope. They have a word for tetra prism.
Speaker 7:  I, I don't know. Yeah. There's, there's some mirrors and things
Speaker 7:  happening inside there, but you don't get the three times, you get the five
Speaker 7:  times. Instead it's got kind of some kind of sensor
Speaker 7:  shift stabilization along with the optical stabilization, which
Speaker 7:  is a good thing. You know, assuming it works, but Yeah. And they're all about
Speaker 7:  these like seven different lenses that you get with it. And that's
Speaker 7:  counting You know macro and the Ultra wide and
Speaker 7:  the, the crop modes you can do. But there's like a new thing
Speaker 7:  where you can push the like main camera icon and it'll switch
Speaker 7:  between like, like equivalent focal legs, like 24
Speaker 7:  millimeters, 35 millimeters. Yeah. Which
Speaker 5:  I think is great. Yeah. Right. I'm, I'm excited for that because
Speaker 4:  I, I just think
Speaker 5:  That the main camera is too wide. I've long felt like the main camera is
Speaker 5:  like equivalent to like 24 or 26 millimeters for a few years now. And it's
Speaker 5:  too wide. Like I don't like it that wide. I like to shoot it like 30 or 35
Speaker 5:  and now I can just like tell, it
Speaker 4:  Can set it by default, which is cool. Can
Speaker 5:  Set it by default. It's gonna like crop in the sensor. It's, it's
Speaker 4:  Really unclear how this is working. Is it cropping the sensor? Because
Speaker 5:  I think it's using the same technology as the two x. It's just cutting into
Speaker 5:  the sensor at that to, to approximate that field of view.
Speaker 5:  And then it will produce a 24 or 12 megapixel image out, the
Speaker 4:  Exact word that we were told was there's some other voodoo going on. Yes.
Speaker 4:  Oh, voodoo. 'cause they, the claim is that it will force shorten the way
Speaker 4:  that those different focal lengths will. Yeah. Which is again, impossible
Speaker 4:  to see on an iPhone in that environment, which is a totally
Speaker 4:  crazy environment with perfect light. So I'm very curious as we review this
Speaker 4:  thing to see if those modes actually foreshorten the way that a
Speaker 4:  proper focal length would, I suspect that they do not.
Speaker 4:  But you should be able to tell the difference between 24 to 35.
Speaker 5:  Yes. It's very obvious as you go down the, the numbers of equivalent
Speaker 5:  focal lengths, the, the smaller they are, the more you notice each
Speaker 5:  millimeter's difference. So when you are going from 24 to 28, it's actually
Speaker 5:  a visible noticeable difference. If you're going from a hundred to 104,
Speaker 5:  you don't notice that difference. It's too, too minute. But when you, you,
Speaker 5:  you can see it punching in 24, 28, 35. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And then I think the Ultra wide is like a 13 or something like that.
Speaker 4:  It's, yeah. And so the range is 13 to one 20 now. Yes. It's cool. Again,
Speaker 4:  impossible to tell you what these cameras are actually like. Like it's just
Speaker 4:  a bonkers environment. They were, they took photos and they didn't, they
Speaker 4:  didn't explode. Yeah. Like that's as much as it got right now. But it's,
Speaker 4:  I think that stuff is cool. Dan, you have some
Speaker 4:  qualms about the telephoto.
Speaker 5:  I don't, I'm not confident that the telephoto is gonna be all that great.
Speaker 5:  I think it's great that it gives a longer reach. Like that was needed. The
Speaker 5:  three x telephoto and prior pro models existed.
Speaker 5:  Never was really that great. I know a lot of people never use it because
Speaker 5:  they don't like the quality out of it. And it also doesn't bring you that
Speaker 5:  much closer. Five x does bring you noticeably closer. That one 20
Speaker 5:  millimeter focal length is noticeably closer. But it's not super long. Like
Speaker 5:  today for the live blog I was shooting with an 18 to 300 millimeter lens
Speaker 5:  on my camera. So like there's a lot further to go.
Speaker 5:  Samsung's 10 x zoom is much further than the five x that you get on the
Speaker 5:  pro now. But in order to make this work and because of physics, they
Speaker 5:  have to put a small sensor in there. And Samsung has the same problem with
Speaker 5:  its cameras. The other manufacturers that have done Periscope or not Periscope
Speaker 5:  cameras in the past have the same problem where they have to put a small
Speaker 5:  sensor in there in order to get the physics to work right. To get the light
Speaker 5:  exposed. And you can tell like pretty easily the
Speaker 5:  quality difference even in the demo area, perfect lighting, all
Speaker 5:  this stuff. I took a photo of some folks across the table and I
Speaker 5:  zoom in and like I look at the details in the hair. It's all kind of blurred
Speaker 5:  and mushed together. It's noisy stuff like that. Allison is gonna do a ton
Speaker 5:  more testing. We'll get a more formal verdict on it. I'm just skeptical.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You know. I, I don't, I think the five x is gonna be there
Speaker 5:  and it, it'll be useful to some people, especially the folks like I said
Speaker 5:  earlier who are standing there pinch zooming on their phone to get as close
Speaker 5:  as they possibly can. It's better to have a five x optical
Speaker 5:  starting point then a three x. But I don't think it's going to be
Speaker 5:  like, I think a lot of people are still gonna fall back to the main camera
Speaker 5:  if they care about the image quality.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I shooted two x a lot with my 14 pro, like I never go to three.
Speaker 5:  And I think that the, the five, the five x existence Allison you were saying
Speaker 5:  earlier, didn't really make sense to have that two x punch in when you have
Speaker 5:  a three x it's not enough difference now. I think it gives more of a reason
Speaker 5:  for that two x punch in to exist because five x is like, if I, if I'm, I'm
Speaker 5:  sitting across from a small table from uni life, I use five x I'm like taking
Speaker 5:  pictures of of your eyeballs. Yeah. And, and your nose. But like two x I
Speaker 5:  can frame you nicely. So I, I think that gives more of that punch in to reason
Speaker 5:  to exist.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Allison, what do you think?
Speaker 7:  I am interested to try it out. I like the five x like is
Speaker 7:  sort of when I use like the Pixel seven Pro has one and
Speaker 7:  I find it useful in these like fringe cases where I'm on a hike and
Speaker 7:  I'm trying to frame something and like three x just gets you nothing.
Speaker 7:  You're
Speaker 5:  You're in the far away section of the Taylor Swift concert. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Right. You're, you're in the back row. But five x is like that much closer
Speaker 7:  and it is an actual meaningful difference. So I'm interested to
Speaker 7:  see what it looks like.
Speaker 5:  The question is, is this good enough to get the pro Max? Because I don't
Speaker 5:  think we've actually stated that this is only on the Pro Max. That's true.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's not on the pro, the pro gets the same three x as last year. So
Speaker 5:  like is this five x a meaningful enough jump to get the bigger, more
Speaker 5:  expensive phone, which we can talk about is also more expensive the last
Speaker 5:  year. But for me, based on what I saw so far, I would say no,
Speaker 5:  I I'm I'm, I'm not gonna make use of that camera often enough and I'd rather
Speaker 5:  have a smaller lighter phone.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But I look, I love a big screen and big battery. You love a
Speaker 5:  That screen
Speaker 4:  You're different and a big battery. We're we're different people
Speaker 4:  like the Yeah, the camera is not the thing. It's the bigger screen and the
Speaker 4:  bigger battery. I don't think anybody is gonna buy this thing for the Zoom
Speaker 4:  lens. I think if it was
Speaker 5:  Good enough, people would, I mean this is not the first time we've seen Apple
Speaker 5:  segregate the camera to the pro. The biggest phone they did with the 12 Pro.
Speaker 5:  Right. The 12 Pro and pro Max. The 12 Pro had the first time it had the
Speaker 5:  really bigger sensor for the main one and the pro, the regular pro one did
Speaker 5:  not. And there was a noticeable difference between the two if you cared enough
Speaker 5:  about that. And so we'll
Speaker 4:  See. I dunno, there's some video stuff here. They now support
Speaker 4:  four K 60 logging coding. When you shoot in
Speaker 4:  ProRes they ACEs, which is an industry standard for color grading.
Speaker 4:  All very good. Cool. It's it's the stuff, it's the pro. It's the most pro
Speaker 4:  phone ever Dan. And then this is I think, fascinating.
Speaker 4:  They support spatial video capture. If you turn the phone sideways
Speaker 4:  and you use the Maine and the Ultra wide, it'll do spatial great. It's for
Speaker 4:  the Vision pro. You're the divorce dad watching a birthday party.
Speaker 4:  No, this is what it's for. It's happening. It's notable
Speaker 5:  That in the demo clip that they showed on stage, it was not a divorce
Speaker 4:  Dad watching it. They did not show the dad
Speaker 4:  interacting with his kids through
Speaker 5:  The face mask. It was You know another person reliving a memory
Speaker 5:  on their couch.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Alone in a headset alone. There's no way to
Speaker 4:  avoid it. You're wearing this headset,
Speaker 5:  You only experience it
Speaker 4:  Alone. Here's what I'll say philosophically, this is fascinating to me. We
Speaker 4:  have been writing about this for a long time. James Baram, our old creative
Speaker 4:  director, has a piece on our site from ages ago. He's like the power of the
Speaker 4:  iPhone. It is the first device where the people
Speaker 4:  consuming the photos are using the same device as the people
Speaker 4:  making the photos. And so your relationship with photography has changed.
Speaker 4:  And we published this eight years ago, this piece like, and
Speaker 4:  James was a pro photographer before. You like big thinky, we'll link it.
Speaker 4:  It's a great piece. I've been thinking about the piece a lot. Every time
Speaker 4:  we do an iPhone interview, like this is the dynamic is there's there, I
Speaker 4:  cannot think of another creative tool actually where it is both the thing
Speaker 4:  that makes the content and the thing that consumes the content. Then you
Speaker 4:  have a relationship with the person on the other end of the the the platform.
Speaker 4:  Right. This is the first time Apple's broken that relationship
Speaker 4:  where you can shoot spatial video on your iPhone
Speaker 4:  and you cannot watch it.
Speaker 5:  See they could have put, cannot put a three D screen on it. Yeah. It
Speaker 4:  We an old school, one of those You grateful the red
Speaker 7:  Phone got tro we've got three d
Speaker 5:  It's all coming. It's all the greatest hits.
Speaker 4:  Red and red and blue glasses.
Speaker 4:  The, I don't think they should put a three D screen on this. They should
Speaker 4:  have done it like the fire phone with like 500 cameras around the screen.
Speaker 4:  I just, there's just something fascinating about that. Yeah. That for
Speaker 4:  the first time ever, the iPhone is a capture device for another system
Speaker 4:  that nobody has yet that's super expensive that no one knows what it's for.
Speaker 4:  And yeah, it sure they should do it, but it's cool they
Speaker 5:  Do it well. They, they they have to do it because otherwise the only way
Speaker 5:  to capture this spatial video is through the headset, which is like,
Speaker 5:  we, we just kind of talked about how awkward that can be stupid. So I mean
Speaker 5:  we'll see what it's like to actually view spatial video on the
Speaker 5:  iPhone. I'm sure what I
Speaker 4:  Expect expect is I'm, it's just gonna be the main camera. It
Speaker 5:  Just falls back to the main camera. Right. It's
Speaker 4:  Between the main camera, it's normal video, then you've got a depth map.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. All that stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And that's what the second camera's doing is creating the depth map. It's
Speaker 5:  got the distance between the lenses to do so notable that you have to turn
Speaker 5:  it in landscape mode to do so. That makes sense. Which makes sense from a
Speaker 5:  technical level. It does not make sense for how 99% of people shoot video
Speaker 5:  on
Speaker 4:  Their phone. You know portrait headset video is not a good idea.
Speaker 5:  I'm just saying
Speaker 4:  This is how people
Speaker 5:  Shoot video on their phones. Yeah. Right. And so like they can switch to
Speaker 5:  that mode. Maybe the phone will have a UI telling them, turn the phone to
Speaker 5:  the side to do this. But if it doesn't, they're gonna have a lot of like
Speaker 5:  weird videos. But like, they had to do it in order to get any content for
Speaker 5:  the headset down the road. Right. We'll,
Speaker 4:  We'll see. I'm just saying it's the first time Apple's broken this
Speaker 4:  sort of power of the iPhone as a camera in that way.
Speaker 4:  Okay. We'll see how it goes. Kind of what they're assuming is that people
Speaker 4:  will shoot spatial video without a headset.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Because they will be buying an iPhone in a week and a half. Right.
Speaker 5:  And and not have a headset for they and
Speaker 4:  Not have a headset. Six plus. So they did say it's coming later, but even
Speaker 4:  then the iPhone Pro installed base, the iPhone 15 pro
Speaker 4:  installed base FM 15 pro install base necessarily will dwarf the headset
Speaker 4:  install base for a long time. So I'm just wondering, like,
Speaker 4:  there's just something in there. It's, there's something important about
Speaker 4:  this camera and what it represents to people that is broken by the ability
Speaker 4:  to shoot spatial video. And it's not a technical thing, it's not a quality
Speaker 4:  thing. It is like a philosophical relationship
Speaker 4:  between the camera and the screen on the iPhone that Apple has
Speaker 4:  for the first time divorced.
Speaker 7:  It's the it's the aspirational thing. Yeah. They're like, you could
Speaker 7:  buy a vision pro, you can, you can record this video. You'll be ready for
Speaker 7:  it. Yeah, yeah. Like, probably won't.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But it's like, what's a good analog
Speaker 4:  analogy? It's like if you bought a V H S camcorder, but you didn't have a
Speaker 4:  V H Ss player in your house. Yeah. Right. It's just like
Speaker 4:  a totally weird thing. Mm. I think it's fascinating. Like I just,
Speaker 4:  I just like thinking about it, like what that represents for this device.
Speaker 4:  Because I think a lot of it's the thing about the tos, how to get,
Speaker 4:  how to take better videos in camp photos in your iPhone. Like everybody
Speaker 4:  has an idea about it. And there's a cottage industry of content creators
Speaker 4:  who are like, here's what you do. You turn your phone upside down, you count
Speaker 4:  to 20, you throw it in the ocean and it's like whatever. Right. And it's
Speaker 4:  because they're like, you, you look at this photo, I will teach you how to
Speaker 4:  make it using the tool that you're holding in your hand. And this, I'm just
Speaker 4:  telling you this, breaks it in a way that I think is utterly fascinating.
Speaker 4:  And I, I'm just like waiting for the day when someone realized
Speaker 4:  they've shot like oceans of spatial video
Speaker 4:  and they're, and they're like, what is this for You know.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I think the people that will use it and know what it is are the people
Speaker 5:  that are going to be the first ones to buy a vision pro when it comes out.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like most people, we're not gonna touch it. They're not gonna go
Speaker 5:  into the mode. They're not gonna
Speaker 4:  Enable it. You know, like, just, just walk through that. You're like walking
Speaker 4:  down the street beautiful San Francisco, like taking a
Speaker 4:  photo of the bay, the bridge, the whole thing. And you're like, I can't wait
Speaker 4:  to go put on my headset and like relive. It's like
Speaker 4:  there's just something. I promise you there's something weird there.
Speaker 5:  Divorce stats are gonna love it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We'll link that piece by James. It, I, I was thinking about it during
Speaker 4:  this entire demo of just how important it is that a lot of times
Speaker 4:  when you look at a photo on your iPhone, you're holding the same thing that
Speaker 4:  someone was holding to take that photo. And there's just something very
Speaker 4:  important about that. And it's all the
Speaker 4:  spatial computing tangent that Apple's going down is about to make all
Speaker 4:  that way weirder. Yeah. All right. I think that's enough for the Oh, the
Speaker 4:  mystery. The big the
Speaker 5:  The whole reason the whole thing.
Speaker 4:  The only thing I want to talk about, okay. The app has wifi six E, which
Speaker 4:  is cool. Sure. 'cause I just bought the wrong heroes. But now they're the
Speaker 4:  right heroes.
Speaker 4:  I was, I should have bought the pro sixes. Should you have. Yeah. 'cause
Speaker 4:  they, they have the,
Speaker 5:  That's a whole nother podcast,
Speaker 4:  Whatever. But I accidentally bought the six E's. Yeah. Which have the six
Speaker 4:  E radios in them. But I have no six E devices because they
Speaker 5:  Use the six E radio to talk to each other.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But six gig cards sucks for that. So whatever, it doesn't matter. Now
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna get an iPhone with six E I'm gonna get the full mega full
Speaker 5:  Gigabit. Lemme tell. You'll never know when it's on six E because it's not
Speaker 5:  gonna tell you it's impossible
Speaker 4:  To force it full gigabit. We're gonna, I'm gonna be downloading movies so
Speaker 4:  fast. The phone explodes, this's gonna be great. But then they also tucked
Speaker 4:  into this press release tucked into the feature Bento box says, plus
Speaker 4:  Thread is a Thread radio. Now if you have been following
Speaker 4:  Gen two E at The Verge You know that Thread is an important part of the
Speaker 4:  future of the smart home. Which Jen has a British accent. She always goes
Speaker 4:  with the smart home, which is great
Speaker 4:  Thread and Matter coexist.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Well so Thread is one of the technologies that Matter runs on. Is is.
Speaker 4:  Right. But Matter can run anything. But the idea is that you'll have this
Speaker 4:  secondary wireless network in New York Smart Home that is Thread.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And it's a mesh network between all your devices. You know a border
Speaker 4:  router that connects 'em to the wifi and the internet, whatever. Why is there
Speaker 4:  a Thread radio in the iPhone by the way? None of that works in it is just
Speaker 4:  a mess. Yeah. Just a disaster mess. None of it quite works. None of it. Quite
Speaker 4:  interoperates. If you buy like one nano leaf light bulb and
Speaker 4:  connect it to a home pod mini with a series of incantations
Speaker 4:  and like crystals, it's a little bit faster than doing for
Speaker 4:  wifi. And that's about as good as it gets. But the iPhone 15
Speaker 4:  Pro has a Thread radio in it. Yeah. And the press release is like,
Speaker 4:  it's there for future ideas in the home app. And
Speaker 4:  you're like, what are those ideas? And everyone's like, we don't know yet.
Speaker 4:  And that's the whole answer. They're like, yeah, some stuff is gonna happen
Speaker 4:  with Matter. And it's like, what Stuff? Like who knows? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I, I've been trying to think about like what you would do with a Thread radio
Speaker 5:  on a phone that I can't do with a wifi or Bluetooth radio order.
Speaker 5:  You're
Speaker 4:  Gonna let up that ran leaf light bulbs so fast. You're gonna, you're gonna,
Speaker 4:  you're gonna think it, it's gonna light up. So,
Speaker 5:  So let's, let's let's think this through. You have Thread Radio on your iPhone
Speaker 5:  and you
Speaker 4:  No. Step one, the Connectivity Standards Alliance
Speaker 4:  finishes the matter. Specification
Speaker 5:  Matter accepted. You have Thread on your iPhone and you
Speaker 5:  have a Thread device and it uses Thread to talk to that device to communicate
Speaker 5:  to it. Yeah. What happens when you leave your house and someone else wants
Speaker 5:  to control that device? Do they need Thread
Speaker 4:  On their No, because they, you'll have some border router in your house.
Speaker 4:  So why do
Speaker 5:  I need Thread on my
Speaker 4:  Phone? This is why I started. That's what I'm saying with the connectivity
Speaker 4:  Standards Alliance finishes the matter specification which includes
Speaker 4:  Thread radio interoperability. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Thread, well technically Thread network interoperability. Yeah. It gets so
Speaker 5:  much woner.
Speaker 4:  Right. So right now my, my new heroes have Thread radios in them. Yeah. But
Speaker 4:  those, and they should make a mesh network with,
Speaker 5:  With your home pods. But they do not. They do not. They do not talk. So now
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 4:  Have two Thread networks in
Speaker 5:  The house. Yes, yes. And if you introduce a Google hub Max three, which I
Speaker 5:  think you have.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. No I don't have, we have, we have the baby ones. Okay. So
Speaker 5:  Those
Speaker 4:  I don't think they
Speaker 5:  Do. No. But a hub Max would introduce yet another Thread network
Speaker 5:  in your
Speaker 4:  House and none of, and all of those are supposed to make one giant happy
Speaker 4:  Thread mesh network. And then you bring the iPhone into
Speaker 4:  it and it sees that happy Thread mesh network and it can connect
Speaker 4:  directly to devices on it. This is the dream. Now Thread, I just don't
Speaker 4:  why Thread Now what is gonna happen is that home kit is also
Speaker 4:  insanity and something on your home kit Thread network will break
Speaker 4:  and the solution to fixing it will be restarting your iPhone, which is
Speaker 4:  often a solution
Speaker 5:  Kit. Which is, yeah. I mean that is the default home kit fix. 'cause
Speaker 5:  you never 'cause Home Kit does not tell you what breaks or how it broke or
Speaker 5:  why the answer is reboot your iPhone. And it weirdly fixes,
Speaker 5:  I've run a Thread network in my home for a couple years now. And frequently
Speaker 5:  if like say I move a home pod to a different room or I decide we don't need
Speaker 5:  to use it anymore.
Speaker 4:  Devices screwing with this family will just
Speaker 5:  Stop working. Yeah. And so like light bulbs will just no longer connect.
Speaker 5:  And they're supposed supposed to be self-healing and all that doesn't do
Speaker 5:  that. This is the first time I've been just like taking them out when they
Speaker 5:  stop working, replacing
Speaker 4:  Them with I three kids. You're just like, they'll never know what's going
Speaker 4:  on.
Speaker 5:  I'm away, I'm away from home this week. And I'm convinced nothing in the
Speaker 5:  house works. They're just sitting in the dark.
Speaker 4:  They're
Speaker 5:  Sitting in the dark or they're like sleeping with all the lights on.
Speaker 4:  Like they're cutting the main power of the house. Go bed. I just think it's,
Speaker 4:  this is the first time the Ultra wide band ship. The first time they shipped
Speaker 4:  in a pro was the, I think the first time they put in a thing that they
Speaker 4:  hadn't quite enabled all the use cases for by the way. Both I found. But
Speaker 4:  they
Speaker 5:  Had some use cases for that.
Speaker 4:  Not yet. Didn't they? Not yet. They they, they announced it with like car
Speaker 4:  keys and they
Speaker 5:  Were hoping car
Speaker 4:  Keys would happen and it never happened. Yeah. And they, they kind of just
Speaker 4:  got
Speaker 5:  But fire. But then they fire tag, they came out with a but that
Speaker 4:  Was next first they first they did the chip. That was the only time I can
Speaker 4:  really think this, by the way, these have new Ultra wideband chips. Yes.
Speaker 5:  That enabled
Speaker 4:  Precision finding with morphs.
Speaker 5:  We could call them U two chips.
Speaker 4:  Apple doesn't like it when you do that.
Speaker 5:  No, but, but I'm gonna do it.
Speaker 4:  They, they kept saying sec second generation Ultra rod band chips. So I was
Speaker 4:  like, listen,
Speaker 5:  They called it the U one.
Speaker 4:  They're
Speaker 5:  Not, it wasn't me that called it the U one,
Speaker 4:  But that's the only time I think this, this time they, they're putting a
Speaker 4:  Thread radio. I'm assuming it's coming for the ride with the wifi
Speaker 4:  six e chip that they're using.
Speaker 5:  That's probably a safe bet.
Speaker 4:  Right. And so they just have it. They might as well do it and they don't
Speaker 4:  know what it's for. And like something good will happen. I just,
Speaker 5:  I someone who has an idea of what to use the Thread radio on an I for
Speaker 4:  It has
Speaker 5:  To be that it's right into the show. And tell me it that
Speaker 4:  Again, it has to be that what you want is a direct connection to that nano
Speaker 4:  leaf bulb or whatever other Thread device. You're laughing.
Speaker 4:  This is all people wanna do. I'm
Speaker 5:  Trying,
Speaker 4:  We're going from red to blue, like switch
Speaker 6:  It. I'm just, I'm just thinking of the nano leaf bulb talking to the little
Speaker 6:  iPhone radio. It's, it's just a, it's a cute little thing in my head. Right.
Speaker 6:  That's all it is.
Speaker 5:  I just, I just don't see a scenario where that would ever happen. Because
Speaker 5:  for the nano leaf bulb to be running
Speaker 4:  On Thread, it's connected to a Thread network in your house. Exactly. That
Speaker 4:  you're on the same wifi with. Exactly.
Speaker 6:  I have so much respect for Jen. 'cause my head hurts.
Speaker 4:  It's not great. Jen, Jen wrote an entire piece that's basically like, what
Speaker 4:  is this? Why is this here? And it just like runs through the options. She's
Speaker 5:  Wrote this multiple times out. We have what is matter? What is Thread? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  What is all No,
Speaker 4:  But with this one in particular, it's like this phone has this chip in it.
Speaker 4:  Why? And she just like runs down the options. And then by the end of the
Speaker 4:  piece she's like, none of these are good ideas. Like,
Speaker 4:  none this, none of this makes any sense. I'm just dying to know
Speaker 4:  what, what Apple obviously has a plan, right? Yeah. They wouldn't,
Speaker 5:  They just don't wanna tell us yet. Apple
Speaker 4:  Often puts stuff in their devices and doesn't even mention it.
Speaker 4:  Even when the tear downs reveal that it's there, whatever, until they're
Speaker 4:  ready to light it up. And here they put it on the slide and in the
Speaker 4:  press release there has to be some plan.
Speaker 4:  I just cannot figure out what it's like. Not even a hypothesis that
Speaker 4:  begins to make sense outside of Dan's kids need to light up
Speaker 4:  their Nana leaf bulbs even faster than they were doing before. That's it.
Speaker 4:  That's what I got. We're doing an entire hour with Jen on the Thread radio
Speaker 4:  and the 15 Pro.
Speaker 6:  I am so bewildered by all of that. I can't, my head hurts. Yeah. So bad.
Speaker 4:  So We just moved. So like I'm buying all this stuff and it's like, this is
Speaker 4:  the worst time to buy smart home stuff. Like all of it is inherently
Speaker 4:  obsolete right now.
Speaker 5:  No. So the move is you buy stuff that is supported by a hub because the hub
Speaker 5:  will get upgraded and then all the devices that connect to that hub will
Speaker 5:  carry along with it. It's the individual devices that are a nightmare.
Speaker 6:  This explains why I have like five hue bulbs just sitting
Speaker 6:  in a, sitting in a box. Because once I knew, but
Speaker 5:  You works on a hub and it's also bulletproof for lizza. No,
Speaker 6:  No, no. The hub does not work in my house because the router is in a closet.
Speaker 6:  So I was like, You know, I will eventually move and then I will unpack
Speaker 6:  these five bulbs for some future time.
Speaker 4:  I'm saying if, if we end up with door locks or require external hub like
Speaker 4:  that something bad has happened in my life. Right. Like
Speaker 4:  that's a real issue. I don't think that's gonna happen. I'm just saying
Speaker 4:  basically you're ready for the next two years of The Vergecast to be
Speaker 4:  nightmare Smart Home integration stories. You
Speaker 5:  Like complaining about the smart home? Yes. Because
Speaker 4:  It's just, it's so not ready.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it, it feels like it's gotten worse
Speaker 4:  But the iPhone 15 Pro is mysteriously ready
Speaker 4:  because it has a Thread radio in it. And I don't know why
Speaker 5:  It's matter ready? If
Speaker 4:  You know why, let me know something will happen. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  If you've got an interesting idea, let us
Speaker 4:  Know. All right. We gotta take a break and be asked to complain about the
Speaker 4:  watches. We'll be right back.
Speaker 13:  Wait, are you gaming on a Chromebook?
Speaker 14:  Yeah, it's got a high res 120 hertz display plus this
Speaker 14:  killer R G B keyboard. And I can access thousands of games anytime,
Speaker 14:  anywhere.
Speaker 13:  Stop playing what? Get outta here, huh? Yeah. I want you to
Speaker 13:  stop playing and get outta here so I can game on that Chromebook.
Speaker 14:  Got it.
Speaker 14:  Go discover the ultimate cloud gaming machine,
Speaker 14:  a new kind of Chromebook.
Speaker 15:  This episode is brought to you by Google. The Google cybersecurity
Speaker 15:  certificate provides the necessary skills to begin a career in
Speaker 15:  cybersecurity visit safety.google/cyber
Speaker 15:  workforce today.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back.
Speaker 4:  Where, where do you wanna start? V I know you got feelings, you've been pent
Speaker 4:  up over there.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so I think a lot of my problems this year is that the
Speaker 6:  smartwatch updates across the board have been so iterative. So the one I'm
Speaker 6:  actually looking most forward to is the Pixel Watch two, because it has the
Speaker 6:  most room to grow. But everything else is like, I think I wrote a blog
Speaker 6:  and it was buckle up buckles. We're gonna have some
Speaker 6:  iterative smartwatch updates. And this is the definition
Speaker 6:  of iterative
Speaker 4:  By the way. Our internal analytics suggest that if you put buckle up in a
Speaker 4:  headline, it bonkers over performs. Like I've heard Annie Hawkins
Speaker 4:  say the phrase people love buckling up before.
Speaker 6:  Well that explains it. 'cause that that blog did do well. So yeah.
Speaker 6:  So You know, I I was, I was there and people were like, what's new about
Speaker 6:  this watch? And it's like, well not much. Yeah. Like on the surface,
Speaker 6:  at least like on the inside after, after kind of checking it out and thinking
Speaker 6:  about what the new features are there, it feels like there is
Speaker 6:  stuff happening, but none of it is apparent on the surface level.
Speaker 6:  So if you look at the Apple Watch series nine, the most I can say is
Speaker 6:  that it now comes in Barbie pink, which I love. But looking at it, it
Speaker 6:  looks like the series eight,
Speaker 4:  Which
Speaker 5:  Looked like the series seven, which
Speaker 6:  Looked like the series, the seven series six. No, no, no. That there's, there's
Speaker 6:  a slightly thinner bezel from
Speaker 4:  Hey.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So
Speaker 5:  Ignoring thinner bezels looked like the series six. Yes. Which looked like
Speaker 5:  the series five, which looked like a series four.
Speaker 6:  It it, it hasn't really changed in terms of looks, it gets incrementally
Speaker 6:  larger when they're like, ah, screens, let's make them slightly larger. And
Speaker 6:  then You know the Ultra two. I actually got told to put my original Ultra
Speaker 6:  away because they were afraid I was going to lose it.
Speaker 6:  That's how similar it looks like to the Ultra two. Wow. So
Speaker 6:  they were like, we just wanna make sure you don't lose your watch. And it
Speaker 6:  was like, well I have this nomad glow in the dark band on, so there's no
Speaker 6:  way I'm losing this. And they're
Speaker 4:  Like, man, there pick pockets here. Yeah. On the demo floor.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I get where they were coming from though. 'cause I was holding the,
Speaker 6:  the Ultra in my hand and I was like, I think this Ultra is lighter. The Ultra
Speaker 6:  two is lighter. And and this woman was looking at me and she's like, I think
Speaker 6:  it's your stroke. Which is their, which is their way of telling me that it's,
Speaker 6:  it's not, it's the same. Yeah. It's basically the same body. So I was like,
Speaker 6:  okay cool. And You know with the Ultra
Speaker 6:  two there was at least the rumor that it was gonna come in a darker color.
Speaker 6:  That that's not the case. It is the same titanium color because titanium
Speaker 6:  is hard to make different colors. So I just don't think they were, they were
Speaker 6:  really gonna do that with this one. But You know it,
Speaker 6:  it basically comes down to there's a new chip. Yeah, there's a new chip And
Speaker 6:  it's been a while since there was a new chip. And the new chip will enable
Speaker 6:  more things. What more things? Well it's all gonna be in the
Speaker 6:  background so you probably will notice how much more convenient
Speaker 6:  everything is gonna be for you. But it will be, it's like Siri will
Speaker 6:  understand you more and it'll do everything lies.
Speaker 4:  They were like, there's nothing that understand using an on-device transformer
Speaker 4:  model, which is as close as they got to saying ai. It said machine learning
Speaker 4:  a lot, but no AI except for one mention of transformer model in the Siri
Speaker 4:  section.
Speaker 6:  So yeah, so Siri is supposed to do things on device meaning, so like right
Speaker 6:  now if you are in your laundry room and it's in the basement and you
Speaker 6:  don't have your phone with you and you say, Siri set my timer for five minutes
Speaker 6:  from my laundry or whatever, it's not gonna work. Siri will be just like,
Speaker 6:  ha sorry, can't do that for you. And it's happened to me a lot of times.
Speaker 6:  But now supposedly Siri will be able to do that for you even if
Speaker 6:  you have no connection. Which You know if you think about it, that's actually
Speaker 6:  kind of convenient and you think about it in a way, it's like,
Speaker 6:  well didn't it always do that? And no, no, it's not something that they've
Speaker 6:  always done. But then at the same time you're like, okay well they're saying
Speaker 6:  Siri will have 25% better diction. I am gonna conduct
Speaker 6:  the longest sentence to test this with, with so many multi
Speaker 6:  syllables and probably an ethnic or international word thrown in there
Speaker 6:  just to like throw it off. 'cause there was a point in time where I said
Speaker 6:  Mahershala Ali a lot just to see whether Siri, would
Speaker 6:  Siri understand it? Just Siri. Yeah. She did not. Okay. It did
Speaker 4:  Not, don't gender the robot.
Speaker 6:  But I'm not gendering Siri. It did not understand that. Now it does. So I
Speaker 6:  can tell you it has improved over time. So You know I'm gonna,
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna You know. I will take suggestions for what ridiculous words I can
Speaker 6:  try and make. Yeah. Siri understand me with, but You know there,
Speaker 6:  there's supposedly that's what's gonna happen. And later on in the year,
Speaker 6:  Siri is gonna be able to answer your health data. Which I don't know how
Speaker 6:  I feel about,
Speaker 4:  Do you see on the, the, the You know the, the flying things you could
Speaker 4:  say to Siri about health data. And one of them was like, Siri, I weigh this
Speaker 4:  much today. And it's like sociopath, that's sociopath stuff.
Speaker 4:  If you're just announcing to your watch how much you weigh every day, like
Speaker 4:  nope. Again, something has gone wrong.
Speaker 6:  Some of that is like they're thinking like, can we do this?
Speaker 6:  Not whether we should. Yeah. Like I don't think you should necessarily be
Speaker 6:  being like, Siri log my weight as X pounds or
Speaker 6:  kilograms.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I I I didn't purchase a connected scale. I bought a new Apple watch
Speaker 4:  to which I announced my weight every day.
Speaker 4:  But that stuff is like interesting, right? It's all background. The the
Speaker 4:  processor's more powerful. They're doing more local processing of stuff.
Speaker 5:  It also enables some other things. It
Speaker 6:  Does enable some other things like double tap or as I
Speaker 5:  Like to call it pinchy pinch.
Speaker 6:  Pinchy pinch. It's the pinchy pinch. They
Speaker 4:  Rejected that one. They didn't, that was on whiteboard at Apple Park. They
Speaker 5:  Didn't, they didn't like that one. But I like it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, no pinchy pinch. That's actually like they're saying it's new. It's
Speaker 6:  not really new because they introduced assistive touch a couple years ago,
Speaker 6:  which is an accessibility feature which lets you control the
Speaker 6:  watch one-handed and now they're just kind of bringing it to the
Speaker 6:  masses, which in my view proves that accessible design benefits
Speaker 6:  everybody but You know. So you, you can do a little pinchy pinch
Speaker 6:  motion and you'll be able to do all the primary actions of
Speaker 6:  your watch single-handed. So someone calls you, you're washing your ditches,
Speaker 6:  you can pinchy pinch official term, you can pinchy pinch and
Speaker 6:  answer the phone call or You know you, let's say set up
Speaker 6:  your camera and you wanna take a photo, you can now pinchy pinch and control
Speaker 6:  the shutter. Cool. If you You know watch OSS 10 has the new
Speaker 6:  widget stacks. 'cause it's all about widgets. So you can scroll through your
Speaker 6:  wi your widgets by pinching. So it essentially
Speaker 6:  becomes a one-handed device because You know you wear it on one wrist, you
Speaker 6:  have to use your other hand to to use it. But now you don't have
Speaker 4:  To do that. Incredible moment of the keynote when Jeff Williams said, this
Speaker 4:  is great for those moments when your other hand is occupied.
Speaker 4:  No, no further details. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  No examples of
Speaker 4:  What it can be occupied with but, and it's like, well you're just waving
Speaker 4:  your watch hand around and then this hand's busy. And I was like, okay.
Speaker 4:  Incredible thing to say out loud. You're the co again of the richest, the
Speaker 4:  c o o of the richest company in the world. And you're like, You know a problem.
Speaker 4:  I have a lot. One hand's busy. It's like weird. It's
Speaker 4:  weird. It's weird all the way around. And I was like, You know what? Like
Speaker 4:  that's better than using my nose, which is what I have been doing this whole
Speaker 4:  time. That's
Speaker 6:  It is, it is better than that. 'cause like we have all gone like, ah crap,
Speaker 6:  someone's calling me like Yep. Stick your nose into the, into the watch.
Speaker 6:  So it, it is better. I I do have some questions about how
Speaker 6:  intuitive it'll be for everyone because with assistive touch you're basically
Speaker 6:  being very specific about what these actions are doing. This is meant to
Speaker 6:  be more contextual. So they're kind of making assumptions
Speaker 6:  as to what you are going to think when you, when it comes time to
Speaker 6:  pinchy pinch. And I don't know that everyone has the same thoughts.
Speaker 6:  They did tell me that some aspects will be customizable. So when you are
Speaker 6:  going to do your music, not everyone has the same thought about whether it's
Speaker 6:  going to play pause or skip forward because
Speaker 6:  these are different assumptions we have from other devices. So that at least
Speaker 6:  will be customizable. There's another one that I forget what will
Speaker 6:  be customizable but eh You know. So that, that's cool on a
Speaker 6:  very nerd level. I find it cool that it does not have to be your index finger.
Speaker 6:  You can use your middle finger or your ring
Speaker 4:  Finger. Oh that's important. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's very important. 'cause I was like, hmm, yeah, what if you don't have
Speaker 6:  an index finger, which is You know some, some people don't have index
Speaker 6:  fingers. So that at least is neat
Speaker 6:  and I think it will be kind of cool once you get used
Speaker 6:  to using it. But you do have to get used to using it. I did the demo like
Speaker 6:  six different times on the demo floor and for the first few times
Speaker 6:  I was just aggressively pinching likes.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 5:  Not, the thing that makes it hard like initially is the watch has to be awake.
Speaker 5:  So you have to do the gesture to wake it up, then you pinchy pinch and then
Speaker 5:  it, then it works more reliably. But, but if you're, if the watch isn't awake,
Speaker 5:  you'll just be pinching. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  That that was me. I was just pinching and I was like, why isn't it working?
Speaker 6:  And they're like, oh, you have to do the gesture to wake it up and then you
Speaker 6:  can pinch. Yeah. But then I was only pinching once and not
Speaker 6:  double pinching. So it has to be a double,
Speaker 5:  It's it's not a pinch, it's a pinchy pinch.
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 4:  A pinchy.
Speaker 7:  Are they gonna add like
Speaker 6:  A double?
Speaker 4:  It's like brute forcing this into reality and making it, I don't want
Speaker 4:  you to,
Speaker 6:  I mean it, I I am just thinking of myself. Eventually I will be double wristing.
Speaker 6:  'cause I'm always double wristing except for right now. But, and I'm just
Speaker 6:  gonna be sitting here just thinking, oh my gosh,
Speaker 7:  I can't wait.
Speaker 4:  So this is not You know there, their whole thing is this is because the SS
Speaker 4:  nine chip we're doing sensor fusion. We're measuring your blood flow.
Speaker 4:  I dunno about that. Well,
Speaker 5:  So I mean that is how it's worried. It's, it's monitoring the muscles in
Speaker 5:  your forearm that react when you do these gestures with your fingers. So
Speaker 5:  that, that is why it works with your other fingers. And like they said, You
Speaker 5:  know you could do it with a pinky, but depending on certain people the way
Speaker 5:  their arms are, it may not work as reliably. And that
Speaker 5:  most people, it works reliably with the index finger or the middle finger.
Speaker 5:  But it's, but that's what it's monitoring. It's monitoring the blood flow
Speaker 5:  through your wrist in your forearm.
Speaker 4:  So is the heart rate sensor on all the time? Yes, yes. Yes.
Speaker 5:  At well when it's awake
Speaker 4:  They light up the heart rate sensor.
Speaker 5:  There's, and yeah, it lights up the heart rate sensor and then it's ready
Speaker 5:  to, to, I think this is probably why it doesn't work when it's not awake.
Speaker 5:  One probably to stop false triggers, but also it does have to light up
Speaker 5:  a bunch of sensors in order to detect.
Speaker 4:  And so this, but this is the argument of the S nine, right? We need the gyroscope,
Speaker 4:  we need the heart heart rate sensor, which they hadn't mentioned specifically.
Speaker 4:  That's really cool to know. And then we're doing sensor fusion and machine
Speaker 4:  learning. Yeah. And we're detecting a pinch.
Speaker 5:  That's what, that's what the S nine enables and that's what all the extra
Speaker 5:  cores. It's got a four core neural co-processor, whatever they call
Speaker 5:  it, a sip as opposed instead of an S O C that we're used to hearing from
Speaker 5:  other devices.
Speaker 4:  SS o C is everything is on the same chip. D the SIP is
Speaker 4:  a package. So you have multiple chips integrated package stacked and assembled
Speaker 4:  into a package. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So they keep referring to the SS nine as a sip, but it's got all those
Speaker 5:  and it's, and like this is why you have a neural processor on your wrist
Speaker 5:  to figure out these kinds of features.
Speaker 6:  Also more power efficient. But You know, apple has this
Speaker 6:  tendency of like with power efficiency to be like and So, we will do
Speaker 6:  more things with the power efficiency that we have instead of giving what
Speaker 6:  some people want, which is longer battery life. So You know,
Speaker 4:  You know
Speaker 5:  The screen gets brighter, the screen
Speaker 6:  Gets,
Speaker 4:  Gets
Speaker 5:  Brighter, made the screen goes up to 2000 NIS on the S nine now
Speaker 6:  On the, on the series nine. And we
Speaker 5:  Saw a demo compared to the eight and it
Speaker 6:  Was noticeable.
Speaker 5:  Noticeably different. Noticeable.
Speaker 6:  It's noticeable
Speaker 5:  When it's at Peak prices.
Speaker 6:  So like the original Ultra goes up to 2000 niss. Yeah. And when you're outside,
Speaker 6:  that's quite bright. And now the Ultra two goes up to 3000. So
Speaker 6:  I'm just like, wow.
Speaker 4:  Could you see that? Was that, that seems like a difficult thing to see, so
Speaker 4:  I'm not sure outside. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  You need the older model right next to it at Max brightness
Speaker 6:  to really understand it. 'cause when I was looking at the SS nine in the
Speaker 6:  perfect lighting in, in heaven's Steve Jobs theater, I was like,
Speaker 6:  I I I can't tell the difference. But when they put the two next to each other,
Speaker 6:  then you could see that. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Well they, they put, they, they, they demoed an SS eight that had been tricked
Speaker 5:  into full brightness and an S nine that had been tricked into full brightness
Speaker 5:  next to each other. And that's when you could see it. And the idea being
Speaker 5:  that if you are in an environment where you need this brightness, that's
Speaker 5:  where it'll come help you. But ultimately it just looked nicer when it's
Speaker 5:  brighter.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah it does. Yeah. But that's brighter screens
Speaker 6:  and You know, they always say the same battery life, it's never the same.
Speaker 6:  Like with smartwatches, your individual usage really does kind of
Speaker 6:  impact how much mileage you're going to get. But when, when Apple
Speaker 6:  says 18 hour battery life, like the series four Hmm. That was maybe
Speaker 6:  like 24 hours Series five that was Hmm. Maybe 20
Speaker 6:  hours. Like you can get more, apple is very conservative
Speaker 6:  with their battery life estimates. So when they say 18 hours, I, I'm
Speaker 6:  really gonna see how how far you can push that 18 hours for the original,
Speaker 6:  not the original for the regular one, but for the Ultra two they said it
Speaker 6:  was 36. Yeah. And I just You know I have gotten as far as 60 hours
Speaker 6:  on the Ultra without doing anything going on
Speaker 6:  runs. Like I did a half marathon, a slow half marathon. I
Speaker 6:  was not fast that day and I think I only lost 15% battery.
Speaker 6:  Wow. With no low power mode enabled. So I'm really
Speaker 6:  curious to see whether the, the extra power efficiency
Speaker 6:  will push the Ultra into the 70, 72
Speaker 6:  hour territory. Because I haven't, which
Speaker 4:  Is what they're claiming for low power mode, which
Speaker 6:  Is what they're claiming for low power mode. But I think, I think
Speaker 6:  depending on how you use it, because let's be real, not everyone buying
Speaker 6:  an Ultra is the weather beaten explorer athlete that they
Speaker 6:  No, they said
Speaker 4:  This. So you wrote a piece that was like, who is the Ultra for? And I think
Speaker 4:  Chef Williams read it
Speaker 4:  because in his presentation he was like, here's who the Apple Watch Ultra
Speaker 4:  is for. He said, did you catch this? He said it out loud. Yeah. And his
Speaker 4:  answer was, it's for people who want a big display in the best battery life.
Speaker 4:  And he was not like an ocean explorer. It's like, it was like the biggest
Speaker 4:  display and the best battery life.
Speaker 6:  Because I, I'm gonna be real, like I go to, I am not the most athletic
Speaker 6:  person on the planet. I would consider myself a weekend warrior, a reformed
Speaker 6:  couch potato. Like I, I, I do do a lot of exercise. I
Speaker 6:  exercise probably like six outta seven days of the week. But I'm not
Speaker 6:  athletically gifted and I never will be. But I do go to like
Speaker 6:  run groups. I have friends who are athletically gifted and absolutely none
Speaker 6:  of them are interested in the Ultra. They're just not, they're like, I grab
Speaker 6:  my Garmin and my Garmin has 40,000 metrics that the, that
Speaker 6:  the Apple watch will never have. And they're very like, happy with that or
Speaker 6:  a regular Apple watch. So thinking about that, I was just like,
Speaker 6:  I don't think that the Ultra is really
Speaker 6:  for those extreme athletes until you can be like, oh yeah,
Speaker 6:  the Ultra marathon or you can run 60 hours. I don't know why you would want
Speaker 6:  to, but I know these people do run 60 hours and you won't need to
Speaker 6:  carry your charger on you until, until it can legitimately do that. I don't
Speaker 6:  think that the Ultra is really for that extreme
Speaker 6:  explorer. So that was a question I did have. Like who is this
Speaker 6:  watch for? And the facetious answer that I get is, is
Speaker 6:  for people who wanna flex, it's for people who have $800
Speaker 6:  and yes and no. Right? Because,
Speaker 4:  And on the iPhone side, if you have $800, you get, you're like, you
Speaker 4:  get last year's garbage
Speaker 6:  Year's garbage. Here's
Speaker 4:  Shit we had in the part spin. You must be two. Yeah, exactly. This is a,
Speaker 4:  this is an eighties Pontiac
Speaker 4:  made of leftover Cadillac parts. Like that's what we're doing here.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Oh, the other thing that the Ultra that, that they did demo for us
Speaker 6:  on the Ultra two was this automatic night mode. And I was
Speaker 6:  like, woo. This was was like a parlor trick that I should not have been as
Speaker 6:  excited to see as I was. But if you turn off the light, it'll automatically
Speaker 6:  switch into that red mode and you turn the light
Speaker 5:  On. This is because the changes with Watch West 10. Yes. So you used to on
Speaker 5:  watch West nine with the first Ultra, you use the digital crown to switch
Speaker 5:  between the special watch face between its night mode reds, which
Speaker 5:  you, you can't do on that watch face Neli. You need to use a special watch
Speaker 5:  face. Yeah. But with watch West 10, if you spin the crown, you go into the
Speaker 5:  widgets. So you couldn't do that anymore. So basically they're using the
Speaker 5:  light sensor to know when the lights are out and switch into the dark box.
Speaker 6:  But that, that actually is something that I'm like, ah, there we go.
Speaker 5:  And to be clear, this is coming to the first Ultra as well. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Yes. It's, it's so,
Speaker 5:  It's not not exclusive.
Speaker 6:  I'm just gonna complain about smart watches for a hot second, remembering
Speaker 6:  what comes on, watch OSS 10 to which watches
Speaker 6:  and which is exclusive to what, on what skews
Speaker 6:  is, is just like, I need a whole other co-processor brain to remember that.
Speaker 6:  You need a sip, I need a sip. I need a sip to, to memorize all that stuff.
Speaker 6:  SIP
Speaker 5:  Is something,
Speaker 4:  But is a new, there's a new watch face. You know watch faces. Yep. Modular
Speaker 4:  Ultra. Is that coming to this Ultra?
Speaker 6:  Yes, it is coming.
Speaker 5:  Watch 10. Yep. There's no real reason for anyone to upgrade
Speaker 5:  from the first Ultra to the
Speaker 4:  Second. Well, it's the Flex Dan, I mean, other than
Speaker 5:  Flex, you get the pinchy pinch and you get the 3000 knits
Speaker 5:  and that's really it. Oh,
Speaker 6:  And the new U two
Speaker 5:  Chip and the U two chip for
Speaker 6:  Precision finding. Yeah. Which my fellow A D H
Speaker 6:  D can't remember where you put anything. Hell yeah, it's, but you
Speaker 6:  have to get an iPhone 15 for that to actually work. Yeah. But You know, they
Speaker 6:  showed it to us and it was like, oh, it'll tell you exactly which direction
Speaker 6:  to go, how far to go to find your phone, which I'm super excited
Speaker 6:  about because I have lost my phone in a fridge before.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's basically the same experience. You get tracking an air tag with
Speaker 5:  an iPhone. Yes. Except you're tracking an iPhone with your Apple watch.
Speaker 6:  It's a little slower. I did notice that, because when you do, when you do
Speaker 6:  do it with the air tag, it's like pretty quick. This, you can only track
Speaker 6:  your iPhone 15. You can't track like an air
Speaker 6:  tag that's gonna be there. So it, it does need to have that. But I was like,
Speaker 6:  yes. For me specifically, I use the find my phone
Speaker 6:  function at least 20 to 30 times a day. So yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's it. But the watch, it's a, they upgraded a chip, they made things
Speaker 4:  a little bit brighter. They
Speaker 5:  Did not make, they added
Speaker 4:  The double
Speaker 5:  Tap titanium series nine, which they
Speaker 4:  Did not make a titanium series nine. Really. It's interesting that the double
Speaker 4:  tap is hardware locked. These new ones. Do we think that the old phones,
Speaker 4:  the old watches can't do 'em?
Speaker 5:  That is their line, right? That their line is that the S nine enables this
Speaker 5:  feature because of its neural engine and because it's able to take all that
Speaker 5:  data from the sensors and spit out something smart. And
Speaker 4:  Yet if you turn on an assistive, touch it like,
Speaker 6:  So I think the part of that is the, the contextualizing of it so that
Speaker 6:  it's built into the system. Whereas assistive touch is something
Speaker 6:  that you have to go in and enable. And there is kind of a learning
Speaker 6:  curve with assistive touch. So there's that. There's
Speaker 6:  also more customizability with assistive touch. So yeah, I
Speaker 6:  don't know, but yeah. Yeah, like I could see
Speaker 6:  an argument for that just because your wrist is a very noisy place in terms
Speaker 6:  of sensors. It's actually not great for heart rate
Speaker 6:  accuracy. The, I think the most accurate place is the underside of your finger,
Speaker 6:  where your ear, so on that front, if you want
Speaker 6:  it to be accurate, if you want it to be something that a lot of people can
Speaker 6:  use reliably with multiple fingers, I could see an argument for
Speaker 6:  needing a more powerful sip for that. But eh,
Speaker 6:  yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. That's, that's what I'm gonna say.
Speaker 4:  That's good. No, that's well remembered.
Speaker 4:  I think that's Watch we didn't say the prices. The Apple Watch series
Speaker 4:  9 3 9 3 9 9. The Ultra seven nine
Speaker 4:  You know if you wanna flex. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  If you wanna flex. They did not drop the price of the se. Some folks were
Speaker 5:  hypothesizing that they might drop the SE price. That did happen, but
Speaker 6:  They dropped it last year. It went from two. But You
Speaker 5:  Know, I think there's an argument that they should, that they, there's room
Speaker 5:  to drop it now that the series three is dead and gone. There's nothing at
Speaker 5:  that 1 99 price point.
Speaker 4:  All this stuff hits September 22nd. Yep. All of it is pre-orders on
Speaker 4:  Friday. Yeah. iOS 17 comes out September 18th. Maca
Speaker 4:  Sonoma, September 26th. And then also the 22nd are the
Speaker 4:  USB C AirPods Pro, which have
Speaker 4:  mysterious and another mystery. They have a new mysterious
Speaker 4:  Lossless audio feature that for the Vision Pro only works with the Vision
Speaker 4:  Pro. Yes. It is a quote, groundbreaking new
Speaker 4:  wireless audio protocol and quote, revolutionary new format
Speaker 4:  that allows 20 bit 48 kilohertz audio transmission from the
Speaker 4:  Vision Pro to the AirPods Pro. So the
Speaker 4:  goodbye Bluetooth. Get outta here. You old pirate.
Speaker 4:  Like
Speaker 5:  I wonder, I wonder if it is a, a modification or a form of Bluetooth. I think
Speaker 5:  if I had to like hypothesize as to like why it's an only on the Vision
Speaker 5:  Pro. I wonder if it's a distance thing. If you're wearing the AirPods and
Speaker 5:  the Vision Pro in your head, there's a maximum of six inches of distance
Speaker 5:  between the devices. Whereas if it's on your phone and the AirPods,
Speaker 5:  you've got a few feet between them and it can't maintain that Fidelity,
Speaker 4:  Who knows man, who knows
Speaker 5:  The phone's got a Thread radio man.
Speaker 4:  It's like there's just a lot of mysteries that Apple did not address today.
Speaker 4:  It obviously doesn't work with the iPhone. No Lossless audio from the AirPods
Speaker 4:  Pro. The old AirPods Pro don't get it.
Speaker 4:  And you cannot buy the USB C case for your old AirPods Pro. We were told
Speaker 4:  that it might be a quote service part, which is fascinating. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The precedence for it being sold separately was when they
Speaker 5:  moved, I think it was the AirPods two came out initially did not have
Speaker 5:  wireless charging and then they updated it to a wireless charging case. You
Speaker 5:  could just buy the case if you wanted, but it doesn't look like that's happening
Speaker 5:  with the USB C AirPods Pro two. Also notable the regular AirPods
Speaker 5:  three not getting USB C. We mentioned earlier the AirPods Max
Speaker 5:  not getting USB C, at least not today. So Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But the AirPods Pro also the 22nd with
Speaker 4:  USB C. Yes.
Speaker 5:  You can buy, this is mysterious. If you have an AirPods Pro two today, you
Speaker 5:  can buy New AirPods Pro two.
Speaker 5:  That's good. And I don't know, they've been out for a while. Maybe your battery's
Speaker 5:  not lasting. All
Speaker 4:  Right. I think that's it. We've really bled this one dry. We've
Speaker 4:  talked about every bento on the Bento box. It was, I mean, it was a good
Speaker 4:  event. It was. It was fun to be there and like do our thing. When I say that
Speaker 4:  Bento boxes don't have a lot of stuff on them, the iPhone 15 Bento box has
Speaker 4:  five G on it.
Speaker 5:  Oh no.
Speaker 4:  And it's like you guys like, what are we doing here? But yeah, ITER
Speaker 4:  updates all around, but I think solid. I think U S PC stuff is gonna go over
Speaker 4:  well. But that's it. This is the beginning of just a bonkers
Speaker 4:  two months in tech basically. September, October are gonna be nuts. We'll
Speaker 4:  be back on Friday. Talk about the Google antitrust case and everything else
Speaker 4:  that's happening. And then it is just a sprint to the finish line of fall
Speaker 4:  from here on out. We are gonna be so dead at the end of this. It's gonna
Speaker 4:  be good though. This is what we're here for. This is what you signed up for.
Speaker 5:  It is true. It's why we, it's why we, it's why we wake up in the morning.
Speaker 4:  It's nuts. It's clear
Speaker 5:  Brunch. Just year. It's very
Speaker 6:  Busy. It's, I feel like there was at least like a day you
Speaker 4:  Could breathe. No, in September last year. Amazon Devices and services event.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, let's do it. Get in there. Microsoft
Speaker 5:  Service Event. Yeah. Meta Connect. Pixel
Speaker 4:  Watch too.
Speaker 5:  Let's not forget about Code Watch
Speaker 6:  Too. I'm excited
Speaker 4:  For that. Thread radio's everywhere for no inherent reason. Alright,
Speaker 4:  that's it. That's The. Vergecast. Rock and Roll.
Speaker 16:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 16:  us an email at Vergecast at The Verge dot com. The Vergecast is
Speaker 16:  a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast Network. The show is
Speaker 16:  produced by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 16:  Our editorial director is Brooke Miners. That's it. We'll see you next week.