# Transcript
ID: b6442fee-776d-4107-b1f3-b7084babee89
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Fortnite, GTA VI, and the fate of AAA games
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/8498057339843146616/-1450850979896007857/s93290-US-4598s-1700479345.mp3
Description: In episode three of our video game miniseries, The Verge's David Pierce and Polygon's Russ Frushtick and Chris Plante discuss the state of the industry's blockbuster games like Grand Theft Auto, Call of Duty, Overwatch, Fortnite, and others — and what they signal for the future of gaming.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  This podcast is brought to you by Meta Quest. Three, the new mixed reality
Speaker 2:  headset from Meta. Expand your world in ways you never thought possible with
Speaker 2:  the new Meta Quest. Three, put on the most powerful quest yet and
Speaker 2:  jump into fully immersive games like Assassin's Creed Nexus, or blend
Speaker 2:  virtual elements into your surroundings in games like Stranger Things vr.
Speaker 2:  With over 500 titles, it's easy to dive into whatever you're
Speaker 2:  into. Expand your world with Meta Quest three. See child safety guidance
Speaker 2:  online accounts for 10 and up certain apps, games and experiences may be
Speaker 2:  suitable for a more mature audience. Learn more at Meta dot com.
Speaker 4:  Welcome To. The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of DLCs. I'm your friend,
Speaker 4:  David Pierce. And this is the third and final episode in our miniseries about
Speaker 4:  the future of gaming. We've talked about handheld gaming and why consoles
Speaker 4:  like the Switch and the Steam deck might just be the future of everything.
Speaker 4:  We've talked about how to emulate and preserve old games
Speaker 4:  and why that matters in a really important way. And today we're gonna talk
Speaker 4:  about big games, the biggest games, games like Fortnite and
Speaker 4:  Call of Duty and Roblox and Madden and Assassin's
Speaker 4:  Creed. The kinds of games that even people who don't care about games know
Speaker 4:  about. These games are so culturally important and
Speaker 4:  economically outrageous that it often feels like as
Speaker 4:  those games go, so goes the whole gaming industry. But those
Speaker 4:  games are changing. The way that they get made is changing. The way that
Speaker 4:  they get sold is changing. Everything about them is changing. So we're gonna
Speaker 4:  try to figure out today what happens to the biggest games and
Speaker 4:  what it means for all the rest of the games and for us who play them. My
Speaker 4:  colleagues from Polygon, Chris Plant and Russ Frushtick are back with me.
Speaker 4:  The way this is gonna work is we're gonna talk it out a little bit and then
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna go do some research, talk to some people and then present them
Speaker 4:  with what I've discovered and see if I've learned anything at all. Also,
Speaker 4:  before we get into it, I just wanna say we've had this crazy run of
Speaker 4:  miniseries over the last few months. I know it's been a lot of
Speaker 4:  Vergecast and I'm so grateful to all of you who have listened to all these
Speaker 4:  episodes and gone with me and us on these weird adventures into
Speaker 4:  AI and connectivity and gaming. We've had a ton of fun making these
Speaker 4:  episodes. I know it's been a lot. The. Vergecast Feed is gonna go mostly
Speaker 4:  back to normal now, but seriously, thank you to everyone who has sent nice
Speaker 4:  emails, who has called in with thoughts on the hotline. We're very grateful.
Speaker 4:  It's been incredibly fun. With that, let's just get into it. Russ and Chris
Speaker 4:  are here. Here we go.
Speaker 4:  Chris, plant Welcome back. Hey, thank you. Russ Frushtick, Welcome back.
Speaker 4:  Thank you. Thank you. This is the third of our three episodes. It's been
Speaker 4:  very fun so far. I have learned an enormous amount about the gaming world
Speaker 4:  that I did not know already. And for this episode, we've kind of
Speaker 4:  noodled around like the edges of what is coming for gaming
Speaker 4:  in the last two episodes. But this time we're gonna talk about like the
Speaker 4:  biggest games and game makers on planet
Speaker 4:  Earth because we've gone through this huge transition in so much
Speaker 4:  of entertainment, whether it's the way that we consume music or the way that
Speaker 4:  we consume TV and how Netflix changed the whole business of how
Speaker 4:  television and movies get made and all that stuff. And what you guys have
Speaker 4:  told me sort of in the planning process for this is that gaming is in the
Speaker 4:  middle or at the beginning of a similar transition. That the way
Speaker 4:  we think about what games are and how we buy them and the biggest
Speaker 4:  names of all of them is set to shift and shift fairly
Speaker 4:  quickly. Is Russ, you're nodding? Is that a fair way of thinking about it?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, absolutely. We're already seeing it. The rise of the subscription
Speaker 5:  model for game ownership with the rise of something
Speaker 5:  like Game Pass means that you can pay your $15 a month,
Speaker 5:  whatever it is for a ton of games and
Speaker 5:  you don't actually end up buying any physical games. You end up
Speaker 5:  just like kind of renting them in a way through these services. And this
Speaker 5:  has already been a huge priority for companies like
Speaker 5:  Microsoft. And you're gonna see it continue to increase over time.
Speaker 4:  I'm just sort of trying to think this through and like I think one of the
Speaker 4:  things that's happened in Hollywood is basically the whole middle fell
Speaker 4:  out, right? You can either make a giant, like a Avenger style blockbuster
Speaker 4:  or you can make a relatively small budget thing or you can make a TV
Speaker 4:  show, right? Like we've, we've figured out how to do sort of prestige tv.
Speaker 4:  But if you are in the business of making like event movies, which I would
Speaker 4:  say is probably the closest thing to AAA game in that space.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, sure. Like a Marvel, big Marvel movie. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's not a perfect analogy, but it's close enough. There is nothing
Speaker 4:  in the middle anymore. You either have to spend very little and hope or
Speaker 4:  spend a gigantic amount of money on super safe IP and that's all
Speaker 4:  that's left. Is that where we're headed in video games too,
Speaker 6:  Kind of though with maybe a, an adjustment to like the framing of the middle.
Speaker 6:  There's a lot of middle now. We just don't watch it there. There's
Speaker 6:  like so much middle, there's You know Netflix has a
Speaker 6:  gajillion middle productions and they come out every week and they don't
Speaker 6:  even market them and they, they're not
Speaker 6:  particularly good. And it used to be that you like would go to a movie
Speaker 6:  theater and people had to put effort into the middle and now the middle is
Speaker 6:  just like filler.
Speaker 4:  You could like make a cultural moment out of the middle in the past. And
Speaker 4:  I think that is long gone in Hollywood.
Speaker 5:  Yes. On the gaming side, the middle used to be the like
Speaker 5:  10 to $20 million game that took, let's say three years
Speaker 5:  to make and came out and did pretty well. And Activision
Speaker 5:  would put out a bunch of those. EA would put out a bunch of those. And what
Speaker 5:  you're seeing is these big studios because of the ex rising
Speaker 5:  expenses of game making at that level, yeah they are unwilling
Speaker 5:  to do those smaller investments because they're really sinking hundreds of
Speaker 5:  millions of dollars into the big franchises, the Diablos of the world, the
Speaker 5:  GTAs of the world, and they just can't afford to focus
Speaker 5:  on those small potential wins. 'cause the losses can be huge
Speaker 5:  even for those like mid range titles. So what you're seeing is, yeah,
Speaker 5:  the AAA and that's paired with the like indie world, which
Speaker 5:  can obviously be very low budget up to let's say two and
Speaker 5:  $3 million games. Which honestly these days is small in the way
Speaker 5:  that like an indie movie at two and $3 million is small. But
Speaker 4:  Then at the same time, it also seems like some of these companies that make
Speaker 4:  these huge AAA games are making fewer of them.
Speaker 4:  Like I, I feel like, and I can't prove this, maybe you guys would definitely
Speaker 4:  know better than I would, but I feel like the, the number of like big name
Speaker 4:  games that I've never heard of goes down every year. Yeah. That
Speaker 4:  it's, it's all games that I've been hearing about forever. It's all Assassin's
Speaker 4:  Creed, like EA just keeps running back the same six sports games. It does
Speaker 4:  every year. There's like a, there's a something three and a something four
Speaker 4:  and a something 11 that comes out every year. But I don't feel like there
Speaker 4:  are that many truly new things coming out
Speaker 4:  of these giant studios anymore. Is that true? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I, I think that this and to connect us to the middle, this
Speaker 6:  happened actually before streaming and this is the what the Call of
Speaker 6:  Duty Mass effect Madden era did to AAA
Speaker 6:  is You know when Fresh and I were starting and covering video games,
Speaker 6:  it wasn't unusual for Yu Bsof to try
Speaker 6:  a few different random things. You know they had, there was a time where
Speaker 6:  you had a new driver game and it played like Google Maps
Speaker 6:  meets racing or a new Sean White skateboarding game where
Speaker 6:  you could create rails out of like Green Goo and
Speaker 6:  they're just like, yeah, let's, let's put a mid-budget game and try it and
Speaker 6:  see where it goes. Along with all the license games, when
Speaker 6:  Call of Duty blew up Activision it felt like
Speaker 6:  had to basically shift all of its resources behind this
Speaker 6:  big bet. And they had that with Guitar Hero and they had that with Tony Hawk
Speaker 6:  all around kind of the same time. And as a result, everything else just,
Speaker 6:  there just weren't enough warm bodies to make the other stuff that's
Speaker 6:  at least how it felt You know if they wanted to get annual releases. So they
Speaker 6:  kind of created their bed and now they're having to sleep in it.
Speaker 6:  Is that, is that the metaphor? Is that the phrase? I think so, yeah. They
Speaker 6:  are now having to stick to these things because they're making
Speaker 6:  enough money that they can't stop doing it. But not so much that they can
Speaker 6:  like go and focus elsewhere. The other pickle that they have
Speaker 6:  is now with streaming and with some of these indie developers becoming indie
Speaker 6:  publishers and being able to like create more of these mid-budget games
Speaker 6:  is the general quality of video games right now is just very
Speaker 6:  high. So their fear is we have two games
Speaker 6:  out of the year we really need them to hit because they're gonna be
Speaker 6:  competing against hundreds. And once they do hit, we need to lock people
Speaker 6:  in. And that has just created this like bad bet after
Speaker 6:  bad bet they're, they're, they're making things harder and harder and harder
Speaker 6:  for themselves rather than looking at the industry and saying,
Speaker 6:  Hey, why don't we just do the thing that we're running from, we actually
Speaker 6:  are quite powerful. Why are we not putting out 20 or 30 games
Speaker 6:  a year? Why Devolver the indie publisher is out there
Speaker 6:  and just wasn't acquired at any point is confusing to say
Speaker 6:  the least.
Speaker 4:  Interesting. Okay. Is there a new generation of these like upstart companies
Speaker 4:  trying to do that? Like normally the way you would think it would work, right?
Speaker 4:  As these, these big companies get settled into their sort of small handful
Speaker 4:  of franchises like you're describing and then outta that comes a bunch of
Speaker 4:  new companies saying we have new ideas, we can build games faster, we have
Speaker 4:  new ways of doing it. We don't have all this tech debt, we don't have massive
Speaker 4:  companies we have to support, we can build the next thing. Is that
Speaker 4:  happening?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think it's happening. You know Plant mentioned Devolver,
Speaker 5:  which is one of the biggest indie studios publishing
Speaker 5:  studios in there. And I think all of that work that they
Speaker 5:  have is really talent acquisition. They go out, they see,
Speaker 5:  oh, here's this small indie developer that's basically been doing it solo
Speaker 5:  or with a team of three people or whatever. We're gonna give them that two
Speaker 5:  and $3 million budget and we like what they're doing so we're
Speaker 5:  gonna elevate that. And it becomes a decent sized hit. Like a death store
Speaker 5:  for example was an indie game that came out last year and and did pretty
Speaker 5:  well. So they are kind of curating that stuff. But because
Speaker 5:  of the nature of the expense of larger
Speaker 5:  game publishers having to make these big games, they can't
Speaker 5:  do that. Like EA can't be doing that. So they are focused instead
Speaker 5:  on the battlefields of the world and and their big franchises. So there is
Speaker 5:  this, this divide in terms of creating new ideas and
Speaker 5:  almost all of them are coming from the indie side.
Speaker 6:  You also mentioned the tech data of it all in the past being a big
Speaker 6:  publisher benefited from the fact that you had an internal engine like
Speaker 6:  EA had the frostbite engine or I think Ubisoft had, anvil was one they
Speaker 6:  used for a while I believe or don don't know.
Speaker 6:  One. Those engines just are often more frustrating than
Speaker 6:  Unreal or Unity or any of the indie
Speaker 6:  engines. So you have that like so much for it being You
Speaker 6:  know, like losing tech, you're, you're actually frustrated. You know you're
Speaker 6:  bringing on people who have to learn your new thing. Sure. And then two,
Speaker 6:  you're competing with people who have access to Unreal
Speaker 6:  and are perfectly fine using it. And when they go
Speaker 6:  out and hire people to work on it, people already know how to use those engines.
Speaker 6:  So it's all kind of inverted. It's actually just easier
Speaker 6:  for these these smaller and to mid-sized developers to work
Speaker 6:  because they're not married to all these kind of massive corporate
Speaker 6:  decisions that sound like they're money saves on paper but are
Speaker 6:  not actually beneficial to the people making the games.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Yeah. I later in this episode we're gonna do a bunch of 20, 24
Speaker 4:  predictions about kind of where all this is going. 'cause it does seem like
Speaker 4:  there are a bunch of things in other industries you can look at to see how
Speaker 4:  this might change. But also gaming we've learned is different in a lot of
Speaker 4:  ways and I think we're, we're gonna talk to some smart people but also just
Speaker 4:  spend some time the three of us trying to figure out where all this is going.
Speaker 4:  But before I run off and chase down some smart people about where we're going,
Speaker 4:  Chris, I want you to tell me why you wrote GTA six
Speaker 4:  in our Google Doc in large letters.
Speaker 6:  Yes. So this is the big question. This is the, the huge question I have for
Speaker 6:  you is GTA six gonna be the last mega
Speaker 6:  game. And I'm not talking about even AAA, I'm talking about
Speaker 6:  quadruple a i I we get You know one of these a year
Speaker 6:  maybe sort of games. And yet the big publishers
Speaker 6:  can't help themselves from continuing to chase these dreams.
Speaker 6:  And I wonder if GTA six we will see a change after that
Speaker 6:  if we've raised the cost of making games
Speaker 6:  so high and the risk so high that
Speaker 6:  people will have learned their lesson or if the opposite will
Speaker 6:  happen, which is despite all of the trouble we're seeing in the video game
Speaker 6:  industry financially, if GTA six will come out, it
Speaker 6:  will be a hit and then everybody will go, could be
Speaker 6:  me I that I could be that.
Speaker 4:  Well, so, okay, wait, explain this to me really fast because GTA five has
Speaker 4:  been out for good lord like 65 years at this point. Yeah. But GTA
Speaker 4:  six is like a, a sequel on top of sequels, on top of sequels. Like why is
Speaker 4:  Grand Theft Auto six different from say the new Call of Duty which I assume
Speaker 4:  will come out at at once a year every year until like the Heath he death
Speaker 4:  of the universe? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I mean you, you kind of said it. They don't put them out all the time. Okay.
Speaker 6:  They work on them until they are in their opinion just right.
Speaker 6:  And they seem to know quite well even if I don't always love every bit of
Speaker 6:  their games they sell extravagantly. It's hard to say with
Speaker 6:  GTA six 'cause we haven't seen much of it. Others, some some leaked gameplay
Speaker 6:  footage, right? That was very, very early. But there's also
Speaker 6:  questions around that game on its own. There's different management in charge
Speaker 6:  of this game than there has been in the past. I would say the first real
Speaker 6:  shakeup of of editorial direction for this game
Speaker 6:  in the entire series is lifetime. Hmm. So again, we have this game that
Speaker 6:  just embodies the mega budget game
Speaker 6:  and it has its own question marks around it. And I think a
Speaker 6:  lot of where we're at right now is based off of GTA Five's success and people
Speaker 6:  hoping that they can be that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Just to give a data point to that GTA five cost
Speaker 5:  around $260 million to produce. Wow. There have been recent
Speaker 5:  leaks like GTA six leaked of about a year ago
Speaker 5:  and as part of that leak there was some speculation that the games
Speaker 5:  development costs have overcome a billion dollars at this point.
Speaker 4:  Whoa. You know what this makes me think of is right before the second avatar
Speaker 4:  movie came out, James Cameron did an interview and said something to the
Speaker 4:  effect of like, this movie is gonna have to be the third biggest movie of
Speaker 4:  all time just to break even. And it's like at some point that's
Speaker 4:  a totally insane thing to say unless you're James Cameron, you, you've made
Speaker 4:  the other two biggest movies of all time and like I guess GTA six
Speaker 4:  is kind of in the same position. It's like if you're anyone other than the
Speaker 4:  people who make Grand Theft Auto, you might be outta your mind. But if anybody
Speaker 4:  has a chance to make that worthwhile, it's probably rockstar.
Speaker 6:  I guess like a thought to leave the listeners on who maybe don't follow games
Speaker 6:  closely because this might sound drained. How, how could we see the end of
Speaker 6:  AAA? And I'm not saying that there's a guarantee that that will happen at
Speaker 6:  all, but think about the Marvel era in the superhero era
Speaker 6:  that is coming to an end. It is at the very top of
Speaker 6:  pop culture until these increasingly big betts
Speaker 6:  start to like flop, right? And you get three or four of these in
Speaker 6:  a row and suddenly they're not making money and suddenly it's a bad
Speaker 6:  bet and the market signals that they're looking at other things. We
Speaker 6:  have Oppenheimer and Barbie, this You know Summer really popping off
Speaker 6:  in a lot of other movies and that's when things start to shift.
Speaker 6:  And that is a sort of shift that I am curious what it will
Speaker 6:  look like in the video game industry because it feels like we're heading
Speaker 6:  towards some sort of change. It's just hard to say what
Speaker 5:  It's, I mean you can look at it from a couple years ago at
Speaker 5:  Cyberpunks launch Cyberpunk launched, it was a total disaster. That game
Speaker 5:  was enormously expensive to produce. They've since brought it back from the
Speaker 5:  edge with updates and and DLC and all sorts of stuff. The
Speaker 5:  game is great now, but that was a representation of
Speaker 5:  what can happen. Even if you throw hundreds of millions of dollars
Speaker 5:  at a game, you are not necessarily guaranteed to get that back if the game
Speaker 5:  launches and it's a disaster. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's that's a good one. And yeah, I, I like the idea of like are we still
Speaker 4:  in the Marvel can do no wrong era or are we, are we in the,
Speaker 4:  everybody's kind of bored of Marvel era and it turns out like
Speaker 4:  you're saying Russ, you don't have to get it wrong that many times for it
Speaker 4:  to fall apart pretty fast. That's right. Alright, I am gonna go see if I
Speaker 4:  can figure out what the Barb Heimer video game era is gonna look like. And
Speaker 4:  then we're gonna come back, we're gonna talk about that. We're gonna do some
Speaker 4:  big hot Takey 2024 predictions that are gonna make everybody really angry.
Speaker 4:  Thank you both as always. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  This podcast is brought to you by Meta Quest three, the new mixed reality
Speaker 2:  headset from Meta. Now you can expand your world in ways you never
Speaker 2:  thought possible with the new Meta Quest three, put on the sleek most
Speaker 2:  powerful quest yet and jump into fully immersive games or blend virtual
Speaker 2:  elements into your physical surroundings with mixed reality. Instantly Go
Speaker 2:  from watching to playing the part in your favorite show with Stranger Things
Speaker 2:  vr, live the action and really feel what it's like to step into the
Speaker 2:  shoes of an assassin, an Assassin's Creed nexus. Even turn
Speaker 2:  your couch into courtside seats with X Stadium and watch your favorite
Speaker 2:  NBA team. With over 500 titles, it's easy to dive into
Speaker 2:  whatever you're into, expand your world with Medi Quest three,
Speaker 2:  see child safety guidance online accounts for 10 and up certain apps, games
Speaker 2:  and experiences may be suitable for a more mature audience. Learn more at
Speaker 2:  Meta dot com.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. As always, it's been a few weeks through the magic
Speaker 4:  of Time travel and podcast editing. We're back. You guys look different.
Speaker 4:  I have to say you've changed since we were here last.
Speaker 5:  I've seen some things, especially
Speaker 4:  You Chris.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah, well Plant has seen a lot of things. And
Speaker 4:  Then so the thing we're here to talk about is big games
Speaker 4:  and this one was actually the most fun for me of all of the episodes that
Speaker 4:  we've done because this is a topic I know essentially nothing about. So
Speaker 4:  what essentially what we're gonna do is I did a bunch of research, I talked
Speaker 4:  to a bunch of people and I tried to like speed run my way through learning
Speaker 4:  about the very big business of very big video games. And
Speaker 4:  I have come with some, some ideas and theories about where all of this is
Speaker 4:  headed and I want you guys to like check what I have come up with
Speaker 4:  and sort of bring it back to reality for me. How does that sound? It
Speaker 5:  Sounds good. Sounds great.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So the way that I've framed this because I have, I have found myself
Speaker 4:  unnecessarily structuring all of these things is I have gone through it just
Speaker 4:  to help it make sense is like if the big question is kind of where do
Speaker 4:  AAA games go? I have four possible futures. I
Speaker 4:  don't know which one of them I think is right, but there's kind of an
Speaker 4:  analog somewhere else in the world that could be how this goes. And I'm just
Speaker 4:  gonna walk you through all of them and we're gonna talk them out. But first
Speaker 4:  I have to say, you guys screwed me over really badly because neither of you
Speaker 4:  prepared me for the idea that absolutely no one agrees on what
Speaker 4:  AAA means or what indie means or any of these terms. And
Speaker 4:  so for every single person I talk to, I was like, let's talk about AAA games.
Speaker 4:  And they're like, well what do you mean when you talk about AAA i's just
Speaker 4:  like don don't know. You're supposed to know the answer to that
Speaker 5:  If it makes you feel any better. The Game Awards just announced
Speaker 5:  that Dave the diver was nominated for best Indie of the year. One of
Speaker 5:  five or six that were nominated for Best Indy of the Year gave the Diver
Speaker 5:  was produced by a studio of 18 people
Speaker 5:  within Nexon, which is an enormous, enormous
Speaker 5:  company. And even Nexon has said, yeah, it's not really an
Speaker 5:  indie studio but it kind of looks indie, it's got like Pixel graphics and
Speaker 5:  stuff. So yeah, no one knows for sure what the difference is.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no it, it was, it was actually very funny prepping for this in the
Speaker 4:  process of that happening. 'cause there were a bunch of people really mad
Speaker 4:  about that. And then the flip side was Boulder's Gate was
Speaker 4:  nominated for Oh yeah, like Game of the Year. And there were a bunch of people
Speaker 4:  saying, well that's an indie, it should have also been nominated as an indie.
Speaker 4:  And that's sparked this whole thing about what is AAA game and was an indie.
Speaker 4:  And what I've learned is that it mostly doesn't matter, like in real terms
Speaker 4:  it doesn't matter. So, but for my purposes, just for today, we're going to
Speaker 4:  define AAA games as like the kind of two
Speaker 4:  handfuls of very big, very expensive games that
Speaker 4:  everybody has heard of. Like people who don't play games have heard of these
Speaker 4:  games, right? That's kind of, it's not a perfect definition but that's what
Speaker 4:  we're gonna do. And then Indie is like the opposite of that. And I'm not
Speaker 4:  gonna try to define it further because I will just run into trouble and don
Speaker 4:  don't need that in my life. So that's what we're gonna do. Future number
Speaker 4:  one, I've named all of these, I'm very excited about the names I have for
Speaker 4:  them. Future number one is what I would call the Avengers future. And basically
Speaker 4:  what that would be is that we've spent the last
Speaker 4:  decade or so, but really sort of phase of video games
Speaker 4:  with a handful of gigantic properties
Speaker 4:  that everybody loved that just came to like completely dominate the landscape.
Speaker 4:  Like I went through the, the most popular games of the last 10 years and
Speaker 4:  I bet the two of you sitting here now could name most of them off the top
Speaker 4:  of your head, right? Like Call of Duty appears 17 times on
Speaker 4:  the list of 10 years. Madden is there 10 times in 10 years.
Speaker 4:  GTA five, one game is there for five years. Like most of these things will
Speaker 4:  not be surprising to people. So we're in this place now where there's this
Speaker 4:  gigantic sort of earth shatteringly huge
Speaker 4:  property that owns the world. Like it's not a perfect analogy 'cause
Speaker 4:  it's a bunch of games instead of just like the cinematic universe. They've
Speaker 4:  been big for a really long time. But now there is this feeling that these
Speaker 4:  things are so big and so frankly bad.
Speaker 4:  Now they've gotten so risk averse because they're so big and they're so expensive
Speaker 4:  and they're so complicated that they're starting to crack and that
Speaker 4:  eventually the Avengers can't be good forever. And eventually
Speaker 4:  that stops being good and then there is time for something else. And I think
Speaker 4:  one case you could make is that we're like right at the end of
Speaker 4:  this massive dominance of a handful of properties and
Speaker 4:  the next thing is starting to appear like Call of Duty, modern warfare
Speaker 4:  three just came out by all accounts, just a garbage fire of a game.
Speaker 4:  Everybody seems to hate it. It's still selling a lot because it's Call of
Speaker 4:  Duty, but at least so far doesn't seem to be this success that the others
Speaker 4:  were. And it's like, okay, is this what started happening in Marvel a couple
Speaker 4:  of years ago where it was like the, the Shine is off a little bit, people
Speaker 4:  won't just do it because it's there. Maybe this stuff is gonna start to fall
Speaker 4:  off and the next phase is gonna be full of new things. What do you guys
Speaker 4:  think of that?
Speaker 5:  I think you're right that I think we're starting to see
Speaker 5:  the franchises that were forever easily bankable. We're starting
Speaker 5:  to see them struggle in these environments and and franchises like Call of
Speaker 5:  Duty have sustained themselves not on the, oh man, there's a huge
Speaker 5:  campaign and there's Multiplay whatever just on their, the fact that they
Speaker 5:  have a free to play mode that's very popular in War zone and that is
Speaker 5:  monetized out the butt. So that's where they're making all their money. So,
Speaker 5:  I think that's what you're gonna start to see with those bigger franchises.
Speaker 5:  I think the other struggle that these big franchises come up against, which
Speaker 5:  is actually a good thing, is because there is so much weak in
Speaker 5:  weak out competition from smaller games that are doing
Speaker 5:  cool things, they pull time and resources and money
Speaker 5:  away from people saying, oh, the $60 that I spend only goes to
Speaker 5:  Call of Duty or only goes to Madden or whatever it is. Instead they're gonna
Speaker 5:  say, I'm gonna buy three games for $20 each and I'm gonna play those for
Speaker 5:  30 hours, 40 hours, whatever it is. So, I actually think
Speaker 5:  this is not necessarily a bad thing what you're describing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I, to be clear, I don't necessarily think any of these are actually
Speaker 4:  bad futures. Like one of the things I wrote under the Avengers future
Speaker 4:  bullet in my notes was it's just the end of an era. Everything changes Don't
Speaker 4:  be afraid, right? Like this does not mean it's the end of good video games.
Speaker 4:  I just think it's possible. I would not say it's likely, but it's possible
Speaker 4:  that it is. It is the end of a certain set of
Speaker 4:  video games.
Speaker 6:  I am gonna get really pedantic here do it, but I don't think it is the
Speaker 6:  end of an era at all. Okay. I think it is just a
Speaker 6:  continuation of an era because let me know what this sounds
Speaker 6:  familiar. So there's this company called Activision and it has the biggest
Speaker 6:  game in the world and it stops making all of its other games and it puts
Speaker 6:  all of its resources into that game and it actually has multiple teams
Speaker 6:  working on different versions of that game so they can get it out every year.
Speaker 6:  Right. I'm obviously talking about Tony Hawk's Pro skater.
Speaker 6:  Sorry, actually no, I'm talking about Guitar Hero. Oh wait, no I'm, I'm talking
Speaker 6:  about Call of Duty. Overwatch You know is is now at the end of its
Speaker 6:  lifecycle with eSports or they're closing the eSports league there. There
Speaker 6:  are ebbs and flows to these things and yes
Speaker 6:  those are down, but then Fortnite is up, right?
Speaker 6:  Minecraft is still dominant and those things, yes, like
Speaker 6:  Fresh mentioned, they're not updating every year but they are updating constantly.
Speaker 6:  They're finding new ways to bring in cash. It's just a slightly different
Speaker 6:  cadence and presentation.
Speaker 5:  But you would agree plant that there are way fewer AAA big
Speaker 5:  releases every year or like these years than they are five
Speaker 4:  Years ago
Speaker 6:  For sure. But if we're going off the, the I I guess specifically the Marvel
Speaker 6:  comparison I think doesn't work here because the Marvel games, the big
Speaker 6:  games continue to exist and the big games get only bigger. They're, they're
Speaker 6:  getting larger and larger. But it's weird because on one hand I wanna agree
Speaker 6:  with that. There are fewer big games, but I don't even know if that's true
Speaker 6:  anymore. There are fewer big games made by U Bsof and EA
Speaker 6:  and Activision, but now other teams are
Speaker 6:  making big games. We're getting pretty large size
Speaker 6:  games from Sega and Atlas. We're getting large games from Remedy.
Speaker 6:  We're getting even indie quote indie former indie studios that have a
Speaker 6:  ton of money that are now making their own very large scale
Speaker 6:  projects. So it's like a blend. We're
Speaker 6:  we're watching all these different ways of engaging with games kind of blend
Speaker 6:  together where yeah and maybe in the past it felt like no
Speaker 6:  there are kind of two things. There was the, you play games that came
Speaker 6:  out from ea, you be soft in Activision or you played like download Blendy
Speaker 6:  games and now yes, all of that is kind of like blurring together and the
Speaker 6:  big companies are making some downloadable games and the You know small indie
Speaker 6:  companies are actually quite big now and they're making big games and it's
Speaker 6:  just getting more messy.
Speaker 4:  You're gonna really like hypothetical future number two. Yeah Chris, but
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna get that, I'm gonna get to that in one second because I think,
Speaker 4:  I think what you just described is a perfectly plausible version of this.
Speaker 4:  The one thing I will say for the the Avengers future that we live in
Speaker 4:  is just from a pure like greatest hits
Speaker 4:  of gaming thing you look through and basically if
Speaker 4:  you are not sort of a plus IP like Harry Potter
Speaker 4:  or Star Wars, if you're not a sequel, that's it. It's just those two things.
Speaker 4:  That's how you succeed in video games right now if you want to be like one
Speaker 4:  of the 10 or 20 biggest games, those are your only two moves
Speaker 4:  right now and we've been on that path for a long time. You either, you
Speaker 4:  either make the annual sports game, you make a game based on
Speaker 4:  You know Star Wars or Harry Potter or some other
Speaker 4:  like extremely old ip. I almost said James Bond because I'm like desperate
Speaker 4:  for more James Bond games. But Alas, or you make a sequel, we have
Speaker 4:  You know Diablo four and Resonant Evil four and Dead Island two
Speaker 4:  and Final Fantasy 658. Like this is kind of what it
Speaker 4:  takes to really have a huge hit now. And I'm leaving out the live services
Speaker 4:  stuff 'cause we're gonna get to that. But I think that is a different corner
Speaker 4:  of the future of video games. But I'm just saying for these like giant titles
Speaker 4:  that people pay money for, that's still kind of the world we're in.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean again, success being like most
Speaker 5:  amount of profit, right? Obviously people are seeing success not only
Speaker 5:  creatively but also making a ton of money relative to what they're putting
Speaker 5:  in for smaller projects. You know if you're game costs
Speaker 5:  $10 million to make versus a hundred million dollars to make and you end
Speaker 5:  up making 50 million on it, like that's a really good return. So well
Speaker 5:  done. Yeah, You know again, it is difficult to determine
Speaker 5:  whether something is successful or not strictly on the like total copies
Speaker 5:  sold. But I do agree that like for the bestselling
Speaker 5:  list 100% it's all franchises you've always heard of.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Hypothetical future number two is what I call the
Speaker 4:  prestige TV future. And this is I think closer to what
Speaker 4:  we've been describing, right? Which is basically we're gonna get a whole
Speaker 4:  industry shifting away from there being kind of one big
Speaker 4:  giant move, which is like make big movies,
Speaker 4:  put them in theaters and try to make a lot of money and towards something
Speaker 4:  a little broader, a little different, the business model changes a little
Speaker 4:  bit but it lets you do all kinds of different stuff. You can start to take
Speaker 4:  a-list actors and make limited series and sell them that way. You can start
Speaker 4:  to make longer running TV shows, you can make documentaries have a comeback
Speaker 4:  like this idea that by upending the way the business works
Speaker 4:  and essentially taking it out of a couple of company's hands, you give people
Speaker 4:  many more ways to make things at many different
Speaker 4:  scales that make money. Which I think to some extent like
Speaker 4:  signals a big part of the end of like these unbelievably expensive AAA
Speaker 4:  games because that no longer is the only move is to spend an outrageous amount
Speaker 4:  of money to try to make an outrageous amount of money and means this whole
Speaker 4:  other class of stuff can start to come up. And just based on what we've been
Speaker 4:  talking about, it sounds like maybe that's a little closer to what you guys
Speaker 4:  have been seeing already.
Speaker 6:  It's so tough because I So I feel like we talked about this and I can't
Speaker 6:  remember which episode on, but like the each platform or each
Speaker 6:  store is going for different things. So Nintendo is making
Speaker 6:  great toys. They also make easy to like ship indie games on their thing,
Speaker 6:  right? But you're getting the Nintendo product when you go to Nintendo. I
Speaker 6:  think what you're talking about doesn't quite align with like what I think
Speaker 6:  of with Sony, which is Sony is we are a showcase
Speaker 6:  of of hardware in your living room and we're going to continue to make
Speaker 6:  these 70 to $80 video games that are very, very
Speaker 6:  fancy and blockbuster, right? And that's our brand. What you are
Speaker 6:  describing makes a lot of sense to me for Xbox and
Speaker 6:  as, especially as it pushes onto Game Pass where there becomes much more
Speaker 6:  value in novelty and just
Speaker 6:  pure raw output. The number of things that you are shipping
Speaker 6:  and less on, Hey here's the one game that you're going
Speaker 6:  to play for the next five years game. Xbox I think
Speaker 6:  would be much happier for you to play 10 games a month than
Speaker 6:  one game a month because you're playing, ultimately the product is
Speaker 6:  Game Pass. The games are just a piece of that, right? So
Speaker 6:  I can see what you're talking about. I think it also leans itself into Steam.
Speaker 6:  But at the end of the day, the thing that I, I'm curious what
Speaker 6:  both you and Fresh think about is still the financial risk just making
Speaker 6:  games remains very expensive. It's much cheaper than it ever
Speaker 6:  was before in terms of distribution and You know engines,
Speaker 6:  but it is really risky and don don't know how
Speaker 6:  what you're describing mitigates that risk.
Speaker 5:  I mean the risk of making a 60 hour
Speaker 5:  giant open world game is unquestionably enormous.
Speaker 5:  It's probably the riskiest thing you can do. The risk of making a four
Speaker 5:  hour narrative adventure that Microsoft wants because it's
Speaker 5:  a good advertisement for Game Pass is a lot lower. Like
Speaker 5:  it takes two as like kind of a great example of something that is like
Speaker 5:  not that risk. I mean it has some risk, obviously it's a weird divorce game,
Speaker 5:  but it's not that risky from an overall scale of the project standpoint.
Speaker 5:  And I think You know Microsoft has the deep pockets that can pay for
Speaker 5:  things and if one of those fails it doesn't mean game Pass fails. You
Speaker 5:  look at Red Fall, that's a good example. Red Fall was an an enormous project
Speaker 5:  that really had a disastrous launch, came out on Game Pass, was
Speaker 5:  supposed to be like a big push for Game Pass. And the fact that it
Speaker 5:  like didn't Sink Game Pass long term is telling it how
Speaker 5:  divested Microsoft is on this surface with all the other releases that were
Speaker 5:  coming out.
Speaker 6:  I will say two different things about risk there in relation to that. You,
Speaker 6:  you kind of hit the nail on the head with the game pass of it all. Yes if,
Speaker 6:  if Microsoft has given you a contract before you start making this
Speaker 6:  thing, yeah there's definitely not that much risk there. You know you have
Speaker 6:  a great thing going for you, but most developers are not going
Speaker 6:  to have that. They might not even know if they should be on Game Pass or
Speaker 6:  not. And whether you're making a giant game or a small
Speaker 6:  game, it's all relative to you making money at the end of the day. Right.
Speaker 6:  I, I think the other thing that I, that I'm just kind of bashing up
Speaker 6:  against with this theory in terms of like the business and where the
Speaker 6:  people who the investors, the board members go is we're gonna have
Speaker 6:  Grand Theft Auto six come out next year or the year after that and
Speaker 6:  every board member is gonna say, that's what I want. I wanna continue getting
Speaker 6:  that. That's absurd number and I'm not gonna get that because
Speaker 6:  somebody released a cooperative divorce game. I'm gonna get it. Because again,
Speaker 6:  they keep chasing this thing and so long as these big
Speaker 6:  companies are tied to those boards, don don't know how
Speaker 6:  the big companies get away from it. And maybe that's, maybe that's it. Maybe
Speaker 6:  they're like doomed, like maybe You know that, that they're weirdly
Speaker 6:  their shareholders are this albatross with where the direction that
Speaker 6:  the industry is going in. I, I don't know.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. One of the most sort of fascinating threads of this entire like reporting
Speaker 4:  and research project was talking to people who
Speaker 4:  like care about games at like an emotional sort of, I play games level
Speaker 4:  and those people cannot fathom why all of these
Speaker 4:  companies have stopped caring about making games that are fun to play. Because
Speaker 4:  if you make games that are fun to play, people will play them, then you'll
Speaker 4:  sell more of them and everybody wins, right? And then I talk to people on
Speaker 4:  the business side who are essentially like making games fun to play is like
Speaker 4:  not the point. Like we're a business, we're here to make money and if
Speaker 4:  we can make more money while making the game slightly less fun to play, but
Speaker 4:  people still buy the game, like that becomes a harder choice than I think
Speaker 4:  you would like it to be. And like people tell the story of Halo all the time,
Speaker 4:  right? I feel like it's, it's like sort of the canonical version of this,
Speaker 4:  right? Like you have Bungee, which makes great games because it wants
Speaker 4:  to make great games and then it gets so big that it kind of gets crushed
Speaker 4:  by its own bigness and it switches developers and the culture is different.
Speaker 4:  It becomes about making money and then Halo just kind of like falls in on
Speaker 4:  itself like a dying star over time. But I think you're right in
Speaker 4:  that that tension is super real, but it also gets
Speaker 4:  to a point where eventually that's gonna turn on somebody in a really big
Speaker 4:  like earth shakingly huge way that's gonna make everybody afraid.
Speaker 5:  I mean it it, it has, I mean Halo is a great example of that. Yeah. Like
Speaker 5:  this is the big one of the biggest franchises ever in the history of video
Speaker 5:  games and because of it wasn't just monetization
Speaker 5:  decisions, that was part of it. They made some like pretty scummy monetization
Speaker 5:  decisions but also like design issues and technical
Speaker 5:  issues and like all that stuff You know resulted in
Speaker 5:  a major calamity for this franchise that will need to be rebooted
Speaker 5:  again. Yeah. And that is like a total cautionary tale
Speaker 5:  for all of these companies that is like, okay, well
Speaker 5:  there's a limit to what you can do. You know Battlefront Two was another
Speaker 5:  example of that and You know, even Cyberpunk was another example of that
Speaker 5:  where like You know they've righted the ship, but it
Speaker 5:  took them several years to get there and that was an enormous
Speaker 5:  risk. And, and I do think you will start to hear
Speaker 5:  within these giant companies some pushback because
Speaker 5:  someone will say, Hey, we need to push this out in fall of 2024
Speaker 5:  or whatever it is. And someone else is gonna say, yeah, but remember what
Speaker 5:  happened to Cyberpunk Was that good for our bottom line, right? Maybe we
Speaker 5:  should wait six months. And I think star fielders representation of that,
Speaker 5:  like they delayed that game basically a full year. It was done and dusted
Speaker 5:  for a full year and they spent that all on Polish. I'm not saying that's
Speaker 5:  a great game, but like clearly it's one of the cleanest games that
Speaker 5:  Bethesda's ever released. So I do think there is a
Speaker 5:  slight sea change going on.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I I maybe a comparison is not just the
Speaker 6:  the Prestige TV but the end of the studio era
Speaker 6:  in filmmaking, which is like the twenties to the fifties where it's like
Speaker 6:  these like just a handful of studios have total control.
Speaker 6:  Even the the talent there is like they're good for tabloids, but they are,
Speaker 6:  they are, they do not have much of a say no
Speaker 4:  They like signed contracts with the studio and then did whatever the studio
Speaker 4:  told them to do. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Exactly. And the studios themselves had a lot more say in distribution
Speaker 6:  and that yeah, maybe we are coming out of that for
Speaker 6:  games and we will see something similar to what we saw for film in the
Speaker 6:  sixties and seventies. So this is Phil
Speaker 4:  Spencer's big theory, right? Is that he, he wrote that email that came out
Speaker 4:  in the, the Xbox leaks over the summer basically saying that
Speaker 4:  now that the handful of big publishers don't have like that
Speaker 4:  retail store shelves distribution monopoly, everything has suddenly
Speaker 4:  open and those companies have been slow to figure it out. Like that's, I
Speaker 4:  think there's something to that theory. I think we're probably just at the
Speaker 4:  beginning of that because there's more to just store shelves than
Speaker 4:  in in changing the way people find and buy games. But I do think, I think
Speaker 4:  you're onto something and at the end of that road is something like Game
Speaker 4:  Pass, right? Which changes the way we think about discovery because you don't
Speaker 4:  have to buy a game before you can play it. You can just show up and play
Speaker 4:  it. It changes the way the games get made because they're gonna end up You
Speaker 4:  know a lot of cases getting paid for how people play, not just by getting
Speaker 4:  you to buy the game with by calling it Hogwarts. All of that feels
Speaker 4:  like it's, it's in the middle of like being turned on its head right now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I do wanna be careful though because when we say, oh this might be the end
Speaker 5:  of like the studio era, we are still in a circumstance where like
Speaker 5:  a very, very small number of companies are
Speaker 5:  in control of the vast majority of the generation of
Speaker 5:  wealth within the games industry. Microsoft just merged with with Activision.
Speaker 5:  That is a huge percentage of the game space. Yeah. Look
Speaker 5:  at how much valve controls the PC gaming market and
Speaker 5:  that's what are they getting 30% on each sale for that? I mean effectively
Speaker 5:  that's a studio deal in a lot of ways. So You know, I don't think
Speaker 5:  it's that divested among So. I mean a lot of people
Speaker 5:  are making money in games, don't get me wrong, but like mostly it's these
Speaker 5:  like eight companies that are like doing very well and I think it'll only
Speaker 5:  increase to combat what you were just talking about because the way to solve
Speaker 5:  that problem of not having the store shelves is acquisition You
Speaker 5:  know Microsoft going out, buying Bethesda, buying Activision You know
Speaker 5:  Sony needs to make the same sort of moves to ensure that they have these
Speaker 5:  franchises that can like rise above. And again, all that does is
Speaker 5:  just make it fewer and fewer companies.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I found one study that said the, the public gaming
Speaker 4:  companies like Nintendo and EA and a few others right now have more than
Speaker 4:  $45 billion between them just in cash sitting around. And obviously
Speaker 4:  that's not gonna buy you an Activision, but there's only one Activision and
Speaker 4:  Microsoft already did that. And so the, the theory coming out of that was
Speaker 4:  we might be in for a huge phase of
Speaker 4:  consolidations and acquisition and we're gonna go from this
Speaker 4:  sort of interesting splintering of people who can make
Speaker 4:  big good cool, exciting games and that might all start
Speaker 4:  to get compressed again because it's gonna get bought by the same handful
Speaker 4:  of companies that have been doing this for a really long time. I think that's
Speaker 4:  very possible and I think would be kind of bad news.
Speaker 6:  I maybe the only hesitation I have with that is like we've
Speaker 6:  seen Embracer group try to do that, right? Like a large company
Speaker 6:  be like, I'm gonna buy up 30 different things and try to run 'em all
Speaker 6:  and it doesn't work. Well. I think there's a reason that even
Speaker 6:  again going back to film studios, they let a lot of
Speaker 6:  independent creators and studios and groups make something and
Speaker 6:  they go and acquire that product and then they like
Speaker 6:  they, they, one, they avoid the risk of like the early days of development,
Speaker 6:  but two, they're not managing so many things. I wouldn't be
Speaker 6:  surprised if people made the bad decision to like over consolidate and try
Speaker 6:  to get as many studios under your banner as possible. But I,
Speaker 6:  at the same time, I'm impressed by Disney who keeps, I feel like every other
Speaker 6:  week you hear Disney needs to go out and buy a video game in the studio.
Speaker 6:  That's the best thing for Disney. And it's like no You know what's great
Speaker 6:  for Disney having control of all this different IP that everybody wants to
Speaker 6:  work for having no overhead cost and being able to set how much money you
Speaker 6:  want from each project.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well and that like to, just to pull it back to the, like the
Speaker 4:  TV streaming era, that's very much how we got
Speaker 4:  peak tv, right? You have all these different players looking for content.
Speaker 4:  You get into this place where like being someone who makes good things becomes
Speaker 4:  an incredible advantage because you're gonna, you have all this competition
Speaker 4:  for your work and everybody's looking for new things and so the, like you
Speaker 4:  get this phase of frankly too much spending on the
Speaker 4:  like distributors side, but it's a huge win for the people who like make
Speaker 4:  and consume content. So like it all turns into a giant mess, which is
Speaker 4:  what we're living through in the TV world right now. But there is a phase
Speaker 4:  where like if, if that comes true like you're describing Chris, we might
Speaker 4:  get a hell of a lot of really good games really fast, which could be very
Speaker 4:  exciting.
Speaker 6:  I'm so curious what number three is gonna be here.
Speaker 4:  Okay, do you want to hear number three?
Speaker 6:  Yes. Oh
Speaker 4:  Shit, I have two more and I can't decide which to do first. All, right? We'll
Speaker 4:  just do number three right now. Number three is what I call the iPhone future.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Which is that everybody starts to complain that the
Speaker 4:  big thing is boring now everybody gets mad and oh would you look at that?
Speaker 4:  It just keeps winning. And the part of me that thinks this
Speaker 4:  might be the truth is the part of me that has talked to folks who say some
Speaker 4:  of these franchises we have are just completely
Speaker 4:  un killable that there is nothing you can do to
Speaker 4:  Assassin's Creed. There's no version of Assassin's Creed you can make that
Speaker 4:  is so bad that people will stop playing it or that people will stop making
Speaker 4:  it. Same for Call of Duty, same for Madden. Everybody's gonna keep making
Speaker 4:  Star Wars games because it's Star Wars. Everybody's gonna keep making Harry Potter
Speaker 4:  games because it's Harry Potter and that world is now
Speaker 4:  so big and so successful that breaking it up or even
Speaker 4:  breaking into it is going to be much harder than anybody reckons
Speaker 4:  for. And there might be a bunch of cool folks on the outside competing for
Speaker 4:  scraps, but like the winners are gonna stay the winners no matter what they
Speaker 4:  do. It
Speaker 5:  Is funny that you mentioned Assassin's Creed at the top there because Assassin's
Speaker 5:  Creed historically was an annual franchise just started
Speaker 5:  You know Ubisoft was pumping them out at an insane rate and then
Speaker 5:  just recently, like You know, they released Fal Hallow and the Xbox Series
Speaker 5:  X and PlayStation five launched and then had like a gap of
Speaker 5:  three or four years between that and Mirage, which just came out
Speaker 5:  to like kind of tepid reviews. I think that's a representation of like
Speaker 5:  Yousoft realizing, hey there's a lot of burnout here and we can't keep up
Speaker 5:  with it. It is not necessarily the bankable franchise that it once
Speaker 5:  was So I. While I agree with you like Assassin creed's not
Speaker 5:  gonna like go away forever. I don't think it's the like lock
Speaker 5:  solid guarantee that it once was.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And and I think you already named Halo. Yeah. And
Speaker 6:  before that we talked about Tony Hawk and Guitar Hero, nothing's un killable
Speaker 4:  To be fair, nobody killed Tony Hawk. Tony Hawk remains, he's
Speaker 5:  Doing great.
Speaker 6:  That depends on which conspiracy theories you believe. I could
Speaker 6:  see that in the, in the sense that like yes, certain IP that transcend
Speaker 6:  games like Hogwarts or whatever. Yeah
Speaker 6:  of course they're just gonna keep making them and once they You know
Speaker 6:  burn through one developer, they'll go to a different one. I could maybe,
Speaker 6:  I think the exception to the rule here is yes, something like Call of Duty
Speaker 6:  where it will extend long beyond
Speaker 6:  its lifecycle. But You know Call of Duty, modern Warfare three might
Speaker 6:  have been You know, laughed off the face of Meta critic War
Speaker 6:  zones, still making plenty of money. You know like so they're,
Speaker 6:  they've done the thing that I think Esof wanted to do with Assassin's Creed,
Speaker 6:  which was hey we need to get away from these annual games,
Speaker 6:  we need to get a like living game version of this out.
Speaker 6:  And we're still waiting for that with Assassin's Creed where so
Speaker 6:  far Call of Duty has done a pretty good job of
Speaker 6:  adjusting and, and they have a history of doing this. You know they had
Speaker 6:  mobile Call of Duty games that were available and I believe in
Speaker 6:  China, South Korea, Japan, years, years ago
Speaker 6:  before they were even here, they, they I believe had a partnership with Tencent.
Speaker 6:  This is things that you'll need to fact check, but they're aware that they
Speaker 6:  have to evolve with the times and then yes, the core product can just kind
Speaker 6:  of keep being there. It's funny talking about all the
Speaker 6:  Marvel stuff in the superhero era 'cause it's not so unlike
Speaker 6:  what Marvel has done with comics, right? Yeah. Comics themselves
Speaker 6:  go up and down, but they're always trying to get into
Speaker 6:  film or TV or audio books or who knows what else. And
Speaker 6:  even if the original comics are not the top sellers, they're, they never
Speaker 6:  fully go away.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think that's right. And I think one of the things for me that has
Speaker 4:  been the most interesting in trying to figure out this particular future
Speaker 4:  is it feels like, I do think some of these franchises
Speaker 4:  are if not too big to die, like damn hard to
Speaker 4:  kill. But then there's also this thing, like you talk about the live services
Speaker 4:  game and, and it also feels like we now have this dominant generation
Speaker 4:  of a handful of those games. You have You know Roblox and
Speaker 4:  Fortnite and don Don't know Apex Legends kind of
Speaker 4:  and War Zone and like there probably aren't more than five
Speaker 4:  of these games that essentially dominate that space.
Speaker 4:  And it also feels like those are now so entrenched that it might be hard
Speaker 4:  for someone else to come in and do it. So maybe don don't know, maybe, maybe
Speaker 4:  that old version was like the iPod era and now
Speaker 4:  the live services games or the iPhone like poised to do the next 15 years
Speaker 4:  and maybe that's just the cycle we're in now.
Speaker 5:  We were talking about risk and I was saying how a 60 hour open world RPG
Speaker 5:  is a huge amount of risk these days. Doing a free to play high
Speaker 5:  budget game in the live services space is enormously
Speaker 5:  risky. Yeah, it is so hard because those games in particular
Speaker 5:  more so than like the star fields of the world free to play live
Speaker 5:  service games are designed to maintain the player base. There's
Speaker 5:  no winning those games. You're always constantly given stuff to
Speaker 5:  unlock or buy or whatever it is. Fortnite changes every other
Speaker 5:  week. They are constantly trying to hold on. So you would literally have
Speaker 5:  to steal players away from the other game that they're playing
Speaker 5:  to have your game be successful. To the point where Remedy, who
Speaker 5:  just put out Allen Wake two to a critical claim announced very
Speaker 5:  recently that they were working on a multiplayer free to play live service
Speaker 5:  game that is no longer free to play and more narrative focused and
Speaker 5:  more driven by what they're good at. So I think
Speaker 5:  companies are realizing how disastrous it can be trying to
Speaker 5:  jump into a space that is already pretty well dominated by a handful of
Speaker 5:  players.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The the network effects of it are just so big to me. That's the thing
Speaker 4:  I keep, I keep thinking about. It's like you not only have to get me to think
Speaker 4:  a game is cool, you have to get a bunch of people I like and then a many
Speaker 4:  tens of millions of strangers to also think it's cool before I can actually
Speaker 4:  like do anything in it. But the flip side of that is the
Speaker 4:  reward seems to be higher than ever, right? Like the, the sense is
Speaker 4:  we can build this game essentially once and make
Speaker 4:  money from it forever. And that seems to be what everybody wants now.
Speaker 5:  Fortnite revenue is astronomical. I You know some of the
Speaker 5:  leaks came out as part of the Epic lawsuit and like it is
Speaker 5:  staggering how much money they're making. But you have to keep in mind, even
Speaker 5:  though it seems like you're right, you could just make one game and You know
Speaker 5:  maintain it or whatever it is and and people just stick around. That is very
Speaker 5:  much not the case. The only way you can get people to stick around is by
Speaker 5:  constantly changing it, adding new maps, adding new modes,
Speaker 5:  skins, whatever it is forever. Like there's no ending to that. Yeah. So
Speaker 5:  you really are committing to this forever tale to maintain that
Speaker 5:  player base so that You know it's, it is not as easy as you have your
Speaker 5:  smash hit and then it's, it's good to go. But it that that also
Speaker 5:  shows you how hard it is to jump into the space because people are committing
Speaker 5:  to not a three year project but a 20 year project.
Speaker 4:  Chris, what do you make of all that are is live services just going to take
Speaker 4:  everything over for this next phase?
Speaker 6:  It definitely won't take everything over. Everything exists at the
Speaker 6:  same time. You know it helps to think of video games like
Speaker 6:  channels on a tv. They can all be doing
Speaker 6:  a different thing. You know you can, you can go to CNN and have 24 hour
Speaker 6:  news and you can have a 24 hour thing. You can go to another channel and
Speaker 6:  it's like the Weather Channel and they do the same thing every five minutes.
Speaker 6:  Right. But
Speaker 4:  The You know why that's a fun example is because a handful of those channels
Speaker 4:  pay for all the rest of them.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And most people only use three or four of those channels. Right. And
Speaker 6:  yet you would say like, Hey, do you like tv? And they're like, yes,
Speaker 4:  But don don't think anybody means the Weather Channel when they say they
Speaker 4:  like tv. Like
Speaker 6:  No, they mean the Weather channel. I mean, have you seen the CG on the Weather
Speaker 6:  Channel lately? They're doing wild stuff. Listen,
Speaker 4:  The weather channel's sick, the thing they do with the storm surges, like
Speaker 4:  I'm all
Speaker 6:  About it. They have no respect for human dignity. No, I
Speaker 6:  think it's easy to think of video games and video game
Speaker 6:  business as this monolithic force. But it really is,
Speaker 6:  it's a sports industry. It's a lifestyle industry. It is a children's
Speaker 6:  entertainment industry. It is a grownup single player thing. It is a
Speaker 6:  means of communication. It is all these different things. And
Speaker 6:  I mean I think that is probably the reality of everything that we're talking
Speaker 6:  about is all of the futures that you're talking about are going to be true
Speaker 6:  in some capacity and they're going to overlap and
Speaker 6:  often conflict with each other. It'll just depend on like what are the
Speaker 6:  type of games that you see as the video game industry? I,
Speaker 6:  when you go to the Game Developers conference in San Francisco, every year
Speaker 6:  they have these summits that are broken up with like the VR summit,
Speaker 6:  the free to play summit, right? And the business people
Speaker 6:  that that attracts are just completely different
Speaker 6:  human beings. They, they're, they're strategies, the type of games
Speaker 6:  they're making, everything about it is so distinct that you could
Speaker 6:  go to one of them and think, wow, this is everything. And then you walk into
Speaker 6:  a room across the hall and you're like, I'm hearing the exact opposite of
Speaker 6:  everything I just heard an hour ago. And neither of them are necessarily
Speaker 6:  wrong. Well we are in Bitcoin. They were probably both wrong.
Speaker 6:  But other than that it was great.
Speaker 4:  No, I think you're right. And I think one of the actually most encouraging
Speaker 4:  things I found doing all this research was that we're in kind of a weird
Speaker 4:  time in the entertainment business in general. pwc the like accounting and
Speaker 4:  consulting firm, they do a really interesting like state of the entertainment
Speaker 4:  business thing every year. And the basic takeaway for, I think this
Speaker 4:  year's was 23 through 27, so sort of the next five years
Speaker 4:  was kind of the outlook. And basically the overarching theory is like the
Speaker 4:  entertainment businesses weird and messy and growth is going down
Speaker 4:  in a lot of ways except for gaming, which just against all Odds
Speaker 4:  continues to grow along. Basically every axis you can think of like
Speaker 4:  more people are coming into gaming. They had this fun stat that like people
Speaker 4:  over 45 are one of the fastest growing groups of gamers right now. Mm.
Speaker 4:  So are women, so are young girls. Like it's a, it's a, every faction of
Speaker 4:  people you can think of are increasingly gaming. And what that means is
Speaker 4:  probably that like a handful of big things get even bigger over time.
Speaker 4:  Like a lot of these people are gonna show up and play Call of Duty, that's
Speaker 4:  fine, but it also does mean just the pie gets so much bigger that
Speaker 4:  it's just gonna allow for a lot more things. But all of that being said,
Speaker 4:  I think it is still going to be true for a long time that a handful
Speaker 4:  of companies and properties run this
Speaker 4:  business in a pretty real way. Like Call of Duty is going to continue
Speaker 4:  to be a bellwether for a lot of things in a way
Speaker 4:  that most things are not.
Speaker 6:  Yes, I think that's right. I think we can know for a fact
Speaker 6:  that Grand Theft Auto will make a lot of money and it will be absolutely
Speaker 6:  humongous and Take two will be okay because of it. We can know for a fact
Speaker 6:  that FIFA now EA Football Club or whatever
Speaker 6:  they call it,
Speaker 4:  EA Sports fc, the worst named video game of all time.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It, it's gonna keep ea just afloat enough for them to continue
Speaker 6:  to try to figure out how to make mass effects Excel. Again, what is
Speaker 6:  confusing is like will ea be as big as it once was?
Speaker 6:  I don't know. Will UV Soft be as big as it once
Speaker 6:  was? don don't know. Will new players rise in
Speaker 6:  their place like Epic with Fortnite and You know Publishing Remedy?
Speaker 6:  Probably So I think you're right. The big differences that just
Speaker 6:  who those people are might change in the same way that You
Speaker 6:  know Capcom. If you had asked me about this 10 years ago or
Speaker 6:  Sega, I would be like, what are you talking about? Sure. And if you asked
Speaker 6:  me about Capcom and Sega today, I'd be like, they do no wrong. They, they
Speaker 6:  continue to make, well Capcom has a really good streak right now. Sega,
Speaker 6:  it depends. It can go back and forth. Or if you had told me that Konami would
Speaker 6:  not have put out games really for a while and that Bandi
Speaker 6:  Namco would be huge now none of these things were
Speaker 6:  the things I could have predicted and yet now arguing against Elden
Speaker 6:  Ring as anything but one of the biggest games in the world Sounds silly.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You know I, and I think that applies to the game franchise as well.
Speaker 5:  You know people didn't have much understanding of what
Speaker 5:  Minecraft was gonna be when Minecraft launched. And the fact that it is
Speaker 5:  now a worldwide property that was originally made by a very, very, very small
Speaker 5:  team tells you that it is possible that is like the
Speaker 5:  jackpot of jackpots. There's really no scenario where anyone would ever bet
Speaker 5:  the likelihood of that happening. But it is possible for new franchises to
Speaker 5:  get in there. It's just very, very rare. It's like a once every five
Speaker 5:  years kind of thing if that. So yeah, I mean I,
Speaker 5:  you will see movement, but again, I You know so long as you're not
Speaker 5:  super hyper-focused on the large business side of
Speaker 5:  it and if you're just sitting at home and you wanna play cool games, the,
Speaker 5:  it's never been better for that. Like it is literally
Speaker 5:  so diverse and you have so many options and
Speaker 5:  from a like inexpensive nature like playing
Speaker 5:  games and being into games pretty damn cheap for what you're getting out
Speaker 5:  of it, like the ROI is incredible. So I think it is kind
Speaker 5:  of a great time, as you said for the audience to really grow and
Speaker 5:  become bigger and more welcoming. Can
Speaker 6:  I just tell you the unfair thing about video game culture? The one thing
Speaker 6:  just, just the, this is actually the only one, the only issue I have. I've
Speaker 6:  never actually had any concerns and, and that's well documented that freshmen
Speaker 6:  Minecraft and I can say something like I
Speaker 6:  played the original build of Minecraft when it was in a forum
Speaker 6:  and I say that out loud and I sound like the biggest asshole and
Speaker 6:  nobody thinks it's cool.
Speaker 4:  You also sound like you're 200 years
Speaker 6:  Old. I do. But if I said something like I saw those lovely
Speaker 6:  boys in Liverpool at a little bar down the street and
Speaker 6:  then they went on to become the Beatles, people would be like, holy moly,
Speaker 6:  that's incredible. And don don't know what that is. There's something,
Speaker 6:  there's maybe it's just game history that that was still of a dork era
Speaker 6:  that people are like, yeah, that just means that you're around in a dork
Speaker 6:  at that time. You know pip squeak and give you a swirly. Chris,
Speaker 4:  I just want you to know I think you're impressive.
Speaker 6:  Thank you. Honestly, I just wanted praise and I got it. I'm
Speaker 4:  So proud of you. I could not Thank you. I couldn't even begin to tell you.
Speaker 6:  You might think that it doesn't work, but it does. I do feel better.
Speaker 4:  I am. Listen, I'm proud of you. You were early to, you were, you were early.
Speaker 4:  Whatcha are you gonna do? You were the first one. You get to be a Minecraft
Speaker 4:  hipster. Congratulations. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna cut this recording out and then just listen to it every morning
Speaker 6:  when I wake up. Here we go.
Speaker 4:  All. right? We need to take one more quick break and then I have one more
Speaker 4:  theory that we've kind of already talked about and then I have some questions
Speaker 4:  for you and then we're gonna get outta here. We'll right back.
Speaker 2:  This podcast is brought to you by Meta Quest three, the new mixed reality
Speaker 2:  headset from Meta. Now you can expand your world in ways you never thought
Speaker 2:  possible with the new Meta Quest three, put on the sleek most powerful
Speaker 2:  quest yet and jump into fully immersive games or blend virtual elements
Speaker 2:  into your physical surroundings with mixed reality. Instantly Go from
Speaker 2:  watching to playing the part in your favorite show with Stranger Things vr,
Speaker 2:  live the action and really feel what it's like to step into the shoes of
Speaker 2:  an assassin, an Assassin's Creed nexus. Even turn your couch
Speaker 2:  into court side seats with X Stadium and watch your favorite NBA team.
Speaker 2:  With over 500 titles, it's easy to dive into whatever you're
Speaker 2:  into, expand your world with Meta Quest three, see child safety
Speaker 2:  guidance online accounts for 10 and up certain apps, games and experiences
Speaker 2:  may be suitable for a more mature audience. Learn more at Meta dot com.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. My last theory we've basically already talked about,
Speaker 4:  but I'm just gonna like put a couple of pieces together very quickly for
Speaker 4:  you. And this is what I call the music industry theory, which is basically
Speaker 4:  that instead of a radical change in content, the first thing
Speaker 4:  we're gonna get is a new kind of consumer product that is actually
Speaker 4:  then going to back into changing all of the content. And I think the two
Speaker 4:  versions of that, both of which we've talked about a little bit are Game
Speaker 4:  Pass and things like it. This idea that you pay one price for lots of games
Speaker 4:  instead of buying games individually and live services games, which is
Speaker 4:  just a completely different way of monetizing a game that functionally
Speaker 4:  changes. Like you were talking about Russ, what those games are and how they're
Speaker 4:  made and maintained over time. So I think in this case Game Pass is
Speaker 4:  probably the more relevant one to like us right now at this moment because
Speaker 4:  what we haven't seen is what that will mean for how games get made. Whereas
Speaker 4:  I feel like the live services answer is just obvious, right? Like if
Speaker 4:  Microtransactions changed how games got made like that, that just exists
Speaker 4:  in the world now. I don't think that's arguable anymore, but I do think the,
Speaker 4:  the question of like, is the way that we buy and pay for games going to change
Speaker 4:  the games themselves is still kind of in the middle of being sorted out.
Speaker 5:  I actually think that Game Pass is already
Speaker 5:  determining how some games get made really?
Speaker 4:  Okay.
Speaker 5:  It's, I think it's already happening. I think there are three hour narrative
Speaker 5:  games that would not exist if a Pitch wasn't green
Speaker 5:  lit by Microsoft and said, okay, oh this is
Speaker 5:  great. We love what you're doing and here's this like cute little walkthrough
Speaker 5:  of it and, and we're into it, it's gonna come to Game Pass. But
Speaker 5:  ordinarily that three hour narrative game would really struggle on Steam
Speaker 5:  or another platform and Game Pass is the solve and the way that it kind of
Speaker 5:  reaches all the people.
Speaker 4:  Chris, you, you were pointing during that, I'm assuming you liked this theory.
Speaker 4:  I was waiting
Speaker 6:  For Fresh to say my game of the year from last year
Speaker 6:  Intimate. It was made within the Xbox family. This is an
Speaker 6:  indie game. But what happened is Obsidian who
Speaker 6:  has made very, very large role playing games decided
Speaker 6:  let's make a book about the 16th century.
Speaker 6:  And when I say a book, I meant video game, but that was a hell of a fian
Speaker 6:  slip because it was really just a game that
Speaker 6:  you read a lot about. You are an illuminator.
Speaker 6:  So like the person who made like You know texts look beautiful
Speaker 6:  way, way back in the day. And then there's kind of like a murder mystery
Speaker 6:  that happens. It is a slow game. It is a deeply
Speaker 6:  thoughtful game. It is a religious and spiritual
Speaker 6:  game. It would've never ever been
Speaker 6:  made within the Xbox system without Game Pass. And Xbox made a
Speaker 6:  lot of indie games where there is a huge difference between limbo and
Speaker 6:  ment. And I think Xbox proving that
Speaker 6:  is showing like, hey, this is something that we're looking to do inside.
Speaker 6:  I think that they are doing it. I think there's a lot of reasons for them
Speaker 6:  to do that. I think that is a great way to retain talent because
Speaker 6:  how often in the past would it be like, well this person made all their money
Speaker 6:  and now they're gonna leave and go make intimate because they can and being
Speaker 6:  able to say, Hey You know what, stay here. We'll keep you paid, we'll hit
Speaker 6:  take care of your health insurance and you can just make it here. I think
Speaker 6:  that's encouraging. I think it also is a great way for them to test out
Speaker 6:  ideas. Playing a game like Intimate, you can feel a lot
Speaker 6:  of the groundwork for probably much larger games that this studio
Speaker 6:  will do in the future. So it creates I think a healthier ecosystem
Speaker 6:  at these very large companies. Fresh mentioned really earlier
Speaker 6:  in this Dave, the diver at Nexon being You know
Speaker 6:  mistaken for an indie game. But I think it's telling that Nexon would
Speaker 6:  want to try to create something like that and have that as part of their
Speaker 6:  portfolio. It it's feels crass and you have to say like
Speaker 6:  as part of a portfolio. But again, at the end of the day, these are businesses
Speaker 6:  and they're balancing these needs. I am more curious what
Speaker 6:  this means for studios that are not owned by a major publisher though
Speaker 6:  and are like, how will they start designing games towards Game Pass?
Speaker 6:  Especially if they don't have a contract before they You know start
Speaker 6:  work.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's worth noting don don't think there's a scenario, especially in
Speaker 5:  those external cases where they don't kind of
Speaker 5:  start with a, a representation of what the project's gonna be and Pitch to
Speaker 5:  Microsoft and say, Hey, here's what the game is. So no one's starting from
Speaker 5:  zero zero to get on game bass. But I do agree, I think those pitches are
Speaker 5:  altered by game has simply existing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's like the, the I, it just always makes me think about the, the
Speaker 4:  thing on Netflix where like every Netflix miniseries is like two episodes
Speaker 4:  too long because they're, they're very interested in the idea of getting
Speaker 4:  you to watch as long as possible because that's what success looks like.
Speaker 4:  And so every, every movie is 30 minutes too long and every
Speaker 4:  miniseries is two episodes too long. And part of that is just a
Speaker 4:  function of what the system is, right? It's, it's the incentives, it's how
Speaker 4:  people experience these things. It's what gets you in the door. And I
Speaker 4:  think in games that will do some really interesting stuff just in the same
Speaker 4:  way that like the app stores is another recent example of this, right? Like
Speaker 4:  the app store changed the way that people thought about paying for games
Speaker 4:  because it pretty quickly everybody decided that you can't put a $70 game
Speaker 4:  in the app store. Whether that was a good decision historically or let us
Speaker 4:  down a bunch of really horrible roads we can debate. But then that changed
Speaker 4:  a bunch of games and that's where a lot of the free to play stuff started
Speaker 4:  to come from and like our, our loot boxes started to become the thing and
Speaker 4:  it changed Apple Services business and like you spiral all of that out of
Speaker 4:  this like one how it monetizes decision in really
Speaker 4:  messy ways. It also led to a lot of awful, awful crap
Speaker 4:  on the app store that is just designed to con you into paying for stuff you
Speaker 4:  don't actually want. And my fear for something like Game Pass would be that
Speaker 4:  like if not properly curated, it will turn into something like
Speaker 4:  that too. Like I think all the time about Spotify's thing where there are
Speaker 4:  all these white noise podcasts on Spotify making a ton of money
Speaker 4:  because the way that they make money is by getting you
Speaker 4:  to play stuff for a long period of time and if you play a 12 hour noise podcast
Speaker 4:  for eight hours, that's gonna make the podcast some money even
Speaker 4:  though it's just white noise. And so that's just like, it's a little way
Speaker 4:  of breaking the incentive structure that I think there are gonna be ways
Speaker 4:  to do that in games that are gonna be ugly and it's gonna be interesting
Speaker 4:  to see Microsoft and others try to not let that happen.
Speaker 5:  What is good is that because you have to pay for Game Pass,
Speaker 5:  Microsoft really can't put free to play games on Game Pass 'cause those are
Speaker 5:  free. Yeah. So at least you can avoid that. There are games on there
Speaker 5:  that have monetization elements where you can buy skins or whatever it
Speaker 5:  is, even though it is on Game Pass. Broadly speaking, that's not the case.
Speaker 5:  Most of the games that are on there are like pretty full games to begin with.
Speaker 5:  But I do think having that small barrier to entry of payment
Speaker 5:  actually makes a huge difference. Apple Arcade is the other representation
Speaker 5:  of that where none of those games have monetization built in because
Speaker 5:  they're already getting the money up front
Speaker 6:  And both of them are also retailers. So
Speaker 6:  I, it's the difference between like Netflix and Amazon Amazon Prime, right?
Speaker 6:  Where Netflix doesn't also sell the movies so they just try to get as
Speaker 6:  much as possible within Netflix. But I feel like in both the Game Pass
Speaker 6:  and Apple Arcade case, you can have chaos, you can have
Speaker 6:  thousands of options go buy 'em. But when part of the
Speaker 6:  sale of joining these services is the curation
Speaker 6:  You know you're only going to get the quote PEs to the best.
Speaker 4:  No, I think that's right. And I think in if that holds, it can lead to some
Speaker 4:  very cool things and again is another kind of thing that can open up lots
Speaker 4:  of discovery and different avenues for doing different kinds of stuff because
Speaker 4:  you don't just have to bet on the stuff that You know works because you have
Speaker 4:  other ways to put it in front of people. I think that's very cool. Alright,
Speaker 4:  it sounds like all my theories are true. I feel great about this. I I crushed
Speaker 4:  this research project. You
Speaker 5:  Did so well. I'm really proud
Speaker 6:  Of you.
Speaker 4:  I have three questions for the two of you that I have not successfully answered
Speaker 4:  in any way, shape or form by talking to people and that you guys have brought
Speaker 4:  up and I wanna talk about it and then we're gonna get outta here. The first
Speaker 4:  question is, is the $70 price tag for
Speaker 4:  a game gonna last? Can that hold? I see people who are furious about it.
Speaker 4:  I see people who are like, actually that's an
Speaker 4:  undersell for what some of these games are worth. Like is that, is that sustainable
Speaker 4:  in the gaming industry?
Speaker 5:  Certainly not gonna go down. Yeah. Like it's, it's, it's at
Speaker 5:  $70 now for You know quote, next gen games. Obviously
Speaker 5:  smaller games can be cheaper than that, but yeah, that, I think that will
Speaker 5:  stay. But I also think some games, if you're
Speaker 5:  gonna spend Hell Elden Ring perfect example. I played Elden Ring for
Speaker 5:  150 hours, easily worth, I think it was
Speaker 5:  try $60 when it came out, easily worth that $60. I'd pay
Speaker 5:  a hundred dollars and be happy. So yeah, I I I think
Speaker 5:  it is sustainable insofar as it's not gonna come down from that.
Speaker 6:  I also think we're seeing more variety of pricing
Speaker 6:  across the landscape. You know Assassin's Creed Mirage didn't cost
Speaker 6:  $70. Yeah. And yet it's the Ubisoft's big game. There's, I I
Speaker 6:  think it's never great to have to pay more money for things, but
Speaker 6:  also the pricing of video games has been a disaster for
Speaker 6:  two decades. And how that has been
Speaker 6:  addressed has been everything from Horse Armor, You know to
Speaker 6:  other DLC and, and the studios are always trying to figure out like,
Speaker 6:  how are we going to make this work? The
Speaker 6:  industry is a bit more financially perilous than I think sometimes people
Speaker 6:  give it credit for. That's not to say that there aren't CEOs taking just
Speaker 6:  absurd paydays and that there is a better ways to run these businesses,
Speaker 6:  but even with that, the sheer cost to make a game
Speaker 6:  is just getting higher and higher and the risk associated with it is getting
Speaker 6:  higher. With that,
Speaker 5:  What I would also add is go back and find copies of like the Toys or US
Speaker 5:  magazine from when the Super Nintendo launched and you will see the
Speaker 5:  prices were like pretty much in line with the prices we see today,
Speaker 5:  sometimes even over back then. So really game prices
Speaker 5:  have not kept up with inflation in the way that other industries like movie
Speaker 5:  tickets have
Speaker 6:  Though we have Verge listeners, so we will recognize that is because it
Speaker 6:  is cartridges with chips inside and it costs more
Speaker 6:  to actually make them than discs. We recognize all of it. I'm just saying
Speaker 6:  I could, I could feel, I could feel people tensing their hands around
Speaker 6:  their steering wheel being like, am I gonna just drive right off the edge?
Speaker 5:  Companies will charge exactly what they think they can charge and still make
Speaker 5:  money. And
Speaker 4:  I will say it's, there is really no historical precedent for that number
Speaker 4:  going down. I think you're right. Okay. I'm gonna combine my last two questions
Speaker 4:  into one question, which is what the hell is the deal with GTA six?
Speaker 4:  I I, I have talked to so many people and done so much research on this and
Speaker 4:  there is this thing that is happening where the news of a
Speaker 4:  possible forthcoming trailer for GTA six was like
Speaker 4:  Nationwide News. GTA five is like a good game. It's very old,
Speaker 4:  it's very popular. Grand Theft Auto is not like by an order of
Speaker 4:  magnitude, the biggest game on planet earth, but there is something about
Speaker 4:  this game coming we think next year, right?
Speaker 4:  2024 that is different. Like what is the deal with this
Speaker 4:  game?
Speaker 5:  I mean, I would look to, when Grand Theft oh five came out that year,
Speaker 5:  it was a guaranteed lock solid, no question about it. It biggest
Speaker 5:  Game of the Year by a mile and it's continued to make a ton of money
Speaker 5:  over the course of the last decade because of
Speaker 5:  monetization, GTA online stuff.
Speaker 4:  So maybe I'm underwriting how big GTA really is.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah, big time. There are very few games, and this is applies
Speaker 5:  to like Call of Duty as well, very few games in the world that
Speaker 5:  You know for sure are going to totally dominate the
Speaker 5:  sales of a given year and GTA is one of them.
Speaker 4:  What if it sucks? Like, is is there any remote
Speaker 4:  possibility that this just like isn't a good game? It's been a long time.
Speaker 4:  Oh sure,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They've had some turnover with staff. It, it's certainly possible.
Speaker 5:  I mean we've seen You know cyberpunk. Everyone was so sure that
Speaker 5:  that game was gonna come out and be incredible because Witcher was amazing
Speaker 5:  and that studio does amazing work broadly speaking and, and it came out and
Speaker 5:  obviously wasn't. So it's always possible. I do think, and I brought this
Speaker 5:  up earlier, I do think because of the Cyberpunks of the world,
Speaker 5:  if there was a chance that it was gonna come out and be a total disaster,
Speaker 5:  they would hold it. They would not put it out because the amount that they've
Speaker 5:  already sunk into it would not allow them to eat the
Speaker 5:  amount of shit that they would have to eat if it came out and was a disaster.
Speaker 4:  That's fair. Chris, I remember in one of our first
Speaker 4:  conversations about this series, one of the questions you floated was
Speaker 4:  what if GTA six is the last AAA game? I I, I think it
Speaker 4:  won't be, but I think there is something about this
Speaker 4:  moment and this game that feels don don't know Inflective.
Speaker 4:  Is that a thing like at, at an inflection point? Can you be I don, whatever?
Speaker 4:  It feels like a moment in the broader gaming world too.
Speaker 6:  It is because it always is bigger. Every GTA game
Speaker 6:  is bigger than what we thought possible. I remember when I played GTA five
Speaker 6:  for the first time on the Xbox 360 and it felt like the dark arts,
Speaker 6:  it felt like it should not be running on that hardware. And it was just so
Speaker 6:  grand in scope and ambition whether or not it's even good, it's just
Speaker 6:  big. It's funny since we talked about that, I actually dug up an
Speaker 6:  old story and it's telling that I can't even remember if it was during GTA
Speaker 6:  four's launch or GTA's Five's launch, which was by
Speaker 6:  somebody who was saying just that this is the end of AAA games. It can't
Speaker 6:  get any bigger than this. It's not sustainable. We'll never
Speaker 6:  see anything like this ever. And like obviously that was not the
Speaker 6:  case that said we are in a different point in the industry than
Speaker 6:  we were when GTA five and even GTA four came out. Everything we just
Speaker 6:  discussed before this, there is more variety and more choice.
Speaker 6:  There are not just the single player games, it's people
Speaker 6:  might forget the GTA five with online. Online came
Speaker 6:  later and broken and it took a while to like get, get itself up and
Speaker 6:  running. And now either online is an entirely separate game or
Speaker 6:  it It works at the beginning it's gonna be one or the other, but we're not
Speaker 6:  gonna see that that happen again. So yeah, I
Speaker 6:  I don't think it's the last AAA game, but I do think
Speaker 6:  it will feel different than anything that we've seen before it.
Speaker 5:  And I also think the wait for GTA seven might be even
Speaker 5:  longer because they've realized how much money they can make building
Speaker 5:  a really sustainable online system with monetization built in that
Speaker 5:  this feels like the launch of a live service game as much as it is
Speaker 5:  a single player campaign where you You know commit crimes. So
Speaker 5:  yeah, it's gonna be a big deal and it's gonna be a game that we're gonna
Speaker 5:  be all living with for easily a decade, if not 15,
Speaker 5:  who knows? 20. Can
Speaker 6:  I tell you my ridiculous GTA seven theory? Yes. GTA seven
Speaker 6:  is gonna be the return to New York and they're obvi. They've already
Speaker 6:  spoken a lot about their interest in AI and generative tech
Speaker 6:  and I don't think they, they do GTA seven unless you can go in buildings
Speaker 6:  in New York, which would be just an absolute absurd
Speaker 6:  idea. But I don don't know. I I'm curious like
Speaker 6:  what the big turn is as they, as we look
Speaker 6:  You know 15 years out from now, what are they thinking about?
Speaker 5:  Hey, hey Chris Plant we've played it. Guess what? We've played that game
Speaker 5:  you're talking about, it's called Starfield. It's got thousands of planets
Speaker 5:  and you want to go in none of them.
Speaker 6:  Well, no, no, no. See what you forgot though is that game was called load
Speaker 6:  screen. Yeah. I'm talking about a game where you actually get to do the thing
Speaker 6:  that you're promised. Man, Starfield really walked into the room at the wrong
Speaker 6:  time. I'm sorry, Starfield not that bad of a game. I'm very interested
Speaker 6:  in, man, maybe this is a series that we do next. That distant
Speaker 6:  future of video games is where I'm really curious about what things
Speaker 6:  are going to get because on top of all these other inflection points, we
Speaker 6:  are hitting a technological moment that I think is going to
Speaker 6:  really change what video games look like and feel like.
Speaker 4:  I think that's right. I've heard a surprising amount of people saying generative
Speaker 4:  AI is going to completely change everything about how we make and experience
Speaker 4:  video games. And everybody says that about generative AI and everything.
Speaker 4:  So I'm like, I I kind of do a lot of like patting people on the head when
Speaker 4:  they say that stuff. But I think fast forward a while and, and you're, you're
Speaker 4:  probably not wrong.
Speaker 6:  I was just gonna say with generative ai, I understand that people hear that
Speaker 6:  and they might think like, oh, generative AI is like creating a game that
Speaker 6:  I hit the make me a good game button. I'm not talking about that. Like
Speaker 6:  if you go to any of these major studios, they are farming out
Speaker 6:  so much work to people who just make
Speaker 6:  apples and fake Blu-rays and tables that they put in their game.
Speaker 6:  Just, just stuff assets.
Speaker 6:  That is a thing that I, I think will be filling that, right? Like
Speaker 6:  there are, and again, whether or not that's good or evil or
Speaker 6:  or whatever is a whole different thing, but it is going to allow
Speaker 6:  for scale at a, in a way that I think is gonna be kind of
Speaker 6:  disorienting at first
Speaker 4:  All, right? Well in 2038, the three of us are gonna do like a hologram
Speaker 4:  revisit of this series and we're gonna see what we got right and what we
Speaker 4:  got wrong. But for now, we gotta go thank you both for doing this. This series
Speaker 4:  has been been so much fun. We're gonna have to like invent a reason to do
Speaker 4:  this again. I have very much enjoyed doing this with you guys.
Speaker 6:  Hey, can we plug our show
Speaker 4:  Please?
Speaker 6:  If you have enjoyed listening to Russ Frushtick and myself,
Speaker 6:  we have a podcast called The Besties that we do every week with
Speaker 6:  Justin and Griffin McElroy of the Adventure Zone and my brother
Speaker 6:  and my brother and me. That's kind of how you say it. And we also
Speaker 6:  have a every other week spinoff on the same feed called the Rest Eats, where
Speaker 6:  it's just fresh and I kind of getting into the nitty gritty of things. So
Speaker 6:  if you enjoy that, you can get that. And if you enjoyed us being here,
Speaker 6:  you can reach David at Neli
Speaker 6:  Patel at compuserve.com I think is his email address.
Speaker 6:  Yep, that's right. And and we'll take care of it from there.
Speaker 4:  I'll leave his phone number in the show notes.
Speaker 6:  One 800 Cool guy.
Speaker 4:  Perfect. Awesome. Thank you both. We will, we will do this again someday.
Speaker 4:  When GTA seven comes out. It's gonna be epic
Speaker 4:  All, right? That's it for The. Vergecast, thanks to Chris and Russ for being
Speaker 4:  here. This was super fun. I will miss you terribly. And thanks to all of
Speaker 4:  you as always for listening. As always, if you have thoughts, questions,
Speaker 4:  feelings, or other big games you wanna talk about, you can always email
Speaker 4:  us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or keep calling the hotline.
Speaker 4:  8 6 6 Verge one one. We have some fun hotline stuff planned between now and
Speaker 4:  the end of the year, so keep calling in with all of your questions, thoughts
Speaker 4:  and ideas. This show is produced by Andrew Moreno and Liam James The. Vergecast
Speaker 4:  is a VERGE production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. We're off
Speaker 4:  for the rest of this week for the Thanksgiving holiday, but we'll be back
Speaker 4:  next week because there is more news. We got some fun end of the year stuff
Speaker 4:  coming, all kinds of good stuff. We'll see you then. Rock and roll.
Speaker 2:  This podcast is brought to you by Meta Quest three, the new mixed reality
Speaker 2:  headset from Meta. Expand your world in ways you never thought possible with
Speaker 2:  the new Meta Quest. Three, put on the most powerful quest yet and
Speaker 2:  jump into fully immersive games like Assassin's Creed Nexus or
Speaker 2:  blend virtual elements into your surroundings in games like Stranger Things
Speaker 2:  vr. With over 500 titles, it's easy to dive into
Speaker 2:  whatever you're into. Expand your world with Meta Quest three. See child
Speaker 2:  safety guidance online accounts for 10 and up. Certain apps, games and experiences
Speaker 2:  may be suitable for a more mature audience. Learn more at Meta dot com.