# Transcript
ID: 1f625b19-f2f0-4e8d-867c-5e533cf1107a
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Streaming goes up, Zoom comes down
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-3704744136869309994/-6784691839489150366/s93290-US-5506s-1691757547.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz break down the chaotic and increasingly more expensive state of streaming video. Are we just recreating cable TV? And afterwards, the crew explores the wild world enterprise software.
Speaker 3:  Hollywood writers and actors are still striking and one of the things
Speaker 3:  they're fighting against is AI swooping in and taking their jobs.
Speaker 3:  But truth is AI is already all over Hollywood.
Speaker 4:  You know Harrison Ford has come out and said that
Speaker 4:  he not only is okay with the de aging process that was
Speaker 4:  used in the most recent Indiana Jones, but he thought it was skillfully
Speaker 3:  Done. The fight over AI in TV and film This
Speaker 3:  week on Intuit. Vultures Pop culture podcast.
Speaker 5:  Hello and Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of integrating
Speaker 5:  apps into five g a plan. That totally worked. And
Speaker 5:  now we live in a utopia of robot surgery and video conferencing.
Speaker 5:  David, what's Utopia like? We're
Speaker 6:  The flagship podcast of all of that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, the whole thing.
Speaker 6:  It's a lot to be the flagship podcast of,
Speaker 5:  It's a big concept. There's not a lot of competition in the space. And
Speaker 5:  that's, that's business baby. You gotta find, find,
Speaker 5:  you gotta find your, your niche. I'm your friend. Neli. David. Pierce is
Speaker 5:  here.
Speaker 6:  Hi, I I too am integrated into five g
Speaker 5:  Alex. Cranz is here. Alex is in San Francisco.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I'm in San Francisco. Wondering like, who isn't integrated into five
Speaker 7:  G At this point. Come on guys, get it together.
Speaker 5:  I saw in one of the trade publications, I saw a headline that was like, the
Speaker 5:  hottest thing in five G isn't public, five G networks. And then
Speaker 5:  what is it? It's private five G like obviously the other things. Sure.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So they've, they've given up on us, the lowly
Speaker 5:  public and your private five G network for
Speaker 5:  warehouse operations is where the money is. And I just want to go
Speaker 5:  back in time and like show people that headline in meetings like
Speaker 5:  you are lying.
Speaker 6:  The hottest thing in public five G is still slightly faster.
Speaker 6:  Netflix downloads in the airport before you get on the plane,
Speaker 5:  Which isn't bad. It's like, I don't hate it. It's something. But we could've
Speaker 5:  just, we could've just fixed the wifi networks in the airport. I think we
Speaker 5:  would've gotten
Speaker 6:  It. There's that.
Speaker 5:  Anyway, this is not the flagship podcast of any of that, although I promise
Speaker 5:  you there'll be a slight amount of telecom five G Dunking
Speaker 5:  in this episode of the verse cast. That's what we do here every
Speaker 7:  Episode. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  As is our right.
Speaker 5:  A lot talk about this week, a bunch of Streaming news this week. Slack had
Speaker 5:  a redesign. We have some reader emails, which are always fun.
Speaker 5:  There's some CarPlay news to get into. Got a
Speaker 5:  MrBeast update. There's just like a lot going on like a, like a summer grab
Speaker 5:  bag. But like we did last week, we want to begin by just getting the
Speaker 5:  Elon News out of the way. We, we know you like
Speaker 5:  it even though you, you tell us you don't like it. I don't know how to
Speaker 5:  describe the exact phenomenon. You tell us
Speaker 5:  loudly. You hate it in the comments of the posts that you have clicked on.
Speaker 5:  Read to the Bottom and then left comments on It is,
Speaker 5:  it is a weird dynamic, but we know You know you want it. So David, can
Speaker 5:  you just give us quickly all of the Elon news this week that's worth talking
Speaker 5:  about?
Speaker 6:  Sure. Okay. Here, here is everything I've compiled
Speaker 6:  that has happened this week. That matters.
Speaker 6:  All right. That's it.
Speaker 6:  That help everybody feel good.
Speaker 5:  It's beautiful. That's all the news in the world of Elon that is actually
Speaker 5:  worth noting this week. Just a dull roar
Speaker 5:  of noise. And that's where we are this week with Elon. So that's good. The
Speaker 6:  Only actual Elon thing I'll say is that Casey Newton wrote a very good
Speaker 6:  issue of platformer that we also ran on The Verge about how we talk about
Speaker 6:  Elon. That I thought was very good and very instructive and people should
Speaker 6:  go read that. Yep.
Speaker 5:  It's on the site. It's on platform Mark. Go read it. Case is great. Okay,
Speaker 5:  let's talk about national news. We've been sort of talking at this moment
Speaker 5:  in Streaming, the two strikes that are going on, the interlocking
Speaker 5:  strikes between the writers and the actors. Bob Iger had gave
Speaker 5:  an interview to C N B C A while ago that set everything astray.
Speaker 5:  Then there were some news that said the writers are coming back to the table
Speaker 5:  at the studios. Disney had earnings, which were really revealing. Alex, what
Speaker 5:  is going on in the world of Streaming?
Speaker 7:  Well I think the big thing is Disney's hiking the price of Hulu
Speaker 7:  and Disney Plus, but only the
Speaker 7:  ad-free version. So if you're already paying 7
Speaker 7:  99 a month for the ads, you're fine.
Speaker 7:  Keep enjoying all of those beautiful ads. If you were like me trying
Speaker 7:  to avoid the ads, the prices have gone up. Disney Plus is now
Speaker 7:  gonna cost 1399 and then
Speaker 7:  Hulu no ads is gonna cost 1799. But if
Speaker 7:  you wanna keep both, you can just pay 1999. Oh
Speaker 7:  boy, And I. Think the streamers were looking out in the world and they were
Speaker 7:  thinking, okay, how can we make this pricing scheme make sense? And they
Speaker 7:  just looked to like cell phone providers. Like
Speaker 7:  that's my best guess. 'cause it's just like caught confusing garbage.
Speaker 7:  Can
Speaker 6:  I just say there's a table in the story we wrote about the price
Speaker 6:  hike that lays out the different prices that you can pay for
Speaker 6:  Disney's various Streaming services. And it is like deranged
Speaker 6:  how complicated this is. If you want Disney plus, there's two options. If
Speaker 6:  you want Hulu, there's four options including one that is ans
Speaker 6:  espn plus with Hulu add-on No boy, which I guess is also Hulu if you want
Speaker 6:  ESPN plus there's three other ones. If you want bundle offerings, there's
Speaker 6:  three other ones. And if you just want Hulu with plus live tv, there's two
Speaker 6:  other ones. So basically you have like 400,000 different ways to
Speaker 6:  get all of Disney's content, but it's abundantly clear.
Speaker 6:  Alex, correct me if I'm wrong, that the thing Disney would really like you
Speaker 6:  to do is pay 7 99 and watch ads.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. 'cause why have a Streaming service when you
Speaker 7:  can just have a couple of cable channels where you don't have to
Speaker 7:  deal with cable carriers? Like if I'm, if I'm a business person,
Speaker 7:  that makes a lot of sense to be, if I'm a person who wants anything to be
Speaker 7:  nice and effortless and work smoothly, it makes no sense. But,
Speaker 7:  but like the business case makes a lot of sense. And I hate it because it
Speaker 7:  makes so much sense. But yeah, we're just kind of like back to cable
Speaker 7:  again. Yeah. But we have to do it all ourselves. Which is, I mean, that was
Speaker 7:  the point, right? Like that was the, that was the initial promise of this.
Speaker 7:  All right. Like we were gonna cut our cables and then we were gonna be really
Speaker 7:  happy because we could just choose And. I would never have to pay for E S
Speaker 7:  P N. Again.
Speaker 5:  What I'm learning now in my old age is that by making everyone
Speaker 5:  pay for everything, we subsidized a lot of the niche stuff. Yeah. So
Speaker 5:  everyone that was forced to pay for E S P N, that made them a
Speaker 5:  lot of money. Just a, a lot of money that they could then subsidize a lot
Speaker 5:  of stuff with
Speaker 6:  Like the Disney channel,
Speaker 5:  Right? And then when you break it all up and you say, everyone pay for exactly
Speaker 5:  what you want, it turns out like that's
Speaker 7:  Expensive.
Speaker 5:  Everyone will pay for exactly what they want and everything will make smaller.
Speaker 5:  Like the pie will stay the same size, but it'll have more slices.
Speaker 5:  And that's not great. And so it's very clear they're trying to get back to,
Speaker 5:  okay, you pay for access to this, the advertisers will come in. 'cause the
Speaker 5:  advertisers will spend a lot of money and that'll give us the
Speaker 5:  margin to go subsidize all the other stuff. It's not clear if that's gonna
Speaker 5:  work either, but that's just very much where they would like to go back to.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. I mean it, it is deeply hilarious to me
Speaker 6:  how quickly we're going back to it should just be like
Speaker 6:  cable but better. And it's like if, if you could just go back 20 years
Speaker 6:  and be any of these big cable providers, and if they were just like, what
Speaker 6:  if we just let people pick the shows they wanted to watch and changed nothing
Speaker 6:  else, they would've just dominated the universe for
Speaker 6:  forever. Because it turns out that's all people actually wanted. Like I just
Speaker 6:  want to choose what show is on turned out to be the only behavior anybody
Speaker 6:  actually wanted to change. Everything else was like pretty all right in most
Speaker 6:  cases. Well, there was,
Speaker 7:  There was a sports agnostic folks like
Speaker 7:  who didn't wanna have to pay for E S P N and now I don't have to. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But all the people who watched E S P N were paying for the Disney channel
Speaker 6:  and Nickelodeon and all of the other stuff on your TV that got
Speaker 6:  funded by the fact that E S P N made so much money, right? Like E S P N
Speaker 6:  was such a cash cow for Disney that it funded all this other stuff. And so
Speaker 6:  it's just like, in a way, this system like didn't make any sense, but
Speaker 6:  actually seems like it kind of worked except that cable was bad and expensive.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Oh,
Speaker 5:  I'm saying look, every like 15 years or so, there's like a lawsuit from someone
Speaker 5:  who's like, my taxes go to the military, And I don't want my taxes to go
Speaker 5:  to the military. And then they lose. That was
Speaker 7:  Us. That was us
Speaker 5:  Esp. It's like, and then like the lawsuit goes and the court's like, nah,
Speaker 5:  that's not how taxes work. Like Right. You pay your taxes, you go, everyone
Speaker 5:  gets decide. That's E S P N E S P N is the military industrial
Speaker 5:  complex. Yeah. And we, the American consumers should be forced to pay our
Speaker 5:  taxes because that subsidizes like the 35th show
Speaker 5:  on the Disney channel. Right. And that's how that's gonna work. Well,
Speaker 6:  And it's like, do You know how that, like your Google Maps knows where you
Speaker 6:  are? Like, thank the military for g P s being a thing. Right. It's like it
Speaker 6:  turns out like all this stuff is connected a little more than
Speaker 5:  You think. So, but this is like Disney had earnings, right? And their earnings
Speaker 5:  are mixed bag, it's earnings are never that interesting to talk about.
Speaker 5:  But they lost a bunch of subscribers in India because they lost the rights
Speaker 5:  to cricket. So Disney Plus is coming back down to Earth, but
Speaker 5:  the parks are doing well, and it's just unclear what new
Speaker 5:  content they will have because of the strikes
Speaker 5:  Iger notably was like, I hope we can figure this out this time.
Speaker 5:  Whereas a few months ago, he was like, I'm very disturbed by these sick bastards.
Speaker 5:  You know. Like the tone has shifted a little bit
Speaker 5:  and it just seems clear. Like Disney, they've got a, they've gotta
Speaker 5:  power through this moment and actually have stuff worth buying and watching.
Speaker 5:  And it's sort of unclear what that stuff is gonna be.
Speaker 7:  Well, and that's, that's part of this too, is like you think, okay, they,
Speaker 7:  they did Disney, Disney Plus and Marvel was supposed to be a big
Speaker 7:  subscriber. Like the main reason people subscribe to Disney Plus is 'cause
Speaker 7:  they have children. But everybody who doesn't have children, myself included,
Speaker 7:  we wanna like, why would we wanna go subscribe? And the idea was, okay, well
Speaker 7:  you're gonna subscribe for Star Wars and you're gonna subscribe for Marvel,
Speaker 7:  and then all those shows are kind of garbage.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It sounded like a pretty compelling argument. And even at the beginning
Speaker 6:  it was pretty good. Like Wand Visions was great. Yeah. The Mandalorian was
Speaker 6:  great. It was like, it started well, and then just over the course of the
Speaker 6:  next few years, they just systematically got worse. Right. As all the other
Speaker 6:  factors got harder for Disney. And so it's just like this perfect storm of
Speaker 6:  like, what is the pitch here? And it seems to get harder and harder
Speaker 6:  all the time.
Speaker 7:  Like you could not get, pay people to care about
Speaker 7:  Secret Invasion, which was the, the latest Marvel show. I, I watched all
Speaker 7:  of it.
Speaker 7:  I know what happened. Do I ever wanna talk with anyone else about
Speaker 7:  it?
Speaker 5:  You're like, no. Barely wanna admit that you watch the show. Here's my
Speaker 5:  understanding of secret invasion. Just to be clear, I have not watched it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I've barely paid attention to it. It's the show where everyone is
Speaker 5:  revealed to be an alien so that they can recast new actors in those roles,
Speaker 5:  the next movies. Yeah. I
Speaker 7:  Mean, and that kind of like, that's a big part of it. Okay. And it's,
Speaker 5:  But my sense of it is, the reveal in every episode is this beloved
Speaker 5:  character has always been an alien. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  It's like this person is secretly an alien. The
Speaker 6:  Show is just like, it's like an intermission between Marvel things. They're
Speaker 6:  just like, here's we're, we're going to reboot the show over
Speaker 6:  seven Yeah. Different episodes. And then at the end of it, new
Speaker 6:  Avengers. Yeah. Basically.
Speaker 5:  It
Speaker 7:  Was so
Speaker 5:  Bad. Like, it, it seems it's cynical on its face. Like just even
Speaker 5:  I know that much about it, which I don't even think that's spoilers, like
Speaker 5:  the show's called Secret Invasion, I think Yeah. It, that's what it is on
Speaker 5:  the Tint You know, like, I don't think I spoiled anything about this show
Speaker 5:  for anyone, but it, it's like, oh, we need some new actors. So
Speaker 5:  what if all the old actors are revealed to be aliens and then they get in
Speaker 5:  a spaceship and go back to their home planet. It's like, oh, this is, you
Speaker 5:  guys are really out of ideas here. Like, you're starting over. I think they,
Speaker 5:  oh, they now that's a spoiler Alex now that people are gonna use this.
Speaker 7:  Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Nevermind guys. So,
Speaker 5:  But the big picture here is just generally across the
Speaker 5:  Streaming market, Disney has these problems. They're gonna start doing some
Speaker 5:  Netflix news, right? They're gonna actively explore cracking down on password
Speaker 5:  sharing, which seems to have worked really well for Netflix. They keep
Speaker 5:  gesturing at the idea of selling themselves to Apple.
Speaker 7:  This. Okay. Okay. I wanna, like, this is, this is what I wanna call, I wanna
Speaker 7:  use, I'm gonna drop a a curse word here. This is utter bullshit. This happens
Speaker 7:  like every time Apple is one of those companies that has a ton of money and
Speaker 7:  they always have a ton of cash around, right? And so everybody's like, oh,
Speaker 7:  what should they do with it? And like six, seven years ago, I was like, they
Speaker 7:  should buy Netflix. Yeah. And they were never gonna buy Netflix because that
Speaker 7:  doesn't make sense.
Speaker 6:  First of all, they absolutely should have bought Netflix.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It would've been great then, but they were never going to because it
Speaker 7:  didn't make sense. And the idea that they were gonna go and like Tim Cook,
Speaker 7:  who's entire thing is like making money by being really smart about logistics
Speaker 7:  is gonna take on the cruise and the theme park
Speaker 7:  industry. Tim cook's about to retire. Like he doesn't
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's why you buy Disney at the end and you're like, look, Bob Iger,
Speaker 5:  you hate retiring. Yeah. Have you thought of being the c e o of here you
Speaker 5:  go, I bought Disney. You just, I'm gonna, I'm Tim Cook, here's
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Now you go and do all the keynotes.
Speaker 5:  My swan song is headsets and cruises together at last, and,
Speaker 5:  and then he just rides off in the the sunset. That's
Speaker 7:  A very like retiree swan song
Speaker 5:  On a horse made of money. This is the future of cruises is you get on
Speaker 5:  and you put on your Apple Vision Pro on your Disney cruise, and you
Speaker 5:  sit in a recliner,
Speaker 6:  But you're not actually on a boat at all. You're just
Speaker 5:  At home. Well you're, you're, you're in a sound stage that rocks. You
Speaker 7:  Have a little Mickey assistant. This is
Speaker 5:  By the way, the plot of Wally. So a little worried,
Speaker 5:  but at least at the end, You know they save Earth.
Speaker 6:  I don't know. So the Disney apple thing has always seemed suspicious
Speaker 6:  to me. Like to the point where it's, I I I have always agreed with you Alex
Speaker 6:  that this is like a thing people say because it sort of seems like it makes
Speaker 6:  sense, but never was actually real. But the two things that happened this
Speaker 6:  week that I thought were very interesting were Kim Masters at the Hollywood
Speaker 6:  Reporter, who is very much like a person who knows everything about what's
Speaker 6:  happening in Hollywood wrote a one of those stories that is
Speaker 6:  like half reported and half speculative, but it's only speculative because
Speaker 6:  you can't say out loud the things that other people have said to you that
Speaker 6:  You know for sure. Right. Like reading between the lines. This thing is like
Speaker 6:  very accurate and very well sourced about, basically,
Speaker 6:  hypothetically, if you were Disney, here is what you would do if you wanted
Speaker 6:  to sell your company to Apple. You would divest, you would pull the different
Speaker 6:  pieces apart and you would essentially turn yourself into a company
Speaker 6:  full of characters and IP without a lot of stuff
Speaker 6:  attached to it. And then you would sell that to Apple. And then you look
Speaker 6:  around and, oh, that's exactly what Bob Iger kind of sounds like he wants
Speaker 6:  to do with Disney. And so that happened.
Speaker 6:  The piece is very good. It's, we have it linked on The Verge, we should put
Speaker 6:  it in the show notes too. Like Kim is is a person who knows things.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I. I trust, I, I don't think Kim is like making this up out of
Speaker 6:  whole cloth. And then the other thing was, somebody on Disney's earnings
Speaker 6:  call asked Bob Iger directly something to the effect
Speaker 6:  of, are you selling to Apple? And his answer was,
Speaker 6:  he said, basically, I'm not gonna say anything. It's not something that we
Speaker 6:  have obsessed about. And then he said, obviously anyone who wanted to speculate
Speaker 6:  about these things would have to immediately consider the global regulatory
Speaker 6:  environment. And then he said, I'll say no more than that. How do you not
Speaker 6:  read that as, gosh, I'd really like to, but Lehan and the FTC
Speaker 6:  super, super, super would not allow it to happen. Like, I don't know how
Speaker 6:  else to read that statement from Bob Liger.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And I think that's, that goes back to the, the fact that this isn't
Speaker 7:  gonna happen. I mean, theoretically it could, right? Like, like,
Speaker 7:  like I'm, I don't wanna say it's never gonna happen, but it's very unlikely
Speaker 7:  to because the EU would come down on that new combined
Speaker 7:  company and just, just destroy it. Yes. Like they
Speaker 7:  would never allow it to happen. And it would be just borderline
Speaker 7:  unconscionable for the F T C to let two of the biggest companies, the company
Speaker 7:  that has like a practical monopoly in the theater space,
Speaker 7:  practical monopoly in all these other spaces, and the company that has the
Speaker 7:  App store monopoly combine into one mega company.
Speaker 7:  Like that's bad business unless you're Bob Iger.
Speaker 5:  All right, I'm gonna, I'm gonna, I'm gonna, I'm gonna make the argument do
Speaker 5:  it.
Speaker 7:  Okay. Be
Speaker 5:  Bob, I'm coming back to Disney as C e o.
Speaker 7:  Wow. Congratulations.
Speaker 5:  The first thing Bob Iger says in every room, look, I was leaving, but
Speaker 5:  I'm coming back now. Here's the argument. I have two arguments to make. One
Speaker 5:  is like a straightforward argument. We kinda went through this with Microsoft
Speaker 5:  and Activision and eventually the EU caved and the Ft C lost and like
Speaker 5:  whatever, right? Like it is the same shape of thing, right? The
Speaker 5:  big distribution platform buys a bunch of content. We seem
Speaker 5:  to not know how to stop it. It just happens. Fine.
Speaker 5:  Maybe it will just happen. I don't know if it will, but obviously Bob Iger
Speaker 5:  is thinking about the global regulatory environment. Then there's, I think
Speaker 5:  what I would frame as the chaos argument, which is
Speaker 5:  let them dance. You know, like this is how companies fall apart,
Speaker 5:  is like they get too big. Yeah. And then this thing seems
Speaker 5:  unmanageable and like Apple's corporate culture
Speaker 5:  will crush Disney. And then maybe we'll be free
Speaker 5:  You know. It's like, that's like, it's the, it's the worst argument I can
Speaker 5:  make. It is I will say the argument that, for example,
Speaker 5:  has proven to be correct in the case of every at t acquisition in history.
Speaker 5:  But Fi Go ahead. Buy Time Warner. Try to try to rule
Speaker 5:  the world.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean, I was gonna say a o l Time Warner is exactly this kind of
Speaker 6:  merger that you're describing also. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, yeah, go ahead. Try. Like see, see if that works out for you.
Speaker 5:  See if, see if you are not destroyed by your own hubris, I'm not saying that's
Speaker 5:  a great policy outcome. Many, many people lose their jobs along the way
Speaker 5:  and lots of art doesn't get made. Although with Time Warn and at and
Speaker 5:  t we did get the Gray Scale four by three Justice League.
Speaker 5:  So that happened.
Speaker 7:  We're gonna get like a Marvel movie just shot all vertically. So it fits
Speaker 7:  perfectly on your iPhone and profile. That's what you're getting. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I mean look, I I, I'm not saying they should or shouldn't do it. I just think
Speaker 5:  that like if I'm Tim Cook, I'm looking at the history of
Speaker 5:  these kinds of integrations and I'm saying, oh actually in the end,
Speaker 5:  this never works out. Like it doesn't matter about the regulators. Like
Speaker 5:  if you are a smart business person, you look at integrations of this size
Speaker 5:  and you're like, oh,
Speaker 5:  this is death. Like this is what kills both companies in like
Speaker 5:  meaningful ways At the end of the road.
Speaker 7:  He's told people no in the past. Right? Like, wasn't there the one where
Speaker 7:  Elon was like, please buy Tesla. Before Tesla was Tesla. Yeah. And he was
Speaker 7:  like, l o l get out of my office. How did you get in here? Actually,
Speaker 5:  Speaking of things that should have bought right? Like the many,
Speaker 5:  many, many attempts that Apple has made to make a car. Yeah. It
Speaker 5:  should have just bought Tesla. Yeah. Yes. They would've solved the panel
Speaker 5:  gaps, I'll tell you that much.
Speaker 5:  They wouldn't have cheaped outta the materials.
Speaker 6:  There just would be no door handles at all. Your whole
Speaker 7:  Hand goes in those panel gaps.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But this is the thing that comes up every time the like possibility
Speaker 6:  of Apple acquiring some sexy company comes up. Like, do you remember a
Speaker 6:  couple of years ago when Peloton was flagging and everybody was like, oh,
Speaker 6:  Apple's gonna buy Peloton. And then there were a couple of people, I think
Speaker 6:  including our friend Steve Kovac at C N B C, who just
Speaker 6:  basically raised their hand and were like, why on earth would Apple want
Speaker 6:  Peloton? Like why all these companies need Apple? Makes a lot of sense.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Why Apple need the richest company on
Speaker 6:  the planet that has done a very good job of developing the ability to do
Speaker 6:  almost anything very well over time. Why on earth would it
Speaker 6:  need like a warehouse full of treadmills and bikes that no one is
Speaker 6:  buying? Yeah. And in this case, like what does Apple need with a theme park?
Speaker 5:  I mean, they run a very nice theme park in Cupertino. It's a circle
Speaker 5:  the way. Yeah. It's a, i I I guess like a, the basic business
Speaker 5:  advice is like, don't buy problems. You know. Like yeah, this is a huge
Speaker 5:  problem. Like the future of Streaming is a huge problem. Apple's involved
Speaker 5:  in these strikes, right? They are part of the A M P T P. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They're up against sag. They're up against the Writer's Guild Disclosure
Speaker 5:  Alex is part of the Writer's Guild. Our newsroom is unionized with the Writer's
Speaker 5:  Guild. I'm a Netflix producer. Comcast owns a chunk of the company. You should
Speaker 5:  watch our Netflix show. It's great.
Speaker 6:  That was your best one yet. That was like all in one breath. That was really
Speaker 6:  good. Whew.
Speaker 5:  Someone wrote to us and said, your disclosures are starting to sound like
Speaker 5:  flexes. So I'm trying to, but it is true that I'm a Netflix producer.
Speaker 5:  You should watch your Netflix show. That's great. It was nominated for an
Speaker 5:  Emmy. Oh, so
Speaker 6:  You've, you've mech for your other podcast Now. Do you wanna
Speaker 5:  Disclose that? Oh yeah. You can go to store@themerch.com and buy, buy literally
Speaker 5:  my name on a hat. So that's a weird moment for me
Speaker 5:  personally.
Speaker 5:  That's all just really complicated for Apple. And this is like their first
Speaker 5:  baby step in the water, right? They're not like a huge distributor of TV
Speaker 5:  shows. Buying Disney is like now they're in it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like they're fully in. Like let's a good example. Jason Klar took over
Speaker 5:  for at Time Warner, right? He took over Warner Media and he was like, here's
Speaker 5:  the thing we wanna do. All the movies are gonna go to Streaming Day and Date.
Speaker 5:  That is a thing that Apple would want to do to promote Apple TV plus on their
Speaker 5:  devices. And that thing broke. Warner Media pushed
Speaker 5:  Klar out of the c e o role and we ended it with Discovery Max
Speaker 5:  plus whatever it's called. Those are culture decisions that
Speaker 5:  you have to make. They're not business decisions. And, I. Think Apple likes
Speaker 5:  being at a remove the thing that I would offer and,
Speaker 5:  and we have an entire episode about sports and Streaming coming next week,
Speaker 5:  but Apple's really into sports. Yep. And I think they really wanna do sports
Speaker 5:  in the Vision Pro in like a serious way. E S P N over the past couple months
Speaker 5:  and in particular last week, just sort of like casually rearranged the sports
Speaker 5:  media market. Yeah. Right. They took Pat McAfee who was
Speaker 5:  kind of the, one of the biggest indie sports podcasters
Speaker 5:  video people. He had a deal with FanDuel Disney just
Speaker 5:  took him away. He, I think he was unhappy with that FanDuel deal. He's now
Speaker 5:  just part of the E S P N lineup. Like big, huge
Speaker 5:  multimillion dollar deal. And then this last week, Penn
Speaker 5:  Gaming, which was another betting company, heavily invested in Barstool sports.
Speaker 5:  A lot of machinations there. But they basically just gave it back to Dave
Speaker 5:  Portnoy, who is a controversial character in his own right. And said, you
Speaker 5:  can have Barstool, we're going with Disney, we're going with espn. Wow. And
Speaker 5:  e, ESPN opened up to betting for the first time in partnership with Penn.
Speaker 5:  So just in like the last few months, E S P N has just like
Speaker 5:  repositioned some of the biggest indie names in sports media and entered
Speaker 5:  betting. That's all just a lot. Right. That and that those are power
Speaker 5:  moves. Like yeah. This is how E S P N wants it to be. This is how e ESP n
Speaker 5:  is gonna get it. That puts E S P N in the driver's
Speaker 5:  seat of kinda the next turn of things maybe. But
Speaker 5:  it's not clear that Apple wants to be in like the betting business at all.
Speaker 5:  Right?
Speaker 6:  No, I would say it seems overwhelmingly likely that Apple doesn't want to
Speaker 6:  be in that business. Like to the extent that like betting apps are in the
Speaker 6:  App store seems to be only headache for Apple. Yeah. And, I can't imagine
Speaker 6:  them signing up for the, the regulatory complications that
Speaker 6:  come with that anytime soon. And I think like to your, to your point about
Speaker 6:  getting into this world fully, even with
Speaker 6:  TV plus, apple has been sort of dragged kicking and screaming into the
Speaker 6:  broader Hollywood landscape. Like it, it had to commit to spending a bunch
Speaker 6:  of money to put its movies in theaters. It's slowly
Speaker 6:  becoming more of a part of Hollywood. But even still, like
Speaker 6:  Apple's whole thing is, it likes things that can wrap its arms entirely around.
Speaker 6:  And even if you own Disney, you just can't do that. Yeah. So
Speaker 6:  like I can see what Disney would want from Apple out of some You know
Speaker 6:  partnership. What's the phrase everybody uses? Special relationship that,
Speaker 6:  that they had with jobs because Jobs owned Pixar. Yeah. And there was some,
Speaker 6:  he was
Speaker 5:  The largest shareholder of Disney. It wasn't a special relationship. He was
Speaker 5:  the largest individual shareholder of Disney. Yeah. Right. So he was like,
Speaker 5:  I can call them. And they picked up the phone. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  He and Bob had like a special handshake that they did. Yeah. And they would
Speaker 6:  like do butterfly kisses when they saw each other. And that's, that was the
Speaker 6:  Disney Apple relationship.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, I, I'm, I tend to be with you Cranz that this won't happen.
Speaker 6:  But I do think it is possible that we will get to a point where both companies
Speaker 6:  want it to happen, but ultimately decide they can't.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. For a variety of reasons. We
Speaker 7:  Were hearing those rumors a couple of weeks ago that they might get rid of
Speaker 7:  E S P N, they might sell Elf E S P N or something like that, that I
Speaker 7:  could maybe see happening. But even then it's back to like, does Apple
Speaker 7:  wanna get into gambling and also doing sports deals? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Probably not. It's
Speaker 6:  It's a mess. I
Speaker 5:  Think they wanna do sports deals, not gambling. Go ahead.
Speaker 6:  I was just gonna say, can we get a real quick strike update before we throw
Speaker 6:  a break and move on from this stuff? 'cause I feel like a bunch of this stuff
Speaker 6:  came up in these earnings calls and people are back at the table, but not
Speaker 6:  back at the table. So it's,
Speaker 7:  It's all negotiations, which means everybody's gonna have their
Speaker 7:  own opinion on who's the one stepping back. Right now the
Speaker 7:  Writer's Guild is saying, well, it's the producers. They're not coming to
Speaker 7:  the table. They refuse to come to the table. And the producers are like,
Speaker 7:  Uhuh, we're here. And so it's not clear. There's still
Speaker 7:  definitely a lot of like, discourse there and, and people upset with each
Speaker 7:  other. But the, the Emmys have been delayed because
Speaker 7:  of the strikes, right? Because like, you can't have a bunch
Speaker 7:  like it. What good are the Emmys if You don't have a bunch of actors up on
Speaker 7:  stage being like, yay, I want an Emmy. Like it's, it's just the technical
Speaker 7:  Emmys and those are really good, but they haven't televised those for years,
Speaker 7:  so I don't think we're gonna start now. And so you've got that
Speaker 7:  Paramount just, just came out and was like, well, we are totally set. We
Speaker 7:  we are, we are, we, we are refined. We can weather continue to weather this.
Speaker 7:  And this is where I'm super suspicious of other companies who were like,
Speaker 7:  yeah, I just don't know if we're gonna have all the content we need. Because
Speaker 7:  they all knew this, these strikes were coming. They all knew this was
Speaker 7:  going to be happening. They've all been banking shows for, for a while
Speaker 7:  now to get through this. So any of 'em who say, well, I didn't know
Speaker 7:  and everything be super suspicious there. Like, take a moment, look around
Speaker 7:  and be like, is that true? Because it's, it's certainly
Speaker 7:  interesting and everybody's gonna keep doing this. This is gonna be like,
Speaker 7:  there's always, you're gonna have both sides expressing their truth,
Speaker 7:  which is certainly the truth, but it's also specifically their
Speaker 7:  versions of it. So You know, maybe Disney doesn't have
Speaker 7:  enough content to get them through. They could bring Willow back
Speaker 7:  instead of yanking it off of Disney Plus after a few months, I'm fine.
Speaker 7:  I'm not bitter. It's okay. Oh,
Speaker 5:  This is how we get back, girl. Back on on Max. I see it. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  This is how we get it back. They're like, oh my God, this actually will make
Speaker 7:  us more money. The tax break saved us.
Speaker 5:  It's interesting. I'll just note and then we, then we should take a break.
Speaker 5:  The last time there was a rider strike, that's when reality TV
Speaker 5:  happened. Mm.
Speaker 7:  Well it was happening right before it.
Speaker 5:  Right. And the studio started investing in it and massively 'cause it was
Speaker 5:  cheaper. And then it became this like dominant form of media.
Speaker 7:  That's what a lot of 'em are planning on doing. Like a lot of 'em are gonna
Speaker 7:  carry through with that. But at the end of the day, especially 'cause
Speaker 7:  the actors are on strike, like you still want people like to see famous people.
Speaker 7:  That's just the way it is. They wanna see the famous people and the famous
Speaker 7:  people are all out picketing or staying in their houses going Yeah, you
Speaker 7:  go picketers and like Ven Mowing the Strike Fund occasionally.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Will Smith is like, get my weird AI double from that bad movie that we shot
Speaker 5:  in one 20. Get him on the on the line. I still, I can barely
Speaker 5:  remember that movie. It's called the Gemini Man. Get the Gemini man out there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Right now,
Speaker 6:  Gemini man two, three and four are all coming next year.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. If we don't solve this AI Will Smith is coming to your house.
Speaker 7:  That's the real threat.
Speaker 5:  Well, no, it's just like it was last time, it was reality. This time it's
Speaker 5:  gonna be, oh, what if we show you even more South Korean game shows and like
Speaker 5:  that's gonna be a weird, it's gonna be a weird thing to look at a few years.
Speaker 5:  Shout out this isn't get resolved soon is all I'm saying.
Speaker 7:  Netflix is gonna have a great time because they have a huge international
Speaker 7:  library. So they're, they're like set Paramount set.
Speaker 7:  Disney's the one. I'm kind of surprised that they weren't set because you
Speaker 7:  would think Hulu is definitely set. But yeah, we'll see. I
Speaker 6:  Don't know. After only murders in the building season three, like what is
Speaker 6:  there on Hulu?
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  For anyone.
Speaker 7:  The little fire show with Reese Witherspoon that I never watched but I know
Speaker 7:  exists.
Speaker 6:  Love that. The Little fires one. Everybody's favorite show for your
Speaker 6:  consideration for the Emmy.
Speaker 5:  All that's enough. We will note here just to the end, Barbie
Speaker 5:  is over a billion at the box office. Hell yes. Without any
Speaker 5:  Ryan Gosling. Margot Robbie promotion 'cause they're on strike too, which
Speaker 5:  is also fascinating. And probably everyone's gonna learn the wrong lesson
Speaker 5:  from that. Okay, that's it. We gotta take a break. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Basically the more I talk through this with y'all, the more I am
Speaker 3:  perplexed. I do not know.
Speaker 10:  This week on Unexplainable, we're bringing you a new episode of our game
Speaker 10:  show, unexplainable or not. And we've got three potential
Speaker 10:  mysteries. Mystery one
Speaker 3:  Oh,
Speaker 10:  Mystery two.
Speaker 3:  Oh that's so cute.
Speaker 10:  And Mystery three.
Speaker 3:  Oh my God. Stop. I should have been a scientist.
Speaker 10:  Our guest this week is Sam Sanders, host of Vultures Intuit podcast.
Speaker 3:  I'm good at some things. I'm not particularly good at science things,
Speaker 3:  but I love to talk.
Speaker 10:  Sam's gonna try to guess which of these mysteries are still mysteries
Speaker 10:  and which one has actually recently been solved.
Speaker 3:  I'm scared, I don't know if I'm right or wrong
Speaker 10:  To find out. Follow Unexplainable for new episodes every Wednesday.
Speaker 5:  Hi, I'm Neli Patel, editor-in-chief of The Verge and host of the Decoder
Speaker 5:  podcast. This September I'm taking over as one of the new hosts of the code
Speaker 5:  conference alongside CNBC's, Julia Boton and Casey Newton
Speaker 5:  from Platformer and Hart Fork. You've heard us all talk to major
Speaker 5:  players in the worlds of tech and business on our shows. But Code has
Speaker 5:  live unfiltered journalism you won't find anywhere else.
Speaker 5:  This year we have onstage interviews with x slash Twitter, c e o, Linda Ya
Speaker 5:  carino, Microsoft C T O, Kevin Scott, and many more. From
Speaker 5:  AI to Streaming platform shifts to privacy. No one knows exactly
Speaker 5:  where we're headed, but Code is where the world's most influential people
Speaker 5:  come together to find out. Join us for the start of a new era.
Speaker 5:  Apply to attend the code conference now at Vox
Speaker 5:  media.com/code. That's Vox
Speaker 5:  media.com/code. We'll see you in September.
Speaker 5:  We're back in a hard transition from the state of Streaming. We're now gonna
Speaker 5:  talk about enterprise software.
Speaker 6:  Yes, the two most important things,
Speaker 5:  David.
Speaker 5:  David, you wrote about Slack's redesign this week. A lot going on in Slack.
Speaker 5:  It's turning into teams in a lot of ways.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, basically it's, it's a sort of delightful story because
Speaker 6:  teams spent several years during the pandemic just ruthlessly
Speaker 6:  copying everything it could about Slack and then just sort of
Speaker 6:  decimating it because you get teams for free by subscribing to Microsoft's
Speaker 6:  many other products. Slack is a separate thing you have to pay for. So teams
Speaker 6:  sort of resoundingly won by just copying Slack. And
Speaker 6:  now Slack, which got bought by Salesforce as a
Speaker 6:  half success story, half sort of retrenchment after being destroyed by
Speaker 6:  teams is now just completely copying teams.
Speaker 6:  So they've added a new sidebar where there's like the home
Speaker 6:  feed where that kinda looks like Slack. But then there's also a DMS thing
Speaker 6:  where you can see all your messages from all across Slack. There's an activity
Speaker 6:  thing that'll show you every time you've been mentioned or there are reaction
Speaker 6:  emojis, all that stuff. It's basically like they're trying to sort of filter
Speaker 6:  your messages a little better so you can make more sense of the chaos of
Speaker 6:  Slack. And also make it easier for you to find things like
Speaker 6:  huddles and canvas and some of these other features that they have. In
Speaker 6:  general, the idea makes total sense to me. I think a lot of
Speaker 6:  people are gonna freak out because it does look pretty different and it's
Speaker 6:  a really different way of thinking about Slack. Like Slack, I don't know
Speaker 6:  how you guys feel about it. It's pure chaos, but it is like an
Speaker 6:  understandable kind of chaos. And, I think
Speaker 6:  shifting. That is tough, especially for something like this. It's like people
Speaker 6:  use this stuff for work all day, every day. And the idea of just like we've
Speaker 6:  put in a new icon always freaks people out. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's understandable. Okay. That's 'cause most things in Slack are the same
Speaker 5:  kind of thing. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's messaging. It's just a bunch of messages in a row, right?
Speaker 5:  It's a, here's a line of text that You know it's like sent to someone or
Speaker 5:  some room and at worst maybe you'll like send someone a line of text in the
Speaker 5:  wrong context and that's bad. Great. But like it's all the same thing.
Speaker 5:  And what's happening now with this redesign is like
Speaker 5:  many more kinds of things are gonna come to the front like huddles
Speaker 5:  and the canvas thing, which is like a Google doc for a room.
Speaker 5:  And that's the term that I, I think they've wanted to make for a long time.
Speaker 5:  Like this is where we work and work involves lots of different
Speaker 5:  kinds of communication and context versus this is where you send lines of
Speaker 5:  text to other people and we will see,
Speaker 5:  whereas teams we, we had a long conversation about teams in like The,
Speaker 5:  Verge team, Slack room because Teams is much bigger,
Speaker 5:  like an order of magnitude more users than Slack. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And it is mostly in big companies used as a video conferencing
Speaker 5:  application, not any of the other stuff.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. A lot of 'em still use Slack for like dms
Speaker 7:  and stuff and then they use teams for their video conferences. Which
Speaker 5:  Is bizarre.
Speaker 6:  Which is insane for like a bunch of reasons. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  The IT guy's just like, I got money to spend, man, I'm having a great time.
Speaker 7:  Like blowing that whole budget. Enjoy yourself IT guys,
Speaker 5:  If you're not watching the video, Alex just made the like make it rain motion
Speaker 5:  with her hands to describe an IT administrator buying Slack.
Speaker 7:  You already got themes out there and he's just throwing money around. She,
Speaker 7:  they, the
Speaker 5:  Thong songs playing Alex is like buying enterprise software.
Speaker 7:  Woo.
Speaker 7:  That's how I, that's how like as a lover of enterprise software.
Speaker 7:  That's how I think about it.
Speaker 5:  We'll see, I well I haven't gotten the new Slack update yet. David, are you
Speaker 5:  using it?
Speaker 6:  I haven't gotten it yet either. It's gonna roll out slowly. Slack always
Speaker 6:  says is really slowly, they're like desperately afraid of making
Speaker 6:  people nervous about changes. So you can like opt in to being
Speaker 6:  fast or medium or slow and how you get updates. I think it's coming to free
Speaker 6:  users first because like Slack doesn't care about you if you don't give them
Speaker 6:  money. So just deal with the new thing and then sort of slowly to everybody
Speaker 6:  else. I'm very curious about it. But the reason I added it to the rundown,
Speaker 6:  and we don't have to spend too long on this, but I think it's really interesting.
Speaker 6:  We, we had this debate ironically in Slack
Speaker 6:  after this story went up about why people care about Slack
Speaker 6:  so much. Hmm. Like just to let people into how The Verge works. I've written
Speaker 6:  about Slack a lot over the years and every time a ton of
Speaker 6:  people read it in a way that if I write about like a new feature in Google
Speaker 6:  Docs or Excel or these other, like
Speaker 6:  in many cases, much more popular features. Like sometimes they're like
Speaker 6:  big new things. But in every case, like a teeny tiny iterative update to
Speaker 6:  Slack, people care about a lot. And. I. I have been trying to
Speaker 6:  figure out why this is for a long time. Like what is it about Slack
Speaker 6:  that means this much to people in a way that like your
Speaker 6:  average app you use at work doesn't really matter.
Speaker 5:  I think it's 'cause people use Slack for their friends and
Speaker 5:  most enterprise software is just like not used that way. Like that's,
Speaker 5:  that's just my thing is like you live in Slack for like
Speaker 5:  a lot of things you do with other people. If you have a d
Speaker 5:  and d group, there's a chance you have a Slack, maybe you have a Discord,
Speaker 7:  We have a signal. Thank you.
Speaker 5:  Right. Like but so many people just have slacks for
Speaker 5:  things outside of work. Yeah. And, I think that that means
Speaker 5:  like everyone's just kind of interested. Like here's this interface I have
Speaker 5:  for communities on the internet that is changing or
Speaker 5:  You know. The Slack just captured so much of the imagination to begin with
Speaker 5:  that everyone is interested like remains interested in it. But like Zoom
Speaker 5:  isn't that thing no one reads about when we do Zoom updates. No. Unless they're
Speaker 5:  stealing all your data.
Speaker 6:  Well, with, with one recent exception, which we'll come back to,
Speaker 7:  But I'm curious how this like, because I think you're right Neli
Speaker 7:  where it is, it is people use this outside of this. How is that gonna
Speaker 7:  affect adoption when they change it? Because right now if you go and you
Speaker 7:  look at Discord and Slack, there's definitely some differences, but they
Speaker 7:  fundamentally look a lot alike. And now it's not gonna look like
Speaker 7:  that way. One's gonna be very for like business and the other's
Speaker 7:  gonna be where your gamer friends say me Mu and like, which
Speaker 7:  is the one, I don't have gamer friends to say that. Just to be clear,
Speaker 7:  you're the
Speaker 5:  Gamer friend who says that the,
Speaker 7:  Which is gonna be the one. Like, like are people gonna still use it or they're
Speaker 7:  gonna look at it and be like, Hmm, old people use that and click out of it.
Speaker 5:  So I have this like theory of competition and software and it
Speaker 5:  And I think it's best expressed with the Iowa standard. They
Speaker 5:  diverge in the way the interfaces look and then they converge again like
Speaker 5:  all the time. And you can drive yourself crazy
Speaker 5:  and certainly gain a lot of like hate replies on Twitter if you say
Speaker 5:  iOS copied Android or Android copied iOS. Right? Like that's the cycle they're
Speaker 5:  in. Right. But the reason they do that is very obvious is that if you
Speaker 5:  want people to switch between platforms, you have to lower the cognitive
Speaker 5:  burden of switching. Yep. If you are Google and you want people to switch
Speaker 5:  from iOS to Android, you cannot have a radically different
Speaker 5:  interface. Right? Yeah. You, you need to welcome them in and say most of
Speaker 5:  the things are in most of the same places and the things that are different
Speaker 5:  are substantially better for X, Y, or Z reason. And you can
Speaker 5:  100% argue over whether that is successful in the case of Android. But that's
Speaker 5:  basically the thinking, right? Is like you gotta make it easy to switch.
Speaker 5:  If you are Slack and Microsoft teams is way bigger than you,
Speaker 5:  it makes all the sense in the world that you're gonna make Slack look slightly
Speaker 5:  more like Microsoft teams to try to peel that market share
Speaker 5:  back. What's interesting, to your point Alex, is they're not
Speaker 5:  looking more like Discord. Yeah. Hmm. Because that's the other competitor.
Speaker 5:  It's just no one wants to admit that Discord is a competitor. Like I had
Speaker 5:  former Slack, C E O Stewart Butterfield on decoder ages ago,
Speaker 5:  I don't even been the verse might have been pre decoder the last time I talked
Speaker 5:  to him about this specific thing. He was like, yeah, I don't think Discord
Speaker 5:  ISS a competitor, but it obviously is. It's just in this moment
Speaker 5:  where where's the money? The money is paid users of
Speaker 5:  Microsoft teams, not a bunch of randos and a crypto discord.
Speaker 5:  And like
Speaker 7:  Remember a great time, time
Speaker 5:  Of their life over there. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Slack and Discord have been refusing to run at each other for years.
Speaker 6:  Like, I remember asking the Discord folks, I don't know, four years
Speaker 6:  ago now, when are you doing Discord for teams? And they were like, we don't,
Speaker 6:  we don't wanna mess with that. It, it involves a bunch of like compliance
Speaker 6:  and administrative work we don't want to do. If you want to use it for work,
Speaker 6:  great. But that's not officially what it's for. And Slack says
Speaker 6:  literally the exact same thing in reverse. They're like, if you wanna use
Speaker 6:  it for personal stuff, that's awesome. Knock yourself out. That's not what
Speaker 6:  it's for. And it's like the, these two companies just keep staring at each
Speaker 6:  other like refusing to acknowledge that they're actually doing the same thing.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Well
Speaker 7:  I think that's why Slack was so popular versus
Speaker 7:  all of those competitors, right? Like remember HipChat,
Speaker 5:  We were a HipChat's shop for a minute. Oh yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Hip Chat, was it Campfire? Yep. And then like Teams.
Speaker 7:  Teams was, teams is relatively new and it was able to get an enormous market
Speaker 7:  share because it's Microsoft and it already was in all of those spaces. And
Speaker 7:  it was just like, Hey, now we give you this free cancel your Slack subscription.
Speaker 7:  And so for the longest time it was popular partially because it was such
Speaker 7:  a social app in a way that teams really isn't. And so it's like, okay, well
Speaker 7:  if you go that way, aren't you ruining why most people adopted
Speaker 7:  it to begin with? And I don't. I haven't used it. I don't know like if it
Speaker 7:  allows me to not accidentally broadcast things
Speaker 7:  that I thought were dms
Speaker 6:  Great,
Speaker 5:  The Alex Cranz experience,
Speaker 7:  But I look forward to it. But I am like curious if that's gonna happen.
Speaker 7:  And
Speaker 6:  Actually, ironically, Microsoft is the company that is trying to do both.
Speaker 6:  Like, it, it made all this noise a couple of years ago about Teams
Speaker 6:  for families, which to me is just like outrageous.
Speaker 5:  It's just a threat that's like Excel Yeah. For preschoolers. Like
Speaker 5:  we're coming for you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like Microsoft cannot let go of this idea that you should
Speaker 6:  use its tools for your regular life. And to me it's like
Speaker 6:  if they had called it Microsoft Chat, it might have had a chance to be
Speaker 6:  something. Yeah. But if you, if like can neli, can you imagine
Speaker 6:  hanging up this call and going upstairs to Becky and being
Speaker 6:  like, Hey, let's plan in teams.
Speaker 5:  No. Again, my, my goal in life is to not use software.
Speaker 5:  It's just a stated goal. I, I think I've said this in the show, my ambition
Speaker 5:  in like my career is not to accumulate more titles or power.
Speaker 5:  It is to use as little enterprise software as possible. Like I
Speaker 5:  just want to get to the place where people walk into my office. I don't have
Speaker 5:  an office. So like I've got ages to go, but people like
Speaker 5:  show me printouts of emails, And, I, like sign them with a Sharpie.
Speaker 7:  I want this for you.
Speaker 5:  It's like all, all I want is to not use enterprise software at work.
Speaker 6:  You have an attache who carries your phone for you. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And You know, like You know the, the masters of the universe. They're
Speaker 5:  not, you think Tim Cook looks at an email, he's got an iPad
Speaker 5:  for god's sake.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Does Tim Cook use an iPhone on?
Speaker 5:  That's actually a good question. I've never actually seen him use a phone.
Speaker 5:  I've seen him use an iPad.
Speaker 6:  Wait, Neela, do you, do you have like family coordination software
Speaker 6:  that you use? No,
Speaker 5:  We both work at home. Like we don't You need to do that stuff when you're
Speaker 5:  like asynchronous. But like we see each other all day long.
Speaker 6:  You just yell. You just yell
Speaker 7:  At
Speaker 6:  Her. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like we are, we are communicating, I think now Max is going to start in kindergarten.
Speaker 5:  So like there's a, there's another force in the world that
Speaker 5:  has to schedule us And, I think maybe now we will need to share a calendar.
Speaker 5:  But three people who spend all day together,
Speaker 5:  you should not need software to manage that relationship.
Speaker 5:  Really. I really cannot emphasize that enough. If you spend all day
Speaker 5:  with two other people, you should not be like, I'd like to introduce some
Speaker 5:  software into this.
Speaker 6:  There was a minute where I tried to get my wife on on Trello
Speaker 6:  for life planning purposes and the, she was into it,
Speaker 6:  but then we couldn't agree on how to format the Trello cards. So
Speaker 6:  it all fell apart.
Speaker 6:  She, I was just like, no, you have to use these things as checklists on the
Speaker 6:  Trello cards. And she was just like, whatever, I'm gonna write it all in
Speaker 6:  the description and like three days later it just all fell apart. And now
Speaker 6:  we just have like a series of context free
Speaker 6:  links sent in our text message chain. And that's, that's our, yeah, that's
Speaker 6:  how we talk to each other.
Speaker 5:  That's not good. Are you, have you have I converted you to Apple Watch walkie
Speaker 5:  talkie people yet? That's the the thing I'm gonna miss the most when we like
Speaker 5:  go back to offices and lives and whatever.
Speaker 6:  No, she's a green bubble. Anna Anna's a pixel owner
Speaker 6:  and a very happy one who will never switch. So when I'm like using our
Speaker 6:  testing an Android phone, we can just like duo our faces off and it's
Speaker 6:  great. But sadly, sadly there will be no
Speaker 6:  walkie-talkies.
Speaker 7:  Walkie-talkie is dangerous. No one in my family understands how to use
Speaker 7:  it. So I had to turn it off 'cause I'd be like just hearing the whistling
Speaker 7:  from my wrist W whatever I was doing that day, And I was like, nope, we're
Speaker 7:  not doing this anymore. Revoked.
Speaker 5:  We are so deep in the, I mean this is enterprise, this is when
Speaker 5:  you say have you integrated Microsoft teams into your life? It's like n no.
Speaker 5:  But have you been in the grocery store talking to your wrist about which
Speaker 5:  bread to purchase? Yes. Effectively
Speaker 5:  on speaker phone too. Like yeah, it's the Apple Watch is is loud now
Speaker 5:  and I'm just like, boop.
Speaker 5:  Like, like I said, my entire life is just headed toward power moves of this
Speaker 5:  kind. That's all I want. Love it. We actually, we we're kind of on
Speaker 5:  the subject of like a bunch of behaviors changed and the pandemic work from
Speaker 5:  home moment and now everyone's sort of headed back to offices in various
Speaker 5:  ways. One a very funny example of that Zoom called everyone back to office
Speaker 5:  this week, which is choice Zoom. Like just
Speaker 5:  perfectly choice. Do
Speaker 6:  You think Zoom knew, like when they're sitting there being like, we're about
Speaker 6:  to send this like all staff email telling everybody to come back to the office.
Speaker 6:  Like do you think they knew that? They were like, well we we're about to
Speaker 6:  play ourselves so hard. As soon as this email goes out, if
Speaker 5:  I'm Zoom, I'm doing this just to generate some headlines about Zoom. 'cause
Speaker 5:  like no one's been talking about Zoom for weeks. You know and it's like You
Speaker 5:  know what we should do is call everyone back to the office. Like everyone
Speaker 5:  will be like, remember Zoom? Zoom was great. It was better than the teams
Speaker 5:  were forced to use Network. Where's that IT guy spending the money in the
Speaker 5:  strip club,
Speaker 7:  He's out there. He's like, oh you want Zoom? I got you.
Speaker 7:  He just, he's free with the budget.
Speaker 5:  And then Zoom also got itself in trouble this week as you alluded to earlier,
Speaker 5:  David. Yeah. They changed their terms of service. And I
Speaker 5:  understand why they changed their terms of service. They just did it in the
Speaker 5:  most ham-fisted stupid way possible. So they basically changed their terms
Speaker 5:  of service to say all the data that you're putting through Zoom, zoom has
Speaker 5:  a license to, and they need that. If you run a service on the
Speaker 5:  internet, you, you need a license to all the data that users put into your
Speaker 5:  service for any infinite number of copyright reasons. Like
Speaker 5:  you run servers, you're gonna copy data from one server to another, you're
Speaker 5:  gonna introduce new features that might remix the user data, all this stuff.
Speaker 5:  So you just need this like big broad license. And then the
Speaker 6:  Example you always use when we talk about this stuff that I really like is
Speaker 6:  thumbnails. Yeah. If they don't have the rights to
Speaker 6:  use and change and copy your stuff, they can't make the little versions of
Speaker 6:  the image that you click on to get the big version of the image. Like it's
Speaker 6:  that simple in many
Speaker 5:  Cases. Oh yes. They can't overlay text on those images. They, because that's
Speaker 5:  a derivative. You just write yourself the biggest, broadest license you can
Speaker 5:  and they added these lines that are like for artificial
Speaker 5:  intelligence and training models and it's like everyone lost their mind
Speaker 7:  So fast
Speaker 5:  By the raw language of it. That means everything you say into Zoom
Speaker 5:  can be used to train artificial intelligence.
Speaker 6:  Right? It's like, oh, we're selling your data to open AI to put into GPT
Speaker 6:  four. Right. And we're allowed to now is like the, the
Speaker 6:  implication of that, I, speaking of the strike, I saw a bunch of people
Speaker 6:  in Hollywood tweeting like, oh we can't use Zoom when we're creating stuff
Speaker 6:  anymore. It's like people are so primed to see
Speaker 6:  this stuff being taken from them and see this all being used against them
Speaker 6:  in a lot of ways that Zoom did this the wrong way at exactly
Speaker 6:  the wrong time. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  If they'd done this like three months ago, nobody would've batted an I until
Speaker 7:  somebody like did a TikTok right now being like, did You know three months
Speaker 7:  ago Zoom decided to steal all your data and give it
Speaker 7:  to chat G P T and now you own nothing including your face
Speaker 7:  Zoom does.
Speaker 5:  Right? So this specific block of text is in like
Speaker 5:  almost every terms of service and it's, it's just like what you need
Speaker 5:  to run a service, right? You need to take a perpetual, worldwide,
Speaker 5:  non-exclusive, royalty free sub-license or transferrable license to do stuff.
Speaker 5:  Access, use store, transmit, review, disclose, preserve, extract, like it's
Speaker 5:  just a list of verbs. We are giving ourselves the broadest license
Speaker 5:  to do verbs to your data. Because if you run a service,
Speaker 5:  there's, you want to do stuff, you're gonna,
Speaker 7:  You're gonna
Speaker 5:  Do verbs. Verbs is what we're here for. It's not nouns.
Speaker 5:  If you're living a nouns life, You know. So they added this language
Speaker 5:  about artificial intelligence. So you just kind of combine the like usual
Speaker 5:  panic like every couple years, like some teenager discovers the
Speaker 5:  Instagram terms of service and people freak out. Yep. Yeah. And everyone
Speaker 5:  posts that copy that's like, I do not give Instagram the permission to do
Speaker 5:  shit and then I have to like write a blog post that's an auto complete of
Speaker 5:  a blog post here. Four years ago,
Speaker 6:  This is literally the case by the way. J Peters wrote our, our story about
Speaker 6:  this Zoom AI thing and has back links to one about
Speaker 6:  Instagram from 2012 and one about Dropbox and
Speaker 6:  Google Drive also from 2012. And they are, I mean like
Speaker 6:  almost exactly the same post, both written by Neli both being
Speaker 6:  like, guys, this is just, this is just the words you need to
Speaker 6:  have things on servers. Everything's probably fine. But so
Speaker 5:  What's interesting about this is there's the general AI panic that is happening.
Speaker 5:  It's like David was saying, even the writer strike has, has big elements
Speaker 5:  to this. And then there's the actual problem, which is yeah, if you
Speaker 5:  just read the language, it sure sounds like it. So Zoom had to clarify
Speaker 5:  that customer data is customer data, which is if you are an enterprise software
Speaker 5:  company, the worst thing to have to clarify.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like that's the whole point of the enterprise software company. That's fundamentally
Speaker 5:  why Slack and Discord are not the same, right? Like Slack makes these big
Speaker 5:  promises to big businesses about its relationship to them.
Speaker 5:  And Discord is like, yeah, it's for Gamers. We're gonna mine all
Speaker 5:  of your data. Like it's You know. It's like, it's just like a very different
Speaker 5:  approach. And, I, think Zoom stepped in it and we're gonna see
Speaker 5:  hundreds of other companies step in it because at the end of the day,
Speaker 5:  zoom probably wants to use AI to do things like better
Speaker 5:  beauty filters that people ask for in Zoom calls to do things
Speaker 5:  like automated transcripts that are better than the already AI
Speaker 5:  powered automated transcripts are doing. What you want is to write yourself
Speaker 5:  a broad license so you can innovate freely. And the reality is you,
Speaker 5:  you're gonna have to start asking permission step by step for all that stuff.
Speaker 5:  'cause this panic is coming over and over again.
Speaker 6:  Part of me is like, okay, zoom did this exactly wrong, right? Like
Speaker 6:  the, they added a statement after all of this kerfuffle that
Speaker 6:  said, not withstanding the above, which is a deeply hilarious way to say,
Speaker 6:  well we wrote that badly. So here's some new words. Zoom will not use audio,
Speaker 6:  video or chat customer content to train our artificial intelligence models
Speaker 6:  without your consent. Like a, like you're saying Eli Wild that
Speaker 6:  that was not in there the first time, but b
Speaker 6:  I kind of don't know other than that one
Speaker 6:  bit of, I think clarification that some lawyer at
Speaker 6:  Zoom didn't think they needed to do because it was inherently obvious but
Speaker 6:  is not obvious to people who like to track changes on terms of service.
Speaker 6:  It's, this is just a hard thing to do. And I think one of the things
Speaker 6:  we've discovered with a lot of these tools is like the thing that happens
Speaker 6:  when somebody starts recording a Zoom call and there's that very loud thing
Speaker 6:  that goes like, this meeting is now being recorded. Yeah. And they have this
Speaker 6:  new thing with the AI meeting summaries where it like
Speaker 6:  goes way out of its way to let You know that it's doing AI meeting
Speaker 6:  summaries and you have to like click a thing to make the giant window
Speaker 6:  full of texts go away. We're just setting ourselves up for this
Speaker 6:  like heinous user experience because these companies are
Speaker 6:  afraid of our reaction to what they're doing in order to run their service.
Speaker 6:  And there it feels like there has to be a middle ground in there somewhere,
Speaker 6:  but I don't know what it is and it feels like it's gonna be a while before
Speaker 6:  we find it.
Speaker 7:  I think it's like one, they have to repeatedly prove that
Speaker 7:  they're not gonna do nefarious things with your data. And
Speaker 7:  that's pretty hard for them to currently do because
Speaker 7:  everything we cover at The Verge dot com, there's so many examples of it,
Speaker 7:  right? And so like they've, they've kind of set themselves up to fail in
Speaker 7:  that respect because they have misused data over and over and over and over
Speaker 7:  again. Yes. And so it'd be like, no, no, but this time is different. Like
Speaker 7:  nobody's gonna believe that you've got, you've got a really sa you've got,
Speaker 7:  people are way more savvy about this stuff than they were 10, 15 years ago.
Speaker 7:  And so you, you've gotta fix that And I think until they can
Speaker 7:  kind of earn that trust back, they're gonna be in this
Speaker 7:  place. And then the other side of it is like, people please like go read
Speaker 7:  anything chat G P T wrote that is longer than like
Speaker 7:  a hundred words and then come back to me and say that it's gonna steal my
Speaker 7:  job. Like right. You know this stuff is not, we,
Speaker 7:  we are very excited about it and everybody's like, oh it's gotten so big.
Speaker 7:  But at the same time it is still very early days chat G P T and these
Speaker 7:  other generative AI systems are
Speaker 7:  gonna be writing really good books. They'll write books but they're not gonna
Speaker 7:  be readable fun books most of the time. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I do wonder though if, to your point neli about
Speaker 6:  companies running into this, if what they're gonna learn from this is
Speaker 6:  just barrel your way through it. No, that's all. Don't ask.
Speaker 6:  We've learned, don't be nice, just do what Google did and say Yeah,
Speaker 6:  we take your shit from the internet. What are you gonna do about it?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The problem is Zoom exists in a world where Microsoft Teams exists
Speaker 7:  And Slack
Speaker 5:  Fair and Slack, right? Like Google Google's approach to
Speaker 5:  data on the internet right now explicitly now in some of their terms is if
Speaker 5:  the crawler can see it, we can train AI with it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And that's a nightmare choice, right? You have to say don't
Speaker 5:  index my website in Google search.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Like maybe like, I'm gonna shut my business down rather than like Google
Speaker 5:  train its models on my, like you have to be Google to put yourself in that
Speaker 5:  position with Zoom. It's like, well I'm just not gonna use Zoom. Like it's
Speaker 5:  like the market works. The real answer I think is
Speaker 5:  unfeasible in America. But you need some sort of privacy
Speaker 5:  law so that if they do overstep, there's a consequence in that keeps them
Speaker 5:  in line.
Speaker 5:  I don't know if we're gonna get that anytime soon. I just want you to try
Speaker 5:  to, I keep using this example. You have to go into Chuck Schumer's office
Speaker 5:  and be like, alright, there's a spectrum of AI
Speaker 5:  things here from beauty filters in Zoom to the people on Reddit
Speaker 5:  who faked Globo to make the AI right about
Speaker 5:  Globo and World of Warcraft. Write a law Chuck.
Speaker 6:  Well if that's the spectrum, the law is just, all these things are very good.
Speaker 6:  No problems,
Speaker 7:  Only good things there. Only upsides.
Speaker 5:  All right, let's end on on my favorite story of the week. Same enterprise
Speaker 5:  software, real middle section on enterprise software here. Speaking of work
Speaker 5:  from home, the Zoom explosion, all this stuff in the height of the pandemic,
Speaker 5:  when everyone thought no one was ever gonna go work in office again, it was
Speaker 5:  all video conferencing forever. Verizon bought a company called BlueJeans
Speaker 5:  for $400 million. Ugh.
Speaker 5:  They, this was a big deal. Like yeah. The c e o of Verizon went on C N B
Speaker 5:  C to announce it. They were talking about how they're gonna roll it into
Speaker 5:  five g Verizon, You know a big IT supplier. They're like
Speaker 5:  our distribution network. This is the future of business BlueJeans powered
Speaker 5:  by Verizon. Give all your employees Verizon five G phones. The
Speaker 5:  low latency BlueJeans experience will blow anyway. They shut it down this
Speaker 5:  week.
Speaker 7:  It's 'cause Have you ever used BlueJeans?
Speaker 5:  No, no, no, no. I'm a I'm a regular human. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I had to. So that's what the, the, the Writer's Guild of America used as
Speaker 7:  its software. Oh. And so when I was a a union steward,
Speaker 7:  you'd have 200 people on a call in blue jeans
Speaker 7:  and no one knew how it worked. Should
Speaker 6:  Have gone on strike about that. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I'm sorry Jesus. Sorry.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Really. Fuck Alex. It was brutal. It was
Speaker 7:  just the worst app on the planet. And. I. Remember when Verizon bought it?
Speaker 7:  I was like, they'll either they'll make it good or they didn't understand
Speaker 7:  that they bought garbage. And it sounds like it was the
Speaker 7:  latter. Let
Speaker 5:  Me just put that headline right next to something else. Verizon will soon
Speaker 5:  raise prices on unlimited plans again.
Speaker 6:  Yep.
Speaker 5:  Maybe if you hadn't lit $400 million on
Speaker 5:  fire buying a a third rate video conferencing app to make
Speaker 5:  your five G network better, you could have just kept the prices lower. Just
Speaker 7:  Garbage software. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I just, I just feel it. It's called Blue Jeans. Like this is,
Speaker 6:  why have I told you about the career I'm gonna have when I leave The Verge
Speaker 6:  where I just walk into rooms and say that name is stupid. And then somebody
Speaker 6:  writes me a check for $50,000 And I leave Blue. What a
Speaker 6:  stupid name. Can I Oh Blue Jeans me. Like are you serious? That
Speaker 6:  company never had a chance for one second. They
Speaker 5:  Had a bunch of marketing that was like nothing fits like blue jeans like
Speaker 5:  that. That's what they were doing.
Speaker 6:  That's true. And has nothing to do with video conferencing.
Speaker 5:  I'm just gonna read you this sentence. We have made the difficult decision
Speaker 5:  to sunset our suite of blue jeans products.
Speaker 7:  There is more than one product
Speaker 6:  We are taking off our blue jeans.
Speaker 5:  That's bad. So if you're on a Verizon, go unlimited Beyond
Speaker 5:  unlimited or above unlimited. Sure. This
Speaker 6:  Is some real Disney Streaming shit here. I don't like this. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  You'll be playing $3 more per month. They do this like
Speaker 5:  clockwork every year because the new iPhones are
Speaker 5:  coming out and they don't want you on the legacy plans when you get a new
Speaker 5:  iPhone. They want you to put you on the new, more expensive plans when you
Speaker 5:  get the new phone. And so every year they come out with new plans and
Speaker 5:  new blah blah blah. The new subsidies for the iPhones. And they make the
Speaker 5:  old plans more expensive every year like clockwork. And it's,
Speaker 5:  I'm just gonna point out that they, if they had not lit
Speaker 5:  $400 million on fire
Speaker 5:  on a product called Blue Jeans, maybe their investors
Speaker 5:  would be happier with them and maybe, maybe just, maybe
Speaker 5:  they wouldn't have to raise prices so much. Also, maybe if we hadn't let
Speaker 5:  T-Mobile buy Sprint and there are actually four wireless carriers in this
Speaker 5:  country. It'd be actual competition market. That's just me.
Speaker 5:  We don't have a Dish Network Gen Fivey update for you today
Speaker 5:  'cause they've done fuck all
Speaker 6:  That sounds right.
Speaker 7:  That's accurate.
Speaker 5:  Just saying Dish Network was supposed to in a long
Speaker 5:  confusing deal brokered by the Trump administration, stand up a
Speaker 5:  fourth five G network using a technology called O Ran
Speaker 5:  that would compete with the Giants.
Speaker 5:  You can, you look around well,
Speaker 6:  But now Dish Network is merging with EchoStar. So that's which
Speaker 5:  Is the same company. I just want to point out, if you are
Speaker 5:  an old billionaire and you have two companies and you're like, I don't
Speaker 5:  know, merge 'em up together, you have accomplished nothing. This is like
Speaker 5:  when people made me tried to make me care about Paramount and Viacom and
Speaker 5:  c B s all merging and the only good thing about it was that like
Speaker 5:  the parent company was called National Amusements, which is like deeply funny.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, but it's all just the same. Like one old guy owned all the
Speaker 5:  companies, right? And you're like, yeah. And they're like, oh man, this is
Speaker 5:  the greatest succession drama. It's like, no, it's all just the same
Speaker 5:  company. Like none of this matters. That's
Speaker 5:  Dish and EchoStar merging, which we wrote about this week, which is fine.
Speaker 5:  I'm just pointing out we were supposed to have four wireless carriers in
Speaker 5:  America. We let T-Mobile buy Sprint, which was a, a mess. And then
Speaker 5:  we brokered instead of anything real,
Speaker 5:  a fake idea about Dish Network making a fourth network, which look around
Speaker 5:  doesn't exist.
Speaker 6:  It's going really great. I would just say
Speaker 6:  Dish and EchoStar could combine, rename their network to Blue
Speaker 6:  jeans and be heroes.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 6:  Just right there.
Speaker 5:  Look, we like asking for your emails. We're gonna take a break. We'll come
Speaker 5:  back, we'll read some emails. If you are a person
Speaker 5:  beyond just my phone is faster or
Speaker 5:  I've downloaded more pirated Netflix videos than ever in an
Speaker 5:  airport. If you're someone who's actually like,
Speaker 5:  experienced the benefits of five G, I want to hear from you. It cannot be
Speaker 5:  that your bandwidth is just faster. I'm talking you did a robot
Speaker 5:  surgery. Like one of these things they told us would happen
Speaker 5:  with five g I have one example for everyone.
Speaker 5:  I'll, I'll put it out there right now. Last night I watched Taylor
Speaker 5:  Swift announce 1989 Taylor's version from SoFi Stadium on
Speaker 5:  like 45 different like crystal clear live streams on TikTok.
Speaker 5:  That is because N F L stadiums have millimeter wave five G in them.
Speaker 5:  That's why That's it. That's the future baby. But that, okay, I'll give you
Speaker 5:  that one. I I I've taken that one off the table. They put so much
Speaker 5:  bandwidth in N F NFL stadiums that I watched
Speaker 5:  effectively pirate live streams of a Taylor Swift concert. Okay, that one's
Speaker 5:  off the table. Give me something else. Email us Vercast The Verge dot com.
Speaker 5:  I'm dying to know if anyone has done like a
Speaker 5:  robot five G surgery. If they've deployed a
Speaker 5:  low latency application to a telecom company's
Speaker 5:  edge data center. You let me know. I I 'cause I haven't seen one
Speaker 5:  other than these phones are slightly faster. Does
Speaker 7:  Updating your laptop at a hotel count?
Speaker 5:  No. That's just more bandwidth,
Speaker 7:  Which was really nice bandwidth.
Speaker 5:  You, you cannot give me, you cannot give me, I can pull down one gig
Speaker 5:  speeds, blah, blah, blah. You have to give me something on the order
Speaker 5:  of tens of thousands of people in A N F L stadium
Speaker 5:  live streamed crystal clear video to the internet
Speaker 5:  all at once, right? Not just you alone stood on a
Speaker 5:  street corner with, with high bandwidth, tens of thousands of people
Speaker 5:  used the internet once to because of the Taylor Swift. Like that is a, that
Speaker 5:  that And I give you that, that is a meaningful five
Speaker 5:  g thing that you could not do with an L T E network. But give me like one
Speaker 5:  more like we did not do all of this for the ERAS tour.
Speaker 5:  At least I don't think we did.
Speaker 5:  Vercast is Verge hot. Email us. We'll be right back.
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back. We have a little bit of lightning around. There's
Speaker 5:  some good stuff in the lightning round this week I gotta say. Yeah. But before
Speaker 5:  we get to that, last week we asked about fart apps in the Vision Pro. I will
Speaker 5:  say one person completely misinterpreted that conversation got very mad at
Speaker 5:  me on Twitter. What we were saying is when you have a new platform like the
Speaker 5:  Vision Pro, the first wave of apps is like toys.
Speaker 5:  It's like silly stuff, which was the first wave of apps on the iPhone.
Speaker 5:  And then everyone like figured out what they could do because they made so
Speaker 5:  many stupid silly apps. And then you get the wave
Speaker 5:  of mobile apps that is like revolutionized culture. There's someone on Twitter
Speaker 5:  who's like super mad at me that I'm not aware of
Speaker 5:  the apparently successful enterprise VR apps that exist today. And it's true,
Speaker 5:  I'm not
Speaker 6:  BlueJeans vr also Apple coming to
Speaker 5:  Whatever. But this was a prompt, like what's the first wave of silly apps
Speaker 5:  for the Vision Pro gonna be. We got some good answers.
Speaker 6:  We did. I have also come up with one that I think is
Speaker 6:  correct and I'm gonna quit my job and make it and I'm gonna make a fortune
Speaker 6:  in the first year. But we should go through the ones that we got because
Speaker 6:  they're all generally very good. What is, we'll,
Speaker 6:  we'll come back. That
Speaker 7:  Was a tease David. That was a tease.
Speaker 6:  I have to, I have to read through and see all of these to decide if I'm gonna
Speaker 6:  share my idea.
Speaker 5:  All right, so the first one, Josh w his idea for a vision
Speaker 5:  pro fart app Drunk vision, which makes a lot of sense, although
Speaker 5:  you'll puke right away. Literally it's throw
Speaker 6:  Up in your head. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And then that leads right into his second idea, which is Shroom vision. I
Speaker 5:  I buy it. Right? What if you could feel like, like Aren Rogers
Speaker 5:  mode for your Vision Pro is like, it's also called Vision Pro. Very good.
Speaker 5:  Justin g wrote try on clothes app. It's Snapchat
Speaker 5:  filters for your whole body and all you have to do is look at someone else
Speaker 5:  dangerous idea. My
Speaker 6:  Immediate reaction to this was, oh that seems really smart. And then one
Speaker 6:  second later I went, oh no.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But I will say the thing like everyone at Snapchat keeps telling me
Speaker 6:  that the ar tryon thing is real and people like it
Speaker 6:  and use it. And if you could like put on your vision pro and
Speaker 6:  stand in front of the mirror and like see how you would look and stuff like
Speaker 6:  there will be something like that. And I bet it'll work. I don't know about
Speaker 6:  the All you have to do is look at someone else thing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, there's some real consent issues there. I don't wanna
Speaker 7:  Be able to change other people's clothes. That seems like a no go.
Speaker 5:  Here's what I'm thinking. Realtime revenge porn.
Speaker 5:  There's like app store review problems in there. We'll see. But I get it.
Speaker 5:  People like that idea. Michael G says, the obvious answer is
Speaker 5:  fart clouds floating around the user with spatial audio fart sounds.
Speaker 6:  This literally is the answer. Spatial audio fart sounds is a thing that will
Speaker 6:  happen. Like Michael has spoken that into existence and this will happen.
Speaker 6:  Now. People
Speaker 5:  Took the fart at prompt a little too literally. 'cause Zach
Speaker 5:  wrote transparency mode. And you not only hear a fart, but you see
Speaker 5:  a plume of purple and green come out of butts
Speaker 5:  That's right up there with Snapchat filters whole.
Speaker 5:  But like can you imagine you're gonna wearing a $3,500 headset,
Speaker 5:  you're walking around the city and you're just like
Speaker 5:  waiting for farts. So you can see the like sparkle
Speaker 6:  Farts. Oh, so wait, so you're imagining this not as a way to like make
Speaker 6:  it look as if someone is fart. You're imagining like a fart recognition system.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's transparency mode for farts
Speaker 7:  Fart detector. Oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So somebody farts and it's just, it's like the, the thing in the pool that
Speaker 6:  turns your p purple. It's just like ar farts.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's, it's that. And every time it happens, you hear an Apple executive
Speaker 5:  say something like, with the power of the M two chip, like
Speaker 5:  Christopher c writes Slowmo running from Baywatch in whatever space
Speaker 5:  you are in, which I actually don't understand. It's like
Speaker 7:  You're putting it on and you're walking down the street and in addition to
Speaker 7:  all the other people, it's this person's slow motion running towards you.
Speaker 6:  It's just Pamela Anderson slowly running it's,
Speaker 5:  It's Tesla off. It's good that you went to Pamela Anderson. And
Speaker 5:  I went to That's nice. Asshole Hof. That's nice. That says it all really.
Speaker 5:  All right. And then my last one, this is my favorite one because it includes
Speaker 5:  the phrase benefit hypothesis.
Speaker 6:  Hell yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's very good. So Ruben wrote app description
Speaker 5:  colon. When the U s a men's soccer team wins the World Cup,
Speaker 5:  then your Apple Vision Pro will livestream video of former
Speaker 5:  President Donald Trump in prison.
Speaker 6:  Wow. That turned hard in the middle there. It
Speaker 5:  Did. Benefit hypothesis. Both political parties will wonder how a
Speaker 5:  former US president spends his time in prison. Two. The
Speaker 5:  curiosity will cause a positive effect on USA's overall
Speaker 5:  soccer performance over time. So they're
Speaker 6:  Gonna wanna win so bad so that we can see that. Yeah. Oh, interesting.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So that we can all see it.
Speaker 6:  I don't know if this has to do with the Vision Pro, but it's an interesting
Speaker 6:  incentive strategy. And
Speaker 5:  Then he has some potential names here. Victory Watch, ex-president edition,
Speaker 5:  the champion's presidential Stream goal to watch POTUS in prison.
Speaker 6:  These all sound like golf tournaments.
Speaker 5:  And then number 10 here at the end, soccer glory presidential story.
Speaker 5:  I don't know man. I like getting emails. Wow. That's
Speaker 7:  So good.
Speaker 5:  Very good. If you have ideas, this, we already had the prompt. If you have
Speaker 5:  had a meaningful five G experience, you email me and I'm,
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm I'm taking the hes tour off the table. So that's it. We're
Speaker 6:  Gonna get zero emails about that. So what's your better idea?
Speaker 5:  We did get some emails from some Android Gamers.
Speaker 5:  We'll collate those and talk about those. It'll, it'll later
Speaker 6:  Once there's more than one.
Speaker 5:  That's basically what I'm saying. I don't wanna dox the
Speaker 5:  one person who emailed me. Yeah. So what
Speaker 5:  we've got send some more of those. But if you've got ideas on like what the
Speaker 5:  first wave of Vision Pro, I'm, I'm very curious.
Speaker 6:  Can Wait, can I tell you what my idea is? I've actually, I I I have been
Speaker 6:  thinking a lot about this And I actually think I'm right. I think there's
Speaker 6:  going to be this like gigantic genre of what amounts to like
Speaker 6:  fidget spinner apps in the vision Pro ne And I. You And I
Speaker 6:  have both gotten this demo. And just the thing where you can sit there and
Speaker 6:  just like touch your fingers together to do stuff is
Speaker 6:  delightful. And I. Think about like the, do you guys remember that app when
Speaker 6:  the iPhone first came out? That was just a beer on the screen and you could
Speaker 6:  like sl it back Yeah. And forth. Oh yeah.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 6:  That thing was like, oh, look at the accelerometer. This is cool. It does
Speaker 6:  stuff when I move it, the equivalent of that on the Vision Pro is gonna be
Speaker 6:  like, I put my fingers together and something happens. So it's gonna be like,
Speaker 6:  there's gonna be a bubble wrap app that makes a billion dollars. There's
Speaker 6:  gonna be one of the little like popper fidget things that's gonna make a
Speaker 6:  ton like spin something around with your finger. Like it's gonna be huge.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. This is what I'm saying. The person who's all mad at me like doesn't
Speaker 5:  miss the point. The point is when you have a bunch of new interface concepts,
Speaker 5:  the first round of apps is just, can you trigger all the
Speaker 5:  sensors and push all the buttons? Right. And that trains everybody to
Speaker 5:  get excited about what else they can build. And the way that the first round
Speaker 5:  of iPhone apps was like, turn the phone sideways and it looks like you're
Speaker 5:  pouring a beer like that didn't accomplish anything other than
Speaker 5:  getting people used to motion controls on an iPhone.
Speaker 6:  Totally.
Speaker 5:  And like something like that will happen. The first, I guarantee you, the
Speaker 5:  first round of Vision Pro apps is gonna be more stuff like that. I can't
Speaker 5:  say it's gonna be champion story presidential glory,
Speaker 5:  just not a, not a clear business model path.
Speaker 5:  But you can see how some of this stuff will happen. All right. Lightning
Speaker 5:  round Cranz, you've got LK 99, which is the
Speaker 5:  fakest story. This I, can I say this? I will say
Speaker 5:  The LK 99 situation, like exemplifies
Speaker 5:  broken Twitter to the Max. Yes.
Speaker 7:  Hmm. A hundred percent.
Speaker 5:  Like it exists because Twitter decided it would exist and
Speaker 5:  like no one could stop it. And then we all talk about it and then go ahead.
Speaker 5:  You got it. It's you. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It felt very,
Speaker 7:  if people understood how how science is normally reported and how
Speaker 7:  major discoveries are normally reported, they would've been a little less
Speaker 7:  hyped about this. Because generally speaking, when science has really cool
Speaker 7:  big discoveries, they like to be like, Hey, look at these really cool big
Speaker 7:  discoveries we have. They don't like to leak to
Speaker 7:  competing studies on the same product
Speaker 7:  to a different forum and then have everybody argue over whether
Speaker 7:  it's real or not and have very little proof. That's the opposite of science.
Speaker 7:  Everybody who was like, it's all a conspiracy. No, they
Speaker 7:  were incorrect. But LK 99 was, was is a substance.
Speaker 7:  There were a number of developers who came out and they said, oh, this could
Speaker 7:  be the next superconductor. And, and the important thing about superconductors,
Speaker 7:  they're really, really good at conducting electricity at room temperature,
Speaker 7:  at normal pressure. Most superconductors cannot do that. We have
Speaker 7:  superconductors today, but they usually have like thermal or, or pressure
Speaker 7:  issues and which makes them really, really like great to use, but really,
Speaker 7:  really expensive to use. So something that just works at
Speaker 7:  normal ti like out of the box is a huge, huge idea. And
Speaker 7:  one of the things that like tells a superconductor from other things
Speaker 7:  is the ability to levitate over magnets. But those aren't the only
Speaker 7:  materials that levitate over magnets. So when everybody saw this partially,
Speaker 7:  not even fully partially levitating, they're like, oh my God, it's a
Speaker 7:  superconductor. And it turns out that, oh my God, it's not,
Speaker 7:  it's just one of those materials that levitates over magnets. And it sounds
Speaker 7:  like there's definitely some cool use cases for it. It sounds like there's
Speaker 7:  some interesting things here, but the researchers one, some of the researchers
Speaker 7:  already were trying to like sell it. And so this was part of their marketing
Speaker 7:  hype to like sell it. And the other researchers were not. And the
Speaker 7:  superconductor research space was already dealing with some drama.
Speaker 7:  'cause some other people had previously claimed,
Speaker 5:  Wait, can you just say can the superconductor research space was already
Speaker 5:  dealing with some
Speaker 6:  Drama. Incredible. Oh
Speaker 7:  Yeah. There was already drama because there was already another like study
Speaker 7:  that was like, oh yeah, we've got the new superconductor. And it turned out
Speaker 7:  it was all fake and wrong and terrible. So like people keep coming
Speaker 7:  into this space because it's, it's very pro, like it's the potential for
Speaker 7:  profit's huge here. So everybody wants to find that
Speaker 7:  superconductor and then make lots of money. Wait,
Speaker 6:  Can I, can I ask a really dumb question? I, I confess I have like not really
Speaker 6:  followed this story because the night I sat down and was like, I'm gonna
Speaker 6:  read the hell out of LK 99 was the same day. Everybody was like,
Speaker 6:  nevermind, this is nothing. So I basically have not followed this story at
Speaker 6:  all. Okay. And this is where I ask a very dumb question about superconductors,
Speaker 6:  which is like, let's say in theory this had been the thing that some of these
Speaker 6:  people thought it was.
Speaker 6:  So what, like why did this become such a like
Speaker 6:  real world excitement phenomenon so fast?
Speaker 7:  I think the, the, the big thing for superconductors and and where it would
Speaker 7:  be really powerful is like right now superconductors are used in a lot of
Speaker 7:  power plants and stuff like that. But if you can get a cheap,
Speaker 7:  super reliable superconductor, which if this had been one
Speaker 7:  would've ticked those boxes, right? It would've been cheap, it would've been
Speaker 7:  easy to produce. If you can do that, then you can conceivably
Speaker 7:  make like electric cars, anything that runs on power just way
Speaker 7:  more efficient because it's able to move that with and, and without like
Speaker 7:  as much heat and stuff like that, it's super efficiently.
Speaker 6:  So instead in theory of doing what we do with Silicon now, which is only
Speaker 6:  a semiconductor, you could do it much better with a superconductor. Right?
Speaker 7:  You could do it so, so much better. And, and so like, it would
Speaker 7:  just make things way faster. It would make things way less power
Speaker 7:  hungry. Like it would be in a lot of ways magic. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  But
Speaker 5:  I just want to give you this quote from our piece, which is if you start
Speaker 5:  with a rock, you end up with a rock.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And this was the thing. Beautiful. And what I didn't get about the
Speaker 7:  Twitter side of this was how so many people were like, this is crazy. It's
Speaker 7:  so cool. And then they'd go talk to researchers. The researchers are like,
Speaker 7:  we're skeptical. And they're like, you're in the pocket of somebody you hate
Speaker 7:  science. And it's like, yeah,
Speaker 5:  This is what I mean about twi like the broken
Speaker 5:  blue check version of Twitter that we have now, like
Speaker 5:  is made for hype cycles. Yeah. And it
Speaker 5:  every kind of like crypto scammer AI thread Boy
Speaker 5:  had a moment with LK 99 and the media still organized around
Speaker 5:  having Twitter be its assignment editor that this obviously
Speaker 5:  fake thing like ended up everywhere. Like
Speaker 5:  we wrote about it. 'cause there was so much interest in it. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  We, we weren't gonna write it. Like we, we talked about this when it first
Speaker 7:  popped off and we're like, oh, we're not gonna write about it because there,
Speaker 7:  'cause all of the reasons that I talked about, which was didn't seem reliable
Speaker 7:  and everything else, but then so many people were writing about it were like,
Speaker 7:  okay, well we have to like explain how this is all incorrect and they're
Speaker 7:  wrong and that this isn't a big deal. Which is the a bummer
Speaker 7:  of a story to write. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I'm gonna quote Michael Norman, distinguished fellow and former director
Speaker 5:  of material science division at the Oregon on National Laboratory. When you
Speaker 5:  start with a rock, chances are you will end up with a rock.
Speaker 6:  That's awesome.
Speaker 5:  It's a, it's a it's a rock. But it's just like, to me, the thing was, I mean,
Speaker 5:  it's interesting to capture the imagination you love capturing. It's like
Speaker 5:  every so often, I remember early in my, like in Gadget 10 tenure as like
Speaker 5:  a baby blogger. Someone had claimed to have invented a perpetual
Speaker 5:  motion machine and like,
Speaker 5:  but like You know they were gonna like hold a video demonstration and they
Speaker 5:  called them the thing. And like, we were like, I was just like, guys, this
Speaker 5:  is bullshit. Like look at it. And there was this answer,
Speaker 5:  which I still think about all the time, which is the audience is interested
Speaker 5:  and it's a service to go and ask the questions and blah blah blah. And I
Speaker 5:  was like, but we can just answer the questions now.
Speaker 5:  Like, it's definitely not gonna work.
Speaker 7:  I'm just say it's bullshit.
Speaker 5:  It, it didn't work in the end. Surprise. But it's just like this cycle.
Speaker 5:  But because Twitter's in the middle of it, like the idea that something has
Speaker 5:  gone viral on Twitter still carries meaning in the world
Speaker 5:  even though the, the the meaning is sort of divorced from the
Speaker 5:  mechanics of Twitter. Yeah. And so it's like, oh yeah, like a bunch of like
Speaker 5:  Grifters started doing Threads about what it means for there to be a room
Speaker 5:  temperature superconductor and without ever verifying that there was a room
Speaker 5:  temperature superconductor. And then everybody wrote about it because everyone
Speaker 5:  was excited, including our audience basically asked us to write a book. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It
Speaker 6:  Makes me think of all the TikTok trends that like parents and schools get
Speaker 6:  terrified about that weren't actually trends, but it was just like one person
Speaker 6:  made a video and then some some person made a video warning you about the
Speaker 6:  video and then everybody latched onto that. Yeah. And it's like this was
Speaker 6:  never actually a thing that kids were doing, but now we're afraid of the
Speaker 6:  thing that kids aren't doing. If you go to the
Speaker 5:  Original video,
Speaker 6:  It is bad news.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I it's the, it's the, I call it the local news cycle. Once when I,
Speaker 5:  as a child in Wisconsin, the local news once reported the kids were getting
Speaker 5:  high by drinking too much water, which is a real thing that you can do. I
Speaker 5:  have since learned and my mom was like, how much water have you been drinking?
Speaker 5:  And I was like, not enough bro. It's, I've been drinking a lot of Miller
Speaker 5:  Light. Like
Speaker 6:  Yeah, she's not worried about that though. The water's the problem.
Speaker 5:  Anyhow,
Speaker 5:  I've got a quick update on the MrBeast situation. You recall last
Speaker 5:  week, MrBeast sued the company that was doing his
Speaker 5:  ghost kitchens for MrBeast burgers trying to get outta the contract. 'cause
Speaker 5:  there was no quality control surprise. They have now sued him back
Speaker 5:  $400 million saying that he's got more value out of
Speaker 5:  them and he's become more famous because of the
Speaker 5:  burgers. I don't know man. I just, that that's your lightning round update.
Speaker 5:  I think MrBeast versus the Burger company is, it's like
Speaker 5:  the pinnacle of influencer culture in a way. It it is directly related
Speaker 5:  to like the, there are a lot of thread
Speaker 5:  boys threading on the tweets about how MrBeast Burger was like the future
Speaker 5:  of dining. Oh yeah. All of those people should be forced to apologize.
Speaker 5:  Here's my theory. If you were a thread person on Twitter doing Threads like
Speaker 5:  that, and then you wanna join Instagram Threads Instagram should
Speaker 5:  enforce that. You have to post 50 apologies first and
Speaker 6:  Eat 50 Beast Burgers
Speaker 5:  And Eat 50 be you have to do a Beast Burger challenge
Speaker 5:  for if you have ever written a one of 99
Speaker 5:  Twitter thread about how MrBeast Burger was the future of
Speaker 5:  dining, I think, I think you should have your platform credentials revoked
Speaker 5:  until you eat 50 Beast
Speaker 6:  Burgers. I like it. I will say, listen, I'm not a lawyer, but the, the idea
Speaker 6:  that MrBeast is only famous because of the burgers does not make a lot of
Speaker 6:  sense to me.
Speaker 5:  Does not fly. It's also, by the way, his actual work,
Speaker 5:  it is clear he cares a lot about the quality of his
Speaker 5:  actual work. Yep. Like a MrBeast video is like a
Speaker 5:  rigorously edited jewel of a thing. Yeah. And it's like,
Speaker 5:  you can see why he's pissed. The burgers are wrong.
Speaker 5:  It's just like very obvious. Anyhow. All right, David, what's
Speaker 5:  yours?
Speaker 6:  Mine is just a small Threads update, which is
Speaker 6:  a very cool little thing that happened where you can now use
Speaker 6:  your Mastodon profile and your Threads profile essentially
Speaker 6:  as verification systems. So you can, you can go to Mastodon
Speaker 6:  and say, You know my Threads account is this, and then actually use your
Speaker 6:  Threads account to verify that, which at a very small level
Speaker 6:  is like, it doesn't matter, it's like a teeny tiny feature. But it is, and
Speaker 6:  Instagram people have been saying this is the first sort of
Speaker 6:  meaningful step Threads has made into like the
Speaker 6:  activity pub decentralized social media world. And yeah,
Speaker 6:  we've said a bunch of times, like there are lots of reasons to believe Threads
Speaker 6:  will never decentralize in the way that it has promised, but the people who
Speaker 6:  are building the thing continues who loudly say they are going to do it.
Speaker 6:  And this was sort of the first like real world instantiation of that
Speaker 6:  And I think That's very exciting.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it's cool. I mean, it is like a very little thing, but it is true
Speaker 5:  that Thread's engineers were posting like, hope you believe us. Like
Speaker 5:  we're taking these baby steps. They
Speaker 7:  Were so proud about it. It just makes me happy that like how excited people
Speaker 7:  were for it. I'm not excited for it, but everyone was so just pumped. I don't
Speaker 7:  care.
Speaker 11:  But everybody else was so
Speaker 6:  Pumped. So I just wanna say by the way, the, the, every time I write about
Speaker 6:  this stuff or talk about it on a show like this, the overwhelming
Speaker 6:  response is people don't care about decentralized platforms. That's not how
Speaker 6:  you win user experience, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. And that's a
Speaker 6:  stupid argument. People didn't care about anything until they
Speaker 6:  realized why it was cool and started using it. That's how things work.
Speaker 6:  And in this case, like I, I will continue to plead loudly
Speaker 6:  that decentralized social media is a good idea and we should pursue it.
Speaker 6:  And you should care as a person because it will make better
Speaker 6:  products and a better internet. And my number one
Speaker 6:  goal in life is to convince random strangers that decentralized social
Speaker 6:  media is a concept they should care about. So I here I can
Speaker 5:  Well, no, it's, I'll give you the, I'll just flip that around. These
Speaker 5:  clowns forced us to care about crypto,
Speaker 5:  Right? Like they, the money that
Speaker 5:  flowed into that ecosystem to try to force us to care about it.
Speaker 5:  And we to The Verge and The Vergecast audience
Speaker 5:  by and large was like, don't care about this. Like fully rejected.
Speaker 5:  But it's weird that because there's not that much money in the system
Speaker 5:  that people are like, no one will ever care about this. And like, I just,
Speaker 5:  it's the things are not user experiences. The things are
Speaker 5:  the things that enable other people to make products and services that
Speaker 5:  compete, which is the thing that we care about the
Speaker 6:  Most. Yeah. It's like, it's like the moment that the Open web started to
Speaker 6:  beat a o l there were probably bunch of people who are like, who cares? Everybody's
Speaker 6:  on a o l And it's like, no, this other thing is better. Yeah. And like, give
Speaker 6:  me a minute and I'll prove it to you. And like that's how I feel about the
Speaker 6:  future of social stuff right now. And
Speaker 5:  At the end of the day, Twitter's gonna buy Time Warner.
Speaker 11:  It's,
Speaker 5:  It's the final form of Twitter is they're also gonna own Batman
Speaker 5:  for some reason. All right. The last one we got You
Speaker 5:  know I had to end here. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It feels right. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Unfortunately
Speaker 5:  There's a new ev Escalade, it's called the Escalade IQ. I love it.
Speaker 5:  It's so expensive. It's $130,000, but it is
Speaker 5:  hot. It's, and it's huge. It's the biggest
Speaker 6:  Car's. It a massive car.
Speaker 5:  It's ridiculous. It's so big. It's not as big as the escalated is feed. It's
Speaker 5:  not as big as the big as Escalade, but it's still huge. It's bigger than
Speaker 5:  a regular Escalade. Three rows, beautiful.
Speaker 5:  450 miles of range mostly. 'cause the battery is the size of a Sherman tank
Speaker 5:  has a Crabwalk mode Oh yeah. That the Hummer ev has. So it can like go
Speaker 5:  sideways. The thing's cool. $130,000. I sent a photo of it
Speaker 5:  to Becky with just the words Hear me out. And she wrote, that's hot. Oh
Speaker 6:  Congratulations. Good. Right?
Speaker 5:  I was like, what if we sell everything and buy an ev Escalade? And she was
Speaker 5:  like, I'll think about it. It's hot. Go look at pictures. GM,
Speaker 5:  they've been saying this is gonna happen. No CarPlay, huge
Speaker 5:  screens on the inside, the inside of his car looks hot. It's like wall to
Speaker 5:  wall screens.
Speaker 6:  It's a 55 inch screen across.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's an L E D L C D that wraps around the sort of climate
Speaker 5:  clusters. Another screen in the back, there's a third screen
Speaker 5:  screens for days and they're saying no CarPlay Android Auto. Again. They
Speaker 5:  said this was gonna happen ages ago. No one believed them. Here's the new
Speaker 5:  Escalade and they've done it. Now, importantly, Google built
Speaker 5:  in. So you get Google Maps, you get Google all the stuff that you might
Speaker 5:  want off a phone, but no Android or a CarPlay. I don't know if this is a
Speaker 5:  good idea. I haven't used it, haven't seen the car. Many
Speaker 5:  questions. But this is the moment when big car makers say,
Speaker 5:  when Cadillac says You, know what you're gonna buy an Escalade with or without
Speaker 5:  CarPlay also probably you're in the backseat of this Escalade fair. So it
Speaker 5:  doesn't matter. But like they're, they're betting
Speaker 5:  people are gonna buy Escalades without CarPlay because of what they want
Speaker 5:  is an Escalade.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Nila, you were obligated by law to think this is a good idea. So
Speaker 6:  congratulations. What I would just say is, I know I came
Speaker 6:  back to the show and said that I, I agree that CarPlay is bad, but the thing
Speaker 6:  is, I'm looking at the picture of this screen right now and it, it essentially,
Speaker 6:  if I can describe it, it basically the, the photo I've seen here in our piece
Speaker 6:  looks like sort of three distinct sides. One
Speaker 6:  side shows like nav and car information. The
Speaker 6:  middle is kind of classic infotainment. And on the right
Speaker 6:  is, I don't know, like a 15 inch across screen
Speaker 6:  that just has seven icons. Like this, this is what we're doing with our screens.
Speaker 6:  Like here's seven icons. This is awful. This is
Speaker 6:  the worst UI design I've ever seen in my life.
Speaker 5:  Oh no, you, you, no, no. So you're looking at that, that's like a menu screen.
Speaker 5:  So I, I think again, I have not seen this car.
Speaker 5:  So the screen all the way in the right is in front of the passenger. And
Speaker 5:  that is basically a TV of really
Speaker 6:  Skinny candy bar television.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's, it's a really weird TV with,
Speaker 7:  It looks like it's got H D M I
Speaker 5:  Input. It does have, I have one of these in my car. So we have a Jeep with
Speaker 5:  a passenger screen. It has a, it has a with h filter on the front of it,
Speaker 5:  so you can't see it from the driver's seat. And it has HT m i n and some
Speaker 5:  apps. Great. Like we've, I've used it once
Speaker 5:  to Stream a football game to that thing. And the entire time I just told
Speaker 5:  my wife that I was watching football and she's like, I don't care. You often
Speaker 5:  do that on your phone anyway. But I was like, now it's in the car. Like Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But that's what that thing over there in front of the passenger is, is this
Speaker 5:  belief the car industry has that passengers want a dedicated screen that
Speaker 5:  play that is a tv Well
Speaker 6:  It's a dedicated screen for them to put ads on. Yeah. Which is all fine and
Speaker 6:  good. I'm just saying these software designed here is garbage.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. The UI ugly.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, again, we have not seen the thing, so I
Speaker 5:  don't know what mode that is in, but you're right, you've got a thing that
Speaker 5:  is a cluster all the way on the left. Like that's the instrument cluster.
Speaker 5:  You've got your standard infotainment and then there's a set of new
Speaker 5:  ideas on the right of the car that honestly no
Speaker 5:  one in the car industry has figured out. But there should be a screen in
Speaker 5:  front of the passenger that is a tv just watch. It's, it's coming
Speaker 5:  to all of the cars.
Speaker 6:  And there's another screen right in front of the gear shift or like, this
Speaker 6:  is, this is
Speaker 5:  Just, that's the, that's the weird, crazy info. That's the climate control
Speaker 5:  and
Speaker 6:  Ah, because 'cause you don't have that in the other 55 inches. I just
Speaker 7:  Worry about these. Nope. Freezing.
Speaker 5:  Right? So like, here's what we don't know. Is this fast? Is it responsive?
Speaker 5:  Is the interface good? David thinks the interface is bad. What I, we, we
Speaker 5:  have spent but a few minutes looking at this thing. My point is
Speaker 5:  GM's position, And I guarantee you many, many more car makers
Speaker 5:  position over time is going to be, we are not letting
Speaker 5:  Apple take over the user experience of our vehicles. And
Speaker 5:  we think in particular, I think GM thinks with the Escalade,
Speaker 5:  the people will buy Escalades even without car plan Android Auto
Speaker 5:  because it has Google Maps, which is the thing that people care about the
Speaker 5:  most. And that's gonna be that Rivian is already
Speaker 5:  there. Tesla has been there forever. And I think they're, they're basically
Speaker 5:  looking at what people are doing on these phone apps or on these phone projection
Speaker 5:  systems and saying, You know what, by and large they are running Google Maps.
Speaker 5:  So if we just sign the deal with Google and run Google Maps on our thing.
Speaker 5:  Yep. We can run ads on the weird Hulu integration over on the right.
Speaker 5:  Yes, we can like You know as EV charging networks, blah blah blah. We
Speaker 5:  can like monitor the cars better, we can do telemetry, you can sell your
Speaker 5:  data, all that stuff. That seems kind of gross. But fundamentally they're
Speaker 5:  saying, look what you want outta, this is Google Maps and we've signed the
Speaker 5:  deal with Google to give you Google maps and Google is waiting there with
Speaker 5:  open arms.
Speaker 6:  I don't think that theory is wrong. I just don't think there is any
Speaker 6:  evidence in the history of cars that says car makers can make good software
Speaker 7:  Or the history of TVs. Like this is the exact same thing TVs have done,
Speaker 7:  TVs have been doing this for ages. They're like, we're gonna do it. Samsung
Speaker 7:  ties in and then you go buy an Apple TV and you plug it in and you go
Speaker 7:  away and you just can't do that with this because I guess you plug your it
Speaker 7:  into the H D M I port. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You can just plug your phone into H m I port and run off your phone.
Speaker 5:  But only on that screen the passenger gets, we'll see it's
Speaker 5:  $130,000 ev Escalade, like the
Speaker 5:  risk profile for this car is very low. I think the people who
Speaker 5:  are gonna spend 130,000 thousand dollars on ev Sade have people who use
Speaker 5:  their phones for them.
Speaker 6:  Fair. That's gonna be you someday Meli. And
Speaker 5:  That's my dream.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. We're gonna get the Becky review of this car someday.
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be great. Alright. That's it. David, you have a new newsletter?
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 6:  That's, if you're listening to this on Friday,
Speaker 6:  you have one day to sign up. It's called Installer. And the idea
Speaker 6:  was basically to just take all of the cool stuff on the internet
Speaker 6:  and put it all into one place. It's like, there's like new apps
Speaker 6:  every week. There's new stuff to watch, there's new games to play, there's
Speaker 6:  new like cool creators coming out all the time. And I spend a
Speaker 6:  lot of time just like pouring this stuff into like random
Speaker 6:  documents and never doing anything with them. And I was like, I am going
Speaker 6:  to do better at finding new stuff and I've been asking people to
Speaker 6:  send stuff install earth The Verge dot com. Anytime you see anything cool
Speaker 6:  anywhere on the internet, send it to me. I've already gotten a ton of really
Speaker 6:  fun stuff. There's a lot of really fun stuff in the first issue. You can
Speaker 6:  read it on the site every Sunday, but you can also subscribe and
Speaker 6:  get it in your inbox every Saturday. And we're gonna do lots of things like
Speaker 6:  have beta invites and access to cool stuff and like
Speaker 6:  giveaways and stuff. So it's a, it's a big advantage to be a day early.
Speaker 6:  It's The Verge dot com slash Installer. I think that the first issue's really
Speaker 6:  fun. And I, hope it will be forever. It's gonna be awesome. Yeah. Eli's
Speaker 6:  in the first issue I made Neli send me his home screen and tell me about
Speaker 6:  all the truly unhinged apps that he seems to use every day.
Speaker 6:  So if you wanna know what Eli's phone looks like, check it out.
Speaker 5:  I do not know why Spotify, I'm trying Apple Music for, I took that
Speaker 5:  screenshot. I was like, why is this here? Uncurated to the extreme.
Speaker 5:  All right, one more thing. We're doing cybersecurity questions on the
Speaker 5:  Wednesday show. Yeah, right. David, give us a call. 8 6
Speaker 5:  6 Verge one one with your cybersecurity questions. I'm having a lot of fun
Speaker 5:  doing read review back this summer. One question I have for all of you also
Speaker 5:  let us know if, if you like it, if you like it when we're reading the emails
Speaker 5:  and doing the voicemails, that'll be really useful. We are having fun. I
Speaker 5:  just wanna make sure you think it's a good part of the show. Let us know.
Speaker 5:  Also, if you've ever had a meaningful five g experience. I,
Speaker 5:  it's driving bonkers. All right. That's it. That's a rich rock around.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 1:  us an email at Vergecast at The Verge dot com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network. The show is produced
Speaker 1:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. Our
Speaker 1:  editorial director is Brooke Miners. That's it. We'll see you next week.