# Transcript
ID: 88517d62-e257-495c-961b-fa43e8b9ff9f
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The 50-year quest for AI virtual assistants
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5849178826305256619/-8692007800693104970/s93290-US-1904s-1696207807.mp3
Description: In part three of our AI mini series, David Pierce dives into the decades-long endeavor to build a virtual assistant. What can a virtual assistant do? What do we want it to do?
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Support for this show comes from a w s. Innovations in
Speaker 2:  machine learning and AI have completely changed the game. But
Speaker 2:  as with any cutting edge technology, it's important to stay ahead of the
Speaker 2:  curve or you risk getting left behind. Amazon Web Services
Speaker 2:  can help your small business stay ahead of the competition. A W
Speaker 2:  SS provides a framework for businesses to navigate the fast changing landscape
Speaker 2:  and helps businesses harness the emerging capabilities of AI and
Speaker 2:  machine learning. It's time to imagine how a w S can
Speaker 2:  transform your business. Go to a SS is how.com
Speaker 2:  to learn more.
Speaker 3:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of generative search queries.
Speaker 3:  I'm your friend David Pierce and this is the third and final episode in our
Speaker 3:  series about ai. And for this one I wanna talk about one of the oldest stories
Speaker 3:  in AI and really one of the oldest stories in the tech industry as a whole,
Speaker 3:  the virtual digital assistant. My favorite story about this
Speaker 3:  is one I learned a few years ago and I've been thinking about it ever since.
Speaker 3:  So go back to 1979 in Palo Alto, California, this
Speaker 3:  guy named Steve Jobs, you may have heard of him, goes to Xerox Park, which
Speaker 3:  was this ultra successful r and d lab owned at the time by
Speaker 3:  Xerox. People at Park helped create everything from laser printers
Speaker 3:  to ethernet to personal computers. It was this incredible factory
Speaker 3:  of cool technology. But the thing park is probably best known
Speaker 3:  for is what Steve Jobs saw. The graphical user interface
Speaker 3:  which went beyond the text-based command based computers
Speaker 3:  everybody was using and actually used images, menus and
Speaker 3:  space like three dimensional space to help people navigate their computers.
Speaker 3:  And as the legend goes, jobs saw all that, took it back to Apple, made
Speaker 3:  the Macintosh, took over the world. The story's actually slightly
Speaker 3:  more complicated than that. The Macintosh had been in development since about
Speaker 3:  a year earlier and it seems like what the park visit may have really done
Speaker 3:  is help convince jobs that it was a good idea worth pursuing and building
Speaker 3:  rather than, you know, showing it to him for the first time. But that is
Speaker 3:  not what I wanna talk about. The story I wanna talk about was happening in
Speaker 3:  a different lab at park where a bunch of employees were teaching a computer
Speaker 3:  to understand and communicate in natural language.
Speaker 3:  They had this idea for what they called the conversational user interface
Speaker 3:  where instead of typing commands, essentially like writing code into your
Speaker 3:  computer, you could work with your computer by just asking questions and
Speaker 3:  typing like a person. Remember this all sounds very normal now, this is
Speaker 3:  almost 50 years ago. And actually forget typing as a whole. They thought
Speaker 3:  maybe eventually you'd just talk to your computer out loud like a person.
Speaker 3:  The team at Park in general thought that a computer should act more like
Speaker 3:  an assistant than a machine. You'd say book me a flight to Tucson for
Speaker 3:  next weekend and it wouldn't launch a program to do that, it would just do
Speaker 3:  it for you. They actually built this thing called Gus the genial
Speaker 3:  Understander system to show off what they were talking about. And in a
Speaker 3:  paper in 1977, again 46 years ago,
Speaker 3:  the researchers included a sample dialogue of how this interface might work.
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna have two AI voices read it right now just so you get the vibe of
Speaker 3:  how it might work. It starts with Guss, the AI system introducing itself.
Speaker 5:  Hello, my name is Gus. I can help you plan a simple trip by air.
Speaker 5:  Where do you want to go?
Speaker 4:  I want to go to San Diego on May 28th.
Speaker 5:  What time do you want to leave?
Speaker 4:  I must be in San Diego before 10 in the morning.
Speaker 5:  What do you like? P S A flight 102 that arrives at
Speaker 5:  9:15 AM
Speaker 4:  What is the next flight?
Speaker 5:  Air California flight 310 that leaves at 8:30 AM
Speaker 5:  and arrives at 10:00 AM
Speaker 4:  I'll take the first one.
Speaker 5:  In what name should I make a reservation, please?
Speaker 4:  Dan Bobrow.
Speaker 5:  I have confirmed the following flight P ss a flight 102
Speaker 5:  on Wednesday, May 28th from San Jose to San Diego. That leaves at
Speaker 5:  7:30 AM and arrives at 9:15 AM What date
Speaker 5:  do you want to return on
Speaker 4:  On Friday in the evening? Would
Speaker 5:  You like the flight that leaves at 7:45 PM
Speaker 4:  That's fine.
Speaker 5:  I have confirmed the following flight P S A flight 307
Speaker 5:  on Friday, May 30th from San Diego to San Jose that leaves at
Speaker 5:  7:45 PM and arrives at 9:30 PM Thank you
Speaker 5:  for calling. Goodbye.
Speaker 3:  I'm pretty sure the voices there wouldn't have sounded nearly that good in
Speaker 3:  1977, but you get the idea. Obviously the graphical
Speaker 3:  user interface won out at the time and won for a long time.
Speaker 3:  That thing you just heard is not how we book plane tickets and it hasn't
Speaker 3:  been for the last four decades, but people did keep working on this stuff.
Speaker 3:  The idea of a virtual digital assistant that can just do things for
Speaker 3:  you and all you have to do is talk to it like you would talk to a person,
Speaker 3:  has been so seductive to so many people for so long. And
Speaker 3:  in recent years it actually feels like we're kind of veering back toward
Speaker 3:  the conversational user interface as the future of computing. I mean
Speaker 3:  chat G P T is nothing if not a conversational user interface.
Speaker 3:  It's like the whole of the internet in a chat window binging is becoming
Speaker 3:  the same thing Google has barred, which is you know, the same deal. And
Speaker 3:  even with things like Alexa and Siri and Google Assistant, we've been heading
Speaker 3:  down this road for almost a decade, but it actually feels like it's
Speaker 3:  really exploding right now. And this push we're
Speaker 3:  on raises some really interesting questions. How far does the chat window
Speaker 3:  go? Is the future of computing really just like messaging
Speaker 3:  And are we actually with this advent of modern large language
Speaker 3:  models and all of the underlying tech that makes AI smarter and more
Speaker 3:  useful? Getting close to the kind of virtual assistant we've been dreaming
Speaker 3:  about for basically half a century To help me figure out
Speaker 3:  those answers, I called up Richard Soer.
Speaker 6:  I'm Richard Soer and I'm the c e o@u.com.
Speaker 3:  U.com is actually one of the most ambitious AI assistant
Speaker 3:  platforms I've ever tried. It's partly an AI search engine so it can
Speaker 3:  answer your questions or help you find information on the web. That's really
Speaker 3:  where it started. It's also a generative AI tool so you can
Speaker 3:  use it to write code or create images or come up with
Speaker 3:  brilliant emails that just sound like you and long term, if Richard
Speaker 3:  has it right you.com will also become something like the smartphone,
Speaker 3:  a platform on which you can do almost anything all through this one
Speaker 3:  interface. Richard has been in the tech industry for a long time
Speaker 3:  and he's been working on problems of natural language processing for even
Speaker 3:  longer. He actually did a PhD at Stanford on bringing neural
Speaker 3:  networks, which is kind of an AI system to natural language processing,
Speaker 3:  which was at that time a huge leap forward in rethinking how
Speaker 3:  computers process speech point is he knows the history of all this, he knows
Speaker 3:  how it works, he knows how hard it has been to pull this off and he told
Speaker 3:  me that over the last decade as he saw this tech get better,
Speaker 3:  he thought this might be the moment to do it.
Speaker 3:  What he wanted to build was a chatbot kind of and an assistant. Sure.
Speaker 3:  But he looked at all his research on language and conversation and
Speaker 3:  natural language processing and how we interact with computers and he decided
Speaker 3:  the thing he really needed to do was build a different kind of search
Speaker 3:  engine.
Speaker 6:  The biggest application of natural language understanding is in search.
Speaker 6:  That's where billions of people learn something, try to find
Speaker 6:  information, try to get things done, and they start all
Speaker 6:  of these tasks on a search engine. And so do
Speaker 6:  I want to necessarily call that a search engine? It almost
Speaker 6:  doesn't matter what you call it, but it is that sort of magical
Speaker 6:  spot in the beginning of many people's online journey
Speaker 6:  where you sit to be able to be helpful for those
Speaker 6:  users. And so that's sort of led me, what led me to search
Speaker 3:  That like distinction of what you call it I actually think is like part of
Speaker 3:  the reason I'm so fascinated by you.com. 'cause I think you're absolute,
Speaker 3:  I mean you're obviously right that search is kind of the dominant
Speaker 3:  interface for this kind of natural language processing and the idea of
Speaker 3:  just like how people search for information. But simultaneously, even
Speaker 3:  as you're starting to think about how to apply neural networks to this stuff,
Speaker 3:  like obviously you were thinking about this stuff before Chad g p t
Speaker 3:  was around showing, you know, new chat body ideas
Speaker 3:  about how this stuff could work. But you were, you were playing with this
Speaker 3:  technology for a long time and I, I can imagine a world that is
Speaker 3:  not that different from this world where you went much more down the like
Speaker 3:  Siri, Alexa, Google assistant route rather than kind of
Speaker 3:  building something that looks like a search engine even to accomplish
Speaker 3:  relatively the same goal, right? Am I, am I thinking about that the wrong
Speaker 3:  way? Like are those two things kind of further apart in your brain than they
Speaker 3:  are in mine?
Speaker 6:  You couldn't be more spot on. And it's actually very timely too because
Speaker 6:  we dropped the word search engine from you.com. Oh
Speaker 3:  Interesting.
Speaker 6:  Okay. We're now just like make it very clear that this is going to be a
Speaker 6:  conversation and that we're an AI chat assistant
Speaker 6:  that's going to help you learn and get more things done,
Speaker 6:  help you summarize and, and all of these things. And so that's
Speaker 6:  exactly how we're we actually repositioned
Speaker 6:  ourselves after many years we've learned that really search
Speaker 6:  engines do not inspire excitement from people.
Speaker 6:  But an AI chat assistant that helps you with finding information
Speaker 6:  and answers and learn and so on does excite people.
Speaker 6:  They're ultimately the same thing. It is a marketing question. We still
Speaker 6:  want to be able to say this can be the default in your browser. You know,
Speaker 6:  you can start every question you have in your browser, in your u l nav bar,
Speaker 6:  it defaults to you.com because that's where you get the most useful
Speaker 6:  first step in many different intents that you have. But yeah,
Speaker 6:  we're moving away from the term search engine and to
Speaker 6:  be honest, and I probably shouldn't say this, but we don't have it finalized
Speaker 6:  yet, what the new terminology should be. The
Speaker 6:  place we want to be is be the most helpful assistant that you
Speaker 6:  can be. Which honestly is also something that Google has worked on for many
Speaker 6:  years as well.
Speaker 3:  Part of what seems like has changed since you started working@u.com is that
Speaker 3:  I think one thing that you did that was very smart at the beginning was make
Speaker 3:  it look like a search engine. Just because I think that's like a thing people
Speaker 3:  understand that's right. What to do with right? That like even
Speaker 3:  in the way that I think a lot of people open chat G P T now and it's like,
Speaker 3:  well what do I do with this? People instinctively understand what to do when
Speaker 3:  they open a webpage that looks like Google. So building a webpage that kind
Speaker 3:  of looks like Google makes a lot of sense. Even if what you're doing on the
Speaker 3:  other side of that ends up being very different. Do, do you think that's
Speaker 3:  changing, that you can make something that looks less and less like
Speaker 3:  a Google query page and start to bring people along with you into
Speaker 3:  all that other stuff now?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it sounds like you're in our meetings that's, that's
Speaker 6:  very astute, very astute observation too here. This is something we,
Speaker 6:  we exactly found that last year. We had in the summer
Speaker 6:  the first LMS within a search engine context and
Speaker 6:  we tried to innovate over the last two and a half years
Speaker 6:  along a lot of different dimensions of what could
Speaker 6:  con in the past be called a search engine. We tried, you know, we had
Speaker 6:  horizontal scroll where you just see a few sources and then you can always
Speaker 6:  dive deeper into it very quickly. And we had, you know,
Speaker 6:  different apps that are within that search engine context. And
Speaker 6:  what we would often hear from users until late last
Speaker 6:  year was, that's interesting, but I'm just so used to
Speaker 6:  Google, I wouldn't wanna switch to anything that's too different. And it
Speaker 6:  ha we kept getting pulled back by users in our journey
Speaker 6:  to something that is more and more similar to Google and it was quite
Speaker 6:  frustrating. 'cause you know, we had some good ideas we thought and we, you
Speaker 6:  know, in each of these ideas we had a core, a hardcore group
Speaker 6:  of of power users who did love it, but it's just wasn't growing enough.
Speaker 6:  And the majority of feedback we kept getting is it's two different
Speaker 6:  to Google, it's two different to Google. I want something like that's more
Speaker 6:  similar but just a little bit better here and there. And so that
Speaker 6:  all changed thanks to chat G B T all of a sudden
Speaker 6:  a lot of users, a lot of them early adopters, but more and
Speaker 6:  more just normal folks too, basically could
Speaker 6:  conceive a new world of finding and learning
Speaker 6:  about things in the world. And so that is kind of the biggest advantage
Speaker 6:  that we've had since chat. G B T came out and, you know, two and a
Speaker 6:  half weeks later we launched youth chat, which basically was the
Speaker 6:  first l m that is connected to the internet and hence can be up to
Speaker 6:  date factual and have citations for the facts that it tells you.
Speaker 6:  Making it much more trustworthy.
Speaker 3:  Okay, we need to take a break and then we're gonna come back and talk more
Speaker 3:  with Richard.
Speaker 2:  Support for this show comes from a w s. We are living
Speaker 2:  in the future and artificial intelligence is completely transforming
Speaker 2:  how business is done. But without an experienced developer on your
Speaker 2:  team, how can you make the most of these emerging technologies?
Speaker 2:  Amazon web services can help. A w s has been
Speaker 2:  democratizing access to AI and machine learning for companies and
Speaker 2:  customers. They've invested $100 million to build their
Speaker 2:  generative AI innovation center to help customers understand and
Speaker 2:  deploy generative AI to predict trends and prototype with
Speaker 2:  data-driven design. Just imagine how a W Ss can
Speaker 2:  transform your business. Learn
Speaker 2:  more@awsishow.com
Speaker 3:  Welcome back. Like we've been talking about, the uptick in AI
Speaker 3:  and natural language processing and voice assistance has been happening
Speaker 3:  kind of slowly and then all at once over the last decade or so. And
Speaker 3:  even though Siri still kind of sucks sometimes the underlying tech
Speaker 3:  really has come an incredibly long way in that time. But
Speaker 3:  I think if you wanted to pick the moment, the modern era of
Speaker 3:  conversational user interfaces really started, it would have to be the
Speaker 3:  launch of chat G P T last fall.
Speaker 3:  Something about this system that felt like it understood all your questions
Speaker 3:  and responded with human and helpful answers felt like
Speaker 3:  magic to a lot of people in a way that even Alexa and Google Assistant
Speaker 3:  just never did chat. G p T isn't perfect, obviously it's
Speaker 3:  a million miles away from perfect, but it seemed to make people think that
Speaker 3:  it might be someday and that there might be something revolutionary in that
Speaker 3:  this could be the way we access information, not by going to
Speaker 3:  google.com or scrolling stuff on your phone, but just by asking for it. That
Speaker 3:  felt huge, but now it's a year later and that
Speaker 3:  idea has taken a bit of a hit for one thing. We've all discovered the
Speaker 3:  many, many, many imperfections of the tech and also the ways in
Speaker 3:  which conversations maybe aren't all that efficient. I think we're definitely
Speaker 3:  in the low part of the chatbot hype cycle. It'll get better, but
Speaker 3:  it's not what it once was.
Speaker 3:  Richard though started u.com before the chat G p T
Speaker 3:  explosion and so he's seen everything rise and fall and rise and
Speaker 3:  fall and all the parts of the hype cycle here and he's seen people
Speaker 3:  poke at the edges of the tech and really try to figure out where it breaks.
Speaker 3:  So what have we learned What can a virtual assistant do? And if and when
Speaker 3:  the tech really does work, how do we want it to work?
Speaker 3:  Richard says we're still learning. He's still learning, but he has some
Speaker 3:  pretty big ideas about it.
Speaker 6:  Like we, I love text, right? I love natural language processing, but
Speaker 6:  text isn't always the best way to communicate something.
Speaker 6:  Multimodal answers are the best way. So if you
Speaker 6:  ask you Chatt, what's the stock price of Palantir or
Speaker 6:  Salesforce or some company, we're not gonna just give you a bunch of numbers
Speaker 6:  at especially not those that are hallucinated sure by, by an
Speaker 6:  lmm. But we show you a stock ticker that's interactive, you can move your
Speaker 6:  mouse over, you can see the daily trends, the weekly trends that yearly trends,
Speaker 6:  the market cap and all of these different numbers and you just see it
Speaker 6:  directly within the chat window, right? And then you can ask like, well now
Speaker 6:  who's their c e o? And it still captures all the context and remembers which
Speaker 6:  company you talked about before and then, you know, gives you that company
Speaker 6:  c e o even though if you, you know, just did in a retrieval backend who's
Speaker 6:  their c e o, it wouldn't give you anything useful. But you know, we, we learn
Speaker 6:  to transform those queries as one of the many things that that, you know,
Speaker 6:  going on in the background that you have to get right in a lot of different
Speaker 6:  ways and very easy and obvious when you get it wrong. Easy mistakes
Speaker 6:  to make. And So, we believe the answer in the future
Speaker 6:  is going to be multimodal. And that's why we invented also last year
Speaker 6:  this app store where you can essentially, other people
Speaker 6:  can also submit apps to you.com and then they can show up
Speaker 6:  within the search results and within the chat response. And I think that
Speaker 6:  will ultimately be the best interface. Similar to, you know, giving me some
Speaker 6:  good restaurants around me. I, I still remember when speech recognition
Speaker 6:  start started to finally work and I started, you know, investing also after
Speaker 6:  my first company's acquisition. I had a bunch of folks say, oh, we're gonna
Speaker 6:  use speech recognition and to do all of these different things and it's gonna
Speaker 6:  be your personal assistant. I'm like, okay, well gimme an example. And one
Speaker 6:  of the founders was like, well the example is like you asked for a restaurant.
Speaker 6:  And I'm like, so you really say I have this like
Speaker 6:  speech system And I talked to it and I asked it like, what are some good
Speaker 6:  restaurants? And the response is, there are 150
Speaker 6:  restaurants around you. Number one has 4.3 stars. Their favorite
Speaker 6:  dish is Pat Thai and is 0.3 miles away from. And then like 10
Speaker 6:  hours later you'd have a sense of where to go. Like it doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 6:  And so, you know, I love ai, I love natural language processing,
Speaker 6:  but you have to have some user empathy and try to build,
Speaker 6:  build it in a way that meets people where they are and, and not be too
Speaker 6:  much. Like this is the new hammer, everything is a nail kind of thing.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I mean it's, it's kind of a amazing how many systems
Speaker 3:  work like that redo all the restaurants in the neighborhood thing.
Speaker 3:  Like that's where we are with so many things right now. I guess the app store
Speaker 3:  thing was gonna be my follow-up question, which is like, how much of this
Speaker 3:  do you feel obligated to build yourself versus how much can you kind of
Speaker 3:  create the ecosystem for? And I guess I do still wonder that like, especially
Speaker 3:  as it grows in the capabilities grow and there's a lot more things to do.
Speaker 3:  How much of that space is kind of you dot com's job
Speaker 3:  versus being, you know, the platform on which all of this other
Speaker 3:  stuff exists,
Speaker 6:  Huh? Maybe we should hire you now product team. Yeah. That, that
Speaker 6:  is the big, the billion, trillion dollar question. I think
Speaker 6:  long term it's very clear to me that it cannot be all
Speaker 6:  on us and an a system that ultimately lets you accomplish anything
Speaker 6:  and encompasses the entire economy. But it's also
Speaker 6:  clear that there's a cold start problem here. People don't want to build
Speaker 6:  an app on a platform that haven't, doesn't have hundreds of millions of users.
Speaker 6:  Hundreds of millions of users aren't gonna come to your platform if you
Speaker 6:  don't already provide enough functionality
Speaker 6:  to fulfill most of their needs in a really, really
Speaker 6:  good way. And some needs better than anyone else ever or anywhere else.
Speaker 6:  And so that's the cold start problem. So in the beginning it is mostly
Speaker 6:  on us and then I hope over time it transitions and we'll get more and
Speaker 6:  more high quality apps into the ecosystem. And I think that will ultimately
Speaker 6:  be a more fair way of structuring that first
Speaker 6:  page of the internet that currently, you know, Google benefits from everyone
Speaker 6:  else on the internet, but then they don't benefit back right that much other
Speaker 6:  than of course, you know, paying for ads and traffic and having to pay for
Speaker 6:  even their own ads on their own name, just so that there's not a competitor
Speaker 6:  that outbids them on their own name and then they show up on top and like
Speaker 6:  all of these things. So I think it's a better way and a fair way to
Speaker 6:  have ultimately a chat portal again. But I think
Speaker 6:  portals also have a bad marketing connotation and So, we might not call it
Speaker 6:  that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I always thought the one, one of the things you guys did really well
Speaker 3:  from the very beginning was kind of let people just tell
Speaker 3:  you the sources they like better. I've never understood why every search
Speaker 3:  engine doesn't just let me say I really like these four news
Speaker 3:  websites and I'm not that interested in seeing other news websites. Like
Speaker 3:  it seems like such a straightforward thing and I feel like the app store
Speaker 3:  model really just builds on that in a lot of ways, right? You get to curate
Speaker 3:  That's right, right? Like, here is the stuff I wanna see and the ways I wanna
Speaker 3:  see it and others can tap into that. And that's a pretty
Speaker 3:  powerful kind of feedback loop, which I think is very cool.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, in the, in the pre-chat days, Reddit was one of our favorite
Speaker 6:  apps of our users. Yeah. How
Speaker 3:  Do you think about personalization? I mean it seems to me that the perfect
Speaker 3:  version of this, you know, years down the road or however long it takes
Speaker 3:  is an assistant that effectively knows everything about me,
Speaker 3:  right? And knows where I am and what I like and what I'm interested in and
Speaker 3:  on and on and on. And obviously that has big privacy
Speaker 3:  questions, which I want to talk about, but also just like logistically is
Speaker 3:  very hard to do. And I, I'm, I'm just thinking about like search is
Speaker 3:  one thing where it's just kind of up ranking and down ranking web pages,
Speaker 3:  but like if you're trying to help me do stuff, getting information from
Speaker 3:  me seems really important, but also like the kind of thing you don't want
Speaker 3:  too, too much of or you're gonna lose people. Like how do you, how do you
Speaker 3:  think about that?
Speaker 6:  That's right. Yeah. It's something we have been working on for, for
Speaker 6:  many months. You have to know when to do this
Speaker 6:  and when it's not that useful, if you just want to add no, like when was
Speaker 6:  Barack Obama born? It doesn't really make that much sense to be like,
Speaker 6:  well maybe he liked mountain biking too, sometimes, you know, it's like,
Speaker 6:  that's not what I asked for, right? I just asked you a simple question. I
Speaker 6:  want to get a simple fact. And so to not overly personalize, but
Speaker 6:  to know when to do it well and, and when to reuse the facts
Speaker 6:  and then also do it make it seamless for the user. So it's just feels like,
Speaker 6:  oh yeah, like the more I use this, the better it gets for me without
Speaker 6:  being too creepy either and, and still having control over their
Speaker 6:  private information in a way that, you know, makes them feel
Speaker 6:  safe is very important.
Speaker 3:  So what, what are you seeing as, as folks are really starting to embrace
Speaker 3:  the kind of chat assistant piece of this? Obviously the
Speaker 3:  like, help me write an email, help me with my code thing
Speaker 3:  seem to be two sort of killer apps for people. Is there other stuff you're
Speaker 3:  seeing that's jumping out at you as kind of nascent use cases here?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, a ton of things. I think students are going to have a
Speaker 6:  really great time on you.com. We just launched a back to school
Speaker 6:  campaign two, it's now the cheapest way to access GBT four
Speaker 6:  plus, you know, have access to the internet for that chatbot. And on that
Speaker 6:  front too soon we will have a whole new class of
Speaker 6:  questions that are very complex that no other
Speaker 6:  normal lmm chatbot can currently solve
Speaker 6:  accurately, but often pretends to be able to solve and then does make a lot
Speaker 6:  of mistakes, which I think is, is very problematic. It's just
Speaker 6:  a whole new class of, of problems that can be answered with
Speaker 6:  an AI that has just more, more superpowers than just
Speaker 6:  an a large language model. But yeah, for now I think I still
Speaker 6:  see a lot of potential for parents, you know, for,
Speaker 6:  for folks who want to find new recipes for people who'd wanna do
Speaker 6:  travel planning and get like nice ideas for itineraries
Speaker 6:  that are going to be much more personalized also in the coming coming weeks
Speaker 6:  on new.com and then students getting answers for their questions. I'm,
Speaker 6:  I'm excited also to incorporate more and more generative AI capabilities
Speaker 6:  into these, you know, if you ask like, how can I generate an image with AI
Speaker 6:  Then, we just let you do that right then and there. If you're on your pro,
Speaker 6:  you can do it as often as you want. And so yeah, lots of lots of
Speaker 6:  interesting use cases. I think the more where we are still
Speaker 6:  iterating on is like when to make it just as good as Google
Speaker 6:  for the quick navigational stuff and the quick informational stuff, and then
Speaker 6:  when can we really shine by being much more chat
Speaker 6:  first?
Speaker 3:  Right? And you do kind of have to do both, right? Even though the navigational
Speaker 3:  stuff is ultimately not that interesting. That's the, like, that's a
Speaker 3:  big part of the sort of habit building of it, right? And and if you really
Speaker 3:  want to be the kind of homepage of the internet for people,
Speaker 3:  you have to do that as well or better than Google.
Speaker 6:  That's exactly right. You know, and there are a lot of like chat bots out
Speaker 6:  there that some of them I think are a little bit, you know, they have their
Speaker 6:  hype moments, but because they're just not connected
Speaker 6:  to the internet, they're not that factual and up to date they give you, sometimes
Speaker 6:  they even give you citations but don't actually, when you click on the
Speaker 6:  citation, you don't see the facts that they're saying, you know, that was
Speaker 6:  the citation for, it's not at all on that page and, and that that
Speaker 6:  loses a lot of trust after a while. And so, you know, there's, there's a
Speaker 6:  lot of like sort of brief hype chats, but I think
Speaker 6:  to have a really long-term shot, you need to have the
Speaker 6:  utility that is more similar to a search engine, not just be like
Speaker 6:  a dictionary lookup kind of thing that you use once a week.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, totally. As a, I think the idea of an AI chat bot
Speaker 3:  is like a complimentary thing is kind of interesting, but it is like a primary
Speaker 3:  interface to the internet is where this stuff starts to get really interesting.
Speaker 3:  And I think, I think that's coming, but it's displacing Google is harder
Speaker 3:  than most people give it credit for is the thing I have learned over and
Speaker 3:  over and over in the time I've been in this world.
Speaker 6:  That's exactly right.
Speaker 3:  So last thing, talk to me about privacy just for a minute. I know it's, it's
Speaker 3:  a thing you guys have talked a lot about. I know the, the kind of all of
Speaker 3:  this stuff we're talking about utility and personalization and all this
Speaker 3:  stuff often kind of runs directly against privacy. Do you have
Speaker 3:  a strategy for kind of how to have your cake and eat it too here? Like how
Speaker 3:  do you, how do you think you can do right by all those things at the same
Speaker 3:  time?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, great question. We, we used to talk a lot about privacy
Speaker 6:  and we still care about it, but we don't talk about it as much because
Speaker 6:  to be honest, it doesn't e excite enough people. You just can't
Speaker 6:  grow quickly enough a consumer business by just talking
Speaker 6:  a lot about privacy. There are few folks that that can, and they, you know,
Speaker 6:  Dr. Go obviously is like amazing on that front, but we just
Speaker 6:  didn't see the growth from having a, a
Speaker 6:  strong focus on it. And it does in many, many cases
Speaker 6:  slow you down. Like people want to have no bugs and they wanna
Speaker 6:  know that things work, but if you were to never, ever do any, any
Speaker 6:  analytics, you don't know how happy you are making your users,
Speaker 6:  right? And so in many cases we didn't use, you know, we don't use Google
Speaker 6:  Analytics and so on to have the best privacy of any of these chat
Speaker 6:  engines. And when you look at pretty much all our chat competitors, all of
Speaker 6:  them are selling your chat transcripts and your data
Speaker 6:  to others. Maybe not always like specifically, but like, like attached to
Speaker 6:  your IP or something like that. But they're all like using Google analytics
Speaker 6:  and, and, and all of that. And so we're trying our best to
Speaker 6:  be the most private of those engines. But to be honest,
Speaker 6:  we've also, when you talk about it a lot, there's just some people who will
Speaker 6:  never be happy until you're an open source like
Speaker 6:  nonprofit on the tour network that like makes no, no
Speaker 6:  revenue like, and has no ads or anything like, and, and that's just
Speaker 6:  not a viable, viable business strategy either. And so, so yeah,
Speaker 6:  we care about it. We think we're the best private chat
Speaker 6:  engine and chat assistant out there, but we don't, we just don't talk
Speaker 6:  about it as much as, as other features that people seem to care about more.
Speaker 6:  And that helped us grow to many more millions of users than than before.
Speaker 3:  A little while after Richard and I talked, u.com rolled out a feature that
Speaker 3:  he hinted at a couple of times in our interview, it's called You Agent and
Speaker 3:  it's able to do everything from calculations to code execution for you.
Speaker 3:  One of the examples u.com gives is calculating your mortgage, feed it all
Speaker 3:  the data you care about, the amount of your loan, the time, the interest
Speaker 3:  rate, and the agent will run the numbers and spit a payment back to you.
Speaker 3:  This is a fairly benign example, right? There are a million ways to do mortgage
Speaker 3:  calculations on the internet, but u.com also says it plans to support things
Speaker 3:  like file uploads and graphical outputs and much more. So
Speaker 3:  the idea I think is that you could upload all of your mortgage docs and then
Speaker 3:  essentially have the agent explain them to you and do things with them and
Speaker 3:  even do things on your behalf with them. That is some
Speaker 3:  seriously cool virtual assistant stuff. I know I've said this already,
Speaker 3:  but it's important to keep saying that the tech for this all still is
Speaker 3:  not finished. The underlying models are getting better, but they're wrong
Speaker 3:  too often. They make things up too often. They don't show their work often
Speaker 3:  enough and they also just sometimes don't understand what you mean at
Speaker 3:  all. Plus, I really increasingly don't buy the vision that
Speaker 3:  chat is the future of everything, no matter what AI or binging or whoever
Speaker 3:  else would tell you. I don't think typing into a text box is the future of
Speaker 3:  the universe, but I'm more convinced than ever that the superpowered
Speaker 3:  virtual assistant we've been dreaming about and trying to build for more
Speaker 3:  than half a century might finally be here soon
Speaker 3:  and it's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 3:  All right, that's it for the show today. And that's it for our AI mini series.
Speaker 3:  We have had so much fun making this series. I really hope you've enjoyed
Speaker 3:  listening to it as well. We've also got a bunch more fun special stuff coming
Speaker 3:  up this fall, and don't worry, we will be back on Wednesday and Friday
Speaker 3:  with your regularly scheduled Vergecast programming. Until then, AI David,
Speaker 3:  you get one more run at the credits. You wanna do it? Here we go. Okay, that's
Speaker 3:  it for The Vergecast today. Thanks to everyone on the show today, and thank
Speaker 3:  you for listening. There's a whole lot more stuff from this conversation
Speaker 3:  at The Verge dot com. We put some links in the show notes, but also
Speaker 3:  read The Verge dot com. It's a good website. We like it. If
Speaker 3:  you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or other ideas about how to book
Speaker 3:  plane tickets, you can always email us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com
Speaker 3:  or keep calling the hotline, 8 66 Verge one
Speaker 3:  one. Send us all your thoughts and questions and ideas for what
Speaker 3:  we should do on the show. This show is produced by Andrew Marino
Speaker 3:  and Liam James Brooke Minters is our editorial director of Audio
Speaker 3:  The Vergecast is a Verge production and part of the Vox Media
Speaker 3:  Podcast network. We'll be back with your regularly scheduled Vergecast
Speaker 3:  on Wednesday and Friday to talk about DVDs, vr,
Speaker 3:  and all the other news of the week. See you then. Rock and roll
Speaker 2:  Support for this show came from a w s machine learning
Speaker 2:  cloud computing generative ai. Things are changing
Speaker 2:  and they're changing fast. It can be hard to keep up with cutting edge
Speaker 2:  technologies, let alone knowing how to use them effectively.
Speaker 2:  Amazon Web Services may be able to help. They make it easy for
Speaker 2:  businesses of any size to identify opportunities that generative
Speaker 2:  AI and machine learning offer and provide a proven framework for
Speaker 2:  best practices, all with customer support. For any technical and
Speaker 2:  non-technical questions you might have. Just imagine how
Speaker 2:  a w s can transform your business. Learn
Speaker 2:  more@awsishow.com.