# Transcript
ID: 4dfc26f0-9501-11ed-a567-9d4494438a91
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The smart TVs, Matter gadgets, and concept cars from CES
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6143177893729631909/-6244622970800879653/s93290-US-3576s-1673806832.mp3
Description: The Verge’s Alex Cranz, Jennifer Pattison Tuohy, Chris Welch, and Andrew Hawkins discuss the best TVs, cars, and smart home gadgets they saw at CES 2023 — from a color-changing car to a vacuum suction system on an OLED TV.
Speaker 1:  Hey, it's your friend Eli. I just wanna tell you about our new newsletter.
Speaker 1:  It's called Command Line. It's written by the verges, Alex Heath, and it's
Speaker 1:  all about the tech industry's inside conversation with scoops, interviews
Speaker 1:  and analysis you won't get anywhere else. Here's Alex.
Speaker 2:  Each week you'll get scoops about what's coming next from tech giants like
Speaker 2:  Apple and Meta and hear about the product and people moves that matter. And
Speaker 2:  I want you to be part of the conversation. So I'll be answering questions
Speaker 2:  and featuring what you have
Speaker 1:  To say. Head on over to the verge.com/command line to subscribe today. That's
Speaker 1:  the verge.com/command line.
Speaker 4:  Hello, and you're listening to the Vergecast, the flagship podcast
Speaker 4:  of recovering from the c e s Funk. I'm your
Speaker 4:  host Alex cr. No, I'm your friend Alex Kranz
Speaker 4:  and I'm joined with the lovely Gen Tui.
Speaker 5:  Hello
Speaker 4:  The lovely Chris Welch and the lovely Andy Hawkins.
Speaker 4:  Hello. Two of the three of these people were at CES last
Speaker 4:  week and so we're gonna be talking a lot about CES today. We're gonna
Speaker 4:  be talking about smart homes, we're gonna be smart talking about TVs. And
Speaker 4:  as you probably guessed from Andy being here, we're gonna be talking about
Speaker 4:  cars and next week we're gonna have another special episode
Speaker 4:  still getting into ces, where we're gonna be talking with Monica all about
Speaker 4:  the laptops and the weird dual screen laptop that she's actually
Speaker 4:  obsessed with. And we're gonna talk with Victoria Song about all kinds of
Speaker 4:  health stuff that happened at the show. But today we're talking about what
Speaker 4:  really matters matter.
Speaker 5:  That was my segue there, wasn't it?
Speaker 4:  That was your segue. But let's, let's get get started because Jen, it
Speaker 4:  feels like we, we voted matter as like the thing of c e s.
Speaker 4:  This was, this was the big thing at ces. You, you made a very
Speaker 4:  passionate case for it. Now you have to do it again for all of our listeners.
Speaker 5:  I did not, it was not my suggestion. I just wanna point that out.
Speaker 5:  I, I held back, I mean not that I didn't agree, but you know, it was kind
Speaker 5:  of obvious coming from me. But the rest of the team actually was like, you
Speaker 5:  know, it was kind of the thing, we couldn't escape it.
Speaker 5:  Even Chris was like, the Samsung booth was terrible
Speaker 5:  because it was all smart home. So okay, weird. He said it was weird. Not
Speaker 5:  terrible, sorry.
Speaker 6:  It was different cuz you expect like every year you go there and it's like
Speaker 6:  TVs and gaming monitors and all this flashy stuff and hardware and this year
Speaker 6:  some of that stuff was there. But like on the whole, just like Jen saying
Speaker 6:  it was all matter stuff and smart things, this and that and it was just very
Speaker 6:  different.
Speaker 5:  It was very notable. I mean the last, so the first CS I went to,
Speaker 5:  I wanna say it was 2019 and I remember going to the Samsung booth which was
Speaker 5:  the, which was, you know the, the place that Chris loves
Speaker 5:  huge TVs. It was I think when they debuted the wall and in one
Speaker 5:  little corner I managed to find a smart things hub and a few sensors.
Speaker 5:  And then this year the entire booth was smart things
Speaker 5:  and you literally had to go find the TV that was hidden in a room somewhere.
Speaker 5:  I mean it was, it was notable and
Speaker 5:  that's not the case for everyone. But you know, the LGS booth still had the
Speaker 5:  giant walls of TVs and, but Samsung really went all
Speaker 5:  out with smart things and the smart home and in general, so
Speaker 5:  for people that aren't familiar, CES isn't two venues. So there's the
Speaker 5:  big Las Vegas convention center, which is where the Samsung and the LG booths
Speaker 5:  are. And then there's the Venetian Convention Center formerly called the
Speaker 5:  Sands, which is where the smart home had always been put and again
Speaker 5:  had sort of been in a corner in the conference room in the major sort of
Speaker 5:  conference space. And now again you walked in and it was the first thing
Speaker 5:  you saw and it took up half the show floor. It was, it was definitely Smart
Speaker 5:  Home's year and Matter obviously is a big topic in the smart home
Speaker 5:  right now. So Matter was everywhere. I mean literally I
Speaker 5:  took our video director to try and sort of shoot some footage cuz when we
Speaker 5:  announced that matter was the best in show, he said, what am I supposed to
Speaker 5:  shoot? It's not a tv.
Speaker 5:  What do I shoot? So we went around looking for the
Speaker 5:  logos and yes the, and they were everywhere. I think as I said in
Speaker 5:  my piece, it was like the easiest game of Wears Waldorf ever because
Speaker 5:  they were just matter logos just
Speaker 4:  Per everywhere.
Speaker 5:  Just perforating. Yes but, and you know, it's not like now matters
Speaker 5:  here, it's ready and we can all just run off and enjoy this great new smart
Speaker 5:  home. It's still early days but the sheer number of announcements,
Speaker 5:  the sheer number of new products, the real concrete details we,
Speaker 5:  we are getting about how this smart home protocol is gonna work in our homes
Speaker 5:  definitely made it feel like something much more tangible than it has been
Speaker 5:  for the last three years. So that was one of the reasons we kind of gave
Speaker 5:  it this big accolade.
Speaker 4:  Well kind of walk us through those, those details cuz honestly I was
Speaker 4:  surprised to see Samsung Smart things come back. I feel like it has a really
Speaker 4:  passionate, really small user base
Speaker 4:  and and now it seems like Samsung's like oh wait, we still have this, we
Speaker 4:  should do something with It matters here.
Speaker 5:  Yeah so from the smart things side, I mean the smart things you see
Speaker 5:  today is not really the smart things you are thinking of not the original
Speaker 5:  kind of groovy based smart things for the
Speaker 5:  tinkerers that's still there. And they're very keen to point out that you
Speaker 5:  know, they haven't got rid of that although they are transitioning. But what
Speaker 5:  smart things really is now today is Samsung's connectivity
Speaker 5:  platform for its home appliances and TVs. Okay. But they
Speaker 5:  have remained open. So it's always been the most
Speaker 5:  open of all the smart home platforms because it, it works with ZigBee and
Speaker 5:  Z-Wave and a whole host of cloud provided smart
Speaker 5:  home integrations too. So you know, you can use, I am I allowed to
Speaker 5:  say things like Alexa or people gonna get mad at me, but you can use the
Speaker 5:  Amazon Smart Home Assistant, the Google Smart Home assistant or with
Speaker 5:  smart things, it's very open, it's very interoperable and they're keeping
Speaker 5:  that and then Matter obviously is making it even more open.
Speaker 5:  So it means that now things will work with Apple Home as well as Samsung
Speaker 5:  Smart things. You know, and Apple obviously wasn't on the show floor but
Speaker 5:  it was a big part of what's make, you know, the push for matter.
Speaker 5:  They created matter along with all of the other companies we've mentioned
Speaker 5:  and as they like to say, they contributed the main framework of home kit
Speaker 5:  to the matter protocol. So it feels a lot like using Apple
Speaker 5:  Home Kit when you use Matter products which I've done managed to use a few
Speaker 5:  and it is, it does feel a lot like using Apple Home with a
Speaker 5:  sprinkle of smart things and a sprinkle of Amazon and a touch of Google.
Speaker 4:  So you they felt like Apple was still kind of there at the show even though
Speaker 4:  they weren't
Speaker 5:  Actually isn't that always the way?
Speaker 4:  But they don't have a booth, there's not like a special room where you go
Speaker 4:  and meet with Apple people unless you're doing like talking about monitors
Speaker 4:  that you wanna own.
Speaker 5:  No, yeah they're not there. There's no home kit presence but a lot of new
Speaker 5:  products that were announced were from companies that traditionally hadn't
Speaker 5:  worked with Apple Home and now because of Matter
Speaker 5:  are gonna be able to work in that ecosystem because Apple is fully
Speaker 5:  in on matter. So if your device works with Matter it will work
Speaker 5:  with Apple Home. And then there's the vice Versa Pro products that only worked
Speaker 5:  with Apple Home will now work outside of Apple Home like that
Speaker 5:  Eve, which we've who we've covered quite extensively. But for example like
Speaker 5:  Govie and Ye Light and GE Sync are
Speaker 5:  all brands that have light lighting cuz lighting's big and matter right now
Speaker 5:  cause it's one of the first device types supported, those companies
Speaker 5:  all announce products that will now support matter. That
Speaker 5:  means you can buy those inexpensive, which is not normally something that
Speaker 5:  you associate with Apple Home products. Those inexpensive devices
Speaker 5:  will now work with Apple Home if you want to use that as your main matter
Speaker 5:  interface. And you know, that's quite exciting for a lot of people that like
Speaker 5:  Apple Home because it has traditionally been an expensive smart home space
Speaker 5:  to play in. And you know, Amazon on the other hand you can use
Speaker 5:  its smart home assistant with many inexpensive
Speaker 5:  brands that you can find on Amazon of dubious quality in some
Speaker 5:  cases. But
Speaker 4:  Yeah, like I, I think I gave up on using Amazon as my smart home because
Speaker 4:  it just, I moved houses and it was like okay you need to
Speaker 4:  manually delete every single light and then manually
Speaker 4:  re-add every single light. And I had like 20 lights on there and I was like
Speaker 4:  no I'm just stop, I'm just done here.
Speaker 5:  They fix that, they have fixed that or about to fix that. Okay. That's quite
Speaker 5:  exciting. It's not really to do with matter. I'm I'm hoping it will
Speaker 5:  become an a thing with matter though because there could be a lot of duplicates
Speaker 5:  if you start using multiple smart home platforms that that could
Speaker 5:  be one of the problems but hopefully so what's kind of happening with Matter
Speaker 5:  is that each company is doing something new or bringing a new
Speaker 5:  sort of slant to it and we are kind of waiting to see whether
Speaker 5:  the other companies will all follow track because the whole point of matter
Speaker 5:  is that everyone should be able to be interoperable in the same way. So for
Speaker 5:  example, the Amazon feature is there now working with
Speaker 5:  device group sync. So if you have, if you
Speaker 5:  add a device to Amazon and you also, you know, it's say it's a hub
Speaker 5:  bulb rather than it being called Kitchen light in Hue and then
Speaker 5:  just light one in Amazon, which is for some reason the way it defaults
Speaker 5:  now it will sync the name across which is gonna be really useful cause you
Speaker 5:  know when you say hey a turn on the lights and it's like you have
Speaker 5:  500 devices named light, which one would you like to turn on?
Speaker 5:  This will help with that. And you know that kind of just keeping your smart
Speaker 5:  home a bit tidier cuz you're so right. You should see my Amazon Alexa app.
Speaker 5:  It's kind of scary how many devices I have in it and
Speaker 4:  I I think we're gonna save that one for the Halloween episode. Like we
Speaker 4:  can't show that right now. It's too sensitive, too scary.
Speaker 7:  I have a question. Yes.
Speaker 5:  And
Speaker 7:  As a smart home agnostic, I don't have any smart devices
Speaker 7:  in my home and I'm generally wary of
Speaker 7:  handing over my personal data to companies like this and
Speaker 7:  I have, you know, sort of like the the basic laundry list of concerns that
Speaker 7:  people have for not for not, you know, installing any of these devices
Speaker 7:  in your home. Did you get a sense from the show that the companies
Speaker 7:  that are building these, these products are getting better at bringing new
Speaker 7:  people in as consumers or they, do you feel like they're, they're preaching
Speaker 7:  to the choir and still continuing to send sell things to like the people
Speaker 7:  who are already like invested in turning their home into a smart home?
Speaker 5:  That's an excellent question and actually one that was definitely on everyone's
Speaker 5:  mind because it is the latter because Matter
Speaker 5:  isn't actually going to be that great initially for people
Speaker 5:  who are already invested in the smart home. It isn't as
Speaker 5:  functionally advanced so you won't be able to do things like adaptive lighting
Speaker 5:  so you know where you have your lights change color with in sync with the
Speaker 5:  sun or dynamic lighting effects like you know, your
Speaker 5:  hue lights will kind of flash with your tv. Those kind of things,
Speaker 5:  those features aren't available in matter so doesn't mean you won't be
Speaker 5:  able to use them, you'll just have to use the relevant company's app
Speaker 5:  to get to that function. So really what matter is designed
Speaker 5:  for is to be really simple for people who've never used the smart home
Speaker 5:  before. So that when you go to the, you go to Lowe's or you
Speaker 5:  shop on Amazon or Best Buy and you are like, well I need a new
Speaker 5:  thermostat and maybe I need some new light bulbs and you buy them and as
Speaker 5:  long as they work with matter then you can set them up with any smartphone,
Speaker 5:  any ecosystem, any smart speaker you have in your house. You don't have to
Speaker 5:  look for all the little works with badge to see whether it works with your
Speaker 5:  phone or works with your voice assistant. So that's really the sort of
Speaker 5:  core purpose of matter is to make it really simple so that everyone can use
Speaker 5:  it. Because right now the smart home is not simple, it's far from it,
Speaker 5:  which is why I have a job really
Speaker 7:  Well thank God for that. Then
Speaker 4:  It's like Jen HomeBridge hoops, these guys are like we we need,
Speaker 4:  we needed to be super complex for as long as
Speaker 5:  Possible. Yeah, I mean home and and Matter does work with those
Speaker 5:  platforms too. So you know, it's less exciting right now for people who
Speaker 5:  are already really deeply involved in the smart home. The most excited
Speaker 5:  group was probably the home kit users because they're getting access to
Speaker 5:  devices that they didn't have and they won't have to use devices, they won't
Speaker 5:  have to use hoops and HomeBridge to bring those devices into their
Speaker 5:  ecosystem. Like your Nest thermostat will work in home kit
Speaker 5:  natively. Now your new one though, not the old one, which is really annoying
Speaker 5:  cuz I want the learning thermostat in my home kit. But anyway
Speaker 5:  digress. Yes and that's where you hear a lot of complaints about matters.
Speaker 5:  People are like, oh it's really not that exciting, it doesn't really add
Speaker 5:  any new features, it's kind of boring. Well that's kind of the point.
Speaker 5:  It's plumbing. Yeah it's roads, yeah it's infrastructure. It's
Speaker 5:  just making everything work properly, which it hasn't done for a
Speaker 5:  long time.
Speaker 4:  Chris, you saw a bunch of TV stuff, were you seeing any like that ma was
Speaker 4:  matter trickling in there too for you?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think they said that all the lgs, I know support matter they did
Speaker 6:  last year too I believe. But this year that's there again and I think some
Speaker 6:  other companies are also on board but so yeah it's definitely kind of like
Speaker 6:  naturally making its way across all the big brands. I'm
Speaker 6:  not sure what that'll look like in TVs necessarily. Like some might have
Speaker 6:  hub apps and stuff like that but they will support it like at the core, which
Speaker 6:  is nice to see.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think Hiene just announced that it's supporting matter, it
Speaker 5:  just announced that it's CS and basically I think ultimately
Speaker 5:  TVs can be matter controllers so you wouldn't even necessarily need
Speaker 5:  a any kind of hub device separately. And that's another part
Speaker 5:  of matter is the idea being that these hub devices will already just be built
Speaker 5:  into what you own or buy. So you're not gonna have to buy extra little
Speaker 5:  Dons and what's its names to to make your smart home work.
Speaker 5:  And then Samsung actually announce that going forward it's gonna build
Speaker 5:  matter and thread directly into its products. So
Speaker 5:  all TVs monitors and their smart fridges will have
Speaker 5:  refrigerators and the fridges. Yes, yes. They'll all,
Speaker 5:  so they all currently have smart things software hubs in and then they will
Speaker 5:  also get a matter thread chip, ZigBee matter thread,
Speaker 5:  ZigBee chip, nosy wave.
Speaker 4:  How far do these upgrades go back cuz like I know I've got a
Speaker 4:  2017 LG that I'm trying to bully Eli to
Speaker 4:  also replacing his and we're stuck on the pre home
Speaker 4:  kit Premar home stuff right now. They're like no we don't have
Speaker 4:  support for airplay, we don't have support for Chromecast sex to be you
Speaker 4:  and we're probably not gonna get that support now, right? Like, like
Speaker 4:  these older products just aren't gonna get it. You're just gonna be sol.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no, yeah unfortunately there's, there was a lot of talk
Speaker 5:  about backward compatibility and for connected
Speaker 5:  devices, in some cases there will be bridging
Speaker 5:  opportunities. So like Phillips HU has a
Speaker 5:  matter bridge, oh sorry its bridge will be updated to support matter and
Speaker 5:  it's proudly said and rightly so, that it's original
Speaker 5:  Phillips hub bulb that you could have bought 10 years ago will support matter
Speaker 5:  through that bridge. So that's great but there's not a lot of,
Speaker 5:  you know, it's gonna be down to individual manufacturers to support that
Speaker 5:  to add matter to their bridges If they have devices that connect to the
Speaker 5:  bridge that can then connect to matter. But in general most of
Speaker 5:  the benefit of matter is gonna be going forward when you buy new devices,
Speaker 5:  you're gonna see an easier setup and easier connectivity and
Speaker 5:  easier interoperability. One good sign for
Speaker 5:  your old TVs though and old fridges and old washing machines
Speaker 5:  if they have any kind of wifi compatibility. So you
Speaker 5:  know, going back about 10 years, most appliances have some
Speaker 5:  compatibility with wifi. There is this, the new Home connectivity
Speaker 5:  alliance is working to do sort of a similar thing
Speaker 5:  to matter but cloud to cloud cause matter's local, which is something we
Speaker 5:  didn't mention right? But that's one of its sort of selling points and this
Speaker 5:  new alliance which is run by Samsung and includes
Speaker 5:  LG higher, which is like GE and it's like 80
Speaker 5:  to 90% of the home appliance industry, which is what like five companies
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Are all on board with this home connectivity alliance.
Speaker 5:  And they have said going any device that had wifi capability will
Speaker 5:  work with hca which means that you can control it through any
Speaker 5:  app that you like that is, so like if you have an LG think Q app
Speaker 5:  and a Samsung tv, you can control your Samsung TV through that
Speaker 5:  LG think Q app. So you could use, you could w have all your devices in
Speaker 5:  one app, all your home appliances.
Speaker 4:  So theoretically,
Speaker 5:  Theoretically. That's a good point.
Speaker 4:  Well like cuz I, I mean I definitely have that horrible
Speaker 4:  LG app and it is truly the worst. It's one of the worst apps on my
Speaker 4:  phone. I only use it like when I can't find the remote and I'm too
Speaker 4:  late and too tired at night to like look for it re reasonably
Speaker 4:  and even then I cry when I use it. But they don't care about those
Speaker 4:  apps, right? They, they haven't cared about those apps for years. They've
Speaker 4:  kind of just like they did 'em, they made 'em and they're like, all right,
Speaker 4:  it's here. Enjoy your slop. Do you think we'll start seeing other like third
Speaker 4:  parties making apps to be like, okay here's your app to control all
Speaker 4:  your 10 year old appliances.
Speaker 5:  So yes I think, we'll we may see that but with the HCA it has
Speaker 5:  to be one of their appliance companies. But where you will
Speaker 5:  be able to use it is smart things because that's Samsungs
Speaker 5:  so you'll be able to control all your old LG appliances with the smart things
Speaker 5:  app. So you're all in on Samsung now. You look
Speaker 5:  really thrilled about that
Speaker 4:  Idea whether you want it or not, you're all in on Samsung.
Speaker 4:  There
Speaker 5:  Is a chance though that the Home Connectivity Alliance and Matter
Speaker 5:  will get together at some point. I mean they are talking to each other
Speaker 5:  so it is and white good appliances and televisions are
Speaker 5:  in the matter spec, so you know there's gonna be some more
Speaker 5:  political shuffling going on. But I wouldn't be surprised if if eventually
Speaker 5:  they converge. I did hear the, the chairman of the H
Speaker 5:  C A joke that they were just waiting for matter to pay buy them for a billion
Speaker 5:  dollars. Which is kind of funny when C S A is a nonprofit
Speaker 5:  and Samsung runs the hta. So I'm not sure which should
Speaker 5:  buy which, but
Speaker 4:  Well okay, so it was a lot of matter. What was like the coolest
Speaker 4:  matter thing you saw the coolest implementation that had you really excited?
Speaker 5:  Ooh, there were a couple things I think most exciting
Speaker 5:  for me was probably the MOI board. And it's not
Speaker 5:  that it is necessarily a sort of whizbang technologically
Speaker 5:  exciting device, it's more of a sort of shows what matter could bring us,
Speaker 5:  which is because companies don't have to develop for all
Speaker 5:  different platforms now and they don't have to, startups don't have to spend,
Speaker 5:  you know, 90% of their budget with their engineers having to develop for
Speaker 5:  five different platforms. They can really focus on innovation that we might
Speaker 5:  start to see some more interesting devices in the smart home. And the
Speaker 5:  MOI board is, is a piece of wood with l e d lights behind it
Speaker 5:  that just is touch sensitive so you can, you know, you can
Speaker 5:  touch it to turn your lights on and off, you can draw on it. It's just a,
Speaker 5:  it's a very sort of delightful device. It doesn't feel like technology
Speaker 5:  And that's something if anyone's been following my coverage they'll see,
Speaker 5:  you know, I have a real, I don't like smart home tech that feels like technology.
Speaker 5:  I think it's important that your smart home tech needs to fit into your home
Speaker 5:  and you know, Google's been trying this with all their sort of fabricy mesh
Speaker 5:  things and there have been numerous sort
Speaker 5:  of shifts in the way smart home technology looks. So that doesn't sort of
Speaker 5:  stand out too much in your home. But that's what the MOI board does.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's not really a product. I mean they say you're gonna be able to
Speaker 5:  buy it, it's gonna be on Kickstarter. It's more of a kind of concept though,
Speaker 5:  you know, like this is what we can do. Yeah and that's what I'm excited about
Speaker 5:  with Matter that we'll see more of these things because now that you just
Speaker 5:  have to develop for one protocol, it's gonna be a lot easier for startups
Speaker 5:  and inventors to kind of come up with cool ideas for the smart home.
Speaker 5:  And you know, there's obviously there's some fun stuff like I actually think
Speaker 5:  some of the new hubs we're gonna get are kind of fun. Like Samsung
Speaker 5:  came out with the smart things hub, which was a shocker because they had
Speaker 5:  stopped making smart things hubs years ago, but it's it three
Speaker 5:  in four in one device, it's also a wireless charger. It's also a find
Speaker 5:  my or Samsung's thing finder, whatever their name is for find
Speaker 5:  my, so it has you know, multi-function and that's something we saw
Speaker 5:  a trend of. There were four or five new devices that were announced as
Speaker 5:  matter controllers.
Speaker 4:  It's because I can kind of haven't broken out of that mindset that hubs need
Speaker 4:  to happen. But now they're like, oh but hubs can't just be hubs.
Speaker 5:  Yes. So that, that's the thing. Hubs no longer are just going to be
Speaker 5:  hubs on their own. They're gonna be in your tv, they're gonna be in your
Speaker 5:  wifi router, they're gonna be in your wireless charger, they're gonna be
Speaker 5:  in your temperature sensor. Will
Speaker 4:  They be in your car?
Speaker 5:  I dunno. Andy what do you think?
Speaker 7:  They've been trying to stick smartphone operability in cars for
Speaker 7:  years now with like I would, I would argue less success
Speaker 7:  than they've had in the home. And it's all basically about right, like
Speaker 7:  controlling your car from your home but not vice versa. I don't, I
Speaker 7:  think, and I think maybe they're starting to pick up a little bit on doing
Speaker 7:  home stuff from your car, but there is a sense that like, oh you're in your
Speaker 7:  home, you, you've got a, you know, Tesla sitting out
Speaker 7:  in the driveway, maybe you should get the battery started on that car.
Speaker 7:  It'd be nice to be able to do it from your bedroom as opposed to, you know,
Speaker 7:  while you're sitting freezing your buns off in the car itself. But you're
Speaker 7:  dealing with all these companies that have all, you know, that everyone wants
Speaker 7:  to, you know, lock everyone in their various, you know, walled gardens
Speaker 7:  and I think that they haven't quite figured out how to move forward from
Speaker 7:  that.
Speaker 5:  Well that's what they need then matters all about. Yeah, breaking down the
Speaker 5:  walled gardens. So, and the csa, which is the Connectivity
Speaker 5:  Standards Alliance, who promotes and runs matter has said that they are
Speaker 5:  very much looking at bringing matter to other parts of the
Speaker 5:  connected world including cars. They need to get the home sorted out first
Speaker 5:  but hopefully they'll move in, you know, and that's the natural next step
Speaker 5:  would be automotive because there's so much connection between the home
Speaker 5:  and the car. And in particular because one of the things that matter
Speaker 5:  hopefully will really help Kickstart is home energy
Speaker 5:  management should make it a lot easier for
Speaker 5:  apps and infrastructure for energy to sort of
Speaker 5:  talk to each other and gain data to be able to understand
Speaker 5:  energy usage. And obviously cars and EVs are kind of key to that
Speaker 5:  when it comes to home energy management. So I could definitely see some
Speaker 5:  integration that's kind of gonna come along in that space to make it
Speaker 5:  easier from an energy standpoint. And then that could also make it easier
Speaker 5:  from a user sort of interface standpoint. I mean I actually did
Speaker 5:  see, I did a demo with Apple CarPlay in the Amazon
Speaker 5:  booth where I could talk to both Alexa and Siri at the
Speaker 5:  same time in one device.
Speaker 7:  Oh that must have been a fascinating conversation.
Speaker 5:  It was, it was very cute because it was the way Amazon was going, look, you
Speaker 5:  would ask Siri for these things and then you these things you would ask
Speaker 5:  Amazon for. I'm like, but I could ask Siri for all those things too, you
Speaker 5:  know, I don't really need, I don't really need Alexa but, but
Speaker 5:  their point was if I like to use Siri and all
Speaker 5:  and my husband likes to use the Amazon assistant, you know
Speaker 5:  you can do it all in one device but you could go back and I said, but can
Speaker 5:  I, can I talk to 'em both at the same time? Cuz you know, that sounds like
Speaker 5:  fun. And they're like, yeah. Oh wow. So that was, that was kind of
Speaker 5:  interesting.
Speaker 4:  Chris, how angry do you think Sonos is that
Speaker 4:  these car companies and stuff are getting to like good question, proper voice
Speaker 4:  integration when Sonos is like struggled with it for five years?
Speaker 6:  I think they're mostly, mostly happy with being in the home. They've had
Speaker 6:  some card partnerships, I think they did one last year pretty recently. So
Speaker 6:  I think it's more of like a hey we're here and just have like some, some
Speaker 6:  kind of Sonos branding in the car. But I think on the home on the whole they're
Speaker 6:  very happy to just, you know, focus on your home home theater and
Speaker 6:  maybe headphones down the line and who knows what else. But I think cars
Speaker 6:  are like a secondary thing for them
Speaker 4:  That's way back in the back. They're like it's in the rear view mirror for
Speaker 4:  them. I'm so sorry NEI somewhere groaning
Speaker 4:  like Sonos isn't part of matter, right? Like they, they because it
Speaker 4:  doesn't have the, the audio integration yet.
Speaker 5:  So they are member of the CSA if I
Speaker 5:  remember correctly. But from the conversations that we had
Speaker 5:  in Amsterdam, which is where they had a matter kickoff event last year,
Speaker 5:  they're sort of just there for the view at the moment.
Speaker 5:  You know, just kinda looking around seeing what's going on. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And that's true of a lot of the sort of speaker manufacturers
Speaker 5:  outside of the smart speaker, voice assistant
Speaker 5:  manufacturers. Because for them, especially for Sonos who
Speaker 5:  already has their sort of home audio sys
Speaker 5:  multi-room audio pretty nailed down there isn't really a much benefit that
Speaker 5:  they can see at the moment. Right now speakers are not part of
Speaker 5:  any matter spec. So I know one of the questions people kept asking me was,
Speaker 5:  oh now can I add my Google Nest hub to my Apple home kit? And you know that
Speaker 5:  that that stuff isn't gonna work yet. But I think in the
Speaker 5:  future they are trying to move that way. I think there's resistance though
Speaker 5:  from, because the way the way matter works is they create tiger
Speaker 5:  teams. Wow. Where they get all the people from
Speaker 5:  each group together who are, you know, so like Sonos
Speaker 5:  and Bows and name me some speaker companies, Chris
Speaker 4:  JL J
Speaker 5:  Sure. We'll get together in a room and talk about how they want matter
Speaker 5:  to work with their speakers and then they go to the
Speaker 5:  CSA and they don't, right. And that's saying they don't do that. So that
Speaker 5:  hasn't happened yet from what I've heard. So it, it would need some consumer
Speaker 5:  pressure I think to move it along.
Speaker 4:  All right, well we're gonna take a break and when we're back, Chris is gonna
Speaker 4:  tell us all about the TVs that truly sucked at C
Speaker 4:  ces. I'm so sorry. I will not stop,
Speaker 4:  stay tuned. We'll be back.
Speaker 4:  And we're back Chris. I know this was like, this was such a big c s show.
Speaker 4:  Jen was having an awesome time seeing everything and TVs were kind
Speaker 4:  of like a little quiet this year. There weren't, were, there wasn't as much
Speaker 4:  big stuff happening in that space.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it was pretty low key. I think we finally got over that hump of, of
Speaker 6:  like two years ago where like some of like all these HDM I 2.1 features like
Speaker 6:  4K and one 20 VR R, those are finally fairly widespread across
Speaker 6:  all TVs right now. So if you spend like 700 or $800
Speaker 6:  on a tv, you're gonna have those features Now that really wasn't the case
Speaker 6:  necessarily two years ago or even last year in some cases. So I think that's
Speaker 6:  finally settled and this year we saw like a focus on brightness,
Speaker 6:  especially with O lid. Those are getting brighter and trying to close the
Speaker 6:  gap with many LEDs. So both Samsung and LG said
Speaker 6:  they have the brightest oles yet they've ever made. So they're trying to
Speaker 6:  close that gap with mini LEDs from TCL and HS and, and just get the best
Speaker 6:  of both worlds. But on the whole it was like software they're saying oh we
Speaker 6:  can, you know, pick out the subject in scenes now and give them more depth
Speaker 6:  and make them feel more lifelike. There were quite a few Trix
Speaker 6:  using ai. What
Speaker 4:  Does that mean?
Speaker 6:  Right? Yeah. Just making
Speaker 6:  things feel more life flight.
Speaker 4:  That's one of those things I always hear. I don't know, I, I come
Speaker 4:  from the, I want it to be exactly what the director
Speaker 4:  intended, even though I don't have a 30,000 reference monitor, right.
Speaker 6:  And I always say, well you can turn all these AI features off if you want,
Speaker 4:  But why put 'em in there and to begin with Jen Andy, do you guys use the
Speaker 4:  AI features on your tv? Oh
Speaker 7:  Hell no.
Speaker 5:  I dunno if mine has, I
Speaker 7:  Don't know if, yeah, I don't know if mine does. Honestly either. I I assumed
Speaker 7:  you were talking about motion smoothing, right? That's what we're talking
Speaker 7:  about. No, I'm kidding.
Speaker 4:  No, but motion smooth. Like I just, I like Chris, why do
Speaker 4:  they keep putting all of these crappy things that we don't actually want
Speaker 4:  on our TVs onto our TVs? And then you always get at least one
Speaker 4:  person who's like, well actually I like the motion smoothing. It makes the
Speaker 4:  ball look fast and like that person's dumb.
Speaker 6:  There are sickos out there who love motion smoothing, but I think,
Speaker 6:  but I think all TVs are really pretty good now. So like manufacturers are
Speaker 6:  trying to come up with ways to like differentiate and like get you to upgrade
Speaker 6:  after five or six years or however long people keep TVs
Speaker 6:  nowadays. So it's all software, software, software and like very gradual
Speaker 6:  picture refinements too. So that was the case this year. But it was nice,
Speaker 6:  we saw a lot of very nice TVs and quite a few
Speaker 6:  gimmicky TVs as well.
Speaker 4:  We should talk about the gimmicky TV because this was one of my
Speaker 4:  favorite things to come outta ces and I think the worst part was,
Speaker 4:  I was reading your story earlier and I was like, wait, I, I almost wanna
Speaker 4:  buy this tv. Can you, well what was it called? It was called like it, it
Speaker 4:  used to vacuum but I cannot remember the name of the TV now.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's a startup called Displace. I think this was their first time at
Speaker 6:  cs. I haven't seen them before. Okay. But I saw like earlier in the show
Speaker 6:  there were some tweets about it and I was like oh this is gonna be the thing
Speaker 6:  that everybody kind of like, oh it gets excited about,
Speaker 6:  it's some kind of silly gimmick. So it costs $3,000. It's a
Speaker 6:  55 inch 4K olet TV that is totally wireless.
Speaker 6:  And so there are four batteries that you can hot swap around and
Speaker 6:  charge and keep it running at all times. There's a base station where you
Speaker 6:  plug in all your stuff, same sort of thing as the LG wireless thing that
Speaker 6:  we talked about a few last week and, but this one is totally wireless. Even
Speaker 6:  the power is handled by batteries and it lasts. So if you watch TV
Speaker 6:  for six hours a day, then it'll last a month and you can watch for seven
Speaker 6:  point, 7.5 days straight through. And I've seen like already on Twitter,
Speaker 6:  people are like, those batteries are nowhere near big enough to like have
Speaker 6:  that kind of a charge.
Speaker 4:  But there's a key thing about the batteries. Yeah cuz it sucks.
Speaker 4:  It sucks itself on yeah, to the wall, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So there's a vacuum suction system. So you hold the TV against the
Speaker 6:  wall and after a few seconds it like wears up, you can hear it and then it
Speaker 6:  just kinda like sticks to the wall and you just kind of back away and it's
Speaker 6:  on there and you can like pull at it and tug pretty hard and it stays on
Speaker 6:  there. But that is also battery powered. So in the event that all the batteries
Speaker 6:  run out, your $3,000 TV will just fall to the floor.
Speaker 4:  That's,
Speaker 6:  That's where we're at with the CES gimmicks.
Speaker 5:  I'm all for the wireless stuff though ultimately, you know, I don't think,
Speaker 5:  we'll one day we'll have no wires on our own whatsoever. Right. Anyway. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You know our lighting doesn't need wires, you know, things just don't need
Speaker 5:  wires. We have wireless power. I mean that's something we saw the wireless
Speaker 5:  power, which I know has been around, they've been promising for years but
Speaker 5:  it seems like it's getting closer.
Speaker 4:  The they'll get there one day,
Speaker 6:  Right? Yeah. Patience. Patience. Y'all just don't force the hand. You know,
Speaker 6:  you've got both LG and this company doing it this year and it's like, you
Speaker 6:  know, WiFi's not there yet.
Speaker 4:  Do you think like next year displace in partnership with the guys
Speaker 4:  who who've been doing the wireless power for years trying to
Speaker 4:  keep that TV up on the wall but just did they
Speaker 4:  explain what they expected to happen if the batteries ran out? Like
Speaker 4:  were they, were they like, oh no, people will always remove their TV with
Speaker 4:  not in use and put it in the closet.
Speaker 6:  I mean they're hot swappable so I guess the idea is you'll always be like
Speaker 6:  popping one or two in at a time and switching them out and who wants to maintain
Speaker 6:  that schedule? You know, that's
Speaker 4:  So much work.
Speaker 6:  It's like having to remember that and there's like a base station that charges
Speaker 6:  all the batteries but it's just like more and more anxiety that like isn't
Speaker 6:  even there right now. Who wants like, you know like battery charge status
Speaker 6:  for your tv,
Speaker 5:  It's like range anxiety for your ev
Speaker 6:  Right? That's the same exact thing. But for TVs now, suction anxiety.
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  We have to pause a minute for that one.
Speaker 7:  I'm so worried that my TV isn't sucking well enough.
Speaker 4:  How do you go to bed at night? Like, oh no I can't. Like we just,
Speaker 4:  I would wake up every, every 30 minutes being like, is my TV still on my
Speaker 4:  wall? I could just take
Speaker 6:  It off the wall. Honey, did you take it down? I didn't take it down.
Speaker 7:  Maybe we just need to position like a bunch of pillows under the TVs
Speaker 7:  so that it can fall gracefully some sort of
Speaker 4:  Net. I was just thinking of like the person who has this and then also has
Speaker 4:  all the IKEA blinds and then they just have another room for all of the battery
Speaker 4:  packs. They have to keep constantly charged. So they're, they're super smart
Speaker 4:  of the future home works.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so it's kind of silly. I think they know it's a concept thing. They're
Speaker 6:  only gonna sell a hundred of them so they're not saying oh this is gonna
Speaker 6:  be like a mainstream tv but, but it got a lot of buzz on the show floor and
Speaker 6:  was very c e s
Speaker 4:  That TV without the suction. That's like a thousand dollars tv
Speaker 4:  right?
Speaker 6:  Right. Yeah it's just your standard like LG display ole panel. Probably not
Speaker 6:  even 55 inch, $700 or so. So
Speaker 4:  Can you vacuum with it?
Speaker 6:  It doesn't have the vacuums.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Well it's even it's sucking like I, I don't, I just don't know if you
Speaker 4:  can suck other things. So we saw, you saw that TV
Speaker 4:  moving on, we saw that TV but you also saw
Speaker 4:  like a lot of, I feel like we saw a lot of like light stuff happening behind
Speaker 4:  the TVs. I know we talked about Gove earlier but there was a couple of other
Speaker 4:  people doing that that Phillips hu what if we have lights behind the
Speaker 4:  TVs?
Speaker 5:  That's a big theme this year. I think there were like six
Speaker 5:  maybe announcements around tv, audio
Speaker 5:  gaming syncing. So yeah the Gove sink box.
Speaker 5:  Nano Leaf had one which used a camera and then there was
Speaker 5:  one from Twinkly which is an Italian company and
Speaker 5:  that was, that's an app based one which is similar to the
Speaker 5:  Phillips Hue app based one but the Twinkles costs
Speaker 5:  $0 whereas Phillips Hughes costs $130
Speaker 5:  but you know they only work with their own light systems. So there's
Speaker 5:  Phillips Hu has a lot more options when it comes to immersive
Speaker 5:  lighting. And then I think there were a couple others and there are some
Speaker 5:  that already exist. So now it seems like everyone thinks that everyone
Speaker 5:  really wants flashing lights when they're watching tv. Chris, I dunno,
Speaker 5:  what do you think?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, this whole market is so fascinating to me.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean I've done it once and I liked, like I tested one box and it
Speaker 5:  was kind of fun for some movies but I probably only turned it
Speaker 5:  on once or twice after you know, doing the testing cuz you know, you don't
Speaker 5:  wanna watch the nightly news and see like black and red sort of
Speaker 5:  flashing in the background as it, it it's, it's really quite
Speaker 5:  specific for certain entertainment. And then obviously gamers. I think gamers
Speaker 5:  are really the the market. No, yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah for sure. I mean I don't really know anybody who like has these lights
Speaker 6:  in their
Speaker 4:  Home. Oh I definitely do.
Speaker 6:  Certain people definitely do. Like there are, yeah like I know a to of people
Speaker 6:  who don't. So
Speaker 4:  One out of four super nerds on this call has it,
Speaker 4:  that is a small percentage of the wider population.
Speaker 5:  The problem I have though is you can't sync it. Like I have a framed TV
Speaker 5:  so it doesn't really go with the whole lifestyle TV
Speaker 5:  trend. There's definitely two diverging things here. So we got
Speaker 5:  the frame because I love the idea of it not looking like a TV but
Speaker 5:  then I can't fit my lights l e d light strips behind it cuz it's on the
Speaker 5:  wall and it's like this thin. Yeah. So yeah, I mean you can do it with other
Speaker 5:  lights but it seems more suited to gaming monitors honestly than
Speaker 5:  to, than to TVs. I know Thomas Ricker tested it out,
Speaker 5:  tested out the gov one and he really liked that. The older gov one. Now this
Speaker 5:  is a new version I think, but it's definitely a trend syncing with
Speaker 5:  your content and audio. It's not just so it's
Speaker 5:  visual and audio and the, the key difference here between say like
Speaker 5:  what you can do with Phillips Hue music sync in the
Speaker 5:  app and doing this on the TV for all of these products is that it
Speaker 5:  uses software to go across multiple lights.
Speaker 5:  So like you can buy a light strip with a microphone and just sync that light
Speaker 5:  strip to the beat if you want one little light strip. But this way
Speaker 5:  you can go across the entire ecosystem so you could have your
Speaker 5:  whole house flashing in the beat with the beat, which I might have to do
Speaker 5:  for Halloween next year. That would be fun. It's,
Speaker 4:  It's the worst thing in the world. I've done it and then it's just like
Speaker 4:  I just realized I'm too old. I was like if, if I was like
Speaker 4:  set, if I was like 18, 19 in a dorm room, it
Speaker 4:  is the coolest thing in the world. I feel like so awesome.
Speaker 4:  But I am about to hit 40. I am so like no
Speaker 4:  I want my house to look like a house, not the inside
Speaker 4:  of my computer.
Speaker 5:  Right. Not a disco party. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But this, I was gonna, going back to like this was how Phillips
Speaker 4:  Hughes started, right? Like it was originally they had, they had these lights
Speaker 4:  on the back of Phillips TVs like 10, 15 years ago and they
Speaker 4:  realized there was no market for it and nobody bought them and they got
Speaker 4:  like, or a few people, you know, a quarter of the nerdiest of the
Speaker 4:  nerds bought it and and nobody else and then it went away. And
Speaker 4:  so I'm like is it coming back just because it's easier just because more
Speaker 4:  companies have figured out the secret sauce that that Phillips had all those
Speaker 4:  years ago. Like why is it back again?
Speaker 6:  I think the less you need hubs and like all these accessories like that makes
Speaker 6:  it more enticing. Like if you don't have to like hook up, hook up like 10
Speaker 6:  things to make it work up and sync up. It's like the easier it gets, the
Speaker 6:  more tempting it is for everybody. I think
Speaker 4:  That's fair. That's fair. You can actually, you don't have to put your camera
Speaker 4:  like pacing at your TV all the time if you give 'em just natively out of
Speaker 4:  the back of the tv. Well what kind of, so you saw, I know some of the other
Speaker 4:  things you were kind of excited about the CES was we, we saw
Speaker 4:  Roku announced their own TV sets, which I was less enthusiastic but you
Speaker 4:  seemed pretty enthusiastic about so I'm willing to fight with you on the
Speaker 4:  Verge cast now if you want Chris.
Speaker 5:  I didn't even bother going and looking at their smart home stuff. They had
Speaker 5:  all their smart home stuff out there. I was like cat. Aw. So I'll fight
Speaker 5:  with you Alex.
Speaker 4:  Thank you. We're here to gang up on Chris. Andy you have to, you have to
Speaker 4:  side with Chris. Okay that's fine with me.
Speaker 6:  So I think that's a not so much a case about like the actual TVs themselves,
Speaker 6:  they're gonna be fine decent TVs but like more so Roku making
Speaker 6:  its own TVs quote unquote. Like we don't know who's making these, we
Speaker 6:  thought it might be T still or license and apparently it's not. So it could
Speaker 6:  be like a Foxcon situation or who knows. But the fact that they're like coming
Speaker 6:  in now, like apparently it wasn't enough to sell, they said like one out
Speaker 6:  of every three TV sold in the US as is runs Roku software
Speaker 6:  and so now they wanna like come in with their own TVs on top of all of that
Speaker 6:  and they're gonna be priced like super aggressively and yeah it's gonna be
Speaker 6:  pretty fascinating to see like just like what happens throughout the industry
Speaker 6:  cuz like what are TCL and he's gonna do now? Like are they gonna still make
Speaker 6:  Roku TVs like very similar price points or like will they go all in
Speaker 6:  Google TV now because Google making its own TV seems
Speaker 6:  pretty unlikely but I don't wanna speak too soon. Who knows?
Speaker 4:  Like Apple making their own car, right? Because like Roku, the reason that
Speaker 4:  we know who TCL and Heiss are, the reason they've come as close as they have
Speaker 4:  been to being like name brands that we all recognize in our homes is because
Speaker 4:  of Roku, right? Like these were two smaller Chinese TV manufacturers that
Speaker 4:  nobody had heard of and they were like, okay, our first inroads are gonna
Speaker 4:  be on Roku. Is there like, were you seeing like friction there
Speaker 4:  between these companies now that Roku's like we're doing it on our own.
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 6:  A bit too early to say I think. But like all the TVs that were announced
Speaker 6:  by tcl, this cs, those are only Google TVs and also Hyen
Speaker 6:  the same thing. So all they showed off were Google TVs now they come in waves,
Speaker 6:  like sometimes T-Cell will do like a phase of like Google TVs and then
Speaker 6:  come spring they'll do Roku. So it's like too early to say like what the
Speaker 6:  ripple effect's gonna be. They know obviously that Roku's coming into like
Speaker 6:  their, their space and yeah we'll see like how good the TVs are and very
Speaker 6:  curious about, cause like T-Cell and license make very phenomenal
Speaker 6:  TVs for like $800, a thousand dollars. So I'm not sure that Roku
Speaker 6:  can really like top them just coming right out of the gate. But we'll see
Speaker 6:  what they can manage. And I think like, I'm not sure how it's gonna matter.
Speaker 6:  Jesus, I'm not sure how much it's gonna matter if
Speaker 6:  they don't actually like beat TCL license, like based on, you know,
Speaker 6:  just like sheer picture quality. Cause they're gonna be in like every Walmart
Speaker 6:  and Target and be priced super aggressively. So I think they'll make a dent.
Speaker 4:  That was like a big part of their selling point with those original TVs,
Speaker 4:  right? Like they were like, right, okay, you don't know who TCL is, you don't
Speaker 4:  know who heis is, but we, you know, Roku and we worked with them to make
Speaker 4:  sure the picture quality is good. So it's kinda like they're doing that again,
Speaker 4:  but they're like, but we don't wanna even partner with these brands. We just
Speaker 4:  want our name on it. Don't care about who it is.
Speaker 6:  Right, yeah. So they're gonna be out this spring, they're come in like a
Speaker 6:  ton of sizes. They start very cheap. I think even like the 75 inch model
Speaker 6:  is like well under a thousand dollars, so Oh wow. Yeah, so
Speaker 6:  they're, they're coming full of force.
Speaker 4:  Are you gonna be just surrounded by TVs when I get to the office
Speaker 4:  softly weeping under your Roku pile?
Speaker 6:  That is very likely come April. It's always that time of year where they
Speaker 6:  start, they start coming in, so, so we shall see how
Speaker 6:  they end up. But yeah, plus like Roku now they can like have the full stack.
Speaker 6:  They can like do all this advertising stuff. They already do a ton of advertising
Speaker 6:  that's like huge part of their business and now they have the full stack
Speaker 6:  of hardware and software and so that just gives them even more power
Speaker 6:  and control.
Speaker 4:  Was there anything besides Roku that really just got you excited
Speaker 4:  as far as TVs go, despite it being kind of a all right
Speaker 4:  year for TVs?
Speaker 6:  Probably the Samsung cutie oli. I think it's kind of super fascinating how
Speaker 6:  like within two years Samsung display has kind of come into the oli market
Speaker 6:  and like beaten LG display at it. The cutie oles.
Speaker 4:  Really?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so like it's more vivid color and the color brightness is
Speaker 6:  better. So like it gets brighter and it looks better than LGS do. Samsung
Speaker 6:  TV still don't do Adobe vision, which is like their one like major
Speaker 6:  come on already, let's, let's just do this. I mean you have, they've got
Speaker 6:  atmos but no vision. So it's like they're just saving that for one
Speaker 6:  year where there's nothing else to announce. And they're like, okay, now
Speaker 6:  we have double vision as well. They like, so they said the, the cutie can
Speaker 6:  reach up to 2000 knits of brightness, which is like right up there with the
Speaker 6:  very brightest mini LEDs. And like granted that's just like one small part
Speaker 6:  of the screen that's gonna hit 2000 knits, but that's like way better than
Speaker 6:  than where things were even like two or three years ago. So then like a very
Speaker 6:  short time period. Yeah, these oles have gotten very, very good. So
Speaker 6:  that's the TV I'm probably most excited about.
Speaker 4:  So for years now, it's always been like, if somebody says I wanna buy a TV
Speaker 4:  and I don't want it to be like a TCL or a high sense, I wanna spend some
Speaker 4:  money, you just say go get an LG oled. Are you, are you now saying
Speaker 4:  maybe go look at those Samsungs?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, the Samsung was great last year too. That was their first model last
Speaker 6:  year. It was the S 95 B and then Sony had their like top, top, top one that
Speaker 6:  used the same panel as Samsung. But Sony has better processing and like better
Speaker 6:  sound and speakers and stuff like that. So if you want like the absolute
Speaker 6:  best tv, Sony's usually the way to go. We didn't see them at CS this year,
Speaker 6:  they didn't do TVs. They had a car, which we'll cover shortly, but
Speaker 6:  they kind of, they kind of punted their TVs to later on.
Speaker 6:  So we'll see what's coming from them pretty soon.
Speaker 4:  All right, well speaking of, we are gonna zoom to another break
Speaker 4:  and then when we're back, we're gonna talk with Alex.
Speaker 4:  When is enough we're gonna talk with the handy about cars.
Speaker 7:  Just don't say start your engines,
Speaker 4:  Start your, no name it. No, you can't do it now. You
Speaker 4:  ruin it
Speaker 5:  All time for a pit stop. Yes.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna take a pit stop and when we're back we're gonna talk about cars.
Speaker 4:  See you soon.
Speaker 4:  And we're back. Andy.
Speaker 7:  Hello.
Speaker 4:  How's the drive? How are the cars?
Speaker 7:  I thought this year was surprisingly great for cars,
Speaker 4:  Even though we had the big goofy concepts.
Speaker 7:  Even that even cuz who doesn't love a big goofy concept? I mean everyone
Speaker 7:  loves true, you know, a a bunch of like, you know, a
Speaker 7:  pastiche of like ridiculous ideas meshed together
Speaker 7:  in the shape of a car. That's, that's, that's what's fun about CES is just
Speaker 7:  looking at goofy concepts and, and imagining, you know, what is
Speaker 7:  possibly something that could end up in the, in, in an actual future production
Speaker 7:  vehicle. And I think this year was, was was a good year in terms of that.
Speaker 7:  And we also got some, some actual cars and real life cars that we'll see
Speaker 7:  in real life in the future alongside the, the color changing cars
Speaker 7:  and the, the weirder stuff. So for, for that reason, I thought it
Speaker 7:  was a good balance between like actual legitimate, like this is
Speaker 7:  gonna be something that you could potentially end up buying in the future.
Speaker 7:  And also just like here's a little bit of a, you know, a whimsical
Speaker 7:  bit of imagination for, for, for you to take with you.
Speaker 7:  How about a color changing car? That, that would be great, right?
Speaker 5:  Are you saying we're not gonna get a color changing car? Cuz that's what
Speaker 5:  I want. I love that idea.
Speaker 7:  I don't wanna rain on anyone's parade, but it seems very unlikely
Speaker 7:  that you can actually have a production car that's covered in e ink.
Speaker 7:  It just seems, I know you Alex you tell me as soon as there's a hail storm,
Speaker 7:  like what's gonna happen to that car?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, your car will look so sick and so
Speaker 4:  busted.
Speaker 4:  Like, no, no, no. This is the aesthetic.
Speaker 7:  If that's what people want, if they're willing to take that risk in order
Speaker 7:  to have a car that, that has 32 different color options as
Speaker 7:  the BMW I vision d purports to have, then
Speaker 7:  yeah, why not? Who knows?
Speaker 5:  I loved it felt very back to the future like though, right? Didn't they change
Speaker 5:  car colors in that or in some like sci-fi movies? I love concepts like
Speaker 5:  this that feel like we could actually get something we've seen in the movies.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it felt very like old school ces. Like I was like, oh yeah,
Speaker 7:  people remembered what this show is truly about and it's about
Speaker 7:  presenting a ridiculous concepts that probably
Speaker 7:  don't have much chance of ever being a reality, but
Speaker 7:  are still super fun to look at and think about and talk about
Speaker 7:  and share videos about. And you know, it makes us feel
Speaker 7:  good and warm and fuzzy about the future.
Speaker 4:  Well, we talked a bunch last week about the a,
Speaker 7:  The aph,
Speaker 4:  The A, but what were the cars that, like what were the
Speaker 4:  concepts that you were actually excited about? Was it the
Speaker 4:  Aila?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I, I I think legitimately the, the appeal is a ver is an interesting
Speaker 7:  concept because, well, first of all you've got Sony who has not previously
Speaker 7:  ever made a car deciding suddenly that they are going to make
Speaker 7:  a car with Honda, which is a company that has a ton of experience
Speaker 7:  making cars and it seems kind of like a natural pairing between the two of
Speaker 7:  them to work together on a, on a production vehicle. So that's
Speaker 7:  exciting. This is a, a new brand, a new name. It's ridiculous sounding. But
Speaker 7:  then again, you know, all car companies tend to be named after like
Speaker 7:  white dudes. So why not just have like a completely name made up name
Speaker 7:  to name a car company after too. Like it's that it's not too
Speaker 7:  outlandish to think that we're just like making names up. I mean that's,
Speaker 7:  that is what branding is all about, is just inventing a, a new word by
Speaker 7:  sticking a vowel at the, the, the front and end of the word feel.
Speaker 7:  Sure, why not? So I think that that's exciting. I think Sony
Speaker 7:  has a lot to offer the car space, especially when it comes to
Speaker 7:  things like computers, electronics, entertainment, sound system,
Speaker 7:  enter, you know, all infotainment, all of the things that
Speaker 7:  CS is typically about, you know, sort of like the future of the in-car
Speaker 7:  experience in a lot of ways. And I think Sony has a lot to bring to that
Speaker 7:  conversation, which I think is really interesting. And, and they've, they've
Speaker 7:  said a production schedule for themselves. They say in three years we'll
Speaker 7:  have this car, it's gonna be available, you'll be able to drive it, you'll
Speaker 7:  be able to buy it.
Speaker 4:  But is that real?
Speaker 7:  I mean, like maybe it's, it is like, you know, it's, they're not just
Speaker 7:  like some flyby night company that can like, make up deadlines for themselves
Speaker 7:  too. I mean,
Speaker 4:  They're not displaced.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, yeah. And Sony's a gigantic, you know, global
Speaker 7:  conglomerate that has shareholders and expectations and like, you know,
Speaker 7:  and they're, and they're not run by a guy named Elon Musk. So they're, you
Speaker 7:  know, they potentially have like a little bit more of, I think a little bit
Speaker 7:  of credibility I think when it comes to saying the stuff. I mean like, Chris,
Speaker 7:  you tell me you, you know, when Sodi Sodi obviously didn't have any TVs this
Speaker 7:  year, but when they come out and say that, that we're gonna do something,
Speaker 7:  they tend to follow up on that for the most part, right? Yeah. And you know,
Speaker 7:  the PS five is now app apparently like readily available to anyone who wants
Speaker 7:  to buy it. So it stands to reason that they'll have a car eventually
Speaker 7:  too. So I think that that's kind of exciting, you know, like a, a brand
Speaker 7:  new brand a a new company that has not previously been in the space. Now
Speaker 7:  there's a lot of, I think, challenges along the way. I think we've, we've
Speaker 7:  seen companies come out that are non-car companies that say that
Speaker 7:  they wanna make cars and it has not worked out so great for them. I mean,
Speaker 7:  Dyson is like the one that sort of springs to mind immediately when they
Speaker 7:  said that they were gonna make an electric car and everyone's like, oh sure,
Speaker 7:  yeah, you, you made a, a really cool vacuum. Why, why wouldn't you be able
Speaker 7:  to make a car? And so just because you make an amazing
Speaker 7:  TV or a a console or something like that does not necessarily
Speaker 7:  translate into the, the business of making a cool car. But again, Honda,
Speaker 7:  you know, Honda does make cars so
Speaker 5:  Well because they're working with a actual car company, it makes it like
Speaker 5:  80% more likely to happen. Right? I agree. Well, yeah, it
Speaker 5:  gives it, it gives it some cache
Speaker 7:  And Honda's not gonna like, you know, stake its name on a project that I
Speaker 7:  think ends up flopping, you know, with like you know necessarily
Speaker 7:  as well. I think that they have a stake in this to make sure that it happens.
Speaker 7:  And Honda is a company that's also working with one of the biggest
Speaker 7:  car companies in the world, GM on electric car technology.
Speaker 7:  So there's like a lot of through lines here that could be really interesting
Speaker 7:  I think, depending on how this exactly shakes out. So I
Speaker 7:  think that that's exciting.
Speaker 4:  Could it also just end up being like that very first iTunes phone,
Speaker 4:  it's like Sony Erickson or something, which just like, and we had iTunes
Speaker 4:  on it. Bam. Oh
Speaker 7:  Yes, the rocker. I don't know, I I, I think like if you went up to somebody
Speaker 7:  and it was like a PS five, but you can drive it, like that's
Speaker 7:  like, people would be very excited for something like that.
Speaker 7:  So I think that there, you know, there's maybe like a little bit
Speaker 7:  more like kind of like as a foundation potentially.
Speaker 7:  But then again the car itself was a little silly looking. It
Speaker 7:  was not like the most, like design-wise, it was not the most like arresting
Speaker 7:  vehicle that I had ever seen. It looked like, yeah, a mashup of like a portion
Speaker 7:  nine 11 and a lucid air. So it was not, they were not breaking new ground
Speaker 7:  design-wise, but at the same time, maybe that's good. Maybe
Speaker 7:  like, you know, they're sitting their sights, you know, somewhere more realistic.
Speaker 7:  They're not trying to reinvent the wheel necessarily. And
Speaker 7:  I think it's, it's there, there's a strong possibility that, and,
Speaker 7:  and if I turned out to be wrong, then you can bring this podcast
Speaker 7:  back and shove it in my face and show me how stupid I sound.
Speaker 4:  We're just gonna play clips of it. If you're wrong
Speaker 7:  To humiliate me, I would welcome that.
Speaker 4:  Well, what other concepts did you see that you were like kind of
Speaker 4:  excited about? Or it doesn't have to be concepts, it can also be real cars
Speaker 4:  that we know will actually exist next
Speaker 7:  Year. Yeah, so like Volkswagen came with a real car. They have a, the ID
Speaker 7:  seven which is a, a family sized sedan and their next global
Speaker 7:  EV after the ID four, which has been on sale for a number of years. And
Speaker 7:  I think it's kind of cool that it's a sedan. I mean that's not something
Speaker 7:  that most car makers are proposing these days, especially American
Speaker 7:  car makers. And we saw that with Ram at the, at the show they had their
Speaker 7:  Ram 1500 revolution, which was a big ass truck.
Speaker 7:  And that makes sense because Americans love their big ass trucks, but here
Speaker 7:  comes the, the Germans and they're like, oh, but what about the sedan? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And I think that that's kind of cool because I think like they can't
Speaker 7:  all be giant humongous trucks
Speaker 7:  with Yeah, batteries as heavy as a Honda Accord
Speaker 7:  because then you're kind of negating the whole idea of electrification.
Speaker 7:  The industry is shifting to electric if they're all trucks.
Speaker 7:  We're just gonna end up in the same place that we are today with a lot
Speaker 7:  of environmental disaster basically because of the mining that needs
Speaker 7:  to take place, the effect that these heavy vehicles have on our roads today.
Speaker 7:  There's way too heavy to really, our road infrastructure already sucks
Speaker 7:  at supporting Ram 15 hundreds in their ilk. And
Speaker 7:  I think the fact that the, a battery powered RAM 1500 would be
Speaker 7:  exponentially heavier than the gas powered one is just going to
Speaker 7:  you, you're gonna see sinkhole across the nation as a potential outgrowth
Speaker 7:  of that. So I thought it was cool that Volkswagen was like, Hey, what about
Speaker 7:  a sedan? I don't know. We'll see how well that sells in America. But I think
Speaker 7:  like you need to have all the form factors. If we're gonna be like an electric
Speaker 7:  car world now with no more gas, that's gonna take
Speaker 7:  a couple decades to do and they can't all be trucks and SUVs. There needs
Speaker 7:  to be a mix of, of form factors. And the sedan is obviously, I think a very
Speaker 7:  important one to keep in the mix. And so I'm glad to see
Speaker 7:  Volkswagens keeping, keeping the torch lit for the sedan, the family sedan.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Well honestly the EVs are never gonna take off until you take, until
Speaker 5:  you get the soccer mom into the ev and right now there is not a decent
Speaker 5:  vehicle for a family. That's right. I have, I don't, and you know, you really,
Speaker 5:  we are the ones on the road all the time, so
Speaker 7:  Yeah, no, I know. We need a minivan too. There needs to be electric
Speaker 7:  Honda Odyssey Electric, Chrysler Pacificas, you know,
Speaker 7:  Kia Sorentos. There needs to be all the beaters and the Jalopies
Speaker 7:  and the Junkers. We need all of those to be electric because that's the only
Speaker 7:  way we're gonna get like carbon out of the situation altogether. And obviously
Speaker 7:  we need bikes and scooters and like smaller form factor vehicles as well.
Speaker 7:  And there were a lot of those at cs and there were some cool ones to, to
Speaker 7:  see I think Cake, which is a great
Speaker 5:  Band,
Speaker 7:  A great, a great nineties band, but also a great Swedish
Speaker 7:  electric motorbike company. They released at the show a pretty cool looking
Speaker 7:  e-bike that's for the US for the first time. Really great looking. The
Speaker 7:  design is awesome. I know Thomas Ricker has tested out one of their
Speaker 7:  vehicles in the past. He's really excited about this new one that they've
Speaker 7:  got coming out. So more smaller form sedans
Speaker 7:  obviously, but also more smaller form, weird smart cars,
Speaker 7:  neighborhood electric vehicles. There were a lot of those at the show too.
Speaker 7:  And I think that that that's, you know, like a neighborhood full of electric
Speaker 7:  golf carts that can go 30 miles per hour would be a really interesting
Speaker 7:  concept that you'll never see.
Speaker 5:  You know, that's actually my neighborhood.
Speaker 7:  Well, do you live in the villages in Florida? Is
Speaker 4:  That, I was like, that's my, that's my mom's neighborhood currently. Like,
Speaker 5:  But we need
Speaker 7:  To get our seniors into electric golf carts. And so those are, those
Speaker 7:  are a good way to do it. Those were like the main concept, I would say the
Speaker 7:  the BMW color changing car, the Volkswagen sedan, the Ram truck.
Speaker 7:  And there were some other, there were some other ones as well, but I thought
Speaker 7:  most of the, the show was focused on what's going on inside the car
Speaker 7:  screen stuff, tech stuff. We were seeing like
Speaker 7:  Chrysler and reimagining sort of the cockpit
Speaker 7:  BMW was like, Hey, how about no screens, but your
Speaker 7:  windshield is an AR screen. And everyone went,
Speaker 7:  yeah,
Speaker 4:  No,
Speaker 7:  That's a bad,
Speaker 5:  It's a
Speaker 4:  Bring the cause
Speaker 7:  We need to see through the windshield so that we don't run over people.
Speaker 7:  And if I'm getting notifications about all of my, you know, if I'm getting
Speaker 7:  Slack notifications on my, my windshield while I'm driving, that doesn't,
Speaker 7:  that doesn't seem safe, but it's an interesting concept
Speaker 7:  and that's what CS is all about. It's interesting concepts. Well,
Speaker 4:  And this is, we've we've still got the, the Detroit Auto Show coming up
Speaker 4:  pretty quickly, right. And that's where we'll see the more
Speaker 7:  Action actually no, they, they've, they've moved the date of that. It used
Speaker 7:  to be right after ces, which was always fun for all of
Speaker 7:  the auto reporters and their deteriorating health. But now
Speaker 7:  they've moved it to the, the summer. I think the Detroit realized they can't
Speaker 7:  compete anymore since CES has become such a car show over the years that
Speaker 7:  they just threw their hands up and said, screw it, we're gonna move the show
Speaker 7:  to the summertime. So now it's Detroit in the summertime. And you
Speaker 7:  know, auto shows in general have like waned in relevancy over the last decade
Speaker 7:  or so, but CS still stays, has remained I think a pretty
Speaker 7:  relevant auto show. And I, I don't think the pandemic has really
Speaker 7:  had an effect in that, in that respect. It's still is still a pretty great
Speaker 7:  car show and I think it's going to remain a really important car show. I
Speaker 7:  think moving, moving ahead.
Speaker 5:  Well, and they have tractors and boats and stuff. There aren't too. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's
Speaker 7:  Like all manners of moving, moving vehicles. There were electric boats,
Speaker 7:  there was tractors. Yeah, I mean like that's, you know, I thought it was
Speaker 7:  a, a positive development to see that that, you know, the, the electrification
Speaker 7:  shift and also more AI focused
Speaker 7:  software applications. Were also making their way into like beyond
Speaker 7:  like the consumer vehicle and into more industrial and commercial applications,
Speaker 7:  which I think is really interesting, especially for autonomy, because that's
Speaker 7:  like, when you think about like a tractor, you don't need a guy sitting in
Speaker 7:  a tractor driving that back and forth across the field. A
Speaker 7:  robot could very easily handle that type of situation. So
Speaker 7:  that's a really interesting application. I think a a lot more realistic
Speaker 7:  application than your robo taxis and your Tesla
Speaker 7:  full self-driving and things like that is something where you've
Speaker 7:  got like a contain, you know, sort of a very well-defined operational domain,
Speaker 7:  like a field, like a soybean field or a cornfield like that
Speaker 7:  makes a whole lot more sense to, to have an autonomous
Speaker 7:  driving bit of software doing that as opposed to your
Speaker 7:  Tesla model three.
Speaker 4:  Well there was, I will say I was watching NBC this weekend after the
Speaker 4:  show and there was a whole segment about
Speaker 4:  autonomous electric race cars. Oh yeah. Did you, did you
Speaker 4:  check out the, the autonomous race cars?
Speaker 7:  I have not personally checked it out, but I've, I've been pitched by the
Speaker 7:  Indie autonomous racing organization many times and they, they
Speaker 7:  seem like it's really, they've got, I'd love to check that out someday. They,
Speaker 7:  they're, they're an exciting organization. They, yeah, the, the, all the,
Speaker 7:  the vehicles are driverless. They operate obviously on a, on a racetrack
Speaker 7:  and it's all about speed, which is not something that you typically see
Speaker 7:  AV developers focused on. They're all focused on safety and following the
Speaker 7:  rules and making sure that we don't run over pedestrians.
Speaker 5:  This is just go for it. Knock everything over. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And the racing guys are like, let's just make this go as fast as we possibly
Speaker 7:  can, which is kind of exciting. And I think you're starting
Speaker 7:  to see like motorsports are like really kind of like gaining prominence in
Speaker 7:  the US especially with like the popularity of f1. And then you've also got
Speaker 7:  obviously Formula E, which is I think gaining a lot of popularity as well.
Speaker 7:  So this is like, this could be like a next, a possible next step
Speaker 7:  beyond Formula E autonomous racing vehicles I think is a,
Speaker 7:  is a very cool concept. And it'd be maybe like, you know, they'll get picked
Speaker 7:  up for like a Netflix series or something someday, but like
Speaker 4:  Would you really watch two computers just race each other? Isn't that just
Speaker 4:  like watching the bots and Mario Cart race each other?
Speaker 4:  People
Speaker 7:  Watch the robots fight, right? Isn't there like bot wars?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I say robot
Speaker 7:  Wars, robot wars people
Speaker 5:  Love, I've watched my vacuums fight each other. It's so much fun. People
Speaker 7:  Love that stuff. So the idea, because like there is like a human, there's
Speaker 7:  still a human element, like somebody had to develop the software and the
Speaker 7:  vehicle, there are people behind this robot that are, that are racing on
Speaker 7:  the track and while there may not be a guy in the car itself,
Speaker 7:  like there is still some sort of human element that was, you know, and human
Speaker 7:  ingenuity and all, you know, all the effort and
Speaker 7:  work that went into making those, those cars drive themselves that I think
Speaker 7:  you can still celebrate and feel excited for.
Speaker 4:  Well you almost got me excited about autonomous racing, so welcome
Speaker 4:  Anthony. Hell yeah. All right, well you guys have
Speaker 4:  gotta go recover from an absolutely exhausting but very
Speaker 4:  awesome ces. So I'm gonna let you guys go this Friday. We are
Speaker 4:  gonna be back with another episode of the Vergecast and next Wednesday we
Speaker 4:  will be back with even more CES coverage. This time we're gonna be joined
Speaker 4:  by Monica and Victoria talking all the wearables and all
Speaker 4:  of the laptops and tablets and stuff is going to be a lot of
Speaker 4:  fun. But for now you can find everybody on Twitter.
Speaker 4:  Andy is at Andy j Hawk Gin is
Speaker 4:  at JP two E and Chris Welch is at Chris
Speaker 4:  Welch. I'm at Alex h Crans. Stay classy,
Speaker 4:  have fun. See you on Friday.
Speaker 3:  Peace.