# Transcript
ID: 7e54a060-bcf8-11ed-b5f9-7dc5b8bbae6d
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Giles Martin and Sonos CEO Patrick Spence on the new Era 100 and Era 300 speakers
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/889699605206113964/960598437946049490/s93290-US-3732s-1678201094.mp3
Description: Today, Sonos announced a new line of speakers — the Era 100 and the Era 300 — with the latter finally taking on this format that has been a hit-or-miss experience for music lovers, supporting Amazon Music and Apple Music’s spatial audio. Though spatial format Dolby Atmos has been supported on the Sonos Arc soundbar, the Era 300 signals a music-first approach to its speakers supporting 3D soundscapes. Sonos CEO Patrick Spence believes this is the right time to do it. “We didn’t know that, in 2022, 85 of the top Billboard 100 artists would actually release Atmos tracks, but they did,” Spence says. “We feel like we’re at an inflection point.”
On board with Sonos for this shift in music listening is record producer Giles Martin, who mixed the first-ever spatial audio album (a remix of Sgt. Pepper’s Lonely Hearts Club Band, The Beatles album that his father, George Martin, originally produced) and several albums and live experiences in Dolby Atmos since. Martin is also the senior vice president of sound experience at Sonos and was involved in the development of the speaker. “When you’re building a product which has multi sort of use and orientations, you do prioritize ... in a way of, what’s the wow factor?” Martin explains. “The wow factor, which I think is truly extraordinary out of the 300, is the fact that it does spatial out of a single box. And it’s really compelling.”
Both Patrick and Giles joined Verge editor-in-chief Nilay Patel for The Vergecast to talk about the new speakers, supporting spatial audio, and why this is the time to do it.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Hello and welcome to the the flagship podcast of
Speaker 2:  Guitar Players Sneaking Up Behind you Spatial audio. I'm your Fred
Speaker 2:  Eli. Chris Welchs here. Hey Chris.
Speaker 3:  Hello. It's good to be here. The day has finally come. Eli,
Speaker 2:  The day has finally come. Chris, you have scooped this day many, many
Speaker 2:  times leading up to this moment. We're publishing our usual Wednesday episode
Speaker 2:  one day early on a Tuesday because today on the show I spent some time
Speaker 2:  with Sonos CEO Patrick Spence and Sonos senior Vice President of
Speaker 2:  Sound Experience, Gil Martin, who's also a very famous record producer. I
Speaker 2:  just wanna put that out there. I could have talked to Giles about just making
Speaker 2:  records for the entire show, but like Chris said, the day is finally
Speaker 2:  here. Sonos has announced the new era, 100 and
Speaker 2:  300 speakers, which if you've been following the Vergecast or following the
Speaker 2:  Verge following Chris, you know Chris has been inside the air ducts at Sonos
Speaker 2:  for months. Just banana camming
Speaker 2:  these speakers.
Speaker 3:  Yes, yes. First there were renders, then there were photos, and now the whole
Speaker 3:  thing is finally unveiled for everybody.
Speaker 2:  I will say, by the way, just to put, these, were not planted leaks, I don't
Speaker 2:  think Sonos was pleased with Chris, but very gracious Chris, I
Speaker 2:  believe Patrick said you're just doing your job, which is true. Exactly.
Speaker 2:  But they know that we love audio products. They know that we love social
Speaker 2:  products. They were, they're very gracious and, and still came on the show
Speaker 2:  to talk to us before Patrick and Drs came on the show.
Speaker 2:  Chris and I got a chance to go listen to these speakers to hear from the
Speaker 2:  designers and product managers. Let's start with the 100 quickly, Chris.
Speaker 2:  I think it sounds great. It's just a regular stereo speaker though.
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah, it's now stereo ish I guess since there's just one woofer, but
Speaker 3:  the Sonos one was just mono, so this just, this definitely does sound quite
Speaker 3:  better from the test that they ran for us. But it looks similar. It's like
Speaker 3:  barely bigger in size, but it has Bluetooth and line in now, which the
Speaker 3:  Sonos one did not. So you've got a lot more options for playing stuff in
Speaker 3:  your turntable or if somebody comes over and wants to play something in your
Speaker 3:  in your house, that's a bit easier with Bluetooth. So that's a big deal I
Speaker 3:  think. And it's 2 49, which is not much more than the Sonos one was. So
Speaker 3:  I think it's gonna do pretty well. How about you?
Speaker 2:  I thought it sounded great. I think we've caveat this every time we talk
Speaker 2:  about speakers, we listen to in demo environments, we listen to it in their
Speaker 2:  demo environment, right? If it sounded anything but great, it would've been
Speaker 2:  a story. It sounded great in the demo environment, it is a little bit taller.
Speaker 2:  I think the line in is really useful. I think a lot of people are gonna plug
Speaker 2:  record players into this, which Sun knows a lot of people are doing. But
Speaker 2:  it is an incremental improvement over the Sonos one. The thing that stands
Speaker 2:  out honestly over the Sonos one is that it no longer has Google
Speaker 2:  assistant support and Sonos says that is down to a change on Google's end.
Speaker 2:  I think that might be down to the fact that Sonos and Google are suing each
Speaker 2:  other over patents. Yes,
Speaker 3:  The timing does leave some kind of room for interpretation. It
Speaker 2:  Does. So the Sonos one had Google assistant support. I use Google Assistant
Speaker 2:  on my Sonos devices and with my Google devices. I think
Speaker 2:  I'm the only person in the entire ecosystem that has a reasonably good
Speaker 2:  experience doing that anyway. Like Tom Warren is always like, this sucks.
Speaker 2:  Like what does anybody do this? That's it. Like in terms of notable changes,
Speaker 2:  yep, it's got stereo tweeters now it's a little bit taller. It's got Linein
Speaker 2:  and Bluetooth, which is great. But kind of the big omission, the big trade-off
Speaker 2:  is you normally get Google support, which I might be the only person that
Speaker 2:  cares about,
Speaker 3:  Hey, they seem pretty confident with the combo of the Sonos voice control
Speaker 3:  that, and Alexa, I think Sonos voice control just added timers. So
Speaker 3:  there you go. It's slowly doing more than just music functions. Yeah, but
Speaker 3:  I think those two, they should cover a lot of ground, but I'm sure some people
Speaker 3:  will miss Google a system if that's what they're paid into and bought into.
Speaker 2:  So that's the Sonos era 100, which is very nice product. Santa Great the
Speaker 2:  demo room, but pretty incremental upgrade over the Sonos one.
Speaker 2:  The Sonos era 300 is a radically different
Speaker 2:  beast. A much more important product I think in this entire category.
Speaker 2:  The first real standalone
Speaker 2:  multi-service spatial audio device that I can think of, there's the
Speaker 2:  HomePod, but that only does spatial with Apple Music. There's the
Speaker 2:  Amazon Echo Studio, which only does spatial music with
Speaker 2:  Amazon service. This supports them both. It will support more services
Speaker 2:  over time. One imagines and it's spatial audio in a box. What's going on
Speaker 2:  with the air? The Air 300, Chris.
Speaker 3:  So it was built from the ground up for spatial audio. They said it started
Speaker 3:  three years ago with a project and the shape and design people have had
Speaker 3:  some opinions on. We published the photos of them on our site and,
Speaker 3:  and I saw one thread on Reddit where someone was like, I've been a lifelong
Speaker 3:  Zs fan. This is the ugliest speaker I've ever seen in my life. But I will
Speaker 3:  say it plays better in person than it does in like photos. It looks bigger
Speaker 3:  somehow in photos than it does in person. It's actually not that large at
Speaker 3:  all. But yeah, it's been built from the ground up for spatial. There are
Speaker 3:  six drivers in there. And yeah, Sonos thinks that you really can't do real
Speaker 3:  s spatial audio with like a round speaker, like the home pod that just fires
Speaker 3:  in all directions. Gil said you have to have some kind of like front facing
Speaker 3:  speaker or driver in there as well.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, and you will hear in this interview, Giles and I went
Speaker 2:  at each other about special audio and whether it's good or not, I think
Speaker 2:  I have space to go. I think. I think he's correct. When it's really good,
Speaker 2:  it's really good. And I think the industry is position is like,
Speaker 2:  it should all be like this. And I, somewhere in the middle is like, what
Speaker 2:  is a good spatial mix? And the answer is that it's much more restrained than
Speaker 2:  what we're hearing from a lot of things right now. And that that to me is,
Speaker 2:  it's the big question mark with this entire approach. But like I said
Speaker 2:  in the room, the Air 300 sounded great. And I'm curious
Speaker 2:  what it sounds like in lots of other kinds of rooms that are not small boxes
Speaker 2:  with perfect walls. Other little notes before we drop into the
Speaker 2:  interview, Chris, you also got a chance to spend some time talking to Patrick.
Speaker 2:  What'd you learn from that conversation?
Speaker 3:  We talked about Bluetooth and line in, because Sonos used to make fun of
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth. Actually. They had ads where like the music would be like interrupted
Speaker 3:  by phone calls and texts and stuff like that. Patrick was like, well, it's
Speaker 3:  gotten better now. It's more liable. And that combined with line in, they
Speaker 3:  just wanna give people more choice. And that also like adds to the long term
Speaker 3:  future proofing of these products because they had that S one and S two controversy.
Speaker 3:  So they're saying these, these speakers and Pest, I think the play one and
Speaker 3:  Play Five still have years and the years and the years of of life left in
Speaker 3:  them. So that's a relief for customers, I'm sure. Yeah, there should be more
Speaker 3:  in the site as these products launch and more photos and all, all kinds
Speaker 3:  of goodness.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, we've got full coverage of the launch on the site. As you listen to
Speaker 2:  this, if you want look at pictures or read more hands-on impressions for
Speaker 2:  now though, we should jump into the conversation here is
Speaker 2:  Sonos CEO Patrick Spence and Senior Vice President of Sound Experience. And
Speaker 2:  I should note extremely famous record producer Charles Martin
Speaker 2:  Patrick Spence, you're the CEO of Sonos. Charles Martin. You're the senior
Speaker 2:  Vice President of Sound Experience in Sonos. Yeah, it's a short title. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  it doesn't, it means everything. And perhaps nothing we're gonna find out.
Speaker 2:  Well, welcome to the show. You guys have new products, big
Speaker 2:  new products for Sonos, big set forward in spatial audio. I wanna talk about
Speaker 2:  all of that. Patrick, let's start with the products themselves. Two new speakers,
Speaker 2:  ERA 100, ERA 300. What are they? What do we need to
Speaker 4:  Know? Yeah, I mean this is really the next generation of Sonos, so
Speaker 4:  we're doing something very unique for us. You and I in the past have talked
Speaker 4:  about all the changes we made to bring out at least two new products every
Speaker 4:  single year. We've never brought out two products at the same time,
Speaker 4:  and they're from the same family. And we really feel like with ERA 300,
Speaker 4:  we've set the standard for out loud spatial
Speaker 4:  audio listening. And this is something the team's been working on for three
Speaker 4:  years, toiling away, you know, and, and kind of the industry's been developing
Speaker 4:  along the way to have the content we need to actually bring it all to life.
Speaker 4:  And it's hitting at the perfect time. And then with ERA 100, we've really
Speaker 4:  taken our iconic Sonos One and
Speaker 4:  done what I'm very proud of, which is rethink it completely
Speaker 4:  new hardware, new software, all of it to create something that sounds
Speaker 4:  significantly better and really matches the kind of visual
Speaker 4:  ID you would expect oto, Sonos in this day and age. And so it is a new era.
Speaker 4:  We're signaling that with the names of the products as well. We're very excited
Speaker 4:  for customers to be able to experience them.
Speaker 2:  I really wanna talk a lot about the ERA 300 and with spatial audio,
Speaker 2:  which is potentially revolutionized in the music industry in a variety of
Speaker 2:  ways. But let's start with the ERA 100. I think we can kind of
Speaker 2:  understand this product fairly quickly. It sounds great. I listened to it
Speaker 2:  with trials earlier today. It's a full on replacement for the
Speaker 2:  SOS one as you're saying. Yes. What was the decision for you like to say,
Speaker 2:  okay, this is a product that people like, we saw a lot of them, we're gonna
Speaker 2:  just move on. Yeah, you
Speaker 4:  Know, it's, it is, the thinking is really, if you're not cannibalizing
Speaker 4:  yourself and trying to raise the bar on yourself, then you're not pushing
Speaker 4:  hard enough. And we, we have these debates all the time in terms of what
Speaker 4:  we're trying to do and are we pushing hard enough? And
Speaker 4:  it comes a time, you know, seven years that we had the Sonos one out where,
Speaker 4:  you know, kind of you get to itchy at that five, six year mark where you're
Speaker 4:  saying, okay, can we do something much better than this? And Giles and
Speaker 4:  the team and Chris Davey's on the audio side and then our design team are
Speaker 4:  looking at it saying, yeah, we think we can, we think we have something that
Speaker 4:  we think we can do is much better, that we'll raise the bar
Speaker 4:  enough that it's something that we can be really proud of. And so
Speaker 4:  we, you know, know, kind of take a leap of faith in that moment to say, okay,
Speaker 4:  what are the things we need to do to make this product even better? Can we
Speaker 4:  do those things? Can we fit it in there? And do we think it's really gonna
Speaker 4:  stand for kind of that leap in innovation and quality? And we feel like we've
Speaker 4:  delivered that with the A 100.
Speaker 2:  So the Air 100 is a stereo speaker and a single package to
Speaker 2:  tweeters the top, I think a bigger wha for than before
Speaker 5:  Another one, which is a mono speaker. This is a, this is moving stereo. And,
Speaker 5:  and listen, I love and I still love the one, and it's interesting, I can
Speaker 5:  walk into a restaurant or a bar and tell whether there's a one in the bar
Speaker 5:  because it's a, you know, and in my other world of pro audio
Speaker 5:  and creating content, you know, one is used the reference by a lot of it,
Speaker 5:  a lot of engineers and producers because it's a really honest speaker. Well,
Speaker 5:  I mean, there isn't a hypey anything. It's, it's a very, very good scale
Speaker 5:  down version of what we try and do in a studio. That's what one does. But
Speaker 5:  in a mono format, that mono format is limiting because it, you lose things
Speaker 5:  like reverb tales and voices. The reality of the things, we don't listen
Speaker 5:  to music in mono. So with ERA 100, we try to, we, we thought, okay, let's
Speaker 5:  rethink this then, okay, we need to add more weight behind it, we need more,
Speaker 5:  more base. We increased the water size, we by 25%. It was tough
Speaker 5:  though. It was a really tough challenge. It's like, you know, your children
Speaker 5:  have to grow up, you know, that's the thing. And it's like, you know, I
Speaker 5:  really feel like that when we were doing it,
Speaker 2:  One of the themes I see kind of across the big tech players in audio
Speaker 2:  is they're adding an awful lot of computation to their
Speaker 2:  speakers. Especially your, the direct competitor says something like the
Speaker 2:  A 100 A 100 does not seem like it's doing an awful lot of
Speaker 2:  excessive computational tricks. Right. There's a crossover for the two
Speaker 2:  tweeters that create the stereo field. Correct. There's a mono woofer. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And that's the game. You're not, it's
Speaker 5:  Key for us as a company that you listen to music and not technology.
Speaker 5:  It's like one of those things where we try not to hype anything at all. We
Speaker 5:  try not. And however dull it may sound as marketing speak, it's like having
Speaker 5:  a clear window on the world of sound. You wanna literally just switch on
Speaker 5:  a light or switch on music in your home. And it sounds great. And
Speaker 5:  the strange thing about artifacts and and crazy stuff that's done
Speaker 5:  is after a while it wears really thin and it becomes
Speaker 5:  irritating when anything else. And and someone said to me the other day when
Speaker 5:  listening to products, they went, they sound like sonar speakers. And I was
Speaker 5:  like, well that's interesting from, you know, from my point of view, I don't
Speaker 5:  try and give us a sound. And they said, what you, what does that mean? And
Speaker 5:  he went, sounds musical. I was like, great. Okay. That's what it should be.
Speaker 5:  And so, you know, we are doing a lot of stuff under the bonnet and we
Speaker 5:  really are, you know, there's, it's a bit like fighter jets. They'd probably
Speaker 5:  fall outta the air if it wasn't the amount of DSP we're using. But I
Speaker 5:  don't want to, you know, you don't want people to hear that. You don't want
Speaker 5:  people to, you want people to hear a song
Speaker 2:  A very subtly lited trap for you about excessive processing because Right.
Speaker 2:  Spatial audio is like a lot of processing to make that work. And
Speaker 2:  so when you think about the Arrow 100, it does not have any spatial features.
Speaker 2:  It doesn't have the height channels. Well it's, but you're saying
Speaker 2:  there is processing happening inside of it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, of course. Because you know, we're, we're doing, you know, for a start
Speaker 5:  we are, we're trying to create a bigger sound than the box is. We're trying
Speaker 5:  to defy physics all of the time at Sanos. That's what we're trying to do.
Speaker 5:  We're not doing any tricks with phase, but we are, you know, you, there are
Speaker 5:  slight delay going on there to create a stereo spread at the high frequencies.
Speaker 5:  You have to do that at the same time. The most, the the key thing for me
Speaker 5:  in this, actually, what we worked really hard on the, on the, on the 100
Speaker 5:  was we could make the product a lot wider and more
Speaker 5:  spatial than it is. But the detriment to that is voices. The human voice
Speaker 5:  doesn't sound as good. Yeah. You know, because when you know your listeners
Speaker 5:  listen to music, we mix music in stereo and equal left and right
Speaker 5:  is mono and that's generally where the voice lies. And that's the songs you
Speaker 5:  love. If you pull that apart too much, it's, it can sound phasia, it can
Speaker 5:  sound weird. And so it's that argument processing over reality.
Speaker 5:  Of course it's processing, but the key thing is that is it has to sound natural
Speaker 5:  and that's done by human ear. You know, you can't measure natural weirdly
Speaker 5:  enough things can measure completely flat in a room and then sound strange.
Speaker 2:  I feel like I'm so tempted to just immediately start talking about facial
Speaker 2:  audio, but I wanna finish talking about the air 100. Yeah. Because to me
Speaker 2:  the argument with facial audio is when it's done incorrectly or
Speaker 2:  done poorly, you actually lose a lot of that impact. You spread everything
Speaker 2:  out to, to too many channels. Yeah. And everything is,
Speaker 5:  And the same if you play around a stereo too much, if you like, you know,
Speaker 5:  we don't specialize stereo because again, it feels, it's a bit like
Speaker 5:  smashing some of the toffy ham hammer you, everything flies everywhere and
Speaker 5:  you're left with no middle. It's impact like just drums and
Speaker 5:  vocals. And it's fine actually if, if it's a spatial studio tracker, it's
Speaker 5:  ambient tracking to whatever you all bets are off. And sometimes with classical
Speaker 5:  music that helps. But generally, like most pop music or
Speaker 5:  hip hop or r and b is like, it needs that, it needs that dry behind it.
Speaker 5:  And it's really important to mention, we have this sort of team of checks
Speaker 5:  and bounces. We have this soundboard, which we run where, you know, like
Speaker 5:  Mary Marquin is just won three Grammy awards. He's won, he's now won
Speaker 5:  17 Grammy awards. And so, you know, he mixes Lizzo, it's a similar, we'll
Speaker 5:  play Lizzo on era 100 and if it doesn't sound right, we,
Speaker 5:  when our job isn't done, you know, it's that important thing. It's that scalability.
Speaker 5:  You have to be honest. You have to be honest about what you're making. Kind
Speaker 5:  of like this Napoleon complex of a little speaker going, wait a second, I
Speaker 5:  beat myself through war. So you just have to make the best, you have to be
Speaker 5:  honest and the, and then that becomes, that honesty translates into your
Speaker 5:  home and you enjoy listening to it.
Speaker 4:  But I think that honesty is a key and it, it, you know, it sounds
Speaker 4:  somewhat cliche, but I think to Gil's point about the soundboard and all
Speaker 4:  the people that we have on it and all the people in Giles network, we have
Speaker 4:  them listen to these speakers and the mixes that they've done. You know,
Speaker 4:  whether it's the 100 or 300 to say like, does this sound
Speaker 4:  as you intended it? Right. And actually go through that. And I don't know
Speaker 4:  another company that spends the amount of time we do going through
Speaker 4:  that work on the way to actually launching a product. And it's,
Speaker 4:  it's so important to making sure that we're getting it right.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So the Arrow 100 it direct replacement, you're
Speaker 2:  getting itchy with the Sonos one. Sonos one very popular.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And has multiple configurations. Are you gonna do an Arrow 100 SL
Speaker 2:  without the microphones? You
Speaker 4:  Know, we're always considering, you know, what customers will want on that
Speaker 4:  front. So we'll see, you know, what kind of feedback we get at this point.
Speaker 2:  Are you leaving the one SL in the lineup? We are. Okay for now. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  then I noticed we talked about Alexa a bunch of times today. Yeah. Does it
Speaker 2:  support Google Assistant as well?
Speaker 4:  Google Assistant has changed the way that they're implementing it for third
Speaker 4:  parties. And so that's changed. So at this point it won't support
Speaker 4:  Google Assistant. Our existing products that support Google Assistant will
Speaker 4:  continue to, but 100 300 will not.
Speaker 2:  Is that because Google made a change or is that because Google, Google change
Speaker 2:  litigation
Speaker 4:  Between you? Google has nothing to do with the ongoing litigation. You know,
Speaker 4:  as you and I have talked about before, they, you know, YouTube music, like
Speaker 4:  all the different aspects, Google Assistant, the teams continue to work pretty
Speaker 4:  constructively. But they did make a change in terms of how they do Google
Speaker 4:  Assistant on third party products. And it's a pretty big engineering lift
Speaker 4:  for us. And, and the reality is right now we'd like to see it back on the
Speaker 4:  platform. But you know, people are using voice for music timers
Speaker 4:  and weather Right. As they have for many years as you know. And we're well
Speaker 4:  covered with what we have with solo's voice control and Alexa. So we feel
Speaker 4:  pretty good about where we are with these products.
Speaker 2:  Did you assemble a task force to be like, all right, we need Bing to insult
Speaker 2:  people directly from our speakers. Just let it go crazy chat
Speaker 2:  GBT is the future. Just let let people talk to the ai
Speaker 4:  We'll we'll let you sort it all out. Okay. And then we'll figure out how
Speaker 4:  we, every
Speaker 2:  Other company had to like do some sort of weird code red
Speaker 4:  Exercise. No, we will focus on creating great speakers that people can listen
Speaker 4:  to amazing music on the
Speaker 2:  Sonos. I'll figure out as soon as reads all of Tumblr and says, your music
Speaker 2:  taste as shit is not coming. No. Because I, there are people that would buy
Speaker 2:  that product specifically. Yeah. There was like, the song sucks.
Speaker 2:  There's a better version of the song. It's the original. You're
Speaker 4:  Late. Well our friends at Spotify did introduce DJ today in
Speaker 4:  ai dj, I don't know if you saw that. So
Speaker 2:  There you go. This is the future is like you start listening to an album
Speaker 2:  and it's like, I like the second album Better people. I know people like
Speaker 2:  my friends would be like, I just want someone to talk to me about music no
Speaker 2:  matter what it says.
Speaker 5:  I don't have my own opinion.
Speaker 2:  Exactly.
Speaker 5:  That's what they're saying. I want a computer, have my opinion. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Feed in all of Pitchfork and then Pitchfork will tell you whatever you're
Speaker 2:  listening to at six.
Speaker 5:  Tell me, tell me what I really like Zach. We, we can go to very deep conversation
Speaker 5:  about art and anomalies and art about that
Speaker 2:  Music. Yeah. And all of those conversations always kind of sound like you're
Speaker 2:  having them with a moody computer anyway. Yes.
Speaker 4:  So
Speaker 2:  That's right. Big focus on sustainability with the 100 and the
Speaker 2:  300 lots of recycled plastic. Yeah. We saw some custom
Speaker 2:  screws today. Yeah. There's more screws instead of
Speaker 4:  Glue.
Speaker 2:  93, 93 screws in the 100,
Speaker 4:  In the 300
Speaker 2:  In 300 u c when someone says we only use screws instead of glue.
Speaker 2:  Also we need to make custom screws with hearts in them specifically.
Speaker 2:  That's more cost. How do you weigh that kind of decision?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, we're building products for, you know, the decade, right? As we look
Speaker 4:  at where we're trying to, trying to do, we think the biggest thing we can
Speaker 4:  do for the environment for our customers is make sure these products last
Speaker 4:  for a really long time. But we're always looking and pushing on what parts
Speaker 4:  can be used from recycled, how do we do all of these things? How do we
Speaker 4:  improve repairability? That's been a huge issue. And so the screws come in
Speaker 4:  big when we're thinking about being able to repair instead of using
Speaker 4:  adhesives and being in situations where we have to throw away product. Cuz
Speaker 4:  you just don't wanna do that. So what I'm most proud of is we're getting
Speaker 4:  better and better, not just on those fronts, but as well in terms of energy
Speaker 4:  usage, which with each of the products. But I always feel like at the
Speaker 4:  core, the most important thing is are we building something that can, you
Speaker 4:  know, reasonably last in someone's house for a decade. Right? And I think
Speaker 4:  we do that better than anybody else out there. And we'll, we will continue
Speaker 4:  to push on what other parts can come from, you know, recycled materials and
Speaker 4:  all of those things. How do we get better on repairability? We've made a
Speaker 4:  huge leap with era, which is why we've decided like to call this a whole
Speaker 4:  new line, proud of that and we're gonna keep working on it. And
Speaker 4:  it, it all makes sense when you're playing the long game from a cost and
Speaker 4:  investment perspective because I feel like you get more than that
Speaker 4:  back over time in customer loyalty and everything else that we're trying
Speaker 4:  to build.
Speaker 2:  Speakers are one of those products that sit around people's houses for, for
Speaker 2:  decades. Yeah. If not more. Obviously Sonos has had a number of different
Speaker 2:  approaches to upgrading products, trading products in this is something you
Speaker 2:  can take apart. Do you have a thought one day maybe we'll just replace the
Speaker 2:  sort of computer elements of these speakers and leave the drivers alone.
Speaker 4:  I have a real hope that one day that's a possibility. People call me
Speaker 4:  crazy for doing it. Giles might even right now. But I do, I do think
Speaker 4:  that's a potential possibility in the future and I'd love to see something
Speaker 4:  like that and I'd love to see us pushing on how to, how to be that company.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. From your perspective on the audio front, right? A, a
Speaker 2:  great pair of vintage speakers and a stereo set up with an all like people
Speaker 2:  worship at the Alt, I'm one of these people, I'm just gonna admit it, but
Speaker 2:  they last forever. And the sound there is lasting in a way
Speaker 2:  that some people would argue cannot be defeated. A small computer with a
Speaker 2:  bunch of radios in it that happens to have a digital amplifier and a driver.
Speaker 2:  Do you think that can be as long-lasting?
Speaker 5:  It it's based on CPU and not ledge. I mean I would argue that people blow
Speaker 5:  blow old speakers all the time. Yeah. So, and I've been in situations where
Speaker 5:  I've been in very high end audio places where they playback mix. I've done
Speaker 5:  and I've gone, your left channels a bit weird. And they go, oh, valve's just
Speaker 5:  gone. Sorry. So I, there there's, there's, there's a lot of ways looking
Speaker 5:  at this. Yeah. There really is. Yeah. I think that, I think we proved
Speaker 5:  actually, you know, Rick Rubin had a, an old play five outside his porch
Speaker 5:  for 10 years, you know, in the rain. Yeah. And it
Speaker 5:  lasted and that's not even we,
Speaker 2:  I think the last time Patrick was here I was like, why didn't you make an
Speaker 2:  outdoor speaker? And he was like, I know a famous producer had a play five,
Speaker 2:  so thank you for outing him.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. It's great. I'm not done actually I did his podcast
Speaker 5:  recently. I get done. He'll be okay. He's a good mate. So yeah,
Speaker 5:  I think that, I think I love the idea and the ethos of Sonos. I
Speaker 5:  mean actually it's one of those things that, that, you know, I got involved
Speaker 5:  in Sonos nine years ago now because they were the first coming that asked
Speaker 5:  me what was wrong about the sound of the, as opposed to
Speaker 5:  tell us how great we are. And then on top of that, I love the ethos of we
Speaker 5:  want these products to last because why not? We're not asking you to
Speaker 5:  replace 'em. We're asking you to put more in your more in your your house.
Speaker 5:  That's the thing. You know, it's, it's expensive for us to do that. It's
Speaker 5:  expensive for us for a number of different reasons for us to keep products
Speaker 5:  in the marketplace. But it's the right thing to do. I think there'll always
Speaker 5:  be a place for, you know, your, the the listen, I have
Speaker 5:  a whole load of speakers, you know, I have a full studio so I have
Speaker 5:  Abbey Road to use. I think there's a place for things. But just as far
Speaker 5:  as that ability to go think of a song and
Speaker 5:  thinking of a song to listening to it, to wake up with music or have music
Speaker 5:  in your house or, or or gathering your mates and listening son
Speaker 5:  is just brilliant. And that's what everyone says to me. And from my own experience,
Speaker 5:  before I got sent a play three and a play five, I met a guy and I was
Speaker 5:  in the studios in LA and they sent it back, sent to my house in London. You
Speaker 5:  know, my wife was happy for me to have these speakers in the home, which
Speaker 5:  is very rare. Well my dad who was George Martin famous rugby producer, he
Speaker 5:  had no, we had no speakers. And the, he listen to mixes in the car and suddenly
Speaker 5:  we had music in our house. And that's the thing is that there's two different
Speaker 5:  ways and I think everything is, there's no better or worse.
Speaker 5:  It's like vinyl digital, what's your choice? It's like just enjoy music.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's like push towards lossless. And we're gonna talk about spatial, but
Speaker 2:  lossless and spatial seem to have come along at the same time, at least for
Speaker 2:  the major streaming services. Can you hear the difference between 1 92
Speaker 2:  and Lossless and the era 100?
Speaker 5:  No One era 100. No, but it's not that type of unit. It's not
Speaker 5:  like, you know, it's not a reference. We're not trying to build reference
Speaker 5:  speakers. We're trying to build, again, it's like we're trying to build
Speaker 5:  the best possible scenarios so you can enjoy all the music in the home.
Speaker 5:  And it's, there's an interesting point about this because you know, I
Speaker 5:  have a quarter million dollar setup in my studios and
Speaker 5:  yes. And I work, I'm head of Audio and Sound Universal Music Group
Speaker 5:  and I work, I consult with Apple and other stream of services
Speaker 5:  over their quality of their codex and all that sort of stuff. Yes I am that
Speaker 5:  person. However, there's a point where shouldn't you just enjoy a song?
Speaker 5:  Do you know what I mean? Yeah. She's, and people and people talking about
Speaker 5:  numbers all the time. Would you prefer 1 92 or 96 or what the, it's like,
Speaker 5:  wait a second, it's, I'm involved in this. It's just, you know, and I
Speaker 5:  can hear the between certain things and we've done tests and we've sent and
Speaker 5:  we've done tests with s cause we're really interested in this. This is super
Speaker 5:  interesting cause we have to make decisions based on this with pros like
Speaker 5:  mastering engineers. And I have this brilliant guy, Greg McCarty works for
Speaker 5:  me and he invented the system where we'd send Pro tools sessions out with
Speaker 5:  96, 20, 96, 24 files, Spotify streams, apple
Speaker 5:  streams, streams, unnamed on and people's songs.
Speaker 5:  They'd mixed and we're sensing which one do you prefer out of like
Speaker 5:  completely blind listening. And it's amazing how many people didn't wanna
Speaker 5:  do it, you know, there we are. So, so I
Speaker 5:  think what we need to do is focus on the best possible experience from people
Speaker 5:  farm to table as you'd say is the best possible experience. And it's how
Speaker 5:  do we get to that without transients and other objects, artifacts
Speaker 5:  going on and being honest about it's key.
Speaker 2:  Last question on the 100, there's no height channels,
Speaker 2:  there's no spatial push with the 100 you can still use in these rears.
Speaker 2:  Yep. But why no height channels? Why no spatial on the 100? You know,
Speaker 4:  We're in the early days of Spacial for sure. We wanted to
Speaker 4:  really make sure that as we bring a product to the world that
Speaker 4:  delivers the best, you know, experience and sets the bar, we wanted to
Speaker 4:  start with the 300. And we think they're, you know, to J's point of like
Speaker 4:  listening to music and people listening to music and that there's room for
Speaker 4:  stereo speakers as well. So you'll see we keep the five in the portfolio
Speaker 4:  as well for people that want to enjoy that. And we're in a, we're in a transition
Speaker 4:  period. To me that's similar to the mono to stereo
Speaker 4:  transition period where there's a lot of emotional energy about that transition.
Speaker 4:  It took actually decades if you look back on it. And there was both
Speaker 4:  for a while, mono and stereo and going through that. And so I think there's
Speaker 4:  going to continue to be over this next period and we wanna be there for customers
Speaker 4:  no matter what they choose.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think there's people who are wondering, okay, I want the full
Speaker 2:  atmo setup from Sonos, particularly from movies to get
Speaker 2:  up firing rears now is a $900 investment. Am I looking at
Speaker 2:  a future where it will always be a $900 investment or are you planning on
Speaker 2:  building that out over
Speaker 4:  Time? Well, I mean that's what is that $90 a year,
Speaker 4:  you know, as you think about it? Or like, you know, we're talking 10 bucks,
Speaker 4:  you know, a month, a month kind of thing as we go through it, 10, 20 bucks.
Speaker 4:  So I think for the kind of experience that we deliver, I think there's value
Speaker 4:  for money in that for sure.
Speaker 2:  From your perspective, as you think about the split between using these speakers
Speaker 2:  for spacial audio atmos music and then what's
Speaker 2:  required for a great movie experience, is there a trade
Speaker 2:  off that you've made? Is there a balancing that needs to be done or is it
Speaker 5:  No, I mean the first, it's funny, you know, when you're building a
Speaker 5:  product which is, has multi sort of use and orientations, you do prioritize,
Speaker 5:  you do prioritize in a way of like, what's the wow factor? The wow factor,
Speaker 5:  which I think is truly extraordinary out of the 300 is the fact that it does
Speaker 5:  spatial out of a single box and it's really compelling. Yeah. To me it's
Speaker 5:  like there's nothing else on the planet that does what this does.
Speaker 5:  I'm saying as a creator and other creators as well. I mean, I I I
Speaker 5:  say to people and I'm, I'm not really Mr. Jargon at all. I'm pretty honest
Speaker 5:  and I love music, I love sound, I love, you know, I'm passionate. And I'll
Speaker 5:  say to people, I mean I, I was at CS of bumps and produced engineers. I went,
Speaker 5:  it really is amazing. Like they come to my suite and they go, oh my God,
Speaker 5:  this really is amazing. The guitar's like over by, I had a bar area cuz that's
Speaker 5:  the way I roll. It's over by the bar area. Like I'm gonna, you know, that's
Speaker 5:  where the guitars are and it's like I told you and they went, yeah but you
Speaker 5:  know, we didn't. So the single boxing was great and then if there's two of
Speaker 5:  them, it'll do stereo, pure stereo and Dolby Atmos had a stereo.
Speaker 5:  Interesting enough, the way we think about it, doing stereo stereo atmos
Speaker 5:  or two speakers creating Atmos is creating front firing height sides
Speaker 5:  rears. And you've turned those around the other way. That's your home theater
Speaker 5:  setup. You're adding, you are adding. So, so it's kind of the same problem.
Speaker 5:  If you like it, an audio perspective or the same solution is probably a better
Speaker 5:  way of putting it. So that's the way we work. And there is an
Speaker 5:  additive and compelling drive behind doing this. It's, it's,
Speaker 5:  you'd be surprised. I mean I started working Space audio a long time ago
Speaker 5:  and did before Think Sergeant Peppers, the Beatles SLU Peppers album was
Speaker 5:  the first album done in special audio, which I mixed, I then did kick by
Speaker 5:  Ns and they, they were both used for, they played them back in theaters
Speaker 5:  when I did Kick and they made the the Blu-ray, cuz that's going back that
Speaker 5:  far. I went to Capital Studios and the rears were too loud. I went to
Speaker 5:  Dolby Wooden Ambassador, the sub was too loud. I went to Dolby and so
Speaker 5:  Square and the right hand speaker was too loud. Quantum, with Discrete Systems,
Speaker 5:  you can be in a situation where people don't set them up correctly. The
Speaker 5:  elegance of having one box multichannel systems like Arc
Speaker 5:  plus two 300 s is is a pretty good chance for true play. It's gonna be a
Speaker 5:  even balanced sound. It's gonna be rendering. And the dangerous thing about
Speaker 5:  space audio, in fact you get the channel mixed wrong. It's worse a
Speaker 5:  mono, but we have to make sure we we get that right every
Speaker 2:  Time the high channels are based on bouncing off the ceiling. Right? That's
Speaker 2:  right. Do you need to do True play to get the phose effect?
Speaker 5:  No you don't. But true play does we'll adjust delays and
Speaker 5:  and levels and eq you know, we, we do True play for a reason.
Speaker 5:  Indeed. You might find that we might even reduce the Height channel
Speaker 5:  sbl because of true play. All it does is it's, it's matching levels.
Speaker 5:  So you know, it's not like your heights won't, it's not that your heights
Speaker 5:  won't work if you don't use True Play, but your balance will
Speaker 5:  improve and your sound will improve if you do use it.
Speaker 2:  We've gotta take a quick break, but we'll be back with more of my conversation
Speaker 2:  with Patrick Spence and Giles. Mark
Speaker 7:  Al Bruno ran the mob in Springfield, Massachusetts,
Speaker 8:  US growing up Italian and you want to be a criminal. Bruno was the guy that
Speaker 8:  we looked up to
Speaker 7:  Till he was gunned down in 2003.
Speaker 9:  Now Bruno just took about eight to the body at the Italian club on Winthrop
Speaker 9:  Street. I'm like, oh Jesus.
Speaker 7:  Bruno's murder was a mystery but also an
Speaker 7:  opportunity. It was law enforcement's best shot at taking down the
Speaker 7:  Springfield Mafia once and for all.
Speaker 7:  I'm Elliot Am Ellie Honig host of Up Against the Mob, the
Speaker 7:  Springfield crew. As a federal prosecutor, I took down over
Speaker 7:  100 mobsters, but nothing was as wild as what went
Speaker 7:  down in Springfield.
Speaker 10:  Call 9 1 1. I've been shot
Speaker 7:  To solve the case. We'd have to convince made men to break their code
Speaker 7:  of silence.
Speaker 8:  You can't put your hands on 'em or you get killed.
Speaker 7:  And as the dominoes started to fall, all of us just looked at each
Speaker 11:  Other like this case is blowing up,
Speaker 7:  Up against the mob, the Springfield crew from Cafe
Speaker 7:  and the Vox Media podcast Network. Following your listening app to hear
Speaker 7:  new episodes every Wednesday.
Speaker 11:  Unexplainable has got a new three part series called Origins.
Speaker 11:  It's all about the beginnings and boundaries of life on earth.
Speaker 12:  Every marvelous living creature on our earth is built of complex
Speaker 12:  living cells.
Speaker 13:  Life is made up of atoms, molecules and chemical
Speaker 13:  reactions.
Speaker 12:  But what makes them alive?
Speaker 11:  Where did Earth's water come from? How did life
Speaker 11:  actually start? And I don't know, just
Speaker 13:  What is life
Speaker 11:  Origins from Unexplainable starting March 1st.
Speaker 11:  Follow Unexplainable for new episodes every Wednesday.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. So there 100 is kind of the big step forward here.
Speaker 2:  It's the big investment into Spacial. We are looking around,
Speaker 2:  we are pretty sure this is the first standalone spatial audio speaker that
Speaker 2:  is not connected inherently to a streaming service, right? Apple obviously
Speaker 2:  makes the HomePod, Amazon makes the Echo Studio. They would argue that there's
Speaker 2:  some inherent connection there that makes everything work together better.
Speaker 2:  What made you think it's okay we have to invest in this, this is the next
Speaker 2:  great audio format.
Speaker 4:  It was really hearing from Giles and Chris Davies and our audio
Speaker 4:  team. We had a ton of debates in the Lossless period and like, hi
Speaker 4:  Rez hd, can you hear a difference? Should we invest in this? What should
Speaker 4:  we support or not? And we landed in the, okay, there
Speaker 4:  isn't a difference. We're not gonna go, you know, just chase this next technology.
Speaker 4:  And you know, I mean Sonos is known for taking our time to
Speaker 4:  consider what's happening and it was really an understanding of what was
Speaker 4:  happening with the artists and were they beginning to embrace it and they
Speaker 4:  were. And so we saw that three years ago and the labels starting to embrace
Speaker 4:  it and it seemed like there was, there was actually momentum in the industry
Speaker 4:  starting to happen. So, well it was a chance though at that point cuz it,
Speaker 4:  you know, we didn't know that in 2022, you know, 85 of the top
Speaker 4:  100 billboard 100 artists would actually release at most tracks. But they
Speaker 4:  did. And so that's a good thing. We're at a, we feel like we're at an inflection
Speaker 4:  point where more and more people are are releasing an Atmos, which is great,
Speaker 4:  but that was the bet that we basically made and it was on the back of
Speaker 4:  Giles and Chris and the team basically saying, no, no this is special
Speaker 4:  and this is one that mimics that jump from, you
Speaker 4:  know, mono to stereo and this is the next big one that artists are actually
Speaker 4:  embracing. And so, you know, for us then it's like, okay, we gotta be there
Speaker 4:  and we've gotta do this right? And so that took some time to go build as
Speaker 4:  well and do it right. But you know, if we're gonna do it, we're going to
Speaker 4:  try and really set the bar. And I feel like we have, with this product
Speaker 2:  You're launching with support for special from two services,
Speaker 2:  Amazon Music, HD Apple Music, they are
Speaker 2:  not quite the same. Right? There are some format differences between how
Speaker 2:  the services deliver spatial audio. That seems weird to
Speaker 2:  me. What's going on there?
Speaker 5:  It's not down to us. You know, if it was, it wouldn't be.
Speaker 5:  Let's say it's not that the music industry, it's like bearing in mind that
Speaker 5:  I have this weird position where I am, you know, head of audio and sound
Speaker 5:  for both Universal and Sauna. So I I'm at the, the
Speaker 5:  beginning of the source. Yeah. And at the end of the source, which is kind
Speaker 5:  of useful and actually beneficial to, you know, where Universal approached
Speaker 5:  me after Sonos Universal has been three years, four years. And I said, listen,
Speaker 5:  you know, I do and I'm loyal to Sonos. I went, no, I think we think it's
Speaker 5:  a good thing and you know, we work, we work together because you know, I
Speaker 5:  knew at the top of the source, the stream that there'll be Atmos, the spatial
Speaker 5:  audio was coming down the pipe. So I'm like going, we need to embrace this.
Speaker 5:  The way that Amazon or Apple deal with this is not
Speaker 5:  down to us. It's not down to universally, it's down to down to them. And
Speaker 5:  you know, we just have to, we, we have to partner with people and we have
Speaker 5:  to be Switzerland. You know, if that's a not very old reference as far as
Speaker 5:  this is important to us that we provide an ecosystem that the,
Speaker 5:  that the music lover just, I want to use the service so I should listen to
Speaker 5:  it. But
Speaker 2:  As a music lover, I know now when I'm listening to
Speaker 2:  Apple, okay, there's an Atmos logo here. These often sound
Speaker 2:  better than the generic spatial audio logo. And this whole thing
Speaker 2:  sounds different than what Amazon is doing. What are the differences there
Speaker 2:  that you have to
Speaker 5:  Contend? Okay, so I don't think, I'm not hearing a master between
Speaker 5:  Amazon Atmos and, and Apple Atmos. There's Also's only 360
Speaker 5:  to bear in mind
Speaker 2:  And Amazon sports side as well.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. And suppose that, so occasionally. And then there's the headphone
Speaker 5:  thing as well. So if you listen to headphones, the way that Apple renders
Speaker 5:  Boral is different the way that Amazon renders up Boral. So everyone's confusing.
Speaker 5:  When you listen to an ERA 300, it'll be the same
Speaker 2:  The atmo next.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So, so, so if you think about it, I I, I was surprised. I
Speaker 5:  I created this, this love show in, in Vegas with 7,000 speakers in a room,
Speaker 5:  which is essentially the sort of template of Dolby Atmos. We have obviously
Speaker 5:  a lot of hype channels cause it's, it's in the round. I never thought, and
Speaker 5:  I made the this 5.1 album, which I thought was gonna be
Speaker 5:  the future of audio, but then I could never listen to it on a system because
Speaker 5:  I, you know, people don't have five one systems at that, at that stage. I
Speaker 5:  never thought the first steps in spatial audio would be headphones. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  What's interesting headphones actually is that it has become exponentially
Speaker 5:  better as an experience really, really quickly. I mean it was, I thought
Speaker 5:  it was un listenable about three years ago and now it's pretty good. However,
Speaker 5:  the confusing of the consumer, which is goes off top of us and, but it's
Speaker 5:  something that, you know, that we care about. Cause we care about sound experiences
Speaker 5:  for everything is that, you know, you can have a different
Speaker 5:  experience compared to on different headphones spatially as well as
Speaker 5:  spectorally. So EQ as well, spatially. And then on different streaming servers,
Speaker 5:  whether it's Amazon or Apple. And with the
Speaker 5:  Universal group itself speaking by the, it's one of the things we
Speaker 5:  are working with both Apple and Amazon and manufacturers on
Speaker 5:  unifying that experience. Cause it's bad for the artists. One other thing
Speaker 5:  else, it's, and it's, and it's the feedback we get from artists, whether
Speaker 5:  it's like Mick Jagger or Lizzo or wherever going, well
Speaker 5:  I'm not sure I wanna do this cause I don't, you lose control. It's like whack-a-mole
Speaker 5:  suddenly I've put in my music. And so you need that stability to
Speaker 5:  the, to the ecosystem on to make it work. One of the things we're doing with
Speaker 5:  ERA 300, which is really groundbreaking and benefits to the artists
Speaker 5:  as well, the benefits to Sonos is that we've developed a bunch of units
Speaker 5:  for artists where they can mix directly through as a reference speaker.
Speaker 5:  So which gives the bonus, like a, it reassures them that the mixes
Speaker 5:  can sound good out of a single box and B, they can give us feedback if
Speaker 5:  they don't like anything we are doing and we can change it. So with the B
Speaker 5:  or Kodak, that should happen as well. That should be a reference of what
Speaker 5:  it should be. And that's why you get, that's where we get confused about
Speaker 5:  the, where it's rendered.
Speaker 2:  So I would say that I thought headphone spatial audio
Speaker 2:  was really where I heard the loss of impact. Right. And it felt almost
Speaker 2:  like, I know you were going through a 90 CD player that had like the stadium
Speaker 2:  button.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah, exactly.
Speaker 2:  Spread everything out. Correct. And, and sort of empty everything out. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  The demos I heard today, obviously you were there, you made, made sure they
Speaker 2:  sounded good.
Speaker 5:  No, but I but you say that, but you know, and you asked me this question.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So we, so listeners, we were in a room and picture us pictures, the
Speaker 5:  two of us in a room together, we're in a room with like, with where they
Speaker 5:  drew the curtains on the windows. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Ceiling and glass
Speaker 5:  Wall. That's like with this, this special design. So you can have special,
Speaker 5:  it's like, no, this is design, so you can't have spatial audio. It's the
Speaker 5:  speakers in the corner of the room because we had an arc in front of a TV
Speaker 5:  should be, if it's the center you had an even balance all this kind of stuff.
Speaker 5:  But I think that's cool. It's like, you know, I don't believe that that's
Speaker 5:  the only time you're gonna listen to the product, so it's okay. Yeah. You
Speaker 5:  know, and I, it's so important. The impact is the most important
Speaker 5:  thing. Emotional connectivity is much important. That's why mono is kind
Speaker 5:  of cool. And that's way here. I talk about spatial audio on, on new product.
Speaker 5:  We've invested a million dollars in that impact of, and
Speaker 5:  it's funny, I listened, I did, I I I to a chemical brothers track
Speaker 5:  two new tracks with them and I listened to it and I Dolby Atmos room and
Speaker 5:  I had an era of 300 on top of the set of speaker. And I was playing around
Speaker 5:  with the first time I was playing around with a Dante, the, the, sorry, the
Speaker 5:  interface where, where we were, we were switching between the two. And actually
Speaker 5:  I kind of liked the central, like that immediacy you get from
Speaker 5:  300, the era of 300. It's like that's hitting me in the face like you did
Speaker 5:  today where you are absolutely right. Sometimes with space audio, you get
Speaker 5:  that feeling. It's like, wait a second, have I hit the stadium button? My,
Speaker 5:  when an hemp wait a second, I'm just, am I wading through
Speaker 5:  audio all of a sudden. It's, it's, it shouldn't be like that. And
Speaker 5:  that's the tricky thing is that we have to, as artists,
Speaker 5:  as record labels and as manufacturers of products,
Speaker 5:  we have to work on experience.
Speaker 2:  One of the, I would say more cynical criticisms of spatial
Speaker 2:  across the industry is, well, you know why Spotify can't do it, it's because
Speaker 2:  the rights to distributes spatial are more expensive and Apple and Amazon
Speaker 2:  are just paying the money. And spatial is a thing that you can hear. Right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. You can't hear Lossless. I think we've all talked around the idea of
Speaker 2:  not being able to hear Lossless. Most people can't hear Lossless, especially
Speaker 2:  on their AirPods. Yeah. But as a format shift, is it something you could
Speaker 2:  charge higher rates for? Is something you could charge the consumer more
Speaker 2:  spatial is hearable in a way that could lead to different
Speaker 2:  rate structures? Has that been the background of your conversations about
Speaker 2:  why to support this format that the industry is doing this because it represents
Speaker 2:  a format shift from vinyl to cassettes to CD on the next thing? Or is
Speaker 2:  it there's actually something very meaningful here that improves the
Speaker 4:  Experience? It start, it started from the experience. Yeah. From you know,
Speaker 4:  where kind of where we are because you know, for us it's not,
Speaker 4:  you know, we're not involved in any of that part of it. Right. And so
Speaker 4:  from our perspective, yeah, yeah, partially. But that's not how he's paid.
Speaker 2:  No. But yeah,
Speaker 5:  He is. I mean, God I wish I was You wanna say,
Speaker 5:  can
Speaker 2:  You guess? I just wonder
Speaker 5:  If you can renegotiate my consultancy with the universe. I'd be delighted.
Speaker 2:  No,
Speaker 5:  But it's a,
Speaker 2:  It's about call.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's a really valid point. But I think I
Speaker 5:  base things. It's funny when I, way back seven
Speaker 5:  years ago and I mixed Sergeant Pepper and Space Studio, there's been in my
Speaker 5:  David Arnold phone me up and said he went to a room and listened to it and
Speaker 5:  he went, it was the single most emotional audio experience he'd had.
Speaker 5:  I was like, wow, thanks David. And I then paid him. But the point
Speaker 5:  is, is that you can really touch what's, what's, you can travel through
Speaker 5:  space and time and that sounds crazy, but like I did this get back thing
Speaker 5:  with Peter Jackson last year, this Get Back series, and we did that
Speaker 5:  in spatial, but then a mixed letter B and I can put the room that
Speaker 5:  Paul McCartney was in while he sang the piano on the walls of your house.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So he is in the room with you now you can talk about finance
Speaker 5:  and ecosystems and thing. That's why I do it. I do it.
Speaker 5:  So I can sit with Finns and Abbey Road
Speaker 5:  and he can talk to me about how he liked, you know, will I do this
Speaker 5:  mix in Atmos? And I you tried mixing Atmos and he then delivers like a cracking
Speaker 5:  We listen to Del Yeah. Like, like cracking mixes and atmos. And like
Speaker 5:  his engineer has an ear 300, which he uses reference. And that's, that's,
Speaker 5:  that's the, it's fun. You know, we do it. Why do I do it? Why do I
Speaker 5:  do this stuff with so much? It's fun. It's like super cool. It's fun.
Speaker 5:  Now Salian who is, you know, I respect,
Speaker 5:  you know, definitely respect, but it's like, that's not why I'd sit Patrick.
Speaker 5:  Listen Patrick, we need to look at this because, and then, you know, Patrick
Speaker 5:  Lister sat in the room we were sitting in today and go share this sound.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, and we with your daughter. I was like, check this out. It's
Speaker 5:  like, this is,
Speaker 2:  It's
Speaker 5:  Amazing. You're not listening to cash registers. You listen to music.
Speaker 2:  Some people think they're listening to cash
Speaker 5:  Registers. Yeah, they, well they, they're not my friends.
Speaker 2:  It's weird that you can't, you mentioned Blu-Ray is a spatial
Speaker 2:  distribution format. I would say that as not a mainstream distribution format.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I'm like very careful. Like I'm in room with you two and like a bunch
Speaker 2:  of virgin nerds. There's a lot of Blueray players in smallest
Speaker 5:  Vicinity here. Well, listen, listen, the question I got today for someone
Speaker 5:  quite angry was like, why do you not release Revolve in our on
Speaker 5:  Blueray?
Speaker 2:  You have to understand like our producers wanted to, like Andrew wants to
Speaker 2:  know
Speaker 5:  He wasn't question. That's we, we might do.
Speaker 2:  It's on a mainstream for, except for this room. It's
Speaker 2:  weird that you can't own a spatial audio track. You can't buy one
Speaker 2:  from Apple, you can't buy one from Amazon. It's all streaming all the time.
Speaker 2:  Right. Do is that just the nature of consumer preferences?
Speaker 5:  I think you can, Blu-rays are released.
Speaker 2:  So Blu-Ray is your answer. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, I How else, how else would you like to own it?
Speaker 2:  I would like to download a file. Like
Speaker 5:  It's download,
Speaker 2:  There's something, there's something underneath all of this, right? Which
Speaker 2:  is like, as part of a consumer experience shift, there's a
Speaker 2:  business model shift. There is a, an ownership
Speaker 2:  shift. There's a underlying bet on streaming.
Speaker 2:  And to me, you know, like, I like to have my music, I'm serious
Speaker 2:  about it. And there's just a, there's a weirdness where it's like, I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  invest in this product from Sonos and to get the most out of it, I have to
Speaker 2:  pay Apple or Amazon for the rest of my life in order
Speaker 2:  to get the most value out of this product. And that just seems, it's, I
Speaker 2:  don't think it's in your control, but it seems like it's part of the change
Speaker 2:  here.
Speaker 5:  I think you'd argue the same thing about television. Yeah. You know, adolescence.
Speaker 5:  Like what if I,
Speaker 2:  Well you're the one bringing up Blueray. You
Speaker 5:  Brought up Blueray first. Mr. Blueray guy.
Speaker 5:  No, I think there's, I mean that is the, the nature of the beast now.
Speaker 5:  Of course. Like, you know, it's not down to us. He
Speaker 5:  says now talking about  which I am,
Speaker 2:  I really lured you in here to, to put you in like an existential crisis.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. This is the welcome of my life. Luckily my family's standing by by
Speaker 5:  this difficult time. No, it's, it's, it's not down to,
Speaker 5:  it's not down to us. We, we deliver, you know, that analogy of like, you
Speaker 5:  know, the window in the world of sound, we deliver whatever's coming through.
Speaker 5:  And now if it's almost to download it, I think you can and you can download
Speaker 5:  HD tracks. I think maybe you, you know, I'm sure
Speaker 5:  it's funny. I'm sure that there'll be a stage you can download Atmo track.
Speaker 5:  Yes. I
Speaker 4:  I would think so too. But it, it is an interesting point to
Speaker 5:  Think about. Right. And I don't think that's a, I don't think that's a, I
Speaker 5:  don't think that, listen, going back to the previous conversation, your Honor,
Speaker 5:  about, about financial services, I'm sure that
Speaker 5:  if there's a, like HG Tracks Universal,
Speaker 5:  you know, we speaking Universal, we'd go, let's do a
Speaker 5:  deal where you, we are providing downloadable Atmos files for a subscription
Speaker 5:  fee and you can download them. That's not, I don't think that's a, that's
Speaker 5:  not a conversation. We've then that we have to work out the ecosystem of
Speaker 5:  storage. Well and
Speaker 2:  Started as a literal client servers model download. There's a
Speaker 2:  long
Speaker 5:  History here. You're right. And then we'd have to work at a system of, I
Speaker 5:  mean, open a can worms, rust link across the question of like
Speaker 5:  storage and then playing back from a library. So we touch you, we can do,
Speaker 5:  cause we, we test files that way. But
Speaker 2:  Yeah. From your perspective, Sonos runs a radio service. You've thought about
Speaker 2:  recurring revenue models and different kinds of descriptions. Is this something
Speaker 2:  that you would light up as well? Okay, we're gonna have a spatial service
Speaker 2:  or we're gonna need to invest in spatial versions of the radio service.
Speaker 4:  Absolutely. You know, I, I think we want to keep making sure that
Speaker 4:  Sonos Radio is there in terms of the best quality. We have the HD service
Speaker 4:  today, so we wanna make sure that we're there. And so that's something we're
Speaker 4:  definitely focused on for the future.
Speaker 2:  Do you think the Air 300 is a new product for Sonos is going to increase
Speaker 2:  the number of social audio listeners? Or do you think you think it's gonna
Speaker 2:  capture a rising trend of people using spatial on their headphones?
Speaker 4:  I believe this is a moment where there's
Speaker 4:  enough energy from the streaming services, from the
Speaker 4:  labels and then with this product that it's going to bring
Speaker 4:  spatial to a whole new set of people. That's why we're doing it.
Speaker 4:  Because we feel like we want to introduce them to spacial in the right way
Speaker 4:  and this is the right way to do it. And so I do expect a whole bunch of people
Speaker 4:  to experience spatial the first time with Air 300.
Speaker 5:  And there's been an interesting shift, sorry to button on, on age groups
Speaker 5:  and listenership in spatial audio, which we see through the record industry
Speaker 5:  of people, you know, leaning in and listening and a new
Speaker 5:  generation of listeners listening to even old catalog. Like there's been
Speaker 5:  a huge boost in, and I think they're gonna wanna know what it sounds like
Speaker 5:  out loud. And the weird thing is that is, until now, I don't
Speaker 5:  believe, you know, there are niche systems, but I think the 300, the era
Speaker 5:  300 does provide, you know, I know it does. From a, from the working
Speaker 5:  with creator and the creator town, it provides a very real Yeah. Way of experiencing
Speaker 5:  it. And I've found personally that I've really
Speaker 5:  enjoying like, exploring music on it. You know, that's the thing. It's like,
Speaker 5:  what a second? You know, it's Miles Davis. It's like, this is cool.
Speaker 5:  It's like he's in my room. I mean, you know, I'm not sure I want Miles Davis
Speaker 5:  in my room, you know, for a long period of time. It's kind of crazy, but
Speaker 5:  it's like, this is great. Know
Speaker 2:  I'm excited for our headline to be in Charles Martin calls HomePod a Niche
Speaker 2:  system. That's gonna be great.
Speaker 5:  That was very clever. Don't
Speaker 14:  Say anything.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna take one more break and then I'm asking Patrick Spence about
Speaker 2:  the future of Sonos and its products.
Speaker 14:  Hey, it's Newel King, co-host of today, explained here. Bye Now. You've
Speaker 14:  heard about Scott Adams, the Dilbert creator and interpreter of polling
Speaker 14:  data.
Speaker 15:  Well, Rasmussen Poll had a provocative little poll today.
Speaker 15:  They said, do you agree or disagree with a statement?
Speaker 15:  It's okay to be white.
Speaker 14:  Who spent a career building a comic empire.
Speaker 16:  It spoke to so many people. It was the comic strip that you would
Speaker 16:  see push pinned onto cubicle walls as sort of
Speaker 16:  the corporate culture was changing. We needed humor to
Speaker 16:  survive that time. And Scott hit it perfectly,
Speaker 14:  Then got pulled from newspapers after a racist tirade. So many questions,
Speaker 14:  including why is Rasmussen asking people if it's okay to be white?
Speaker 17:  It's a really weird thing to ask people. And to
Speaker 17:  be honest, I haven't heard a good explanation for why,
Speaker 14:  But we found answers today. Explained, it's in your feed every weekday at
Speaker 14:  2:00 PM
Speaker 18:  There's a new season of you out on Netflix. And the show's lead
Speaker 18:  says this season he did fewer sex scenes to
Speaker 18:  protect his real life marriage.
Speaker 19:  Meryl Streep's been married a long time. Do I think that every time
Speaker 19:  she's kissed somebody or had sex in a movie, she thinks, I can't believe
Speaker 19:  I get to cheat on my husband right now just so I can win an Oscar. Like
Speaker 19:  no,
Speaker 18:  You and the state of sex on screen plus the writer
Speaker 18:  of Cocaine, bear on Cocaine Bear this
Speaker 18:  week on Intuit Vultures Pop culture podcast.
Speaker 2:  Okay, I'm back with Patrick Spence and Giles Martin. There have
Speaker 2:  more niche systems in the home pod. So nice. Make Soundbars, right? There's
Speaker 2:  a lot of soundbar atmos in this world. There are ways to get Atmos
Speaker 2:  audio into Soundbars. What do you think the difference is if you've got a
Speaker 2:  514 soundbar set up at home or whatever, is this a meaningful
Speaker 2:  upgrade over that? Is it going to be different because it's focused on music
Speaker 2:  first?
Speaker 5:  Well, listen, we, I mean it's been great that ARC has been used as a reference
Speaker 5:  system in studios. I mean, there's, there's an arc and capital. There's an
Speaker 5:  arc and happy road. There's an arc in, you know, we have, we, we've been
Speaker 5:  saying a lot of reference for, for Atmos Music Ark is the main,
Speaker 5:  has been the main reference. Once pros, you know, we start off when we're,
Speaker 5:  when we're doing it, when we're doing home theory, we actually start off
Speaker 5:  with music. Cuz music is much more fragile than home theater. He says
Speaker 5:  Arrogantly being more music. But I actually mix, I mixed film, so I, sorry,
Speaker 5:  I can say that, but you know, you can, there's much more of a,
Speaker 5:  a fragility to music. If a song goes wrong, you hear it more than a, than
Speaker 5:  a film soundtrack going wrong. And Ark has been used for that, but it's not
Speaker 5:  built for that. It's a home theater system first. And by
Speaker 5:  its fit and form, it has to be by it being a, a tube, if you like,
Speaker 5:  to be frank. So yeah, it's like, you know, would I listen to, I
Speaker 5:  personally listen to an Atmos track on Arc, which has been used as a reference
Speaker 5:  system for or for or on ERA 300? Era 300
Speaker 5:  without question, you know, but watching movies arc is great,
Speaker 2:  But that is sort of the default at most experience for most people right
Speaker 2:  now. Whether it's the Arc or another soundbar. Yeah. Is it worth saying I
Speaker 2:  need to put an Air 300 in this room as well?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think people, I think people hear it and, and they say yes, it is.
Speaker 5:  I think the way that, the way the Air 300, and you heard it today even
Speaker 5:  in the curtain room where we, we asked what, what trickery we are up to.
Speaker 5:  I think that the spacial aspect of the, the way it
Speaker 5:  projects discreet audio, which it sounds very real. It's not blurred like
Speaker 5:  a guitar can be on your far right side. Sounds like a guitar. It's kind of
Speaker 5:  amazing, I think. Yeah, I mean, I'd I'd have one. I have one and
Speaker 4:  I think it's the simplicity too, just like, you know, it's a speaker, you
Speaker 4:  know, what's there, you know, it's for music in terms of what's there. The,
Speaker 4:  the, there still is a, seems to be a mental barrier for many people in terms
Speaker 4:  of listening to music in their home theater kind of setup. Right. And so
Speaker 4:  it's another room. Is it the kitchen, a living room, a sitting room, an office,
Speaker 4:  wherever it's going to be. But there's something that screams music
Speaker 4:  about the era 300. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  This is the part where I just start asking you for new products directly.
Speaker 2:  Patrick, where is my receiver with Sonas built in and True play built? Did
Speaker 4:  You see our works with Sona, with Sony that we did the works with Sonos work
Speaker 4:  on their receiver. So there you go.
Speaker 2:  But I still gotta buy another thing I want, I want you to make it, I want
Speaker 2:  you to be responsible for
Speaker 4:  It's, if I can get your updated list, I'm happy to take your updated
Speaker 2:  List. It's still I do, I do feel like I need to end by sort of asking more
Speaker 2:  expansively about Sonos. Yep. Right. There's a big split. Now
Speaker 2:  I listened to your last earnings call before the era 300 was announced. Speaking
Speaker 2:  of the HomePod, you were basically like, yeah, big tech stopped competing
Speaker 2:  with us. There's like nothing on the market that competes with us for a minute
Speaker 2:  there. That seemed like an existential threat, right? The, the big tech players
Speaker 2:  are coming, they were locking the streaming services to various products.
Speaker 2:  Why do you think that threat has passed? And do you, do you see a sort of
Speaker 2:  resurgent moment for Sonos right now?
Speaker 4:  Absolutely. See a resurgent moment, you only have to look at our holiday
Speaker 4:  results. And if you look at what happened over that period, there just wasn't,
Speaker 4:  as I said, a lot interesting happening in the space, right. From anyone,
Speaker 4:  quite frankly where whether legacy or big tech side of it. And so
Speaker 4:  we've always been very focused on how we build this for the long term in
Speaker 4:  a sustainable way. We didn't get caught up in some of the hype around, you
Speaker 4:  know, voice gonna be, voice is gonna be the next, you know, mobile operating
Speaker 4:  system speaker. Exactly. And I think, I think we live in a day and
Speaker 4:  age where very quickly people's attention turn to the new, new thing.
Speaker 4:  We get all fired up about it. It dominates the headlines for three,
Speaker 4:  six months. You, I mean, whether it's voice or whether it's crypto, or
Speaker 4:  whether it's web three or whether it's now ai,
Speaker 2:  Bitcoins on the
Speaker 4:  Speakers, right? And, and so you're Not taking, don't suggestions and, and
Speaker 4:  we, we don't, we try to be, we try to think about what do these things mean
Speaker 4:  for consumers as you think about it, you know, a decade long period. And
Speaker 4:  we continue to innovate in terms of what you see with
Speaker 4:  the ERA 300 and the ERA 100, but products that are gonna last for a long
Speaker 4:  time. And it's never, it's never with an ulterior motive of trying to
Speaker 4:  capture your data or sell you another service or all of these things.
Speaker 4:  And so I think our, you know, clarity of what we do and why we do it,
Speaker 4:  you know, has helped serve us well in competing with, you know, strong legacy
Speaker 4:  audio brands that we had to come from nowhere to, you know,
Speaker 4:  be in the position we are today. And then even when Big Tech jumped in and
Speaker 4:  infringed all of our intellectual property, we could still keep
Speaker 4:  innovating, keep competing, keep growing, and make sure that we would come
Speaker 4:  out stronger. So I think it's a testament to our focus and our commitment
Speaker 4:  to doing what we do really, really well. And I think it shows you that, you
Speaker 4:  know, hopefully it gives hope to other companies that, you know, just because
Speaker 4:  big tech's gonna jump into your space doesn't mean you should, you
Speaker 4:  know, follow what they're doing necessarily. Like if we had, if we had built
Speaker 4:  a, you know, 25 or $50 speaker, I think that would've been a huge
Speaker 4:  mistake, right? And we, and you and I talked about that before. I don't think
Speaker 4:  you respond in that way. You look at where your strengths are, what you need
Speaker 4:  to do, and how do you compete uniquely in that situation and build on your
Speaker 4:  strengths. And ERA 300 is a perfect example of building on our strengths
Speaker 4:  and going after that. And so hopefully this is a bit of a, you know, a
Speaker 4:  inspiration to others that are building their companies and want to compete
Speaker 4:  in an era where we know it's been very difficult with big tech coming in
Speaker 4:  and, you know, jumping into all these new categories.
Speaker 2:  The last time I spoke to you, you did not have the head of sound experience.
Speaker 2:  You had your lawyer, you had your general counsel with you, and we talked
Speaker 2:  about the big tech lawsuit. Yeah. Thank God it wasn't me is all I can say.
Speaker 2:  I think honestly, you guys should switch spots. Yeah, yeah. He's
Speaker 5:  Great on sound. But Eddie is, Eddie
Speaker 2:  Is Eddie is like, what did love, yeah. How many speakers has the lawyer
Speaker 2:  put up before, is it 7,000? Yeah, but no, how, how is the Google lawsuit
Speaker 2:  going? Are you closer to a resolution? We saw the antitrust bills in Congress
Speaker 2:  sort of come to nothing. Yeah. What's going on there?
Speaker 4:  So the spring we have the northern District case, you know,
Speaker 4:  happening. And so we'll see how that all plays out in the fall. We have the
Speaker 4:  Southern District case, which is a, the federal circuit off the back of the
Speaker 4:  ITC that we won very handily. So these things continue to progress through
Speaker 4:  the courts. We're 10 for 10 against Google in terms of their
Speaker 4:  frivolous actions against us to distract and make us spend, you
Speaker 4:  know, money. So we feel good about where we stand
Speaker 4:  today and we're gonna keep fighting for our intellectual property and you
Speaker 4:  know, if people infringe it, we're going to work with
Speaker 4:  them first. But if they, you know, don't come to the table as Google
Speaker 4:  didn't, then we will take it to the courts and, and we, you know, are
Speaker 4:  in a position thankfully because of a lot of hard work and, and everybody's
Speaker 4:  efforts where we are in control of our own destiny. And we can do that. And
Speaker 4:  I feel that it's important for all the inventors at Sonos, but I also feel
Speaker 4:  it's important for society that we stand up
Speaker 4:  in these situations and say, no, you can't go and infringe what somebody
Speaker 4:  else does. And so I have faith that the, you know, the
Speaker 4:  courts will ultimately help us and will prevail
Speaker 2:  Across the spectrum of big tech. It's actually kind of inconsistent how they're
Speaker 2:  supporting this next standard. Apple and Amazon are doing it. Google is
Speaker 2:  not doing it. Spotify, I think most notably is not supporting
Speaker 2:  it yet for any number of reasons. They actually announced like HiFi two
Speaker 2:  years ago. That's right. Today on the day that we're talking and it's come
Speaker 2:  to nothing, are those conversations you're having like, Hey, we're going
Speaker 2:  ahead with spatial audio, this is the future of music. Are you coming along
Speaker 2:  for the ride or are they just missing out?
Speaker 4:  We, we've definitely been out there talking to all of the streaming
Speaker 4:  services trying to rally everyone around this because we believe it will
Speaker 4:  be the future. And people just work on, you know, they have their own roadmaps
Speaker 4:  and timelines and strategic priorities and all of those things, but making
Speaker 4:  the mistake, we've been out there absolutely letting them know Air 300 s
Speaker 4:  coming, trying to get their support, make sure we're all lined up. So yeah,
Speaker 4:  we'll keep doing
Speaker 5:  That. And I think again, experience and and consumer reaction
Speaker 5:  will, will, will decide as well. Sure. I mean also, you know, automotive,
Speaker 5:  which you know, is becoming bigger and special audio and I think,
Speaker 2:  Do you see the Mercedes eClass announced today with Yeah. Built in spatial
Speaker 2:  Did you, did you do the TikTok camera?
Speaker 5:  I didn't do the TikTok
Speaker 2:  Camera. So it has a selfie camera inside of it. You make tos while the car
Speaker 2:  drives itself. This is the entire future of all media is my, is my, this
Speaker 5:  Is, this is becoming desperate. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  The headline was like, supports ATMO from Apple Music and the
Speaker 2:  sub-headline was selfie camera for tos. And I was like, we should flip those.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, we are, we are not putting a selfie cameras for TikTok in anywhere.
Speaker 2:  No, but but you think it's coming to cars, right? I mean every car is had
Speaker 2:  sort of like a fake surround,
Speaker 5:  I think again, the experience has to be good, you know, that's it. It's like,
Speaker 5:  and that's the thing about spatial is that, you know, if you, if it's done
Speaker 5:  right, which I think we've done, then it's a really compelling, it's a really
Speaker 5:  compelling experience and I think companies will get it right, not just us.
Speaker 5:  And that will then shift the consumer
Speaker 5:  experience and therefore that will influence people like Spotify will then,
Speaker 5:  you know, have to come to the table.
Speaker 2:  Do you think there's gonna be a wave of overly
Speaker 2:  aggressive atmo mixes in this period? Because that's
Speaker 2:  what I'm, that's what I
Speaker 5:  See. Aggressive atmos mixes, like, you know, people throwing things at studio
Speaker 5:  walls and stuff like
Speaker 2:  That. Yeah. Just like the guitars are over by the bar unreasonable.
Speaker 5:  Well it's interesting cuz in lockdown I was sort of overseeing
Speaker 5:  spacial audio for and quality control with, with a team of
Speaker 5:  like 50 engineers that were, you know, it was, it was like mixing,
Speaker 5:  mixing, mixing, mixing and yeah, I mean there were times where it was just
Speaker 5:  like, it's like early stereo, you know? Yeah. Early stereo was
Speaker 5:  crazy. And absolutely, I think it settled down, you know, you know,
Speaker 5:  I'm hearing people do mixes now, which are just truly outstanding
Speaker 5:  and not advanced as far as spatial goes. They just sound good. And
Speaker 5:  that's the point, you know? Okay. You, you, I mean, I know from experience,
Speaker 5:  I mean, I've just done, you know, a whole load of big artists Namos,
Speaker 5:  something like the Stones or the Beatles, Loren Stones. You, you don't,
Speaker 5:  Angie, you don't want things flying around your head. It's like acoustic
Speaker 5:  guitar strings and drums and bass and vocal chemical brothers. You want things
Speaker 5:  flying around your head and going through you and hitting you in the face
Speaker 5:  and all that sort of stuff. Yeah. So I think it's, it's music dependent.
Speaker 5:  And that's the great thing about building like an era 300 is that then you
Speaker 5:  should then have that product that realizes that in your space.
Speaker 5:  So for instance, I can put Paul McCarney back in Abbey Road singing
Speaker 5:  Abbey Road and the walls of every rip comes the wall walls of your home.
Speaker 5:  That's super exciting. That's like really compelling. The chemical brothers,
Speaker 5:  you're at Coachella or whatever, it's, you know, so that's just
Speaker 5:  one creator. There are people who are doing amazing things, space shorty,
Speaker 5:  and you talk to creators. We did a, we did a panel in Santa Barbara with
Speaker 5:  a bunch of careers. It was really interesting. And like Manny Marquin who
Speaker 5:  mixes just about everything now, he was like talking about how it freed him
Speaker 5:  up, how spatial it frees him up to thinking about he's, you know, he has
Speaker 5:  to put, you know, mixing Lizzo or something like that. He's having to put
Speaker 5:  everything in his into speakers and now he can open it out. And we just have
Speaker 5:  to represent that in the home.
Speaker 2:  I was definitely complaining about spatial with somebody who knows and they
Speaker 2:  said, what are you doing? Listen, Totto. And I listened totto and I thought
Speaker 2:  this would be amazing if I was on drugs. And that's like the highlight. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It was not yet on drugs. Yeah. Yet I wanna end here. You are the
Speaker 2:  expert trials. I, there's no way I could offer this instruction to our audience.
Speaker 2:  So I wanna ask you for it. We're about to come into a wave of
Speaker 2:  hyper on spatial audio, right? This is, I would say the air 100 is the,
Speaker 2:  the tip of the iceberg in terms of product launches, in terms of hyper on
Speaker 2:  this stuff. In terms of listening at home on not a soundbar,
Speaker 2:  what should people be listening for? How do you listen intelligently to a
Speaker 2:  spatial mix to know that it's any good? It's a, because I think right now
Speaker 2:  everything is just like, like what if it was all around you and I, that doesn't,
Speaker 2:  that doesn't seem like the right answer.
Speaker 5:  Listen to your heart is what I
Speaker 2:  Would say. Yeah, we're done here. That's, no,
Speaker 5:  You know what, you know what, you can dismiss that. But like, you can
Speaker 5:  sit there but, and honestly it's, and it's, and listens from someone who
Speaker 5:  has to analyze sound and like, I have
Speaker 5:  all of this opinion. There's nothing better than someone putting on music
Speaker 5:  and you've being with a friend, listening to it. And it's another question.
Speaker 5:  So in space audio, you can close your eyes and you can think about
Speaker 5:  where everything is, how your room. And this is why I love, don't think about
Speaker 5:  the speak you're listening to. Think about the song you're listening to.
Speaker 5:  And technically for a bunch of different reasons, we can achieve that
Speaker 5:  in the artist space and the product space a lot better with special audio
Speaker 5:  because we can project sound and because we have channels of projection.
Speaker 5:  You know, spatial audio is mal channel, stereo is two channel, mono is one
Speaker 5:  channel. We have this channel camera, we can actually project
Speaker 5:  color on the walls of your home. And that's what you listen listener listen
Speaker 5:  to. But bubble else, just see whether you enjoy it, see whether
Speaker 5:  you dig it. And that's the thing. And it's really interesting. Sometimes
Speaker 5:  you listen to a track and you go, this isn't very spatial, but I'm enjoying
Speaker 5:  it. It doesn't have to be wide for you to enjoy it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And answer it. What's your favorite spatial track?
Speaker 4:  The one I heard from Finns today is, oh my gosh, was incredible. What,
Speaker 4:  I don't know what the name of it is, but it was, it's a new one that Phineas
Speaker 4:  just did. And it is, oh, you've gotta hear it because you feel it. I think
Speaker 4:  that's the thing to me is you absolutely
Speaker 5:  Feel it concert five years from now
Speaker 4:  Concert five years from now. You feel it when you're there and it, it feels
Speaker 4:  like you're somewhere else. Which, you know, I, I'm, I've been in tech long
Speaker 4:  enough to be cynical about all these things and I really do think Giles nailed
Speaker 4:  it with do you feel it fundamentally? And when you close your eyes, what
Speaker 4:  does that feel like? And you know, for what we do, that's about as good as
Speaker 4:  it gets.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well, Patrick Giles, thank you so much for trying us say, this is great.
Speaker 2:  Thank you. We probably talk to you about special audio for another five hours,
Speaker 5:  But I can come back later on
Speaker 2:  Between the Beatles fans Losing their minds and Your Coms, people lose their
Speaker 2:  minds. It's time to go. I'll get
Speaker 5:  The blue rays done guys. Okay, I'll get, I'll
Speaker 20:  Meet them for you. You can just have Blue Rays. So now on.
Speaker 2:  Amazing. That was great. Thank
Speaker 20:  You.
Speaker 2:  That's it for the VER Has today. Thank you for listening. There's a lot more
Speaker 2:  from this conversation@theverge.com. There are links in the show notes, including
Speaker 2:  lots of links to Chris Welch's coverage. These are only leading the charge
Speaker 2:  scooping these speakers. If you have thoughts, feedback, feelings, tips,
Speaker 2:  you can always email us@vercasttheverge.com or you can call the
Speaker 2:  hotline. It's eight six six Verge 11. We may answer a question you have in
Speaker 2:  a future episode. The Vergecast is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James.
Speaker 2:  Brooke Min is our editorial director of Audio Vercast is a Verge
Speaker 2:  production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. We're back on Friday
Speaker 2:  with more of the Verge crew. Talk about whatever is happening in tech this
Speaker 2:  week. We'll see that.