# Transcript
ID: 54daa9e0-a67e-11ed-a9b3-475bf7c17843
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Samsung announces the Galaxy S23 and the Galaxy Book3 Ultra
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/8088303677652882515/343193270682760987/s93290-US-4779s-1675729699.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Richard Lawler, Allison Johnson, and Monica Chin discuss the announcements from Samsung's Galaxy Unpacked event.
Speaker 2:  Today on the Verge cast, Allison Johnson and Monica Chin join us. We'll get
Speaker 2:  into everything from Samsung Galaxy unpacked, and of course all the big tech
Speaker 2:  news this week that's coming up Right after this,
Speaker 4:  When you arrive in the all new Toyota Crown, every entrance
Speaker 4:  becomes a grand one with an available hybrid max
Speaker 4:  powertrain that says you always arrive fashionably on time
Speaker 4:  style that says, emphasis on the fashionably
Speaker 4:  and presence that says you speak softly and
Speaker 4:  everyone listens. Introducing the Toyota Crown, the car that says so
Speaker 4:  much
Speaker 4:  Toyota. Let's go places.
Speaker 6:  This episode is sponsored by TurboTax. TurboTax has
Speaker 6:  experts who can help relieve you from the stress of taxes and follow for
Speaker 6:  you so you can do not taxes. With TurboTax, an expert
Speaker 6:  will do your taxes from start to finish and sharing. Your taxes are done
Speaker 6:  right so you can relax. Feels good to be done with your taxes,
Speaker 6:  right? Come to TurboTax and don't do your taxes. You can visit
Speaker 6:  turbotax.com to learn more. Intuit TurboTax, full service
Speaker 6:  products only video meeting while expert does your taxes required. See
Speaker 6:  guaranteed details at turbotax.com/guarantees.
Speaker 7:  Hello and welcome to the Road, the flagship podcast of loading your
Speaker 7:  dishwasher. Liam,
Speaker 7:  he won't do it. Our producer, Liam just told us this is a true story,
Speaker 7:  that he could spend a full hour talking about how to load a
Speaker 7:  dishwasher the the right way. Now he's, he's roll.
Speaker 7:  He's like rolling farther and farther away from his microphone.
Speaker 7:  If we ever launch a subscription tier of this podcast, it's just gonna be
Speaker 7:  dishwasher tips.
Speaker 1:  I'm here for
Speaker 7:  It. It's gonna be amazing. We have a lot to talk about today. There's apparently
Speaker 7:  a difference between modern dishwashers and older dishwashers.
Speaker 1:  And drying aid is
Speaker 7:  A thing. Drying aid is a thing. It's a blue liquid.
Speaker 8:  The only thing I know is that everyone has their own way of loading a dishwasher.
Speaker 8:  If you are ever going to have a roommate or a partner, make sure that
Speaker 8:  you see how they load a dishwasher first, because I guarantee you won't like
Speaker 8:  it. But
Speaker 1:  Liam's way, the only right way. Yeah, I've been convinced
Speaker 7:  It's true. People say you should talk about money before you get married.
Speaker 7:  You should sit down and be like, all right, here's a picture of a dishwasher.
Speaker 7:  I want you to start free associating and let's see if this is gonna work.
Speaker 7:  By the way, new dishwashers have two propellers. Old ones only have one,
Speaker 7:  which Liam says changes your whole strategy. He's now turned his bat. No,
Speaker 7:  and I always looked at me.
Speaker 1:  If you haven't counted your propellers, what are you even doing? Yeah, why
Speaker 1:  are you,
Speaker 7:  Are you alright? Kranz is on vacation, but we have an all-star
Speaker 7:  lineup here. I'm your friend Eli. Alison Johnson's here. Hey Alison.
Speaker 1:  Hello,
Speaker 7:  Monica Chin.
Speaker 1:  Hey, I'm coming to you live for my very own camera.
Speaker 7:  It's,
Speaker 7:  I, we got some notes that turning on the cameras again
Speaker 7:  just alters our vibe. I agree. Which we know. And now
Speaker 7:  Monica's like it is because now I have my own camera. Richard
Speaker 7:  Lawler's
Speaker 8:  Here. No Nvidia effects.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. What are you doing man? They said,
Speaker 8:  They said it was illegal.
Speaker 7:  You can you we didn't, we didn't give the people the effects last
Speaker 7:  week. We had some technical difficulties. Here's what I'd like you to do.
Speaker 7:  Just turn 'em on randomly throughout the show and
Speaker 7:  we'll see people commit.
Speaker 9:  We'll try and guess.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, we'll try and guess if you're looking directly at the camera or if
Speaker 7:  it's ai power GPU
Speaker 8:  Software, that is my eyes. I guarantee this. None of this has been AI enhanced
Speaker 8:  or written by chat. G P T
Speaker 7:  I would actually, can we get like a chat G P T version of me to host
Speaker 7:  this show? Because I, that would be great. Everyone knows my at this
Speaker 7:  point chat. There's enough training material for chat G P T. It's like he's
Speaker 7:  gonna bitch about atmos and then probably complain about the government and
Speaker 7:  that's the whole show.
Speaker 8:  What's Comcast doing
Speaker 9:  Week? It's G I 2.1 come up.
Speaker 7:  All right there. There is a lot of news this week. There's Samsung
Speaker 7:  Galaxy unpacked 2023. There's new laptops, there's the
Speaker 7:  new S 23 and S 23 Ultra. There there is some news
Speaker 7:  about the government. The government remains hopelessly
Speaker 7:  confused about the second industry and it's earnings. Richard and
Speaker 7:  the news team have been deep in earning season. We had alphabet earnings,
Speaker 7:  we had meta earnings. Mark Zuckerberg said the word efficiency on the meta
Speaker 7:  earnings call 5,000 times in a row. He went from the metaverse
Speaker 7:  to efficiency. So I would say things are, are going
Speaker 7:  strangely at meta. All the stuff. Talk about, let's start with the most important
Speaker 7:  news out of Samsung Galaxy Impact 2023,
Speaker 7:  which was an announcement. And I think that we all agree that this is the
Speaker 7:  most important news, mixed reality partnership between Google,
Speaker 7:  Qualcomm and Samsung.
Speaker 9:  It's a lot of
Speaker 7:  Companies. It's a lot of companies. They announced, it's,
Speaker 7:  the quote was, it's more of a declarative announcement that they will work
Speaker 7:  together on mixed reality in the future. But they are, they would like you
Speaker 7:  to be aware that at some point something will happen.
Speaker 7:  We're aware we're, I mean this was like a big deal, like a middle of the
Speaker 7:  event. Alice, you were in the room. They like stopped the show. They brought
Speaker 7:  on the executives.
Speaker 9:  Oh yeah, yeah. It was a full like Academy Awards
Speaker 9:  moment, you know, like closeups of executives. And then
Speaker 9:  they came on stage and they're like hugging and it
Speaker 9:  accepted speeches. It was so strange. And
Speaker 9:  then like it just instantly brought the vibe down and you could just
Speaker 9:  feel like everyone was suddenly like very confused and bored
Speaker 9:  and, and then Tiara was like, that's it,
Speaker 9:  we're done.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. They're like, we don't have any real plans. I was just gonna read you
Speaker 7:  some of these quotes. Each player is taking a leadership in each category
Speaker 7:  and then we'll be working very closely together across the different
Speaker 7:  categories. Like if I'm an Apple and I'm working on my headset, I'm like
Speaker 7:  shaking in my boots. I'm like, get to work you guys.
Speaker 8:  How is it even possible that they could have so little to announce? I mean
Speaker 8:  like Meta makes a headset that runs on some
Speaker 8:  variation of Android, right? Yeah. Samsung makes the displays that are
Speaker 8:  in the,
Speaker 7:  The Quest too, like in its basic level is a
Speaker 7:  mid-range Android phone you put on your face. Like that's what it is.
Speaker 7:  It has a Qualcomm chip, it has an OLA display. They're just like, it's so
Speaker 7:  tricky. I dunno. Some lenses it's just like bolt this thing in your face.
Speaker 7:  This is the future of all, all reality and it works. It's
Speaker 7:  very convincing. But that's like what it is.
Speaker 8:  And Google has been working on mixed reality hardware for years. They should
Speaker 8:  be able to fake something, right? They should be able to just make something
Speaker 8:  up and have like a shadowy box on stage and say that's,
Speaker 1:  I mean, ripped to the cardboard.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, we're here. Google's k Miyaki when as for common
Speaker 7:  added, we're excited to work with our partners to build a new generation
Speaker 7:  of immersive computing experiences that will further elevate what users can
Speaker 7:  do with Google. This
Speaker 9:  Really sounds like chat. G P T wrote it. If you
Speaker 9:  were like chat G b t, write an announcement.
Speaker 7:  So
Speaker 1:  Here's what, just add announcement in
Speaker 7:  General. Here's, this is what was coming out like here are the three players
Speaker 7:  in the Android ecosystems. Get 'em on stage
Speaker 1:  Together. I'm getting what you're gonna do with Google.
Speaker 7:  It's like, here's, so the reason I bring this up first is one, it's hilarious.
Speaker 7:  Just like fundamentally hilarious that they announced nothing.
Speaker 7:  It's good. It's, I mean, so
Speaker 1:  Now they're
Speaker 7:  All friends. It's, yeah, we're just like that. Yeah, that was the vibe. But
Speaker 7:  two, this was Samsung's first unpacked in person in a long time and like
Speaker 7:  I, I feel like this is a marker of a return to in-person events. Because
Speaker 7:  if you were not in-person and you're like, okay, here's what we're gonna,
Speaker 7:  we're gonna put on press release and we're gonna make a video. Like you would
Speaker 7:  get to the stage where you like hired a video crew to be like, make a video.
Speaker 7:  And the video crew would be like, what is the video about? And then he would
Speaker 7:  not do this.
Speaker 7:  You would stop, but you're in person. You're like, all right, we got everybody
Speaker 7:  together. Like the Google executive's gonna be here, the Qualcom, let's just
Speaker 7:  get him on stage. Right? Let's just take a couple minutes, throw 'em up there
Speaker 7:  and be like, we love each other. We got something coming. Watch out Meta
Speaker 7:  and then bail. And that's more or less exactly what happened.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, that was it. It was like that's the
Speaker 7:  Show Everyone's looking for the moment that they think the pandemic was over.
Speaker 7:  And I'm telling you it's, it's this kind of nonsense tech company
Speaker 7:  announcement that like we didn't, it didn't happen in the pandemic cuz you
Speaker 7:  couldn't, you couldn't take the next step.
Speaker 9:  Someone would've been like, no, let's not,
Speaker 1:  Let's condense this a little bit. The producer in the back let's
Speaker 7:  Like, like, like the grammar checker reporter is like, this is too many
Speaker 7:  extra words. Just like get rid of these. All right,
Speaker 7:  so that's that announcement. I'm confident that Apple's reality
Speaker 7:  OS team is panicking right now at the future
Speaker 7:  mixed reality efforts from Google, Qualcomm and Samsung. But there was
Speaker 7:  actual news, some really good stuff I would say. I mean I, I've got the two
Speaker 7:  of you here. The laptops perhaps more interesting than
Speaker 7:  the phones.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I think that's fair. That rarely happens. Yeah, because of my moment.
Speaker 1:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  This is shy like, like you got your own camera kid.
Speaker 7:  Let's get out there. Let's start with, let's start with a laptop WAN
Speaker 7:  book three Ultra It, you know, looks like a MacBook Pro but it
Speaker 7:  Samsung's pushing it this year with
Speaker 1:  This stuff. Samsung's pushing it. So there are five new models
Speaker 1:  which you know, everyone was a little overwhelmed when they saw there were
Speaker 1:  five until I explained to them that four of them are very boring and really
Speaker 1:  only one of them we care about. So there are
Speaker 1:  two Galaxy Books Pro and there are two Galaxy Books Pro
Speaker 1:  360 and then there's a Galaxy Book Ultra, which is like this
Speaker 1:  whole other thing. It starts at 2399. It has an RTX 30 50
Speaker 1:  or an RTX 30 70 gpu. It can have a core I seven or a core I nine
Speaker 1:  or 13th Gen Intel H series. They have
Speaker 1:  2 28 80 by 1800, 120 Hertz OLA displays.
Speaker 1:  It looks a lot like it's trying to beat the
Speaker 1:  MacBook Pro. It is a hundred dollars cheaper for the base model, which if
Speaker 1:  you're shopping at that price point is not that much cheaper. It's a pretty
Speaker 1:  similar price. It's hard to say that it's targeting the exact same audience
Speaker 1:  because a big part of this Samsung laptops
Speaker 1:  appeal is that it's for Samsung people who really like Samsung and it has
Speaker 1:  all these things with the Samsung phone, but it seems a little bit like it's
Speaker 1:  trying to do the same thing that you see on the Apple side where they have
Speaker 1:  all these different ways that the phone interacts with it. They have like
Speaker 1:  Samsung apps in Windows similarly to how they're like
Speaker 1:  iOS icons right now on my MacBook screen.
Speaker 7:  Wait what iOS icons on your MacBook screen?
Speaker 1:  Well like, you know, they have consistently been making the icons
Speaker 1:  more like the I counterparts over the past few releases.
Speaker 7:  You're not one of like the few people running iOS?
Speaker 1:  Absolutely. No God no.
Speaker 1:  Let's clear that up right away. Yeah, so they,
Speaker 1:  it's for the past few years the Galaxy Book line has been
Speaker 1:  this really like lightweight line. Like they're super, super light, they
Speaker 1:  have really nice screens and those are sort of like the two things about
Speaker 1:  them. Like they're really light, they have really nice screens. They're kind
Speaker 1:  of like, I guess the, the best use case I'm usually able to like
Speaker 1:  cobble together is like, you really wanna watch Netflix on the train. Like
Speaker 1:  it's in like that kind of thing. This is the first one we've seen in a couple
Speaker 1:  years that really is like, hey instead of buying the MacBook maybe you should
Speaker 1:  buy this now I have no idea how that's gonna go. But yeah, the
Speaker 1:  Galaxy Book three Ultra seems like it's, it's sort of a play for that
Speaker 7:  Category. So last week we were talking about the MacBook Pros with M
Speaker 7:  two PRO chips. I believe you made this comparison and then you immediately
Speaker 7:  apologize for making the comparison. The GPU performance was like a 30 60.
Speaker 7:  Yeah
Speaker 1:  70 37
Speaker 7:  Of the max on the max. So the M two max GP
Speaker 7:  performance, bad direct comparison but rough analog 30
Speaker 7:  70. Yeah this is an actual RTX 40 70.
Speaker 1:  40 70 or 40 50. Yeah. And we don't know how much the
Speaker 1:  40 70 model's gonna cost. We, there are a ton. We don't know how well it's
Speaker 1:  gonna perform. There are a ton of things we don't know in particular. We
Speaker 1:  don't know how good the battery life is gonna be and that is a
Speaker 1:  big question mark both because of the chips and because of the display resolution,
Speaker 1:  which is high because Intel doesn't have like the greatest track record with
Speaker 1:  having great battery life in the past year because Windows
Speaker 1:  machines with discrete GPUs really don't have good track records. Yeah. With
Speaker 1:  having any kind of battery life whatsoever.
Speaker 7:  So, or any kind of thermal management
Speaker 1:  Or any kind of thermal management. We have had some horror stories this past
Speaker 1:  year of laptops that have done discrete GPUs and done each series
Speaker 1:  processors and tried to be thin and have just like been blazing
Speaker 1:  fireballs that died after two hours. So, you know,
Speaker 1:  will this be able to overcome that Will we'll have to see.
Speaker 1:  I hope they can. Am I super optimistic at the
Speaker 1:  outset? No, I'm curious. I think it's ambitious what they're doing
Speaker 1:  but I'm, you know, I'm interested to see whether they can pull it
Speaker 7:  Off. So one of the, the things that is kind of interesting about Samsung
Speaker 7:  right now is they don't really own an operating system.
Speaker 7:  Like there's ties in. Yeah. Which runs on washing
Speaker 7:  machines and televisions. Right. That's great. Dishwashers,
Speaker 7:  I'm sure Liam. Liam do you have any opinions on dishwasher operating
Speaker 7:  systems?
Speaker 1:  Dishwasher ties in
Speaker 7:  Just mid middling
Speaker 1:  Ambivalent on dishwasher operating systems.
Speaker 7:  But you know they don't own Android and they've skinneded Android to Hellen.
Speaker 7:  Back to Google Chag. It was actually, this is the first Samsung event in
Speaker 7:  a long time where they actually made reference to Google existing
Speaker 7:  in any direct way, like putting them on station. Like here's a thing, announcement's
Speaker 7:  one thing. Even just mentioning that they exist is not normal for Samsung.
Speaker 7:  Right.
Speaker 9:  Yeah that was, it was unusual. I mean I saw
Speaker 9:  Deeter, I was like, what are you doing here? Like an agent, a
Speaker 9:  spy
Speaker 7:  Google spy.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But they, you know, they don't own Windows obviously. Is
Speaker 7:  is do we have like a analog to de and Microsoft don't answer that
Speaker 7:  question
Speaker 7:  but they're building this connectivity between those two by heavily
Speaker 7:  skinny and modifying these operating systems. Is it worthwhile?
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I mean I was at, one of the things that surprised me was how easy this
Speaker 1:  stuff was to set up. Like cuz I assume like sometimes when
Speaker 1:  you have to set up like fancy windows stuff, it takes, it's just this
Speaker 1:  whole thing. You have to open up, you have to download all this stuff. You
Speaker 1:  have to like open up 17 different things and it doesn't work the first time
Speaker 1:  and it crashes. And that, I've had that experience many times setting up
Speaker 1:  different connectivity features. For example, razor,
Speaker 1:  this actually worked very well. We set up the QuickShare feature which
Speaker 1:  allows you to like drag files from the
Speaker 1:  computer to the tablet or to the Galaxy phone. We
Speaker 1:  set up second screen which lets you use the Galaxy tab as like a
Speaker 1:  external monitor like next to it, which like is kind of slow but works
Speaker 1:  and it was all like a one click thing and it worked pretty well. It seems
Speaker 1:  like something that could be useful, like if you're a real like Samsung
Speaker 1:  nerd who has all the Samsung stuff, which like I know some people like that
Speaker 1:  and I think it's, I think it could be beneficial. It seems
Speaker 1:  like something could be handy and it doesn't seem like it would be too much
Speaker 1:  of a pain. Which is a really nice thing to be saying about like
Speaker 1:  a Windows laptop using third party software to try to do
Speaker 1:  fancy things. That's like a refreshing thing to say.
Speaker 7:  We got an email from our reader over the weekend and had the word Bixby
Speaker 7:  in it and I was like expecting to get a note every now and again we get a
Speaker 7:  note from somebody who loves Bixby. But instead the note was about somebody
Speaker 7:  who had gone to their local animal hospital and a dog named Bixby had come
Speaker 7:  to the animal hospital and that's,
Speaker 7:  that's as much success as Bixby has ever had was gonna the
Speaker 7:  hospital.
Speaker 1:  That's the most favorable email that's ever been sent about Bixby
Speaker 7:  Too. I saw. And I thank you for that email and if you ever run
Speaker 7:  into dogs' names Bixby, please let us know. It's very important to me
Speaker 7:  personally. But that kind of like cross layer,
Speaker 7:  combine the phone and the laptop, that's what Samsung needs to compete
Speaker 7:  with Apple.
Speaker 1:  I think so. And I think there's also, it's, it's a similar
Speaker 1:  sort of philosophy to what I think Apple has been pursuing over the
Speaker 1:  past couple years with various releases of Mac os. Where it's
Speaker 1:  not only, it's been trying to make it just look more like iOS
Speaker 1:  not only in the way you use it, but just like in the way it looks. I think
Speaker 1:  even in the expense of some like functionality to some extent, like where
Speaker 1:  they put the control center now and like how the settings now look like
Speaker 1:  the iOS settings and not how like system permits used to look. And I think
Speaker 1:  you see this a little bit on these Samsung laptops, the way that they like
Speaker 1:  lay out the task bar and the way
Speaker 1:  that some of the UI and these Samsung apps look like, it looks to me
Speaker 1:  as close as like it could to
Speaker 1:  using a Galaxy phone as a computer. Like it kind of feels like you're just
Speaker 1:  putting the Galaxy stuff and blowing it up on a bigger screen. Which like,
Speaker 1:  you know, it's it, if you're a person who's really used the Samsung interface,
Speaker 1:  maybe that's a thing you like, on the other hand I hear from Samsung people
Speaker 1:  who use Samsung phones all the time that often like the Samsung apps are
Speaker 1:  not the number one thing about them. So, which is like not, which is a little
Speaker 1:  bit different from using Apple where like those, a lot of those apps tell
Speaker 1:  you use all the time so
Speaker 7:  Well because Apple prohibits you from using any other apps. Right?
Speaker 1:  So
Speaker 7:  Richard here Windows person is this, is this laptop calling your name?
Speaker 8:  This is, it's interesting. It it's it, as you said, it looks like a MacBook.
Speaker 8:  My main question is I'm looking at the hardware, you know, it's got the olet
Speaker 8:  it, this, this is a touchscreen of course. Right? Or at least you can't get
Speaker 8:  it with Touchscreen
Speaker 1:  Ultra I don't think is
Speaker 8:  Oh it's not. Well you, I I look at it and I, I wonder
Speaker 8:  if, if your Apple and you're looking at Samsung's laptop that they've put
Speaker 8:  together, they've put together this, oh let's green, it's got this, you know,
Speaker 8:  best in class sort of GPU CPU power. Is this
Speaker 8:  why we're looking at a 2020 five-ish MacBook Pro that's gonna
Speaker 8:  have at least some of these things and we, we presume probably more, more
Speaker 8:  GPU power and o and OED screen. Is that, is that that part of why
Speaker 8:  they're, they're inspired to change. Maybe they're looking at this and seeing
Speaker 8:  that some people might switch. I don't, I don't think most people would switch
Speaker 8:  from when, from Mac to Windows you once you've made your choice here and
Speaker 8:  there. Yeah. But you start to look at these things. Would would people say,
Speaker 8:  would people see that Olded screen and think actually that's a little better
Speaker 8:  than the laptop I have?
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's interesting. I, my sense is
Speaker 1:  that Apple's a a big advantage of
Speaker 1:  what, of like what the new MacBook Pro 16
Speaker 1:  brings like is the combination of power and efficiency that it has.
Speaker 1:  Like it's not just that it's super powerful cause like we know we're gonna
Speaker 1:  have laptops in possibly including this one next year that like are very
Speaker 1:  competitive with it on power. But currently this laptop is bring this Mac
Speaker 1:  laptop. It's like bringing efficiency that just like no one else is bringing.
Speaker 1:  And those two things in combination are what really make it stand out. Not
Speaker 1:  like one of those things or the other. And I think the,
Speaker 1:  I just don't know about the efficiency on the Galaxy book. I think a big
Speaker 1:  advantage the Galaxy Book does have over the MacBook is that it's a lot more
Speaker 1:  portable. It's like, it's around a pound lighter I think than the M two
Speaker 1:  max MacBook and it's a little bit less than a pound lighter than the M two
Speaker 1:  Pro MacBook. But it's a lot. I would much rather have it in my backpack than
Speaker 1:  have like this chunky thing in my
Speaker 7:  Backpack. But then you have to take a battery with
Speaker 1:  You. Right. So that's the question though is how much is the portability
Speaker 1:  that the Galaxy Book has like mitigated by the fact that it's, it might
Speaker 1:  have no battery and therefore like what's the point of bringing it anywhere?
Speaker 1:  And that is something that I think, I mean if I were Apple right now, I would,
Speaker 1:  I would wanna know how well it's doing there before I know whether to
Speaker 1:  be scared. Because I do think that that is a big advantage that potentially
Speaker 1:  Samsung could eat into. But I don't know if it's gonna, I'm not optimistic
Speaker 1:  that it's necessarily gonna do that on that front. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  I think so the potential appeal of this laptop is a bit limited by kind of
Speaker 8:  everything I know about Windows laptops in general. So, so that, that's a
Speaker 8:  downside even for me. But
Speaker 7:  It does have an Nvidia chip in it. So you can run NVIDIA's eye
Speaker 7:  tracking software
Speaker 1:  That's
Speaker 7:  True on it directly, which is critical.
Speaker 7:  He hasn't turned it on yet. I'm, so I'm gonna get you to turn it on by the
Speaker 7:  end of the show. There's more laptops, there's just the regular Galaxy Books.
Speaker 7:  What's going on there?
Speaker 1:  So these are just, these are basically chip bumps. So these are more of the,
Speaker 1:  we've reviewed a bunch of these before. They are the Galaxy Book Pro and
Speaker 1:  the Galaxy of Pro 360, the Galaxy Book Pro 360 is,
Speaker 1:  they are kind of some of the few like 15 inch convertibles that are left
Speaker 1:  on the market. They are some of them, but convertibles in general have gotten
Speaker 1:  like a lot, there've been a lot fewer those released in recent years. And
Speaker 1:  we're seeing more people go for the sort of surface pro esque form factor
Speaker 1:  with their quote unquote convertible options instead. And when I ask companies
Speaker 1:  about that, they all just say like, oh, like no one's buying convertibles.
Speaker 7:  Oh no one puts their their computer in TP mode.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, no one wants to just have it as a tent on their, in their kitchen while
Speaker 1:  they're cooking or whatever. They put in the video advertise mode, not
Speaker 7:  Team mode, tent mode. Please don't cancel me for that.
Speaker 1:  There used to be a, a Dell XBS 15 convertible. There's not that
Speaker 1:  in the same form factor anymore. There used to be, there used to be a bunch
Speaker 1:  of convertible think pads that are now just clamshells. Those are not totally
Speaker 1:  govers, solely falling out fashion. This is still the Galaxo Pro 360.
Speaker 1:  Like one option you might go for if you're one of the like 12 people who
Speaker 1:  like really wants like a big screen thing that can flip around into a tent,
Speaker 1:  that's for
Speaker 7:  You. So you're gonna find it. That's, that's a good Samsung is for though
Speaker 7:  is like very hyper-specific niche products.
Speaker 1:  They have spen support, which is I think pretty crucial
Speaker 1:  if you have a, have a convertible, like you wanna be able to write on it.
Speaker 1:  And otherwise, I think the big upgrade here in addition to the processor
Speaker 1:  is that the screens have gotten a lot better. So one of the things that I
Speaker 1:  didn't like about the Galaxy Book lines of last year and the year before
Speaker 1:  was that they like very stubbornly stuck to the 16 by nine screen
Speaker 1:  and like Samsung's like a company that's known for making
Speaker 1:  good displays, like the displays should be like a huge draw of these panels.
Speaker 1:  And like before they just weren't, cuz they were fhd, they were 16 by nine.
Speaker 1:  So they've gotten a huge upgrade here. They have the 120 hertz,
Speaker 1:  they're calling it three K, but it's 20 80, 1800. There's no three
Speaker 1:  in there. They're not doing that. Yeah. And it,
Speaker 1:  so these, these
Speaker 7:  Are you any other odd numbered Ks?
Speaker 1:  There's not Yeah, one
Speaker 7:  K if you're gonna make up a K's,
Speaker 1:  I mean 5k.
Speaker 7:  Alright, five 5k. But there's only one that has
Speaker 7:  ever been 5k. Like an odd numbered K means you're off on your own.
Speaker 7:  Yes. You're just like off in the
Speaker 1:  No man here, there be Dragons.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's like, oh, I got a 5K display. It's like, yeah, you made a weird
Speaker 7:  choice.
Speaker 1:  Whatever. Yeah. So these are quote unquote three K displays a
Speaker 1:  lot of K's, three whole K's. But they, they look, they look very nice
Speaker 1:  and I, I think previously it was sort of hard to figure out like
Speaker 1:  where these might stand out, like what their niche might be. The big thing
Speaker 1:  was that they were super light. There's like now one more thing to like make
Speaker 1:  them stand out a little bit more, which is that they have the super nice
Speaker 1:  screen whether this will make these into MacBook competitors. I I
Speaker 1:  not
Speaker 7:  Saying is that just like all the, always the frame because Richard's point
Speaker 7:  that people don't switch back and forth, it's like more or less been true
Speaker 7:  for 30 years. Sure. Right.
Speaker 1:  I think, I mean I think that a question I get
Speaker 1:  from people a lot is like, I would buy the MacBook Air, but I'm like not
Speaker 1:  an out person. What's the MacBook Air alternative? And I think
Speaker 1:  that's kind of a currently kind of a power vacuum. Like there are
Speaker 1:  lots of different models that could vy for that, that MacBook Air alternative
Speaker 1:  spot. We didn't like have a decisive one last year. I said it was probably
Speaker 1:  a Zen book, but like it was so hard to get a MD powered things
Speaker 1:  last year that it was hard to recommend. Like this is one you could get that
Speaker 1:  you could definitely buy. I think this is, these are probably going for that
Speaker 1:  error pro alternative slot. They're super, super light. They're really portable.
Speaker 1:  Generally they have pretty good battery life, which is like a big thing that
Speaker 1:  was lacking a lot of models last year that we really look for when naming
Speaker 1:  that, that contender. So whether these will be the best
Speaker 1:  one. See they are usually pretty good, but they're also, because they're
Speaker 1:  so niche, because like they're really, the thing about them is they're super
Speaker 1:  light and they have good displays and that's not, like, that doesn't necessarily
Speaker 1:  lend itself to a big mainstream demographic that I'd broadly recommended
Speaker 1:  for. So we'll see, we'll hope to hope to review these. But
Speaker 1:  I, I think that Samsung is by making these big
Speaker 1:  display improvements, is kind of trying to improve in the
Speaker 1:  place that they as Samsung are best able to improve them.
Speaker 1:  And I, I think that's probably
Speaker 7:  Stuck, right? I mean they're stuck with Intel's chips and Intel is having
Speaker 7:  like a disaster run. Yeah. Andy doesn't have supply like, well
Speaker 7:  they're like, all right screens. We own the screen factory. We'll do
Speaker 7:  screens.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it's that. And the big thing they're pushing is the added continuity
Speaker 1:  features, which is sort of the other thing that they are best able to control.
Speaker 1:  The big speed, the big,
Speaker 7:  The Bigby
Speaker 1:  Experience. Like there's all these, the press release was like 75%. Like
Speaker 1:  here are all the ways you can use this with your Samsung phone, which you
Speaker 1:  could already do last year. We're just gonna repeat them. And then the last
Speaker 1:  paragraph was like, and also their new new display. This
Speaker 7:  Number, there's a laptop connection to this actually. Let's talk about Intel
Speaker 7:  just broadly for one minute. These are launching into a market
Speaker 7:  that basically is seen all the upgrades that are gonna happen,
Speaker 7:  all happen last year instead is, is this like, this just seems like
Speaker 7:  the weirdest time to do laptops,
Speaker 1:  Right? It's a weird time. Apples M two chips are really, really good.
Speaker 1:  Everyone else is really trying to make chips that are that good. We don't
Speaker 1:  know what's going on with AM MD supply. We hope it'll have supply. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  we don't know. We hope Intel will fix its battery life. We prob
Speaker 1:  we hope Intel will
Speaker 7:  To fix its
Speaker 1:  Company. We hope Intel will fix its company. There's lots of things we hope.
Speaker 1:  I think I within the next month or so, we'll we'll have some
Speaker 1:  answers. I hope so. But right now it's a lot of
Speaker 1:  crossed fingers that people can figure stuff out.
Speaker 7:  When do we expect to get these in info reviews?
Speaker 1:  I would hope the ultra they have not given us release date, but I would hope
Speaker 1:  it'll be soon. I keep asking it
Speaker 7:  Before or after the vaporware mixed reality headset.
Speaker 7:  Who
Speaker 1:  Can, who can
Speaker 7:  Say
Speaker 7:  I can't get over it. All right, we gotta take a break. We'll come back and
Speaker 7:  talk about the S 23, S 23 plus S 23 Ultra.
Speaker 7:  Are there more? S 20 threes Allison? That's it. That's it. All right.
Speaker 7:  At least three S 20 threes. We'll see if Samsung announces another one while
Speaker 7:  we take this break. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Today's episode is sponsored by Aura. Here's the riddle. What's the point
Speaker 2:  of a sleep tracker if it's so bulky that wearing it keeps you awake? Lots
Speaker 2:  of stuff is trackable these days. Your heart rate, your steps, but you're
Speaker 2:  only gonna get something out of that data if you have a device you actually
Speaker 2:  want to wear. But the Aura Ring gives you personalized health insights, all
Speaker 2:  from a comfortable to wear water resistant ring during the daytime. The ring
Speaker 2:  sensor technology tracks, heart rate, calories burned, and your activity
Speaker 2:  levels. And then at night it tracks info on your body temperature,
Speaker 2:  sleep quality, respiration rate, and more. You get all that personalized
Speaker 2:  data in the OR app so you can work on building healthy habits.
Speaker 2:  Ordering was nice enough to send me one to try and my favorite thing about
Speaker 2:  it is it just disappears. I forget I'm even wearing it. One small ring could
Speaker 2:  make a world of difference in your health. Visit ora
Speaker 2:  ring.com/verge to find the right ring for you and get $15
Speaker 2:  off your purchase. That's ora ring.com/verge. Don't
Speaker 2:  forget to use your link to save $15 on your Ora ring.
Speaker 10:  Mint Mobile offers premium wireless for just 15 bucks a month. That means
Speaker 10:  spending a little less money on your phone bill and a little more for online
Speaker 10:  shopping, probably on your phone. All plans come with unlimited talk
Speaker 10:  and text. Plus high-speed data. You can use your own phone with any
Speaker 10:  Mint Mobile plan and switch easily in minutes with SEM to
Speaker 10:  get your new wireless plan for just 15 bucks a month and get the plan shipped
Speaker 10:  to your door for free, go to mint
Speaker 10:  mobile.com/box. That's mint
Speaker 10:  mobile.com/vox.
Speaker 7:  All right, we're back. Alison and Chrisman, we have not really talked about
Speaker 7:  this event, really their first in-person event in a long
Speaker 7:  time. You were there. What was the vibe?
Speaker 9:  It was, I mean it was full on, there was, you know,
Speaker 9:  the lights, the stage, it was a pretty big venue,
Speaker 9:  the Masonic Auditorium, which had a bunch of QR codes
Speaker 9:  that said like, understand more about free masonry. And then that kinda
Speaker 9:  weirded me out. I didn't, I did not scan any of
Speaker 9:  those.
Speaker 7:  Stand here for the Illuminati. It's good.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I avoided that. No, it was really
Speaker 9:  kind of high energy, really high production.
Speaker 9:  It felt, and I haven't been to a Samsung event in the past,
Speaker 9:  but you know, apple was pretty subdued and Google
Speaker 9:  Pixel was like very small and subdued.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. And this was like, we're going all out Samsung.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. So
Speaker 7:  Did they have any Broadway dancers? There
Speaker 9:  Were no dancing. Oh
Speaker 7:  No. There was a time when like Samsung would be like full on like, here's
Speaker 7:  a cast of Billy Elliot, they're gonna dance about phones. Like truly some
Speaker 7:  of the strangest events in my entire life occurred.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Okay. Maybe it was restrained then, because this is like
Speaker 9:  Samsung warming up too. They didn't have
Speaker 10:  Doors flying off their hinges at people
Speaker 9:  In the
Speaker 7:  Video. Yeah, like Apple has a vibe because they do their events
Speaker 7:  on their campus and like, you know, they play the, the, the
Speaker 7:  new age music as you're walking up to the thing. Like every Apple event
Speaker 7:  immediately starts with the energy of you might be raptured,
Speaker 7:  right? And like you can't touch, like the whole place is basically a museum.
Speaker 7:  You're like, not a lot like it just, there's an energy to an Apple event
Speaker 7:  that's very specific. Google is like, I dunno, should we be quirky
Speaker 7:  goofballs or not? Like, you know, like here our house. And then Samsung
Speaker 7:  has always just been like glitz, like pure glitz. Like Vegas
Speaker 7:  occurs with Samsung. So it's good to see they're all kind of like returning
Speaker 7:  to form. Yeah. In their way
Speaker 9:  I think. So this, yeah, this was, this was a full,
Speaker 9:  full on deal and, and they started
Speaker 9:  right off with the, the ultra and stuck with
Speaker 9:  that for a long time. Like
Speaker 9:  I was even like, wow, okay, I've, I've heard a lot about this at
Speaker 9:  this point. They got so deep into the camera stuff. I was
Speaker 9:  really surprised. Yeah. I made the mistake of writing in an
Speaker 9:  article that was on the verge.com. They will not say the words
Speaker 9:  full well capacity on stage. I was like, you know, there's cool things
Speaker 9:  happening with smartphone cameras, but they're just, they're boring. Like
Speaker 9:  you can't put them in a presentation. And they frigging said
Speaker 9:  full well
Speaker 7:  Capacity. They read your piece,
Speaker 9:  They, gosh. And I was like,
Speaker 7:  Like scrolling off stage. Yeah. Did this in here. The prompter
Speaker 9:  She'll really hate it.
Speaker 7:  So yeah. Okay, let's talk about this camera. They said ni
Speaker 7:  again, it's a 200 megapixel camera.
Speaker 7:  It uses all of those pixels in different configurations based on
Speaker 7:  lighting from what I understand, or ambient light conditions. What's going
Speaker 7:  on here?
Speaker 9:  So yeah, there really is, there really is the big story of
Speaker 9:  all three of these devices. It's, it's only the S 23 Ultra that has this
Speaker 9:  200 megapixel camera. But it's, it's really interesting.
Speaker 9:  There's, you know, there's other improvements in the camera system. There's
Speaker 9:  like the optical image stabilization is supposedly a little better.
Speaker 9:  There's a new selfie camera, all those little like tweaks and things
Speaker 9:  they do every year. But the new sensor
Speaker 9:  is really interesting cuz like, you don't need 200 megapixels.
Speaker 9:  Like nobody, nobody needs 200 megapixels. But that's not really
Speaker 9:  the point. It's like, like you said, it's doing, it's doing pixel binning
Speaker 9:  in kind of different configurations. It can do, you know, four by
Speaker 9:  four or 16 pixels, you know,
Speaker 9:  all grouped together to give you like the imitation of a bigger
Speaker 9:  pixel and in low light conditions. So
Speaker 9:  better light sensitivity, better photos in theory.
Speaker 9:  I'm gonna check it out. I, I took one 200 megapixel photos so
Speaker 9:  far and that's a lot of pixels.
Speaker 7:  You have to explain what full forewell capacity means at this point. My god
Speaker 7:  time. My god. We're all the way here. You started there. You gotta clo gotta
Speaker 7:  finish it out.
Speaker 9:  So the thing is like the pixels are so tiny on
Speaker 9:  this thing. It's like 0.6 micrometers.
Speaker 9:  When the pixels are so small it's, there's just a level at which
Speaker 9:  they like can't capture any more light. They just, they're like
Speaker 9:  done full and you get, you get
Speaker 9:  oversaturation like blooming and and ugly stuff in your photos.
Speaker 9:  They figured out a way to do some magic that
Speaker 9:  I don't really understand and increase the capacity, the full
Speaker 9:  well capacity of the individual pixels.
Speaker 9:  So that's everything I know about full well capacity.
Speaker 7:  So they, they spend a lot of time on the camera and it's not just,
Speaker 7:  it's better low light performance or less noisy performance. Right. They're
Speaker 7:  they're trying to do a lot of additional things with the sensor.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Yeah. And it's, I I guess dynamically,
Speaker 9:  you know, changing between, you know, you're always gonna get a 12
Speaker 9:  megapixel image when you're in 12 megapixel mode. But
Speaker 9:  behind the scenes it's doing some different things with those
Speaker 9:  pixels and binning or using more of them if you're in
Speaker 9:  good light. Yeah. Just kind of, kind of cranking up the
Speaker 9:  computational photography. Just that extra notch. And there's
Speaker 9:  just, there's other stuff that's really interesting that's coming out. There's
Speaker 9:  this app you can download called Camera Assistant and
Speaker 9:  it gets like really granular in the stuff that it gives you a bunch
Speaker 9:  more controls on the camera. It's, I believe for
Speaker 9:  S 23 and the S 22 series. But you can like,
Speaker 9:  you can override when it would switch from like
Speaker 9:  if you're using the telephoto lens in low light, it would typically switch
Speaker 9:  to the main camera and just digital Zoom cuz there's not enough light. You
Speaker 9:  can override that and you can be like, no, I want you to stick with the telephoto
Speaker 9:  all the time. It's like maybe a bad choice, but you can do that.
Speaker 7:  Bixby now lets you make bad choices. It's like, yeah.
Speaker 9:  You're
Speaker 7:  Like, that's can I have another drink? And Bixby is like, you can,
Speaker 9:  Right. Should you,
Speaker 7:  Yeah, we're not, we're not gonna stop you. Yeah. Like
Speaker 7:  Samsungs vibe all right.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. They're like, here you go. You wanna mess up your pictures,
Speaker 9:  you can do it
Speaker 7:  That level of control. Right. Samsung has sort of always offered it.
Speaker 7:  Is it, are they making the main camera app simpler? Because usually you would
Speaker 7:  just like offload that stuff to make the main experience way simpler.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Yeah. And it is, it is like you have to go download it
Speaker 9:  and then all those settings will appear in the camera app
Speaker 9:  like settings. So yeah, they, they're trying to keep it like,
Speaker 9:  okay, you don't wanna do the deep dive, you don't wanna get it in the weeds.
Speaker 9:  Like you can just use this camera. But yep. It's kind of cool.
Speaker 7:  Is that the big feature of the Ultra? Is there anything else going on there?
Speaker 7:  They squared it off a little bit, which looks nice.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Oh I, yeah, I like it. Maybe I just, I
Speaker 9:  spend too much time like holding phones and thinking about them.
Speaker 9:  I'm like welcome
Speaker 7:  To the verse
Speaker 9:  Cast. Oh my gosh. Yeah. I'm like, if I, I
Speaker 9:  sound crazy when I try and explain it. I'm like, well it's like a tiny
Speaker 9:  bit more flat on the sides and my husband's like, this is
Speaker 7:  Probably the one place. But that's
Speaker 1:  A big feel. Cause I feel like all the only thing I associate these phones
Speaker 1:  with basically, or the big thing I did was like how round they were on the
Speaker 1:  sides. Like, like super
Speaker 9:  Round. It sucks. You're like, and cuz you're trying to use a
Speaker 9:  pen and it like keeps going over the edge. Right. Cuz it's like an infinity
Speaker 9:  pool of screen. So yeah, they, the sides are a
Speaker 9:  little more squared off this time. I like it. I think it looks kind of fancy.
Speaker 9:  I like the cream color. Twitter's yelling me about how they
Speaker 9:  don't like cream color, but I'll die on that hill.
Speaker 7:  I mean at this point Twitter's just like a collection of like Elon in his
Speaker 7:  spots. Yeah. Like Elon doesn't like cream and like that's Twitter.
Speaker 9:  There's just a whole bunch of bots are yelling at me.
Speaker 7:  $1,200 is crazy for this phone.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Which is the same as last year. So at this point
Speaker 9:  we're like, well it didn't get more expensive so that's good. But you do
Speaker 9:  get a higher storage capacity at the
Speaker 9:  base model. It's 256 now for 1199.
Speaker 9:  So that's good. But other things I didn't mention, there's
Speaker 9:  across the whole series there's a new, there's obviously a new Snap Dragon
Speaker 9:  eight gen two processor. It's like technically a
Speaker 9:  very slightly different version that's like special for
Speaker 9:  Samsung. It has just kind of like a higher
Speaker 9:  performance ceiling
Speaker 7:  Has no, it has a name. I'm just gonna read the name. The name is Snapdragon
Speaker 7:  eight gen two for Galaxy.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. It's
Speaker 1:  Like similar to Microsoft's like little fancy Microsoft processors they have
Speaker 1:  in all their surface books. No, it's four
Speaker 7:  Microsoft. Yeah. It's like Qualcomm was like, we turn it up a little bit.
Speaker 7:  It's for you, it's for Galaxy.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. It's special. Yeah, sure. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  The bigger deal is that they're using it worldwide, right?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, yeah. There's no more, you know, some areas get
Speaker 9:  the snap dragon, some get the XOs chip, it's every phone everywhere.
Speaker 9:  All at once has the Snap dragon. That's
Speaker 7:  Really unusual.
Speaker 7:  Something going on with X N S trips. I guess we don't really get them in
Speaker 7:  in the United States, so I've never really known what's going on with x n
Speaker 7:  s chips. Yeah. Like I read foreign publications and they're like this do,
Speaker 7:  and I'm like, great the speed test, but I can't use one.
Speaker 7:  Like it's like illegal to use one here.
Speaker 9:  I think there was like one or two mid-range phones I looked at that they
Speaker 9:  just kind of threw the XOs in and there was really, it was just very quiet.
Speaker 9:  They're like, oh yeah,
Speaker 1:  Gotta clear out their closet.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, yeah, yeah. Maybe they were lying around. I don't know.
Speaker 7:  They're like, can you make XOs for Galaxy? And Samsung was like, no. And
Speaker 7:  it's like, but you're
Speaker 9:  Meos for me.
Speaker 7:  So it seems like running through Ultra on the whole pretty incremental,
Speaker 7:  right? We've, we've seen a pixel bending camera from Samsung before. It was
Speaker 7:  really good. I think we Becca's big camera test last year.
Speaker 7:  She said the S 22 Ultra was the be her favorite camera. Yeah. The best in
Speaker 7:  this context is a very subjective thing to say. It was Becca's favorite camera.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And Becca's the best camera viewer. So I think you can just close those,
Speaker 7:  those dots together. But this seems like the next step
Speaker 7:  of a big pixel binning sensor, not a radical step.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Yeah. It's, it's all pretty incremental and
Speaker 9:  like I, I do think it's interesting like what they had to
Speaker 9:  do to get here, like to get to 200 megapixels and
Speaker 9:  the little tweaks under the hood are interesting. But yeah, at the end of
Speaker 9:  the day it's like, it is a pixel bidding camera. It's got a
Speaker 9:  newer chip. It has like slightly better gorilla glass
Speaker 9:  and but the square, it's square.
Speaker 7:  The head square square though that's where we're our phones are like this
Speaker 7:  black rectangle is squared off on the sides and no satellites And
Speaker 7:  no satellites.
Speaker 9:  Not satellites for Samsung
Speaker 7:  Because
Speaker 8:  Samsung cares about things being ready before they put them in their devices.
Speaker 8:  Sudden.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. You wouldn't think they would just throw stuff at the
Speaker 9:  wall like that would
Speaker 7:  You? Samsung and Qualcomm together? No, they never just
Speaker 7:  announced nothing on a stage.
Speaker 7:  We do that. The satellite thing is on the whole, I find
Speaker 7:  the Apple commercials about sos to be extremely weird,
Speaker 7:  you know and like I get that it works and I'm, if
Speaker 9:  You don't have this, you're gonna die
Speaker 7:  Immediately. Yeah. It's like the one commercial where they're on the mountain
Speaker 7:  in the helicopter comes like this would be, yes. I'm appreciative that
Speaker 7:  this exists. This is the weirdest commercial to be watching in the middle
Speaker 7:  of football. Like it's just like things get real dark for
Speaker 7:  30 seconds and you're out and you're like, oh you're not. I look at my phone,
Speaker 7:  I'm like, one day you'll save my but
Speaker 9:  Right.
Speaker 7:  It's just weird.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Us us 23 Ultras just gonna leave me in the woods.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, you're
Speaker 9:  Doomed. It's just gonna be I'm be done.
Speaker 7:  Well you, you can fire off all 200 megapixels at once. I hope you don't like
Speaker 7:  staying alive Alison.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Oh god.
Speaker 7:  So the satellite stuff is there. I don't think those networks are built out
Speaker 7:  yet. Even like Apple's network is still pretty low bandwidth. You can
Speaker 7:  see why on a very expensive phone, they're not adding more costs to it
Speaker 7:  until it means something to people. Whereas Apple
Speaker 7:  just needed to differentiate it and best we get cart like Apple is like,
Speaker 7:  we'll just scare people in the buying phones this year. Like if you're close
Speaker 7:  to death iPhone, that's weird for them. That's their positioning.
Speaker 7:  Maybe you looked at God today, the iPhone
Speaker 7:  in the
Speaker 9:  Middle of
Speaker 8:  Can you trust your kids with another phone and
Speaker 7:  An iPhone. The next Apple commercial is 10 book being like if you want to
Speaker 7:  stir death in the face, I
Speaker 7:  That's good. It's a very goth year for Apple. The
Speaker 7:  HomePod comes in black first
Speaker 7:  Anyway. The, that's, that's satellite. Whatever. I just wanna come
Speaker 7:  back to the camera for one second. It seems like we are at this place where
Speaker 7:  the mainstream is beginning to realize the cameras are really processed
Speaker 7:  and the photos look weird. And maybe the tech industry
Speaker 7:  particularly Samsung was like what people love is
Speaker 7:  insane colors and no contrast.
Speaker 7:  And like soon Gen Z will just be like, this is what photos look
Speaker 7:  like. And the answer is everyone realizes that that looks a
Speaker 7:  little too wild and it has not become sort of a default look. Are they
Speaker 7:  backing off yet?
Speaker 9:  I, I really haven't seen, I think it's just, they're sort of like doing like
Speaker 9:  Apple where they just pile on options. They're like okay here's
Speaker 9:  our version. You don't like that Fine. You can use
Speaker 9:  cool contrast or whatever. They're all called and
Speaker 9:  yeah I'm sure there's some setting and some camera
Speaker 9:  assistant menu on the Samsung that will be like make the
Speaker 9:  blue sky like a little less neon blue next
Speaker 9:  time. But it's, yeah, it's sort of on like us to
Speaker 9:  figure that out and I would kind of like, could you maybe
Speaker 9:  do something so like I take a picture of a sunset, it doesn't
Speaker 9:  suddenly look like violent purple.
Speaker 9:  Like that's my basic ask.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. There's just something going on here with these phones where it's the,
Speaker 7:  like they've learned just as the TV manufacturers and Best Buy have learned
Speaker 7:  like really bright things win or like Pepsi learned in the
Speaker 7:  eighties, Pepsi will always win the Pepsi challenge at the theme park cuz
Speaker 7:  as more sugar in it. But then you live with it, you're like, my TV looks
Speaker 7:  bonkers. Like this is too sweet. And then I think people
Speaker 7:  now with their phones are like, these photos don't look good. Like I don't
Speaker 7:  love every photo that's coming off of this phone because they're all, they're
Speaker 7:  all so noticeably overprocessed or far from
Speaker 7:  reality and it, it just doesn't seem like either one of these companies is
Speaker 7:  willing to blink yet. Like apple's getting closer to Samsung and
Speaker 7:  we've talked about that so many times and every, every year we're like, the
Speaker 7:  phones are getting closer together and in good light they're kind of indistinguishable.
Speaker 7:  But that target of indistinguishable photo is getting weirder and
Speaker 7:  weirder.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. I just still, I take pictures of people with an iPhone in
Speaker 9:  their orange and I'm like, why are we still having this
Speaker 9:  problem? Yeah. I don't know any orange people.
Speaker 7:  Well I'm just wondering cuz once you have a 200 megapixel sensor,
Speaker 7:  it, I mean the phone's huge but it's still small. Right? And you've got
Speaker 7:  full well capacity that's still teeny tiny. In order to get any
Speaker 7:  image off of that, like we're well beyond what is a photo and into
Speaker 7:  you might as well type in make a photo of a sunset and let
Speaker 7:  like the phone like chat G b t generate the answer for you.
Speaker 7:  Right. Like you're so far away from we're gonna
Speaker 7:  open the shutter and close it and show you a reflection of reality. You're
Speaker 7:  fully, there's a computer at the level of even just gathering the light.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, yeah. Just the, the basic mechanics of like
Speaker 9:  photography and making a photo are just like so far behind
Speaker 9:  us.
Speaker 9:  We are well into the future of neon sunsets
Speaker 9:  and I don't, I don't see it like coming down anytime soon. Like
Speaker 7:  No, my prediction is the next, the Galaxy S 24,
Speaker 7:  instead of how many lenses this time in the back 5, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5,
Speaker 7:  it will have zero and it will just be like a mid journey prompt
Speaker 7:  that's like I'm,
Speaker 1:  That's what Microsoft and Samsung are working on with their mixed reality.
Speaker 1:  It's chatt being the camera.
Speaker 7:  Just like you tell Bicks be like make a photo of my mother.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. In front of the Grand Canyon. She's
Speaker 7:  Like generate that for you. Zero lens cameras. You heard it here on
Speaker 7:  the road fast first, it's gonna be great.
Speaker 9:  I'm looking forward to it.
Speaker 7:  What's going on with the S 23 plus and the regular S 23?
Speaker 9:  So those were even less interesting
Speaker 9:  honestly they, they, they really got just little
Speaker 9:  incremental upgrades. They got the new four Galaxy
Speaker 9:  Snapdragon gen two processor. They, I
Speaker 9:  think maybe the most meaningful thing is that they got slightly bigger batteries.
Speaker 9:  The S 23 is to like relatively small. It's 30
Speaker 9:  900 million hours and then S 23 plus is
Speaker 9:  4,700 in the battery life in the S 22
Speaker 9:  phones I think was like not great. It wasn't, it wasn't
Speaker 9:  like deal breaking bad but you just kind of like, you start to
Speaker 9:  get the, like your palms get kind of clammy by the end of the day when you're
Speaker 9:  like, oh I'm at 20% or whatever. So I think a little
Speaker 9:  battery boost could actually be a big, a good thing here.
Speaker 9:  And that's kinda it. They got the new gorilla glass, the S
Speaker 9:  23 plus got the base model storage upgrade. But
Speaker 9:  the S 23 didn't, no, no change in price,
Speaker 9:  which is good news. I think it's squares
Speaker 9:  still. I don't think those ones are, no they, they
Speaker 9:  had like straighter edges to start with. They already kind of
Speaker 9:  looked like iPhones from 2016, which I secretly
Speaker 9:  really love. So they were already on the right side of
Speaker 9:  history there.
Speaker 7:  We're gonna talk about earnings for a bunch of companies a minute here. Apple
Speaker 7:  just posted their earnings. Google posted its earnings. Samsung is in the
Speaker 7:  same spot with these phones as they are in with laptops and sort of everybody's
Speaker 7:  in, which is everybody bought their upgrade in the pandemic
Speaker 7:  and now they're like, I don't need another phone or laptop. And I think
Speaker 7:  particularly for these mid-range phones, like I thought the iPhone 14
Speaker 7:  plus would be a huge seller cuz a big cheap screen and it's like
Speaker 7:  fine. You know like the thing that's selling is the really high end and the
Speaker 7:  sort of midrange everybody is already upgraded through. Yeah. Do do these
Speaker 7:  S 20 threes, are they just kind of like, well we gotta have something or
Speaker 7:  are they like actually trying to get people to upgrade?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I think these are just, this is just the, the current phone
Speaker 9:  on the shelf with the like new for 2023. That's
Speaker 7:  This one.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. It's like, is it your year to upgrade? Here you
Speaker 9:  go. You know, you don't want last year's model. You want the
Speaker 9:  brand shiny new one. I think like the
Speaker 9:  whole whole kind of launch event and all the like
Speaker 9:  pizzazz and whatever is is more about like kind
Speaker 9:  of convincing you you're in the right ecosystem. Yeah. More than like, oh
Speaker 9:  I gotta run out and go get this S 23 Ultra cuz 200
Speaker 9:  megapixels. It's sort of like, you know when your time comes around you're
Speaker 9:  like, I'm gonna upgrade this here. Kind of remember you're like, yeah, see
Speaker 9:  that
Speaker 1:  Kind of tracks with the laptop stuff too because so much of their pitch was
Speaker 1:  like, hey remember you can do this stuff with the Galaxy phone. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Just FYI guys, we've had this for a while.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I mean Apple, apple does that too, right? They like, here's a new version
Speaker 7:  of Mac Os and then let launch the laptops and like 90% of it is like Mac
Speaker 7:  os features from WW C fine. I'm just saying like,
Speaker 7:  it's great they had an event, it's great. Everyone's back together. Like
Speaker 7:  we're back in it. Samsung next year will have Broadway answers once again,
Speaker 7:  I'm sure. But it's just a weird spot, right? Where
Speaker 7:  everything is very incremental and the market is
Speaker 7:  very much saying we don't need new stuff. So it's not, I I just like,
Speaker 7:  I'm looking at these phones. They're great, they're fun. The edges
Speaker 7:  are more square. The chip is for Galaxy now. I mean
Speaker 7:  that's huge.
Speaker 1:  Oh yeah. No
Speaker 7:  One,
Speaker 1:  No one else can have that
Speaker 7:  Chip. That's all anybody's been talking to us.
Speaker 1:  Apple go
Speaker 7:  Away. No one else can have a stab Dragon chip. I get it. But it, it just
Speaker 7:  seems like they're launching into sort of market that's
Speaker 7:  kind of bored or, or has already done. It's like upgrades. Yeah. And on top
Speaker 7:  of that, the 5G upgrade cycle is it is the thing,
Speaker 7:  I mean, you know, y'all know how I feel about that. That's what chat G B
Speaker 7:  T would really be like is like the robot, like 5G is bullshit. Like,
Speaker 7:  but like it's it's just sort of like happening. It's a default. It's not
Speaker 7:  a reason to upgrade. It hasn't pulled anyone forward. Is that just like,
Speaker 7:  that's is my vibe is like Samsung had to announce a bunch of stuff. There
Speaker 7:  are some new chips, there's some new camera capabilities and like here,
Speaker 7:  here it's, and I I think Apple's like in the same place too. I mean we Chip
Speaker 7:  bumped MacBooks is the same deal. Right?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean I think it was interesting talking to people at
Speaker 1:  CES because I did get a sense that a lot of them were,
Speaker 1:  were sort of like, yeah we're trying to figure out how to keep the PC exciting
Speaker 1:  and target, you know, convince the high end that these PCs
Speaker 1:  can do things that they couldn't do before. And like a lot of what they were
Speaker 1:  pushing was webcam features. That was like a big thing. They're like, well
Speaker 1:  Richard, Richard,
Speaker 7:  You won't do it. Not yet. These are my real eyes.
Speaker 1:  Web gaming is like, oh you're, you know, you're conferencing a lot now you
Speaker 1:  need this. There was a lot of push on the gaming
Speaker 1:  side and people saying like, your game, these new games that are coming out,
Speaker 1:  you can play them now with all this, this these, this new gaming laptop and
Speaker 1:  Samsung didn't is has not been a huge
Speaker 1:  player in either of those spaces with its previous Galaxy Books. And so
Speaker 1:  it seems to me like the book Ultra is maybe the closest thing they have to
Speaker 1:  something that could appeal to the gaming demographic. They, the way they
Speaker 1:  said it to me at the event was like, you know, you could game on this. Is
Speaker 1:  it for gamers? No, but you could game on this was sort of like their, their
Speaker 1:  vibe, which you know is fair. Is it sort of the Apple thing too at this point.
Speaker 1:  So I think that they are coming that that's I think the,
Speaker 1:  the most exciting one of these and the one that I can see people
Speaker 1:  upgrading to. Especially if they have a Galaxy book that doesn't play games
Speaker 1:  really well. Like that could be a reasonable sell for them.
Speaker 7:  All right, we'll
Speaker 1:  See. But you know, we'll see
Speaker 7:  That's the news from unpacked, right? And there was, that's it. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I mean it's again, I don't wanna like end on a down note, which
Speaker 7:  I've been told not to do over and over again. We have to wait for new
Speaker 7:  foldables. We yeah, we gotta wait for new foldables. They got some new screen
Speaker 7:  text. We're not ready. Yeah, but it's like these are this your Samsung rectangles
Speaker 7:  are here, here
Speaker 7:  Bpe like how many times was Bixie mentioned? Did they mention it all? Oh
Speaker 9:  My gosh man, I don't, I don't think I heard Bix. They
Speaker 9:  must have said Bixby like once at least
Speaker 7:  We gotta didn't hear it. Gotta do We, we did our usual super cut. We gotta
Speaker 7:  start doing Bixby. Supercuts. She's like Bixby count one person be like,
Speaker 7:  and it's not Bixby me,
Speaker 7:  but that layer, that service layer, they're trying to build. They keep mentioning
Speaker 7:  it but it hasn't like gone anywhere else. Yeah, okay. I mean
Speaker 7:  look, apple needs a competitor. They're the leader of the market. Google's
Speaker 7:  like, we sold more pixels than ever before and it's still like seven.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I mean the continuity stuff, I think the continuity stuff is cool.
Speaker 1:  It works. Isn't as smooth as Apple's continuity stuff I think.
Speaker 1:  No, I know you said before like, oh people don't switch. Like I switched
Speaker 1:  like I, I switched from Windows to Apple not too long ago. Oh no, I think,
Speaker 1:  I think that we are at a point where
Speaker 7:  That's another full hour page.
Speaker 1:  That's another full fantastic.
Speaker 7:  It's like next
Speaker 1:  Week for the full story for, for my journey.
Speaker 1:  I think there are, this is the first year that I know some really
Speaker 1:  hardcore windows people who are starting to say to me like, should I look
Speaker 1:  at these Macs? And I like I in many, many years in this career, I've never,
Speaker 1:  I basically have never heard that before. And I think if I were same thing,
Speaker 1:  I'd really be trying to pull out the shoe lights is here and put out a competitor.
Speaker 1:  Cuz I do think, you know, if only tot stem the tide of people leaving
Speaker 1:  to Apple. If
Speaker 7:  Not because of the price performance in the process. Yeah. All right, we'll
Speaker 7:  see we gotta take a break. We, there is earnings, like literally as we've
Speaker 7:  been speaking, apple earnings broke, there's alphabet earnings. There's just,
Speaker 7:  we gotta talk about some money. We'll be back in a second. We'll go through
Speaker 7:  it. We'll right back.
Speaker 11:  Running a business is stressful but worrying about how to
Speaker 11:  grow your company in the digital space can make any ambitious person wanna
Speaker 11:  give up. Wouldn't it be nice to have a set of expertly designed tools to
Speaker 11:  help you create your own growth tailored exactly to your company's needs.
Speaker 11:  That's where Unisys comes in. Unisys is a global technology
Speaker 11:  solutions company dedicated to helping people and organizations reach
Speaker 11:  their next breakthrough. They offer tools to help you run your business
Speaker 11:  more efficiently. Like systems integration, consulting services,
Speaker 11:  application management and device management Software plus
Speaker 11:  Unisys applies specialized expertise to strengthen and transform
Speaker 11:  teams and processes by helping organizations act on new opportunities
Speaker 11:  through digital workplace cloud applications, enterprise
Speaker 11:  computing and business process solutions. To learn more, visit
Speaker 11:  uny.com. That's U N I S Y s.com.
Speaker 11:  Unisys keep breaking through.
Speaker 10:  Support for this episode comes from Brex, the corporate card and
Speaker 10:  spend management software teams actually love. If you're a CFO
Speaker 10:  or finance leader today, you know we are operating in
Speaker 10:  transformational times. It can be hard getting people all in the same
Speaker 10:  place and not over another Zoom call Now more
Speaker 10:  than ever before. You need to help build a connection with not only your
Speaker 10:  team but with your clientele in real life. Thankfully
Speaker 10:  BR can help. Brex is an integrated solution of corporate cards
Speaker 10:  and span management software that drives 100% compliance
Speaker 10:  in zero receipt. Chasing in over 100 countries. BRA is
Speaker 10:  easy to set up and easy to use with dedicated implementation
Speaker 10:  software, an intuitive consumer grade design and the Brex mobile app.
Speaker 10:  And if you ever need support you can always reach out by phone app
Speaker 10:  or chat twenty four seven. It's that simple. BR makes it easy
Speaker 10:  to manage every aspect of spending from the smallest purchases to the
Speaker 10:  biggest procurements. No matter where your team works, they help
Speaker 10:  empower employees to do the right thing and spend responsibly and
Speaker 10:  compliance is built in. So with everything from restaurants to
Speaker 10:  retail stores to your work platform, all going cloud-based,
Speaker 10:  isn't it time for your company to use a spend management solution for modern
Speaker 10:  times? Learn more at brex.com/podcast.
Speaker 7:  We're back. It's time to talk earnings. You know, like I spend
Speaker 7:  a lot of time on CNBC and I'm still bad at this. I just wanna be clear
Speaker 8:  Just talking about money man, it's this little unimportant thing.
Speaker 8:  Well
Speaker 7:  You know I have this theory and I've thought about this a lot covering
Speaker 7:  tech, especially for a site like ours that has a, like a inherent
Speaker 7:  built-in like big reviews program is the weirdest part
Speaker 7:  of the media. Like there are very few other parts of the media
Speaker 7:  where you're like, we're gonna cover the people, we're gonna cover the events,
Speaker 7:  we're gonna look at the thing, we're gonna make jokes about bpe and then
Speaker 7:  we're gonna take your product and we're gonna look at it and Allison's gonna
Speaker 7:  be like seven
Speaker 7:  just like never happens. Like it doesn't happen in like in politics
Speaker 7:  the voters vote, right? But that's not you doing it in sports. The teams
Speaker 7:  play and there's a winner and a loser, but you didn't like sports writers
Speaker 7:  are not like out there being like you're gonna win. And we are very much
Speaker 7:  like you lost HomePod. Good. Try,
Speaker 7:  try again. Right? The only thing that up, the only external thing that
Speaker 7:  happens is earnings where the companies tell you if like they made money
Speaker 7:  or not.
Speaker 9:  It's a whole different language to learn the
Speaker 9:  EBITDA and the runway and yeah it's, it's
Speaker 9:  like being thrown into a different world with different people who
Speaker 9:  say different things.
Speaker 7:  Yes. And care very little about like you cannot tell, I cannot go on
Speaker 7:  CBC and be like, it's got a 200 megapixel camera. They'll be like who cares?
Speaker 9:  They're not gonna hear about the full well capacity.
Speaker 7:  The next time I go on tv I'm definitely gonna be like full well capacity.
Speaker 7:  Just throw it out there in like zero context and see what happens. Oh
Speaker 9:  My gosh, do it.
Speaker 8:  The actual US usability, what what people actually think does not matter.
Speaker 8:  How did it do financially? Right? And how do they project that it will do
Speaker 8:  financially next quarter compared to last year? Last year
Speaker 8:  over year. Yeah. Same quarter.
Speaker 7:  I'm saying this is the weirdest, this is the weirdest little intersection
Speaker 7:  of covering tech. Cause nothing else has this part where
Speaker 7:  the journalists evaluate the end result. We're like Google, we covered everything
Speaker 7:  that you did and it's a four. You know like it's just like,
Speaker 7:  and then there's this other part of, of the business anyhow, I just wanna
Speaker 7:  point out, it's weird, we talk about it a lot but it's, it's because it's
Speaker 7:  these earnings every quarter are the moment where the company
Speaker 7:  tells you, the public companies tell you how they did. Right. Did people
Speaker 7:  like our phones? And the answer, we'll start with Apple. The answer is
Speaker 7:  people like the phones but they can't make any so they didn't make as much
Speaker 7:  money as they usually do. Is that about right Richard?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So they reported their earnings for a Q1 2023
Speaker 8:  they took in 117, which
Speaker 7:  Is the holiday quarter. Apples quarters are yes. Are
Speaker 7:  scooted over one. So Q1 23 is really
Speaker 7:  December quarter 22.
Speaker 8:  That's the other thing about about it. You have to learn a whole new calendar
Speaker 8:  that isn't your regular calendar and not all the companies use the same calendar.
Speaker 8:  So you're gonna be saying weird things all the time. Yeah. People will look
Speaker 8:  at you like you are insane because you're like, oh yeah it's q4,
Speaker 7:  Is it?
Speaker 8:  Maybe. Anyhow. But yes, there's been wait times for the
Speaker 8:  iPhone for, for the high end iPhone 14 models they make the most money on.
Speaker 8:  They've had these supply issues, they are kind of reshuffling
Speaker 8:  their supply chain to rely less on China. They've been so many issues in
Speaker 8:  China with C O V D and other issues with labor.
Speaker 8:  Everything in that that is all kind of combined to affect
Speaker 8:  the the profit of one, you know, one of the most profitable
Speaker 8:  companies over the, or perhaps the most profitable company over the last
Speaker 8:  few years. Also they have a problem where the last generation of, when you
Speaker 8:  look at their laptops, the M one laptops were so, were such an incredible
Speaker 8:  upgrade over what had been out there. Two a little bit better but it's
Speaker 8:  just a little bit better.
Speaker 7:  So Apple did predict that Max sales would decline substantially compared
Speaker 7:  to a year ago. They were correct in this prediction. Max sales are down
Speaker 7:  29% and I think that all feeds into it like the M one MacBook error.
Speaker 7:  Like we were like throw your laptop out the window and buy this thing. And
Speaker 7:  then combined with the pandemic it was the thing to buy. And
Speaker 7:  that's a no one is, unless you are very picky about webcams,
Speaker 7:  which I am and that webcam is garbage.
Speaker 7:  There's no reason to buy a new MacBook Air. And I think most people are
Speaker 7:  not that picky about webcams. So you can see apples just like running like
Speaker 7:  this is a company that makes most of its money on the iPhone is having really
Speaker 7:  hard times making enough iPhones to sell,
Speaker 7:  which might mask the fact that people don't want those lower
Speaker 7:  mid-tier iPhones. Allison. Like they want the pros
Speaker 7:  and maybe all the demand for upgrades in the, in the mid-tier is
Speaker 7:  satiated by pandemic upgrades. Upgrade cycles are getting longer
Speaker 7:  so they can't make enough of the high-end stuff and then the all the Mac
Speaker 7:  upgrades are done for now. So they're kind of stuck with services, right?
Speaker 7:  Seems like it. They
Speaker 8:  Are and that's why we suddenly have Apple TV plus we have they, them bundling
Speaker 8:  all their services together says you can get your iCloud and your Apple TV
Speaker 8:  and your news and everything else because the people who buy those highest
Speaker 8:  end devices, the people who get the most expensive subscriptions or get the
Speaker 8:  package, they just wanna find another way to get something from you because
Speaker 8:  that's the way that they can demonstrate revenue growth to their investors.
Speaker 8:  So other than of course launching a car
Speaker 7:  Or this headset, so services revenue for Apple up 6%,
Speaker 7:  they now have more than 2 billion active devices running the services.
Speaker 7:  I'm sure this means an iCloud storage upgrade. Push
Speaker 7:  notification is about to hit all 2 billion of those devices.
Speaker 7:  Did you know that Apple has games in Apple arcade? 2 billion beeps
Speaker 7:  all at the same time around the world, right? Tim cook's like we made some
Speaker 7:  money. The one that surprised me, well two that surprised me in combination
Speaker 7:  wearables, which has Apple Watch and AirPods down
Speaker 7:  which tracks, cuz I think most of those things get bought along with an
Speaker 7:  iPhone. So I think there's some, well AirPods people lose,
Speaker 7:  but I think the vast majority of AirPods get bought with your iPhone. The
Speaker 7:  vast majority of Apple watches get bought around an iPhone. So if iPhone
Speaker 7:  sells, again, let's go down iPad revenue up
Speaker 7:  30%. Even though the iPad line, from what I can tell
Speaker 7:  is more confusing than it has ever been before. But maybe that's
Speaker 7:  it. People are just like going to the store and they're freaked out. They're
Speaker 7:  surrounded by a wall of iPads, you know, like, I gotta watch, I have to have
Speaker 7:  one. All there's gotta one for for whatever. So all in all,
Speaker 8:  I feel like you're at a point in the cycle where, where people are upgrading
Speaker 8:  iPads. It's like, like I bought a new iPad last year. All right. There's
Speaker 8:  gotta be somebody who's like, oh, okay, you know that that old one is just
Speaker 8:  not cutting it anymore.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. All in all, all this adds up to the iPhone is down, the Mac
Speaker 7:  is down, that means apples down, right? Apples year over year 5% down in
Speaker 7:  the holiday quarter. That's a big deal. That's one of those like wow. Usually
Speaker 7:  Apple sluts records in this quarter and I think they're, they're hurting
Speaker 7:  because of the covid stuff in China in particular. So that's Apple.
Speaker 8:  And as as you mentioned, Samsung and Apple and everyone is kind of having
Speaker 8:  these same things and Samsung had just a, after a string of record breaking
Speaker 8:  quarters had like their worst quarter in eight years. Yeah. And that's just
Speaker 8:  where we are now. Liz,
Speaker 7:  We're wrote that great piece last week about all the companies doing layoffs
Speaker 7:  and tech. I, I don't know if we have a lot of like MBA students or MBA
Speaker 7:  professors out there. There's a paper or a book to be written
Speaker 7:  about the single greatest business mistake in our generation,
Speaker 7:  which is everyone thought the things that happened in the pandemic would
Speaker 7:  happen forever. They're like, everyone will buy a new laptop
Speaker 7:  every year to work at home. We should make thousands of. And it's like, no
Speaker 7:  dude, they're gonna buy one and then they're gonna go back outside. Like
Speaker 7:  the entire business community was like, what if these motherfuckers never
Speaker 7:  go outside again? And like here we're,
Speaker 8:  We got 'em.
Speaker 7:  It's like, no, like Barks stock was like, here's what they're gonna do. They're
Speaker 7:  gonna stay inside all day and they're gonna be brains and vats and I'm gonna
Speaker 7:  build the metaverse for the vat brain people. And it's like, I don't,
Speaker 7:  I could have told you what was gonna happen to
Speaker 8:  No, they they would rather go to concerts in person.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It turns out Fortnite concerts were only interesting when you
Speaker 7:  were not allowed to leave your house.
Speaker 9:  Right. We have options now.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's pretty good. A little better just, just touching grass alone.
Speaker 7:  Not in Fortnite is great.
Speaker 8:  And so Apple's launching pay later as, as Tim
Speaker 8:  Cook said on c CBC said it's coming. So this
Speaker 7:  Is very late. They announced this a while ago, but they, they, it's still
Speaker 8:  Out. They're getting big into financial services. Apple is not a bank yet,
Speaker 8:  but they're getting closer. You know, they're gonna let you earn interest
Speaker 8:  on, on your, your balance and suddenly this is a very important thing for
Speaker 8:  them. Like this is, this is, as I said, we're talking about the money here.
Speaker 8:  This is what Tim Cook's whole compensation is based on. What can he
Speaker 8:  do to grow Apple? They're trying to find something and, and I don't, well
Speaker 7:  There's only three categories, right? Like there there's only three
Speaker 7:  categories that are big enough to move the needle for Apple it's healthcare
Speaker 7:  cars and the banks. Like you can't, I'm like,
Speaker 7:  apple should make a TV and you look at the entire TV industry, if Apples
Speaker 7:  took a hundred percent market share of the TV industry, they'd be like, that
Speaker 7:  wasn't enough. That wasn't enough percentage growth. And like
Speaker 7:  this is, this is like a champagne problem. Like Tim Cook cries about this
Speaker 7:  problem while breaking open a magnum of champagne on his yacht. He's like,
Speaker 7:  how do I move the needle? I don't know, bring me another magnum of champagne.
Speaker 7:  Like right. But this is their problem to move the needle. They have to
Speaker 7:  go play in the biggest remaining industries, which is why they're chasing
Speaker 7:  cars, which is why they think they're doctors and now it's
Speaker 7:  why they think they're a bank.
Speaker 9:  Kind of terrifying.
Speaker 7:  It is smaller. Speaking of other gigantic terrifying companies, let's talk
Speaker 7:  about Google. They also had, they had like a
Speaker 7:  flat earnings quarter and it's partially because of the advertising slowdown,
Speaker 7:  partially cuz of Apple, but partially cuz they, they're now having to like
Speaker 7:  spend money to invent new things, which Google has not,
Speaker 7:  I would say had a great track record of doing.
Speaker 8:  You, you may have heard they, their new products don't always, always turn
Speaker 8:  into something or, or they launch something and then a couple of years later
Speaker 8:  they're killing it. I'm not talking about Stadia, but I could
Speaker 7:  Be.
Speaker 8:  But yeah, when you're talking about advertising revenue, they said down
Speaker 8:  2 billion. So yeah, that's a pretty significant hit. And
Speaker 8:  somehow Google will have to get by after they, their profits for the quarter
Speaker 8:  were only 13.6 billion, which I would think is
Speaker 8:  pretty good. But because they made 20.6 billion the year before, they're,
Speaker 8:  they're not so happy with. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Google also just had layoffs. Apple's the only big tech company that has
Speaker 7:  not had layoffs recently. Google obviously just had its first mass
Speaker 7:  layoffs in its history. Amazon just had layoffs. Microsoft had layoffs, meta
Speaker 7:  had layoffs. We'll get to that in a second. It sounds like Zuckerberg wants
Speaker 7:  to have more layoffs cause he just keeps paddling on about efficiency,
Speaker 7:  which is, I know what that means. Y'all know what that means.
Speaker 7:  But Google like, you know, Google is an advertising company. Like fundamentally
Speaker 7:  that's how Google makes money is advertising on the web. They've, we, I've
Speaker 7:  been hammering on this for the past couple weeks. Google's in the hardest
Speaker 7:  spot I think it's ever been in as a company, right? The DOJ is coming after
Speaker 7:  the ad stuff chat g PT is coming after Google's
Speaker 7:  search results on in both directions. You can ask chat g for answers.
Speaker 7:  And then Shady SEO farms are just making chat g b t
Speaker 7:  webpages to ruin Google search results. So the product is getting squeezed
Speaker 7:  on both sides. Apples ad tracking transparency stuff not
Speaker 7:  great for Google, right? It's, it's ruining its ability to, to
Speaker 7:  track users across the web and deliver personalized advertising. The, it
Speaker 7:  just feels like the hardest spot Google's ever been in. And that
Speaker 7:  I would not say that these earnings showcase any glimmer of the
Speaker 7:  future.
Speaker 8:  No. And the, and the new things they've been developing aren't really filling
Speaker 8:  the gap. You look at the cloud, not not doing it YouTube, not doing
Speaker 8:  it pixel hardware. I mean look, we're, we're trying but it's,
Speaker 8:  it's just not doing it. The, the Pixel watch is unfortunately not making
Speaker 8:  a dent in that 2 billion.
Speaker 7:  Wouldn't it be incredible if pixel hardware just like saved, saved Google
Speaker 7:  like tomorrow the pixels like, all right, that's the end, that's the new
Speaker 7:  iPhone gonna run the company. We did it. So just
Speaker 7:  to be specific, lots of Google's main revenue drivers are down
Speaker 7:  over the past year advertising down by 2 billion as Richard said services,
Speaker 7:  which includes Android chrome hardware, which is a bonkers thing to
Speaker 7:  put in services. That's how important hardware is to
Speaker 7:  Google.
Speaker 9:  They just threw it in there. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Just lump it in with Chrome. But services includes Android, chrome hardware,
Speaker 7:  Google Maps, Google Play search and YouTube down by 1.5 billion.
Speaker 7:  And then it also spent more than a 1.5 billion
Speaker 7:  on r and d. So you just see Google, Google's in this place where it has to
Speaker 7:  invent something new cuz the things that make a lot of money are going down.
Speaker 7:  And then on top of that YouTube, which is a bit of a bright spot, they just
Speaker 7:  roll that monetization for YouTube shorts like yesterday. So if this thing
Speaker 7:  is gonna become the next generation of the YouTube creator economy, which
Speaker 7:  TikTok does not have, which Instagram does not have, so if they can actually
Speaker 7:  get the payment split to creators right on shorts, you might
Speaker 7:  see more creators going to YouTube. But that's still pretty insignificant
Speaker 7:  and a long way out. Like that's a pretty tough combination of things for
Speaker 7:  YouTube.
Speaker 8:  I think the executives are walking around asking if anyone has a $7 billion
Speaker 8:  idea for the next quarter. We've got Sergey Brynn putting in poll requests
Speaker 8:  I think for, for the first time in years. So just,
Speaker 8:  just any, if anyone who's still there, if you, if you have a way to make
Speaker 8:  7 billion, they're, they're certainly
Speaker 9:  Interesting. Yeah, well maybe start with Google search and make
Speaker 9:  it le a less miserable experience. I don't know like
Speaker 9:  it's so bad now that I, I don't know, I
Speaker 9:  need to read the article we're passing around but like
Speaker 9:  it's so, there's so much junk you have to like wade through to
Speaker 9:  get to whatever you were looking for. Just feels like it's
Speaker 9:  something a product's been like piled on and piled on and just kind of
Speaker 9:  forgotten about.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, well cuz it's monopoly, it this it's a,
Speaker 8:  A bit of news that came in just as we were getting into the earnings. They've
Speaker 8:  scheduled an event to show off some AI search stuff. We don't know if it's
Speaker 8:  gonna be the chatbot, but February 8th, 8:30 AM Eastern Time
Speaker 8:  live from France AI search stuff.
Speaker 7:  Oh that's great. All right. That's definitely not a panic scheduled event.
Speaker 7:  No, this is, this is rumors I think CNBC reported this week.
Speaker 7:  Google has a version of the search landing page where it just tells
Speaker 7:  you the answer and it has some suggested prompts of things you
Speaker 7:  might ask. It's chap out for. Now to be perfectly
Speaker 7:  clear, Google's claim, and this is
Speaker 7:  what people in the industry believe to be true, is that Lambda, it's big
Speaker 7:  l l m, it's competitor at chat. G p t is superior to chat
Speaker 7:  G P t. That's the claim. That's what people have been saying. They
Speaker 7:  won't release it because like every AI chatbot it will just
Speaker 7:  confidently lie to you. So that's a real problem if
Speaker 7:  you're Google. So we'll see how they deploy this thing. They obviously
Speaker 7:  are very defensive about the fact that they invented a lot of this technology
Speaker 7:  and they have had the scruples of not just releasing it. Whereas open eyes
Speaker 7:  like, I don't know the robot's gonna lie to you, see what happens next.
Speaker 7:  There's also a rumor that the Google version, the chat bot will be able to
Speaker 7:  answer questions like current events, which is like, that's where the
Speaker 7:  confident lining becomes a real problem, you know? So we'll see.
Speaker 7:  I wanna keep talking about ours, I wanna talk about meta, but real quick
Speaker 7:  on Microsoft. Microsoft is an, is just like high on
Speaker 7:  life because it has this open AI investment. So they're just like starting
Speaker 7:  to announce things. Teams Premium has features powered by
Speaker 7:  open ai. So you can watch chat g PT talking teams for
Speaker 7:  you. They're rolling out tech to write sales
Speaker 7:  emails using chat G P T, which is like Microsoft is so
Speaker 7:  excited about having the tiniest tread of a lead in AI
Speaker 7:  and the first thing they thought about doing was like mail merge like the
Speaker 7:  most Microsoft thing. I can't believe that they didn't bring Balmer back
Speaker 7:  for that one. Yeah, cool. It's very good. And then there's this
Speaker 7:  pretty lightly sourced rumor in SE four that the next version
Speaker 7:  of Bing will have chat G P T in it powered by G PT four,
Speaker 7:  which is a huge hype balloon. People think G PT four is gonna be like the
Speaker 7:  best thing ever have, even like the C of an ai. Sam Altman is like, people
Speaker 7:  are gonna be disappointed by chat GBT that's powered by G four because you've
Speaker 7:  hyped it up so much you have no choice but to be disappointed. That said,
Speaker 7:  a new version of Bing that as G PT four powered results
Speaker 7:  is a threat to Google just from Mindshare alone, right? Just
Speaker 7:  from seeming like the cutting edge alone. And I think that's why Google is
Speaker 7:  like, oh we gotta start announcing some stuff and then last year we should
Speaker 7:  talk about meta Mark Zuckerberg is having like a religious experience it
Speaker 7:  seems like. Oh he went to like the Church of
Speaker 7:  Prophets. I was like, we need to make them because he got, you know,
Speaker 7:  he was like, he spent all of his time being like, I'm do the metaverse billions
Speaker 7:  of dollars, let's lose all the money. And then app tracking
Speaker 7:  transparency happened, the market crashed, the advertising market crashed.
Speaker 7:  TikTok happened. Instagram stopped being cool and now
Speaker 7:  he is like, I gotta fire everybody. I don't want managers, managing managers,
Speaker 7:  managing managers, I want people to do stuff so maybe we're gonna get more
Speaker 7:  efficient. And then he had this earnings call where he, he said the word
Speaker 7:  efficiency 500 times in a row. Oof.
Speaker 7:  Which is like, that just means he is gonna
Speaker 7:  start clipping people.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, you're gonna be doing a little bit more with a little bit less. But
Speaker 8:  e, even with all the bad news that we've had about Facebook, about the growth,
Speaker 8:  about how many people are using it, they record over 2 billion daily
Speaker 8:  active users in this last quarter, the highest that we've ever seen. And
Speaker 8:  I wonder what's going on there? Is it because we've got the apps kind of
Speaker 8:  integrated now all of your logins are shared. Like what, what is, what is
Speaker 8:  causing these, these numbers that we're seeing is, is this real? So
Speaker 7:  From what I'm seeing here, it's the 2 billion is Facebook itself the
Speaker 7:  blue app and then the family of apps is
Speaker 7:  3.7 billion people monthly across family of apps on Facebook
Speaker 7:  it's 2 billion daily actives. That's crazy. And I is it just that they added
Speaker 7:  reels to Facebook? Oh boy. Like at
Speaker 7:  this point it's like you open the thing and like it just starts playing video
Speaker 7:  at you, right? They just boosted talk's, move. What they don't have is
Speaker 7:  any monetization strategy for this stuff yet or any creator strategy for
Speaker 7:  this stuff or really any strategy for this stuff. They're just
Speaker 7:  like, screw it. You
Speaker 8:  They have NFTs on Instagram I
Speaker 7:  That'll do it. You
Speaker 8:  You will non fungible these tokens
Speaker 7:  That that'll do it. That is, oh no, Zuckerberg on the call pointed
Speaker 7:  out people like reels. That's what people like. Reels don't have as many
Speaker 7:  ads, they don't have as many ad products. So he is like, we gotta optimize,
Speaker 7:  we gotta make it more efficient how we monetize reels just that
Speaker 7:  word again. See I think they're just in the part of the Facebook growth curve
Speaker 7:  where they're like, here's all the stuff you like reels have at it and they're
Speaker 7:  gonna start adding ads onto it. And I feel like this happened, Instagram
Speaker 7:  already five times in a row we're like, Instagram was great and then Instagram
Speaker 7:  was shit and then they were like fixed it. They made a crap again. And that's
Speaker 7:  what's gonna happen to reels all this in the context of YouTube adding creator
Speaker 7:  monetization and in the context of TikTok basically just being like under
Speaker 7:  attack from everybody. Like there's not a big tech company or at
Speaker 7:  this point a politician America who's like, we should have TikTok in this
Speaker 7:  country. So there's just a weird that
Speaker 7:  weird scrolling video moment. I think we're gonna look back
Speaker 7:  on it in five years and be like, this was one of the weirdest periods in
Speaker 7:  tech when everyone was like, here's what you want. You want vertical video
Speaker 7:  to scroll by as fast as we can make it. And mostly it's weird people dancing
Speaker 7:  like, and we're just, I think we're just gonna look back on this video. This
Speaker 7:  is such a weird format war. Like there's like H D D D and Blu-ray
Speaker 7:  and there's gonna be reels versus shorts versus TikTok and we're gonna be
Speaker 7:  like, that was bizarre because by the end of it, I think the government's
Speaker 7:  gonna have booted TikTok out of the country and Facebook and YouTube
Speaker 7:  are going to have realized that these products don't monetize as well as
Speaker 7:  regular long form video on YouTube or Facebook's
Speaker 7:  other monetization products and they're gonna start to decline them in relevance
Speaker 7:  in their algorithms. That's my prediction then
Speaker 8:  You need more efficiency,
Speaker 7:  You need more efficiency. Just get more efficient. Yeah, I mean I'll say
Speaker 7:  this is the last thing actually these two headlines together are great.
Speaker 7:  I think they're very funny. Perfect example of where the government is at
Speaker 7:  with the tech regulation right now. White House goes after App store
Speaker 7:  gatekeepers, apple and Google. So Commerce department was like, you guys
Speaker 7:  are gatekeepers, you gotta open the floodgates, you gotta let more things
Speaker 7:  happen on your phones. Apple and Google face mounting pressure to remove
Speaker 7:  TikTok from their app stores. It's like guys,
Speaker 7:  either you open the gates and you're like stop being the gatekeepers. Or
Speaker 7:  you say use your power to boot this app off your phones
Speaker 7:  by removing it from the store you you cannot have both things.
Speaker 9:  Open the gates but not like that.
Speaker 7:  Exactly.
Speaker 9:  Shut a little bit.
Speaker 7:  I say this is like a totally weird moment, right where TikTok is still in
Speaker 7:  its ascendancy culturally for sure because the Chinese government pours
Speaker 7:  money into bite dance and we bite Dance is not a public
Speaker 7:  company so we have no idea how it works here. We we can't see
Speaker 7:  into the company to see if it's growing or the advertising working. And then
Speaker 7:  these other competitors are all public companies that are losing money because
Speaker 7:  the market sound all this other stuff and they're under pressure to compete
Speaker 7:  with TikTok and it's just a weird dynamic where the answer is gonna be
Speaker 7:  Facebook convinces the United States government to ban TikTok. I swear to
Speaker 7:  you this is going to happen. This is gonna be great. All right, we gotta
Speaker 7:  wrap this up. We are over as always, I wanna call out some things we great
Speaker 7:  piece about the EV price war or my contributor to the Virgin named Patrick George.
Speaker 7:  Basically his thesis is like, you see the Mustang MA get a price reduction,
Speaker 7:  you see the Tesla get a price reduction. Wait, just wait until there's actual
Speaker 7:  competition in this market and that's good. I'm gonna call it Sean Holster
Speaker 7:  who has just dogged the UFI company for claims about
Speaker 7:  encryption on its home security cameras. I mean you just gotta read the lead
Speaker 7:  of his piece. It's like first they lied, then they deflected, then they lied
Speaker 7:  again and now they've told me the truth. And the truth is the cameras were
Speaker 7:  not encrypted and he has all the responses.
Speaker 9:  No, they had a lot of words for non-encrypted.
Speaker 9:  That's it's a fascinating read.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. In to end encryption in in somehow became
Speaker 8:  into not really, yeah,
Speaker 7:  End of somewhere. I wanna call it Addie Robertson who
Speaker 7:  wrote an Amma, the great headline, the okay computer about the Lisa,
Speaker 7:  the Apple, Lisa, it's the history of the Lisa. We've got a big partnership
Speaker 7:  with the Computer history museum to make stuff like this. So this is part
Speaker 7:  of that partnership. It's an amazing piece. Which was the history, the genesis
Speaker 7:  of Lisa. This thing obviously failed. You can tell that the Verge loves fail
Speaker 7:  technology. We're like Springboard the Lisa, this is what we
Speaker 7:  do here.
Speaker 9:  The sob stories.
Speaker 7:  There's actually much more to come on Lisa coverage cuz of the anniversary.
Speaker 7:  We, there's a big event at the Computer History museum. It was like adorable.
Speaker 7:  All the people worked on Lisa over there. It was fun. We, we sent a bunch
Speaker 7:  of people there. And then lastly, I got a shout out Mia
Speaker 7:  who wrote, I would say a disappointing piece. Like the piece is good, excellent
Speaker 7:  reporting. Mia's a great reporter, well-written the whole thing. But the
Speaker 7:  piece is disappointing about CNET and this private equity company that
Speaker 7:  is like hollowing it out from the inside and it's our direct competitor.
Speaker 7:  So there's your disclosure. I know that CNN's our competitor, but we know
Speaker 7:  a lot of people in the CNN newsroom, they have been a great competitor for
Speaker 7:  a long time and now it's like a private equity VUL is turning
Speaker 7:  it into this like SEO driven machine. It is worth reading.
Speaker 7:  I keep going on and about Google as Alison mentioned, like Google search
Speaker 7:  results are getting worse. Why are they getting worse? Because companies
Speaker 7:  are getting better at gaming Google. And so like the architecture of the
Speaker 7:  web is like based on Google's influences and the CNET story
Speaker 7:  is like a microcosm of what happens when you pivot
Speaker 7:  from making good stuff to making things you think Google will like. And there's
Speaker 7:  a real difference in that. We'll see them, but
Speaker 7:  okay, that's it. Go read all that stuff. Thanks to Monica for joining
Speaker 7:  us. Allison, thank you so much. Thank
Speaker 2:  You
Speaker 7:  Richard. As always, you can tweet at us. I'm at reckless. Allison is Allison,
Speaker 7:  Joe one Richard is RJ CCC and Monica's mc squared.
Speaker 7:  96. Next week on Wednesday we're gonna run a special land of the
Speaker 7:  Giants episode. We're doing a series on dating apps right now. Dating apps
Speaker 7:  like the Wild West of technology. They're the weirdest. The Land
Speaker 7:  of Giants is the Rise dating apps this season. It's very cool. We're on that
Speaker 7:  on Wednesday. You can call the hotline eight sixty six of VER one one. That's
Speaker 7:  it. That's Vercast.
Speaker 2:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 2:  the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend, you
Speaker 2:  can send us feedback@vergecasttheverge.com. This show is produced
Speaker 2:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. This
Speaker 2:  episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith. Our editorial
Speaker 2:  director is Brooke Min and our executive producer is Eleanor Donovan.
Speaker 2:  The Verge Cast is a production of the Verge and Box Media podcast
Speaker 2:  network. And that's it. We'll see you next week.
Speaker 10:  This episode was brought to you by Brex. The corporate card and spend
Speaker 10:  management software teams actually love. No one likes doing
Speaker 10:  expenses. That's why Brex can help make life easy for those who
Speaker 10:  are tired of doing an expense for things as small as a coffee
Speaker 10:  to as large as a five star meal. Brex is an integrated
Speaker 10:  solution of corporate cards and spend management software that drives 100%
Speaker 10:  compliance in zero receipt chasing and over 100 countries,
Speaker 10:  which means less time worrying about expense reports and
Speaker 10:  more time focusing on stuff that really matters. Learn more at
Speaker 10:  brex.com/podcast.