# Transcript
ID: 363d41d4-0643-4ddb-829c-fd7f6ff5f7bc
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: It's gadget season again
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7150545987043312658/-4727050767059118036/s93290-US-4723s-1693929473.mp3
Description: The Verge's David Pierce, Alex Cranz, and Richard Lawler discuss all the gadgets announced at IFA 2023, the next flagship phone events from Apple and Google, and a whole lot more.
Also: Nilay Patel breaks news about the 5G banana surgery.
Speaker 1:  Support for this show comes from American Express Business. If you
Speaker 1:  are a small business owner, you wanna partner with someone that can help
Speaker 1:  make your day-to-day a rewarding experience. That's where American
Speaker 1:  Express can come in. American Express business cards are built for
Speaker 1:  your business with features and benefits like the ability to earn membership
Speaker 1:  rewards, points on select cards, the power to pay for big business
Speaker 1:  purchases, and 24 7 support from a business specialist
Speaker 1:  built for your business. Amex business terms apply.
Speaker 1:  learn more at american express.com/business cards.
Speaker 3:  Support for this show comes from Global Citizen. On
Speaker 3:  September 23rd, the Global Citizen Festival will gather thousands of people
Speaker 3:  who took action to end extreme poverty. Join the Red Hot Chili
Speaker 3:  Peppers, Ms. Lauren Hill, Megan Thee Stallion, and Anita
Speaker 3:  as they take the stage with world leaders and activists to demand
Speaker 3:  action for equity for the planet, for food and for jobs.
Speaker 3:  Download the Global Citizen app today and earn your spot at the festival.
Speaker 3:  learn more at global citizen.org/ Vox.
Speaker 4:  Neli, you made us promises about bananas. Are you here to deliver?
Speaker 5:  I made significant promises about bananas and my fellow Americans, I'm here
Speaker 5:  to say that my administration has delivered.
Speaker 4:  This is your white whale.
Speaker 5:  This is the only story I've ever wanted to do. And after we're done talking
Speaker 5:  about it, I'm gonna leave. I'm done. I'm gonna start a cafe, which
Speaker 5:  has always been a lifelong dream. But no. A couple weeks ago I
Speaker 5:  asked Vergecast listeners on the show that if they had actually
Speaker 5:  experienced the real world benefits of five G
Speaker 5:  to send us a note because the carriers themselves have not
Speaker 5:  experienced the real world money that they thought they would
Speaker 5:  make from five g. Tons of people. Sent me a video
Speaker 5:  of a banana in a Da Vinci robot, which is a
Speaker 5:  robot surgery tool and the banana is getting a raisin pulled out of it and
Speaker 5:  then the banana is getting stitched back up.
Speaker 4:  This video was like very popular. I think
Speaker 6:  I sent it to you
Speaker 5:  Al like it's just around, it's just a me. It's been around, it's been floating
Speaker 5:  around for like a couple years apparently with this text on it that says
Speaker 5:  the surgeon was in London and the banana was in California and
Speaker 5:  this proves five G. Well
Speaker 6:  There's like no provenance for the video or at least like the version I saw.
Speaker 6:  It was just like, here's a banana, it's five G. And I was like, who are you?
Speaker 6:  Random TikTok man. Where did this video come
Speaker 4:  From? Well, and just, just to be the one who says this out loud, who cares?
Speaker 4:  It's, I think one really good reason to not check on this is that is who
Speaker 4:  Caress. But, but this is why The Verge exists because we, well
Speaker 5:  Unfortunately this is my calling, it's this in a cafe.
Speaker 5:  So I, there are version of this video on X that have like 15 million views
Speaker 5:  and once that happens people just were posting it and posting it and posting
Speaker 5:  it. So I promised Vergecast listeners that I would blow the
Speaker 5:  story open. And I'm here to tell you that I did
Speaker 5:  and I, if you are on the Pulitzer committee, I'm available in person,
Speaker 5:  I'll come to you. But I talked to the surgeon
Speaker 5:  who operated on the banana. His name is Dr. Kai Rona. He's located in
Speaker 5:  Southern California. Let's listen to,
Speaker 7:  I did surgery on this banana, but it wasn't over five G.
Speaker 5:  There it is. Done and done. We don't do you need anymore? How did you
Speaker 5:  find this person? So people are lazy. Like the whole
Speaker 5:  story of this is media and the internet is super lazy and
Speaker 5:  in search of views. So if you just start clicking and looking at
Speaker 5:  variations of the video, they all have like fake credits. And so I just started
Speaker 5:  chasing all the credits and one of them was Dr.
Speaker 5:  Rona's Instagram handle, but it wasn't linked. It was on Twitter. It's just
Speaker 5:  plain text, which is an incredible piece of evidence, right?
Speaker 5:  It's like this thing has been booted and pirated and copied so many times
Speaker 5:  that the credit has been survived, but it actually hasn't translated
Speaker 5:  between platforms. It jumped platforms. Yeah. So I had to take
Speaker 5:  the credit from X and then go search all the other platforms and you find
Speaker 5:  Dr. Kai and on his Instagram page there's this video and he's in the
Speaker 5:  comments of the video replying to people who are like, what an amazing
Speaker 5:  demonstration of five G technology. And he's like, this wasn't a, I don't
Speaker 5:  know where this came from, I don't know where this idea came from. So I sent
Speaker 5:  him a message on Instagram, I wrote him an email. I called his office
Speaker 5:  like very politely, like over several times over the course of a few days.
Speaker 5:  It got to the point where the woman who answered the phone, I was like, Hey,
Speaker 5:  it's Neli Patel. And she literally, I heard her turn to the person next to
Speaker 5:  her and say, it's about the banana video again. So is is this because
Speaker 5:  lots of people call about the banana video or because you had become so relentless
Speaker 5:  about the banana video because I had good reporting is about persistence.
Speaker 5:  It is because I had called them so many times about the banana video. Is
Speaker 5:  is Dr. Rona like a well-known fruit surgeon? Like what? Who, no. So
Speaker 5:  I, I finally, he called me, he was, I I believe at the airport he was on
Speaker 5:  his way to Italy on vacation. Fruit surgery pays Well, yeah, from, from what
Speaker 5:  I heard, it's, it's, it's lucrative. But he, he called me. He had some time
Speaker 5:  and he was just cracking up.
Speaker 7:  When I first saw that, I saw someone post my video and say to some surgeon
Speaker 7:  in New York performing, performing an operation on some someone in London.
Speaker 7:  And I was like, wait, what is this? And so I commented, I was like this is
Speaker 7:  not true. You know this is my video. So it, so yeah, it's false. I was, it
Speaker 7:  was done in Los Angeles. I mean the procedure was done in the Los Angeles.
Speaker 7:  The banana was in Los Angeles. So
Speaker 5:  The banana was in Los Angeles. I'm just telling you right now. I blew this
Speaker 5:  story wide open call Dr. Pulitzer right now, get him on the phone.
Speaker 5:  The banana was in Los Angeles sir. So this just keeps happening to him.
Speaker 5:  So, we post the story. This story You know itself has now has a life of its
Speaker 5:  own. A lot of people in our comments are like, I can't believe they did surgery
Speaker 5:  and had over five G just to troll me, which is great.
Speaker 5:  The point that I'm trying to make with this is one we were primed to
Speaker 5:  believe lies about five G by the five G hype industrial complex, right?
Speaker 5:  All of the carriers around the world insisted that five G was a race.
Speaker 5:  Really all that we've gotten out of it is higher network capacity in crowded
Speaker 5:  areas like that is more or less the shape of the
Speaker 5:  five G experience for most people. We
Speaker 6:  Got one more thing. We got misinformation about fruit surgery.
Speaker 5:  Well no, so the, because of all these promises, someone
Speaker 5:  who knows who was able to take this pretty familiar
Speaker 5:  video of a da Vinci robot doing its thing, another video of the robot doing
Speaker 5:  surgery on a grape went viral all by itself with no five G claims.
Speaker 5:  No five G, right? So they just took a banana video, they changed
Speaker 5:  it a little bit to make it different than the grape and then that went viral
Speaker 5:  on its own. And it, I'm telling you that's because we were primed to believe
Speaker 5:  these lies about five G. The second piece is that no one asked
Speaker 5:  even the video that I found that had the credit on it, like all
Speaker 5:  you had to do is chase that credit from X to Instagram and find
Speaker 5:  the surgeon saying no, this wasn't over five G. No one did that work.
Speaker 5:  We haven't fixed that problem at all. Right? And this is nothing, the stakes
Speaker 5:  of the banana getting the surgery over five G are zero. But just think about
Speaker 5:  how much other information like this that we are constantly exposed to that
Speaker 5:  no one is checking.
Speaker 4:  And next time just ask yourself, anytime you encounter something on the internet,
Speaker 4:  just ask Is the banana in Los Angeles?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, the banana is usually in Los Angeles. The
Speaker 4:  Banana is usually in Los Angeles.
Speaker 7:  I'm like turning into like a banana specialist You know. It's like my friends
Speaker 7:  make fun of me because they're like, oh you just operate on fruit all day.
Speaker 7:  That's all you do. I'm like, oh man. That was just during covid.
Speaker 5:  Dr. Rona was great. He was a great sport about it. So thank you to Dr. Kai
Speaker 5:  Rona for engaging in this silly story about the banana, especially for calling
Speaker 5:  me on vacation. That was very nice of him. He said Smart dimensions of weight
Speaker 5:  loss in Southern California. If you're in the market for robot surgery,
Speaker 5:  You know the banana survived. This is my contribution to The Vergecast this
Speaker 5:  week. I'm outta here. David, take it away.
Speaker 2:  Welcome
Speaker 4:  To The Vergecast the flagship podcast of Tech Temp and tech
Speaker 4:  Tober, andto and VE and December and all
Speaker 4:  of the other months to come. It's about to get wild in the tech world y'all.
Speaker 4:  And we're gonna be here for all of it. Alex Cranz is still here. Hi Alex.
Speaker 6:  Hi. What about July
Speaker 4:  To lie? No, if we have to July, we're never gonna make it to TechT. Don't,
Speaker 4:  don't do this to me. Richard here. Hi Richard. Hello.
Speaker 4:  I just want you to know that both I and everyone who listens to The Vergecast
Speaker 4:  prefers you to Neli. So I would just say this is an enormous upgrade over
Speaker 4:  what we had just before the break.
Speaker 8:  I get that a lot
Speaker 4:  People say that.
Speaker 6:  What's your take on bananas?
Speaker 4:  How many times have you done surgery on a banana?
Speaker 8:  I guarantee no banana shakes.
Speaker 4:  You don't have any takes on bananas. Now I now I feel obligated to press
Speaker 4:  on this theory. You don't have any takes on bananas.
Speaker 8:  Riley's banana shakes. Yes. Bananas. No, that's good.
Speaker 4:  Fair enough. That's good. So, we have a lot to cover. This is like the last
Speaker 4:  week of summer. It's about to truly get
Speaker 4:  bonkers in the tech world. Like we, we have this big run of events about
Speaker 4:  to happen. So this was kind of a mix of leaks
Speaker 4:  and information about what's coming this fall plus the last of this like
Speaker 4:  grab bag of news we've been talking about all summer. Like get all your stuff
Speaker 4:  out before Apple announces the iPhone event. Because basically as soon as
Speaker 4:  that happens, like it is the fall and chaos rains forever. But the,
Speaker 4:  the first thing I wanna do is talk about some of the stuff that's coming
Speaker 4:  this fall. And before we were coming into this, I made a list of all of
Speaker 4:  the events of like the next six weeks and I can, I just read
Speaker 4:  them to you and I need you all to feel the feelings that it made me feel
Speaker 4:  to write this list down. Are you guys ready? Do
Speaker 6:  I need like a drink first?
Speaker 4:  You're gonna need several drinks during and after. Take a shot for every
Speaker 4:  time. You're gonna have to work too much in the next six weeks. Don't you'll
Speaker 6:  Die.
Speaker 4:  Okay, here's what we have. IFA is happening right now. The Toronto
Speaker 4:  International Film Festival, which is a surprisingly cool source of movies,
Speaker 4:  especially like smaller stuff you might not have heard of starts September 7th,
Speaker 4:  the Apple event where we're gonna see the iPhone 15 is on September 12th.
Speaker 4:  The Detroit Auto Show is on September 13th. Amazon is having an event,
Speaker 4:  presumably one of those where they just launched 200 things that run Alexa
Speaker 4:  on September 20th. The next day on the 21st. Microsoft is having an
Speaker 4:  event, probably some surfaces. The code conference, which we're obviously
Speaker 4:  a huge part of starts on September 26th. Meta Connect is on
Speaker 4:  September 27th. We're gonna see the Quest three. There's a Google event.
Speaker 4:  We're probably gonna see the Pixel eight on October 4th. And then the next
Speaker 4:  day on October 5th is Samsung's developer conference where I
Speaker 4:  assume they'll just like talk about Bixby a bunch. And that's,
Speaker 4:  that's just between now and the first week of October. So like for all the
Speaker 4:  people who write to The Vergecast email and are like, Hey, can you talk more
Speaker 4:  about gadgets? Like, oh boy, it's coming, it's coming. Y
Speaker 4:  we miss the gadgets too. And they're about to come back with a, a true
Speaker 4:  vengeance. Are we like, is this good? Are we excited
Speaker 4:  about this?
Speaker 6:  I'm always excited about this time of year. 'cause I, I like all the travel,
Speaker 6:  I like the hustle and bustle. I like how you're just moving and then like
Speaker 6:  Thanksgiving comes and you're like, there's just an off switch and you
Speaker 6:  just stop functioning for a week ideally. And that's really, really nice.
Speaker 6:  Like, and and you just get all these cool things to play with for
Speaker 6:  a month and a half. And that's fun. I like that. I like playing with all
Speaker 6:  this stuff. I wish there were more like things that I really enjoy, like
Speaker 6:  not phones, but I'm still excited. Like I want e-readers and
Speaker 6:  and weird tablets.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Real lack of Cobo events this fall for Cranz. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Where are the Cobo events? Okay, where's the Nook event?
Speaker 6:  Like I, I want a Samsung event, but I just want it to be TVs and
Speaker 6:  speakers. That's it.
Speaker 4:  I'm imagining a Nook launch is just like one person at a Barnes and Noble
Speaker 4:  who like spots the new nook on her shelf and is like, oh look, a new nook.
Speaker 4:  And then the c e o just bursts out from a, a display of books and is like,
Speaker 4:  we made it for you
Speaker 6:  With like some music playing. Like the lights start changing.
Speaker 6:  Exactly. But they're like, if you wanna get to some snacks, they're right
Speaker 6:  in the back
Speaker 4:  At this. At the, it'd be great knockoff Starbucks that we put back there
Speaker 4:  in every one of our stores.
Speaker 4:  I don't know Richard, how do you feel about this?
Speaker 8:  Well and I, and I love that and I love the events, the pace of it. Not so
Speaker 8:  much the travel covering them from at home much better. But also
Speaker 8:  it's the time when all of that stuff that came out at CSS and that was announced
Speaker 8:  really early in the year, then you never heard about it again and companies
Speaker 8:  acted like they never announced it at all. When you ask them they're like,
Speaker 8:  like what's that? I don't, we would I would remember if you if you if we
Speaker 8:  had said that, but I don't now it's coming up like Samsung's like, oh yeah,
Speaker 8:  remember we launched 200 gaming monitors and we said they were going to be
Speaker 8:  released now. Now you can actually buy them. Maybe they might be at your
Speaker 8:  local Best Buy. So there's kind of both parts. You have these announcements
Speaker 8:  of products that are about to come out and will be out very soon. And you
Speaker 8:  also have these things that you've been waiting for so long that you probably
Speaker 8:  forgot about them, but here they are
Speaker 6:  And they're all monitors from Samsung. That's
Speaker 4:  True. The thing that precedes all of this actually is like back to school
Speaker 4:  season, which we've been in the throes of for like three weeks now. And that's
Speaker 4:  when everybody who's like selling large TVs and large computer
Speaker 4:  monitors and like wants to sell you a thing with gaming lights on it. Like
Speaker 4:  back to school season is their sweet spot. So we've, we've been in this like,
Speaker 4:  remember that thing you heard about at c e s space for the last few weeks?
Speaker 4:  And I agree it's been delightful. Samsung being like, remember that big screen
Speaker 4:  we told you about? Look at it. Here it is. I love it. I'm in on that.
Speaker 6:  You put it outside, it's great. It's bright.
Speaker 4:  Exactly. Okay, so we're gonna have plenty of time over the next six weeks
Speaker 4:  to cover all of this stuff. So we're just gonna like lightning round it for
Speaker 4:  now. We pulled out a bunch of stuff that's happening this fall. Let's, we
Speaker 4:  each picked one and we're just gonna talk about it for a little bit here
Speaker 4:  now, just kind of what's on our mind as a little preview as we go into the
Speaker 4:  fall. Richard, what'd you pick? The
Speaker 8:  Pixel eight. First of all, Google just can't stop leaking its own phones.
Speaker 8:  The Pixel eight pros showed up on Google's store website a
Speaker 8:  little bit early. Fortunately we didn't have to wa wonder whether or not
Speaker 8:  it was the Pixel eight pro or not because it had some alt text that very
Speaker 8:  clearly described it as the Pixel eight pro. This
Speaker 4:  Is definitely deliberate, right?
Speaker 8:  And the guy in the picture is also probably wearing a new Pixel watch. If
Speaker 8:  you take a look closely, it has to
Speaker 6:  Be deliberate. They did the alt text, like you don't mess that up.
Speaker 8:  It might be, but they also have a track record of doing this that's so long
Speaker 8:  that they might just be that incompetent. They, it's the perfect crime. What
Speaker 6:  If that's actually not incompetence? What if that's the plan? Like it's always
Speaker 6:  been the plan. So everybody's like, oh man, they're always leak. What's it
Speaker 6:  gonna be this time? I'll get excited this time. I don't think it's a good
Speaker 6:  plan, but like I think it could be the plan.
Speaker 4:  Was it last year with the Pixel seven that Google ended up just tweeting
Speaker 4:  out? Like, yeah, here it is. Like weeks ahead of the launch they were just
Speaker 4:  like, yeah, you've seen it enough times. Here it is. Enjoy. I think that
Speaker 4:  was last year. Pretty funny. I
Speaker 8:  Can't, I can't remember if that was the seven or the seven eight, but I I
Speaker 8:  think you're right. That was the seven. They were just like, yeah, look,
Speaker 8:  You know what it is.
Speaker 4:  I feel like it looks like the last one. Whatever
Speaker 8:  The, the bad news unfortunately this week about the Pixel is You know if
Speaker 8:  you bought a Pixel six and you subscribed to Pixel Pass like I did,
Speaker 8:  thinking that you'd be able to easily upgrade because Google said you would
Speaker 8:  be able to, they said you would, you won't, you couldn't upgrade for two
Speaker 8:  years. It was locked. You would have to wait two years to upgrade to a new
Speaker 8:  device. It is now one year in about 10 and a half months and
Speaker 8:  Google says, yeah, we're not doing that anymore. The Pixel pass is over.
Speaker 6:  Do you feel bait and switched?
Speaker 8:  I feel bait and something I don't know switched. Exactly. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Because before this, like before we started recording, you were like, I'm
Speaker 6:  not that upset about it, but you're like, walk me through that. Why aren't
Speaker 6:  you that upset about it?
Speaker 8:  Well, there's kind of two parts to it. What, what people paid for? What,
Speaker 8:  what I paid for? I got, I bought a phone, okay. That I paid for over the
Speaker 8:  course of several months. Also paid a, a kind of bundled discounted price
Speaker 8:  for a bunch of services like cloud storage that I don't really use YouTube
Speaker 8:  music that I do use a YouTube premium. It's pretty nice to forget that YouTube
Speaker 8:  has ads, got all that and even after the Pixel pass goes away,
Speaker 8:  they'll still have a discounted rate for those services and also insurance
Speaker 8:  for the phone and stuff like that. Like it, it was all in one thing. Sweet.
Speaker 8:  But when they announced it, they said that it was going to give you
Speaker 8:  easy device upgrades and you could do it after two years and now
Speaker 8:  no one will get that. Like, it's not even like they're cutting it off. And
Speaker 8:  some people took advantage, some people didn't zero. There there is zero
Speaker 8:  of that, which you can still get like a, a 0% a p r phone if
Speaker 8:  you want to get it like, and, and pay it over the course of months or something.
Speaker 8:  But you just can't do this package again. I
Speaker 4:  Think you're way underselling this. I think this is outrageous. Like I honestly
Speaker 4:  believe this is one of the like crueler
Speaker 4:  and more cynical things Google has done in a series of cruel
Speaker 4:  and cynical things to people who bought its products and cared about them.
Speaker 4:  A and they framed this in, in the course of building up the Pixel over the
Speaker 4:  years as like another way to believe that Google is gonna continue to care
Speaker 4:  about its hardware, right? Like it has said over and over for years now.
Speaker 4:  Like, we are in this for real. We are gonna take care of customers, we're
Speaker 4:  gonna keep giving you reasons to be part of this. We're gonna keep making
Speaker 4:  the deals better on and on and on. And this is like the most
Speaker 4:  deliberate shitty rug pull of a move. I can imagine. Even if
Speaker 4:  everyone more or less like you're saying comes out of it whole, which I actually
Speaker 4:  don't really think is true because I think there are a lot of people who
Speaker 4:  are now gonna go through much more messy and complicated upgrade
Speaker 4:  programs than it would've been if I could have just clicked a button and
Speaker 4:  shipped my thing to Google and gotten a new phone. Like that's a win in a
Speaker 4:  way that like, even if I have to go to my carrier store and do a trade-in
Speaker 4:  is more complicated. So even just making it harder is a, is a loss.
Speaker 4:  But I just think like from a pure, like showing people you
Speaker 4:  don't care about the move, this is such a crappy thing for Google to do
Speaker 8:  And, and the people who are the most dedicated to the brand, like yeah pro
Speaker 8:  probably the biggest Pixel fans who are like, okay, yeah, I'll get one and
Speaker 8:  then two years from now I'll get another one. I I'm willing to sign up. Si
Speaker 8:  let me do it. I
Speaker 6:  Think it's a mischaracterization to call you guys the biggest Pixel fans,
Speaker 6:  I think just Pixel fans, right?
Speaker 8:  Who's a bigger Pixel fan?
Speaker 6:  No, but like
Speaker 8:  I'll fight them.
Speaker 6:  Are there people that, is there anything above a Pixel fan? I think like
Speaker 6:  Pix being a Pixel fan in itself makes you a big Pixel fan.
Speaker 4:  So you're saying like there is no such thing as a small Pixel fan. There's
Speaker 8:  Not like a Zoom tattoo guy of the Pixel community. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  There's no such thing as a small Pixel fan. Like you have to have passion.
Speaker 4:  There are no small Pixel fans, only small people. Like
Speaker 6:  There's, it's like E Inc. There's no such thing as a small E
Speaker 6:  Ink fan. Like you could be like, oh that's a, like I'm not a big Ein fan,
Speaker 6:  I'm an E Ink fan because there's not a lot of us. There's not enough of
Speaker 6:  us for there to be like big ones and little ones
Speaker 8:  Now You know what, I think there are kind of Pixel casuals, okay, as it were.
Speaker 8:  And, and many of them may have picked up the Pixel Pass be because again
Speaker 8:  it was, it was a pretty good deal and a decent way to buy a phone. It was
Speaker 8:  like, oh, You know you can click a button and you can get all the things
Speaker 8:  in in one thing, not your carrier. You can go bring that how you want or
Speaker 8:  you could get Google Fi and get another $5 off. But now those people are
Speaker 8:  just, oh, not happening. I think it's
Speaker 6:  Just like, was just super, I don't know. I am, I'm, I know you're
Speaker 6:  processing it and I know you're in a place where you're like, it's fine,
Speaker 6:  it's chill. But I really hope like next week we come
Speaker 6:  back and we're like, Richard, how are you feeling about it? I hope you're
Speaker 6:  like mad 'cause I'm so mad on your behalf. I'm just like, they
Speaker 6:  like, I'm with David, I'm like, they they bait and switched y'all. They were
Speaker 6:  like, Hey come and do this Nas psych we're, we don't give a crap about you
Speaker 6:  guys. We're not even gonna last two years. Like it feels like
Speaker 6:  disingenuous marketing. It just feels gross and I'm
Speaker 6:  sad for you.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, but believing that Google would actually come through on something
Speaker 8:  that they promised is basically doing it to yourself. That's
Speaker 8:  like I, I've, I've got to take the l on that one. I I just, that should've,
Speaker 8:  should've seen that coming that, that that was, that was not a 5,000 IQ plus.
Speaker 8:  It
Speaker 4:  Really, it really is like terrifying how true that it's like I, I wrote,
Speaker 4:  I wrote a thing, I think it was last week about Google Keep their note taking
Speaker 4:  app, which has gotten a couple of like really nice upgrades. It's a good
Speaker 4:  app. It's kind of a thing people don't like know or use, but the people
Speaker 4:  who do really love it 'cause it's a really good simple note taking app. And
Speaker 4:  like overwhelmingly the comments on the story were like, don't talk about
Speaker 4:  ke Google will remember it exists and kill it. Like if an, if a Google
Speaker 4:  executive reads this, the one engineer who is still building features will
Speaker 4:  get fired and they'll kill this app. And it's like that's how people think
Speaker 4:  about this stuff. Like we literally cannot have nice things from Google anymore
Speaker 4:  because it just ruthlessly kills all of them. And I think
Speaker 4:  if I am the hardware team, they're still in this position of people
Speaker 4:  don't believe them, that they're serious and with, with good reason and lots
Speaker 4:  of evidence. And so like if I was Google, I would've gone way
Speaker 4:  out of my way to say this thing is going to continue to exist where if
Speaker 4:  we, even if we can't think of a way to make it worthwhile for the people
Speaker 4:  who already got it, even if they've already been made whole, we're gonna
Speaker 4:  come up with something new because what we need you to do is be loyal to
Speaker 4:  us and trust that we're gonna be loyal to you. And instead they're just like,
Speaker 4:  nevermind you get YouTube.
Speaker 6:  How, how do they, how can, like I feel like I had this exact conversation
Speaker 6:  two years ago with Dieter on The Vergecast about like when, when
Speaker 6:  that Pixel six came out. 'cause that was the big moment where, where that
Speaker 6:  was what the fourth iteration of, no, we really
Speaker 6:  care about hardware now. This is the moment. And we're like, okay.
Speaker 6:  And they did the Pixel Pass and it's like, okay, they feel like they, and
Speaker 6:  then they, they pulled the rug again. So it's like how do you build that
Speaker 6:  trust? You keep like destroying that trust every
Speaker 6:  time you get a little bit of it, you go and you like poop on it and say,
Speaker 6:  oh Pixel fans, the 12 of you that exist, including Richard,
Speaker 6:  get outta here. We don't like you. I just don't see how they, can they come
Speaker 6:  back from this?
Speaker 8:  Well I think the, I think the writing really was on the wall because when
Speaker 8:  you look at like when the Pixel fold came out and people asked about the
Speaker 8:  Pixel Pass, they were told basically the same language that they, they announced
Speaker 8:  this week that yeah, no, not so much happening. And
Speaker 8:  and I think that's part of what makes it worse is that they could have announced
Speaker 8:  this six months ago. Yeah. But people were like, oh, people were sitting
Speaker 8:  back. They saw, they said they saw the rumors. They were like, oh, Pixel
Speaker 8:  eight is coming out. I'll, I'll just be able to get that check. No, no,
Speaker 8:  you will not. You
Speaker 6:  Have felt better if they'd done it six months ago if they just like So you
Speaker 6:  could have like prepared emotionally.
Speaker 8:  Yes. Emotionally, yes.
Speaker 4:  Alright, let's, let's move on. We're gonna have a lot of time to yell at
Speaker 4:  Google between now and October. Do we know anything about the eight Pro yet?
Speaker 4:  By the way, Richard, is there any, we saw the one picture in the ad. Are
Speaker 4:  there like reputable rumors?
Speaker 8:  Yes, we've seen lots of pictures. We've seen renders, we've seen specs.
Speaker 8:  There's rumors that it'll have wifi seven, it'll probably still have the
Speaker 8:  same. The F c C filings came out this week. Also So, we know that
Speaker 8:  it's basically like the previous ones where like the pro has ultra
Speaker 8:  wideband, but the regular one does not. We've seen
Speaker 8:  kind of hardware specs about the chips. It's a Pixel. Okay. You, you You
Speaker 8:  know how these go. The, the real question is like what are the software features
Speaker 8:  going to be? And there's been leaks of something like video unblur. So just
Speaker 8:  like photo unblur. But for videos
Speaker 4:  That's cool. I just wanna say I was out sick for the last two days and somehow
Speaker 4:  wifi seven happened while I was gone for two days. So that's cool
Speaker 4:  and fun and I'll catch up on that over here. But I do think
Speaker 4:  I'm actually more interested in the Pixel than the iPhone this year because
Speaker 4:  like Google has been saying this thing about like on-device AI for You know
Speaker 4:  years now. And this seems like one of the first years that
Speaker 4:  if it wants to do some like really genuinely wild on-device AI stuff,
Speaker 4:  it might actually be able to. So I think that's gonna be very interesting.
Speaker 4:  But again, we have lots of time to talk about that. I'm gonna go next 'cause
Speaker 4:  I wanna talk about Taylor Swift and Cranz. You can go last. Okay. The true
Speaker 4:  events of the fall I think we can agree is that Taylor
Speaker 4:  Swift's Eras tour is coming to a m c theaters across the
Speaker 4:  country in October. As far as I know, at least from what I've seen so far,
Speaker 4:  this is all kind of just happening. We don't know for how long. We
Speaker 4:  just know that they're doing at least four showings a day at every theater.
Speaker 4:  And that a m c has upgraded its ticket capabilities for five times
Speaker 4:  as much demand as it has had before because of all the Swifties
Speaker 4:  who did or did not get tickets to the Aris tour. I honestly believe this
Speaker 4:  might be like the biggest movie of all time if it was allowed to be.
Speaker 6:  It's a like concert movie, right? It's it's not live streams.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So from just like the little tiny bits I've seen, you can see some
Speaker 4:  snippets on like Taylor Swift's TikTok account was I think where I saw it.
Speaker 4:  It looks basically like a super well produced concert film.
Speaker 6:  I love that. That sounds great.
Speaker 4:  It sounds amazing. And you'll get to see it in like a gigantic theater with
Speaker 4:  You know cool surround sound and it'll be a million swifties like they even
Speaker 4:  said bring the friendship bracelets dress in all the Eras stuff. Like you
Speaker 4:  better believe I will be there giving people bracelets that say
Speaker 4:  Verge Swifties and we can all be Verge swifties together. I
Speaker 6:  I won't be there but I will support all of you. Are there Verge, Swifties
Speaker 6:  Swifties besides you and Neli?
Speaker 4:  I think sneakily like two thirds of The Verge is Swifties. I
Speaker 4:  know at least a couple of people tried and failed multiple times to get Eras
Speaker 4:  tickets. Richard is being suspiciously quiet, which makes me think he's definitely
Speaker 4:  a swifty for sure.
Speaker 6:  I was like, hmm, look at Richard's off looking in a corner. Richard.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I just don't know what's going on here.
Speaker 8:  I'm very happy for you
Speaker 4:  Though. The cultural event of the summer and fall and winter
Speaker 4:  and the rest of our lives. I'm sure this movie might be in theaters for a
Speaker 4:  decade. Richard,
Speaker 6:  She, she fixed the economy. Like, like they keep being like, oh yeah, the,
Speaker 6:  the Eras to her increased spending, like it fixed the economy.
Speaker 6:  I don't think it fixed the economy, but it increased spending. What if she
Speaker 6:  like lowers the rent? What if she, what if she like
Speaker 6:  changes the world with this tour? I fully believe in her, her
Speaker 6:  economic prowess. Oh,
Speaker 4:  I agree. At some point when the, when the era's tour ends, we're going to
Speaker 4:  find somebody fun to talk to about this and we're gonna go through like the
Speaker 4:  insane like stratospheric records that this
Speaker 4:  tour has set and nothing will ever top it ever again. And
Speaker 4:  like the things she has, it's insane and wild and I'm very excited about
Speaker 4:  this movie. And that's all everybody, you probably can't get tickets if you're
Speaker 4:  hearing this now. Well it created
Speaker 8:  Congressional hearings about Ticketmaster.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah, well yeah, yeah. She broke Ticketmaster. She's gonna make a m c
Speaker 4:  the most valuable company in the universe now. This is, she runs
Speaker 4:  the economy. This is what it is. Alright, Cranz, you're up. What do you got?
Speaker 6:  Okay, iPhone's coming two weeks. I'm really mad. I bought
Speaker 6:  an iPhone 14 pro last year and I was really excited about it and I was like,
Speaker 6:  I'll be fine. I don't need the next one. And now the next sounds like it's
Speaker 6:  almost definitely gonna have USB C and the FOMO
Speaker 6:  is extreme for me at the moment and like I'm, I'm locked into
Speaker 6:  this payment plan for another year. So it's not like I'm not, I'm I'm cheap,
Speaker 6:  I'm not gonna be going and buying it, but I'm gonna be regretting my life
Speaker 6:  choices a lot. Like come two weeks from now,
Speaker 4:  You didn't get the iPhone upgrade plan.
Speaker 6:  No, I wanna pay in cash because it didn't work with my Apple Pay
Speaker 6:  card, I think. And I want my, I want my 3%.
Speaker 4:  I like imagining that you just walk in with a bag of nickels and just like
Speaker 4:  throw it on the desk in the Apple store and you're like, gimme an iPhone.
Speaker 6:  I just whip it across the, the genius bar at 'em. Yeah, but
Speaker 6:  it it seems exciting. I, I don't know. Does iPhones are
Speaker 6:  kind of weird in a weird place, right? Like they yeah, they're in a weird
Speaker 6:  place. Last year the exciting thing was the dynamic island and we, we enjoyed
Speaker 6:  the island, but try explaining to anyone who doesn't listen to The
Speaker 6:  Vergecast what the Dynamic Island is. And that's a less fun
Speaker 6:  conversation.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They'll just say it's that thing at the top of the screen that screws
Speaker 4:  up all the apps sometimes. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  The, they're just kind of annoyed with you. But like USB c i
Speaker 6:  I'm su like beyond excited about USB C I just got a new USB
Speaker 6:  C charger from from Anker and I'm so like it
Speaker 6:  charges my phone or not my phone. It charges like my, my
Speaker 6:  computer, it charges my Steam Deck, it charges
Speaker 6:  just everything I own that I can plug USB C into and it's
Speaker 6:  wonderful and I'm like, oh I want my phone to do that too.
Speaker 6:  That seems cool.
Speaker 6:  So USB C alone has, has been pumped for it and we're getting USB C on the
Speaker 6:  AirPod case. I'm not gonna buy it because again, like if my phone
Speaker 6:  doesn't do USB c I refuse to let my AirPods case do USB C
Speaker 6:  it has to wait in line. But this is like exciting. If you like
Speaker 6:  USB C it's gonna be a big event. If you like anything else, it's gonna
Speaker 6:  be an iPhone event.
Speaker 8:  Well also if you like wireless charging, I mean we'll talk to John in a bit,
Speaker 8:  but the big news at IFA is these wireless chargers that are getting announced
Speaker 8:  with the Q two standard that the iPhone 15 may
Speaker 8:  support. We'll I guess we'll find out and allow kind of non MagSafe
Speaker 8:  chargers to charge iPhones at the same rate as MagSafe and also You know
Speaker 8:  kind of other devices, other phones that support 15 watt wireless charging.
Speaker 8:  So if you like wireless charging, this is your moment. Oh, I
Speaker 6:  Got a wireless charger too. I spent like $150 or,
Speaker 8:  Or if you wanna buy a new charging stand or something like that. Yeah, don't
Speaker 8:  for like the next couple
Speaker 6:  Times don't, don't be me, I bought it last month. I do not read our website
Speaker 6:  enough is what happened there.
Speaker 6:  A lot of regret.
Speaker 4:  I was talking to somebody at one of the charging companies the other day
Speaker 4:  and, and they were basically saying that the USB C thing is cool
Speaker 4:  but it's a mirage because wireless is the real thing that it's like the actual
Speaker 4:  arc that we're on is wireless charging taking over. And
Speaker 4:  it would've been great if USB C had been ready You know 12 years ago and
Speaker 4:  we could have just gone straight to that but we didn't. And that's fine.
Speaker 4:  But where we're actually headed and I think where Apple has pretty clearly
Speaker 4:  been wanting to head for a long time is wireless charging. Wireless charging
Speaker 4:  is mostly still very bad and not as good
Speaker 4:  or fast as wired charging. So I think we still have a ways to go, but I agree.
Speaker 4:  I think, I think especially some of the stuff we're seeing at EFA that we're
Speaker 4:  gonna talk about a little later, it's, it's pretty exciting. Richard, do
Speaker 4:  you care about this? iPhone convince me to care about this iPhone. Well
Speaker 6:  I had more things to convince you about the iPhone.
Speaker 4:  Oh, you're not done. Okay. You didn't talk about the action button yet. Hit
Speaker 4:  me.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Wait, I was about to say the action button. I think it's the stupidest
Speaker 6:  thing in the world and I'm not excited about the action button. I I would
Speaker 6:  be excited about the action button if it didn't replace the mute button and
Speaker 6:  like if I'm just gonna have to program it to be the mute button, then it's
Speaker 6:  not an action button, it's just a mute button that I had to like do an extra
Speaker 6:  step to make a mute button. I want, I want both.
Speaker 4:  I just straight up had to look at my phone to see, see if it still had a
Speaker 4:  mute button. That thing has been on mute since the minute I took it outta
Speaker 4:  the package and I have not touched it since anyone who lets their phone ring
Speaker 4:  loud is 75 years old. Blanket rule of the
Speaker 4:  universe. If your phone rings, you are a hundred years old and
Speaker 6:  Should, don't you like being able to just go, oh, is it on mute?
Speaker 6:  Take a quick look or like reach into your pocket and go, eh, and kind of
Speaker 6:  hit the little switch while you're walking down the street and be like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  it's on mute. I I I just want, I want that. I like that.
Speaker 6:  I don't wanna have to like pull my phone out, program the mute button and
Speaker 6:  then hit mute.
Speaker 8:  You don't miss the art of Ring of ring tones.
Speaker 6:  They're trying to bring ring tones back by getting rid of the mute button.
Speaker 6:  No,
Speaker 4:  Maybe it's the opposite. Maybe they're killing it forever. It's like your
Speaker 4:  phone can no longer make noise when it rings would be like
Speaker 4:  truly Apple's most innovative feature in years.
Speaker 6:  They have to go to my mother's house and explain that to her. Like
Speaker 6:  I'm not doing it. I'm not letting anyone at the like Apple Tim Cook
Speaker 6:  has to fly to my mother's house and explain to her why her phone doesn't
Speaker 6:  ring anymore.
Speaker 4:  Does your mom have the ringtone that rings like an old timey phone? My
Speaker 4:  mother-in-law has that ringtone and it drives me nuts.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah, she's got the ringtone and she's got it on her watch too,
Speaker 6:  which she answers in the supermarket. I learned so sorry to all the
Speaker 6:  H H E Bs shoppers of Texas for having to listen to all
Speaker 6:  of my conversations with my mom while she's picking up groceries. It's great.
Speaker 4:  Alright, before we go to break Alex, you wrote down one other one in the
Speaker 4:  fall, things coming up that you're excited about. Give us 30 seconds. Then.
Speaker 4:  We're going yes,
Speaker 6:  Starfield. It's the new Bethesda game. Like all other
Speaker 6:  Bethesda games, I think it's gonna be stupid, but then I'm, I'm reading all
Speaker 6:  the reviews and now I really wanna play it. But I also know that like every
Speaker 6:  other Bethesda game, I'm gonna play it for a hundred, 200 hours. Never finish
Speaker 6:  it and tell everybody it sucks. I'm so excited. So
Speaker 4:  Stupid is not the word you're looking for here.
Speaker 6:  It's gonna be stupid. It's gonna be like the characters look stupid. I
Speaker 6:  feel stupid playing it because I'm like, oh you can't look dumb. Like the
Speaker 6:  Bethesda characters look dumb and that's a bummer. And so
Speaker 6:  far that seems to be the case for this game as well. But also I
Speaker 6:  wanna travel around delivering coffee in space. That seems cool. I don't
Speaker 6:  wanna do that in real life, but I wanna do that in Space.
Speaker 4:  Richard's just like, if it's not Overwatch, don't even talk to me.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I'm sorry. I I I want another games as a service shooter. Just something
Speaker 8:  I can play in 15 minute. You
Speaker 6:  Just wanna play Red Fall forever. Like that's,
Speaker 8:  If it weren't so terrible, if it were just any slight bit less terrible I
Speaker 8:  would, I would be playing it right now.
Speaker 4:  I like it. All right, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back
Speaker 4:  and we're gonna talk about all the other mishmash of nonsense
Speaker 4:  happening in the tech world this week. We'll be right back
Speaker 9:  This week on Intuit a TV and movie fall preview
Speaker 9:  from the new Scorsese film Killers of the Flower Moon. I
Speaker 10:  Was sent down from Washington DC to see about these murders
Speaker 9:  To the Golden Bachelor. He's Gary and
Speaker 4:  I'm your first
Speaker 11:  Golden Bachelor.
Speaker 9:  We'll tell you what to watch. Also a few recommendations of
Speaker 9:  stuff you might've missed so far this year, like Project Greenlight.
Speaker 13:  It's not excellent but it is a fascinating portrait of making
Speaker 13:  movies and the problem with making movies at this
Speaker 13:  moment.
Speaker 9:  This week on Intuit Vultures Pop culture podcast.
Speaker 12:  Hey, it's Casey Newton, founder and editor of Platformer, a publication
Speaker 12:  about tech, social media and democracy. And I wanted to let You know that
Speaker 12:  applications are still open for this year's code conference. It's hosted
Speaker 12:  by me and my friends, NELI Patel from The Verge and Julia Borson from
Speaker 12:  cnbc. We're gonna be taking the stage with x slash Twitter, c o
Speaker 12:  Lindy Yao, gm, C E O, Mary Barra, Microsoft C
Speaker 12:  T O, Kevin Scott, and many more of the biggest names in tech and business.
Speaker 12:  It's all happening soon, September 26th and 27th and
Speaker 12:  spots are filling up fast. So apply now at Vox
Speaker 12:  media.com/code. That's Vox
Speaker 12:  media.com/code. We'll see you there.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. So lots of little news this week. There
Speaker 4:  was some threads news, it seems like we're getting search Sony
Speaker 4:  raised the prices on PlayStation plus we've got some
Speaker 4:  X doing sketchy stuff. I don't really wanna talk about that anymore.
Speaker 4:  Wireless carriers doing weird stuff. Again, call of duty using AI to moderate
Speaker 4:  voice chats, which is just America's worst idea in years.
Speaker 4:  Let's, let's just blast through all this. We can't get to all of this so
Speaker 4:  let's just lightning round this again.
Speaker 4:  Cranz, you're you were, you're still on the roll. You get to go first.
Speaker 6:  I'm so excited. So Dolby just announced this thing, it's called Dolby Atmos
Speaker 6:  Flex Connect and the name is very stupid. That's okay because
Speaker 6:  what it could do could potentially be very, very cool, which is that it will
Speaker 6:  automatically like just make your speakers, your
Speaker 6:  wireless speakers work with your TV provided they both support Dolby
Speaker 6:  Atmos Flex Connect and only one of TV will support that in the next year
Speaker 6:  that we know of. And it's from T C L, so it's not gonna work with any of
Speaker 6:  your current stuff and it's probably not gonna work with most of your stuff
Speaker 6:  next year, but like five years from now, this is gonna be
Speaker 6:  sick as hell. And I'm, I'm actually excited about it because like Sonos
Speaker 6:  has done a lot of this stuff in the past. They do the automatic calibration
Speaker 6:  and everything like that, but it's just Sonos and you have to use Sonos speakers
Speaker 6:  and you're stuck in that. And this means like okay I can go get any speaker,
Speaker 6:  like any wireless speaker I want and it's gonna bounce,
Speaker 6:  it's gonna take and pinging the audio from that speaker. The
Speaker 6:  TV's got its own microphones built in, it's gonna receive it and it's gonna
Speaker 6:  go oh and fix it all. You don't have to worry about a stupid soundbar because
Speaker 6:  sound bars are bad. I'm sorry you even though I own one, you don't
Speaker 6:  have to worry about like messing with anything. It should just
Speaker 6:  all work. And for like the last what 20
Speaker 6:  years TV audio has not just worked.
Speaker 6:  So that feels appealing even though you're still like
Speaker 6:  now gonna have to buy additional speakers for your tv. At least
Speaker 6:  it should make it a lot easier and more natural
Speaker 6:  and hopefully cheaper than the Soto solution, which
Speaker 6:  is why I'm not buying a new iPhone this year.
Speaker 4:  So the idea seems to be, if I'm understanding this correctly, yes
Speaker 4:  and I'm genuinely not sure that I am, but if I, if I'm understanding this
Speaker 4:  correctly, it's that you don't have to buy like a
Speaker 4:  full surround sound set. You don't have to buy that one
Speaker 4:  gigantic box at Best Buy. You can, you can sort of bring your own
Speaker 4:  speakers and essentially as long as they're like compatible with this one
Speaker 4:  Flex Connect spec, Dolby will be able to
Speaker 4:  stitch them all together. You'll be able to put them in a system and it'll
Speaker 4:  work.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that that, that's it. Like theoretically if Vizio supports
Speaker 6:  this, you can go get those super cheap but decent
Speaker 6:  Vizio speakers set it all up and then instead
Speaker 6:  of like getting all weird and finicky and trying to use the not very good
Speaker 6:  super cheap Vizio technology to make the speakers sound good, just have
Speaker 6:  Dolby do it and do it well and it'll all sound
Speaker 6:  well. So
Speaker 4:  This seems great. This also seems like a thing that shouldn't be that hard
Speaker 4:  to do and probably should have happened 15 years ago, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. Like Sonos does it now and Sonos is wildly
Speaker 6:  expensive. The TV companies have not really cared about speaker. Like
Speaker 6:  they haven't cared about this, they haven't needed to. 'cause they're like
Speaker 6:  okay for them there's three, there's three TV
Speaker 6:  buyers, right? There's the people who spend all of
Speaker 6:  their time in AV forum. It's like me and Eli like we're over,
Speaker 6:  we're over there and and we're gonna go buy a bunch of stuff and we're gonna
Speaker 6:  spend 12 years working on our system and it's gonna sound beautiful and
Speaker 6:  people will ask us how much we spent and we'll have to run from the room
Speaker 6:  screaming and saying you don't need to know that. That's us. Then
Speaker 6:  there's like me a couple of years ago and a lot of
Speaker 6:  people, probably most people listening to this who are like, I want speakers
Speaker 6:  that sound good. So you go and you buy some speakers, they're Sonos or Visio
Speaker 6:  or whatever and you plug 'em into your TV and it sounds reasonably
Speaker 6:  good, probably not as good as any C R T TV you had 20 years ago
Speaker 6:  but decent. And then there's everybody else who doesn't
Speaker 6:  listen to The Vergecast and doesn't know that all speakers and TVs suck
Speaker 6:  because speakers require space and TVs don't give them any. And so
Speaker 6:  they go and they buy a TV and they're like, wow, the speakers stop. So they
Speaker 6:  turn the volume way up, they turn on the subtitles and they're just like,
Speaker 6:  why can't I hear anything anymore? And while part of that is definitely the
Speaker 6:  fault of Hollywood, so much of it is the fault of bad TV bakers
Speaker 6:  not caring. And they're like, well if you care that much, go be one of those
Speaker 6:  people who buys speakers from us and puts it in the
Speaker 6:  back. We don't care enough to like make it nice but do it.
Speaker 4:  There was this post I saw, I forget which social platform it was on, there's
Speaker 4:  too many of them at this point. But there was somebody who was like, guys
Speaker 4:  you don't even know. The reason you think Netflix sounds so bad is because
Speaker 4:  by default its sound is turned to 5.1 and if you are using
Speaker 4:  your built-in speakers, that means you're not getting the right ones. Just
Speaker 4:  go and switch it to stereo and everything will be amazing. And this post
Speaker 4:  went like hugely viral. Everybody like, oh my God, you've solved it.
Speaker 4:  And I was just like, my guy, like this ain't it. You didn't do it. You just
Speaker 4:  had a setting wrong on your Netflix. Like I don't know what to tell you.
Speaker 4:  That is not it. And also you're gonna put it on stereo and you're gonna be
Speaker 4:  like, oh, now it sounds bad in stereo
Speaker 6:  From two sides instead of five.
Speaker 4:  I don't know. Richard, you're, you're a guy who lives in V forums and owns
Speaker 4:  30 or 40 televisions. Does, does this idea excite you?
Speaker 8:  I think it sounds great from the idea that, okay, so you can just go get
Speaker 8:  some speakers and press the button and it'll say, alright,
Speaker 8:  I'll get, I'll get the sound figured out. And that's kind of always been
Speaker 8:  the problem of Atmos is that they've programmed in the sound. So it doesn't
Speaker 8:  need like, okay so how many channels do you have? Do you have two channels?
Speaker 8:  Do you have 2.1? Do you have 5.1? Do you have 7.1? Do you have 9.1
Speaker 8:  8.2? No, I have some speakers do it for me. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  and you'll do it also. They have never gotten
Speaker 8:  surround sound audio, right? Ever at any point. It has never been seamless.
Speaker 8:  It has never worked the way that it should. So I don't know why we should
Speaker 8:  expect that. It will. And
Speaker 6:  I'm an optimist at heart Richard.
Speaker 8:  The, the thing is the technology exists, like this should be possible. This,
Speaker 8:  this is the kind of thing that like with a microphone in the tv with speakers,
Speaker 8:  with the right technology you could do it. I'm sure that it will make Dolby
Speaker 8:  money as they get licensing fees from all the speakers that are now compatible.
Speaker 8:  How long it'll be be until I can use this in my own living room. I'm not
Speaker 8:  so sure.
Speaker 6:  Well You know if it sucks, which it very well
Speaker 6:  could, but it's a good idea. Somebody else could go
Speaker 6:  like, can be like, oh, like physio could just go and do that.
Speaker 8:  Well it'll be d t s not Flex Connect.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. D t s Flex Connect.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I just, I always think about like the, so the the Ultimate Ears
Speaker 4:  boom series are like the best Bluetooth speakers on the planet. And one of
Speaker 4:  the things that they've done really well is you can actually daisy chain
Speaker 4:  a bunch of them together and it's not terribly complicated. It just
Speaker 4:  like synchronizes the sound coming out of a bunch of speakers, right? So
Speaker 4:  if you have a big house and you don't wanna rig up a whole speaker system,
Speaker 4:  you can just put four Bluetooth speakers around the house, sync them all
Speaker 4:  together and it plays. And the fact that that alone is like an innovative
Speaker 4:  feature in speakers is bananas. Like you can do this with
Speaker 4:  Bluetooth, you can do this with wifi. Like this is not a complicated
Speaker 4:  technological problem. We've done much harder things than
Speaker 4:  make speakers play. And I think like to Richard's point about
Speaker 4:  You know a a million different kinds of surround sound, none of them that
Speaker 4:  have ever been done very well. I think just the fact that it's as difficult
Speaker 4:  as it is to buy like two pretty good speakers, stick them on the either side
Speaker 4:  of your television and have it work is nuts. Like that's the reason I tell
Speaker 4:  people to buy Soundbars because you don't have to program it You know where
Speaker 4:  it goes, just don't worry about it. Even buying two speakers
Speaker 4:  ends up being more work than it's worth for not that much better sound most
Speaker 4:  of the time. So I think the idea that it's going to like perfectly correctly
Speaker 4:  tune your room. I, I agree. I don't trust, but I really hope it
Speaker 4:  works. Like I super, super, super hope it works. 'cause it would be awesome
Speaker 4:  five
Speaker 6:  Years from now, it'll be, it'll be cheaper than Sonos
Speaker 6:  and not as good but better than nothing.
Speaker 4:  I mean, I'll take it,
Speaker 6:  Which is the entire story of a home theater audio at this
Speaker 6:  point
Speaker 4:  As is Dolby almost. Got it. Right. That's like, that's
Speaker 4:  Dolby's slogan. Like we all, we almost got it this time.
Speaker 6:  No, we're not gonna, we're gonna, we're gonna run for the last second screwed
Speaker 6:  up. Sorry guys.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Richard, what's your next one? Yeah,
Speaker 8:  You know my, my thing is Google's Duet ai becoming
Speaker 8:  available in Docs and Gmail and other Workspace apps. You know you reported
Speaker 8:  on this this week. I wanna hear more from you about the people you talk to
Speaker 8:  and all the things they said. But what strikes me is the price. We saw
Speaker 8:  this with the Microsoft binging AI and then making it available in Microsoft
Speaker 8:  365 and it looks like Google's going about the same, same way
Speaker 8:  they're charging, it looks like $30 per person per month. That's a lot of
Speaker 8:  money. And as soon as I saw that with the Microsoft thing, and now I see
Speaker 8:  it with Google, I understand why they're pushing AI so hard because they're
Speaker 8:  gonna make a lot of money from it. The bad news is that the companies who
Speaker 8:  buy it, they're probably gonna wanna save money somewhere else. Whether or
Speaker 8:  not these AI tools actually work or make people more productive or do not,
Speaker 8:  they're going to be spending a lot of money on them. So there's gonna be
Speaker 8:  cut somewhere else and it, it just seems like that's assured.
Speaker 6:  Is it $30 per month per head
Speaker 6:  user?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like
Speaker 6:  Per account? Yes.
Speaker 4:  Yep.
Speaker 6:  No, yeah. Nope. Hard pass.
Speaker 6:  That's a no for me it would have to be magic.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Like do You know? Do you, can you then, can you just think for a second
Speaker 8:  how good it would have to be to justify that price? It would
Speaker 6:  Have to be magic.
Speaker 4:  There's like a, there's a set of people who will just get
Speaker 4:  this because it's useful and there's a set of these things that I think are
Speaker 4:  like time saving in a way that will actually be meaningful to people,
Speaker 4:  right? Like the, the idea that I can, I don't know, take a
Speaker 4:  Google doc and say Duet turn this into a spreadsheet and
Speaker 4:  it'll turn it into like a
Speaker 4:  remedial but functional Google Slides Deck in 45 seconds
Speaker 4:  is like, there are a lot of people to whom that is worth $30 a month
Speaker 4:  easily. There are a lot of people who essentially do that one thing for a
Speaker 4:  living. And I think the question of what happens to those people to your
Speaker 4:  point is really interesting and really complicated and probably really messy
Speaker 4:  and bad in the long run for those people. But I, I tend
Speaker 4:  to agree that I, I think the number of people for whom there are
Speaker 4:  $30 a month worth of good features in Google
Speaker 4:  Duet is gonna be smaller than Google thinks. And I think it's gonna be the
Speaker 4:  same with copilot that like if you just give it to people, they'll use it
Speaker 4:  because having a thing that can You know, clean up my email grammar or
Speaker 4:  make a graph out of my spreadsheet data for me is useful.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I, I I would use that if it was just there. But paying
Speaker 4:  what amounts to like three x, the price of Google Workspace
Speaker 4:  for that is super, super, super steep. And I don't
Speaker 4:  know that Google has made a particularly convincing case that this is gonna
Speaker 4:  like work. Like we've all used Bard in the last six months. I don't really
Speaker 4:  have any reason to believe this thing is going to be as good as they say
Speaker 4:  it is.
Speaker 6:  Is it gonna work with like your calendar?
Speaker 4:  What do you mean?
Speaker 6:  The only thing I would pay $30 a month for is an
Speaker 6:  AI that just understood and did all my calendar scheduling for me.
Speaker 6:  Like including the polite dms to people to be like, can I put some time on
Speaker 6:  your calendar? Is this okay all like, I want it to just do all of that.
Speaker 6:  If it did all of that, I, I personally would pay $30. I don't know if
Speaker 6:  I could get Vox Media to agree to pay $30, but like I'd
Speaker 6:  be like, oh, I'll see you check. Let's do that on
Speaker 4:  The side. There's an app called Motion, I think it's motion.io I think
Speaker 4:  that does exactly that and I think it's like $15 a month.
Speaker 6:  But is it trustworthy?
Speaker 4:  I haven't used it in a while, but by all accounts it's actually pretty good.
Speaker 4:  I hate those apps. Yeah. Like even as a person who is like obsessed with
Speaker 4:  my calendar and spends way too much time, like managing the blocks in my
Speaker 4:  calendar, I
Speaker 6:  Can, I can't trust them.
Speaker 4:  No. 'cause it's like tell us about your flow state and we'll schedule and
Speaker 4:  I'm like, I don't know. It like depends on what I ate for lunch that day.
Speaker 4:  Like leave me alone calendar.
Speaker 6:  I was like, no, you should just know. Like I basically want an assistant
Speaker 6:  but it's only $30 a month. I am the problem with the economy,
Speaker 6:  I'm why they're all so excited.
Speaker 4:  You're literally the reason they built Duetta. Like here's the
Speaker 4:  best we can do, but
Speaker 6:  I don't trust it. Like a person I would be like, Hey, don't do that in
Speaker 6:  the future. And they'd be like, yeah, pay me more than $30 a month. That'd
Speaker 6:  be fair. Fair. But like I, I
Speaker 6:  just can't imagine trusting it because when it would
Speaker 6:  screw up, it would probably screw up in the worst way. It would probably
Speaker 6:  like decline an invite from an Apple event, which would be
Speaker 6:  hysterical and be like, no, you're not going to that. Decline it and be like,
Speaker 6:  you've gotta go do your performance review. And I'd be like, no, those are
Speaker 6:  two different things and one matters more in this moment. Performance reviews
Speaker 6:  always matter, but not on the same day as Apple events.
Speaker 4:  I don't know, I just think like
Speaker 4:  my initial read of Duet is very much that like,
Speaker 4:  this is clear evidence that Google has not figured out what the killer
Speaker 4:  app for AI is for. And it's the same with Microsoft where they, they've come
Speaker 4:  up with a lot of relatively small, mostly
Speaker 4:  useful sounding things that these tools can do without anything that you're
Speaker 4:  immediately like, oh, I need that in my life. I'm also cognizant of the
Speaker 4:  fact that the three of us do not have real jobs
Speaker 4:  and that most jobs involve email spreadsheets
Speaker 4:  and slide decks. And most people and
Speaker 4:  most companies would be willing to pay a lot of money to make any of those
Speaker 4:  three things slightly more efficient. And
Speaker 4:  like Google's bet is essentially like, okay, if we can make each one of one
Speaker 4:  of those a little tiny bit better, we can help you write emails faster. We
Speaker 4:  can help you like get more actual data out of your spreadsheet.
Speaker 4:  We can help you make more beautiful decks on deadline.
Speaker 4:  Like that might work.
Speaker 6:  All they have to do is be like, we'll do the pivot tables and you'll never
Speaker 6:  have to understand what a pivot table is. Like a
Speaker 6:  lot of places would probably be like, yeah, $30 a month, never
Speaker 6:  have to learn about a pivot table.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And then every just out of business school employee on planet
Speaker 4:  Earth just got fired. Like right as I was saying that sentence, they all
Speaker 4:  lost their jobs. Yeah. Sorry
Speaker 6:  Guys.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. If you are a like junior account executive
Speaker 4:  at a marketing company, like you're so screwed. And I'm so sorry.
Speaker 8:  Fortunately the thing that you'll, that we'll be replacing you, our boss
Speaker 8:  asked Bard, what's the coolest thing anyone could do and receive some
Speaker 8:  answers. Can you
Speaker 4:  Just read the
Speaker 8:  List? Some cool things people have done. It's so good. Include
Speaker 8:  walking to a destination, even if it's 3000 miles away
Speaker 8:  playing World of Warcraft for 100 hours in a week. Yes.
Speaker 6:  I'm cool.
Speaker 8:  Being in a movie with Will Smith. Pretty cool. Pretty cool, cool
Speaker 8:  things in the world include chewing gum skateboards and cohort
Speaker 8:  outfits. I don't know. I don't know what those are. I guess I'm not cool
Speaker 8:  enough.
Speaker 6:  You're
Speaker 8:  Not cool enough. The bar knows.
Speaker 4:  Don't feel bad. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Who do we also cool for like 1995 with a
Speaker 6:  queuing gum and a skateboard? We were bad asses.
Speaker 4:  You know, there's like a, there's a marketing person at like a fashion agency
Speaker 4:  right now who is furiously Googling what is the coolest thing anyone can
Speaker 4:  do. And just being like, I would not pay $30 a month for this.
Speaker 6:  This is it.
Speaker 4:  And I just, I very much enjoyed that. Eli's when when he posted that, he
Speaker 4:  was like, I can't believe it didn't say a back flip, which is objectively
Speaker 4:  the coolest thing. Could It's, yeah. It's very good. But I, I like
Speaker 4:  all of this stuff to me just says, none of this is
Speaker 4:  finished yet. And it's kind of wild to see
Speaker 4:  who is willing to pay for this stuff even though it's at the very, very,
Speaker 4:  very, very beginning of whatever it's gonna someday be. And
Speaker 4:  who is going to say at the end of their free trial, this is neat.
Speaker 4:  Not worth $30 a month per person for my entire company. And
Speaker 4:  if I were a betting man, I would bet on that second thing being a lot
Speaker 4:  more true than either Google or Microsoft. Think
Speaker 6:  How long is the trial?
Speaker 4:  I don't know.
Speaker 6:  Because like if it's like a year long trial, maybe they have a shot they
Speaker 6:  can take the year to figure out how to make it useful. If it's a one month
Speaker 6:  trial like, yo, what are you doing? You gave, you gave Richard
Speaker 6:  more time than you're giving these people. Come on.
Speaker 4:  I think it might be 30 days. I think that is, I think that might be how long.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 8:  Absolutely not. I think their bet is that the executive who makes the decision
Speaker 8:  is the person who's going to find it really useful right away. And they'll
Speaker 8:  just say, yeah, we'll sign off on it and we'll fire a hundred other people.
Speaker 8:  It doesn't matter how, how well it works or does not work. And we just saw
Speaker 8:  this week of, I think Walmart announced that, that they're gonna roll out
Speaker 8:  AI for basically all their office employees. And they didn't say which one
Speaker 8:  they're using or how much they're paying, paying or anything. But I wonder
Speaker 8:  how, how much, how long they'll stick with it and how many people will continue
Speaker 8:  to have access to it.
Speaker 6:  It's gonna be the Walmart ai, that's what it's gonna be called.
Speaker 6:  And they're not gonna pay it very well, but it's gonna do the
Speaker 6:  job and then the rest of us will subsidize it with our tax dollars. And
Speaker 4:  There will be one in your town before You know it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There'll be one in every town. It's gonna be great. It's gonna get
Speaker 6:  rid of all the other little, little mom and pop AI stores
Speaker 6:  in your town. I'm so sorry.
Speaker 8:  The AI needs to unionize
Speaker 4:  Now. That is gonna be, when this gets really interesting, the
Speaker 6:  AI labor movement for the through ais themselves,
Speaker 4:  It's, I don't even, yeah, we'll come back to that. My lightning round thing
Speaker 4:  for this segment is I feel obligated to be the one continuing to chronicle
Speaker 4:  the ever consuming normalization of all of
Speaker 4:  these video apps in which they just all slowly become the exact same thing.
Speaker 4:  And the version of this this week is that Instagram appears to be working
Speaker 4:  on a version of Instagram Reels that lets you upload videos up to 10 minutes
Speaker 4:  long, which you can now do on TikTok, which TikTok did in order to be more
Speaker 4:  like YouTube, where people have always been able to watch You know longer
Speaker 4:  videos. And people on YouTube, of course, have started making shorter
Speaker 4:  videos for shorts, which was created to compete with
Speaker 4:  TikTok. And Reels is also created to, I could do this forever. The
Speaker 4:  point is, all of these apps are the goddamn same thing now.
Speaker 4:  And it's, they're not, though. It's driving me nuts and Alex. I, I
Speaker 4:  wanna get to why you're wrong very shortly here, but the last thing I want
Speaker 4:  to say about this is I think 10 minute vertical videos
Speaker 4:  are actually an extremely good idea. One weird thing
Speaker 4:  that I have discovered is that I just really like watching vertical things.
Speaker 4:  Like there's something to this sort of flow of like how you swipe and how
Speaker 4:  you watch and all that stuff. But also like, I think for a long time there
Speaker 4:  was this idea that you can't do as much in a vertical frame
Speaker 4:  and in certain ways that's true. But also like, I don't
Speaker 4:  mind, I found myself sitting watching longer things on vertical
Speaker 4:  screens than I thought. And like I'm holding my phone the way I normally
Speaker 4:  hold my phone. And so the idea that like somebody is gonna come out and make
Speaker 4:  like a show out of one of these 10 minutes at a time
Speaker 4:  I actually think is not crazy.
Speaker 6:  You mean like, like Quibi
Speaker 4:  Dude? So I listened to a podcast
Speaker 4:  this week, it's called The Big Flop or something like that. Oh
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I saw about this.
Speaker 4:  The first episode is about Quibi and the single
Speaker 4:  wildest take that I will say on this show this week is that it,
Speaker 4:  it convinced me that Quibi didn't actually miss by that much.
Speaker 6:  I I would agree honestly. I remember seeing Quibi at the time and being
Speaker 6:  like, this feels like it could be a really good idea if it's
Speaker 6:  executed well and that it was just executed terribly and also
Speaker 6:  released at the worst possible moment.
Speaker 6:  An app of that nature could have ever been released in the history of the
Speaker 6:  world.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So that's reasons two and three reason one is it was called Quibi.
Speaker 4:  Like that's the, that's the first thing that ruined Quibi. Like if Quibi
Speaker 4:  had been called Max, it would've had a real chance, right? Like it would've
Speaker 8:  If they hadn't spent a trillion dollars on content at the beginning
Speaker 4:  On like Flip My murder house
Speaker 8:  Given some YouTubers like 50 bucks,
Speaker 6:  The Rachel Brosnahan show where she just, the silver arb.
Speaker 4:  But this is what I'm saying, but bring Quibi back as 10 Minute Reels and
Speaker 4:  I'm into it. But yeah,
Speaker 8:  No vertical video is, it's a, it's a little limiting, but it also is
Speaker 8:  a little bit more focused and I think people generally do it better. It it
Speaker 8:  does work. It ha it has a place. But I kind of lean David's way. Alex,
Speaker 8:  they all just become TV shows eventually. Yeah. And I'm a person who's never
Speaker 8:  watched 10 minute videos on YouTube, so I'm not gonna watch 'em on Instagram.
Speaker 8:  I'm not gonna watch 'em on TikTok. I just won't do it.
Speaker 6:  Oh, I watch 'em on TikTok all the time. But it's the same ones I watch on
Speaker 6:  YouTube only now they're vertical and he, and the dude doesn't like cut,
Speaker 6:  like trim it to make it vertical. So a lot of times it's just like blank
Speaker 6:  space and you can hear him doing things because he's not in the frame. And
Speaker 6:  I'm like, yes.
Speaker 4:  It's just like his left hand in the frame and that's all you can see. See
Speaker 6:  You see like just a left hand cutting something and you're like, yeah, this
Speaker 6:  is great. It's so soothing. 'cause I already watched it on YouTube. But
Speaker 6:  I was gonna say like there is one big differentiator between all of these
Speaker 6:  and that is YouTube still does horizontal video and the other
Speaker 6:  ones don't.
Speaker 4:  I mean, YouTube does, or
Speaker 8:  TikTok does do horizontal vi video. You can have videos that that rotate.
Speaker 8:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I just, I guess I haven't been presented with them. Am I supposed to be watching
Speaker 6:  this guy in horizontal all this time? If
Speaker 8:  You upload a, a widescreen video on TikTok, I think it'll like give you the
Speaker 8:  option. So like, it depends on how they uploaded it and what they did. Okay.
Speaker 8:  But yeah, it definitely can do it.
Speaker 4:  I have watched so many videos on TikTok that are the little horizontal video
Speaker 4:  in the middle. 'cause it's like, yeah, CLIPP, it's like clipped from a YouTube
Speaker 4:  video and then just gigantic letter boxes on top. You're telling me I could
Speaker 4:  have been doing it better this whole time. I think there's
Speaker 8:  Times I'm like tell you like, Hey, turn your, turn your phone. I'll just
Speaker 8:  be like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  This is service journalism here at The Verge. This
Speaker 4:  Is also my favorite TikTok genre is people explaining little known
Speaker 4:  features of TikTok. Like the thing where if you put your thumb on the left
Speaker 4:  side of the screen, it plays at two x speed. Mind blowing. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Learn how to use TikTok on TikTok. It's like the, it's it's like the
Speaker 4:  YouTubers being mad at YouTube, like that's what they do on TikTok. It's
Speaker 4:  great.
Speaker 6:  Incredible.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. All right, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna come back
Speaker 4:  and we're gonna go through some of the biggest announcements coming out of
Speaker 4:  IFA, the gigantic European gadget show that is happening as we speak.
Speaker 4:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. So none of us is at IFA this year.
Speaker 4:  John Porter and Jen Tui were there. They did a lot of really great coverage
Speaker 4:  for the site. There's a stream of all the stuff that they found. They went
Speaker 4:  and just had adventures with vacuums and lights and headphones and
Speaker 4:  speakers. And now
Speaker 6:  They're sleeping
Speaker 4:  And now they're sleeping. It really is how it goes. You basically, you go,
Speaker 4:  you touch gadgets for three days with no sleep or food and then
Speaker 4:  you drink heavily and go to sleep. And that's pretty much the run of one
Speaker 4:  of those shows. So they are hopefully at this moment in the sleep phase of
Speaker 4:  that. Not the drinking kids of that. It's listen, it's win both Win win both.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's either way. But let's, there was a bunch of things going
Speaker 4:  on, but we, we've kind of figured out how to divide it into three categories
Speaker 4:  of interesting stuff. And Richard, you alluded to one of them earlier.
Speaker 4:  So take us through the, the like charging world of
Speaker 4:  EFA this year.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It's all kind of centered around the iPhone 15 launch
Speaker 8:  because Apple is finally going to release phone, we think with a
Speaker 8:  USB C Port, first of all. So lightning and tons of
Speaker 8:  Docs, tons of chargers, tons of stands that people have when they get a new
Speaker 8:  phone starting this fall, those won't apply anymore. They're gonna need new
Speaker 8:  chargers, they're gonna need new things, they're gonna need new cables. So
Speaker 8:  of course all the companies that make those are just ready with new
Speaker 8:  products. And beyond that, there's also this new standard QE two
Speaker 8:  to replace the wireless cheese standard that assuming Apple
Speaker 8:  supports, it could allow outside maker's Chargers to charge iPhones
Speaker 8:  at up to 15 watts. You know just by touching it,
Speaker 4:  Which would be like twice what it has been before, right?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It was 7.5. If you weren't a MagSafe charger, it was half the rate.
Speaker 8:  So, and, and You know these things, they throttle kind of as it as it goes
Speaker 8:  through the charging. So like it's not just gonna be twice as fast, but it'll
Speaker 8:  be faster and you'll, you'll love it. Anker and Belkin are two of
Speaker 8:  the companies that have announced Q two products. One of the things that
Speaker 8:  I noticed about these announcements is that everyone who's announcing Q two
Speaker 8:  products does not have a date for when they'll be released. They don't have
Speaker 8:  a price, they don't really have anything. It's coming later this
Speaker 8:  year probably maybe early next year for some things, but eventually, and
Speaker 8:  I think we'll probably get a lot more clarity once the iPhone 15 is actually
Speaker 8:  announced. But we've got stuff like battery packs, Anker, they've got it
Speaker 8:  all branded under their MagGo line. They've got new stands, they've got
Speaker 8:  You know different charges, different kind of desktop charges, all kinds
Speaker 8:  of things. And the same thing for Belkin. And I think that this new Q two
Speaker 8:  standard is going to be the kind of thing that you will actually
Speaker 8:  replace several of the chargers that you have probably within your reach
Speaker 8:  on your desk right now. I
Speaker 4:  Just realized as you were talking that this is kind of about to be the most
Speaker 4:  exciting moment for phone accessories like ever
Speaker 8:  That there has ever been. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  For the first time, if I'm an accessory maker, I can make something that
Speaker 4:  works with your phone, your laptop, your tablet, your
Speaker 4:  other phone, your partner's phone. Like you can build something that is
Speaker 4:  going to work for everything and is going to last because I think
Speaker 4:  you can reliably assume we're gonna be on USB C at least a few years
Speaker 4:  from now. And so I have a feeling we're about to see like a
Speaker 4:  glut of stuff and like Lord knows Anker alone is gonna make
Speaker 4:  700 different USB C products between now and like
Speaker 4:  September 12th.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And of course it, it's not all, if it's USB c it can work with
Speaker 8:  whatever, but they, they have like a little thing that kind of latches onto
Speaker 8:  the bottom of your iPhone with USB C. It does, it does. They can't show it
Speaker 8:  connecting to an iPhone yet. But You know what it's, and and
Speaker 8:  that's just kind of where, where we are with those products. So there's just,
Speaker 8:  there's going to be even more and even better. I, I think kind of charging
Speaker 8:  stuff. So if you're the kind of person who, when it's one of those Amazon
Speaker 8:  deal days or something, you're like, okay, yeah, I'm gonna go get some chargers.
Speaker 8:  It's time. It's going to be your time very soon.
Speaker 4:  Cranz. This ones make you so happy. I'm,
Speaker 6:  I'm not happy at all because I just bought so much wireless charging stuff
Speaker 6:  like two months ago. I feel so dumb.
Speaker 6:  I'm just like, I was like reading all of the news out of IFA being like
Speaker 6:  rookie move Cranz just,
Speaker 8:  It's every time when, when the prices are really good and you're like, oh,
Speaker 8:  okay, I'll get it. It's all on sale. I I should, I should buy these.
Speaker 6:  I got that wireless charger slash battery from Anker. That thing is
Speaker 6:  great. The
Speaker 4:  Little cube.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That like, oh it's beautiful.
Speaker 4:  I love that thing. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I love it. And now I'm like, well damnit, there's another one and I want
Speaker 6:  that one more 'cause it's got like a little screen has
Speaker 8:  A screen on it now. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I'm like, so if anybody needs a a, a generation one charger,
Speaker 6:  I'm in the market to, to sell it at cost.
Speaker 4:  I do wonder if there's gonna be like a black market for old, old
Speaker 4:  chargers and Docs going forward. Like all the people who just
Speaker 4:  desperately hold onto their iPhone eight minis. Like I'm
Speaker 6:  Re-gifting it all to family Christmas is gonna be really crummy
Speaker 6:  for them and great for me
Speaker 8:  The be before we're done with this, I wanna make the case for slow wireless
Speaker 8:  chargers. I have the, the older Pixel stand near my bed now see if
Speaker 8:  you're one of those people who you want to go to sleep and stop using your
Speaker 8:  phone, one way to do that, put the wireless charger out of your reach.
Speaker 8:  Yes. So that you have to decide, am I going to put the phone on the stand
Speaker 8:  and let it charge overnight so that it's not empty, the battery isn't empty
Speaker 8:  when I wake up, or am I going to use, use the phone and maybe fall asleep
Speaker 8:  with it in my hand, wake up with a phone on zero and I don't have a fast
Speaker 8:  charger to charge it up.
Speaker 6:  That's good.
Speaker 8:  That's stress. It, it will, it will improve your life. That's smart. Get
Speaker 8:  yourself a slow charger.
Speaker 4:  No disagree. I really like, I think the single most like
Speaker 4:  aspirational thing I have done over the years is try to be a person who charges
Speaker 4:  my phone outside of my bedroom. So many times I have tried to be this person,
Speaker 4:  I'm like, okay, I'm gonna have a stack of like print books and magazines
Speaker 4:  and that's what I'm gonna read before bed. I'm not gonna sit here and like
Speaker 4:  scroll Reddit until I fall asleep. And after like
Speaker 4:  three days, inevitably I'm like, how did my charger get right back into my
Speaker 4:  room and next to my bed? And I'm scrolling Reddit again. Like I don't remember
Speaker 4:  ever putting it back in here. And yet it has arrived. And I've, I've, I
Speaker 4:  swear I've tried this 25 times in my life and I think it shows real personal
Speaker 4:  growth that I have stopped trying. Like I think it says, it says a lot about
Speaker 4:  me as a person.
Speaker 6:  Are you, I mean you're not a very lazy person. So is just putting it on the
Speaker 6:  other side of the, because putting it on the, the charger on the other side
Speaker 6:  of the room, that's enough for me. Yeah. I'm that lazy that like once it's
Speaker 6:  on there, I'm not getting outta bed again. For
Speaker 4:  Me it's not getting, it's not even the laziness factor. It's like the, the
Speaker 4:  actual feeling of getting out of bed is so awful still works.
Speaker 4:  It's the taking off the covers. Like even if my charger was right there,
Speaker 4:  but I had to take off the covers to get it, I wouldn't do it. Do it
Speaker 6:  Is sometimes there's one time where I did that, but like I like army
Speaker 6:  crawled across the floor with like the cover still on a single foot being
Speaker 6:  like, ah,
Speaker 4:  I'm not technically out of bed.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it worked. It was fine. It's fine.
Speaker 4:  It's very good. But yeah, I, I suspect it's about to be a very, very, very
Speaker 4:  exciting like six months in the accessory world. And the other thing I will
Speaker 4:  say is this is just a p ss a to everyone now don't buy
Speaker 4:  any accessories, don't buy any accessories the day Apple launches. Things
Speaker 4:  don't buy any accessories the day it ships. Because what's gonna happen is
Speaker 4:  between now and Christmas there's going to be this unbelievable glut
Speaker 4:  of cool new stuff that comes out. And it's gonna happen really fast because
Speaker 4:  all these companies are already making USB c stuff. So they're not gonna
Speaker 4:  have to get used to a completely new connector. Apple will have some weird
Speaker 4:  tweak to it because it always does. But there's going to be just a
Speaker 4:  run of new things that all these companies are ready for. And so whatever
Speaker 4:  you buy today or tomorrow or on September 12th, September
Speaker 4:  20, whatever, when the iPhone ships, there will be something in November
Speaker 4:  that is better and by Black Friday it will cost $5. So
Speaker 4:  Alex Cranz stop buying accessories
Speaker 6:  And like you were talking and I was like, actually maybe it was good that
Speaker 6:  I just bought all of this stuff because we're not gonna be buying. I'm like,
Speaker 6:  I, I can't, I just bought a new dining room table and four like wireless
Speaker 6:  chargers. I'm broke for the next year. Like it's great.
Speaker 4:  There you go. There we
Speaker 6:  Go.
Speaker 4:  Alright, you go next. Cranz. What, what did you look up for IFA? So there
Speaker 6:  Was a lot of smart home stuff, ton of stuff. That's why my Jen was there
Speaker 6:  and she was doing incredible work. A lot of stuff coming out from Philips
Speaker 6:  Hugh who historically just does lights and
Speaker 6:  if you like me, are tired of spending so much money on Hue lights.
Speaker 6:  There's a lot of competitors in this space now. There's a ton of other really
Speaker 6:  good lights. I've got some like little candelabra lights. They're beautiful.
Speaker 6:  They do like the pride flag. It doesn't actually look like the pride flag.
Speaker 6:  But in July I, or in June I was like, yeah, cool.
Speaker 4:  Is Hugh still the best one though? I, I confess I'm slightly behind the times
Speaker 4:  on my own personal smart home care, but my read was always Hugh
Speaker 4:  is the best. It's also twice the price of everything else. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Hugh the, yeah, like, like it's, it's like the Apple deal for a long time
Speaker 6:  where you're like, well sure I'm paying twice the price but I can smugly
Speaker 6:  say it works. Can you say that Richard fair in
Speaker 6:  your Windows machine? But that hurt.
Speaker 6:  Can I say that about my Mac lately? No, but,
Speaker 6:  but yeah, so it typically just works but it costs
Speaker 6:  a ton more. But there's a, there's so much stuff out now in the space that
Speaker 6:  really does also just work. Like I was using,
Speaker 6:  adding stuff both to home assistant and to, to
Speaker 6:  HomeKit zero issue. Like totally flawless. Even the
Speaker 6:  stuff that some people complain about, like nano leaf can
Speaker 6:  sometimes be a little buggy works. And so Hugh
Speaker 6:  has a whole bunch of stuff. They've got track lighting now, which is big.
Speaker 6:  That's exciting because oftentimes track lighting you can't replace like
Speaker 6:  there's no little bulbs to go in there and replace that he probably would
Speaker 6:  make if they could. So you have to get the whole thing. So that's cool.
Speaker 6:  And they, they got into to security cameras, which is
Speaker 6:  a big deal for them. They've, they've just been a company that does lights
Speaker 6:  and now they're doing security cameras. Predictably expensive security
Speaker 6:  cameras.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's very telling to me that that's where they went actually that like,
Speaker 4:  I think it's, it's pretty obvious that if you're a company that wants to
Speaker 4:  do smart home stuff, lights is the place to start. Right? It is kind of the,
Speaker 4:  it's like the gateway drug to the smart home for basically everybody. And
Speaker 4:  it's very interesting to me that after all this time the the Hue
Speaker 4:  team looked around and was like, okay, what's the next thing we wanna do?
Speaker 4:  And decided it was security cameras. Not like other sensors or
Speaker 4:  weird things for your garage door or things for your car.
Speaker 4:  It's just, it They're just like security cameras. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And, and these are very expensive. It's got end-to-end decryption. It
Speaker 6:  currently does not work out of the box or won't work outta the box
Speaker 6:  with Alexa and Google Assistants home security camera integrations.
Speaker 6:  So you won't be able to just like play it on your little Google speaker anywhere.
Speaker 6:  That kinda sucks. It won't work with Home kit and tell
Speaker 6:  matter start supporting video for security cameras
Speaker 6:  because that's the only way it's gonna work with HomeKit. It won't work
Speaker 6:  with like home kit's secure video platform, which isn't actually very good
Speaker 6:  to begin with. So that's not the worst one. Like that one you're like, oh
Speaker 6:  that's kind of sucks. But also I'm fine with that or at least I am. But
Speaker 6:  it will work with matter. And the most exciting part of all
Speaker 6:  the Philips U news is it finally is gonna start supporting matter. It's pushing
Speaker 6:  out an update next month. I am unreasonably
Speaker 6:  excited. I've been spending this whole week being like, I cannot
Speaker 6:  DMM Jen 'cause she's very busy working. And all I wanna
Speaker 6:  do is be like, Jen, Jen, Jen, Jen, Jen, this is such a good moment. So I'm
Speaker 6:  like being very patient and waiting until she comes back and gets over her
Speaker 6:  hangover and, and is having a good time and then I'm gonna
Speaker 6:  just assai her with it. But that's exciting. Like it's been
Speaker 6:  ages since they promised matter. And the stuff I use that
Speaker 6:  where Matter works is wonderful.
Speaker 6:  I'm in the future. I'm having the best day of my life. I've set up my entire
Speaker 6:  system. Oh it doesn't work with matter. I hate everything and everyone
Speaker 6:  and I want it all to die. Especially my robot vacuum cleaner, which
Speaker 4:  There were also a bunch of it IFA. I just love that the robot vacuums
Speaker 4:  are becoming like an outrageously competitive
Speaker 4:  space. There are so many good robot vacuums out there now. I love it.
Speaker 6:  I, this was the first one I'd ever like, I tried one 10 years ago and it
Speaker 6:  was garbage. And I was like, I'm okay. I can just walk around with a vacuum
Speaker 6:  cleaner, like a normal person. And back this summer somebody was
Speaker 6:  like, oh, go get a robot vacuum cleaner. They're really good now. And this
Speaker 6:  was a person that I trust. And so I was like, you, you generally aren't stupid.
Speaker 6:  And I went and I got one on sale and I was like, oh, it's really good now.
Speaker 6:  It like, my house is just clean. That's, and with a dog
Speaker 6:  that's not common. So
Speaker 4:  They're good now. And now there's a, there the robot lawnmower
Speaker 4:  industry is booming. I think Jen and John saw one of those. It's
Speaker 6:  Starting to boom. Yeah, there was, she she was, she saw a robot
Speaker 6:  lawnmower. The problem with robot lawnmowers is they generally have really
Speaker 6:  crappy range and American lawns tend to
Speaker 6:  be pretty big. Like they, they, they, there's a lot of space,
Speaker 6:  there's a lot of stuff going on in them. And these weren't doing it very
Speaker 6:  well. They're really meant for those little tiny like postage stamp
Speaker 6:  lawns in Europe. And so this can do like half an acre,
Speaker 6:  which I would've loved at the age of 13 when I had to hop on the
Speaker 6:  riding lawnmower and like mow the front in the backyard and in the garden.
Speaker 6:  It was the worst time of my life. My family still talks about how much I
Speaker 6:  complained about it. This would've been amazing. I would've like been
Speaker 6:  campaigning for it immediately. So I'm so excited. All you kids out there
Speaker 6:  listening. I know there's a lot of 13 year olds that listen to The Vergecast
Speaker 6:  and I know you're very excited about this. Start campaigning now. This is
Speaker 6:  a great Christmas gift for you. Probably not. Your parents will not buy it
Speaker 6:  'cause it's like $2,000. But aspirational. Aspirational.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Everybody talks about how like kids are not gonna grow up and learn
Speaker 4:  how to drive and they're gonna miss like a key part of life. And I just feel
Speaker 4:  like if, if your parents never force you to mow the lawn, like you, you've
Speaker 4:  you've missed something. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You really have.
Speaker 4:  It's like 111 degrees. It's called Tide. And you have a push mower that barely
Speaker 4:  works and they're like, shut up, we're gonna pay you $1. Go mow
Speaker 4:  for five hours David, and then rake all the leaves.
Speaker 4:  It's fine. My childhood's fine. I hated the leaves. It's fine. It's the
Speaker 6:  Worst.
Speaker 4:  Oh, the
Speaker 8:  Leaves. Yeah. Look man, spending, spending 45 minutes trying to get that
Speaker 8:  thing to start is character building. That's
Speaker 4:  Exactly right. You feel like
Speaker 6:  You're, you're a mechanic afterwards. Like when somebody's car breaks down
Speaker 6:  you're like, hold up. I've jump started a lawnmower. I think I can help.
Speaker 6:  You can't, it doesn't work that
Speaker 4:  Way. Is there a thing I can pull on really hard and hope that starts it.
Speaker 6:  Alright,
Speaker 4:  The last thing from Eva, which I should just run through real fast was there
Speaker 4:  were a few headphone and speaker announcements, but a couple
Speaker 4:  were actually very cool. So I just wanna basically, basically call out two.
Speaker 4:  One is new Jabra headphones. They're called the Elite Tens
Speaker 4:  and the Elite Eights, they're basically new wireless earbuds. I think
Speaker 4:  Jabra in general does not get the shine it deserves in the headphones space.
Speaker 4:  Everybody talks about AirPods and Pixel Buds and Galaxy Buds and kind of
Speaker 4:  all the stuff that's like bundled with devices. Jabra does a really good
Speaker 4:  job of making just like very good headphones that work with everything. It
Speaker 4:  supports like all of the open standards. It can, it has really good noise
Speaker 4:  cancellation. The mics tend to be pretty good. The battery life is pretty
Speaker 4:  good. The audio
Speaker 6:  Is good. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Like they're very good headphones but
Speaker 6:  They're big. They sit like if you have tiny ear canals, that's, that's why
Speaker 6:  I don't use 'em. 'cause my ear canals are too small.
Speaker 4:  So that's actually one of the things that I think is exciting about these
Speaker 4:  new ones. The elite tens, which are the higher end one, I think they're
Speaker 4:  250 bucks. They have a like semi-open design,
Speaker 4:  which in theory should help with that feeling of
Speaker 4:  being sort of smooshed in your ear. Yeah. Personally I end up using very
Speaker 4:  few of those kind of closed ear headphones because I get the same thing.
Speaker 4:  Like my ear canals start to hurt after a while. If I listen to
Speaker 4:  those, like I got the Sony link buds and they cau, they like
Speaker 4:  cause pain or they fall out.
Speaker 6:  I love that pain that like you're like, oh, it fits so good. Agony,
Speaker 6:  agony, agony. Oh yeah, put this Taylor sounds lovely.
Speaker 4:  Oh, it sounds amazing. Yeah. But I like, after 30 minutes I'm like, oh, I'm
Speaker 4:  gonna lose both of my ears. Like this is cool. And they
Speaker 6:  Feel like they're
Speaker 4:  Bleeding. Yeah. But so the elite tens seem cool, sound great. They have six
Speaker 4:  mics. I think the the audio quality should be good. They're supposedly one
Speaker 4:  of the best. They've that Jabra Hass ever made. And then there's the Elite
Speaker 4:  eight, I think it's technical called the Elite eight active that are
Speaker 4:  IP 68 rated, which is like more or
Speaker 4:  less everything you would need as a person. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  You can get disgusting. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Exactly. It's like you can throw it in the wash and they'll come out fine
Speaker 4:  and they're just super, super rugged. And personally like I lost a pair of
Speaker 4:  AirPods because I got caught in a rainstorm. I lost another pair of AirPods
Speaker 4:  because I dropped one of them in a puddle and then put it back in the charger
Speaker 4:  and it ruined everything. Which if you're wondering, yes, it was stupid,
Speaker 4:  but this is the life I lead. You
Speaker 6:  Had to charge it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And so just, I like blew on it a bunch of times and then put it back
Speaker 4:  in the case. And then about 45 minutes later it was like that was the dumbest
Speaker 4:  thing I could have possibly done. But now here we are. But so the idea of
Speaker 4:  like a super ruggedized pair of pretty good headphones,
Speaker 4:  I actually sound very exciting. But they both do wireless charging. They
Speaker 4:  both do multi-point Bluetooth. They both do the mono mode, so you can
Speaker 4:  just wear one earbud at a time. They just like have all the features. And
Speaker 4:  I think like in general, if you're shopping for wireless headphones, most
Speaker 4:  people don't think of Jabra and you should. But the other thing which I
Speaker 4:  think is much more exciting is this new JBL,
Speaker 4:  I think it's called the authentics speaker. Authentic.
Speaker 6:  They look nice.
Speaker 4:  They do, right? The 200, the 300 and the 400, yeah. They're all stupid
Speaker 4:  expensive. They're like anywhere from 330 to $700
Speaker 4:  for a Bluetooth speaker, which is preposterous.
Speaker 6:  Can't put a price on fashion. But
Speaker 4:  Not only are they great looking, they are, they have this like cool sort
Speaker 4:  of fabricy retro thing going on, but they also have Alexa
Speaker 4:  and Google assistant in one device and it can hear both wake words
Speaker 4:  at the same time. You don't have to do the Sonos thing where in setup you
Speaker 4:  pick which one you want to use. You can use both and you can tell it with
Speaker 4:  one to start the music and with the other to stop the music. And they found
Speaker 4:  some ways in which that gets weird. Like if you start a timer with Alexa
Speaker 4:  and then you try to use Google to stop the timer, that doesn't quite work.
Speaker 4:  But we,
Speaker 6:  It worked if the timer was going off. But if you like started a timer and
Speaker 6:  then you're like, oh no, didn didn't wanna do that timer. Oh, interesting.
Speaker 6:  And you try to tell it to stop. Yeah. John like, I guess he got, he got to
Speaker 6:  play with one and apparently just had a whole list of ways
Speaker 6:  he was gonna screw with this thing. I love it. And just went through his
Speaker 6:  whole list. He chronicled it all in his piece and it, I was just like,
Speaker 6:  yeah. Yeah, just like chanting as I read it. It was great. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  His piece is really great. And he also, he asked Google like,
Speaker 4:  should I take this as the beginning of a trend? Is this gonna actually be
Speaker 4:  the sort of interoperable voice assistant world we've been wanting to live
Speaker 4:  in? And the Google representative was
Speaker 4:  sort of sketchy about it and so who knows? And
Speaker 6:  Then ran away fleeing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean basically. But the, at least this proves that like this is a
Speaker 4:  thing that can be done and here's hoping that it's not just on
Speaker 4:  this one set of expensive JBL speakers. Do you
Speaker 6:  Think Sonos is gonna do it at some point? Like a good version?
Speaker 4:  I think at this point Sonos and Google are at such odds that I would be
Speaker 4:  surprised if Google was interested in playing along with Sonos.
Speaker 6:  They would rather just get rid of it entirely. If it would piss off.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But like could the next youi boom that I buy
Speaker 4:  because I'm inevitably gonna buy 500 more of those in my life. Could that
Speaker 4:  have both? That would be awesome. Like the, the speaker world is big and
Speaker 4:  wide and imagine if you could have them with the Dolby stuff that worked
Speaker 4:  all over your house and you could talk to each individual one with whatever
Speaker 4:  voice assistant you wanted. Like how is that not the world we live in? This
Speaker 4:  is the world we should live in.
Speaker 6:  That's the future. That's what I want. That's the interoperable future I
Speaker 6:  want.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I just wanna yell whatever I want at my speakers and they have to listen.
Speaker 8:  I do not wanna do that. I don't want to talk to my speakers ever about
Speaker 8:  anything. But I do love these. They look incredible. Like if you remember
Speaker 8:  how speakers looked, those old seventies and eighties speakers, you do have
Speaker 8:  to look at these. Finally. Someone's bringing that back. I don't know why
Speaker 8:  they didn't before, but they are now and I like it. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's based on the L one hundreds, right from the seventies.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. After like two decades of trying to make speakers look like spaceships.
Speaker 4:  Now we're back to making them look like speakers and it makes me very happy.
Speaker 4:  Like these, yeah, these look great. The one has a handle on it, which is
Speaker 4:  basically just to remind you like, yes, you can pick this thing up. It's
Speaker 4:  allowed, they have, they have actual knobs for all of
Speaker 4:  the different levels. It's just wonderful. Like what a world.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I'm not, I'm not saying that you should do cocaine off of these speakers,
Speaker 8:  but like if you wanted to. If you wanted
Speaker 6:  To. Yeah, they've got some good, there's some good flat spaces there for
Speaker 6:  a nice, a nice line. We don't endorse cocaine on The
Speaker 6:  Vergecast.
Speaker 4:  All right, well now that we've gone well and fully off the rails, it's time
Speaker 4:  to end the first cast just in case this is the last episode
Speaker 4:  you ever listened to. This is what I wanna leave you with.
Speaker 6:  It's snowing somewhere.
Speaker 4:  All right. A lot of good stuff on the site. This week we had the most recent
Speaker 4:  piece in our big series investigating the effect of Google in the
Speaker 4:  world. Ryan bro wrote a really great piece called The End of Google Verse.
Speaker 4:  Really interesting. It's full of like old internet heads reminiscing on
Speaker 4:  like the weird things people used to do with Google in the early two thousands.
Speaker 4:  It's really fun. Our video team and our producer, Andrew Marino,
Speaker 4:  made an amazing video with one of those heads
Speaker 4:  that does bin oral audio and noise canceling headphones to like
Speaker 4:  really test how good noise canceling is. It's a wild video
Speaker 4:  with like lots of graphs that I didn't understand and tons of interesting
Speaker 4:  people. And Andrew sweating to death on a summer in New York City. It's a
Speaker 4:  really great video. Andrew also did another piece on the button of the month
Speaker 4:  about a USB button that helped people win Jeopardy.
Speaker 4:  It's delightful. And I want one just to like mute and unmute my microphone
Speaker 4:  now. I have no use for it, but I want it. I, I want
Speaker 2:  One real bad.
Speaker 4:  The latest land of the Giants episode is out. It's about Tesla in China.
Speaker 4:  It's very good. That whole season has been really great. Like Land of the
Speaker 4:  Giants has always really great, but I actually think this might be my favorite
Speaker 4:  season we've ever done. It's really good. Everybody just go listen to it.
Speaker 4:  We are going to be off next Wednesday because it's Labor Day, but then we're
Speaker 4:  gonna be back next Friday. We're gonna have more Apple to talk about. Like
Speaker 4:  I said, there is just a massive tidal wave of
Speaker 4:  gadgets and tech news coming in the next three months. So we're gonna be
Speaker 4:  doing a ton. It's gonna be a lot of fun. We'll see you then. Rock and roll.
Speaker 14:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 14:  us an email at Vergecast at The Verge dot com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 14:  production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network. The show is produced
Speaker 14:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. Our
Speaker 14:  editorial director is Brooke Miners. That's it. We'll see you next week.