# Transcript
ID: bf299f50-bf23-11ed-bd03-bb2695b8f1fa
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Spotify's redesign, streaming boxes suck, and Gigi Sohn withdraws from FCC nomination
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8836567189564204052/5742041410682136371/s93290-US-5956s-1678439570.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, Alex Cranz, and Richard Lawler discuss Spotify's changes within its app, what happening this week at Twitter, Gigi Sohn withdrawing her nomination for FCC commissioner, and a whole lot more.
Speaker 1:  Support for today's show comes from Deloitte. In the business world, it can
Speaker 1:  be especially crucial to innovate. You can either build your own future or
Speaker 1:  bet on someone else's. No one knows what tomorrow will bring, but you push
Speaker 1:  forward and create enterprise anyway. That's why Deloitte's mission is to
Speaker 1:  help engineer advantage for their clients by harnessing the latest innovations
Speaker 1:  and technology while exploring the ideas and opportunities that can look
Speaker 1:  beyond today. Transform what's next into what's now.
Speaker 1:  See how you can engineer advantage with Deloitte at
Speaker 1:  deloitte.com/us/engineering advantage.
Speaker 3:  Hello and welcome to Ro Cast, the flagship podcast of Wiper
Speaker 3:  Innovation where all your wiper innovation needs. The code is first
Speaker 3:  cast. Do you think that there's a podcast for the wiper industry?
Speaker 3:  I was
Speaker 4:  Just wondering, what's the competition there do you think? Is it heated?
Speaker 1:  It
Speaker 3:  Exists. Well, I, I mean I love nothing more than a good
Speaker 3:  trade publication. Like I, I will just sit around reading Tire Business Weekly,
Speaker 3:  a magazine for people who run tire stores. It's very good. What
Speaker 5:  If, what if there's been monopolization in the windshield wiper industry?
Speaker 5:  It's like glasses where like one company actually makes all the brands,
Speaker 3:  Right? But even that company has like probably a newsletter like
Speaker 3:  looks SOA weekly
Speaker 3:  and like every page is like, we bought another sunglasses company
Speaker 3:  competition. We have, Lexia has always been at war with East Asia.
Speaker 3:  Hi, I'm nea. I'm your friend Alex Kino. Cranz is here.
Speaker 1:  I'm not at war with Asia.
Speaker 3:  Good. That's
Speaker 1:  Big announcement for the show today.
Speaker 3:  I think we should start every episode by stipulating that Alex is
Speaker 3:  not at war with Asia.
Speaker 1:  The whole continent, the whole thing.
Speaker 3:  You just one of these days though, if we do it
Speaker 3:  enough, eventually we have to pay it off. It's like check off's gun. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  like eventually we're like, it's Alex's last episode. She's declared
Speaker 3:  war. Richard Lawler is here. Hey Richard.
Speaker 5:  I have not committed securities fraud today.
Speaker 3:  Hey. Yes, that's a win. I mean honestly in the context of a
Speaker 3:  tech show, not committing securities fraud in 2023 is a
Speaker 3:  win. I'll
Speaker 5:  Take it. It's,
Speaker 3:  That's good. Has your, have you collapsed a bank today because it's the second
Speaker 3:  of two has collapsed.
Speaker 5:  I, I didn't say that. I
Speaker 3:  Haven't. And then as you may have heard ominously in the background, David Pierce
Speaker 3:  has returned, hello,
Speaker 4:  I'm back. Back. I cannot honestly say I have not committed securities fraud
Speaker 4:  today. It's like, it's a bold thing to just confidently say, right? Like
Speaker 4:  I don't know what's happening to me today. What do I know about securities
Speaker 4:  fraud?
Speaker 3:  You sound like every crypto executive in America. You're like what is the
Speaker 3:  security and what is fraud and can you really add them together? Yeah. Is
Speaker 3:  that a sentence? What is a
Speaker 4:  Sentence? I live in The Bahamas. I can, I can do nothing wrong. Like what?
Speaker 4:  There are no rules here.
Speaker 3:  Buy a Bitcoin, please God. Buy a Bitcoin someone.
Speaker 3:  What's what we're referencing by the way, is it over the weekend Richard
Speaker 3:  Silver Gate, which is a financial institution that was backing a lot of
Speaker 3:  crypto teetered. Its way towards a collapse. And then actually
Speaker 3:  today this bank has not collapsed. It's Silicon Valley Bank, which is a
Speaker 3:  sort of legendary Silicon Valley financial institution. One of the top
Speaker 3:  15 largest banks in the country. I think its stock is
Speaker 3:  collapsing cuz it has been exposed to crypto as
Speaker 5:  Well. Yeah, the financial contagion continues. It's not good. And
Speaker 5:  as Liz Lato wrote about the silver gate collapse, one of the major impacts
Speaker 5:  is that it's gonna be a lot harder to kind of get your cash out of crypto.
Speaker 5:  So if you were planning on doing that, you might want to figure out
Speaker 5:  something
Speaker 3:  That won't accelerate the cycle at all.
Speaker 5:  No, no. Never does. It's not
Speaker 3:  A big if Richard's like, here's what you should do. Run on the bank.
Speaker 5:  I I didn't say you shouldn't.
Speaker 4:  It's like it's wild how quickly the run on the bank has turned
Speaker 4:  into like the run on crypto has turned into like the run on the financial
Speaker 4:  system. Yeah, it just every day like the concentric circles just get
Speaker 4:  a little bit wider. It's really wild.
Speaker 1:  Well that's what happens when a pyramid collapses.
Speaker 3:  No, that's a triangle. David was talking about circles
Speaker 1:  Pyramid circle. It's fine, don't worry about it. I did okay in
Speaker 1:  geometry.
Speaker 3:  That might be the worst joke I've ever told in the show. Look at the end
Speaker 3:  of it, the, it collapses enough in Crans declares war on the continent of
Speaker 3:  Asia. So stay tuned for that. It's coming. I don't wanna talk
Speaker 3:  about crypto though. I, although I will say after two and a half years
Speaker 3:  of pandemic, being able to use words like contagion in a different
Speaker 3:  way, frankly refreshing. Just putting that out there. Okay,
Speaker 3:  let's talk about the cyber truck wiper. The only story in technology, there's
Speaker 1:  A bold claim.
Speaker 3:  There's only one story and it's a windshield wiper. So here,
Speaker 3:  here's some inside baseball and how journalism is made.
Speaker 3:  We're, we're doing the thing that we do. We, you know, we open our, we wake
Speaker 3:  up, we open our laptops like what's going on in the world. We see a bunch
Speaker 3:  of pictures of like Tesla fans at the Tesla
Speaker 3:  headquarters in California. Cuz you know, Tesla's two headquarters now they
Speaker 3:  move the company officially to Texas with the
Speaker 3:  engineering headquarters in California. Elon was just in California. Governor
Speaker 3:  Newsom, they announced this whole expansion, whatever. So they have this
Speaker 3:  event investors, the whole thing. They park a bunch of Tesla vehicles outside
Speaker 3:  of a building, including a cyber truck. Like any good editor-in-chief, I
Speaker 3:  basically screamed, get me photos of Spider-Man. There's two
Speaker 3:  things you wanna do as an editor chief. You wanna circle print layouts hung
Speaker 3:  on the glass walls of a conference room and say, fix this up before you go
Speaker 3:  to print. I've never been able to do that. Maybe one day I will. Although
Speaker 3:  we did just win the as award for best print design, which is deeply funny.
Speaker 3:  However, that's one. And then two, you want, you wanna scream, get me photos
Speaker 3:  of Spider-Man. So we see the cyber truck, we see the wiper ice cream. Get
Speaker 3:  any photos of Spider-Man, I literally said this in Slack. Veen
Speaker 3:  goes out with a long lens, try to get splice shots of the cyber truck
Speaker 3:  to the place where the, the cyber truck was by the time he arrives by the
Speaker 3:  way. And he like recruits his Uber driver into like a scheme to sneak
Speaker 3:  ever closer to the cyber truck like the Uber driver's gonna pose as a fan
Speaker 3:  of Tesla.
Speaker 3:  It was great. We were like very excited. And they get there and the cyber
Speaker 3:  truck is gone. However, then Tesla has its
Speaker 3:  investor day, which is mostly a dod and after that Tesla had a design
Speaker 3:  franson whole housing tweets, a picture in front of the cyber
Speaker 3:  truck being like, I just took the beta out for a drive. And in the picture
Speaker 3:  the truck has clearly been out in the rain. And you can see
Speaker 3:  the sweep of the gigantic wiper.
Speaker 3:  This is the, like I frozen my tracks when I saw this tweet.
Speaker 3:  I can literally just imagine you like at home just screaming
Speaker 3:  enhanced at your computer. Just like furiously making the browser bigger.
Speaker 3:  Trying to get the picture. Yeah, I mean I, it's there. I was like, God
Speaker 3:  damnit Tim bake this a touch screen
Speaker 3:  so you, you can see it, you can see how the wiper is gonna work
Speaker 3:  if you, in following along on the show, you know that the cyber trucks
Speaker 3:  wiper has been a point of major contention cuz they announced this
Speaker 3:  thing by throwing rocks through the windows, but it didn't have a
Speaker 3:  windshield wiper. So they, they got all distracted by the not
Speaker 3:  bulletproof, bulletproof glass and forgot the windshield wiper. Then
Speaker 3:  Elon's tweeting. I am deeply concerned about the wiper, which is an amazing
Speaker 3:  thing for an automotive CEO to tweet like period. Just
Speaker 3:  in li I've interviewed a lot of auto CEOs. None of them are ever, like, what
Speaker 3:  keeps me up at night is windshield wipers. God knows they care about them.
Speaker 3:  They just keep that under wraps. Like what's top 10 anxieties of the CEO
Speaker 3:  Volvo. It's like, he's like windshield wipers. Well they
Speaker 1:  Actually, they talk about it in the publication. Yeah. Like they're industry
Speaker 1:  pup
Speaker 3:  In the wiper pop.
Speaker 1:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  It's fine. Anyway, Elon's tweeting about it. He's like, the best thing would
Speaker 3:  be for it to extend. And that's complicated. So everyone starts to think
Speaker 3:  that the cyber truck wiper is going to extend the people. Tesla
Speaker 3:  fans are leaping out of bushes to tell you about the Mercedes mono
Speaker 3:  wiper concept from like the 1982 C class. It's fully
Speaker 3:  ridiculous. There's, there's a YouTube video showing
Speaker 3:  how the Mercedes mono wiper worked that I swear to God has
Speaker 3:  a million views and it's just hopeful cyber truck fans. Aw.
Speaker 3:  Because the concept, all 12 of them watching it several
Speaker 3:  thousand times a piece and like, it's very cool and like it
Speaker 3:  was actually, it was mounted in the, the middle of the windshield and
Speaker 3:  it's, it makes like a bow tie shape and there's like a gearing, there's a
Speaker 3:  gear set in the wiper. The point of this is that Mercedes did not make
Speaker 3:  this anymore. They were like, this was a bad idea and they went
Speaker 3:  back to wipers. Cyber truck wiper does not extend,
Speaker 3:  it just leaves a whole chunk of the windshield dirty. It's amazing
Speaker 3:  that after all of this time they're like, I don't know, does the passenger
Speaker 3:  need to see out the windshield? No they don't. I love it. I can't
Speaker 3:  get enough of this thing. How
Speaker 1:  Much water do you think it sloughs off? Like does it soak the people
Speaker 1:  and the other cars just ah, every time like
Speaker 3:  It has to Yeah, but it's like raining really hard and you and you're moving
Speaker 3:  like a four foot wiper. Just
Speaker 4:  I, by the way, four foot wiper is as far as I can tell. Not
Speaker 4:  an exaggeration. Like I, I'm just, I'm just doing math here cuz for I'm,
Speaker 4:  I'm now at 500% zoom on this photo on my Twitter professor.
Speaker 4:  This is, this is where I am. It's very good to be back in the verge cast.
Speaker 4:  It's like you assume, you know, Franz is a normal height dude.
Speaker 4:  This thing is at least 75% as tall as he
Speaker 4:  is. So this is, this is a human sized windshield
Speaker 3:  Wiper. I'm gonna need like the Reddit people to do the thing where they like
Speaker 3:  de warp the photo because there's a perspective trick that's happening
Speaker 3:  there.
Speaker 4:  Sure. But he's also standing right in front of it. It's not like, it's not
Speaker 4:  like the distance between the two things. Unless the cyber truck is sneakily,
Speaker 4:  you know, 17 feet wide, which would not totally shock me. It's like the first
Speaker 4:  two lane wide vehicle ever. Like, I don't know. But yeah, it just, it
Speaker 4:  covers, it gets the whole driver's side super clean on the driver's side
Speaker 4:  it seems, except for about a, a little stripe on top. And
Speaker 3:  That's fine, that's
Speaker 4:  Fine. It's normal. But then you come around and as you get all the way to
Speaker 4:  the other side, it, it's about the top right?
Speaker 4:  I don't know, sixth. It just ignores entirely. It's like, ah, there's no
Speaker 4:  one here. You're not gonna need to see out of this. It's fine. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  You'll definitely never turn your head to the right while driving the cyber
Speaker 3:  truck.
Speaker 4:  No. Yeah. If if ever a drone is flying up
Speaker 4:  kind of just above you and to the right, you'll never notice your toast.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's all, all of it's very funny. I still think they should go with
Speaker 3:  three wipers in a circle, which I, I promise you can be done. You get the
Speaker 3:  two at the bottom going like this and one at the top going like
Speaker 4:  That. I was imagining like a spinning Roomba on your windshield.
Speaker 3:  I mean, at this point nobody looks in the middle.
Speaker 3:  I don't know when the cyber truck is gonna ship. I swear to you,
Speaker 3:  the wiper on the cyber truck is a monumental
Speaker 3:  piece of tech history because if the cyber truck is not
Speaker 3:  a success or if they can't solve the wiper and ship the cyber
Speaker 3:  truck, Tesla's in trouble. There are facts, right? Like
Speaker 3:  they've collected millions of hundred dollars reservations
Speaker 5:  For this thing. I'm looking at it now and you know what, I'm gonna go the
Speaker 5:  other way. I think the wiper works.
Speaker 3:  Huh? You think the wiper works? The
Speaker 5:  Wiper works. If you take a look at
Speaker 4:  The top of it, Richard, it objectively doesn't, it just doesn't,
Speaker 4:  it does not wipe the windshield.
Speaker 3:  The
Speaker 5:  Roof of the car comes in under the glass, like you
Speaker 5:  can't see through most of that anyway, where the, where the wiper isn't wiping,
Speaker 5:  it just has such a monumentally stupid design
Speaker 5:  that it looks like it's not clearing the visible area. But you can't even
Speaker 5:  see outta that spot. Anyway. I, I don't know, is that like a
Speaker 3:  Pocket up here? No, that's not right. I, I see what you're saying. But there's
Speaker 3:  like a, I don't know, we, I get, we gotta see this is, it's get me
Speaker 3:  photos of Spider-Man. If you're out in the world and
Speaker 3:  you see a cyber truck just as much as you can get photos
Speaker 3:  of this wiper, it's the only story in technology that matters.
Speaker 3:  I promise you it's all I want. It's all I wanna talk about. The best part
Speaker 3:  of this story is I put that up on our new site in our, our with our new tool
Speaker 3:  is a quick post because yes, it was worth 20 minutes of our
Speaker 3:  time, but I was like, I can't be overwriting this.
Speaker 3:  And another publication wrote an entire story.
Speaker 4:  Listen, it's weird. Wiper weekly needs something to put on the cover. You're
Speaker 4:  like, don't
Speaker 3:  Shame wiper weekly. God, if there's a trade publication for wiper
Speaker 3:  engineers, can you please reach out to us? I would love to interview you
Speaker 3:  Ezer if you're a reader or if you're a writer or an editor, it doesn't matter
Speaker 3:  if you are just aware of the wiper industry trade publication,
Speaker 3:  reach out. I just wanna know what you're like. Alright, that's enough on
Speaker 3:  windshield wipers. Let's talk about the other biggest design story in technology,
Speaker 3:  which is Spotify and the general TikTok application
Speaker 3:  of everything. David, y you wrote up the design, there was an event
Speaker 3:  this week, Alex Heath was there. We're gonna have some more coverage. We
Speaker 3:  got an interview with our head of design and decoder coming out next week.
Speaker 3:  But tell us what's going on with Spotify.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, so this was Spotify's Stream on event, which it does
Speaker 4:  occasionally. The last one I think was two years ago. It's their big kind
Speaker 4:  of state of the union. Here's what's going on at Spotify thing. And
Speaker 4:  mostly they talk to creators. It was like 90 minutes of them being like,
Speaker 4:  are you a creator? We love you all creators, we love you.
Speaker 4:  We are Spotify. Come to Spotify. We love you creators. Hello. They brought
Speaker 4:  out the Jonas Brothers just to introduce a video, which was the coolest flex
Speaker 4:  I've ever seen in my entire life. They just came out and they were like,
Speaker 4:  look, Jennifer Lopez also like Spotify. And then they've left. It was amazing.
Speaker 4:  But anyway, the big announcement was that they're redesigning
Speaker 4:  the Spotify homepage and anyone who has used Spotify knows that
Speaker 4:  basically Spotify is just like a lot of album covers. That's the only sort
Speaker 4:  of design in there. It's just rows and rows of tiles of album covers. And
Speaker 4:  now it looks a lot more like some mix of like
Speaker 4:  Instagram stories and TikTok and like a little
Speaker 4:  bit of YouTube. But the idea is basically if you go to like the podcast
Speaker 4:  thing, instead of getting a bunch of album covers of podcasts, you're gonna
Speaker 4:  get actual like feeds of auto playing
Speaker 4:  podcasts. They're, they're big into video for as a thing.
Speaker 4:  They're big into big imagery. Now. The idea is to be much more sort of immersive
Speaker 4:  and also like discoverable. Instead of just
Speaker 4:  fighting to have better album covers, it's gonna actually start to try to
Speaker 4:  play you the most interesting bit of a podcast or a song or an audiobook
Speaker 4:  and actually connect to you that way. So that's the sort of
Speaker 4:  detoxification of it all. Everything is much more full screen. It's auto-playing.
Speaker 4:  It's much louder, it's much more visual. And as far as I can tell
Speaker 4:  Spotify users hate this in the same way that
Speaker 4:  they've hated every other non-music listening thing that Spotify
Speaker 4:  has done, which is now the impossible track that Spotify is on. Or Spotify
Speaker 4:  is like, okay, as we've talked about many times in this show, it turns out
Speaker 4:  being a streaming music company is an awful, awful, awful, awful business.
Speaker 4:  It's not great. Don't do it if you ever wanna make any money. So Spotify
Speaker 4:  is now this big company that like can't stop losing money on music and is
Speaker 4:  trying desperately to find other ways to make money. They've, they've made
Speaker 4:  this big bet on podcasts. They've bought an audiobook company, they're trying,
Speaker 4:  trying to make live audio happen. And then you have Spotify users who just
Speaker 4:  keep raising their hand being like, I I just would like to listen to my music,
Speaker 4:  please, can you leave me alone? And this is Spotify trying
Speaker 4:  to sort of satisfy everybody and at least based on the reaction to
Speaker 4:  what we've seen, the app is not out yet for most people, but people do not
Speaker 4:  like the idea of what Spotify is going for here. As far as I can
Speaker 3:  Tell, I'm very sympathetic to the notion that people hate redesigns. I've,
Speaker 3:  I've lived through it myself. Yes, absolutely, that's fine. But I will say
Speaker 3:  that we, Reddit did a mild redesign this week too.
Speaker 3:  We had the chief product person from Reddit on decoder. They're splitting
Speaker 3:  that into a text feed and a video feed and all the feedback is get this video
Speaker 3:  feed outta my face. Yep. Like we don't want it, even though all of the numbers
Speaker 3:  inside of Reddit are, oh boy, people are spending a lot of time on video.
Speaker 3:  People hate the video player. If we're gonna do video, we should, we should
Speaker 3:  just put it over there and make a video feed and a text feed. And even then
Speaker 3:  people are like, get this video outta my face. So I think there's like a
Speaker 3:  revealed preference. That's when you're alone and you're
Speaker 3:  your private time, you're watching the videos and when someone asks you about
Speaker 3:  it, you're like, I never watch videos. I only read novels. Yes. And I think
Speaker 3:  every one of these companies is like dealing with that.
Speaker 4:  But the challenge there is the metrics don't
Speaker 4:  track reality, right? Because it's like, if I'm on Spotify is a
Speaker 4:  perfectly good example, right? If I open up Spotify, press play on a playlist,
Speaker 4:  turn my phone off, put it in my pocket and never touch it again, in a certain
Speaker 4:  sense, that's a huge victory, right? Like that is the intended use of Spotify.
Speaker 4:  I can listen to music all day without needing to interact with the app. Like
Speaker 4:  from user experience, that's a gigantic win for Spotify trying to like, make
Speaker 4:  money and sell lots of really great powerful visual ads, that's a disaster.
Speaker 4:  And so what this is now is Spotify saying, and they even said this during
Speaker 4:  the stream on event, they're like, we're not worried about engagement metrics.
Speaker 4:  We're not here to just try to keep you inside of our app as much as you can.
Speaker 4:  While very clearly building things that autoplay, that autoplay
Speaker 4:  with sound and that are designed to be endlessly scrolling so that you look
Speaker 4:  at them for much longer. It's like you at some point you can't have it both
Speaker 4:  ways and they're gonna be like, oh, well engagement went way up. And it's
Speaker 4:  like, well of course it did. But that's, are we sure that's good? Like is
Speaker 4:  that what we want out of Spotify?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I So one thing that, that the music industry in particular
Speaker 3:  is fighting against straight up is TikTok. TikTok is
Speaker 3:  where every song breaks. It's where, I don't know, like Fleetwood
Speaker 3:  Mac rises like a zombie to continue haunting me for the rest of my days.
Speaker 3:  Just shut up. It's so tiresome,
Speaker 3:  rude. Sorry. I, under the music is beautifully made and I understand they
Speaker 3:  were all dating each other and it, it is on a technical level
Speaker 3:  some of the finest music ever made. It is
Speaker 3:  so boring. I'm sorry, Eli reviews
Speaker 3:  rumors and ranting out Fleetwood Max since I was 16 years old.
Speaker 3:  This is like the sanded off edges of me talking about the,
Speaker 3:  but like that's a thing that happened, right? The guy riding the
Speaker 3:  longboard in California, getting the free cranberries for life or whatever
Speaker 3:  is an entirely a TikTok phenomenon. I realize that if you don't know
Speaker 3:  what I'm talking about, that sounded completely bonkers. But if you just
Speaker 3:  put those words into Google, you will, you will understand.
Speaker 3:  It's a whole thing that happened. Yep. That's TikTok. Like TikTok just like
Speaker 3:  made that song relevant again. It made fleet relevant again. It's doing it
Speaker 3:  over and over and over again. It's where new artists break, it's
Speaker 3:  changing the complexion of the music industry. It's making songs shorter,
Speaker 3:  which is very funny. It's like sampling it. Like if everything is in the
Speaker 3:  music industry is happening on TikTok and then underneath it all,
Speaker 3:  TikTok is not a music service really. And so
Speaker 3:  they're kind of like, yeah, music industry, you want to break a song, just
Speaker 3:  pay us a bunch of money and we'll make sure those tracks get promoted
Speaker 3:  in a way that if Spotify does it and people claim Spotify does
Speaker 3:  it, but if they actually do that, everyone will get really mad at Spotify.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So like Spotify's just got like a, a major problem on its hands that
Speaker 3:  all discovery happens on TikTok and then people go to Spotify to listen to
Speaker 3:  the song, but they're spending all of their time on a platform that has video
Speaker 3:  advertising built into it, which is much more lucrative than Spotify
Speaker 3:  free.
Speaker 4:  Right. But the the important second piece of that though is like,
Speaker 4:  it's not audio led discovery, right? Like people are watching
Speaker 4:  videos through which they discover audio and that's
Speaker 4:  like Spotify has everybody, lots of different publications or not
Speaker 4:  publications. Lots of different companies have tried to figure out how to
Speaker 4:  do Audio First discovery. And it turns out it's essentially impossible because
Speaker 4:  the idea of like, I'm gonna sit here and just listen to something I've never
Speaker 4:  heard of for a while is super boring and people get tired of it and that's
Speaker 4:  why everybody puts the hook to their song at the beginning of the song now.
Speaker 4:  And so, but what you have with the video is it's, it's just
Speaker 4:  more interesting. It's just gonna hold your attention a little longer, which
Speaker 4:  gives the song a chance to catch you a little longer and then you can sort
Speaker 4:  of trip through TikTok that way. And so Spotify has been trying to play this
Speaker 4:  like how do we do more visual things game forever to keep you looking
Speaker 4:  at the app and has just never solved it anything like the way
Speaker 4:  TikTok has solved it. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And now they've just made TikTok again. And I, I think that the big question
Speaker 3:  is whether people are going to open Spotify first
Speaker 3:  to be like, I wanna find some new things. This is Spotify's claim, right?
Speaker 3:  That the business they're in is actually discovery and not
Speaker 3:  playback. And if you, you listen to the interview with
Speaker 3:  Gustav that Alex is gonna do on decoder next week, or if you listen to their
Speaker 3:  event, they're very clear that the the whole
Speaker 3:  thing they're doing is trying to get people to try new things. Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  that is fundamentally Spotify's value to the world is discovery across the
Speaker 3:  list. I'll just read this quote, not to give away the whole interview, but
Speaker 3:  he says in regards to cover art, he said to Alex, you have to click through
Speaker 3:  one of the titles and you have to wait for one and a half on minutes on average
Speaker 3:  to get to the hook. That can't be the best way to discover music. The best
Speaker 3:  way to discover audio must be through audio, which makes
Speaker 3:  intuitive sense. But I know that when people open Spotify and
Speaker 3:  it just starts blasting them with hooks, they're gonna lose their minds.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think that's right. And I think by the way, the, the discovery thing
Speaker 4:  is something you'll hear from every single music platform. They all think
Speaker 4:  that the main thing that they can do for the music industry and for
Speaker 4:  listeners is expose you to new stuff. Right? Because it's like, if I wanna
Speaker 4:  listen to Rumors by Fleetwood Mac, I have Infinity Options, many of them
Speaker 4:  free one of them type it into YouTube.
Speaker 3:  And the last one being Don't
Speaker 1:  Rude Rumors is wonderful, a perfect album.
Speaker 3:  Look, I'm not even disputing that the argument, I know that many
Speaker 3:  people feel this way.
Speaker 1:  Mila Hayes for you it back
Speaker 4:  When I spent a bunch of time with Lior Cohen who runs YouTube music a while
Speaker 4:  back and he said very much the same things. And like Apple will say the same
Speaker 4:  thing. That's why they gave Zane Lowe all that money, right? It's like discovery
Speaker 4:  is the thing. They want to help break artists so they can be friends with
Speaker 4:  the music industry. They want to help break artists so that listeners will
Speaker 4:  keep coming back to discover new things. Like that is the product in a really
Speaker 4:  real way, it's just that TikTok showed up and is so much better at it than
Speaker 4:  anybody else.
Speaker 1:  Is it also because like the playlist suck because for a long time they kind
Speaker 1:  of tried to replicate the DJ by doing all day playlists,
Speaker 1:  right? And and are people just not listening to those playlists and finding
Speaker 1:  new musicians that way?
Speaker 3:  Well, Spotify rolled out the AI playlist. Yeah, but those suck. So they're
Speaker 3:  doing much, much more of this stuff.
Speaker 5:  It sounds like the problem for TikTok, the problem for Spotify, the problem
Speaker 5:  for YouTube music is that I am not 16 always
Speaker 5:  and I'm not always hearing the best music I will ever hear ever
Speaker 5:  at that point in my life.
Speaker 5:  And if I were, maybe I would wanna listen to these playlists and listen to
Speaker 5:  a bunch of new songs because I'd be young and I I would be experiencing new
Speaker 5:  things and I would say, yes, I am them. I'm making this music my entire personality
Speaker 5:  now as, as I did then. But it's now X number
Speaker 5:  of years later that music is still my personality. I want to hear the music
Speaker 5:  that I listened to a decade plus ago. That is the only thing that I want.
Speaker 5:  I do not want a playlist. I do not want suggestions. I want to hear the same
Speaker 5:  songs that I've already heard. Possibly you could remix them and blend them
Speaker 5:  together. That's cool. No new music. But I, I guess that's a
Speaker 5:  problem for Spotify that that I don't wanna listen to the new things.
Speaker 3:  Well, so under underneath that is, the real problem for Spotify
Speaker 3:  is that you listening to hits from the nineties over and over
Speaker 3:  again does not actually make those artists any money. And maybe it
Speaker 3:  shouldn't, right? Like in the CD era, you would buy that cd, you would listen
Speaker 3:  to it for the rest of your life. That artist would not get money every time
Speaker 3:  you listen to a cd. But they got a lot of money up front for the
Speaker 3:  cd, right? And that u usually sustained most artists now
Speaker 3:  it's like the game that they're all playing is like pennies forever,
Speaker 3:  right? So Spotify has a lot of incentive to make their catalog artists,
Speaker 3:  or like the catalog artists from major labels happy because no one is getting
Speaker 3:  the big dollars up front. They're all just getting pennies over time. But
Speaker 3:  they still have to break new artists. And to break new artists, you gotta
Speaker 3:  shove 'em in people's faces all the time. You gotta break new songs. And
Speaker 3:  I, I think all of this stuff is in a real tension with the other piece
Speaker 3:  of what they announced, which is an emphasis on video podcasts
Speaker 3:  and showing you little clips of video podcasts in the feed as you
Speaker 3:  scroll. Because that is just a jarring transition from like,
Speaker 3:  here's the hook of a song, here's the hook of a song. Do you like this playlist?
Speaker 3:  Go over here, here's three people talking about whatever. Which is
Speaker 3:  admittedly what we do here.
Speaker 1:  Hi guys.
Speaker 3:  And we'll probably figure out how to get involved in that on Spotify. But
Speaker 3:  it's just, there's a lot of stuff, there's a lot of business models
Speaker 3:  they're trying to cram into one experience.
Speaker 4:  But this is the magic of TikTok. Like that that thing
Speaker 4:  you just described is the thing that has made TikTok so powerful, which is
Speaker 4:  that it can be wrong about what you're gonna be interested in nine
Speaker 4:  outta 10 times. And TikTok that that like endless vertical scrolling
Speaker 4:  thing with video and sound is like immersive enough
Speaker 4:  even when you don't care about what it is that it keeps you scrolling. And
Speaker 4:  that's like, that's the magical thing that TikTok solved is most of the time
Speaker 4:  you don't care about the thing that's being shown to you, but the price of
Speaker 4:  TikTok being wrong is so low because the scrolling experience
Speaker 4:  is so fun that you will just keep scrolling even when you don't care about
Speaker 4:  the content. Like the activity is enough. And what that gave TikTok
Speaker 4:  permission to do was just shove stuff you don't care about in your face
Speaker 4:  all the time to see what hits. And everyone is copying that for exactly
Speaker 4:  that same reason, right? Like that's what Facebook is trying to do. They're
Speaker 4:  like, we are you interested in this? And you say no. And they're like, what
Speaker 4:  about this? And you say no. And they're like, what about this? And they'll
Speaker 4:  just do that
Speaker 3:  Forever and, and Facebook can't figure it out. It's like, is it girls? And
Speaker 3:  they'll, there's just like one bikini girl no matter what at all times.
Speaker 3:  And I'm like, no, no, no, it's trucks jumping over stuff. I want to be very
Speaker 3:  clear about this. I literally typed the words into the search box
Speaker 3:  and like every couple weeks I was like, I don't know, just one thing that'll
Speaker 3:  make your wife
Speaker 4:  Mad minus bloopers from the office. It's just like when in doubt, TikTok
Speaker 4:  just show me bloopers from the office and like, we're cool again, everything's
Speaker 4:  fine. But no, but that's the thing and that's why you do that extra visual
Speaker 4:  thing because it's just constant. There's just so much going
Speaker 4:  on in a way that like if you show me eight seconds of silence at the beginning
Speaker 4:  of a song and a playlist or like a slow building guitar, people are out.
Speaker 4:  But if you just like play loud noise over and over again as I scroll. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like that's gonna keep me
Speaker 1:  Engaged. Okay, so in the seventies, like music in the seventies, that's when
Speaker 1:  we started getting the long guitar solos and stuff before that in the forties
Speaker 1:  and fifties. Bill Specter, horrible man, dead now, but he made the wall
Speaker 1:  of sound, right?
Speaker 3:  Horrible man. Dead was coming to him. Phil
Speaker 1:  Was coming to him. I mean played like Russian roulette, Jesus and the lady
Speaker 1:  died, it was not great. True. Wore a cape, dude,
Speaker 1:  like wore a cape to record music. But in the fifties and
Speaker 1:  sixties wearing his little cape, he created That's true. Like a
Speaker 1:  whole new way of listening to music, which was just blasted
Speaker 1:  into your ears on every single, like, he was like, I'm gonna make
Speaker 1:  it really, really loud because everybody's just listening on radio. And so
Speaker 1:  the louder it is, the more they'll like be likely to sit around and listen.
Speaker 1:  Which is why we have the Beach Boys, but also like all of those great
Speaker 1:  pops from the, the early sixties. So that's just kind of what they're doing
Speaker 1:  again on TikTok,
Speaker 3:  Pretty much the, the music distribution thing is like really interesting.
Speaker 3:  So Phil Specker is like a, in the like the 45 era, right? He's like
Speaker 3:  doing singles, he's distributing on radio. There's a really great Vox video
Speaker 3:  about the dawn of the 12 inch single and like bands like
Speaker 3:  New Order, were like Blue Monday will be 45 minutes long. Cause we've got,
Speaker 3:  we can just have like oceans of vinyl to print on. Yeah. And then we
Speaker 3:  collab and then you kind of get into those seventies, eighties songs
Speaker 3:  where it's like, what if we did synth pads for like a minute
Speaker 3:  before a single drum? Right? And it's like these like
Speaker 3:  huge builds and like Pink Floyd is just like, you know,
Speaker 3:  swishing around your house, just haunting you. That's great. Like
Speaker 3:  that music is great. Could not work with any modern distribution. No. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  because you can't, you there's, you just can't get to the hook right away.
Speaker 3:  And all of that was when people bought vinyl records, they,
Speaker 3:  they literally thought they wanted a lot of music for the money.
Speaker 3:  Like the Clash is like Sand Anisa is 3, 3 12
Speaker 3:  inches. It's like six sides of vinyl. There are skits in here for some
Speaker 3:  reason we don't know why. And that's just value for dollar. And
Speaker 3:  now everything is free. So it's like just on to the next one. Fine.
Speaker 3:  The thing that's really interesting on Spotify one, it's not a swipe, it's
Speaker 3:  a scroll, which is the smallest distinction, but I
Speaker 3:  think a weird one, right? They're trying to like cop this user interface
Speaker 3:  behavior from TikTok, but they're making you like slowly scroll through this
Speaker 3:  stuff. I think I would bet they switch to swipes pretty soon. And then two,
Speaker 3:  what TikTok has is a, a infinite universe of user generated
Speaker 3:  content. So there, there is a lot of garbage, but then
Speaker 3:  like things will hit that no one ever thought of, right? And that's like
Speaker 3:  the magic Spotify is still pretty curated. Like what
Speaker 3:  ends up in that feed is gonna be pretty curated by the music industry,
Speaker 3:  by the podcast industry. Spotify does have anchor, they're like user
Speaker 3:  generated podcast tool, but they've really diminished its stature.
Speaker 3:  I think they've even renamed it. Yeah. It's part of like Spotify for podcasters
Speaker 3:  now. Yeah. So you've just got this feed, it's like it acts a little differently.
Speaker 3:  It is way more curated and professional. And usually those
Speaker 3:  things together mean that they get stale fast as opposed to
Speaker 3:  like the endless, like what are the kids doing today of TikTok?
Speaker 5:  The question for Spotify is that now that they're, they've leading into video,
Speaker 5:  can they be on the go 90 scale?
Speaker 3:  Can I read you this quote that I've just been thinking about? So Spotify's
Speaker 3:  leading into video podcasts, everyone's in the video podcasts. The reason
Speaker 3:  is not complicated, right? It's that for the platforms,
Speaker 3:  not for necessarily for the podcasters, but for the platforms being able
Speaker 3:  to insert video advertising is more lucrative
Speaker 3:  than audio advertising. We are obviously this shows on YouTube
Speaker 3:  now, like the details of our money are actually opaque to us. That's the
Speaker 3:  whole point of the fact that we are journalism. There's a sales team, they
Speaker 3:  do it all over there, but there's a real dynamic between the money you make
Speaker 3:  and, and the audio and the money you make in video. And the dollars in video
Speaker 3:  are generally higher. They're not higher on YouTube, which is weird.
Speaker 3:  But YouTube is like the gold standard video platform. A
Speaker 3:  lot of the platforms want to go capture those video dollars. So that's why
Speaker 3:  Reddit does it. That's why Spotify's doing it. But here's this quote and
Speaker 3:  it just video podcasting is one of the fastest
Speaker 3:  growing areas of podcasting and we expect that growth to continue.
Speaker 3:  That's from Julie McNamara, head of Global Podcast Studios at Spotify at
Speaker 3:  this event. What's the video podcast? Is it just videos of
Speaker 3:  people talking? I mean I, this is a video podcast, right? That's, yes. I
Speaker 3:  think we get that is the view of video podcast. Yes.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Hundred percent. What is it? A video
Speaker 3:  podcast?
Speaker 4:  I actually, I think Alex is right. Like I, I think the the, there was a
Speaker 4:  great Twitter thread and I don't remember who it was, but I'm sorry. I'll
Speaker 4:  see if I can find it and I'll tweet it back out. Actually I won't. I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  use Twitter. But that's a whole other point that they were talking about
Speaker 4:  Jason and Travis Kelsey, these football playing brothers who have had a super
Speaker 4:  successful thing. And one of the points that the thread made was that they
Speaker 4:  don't call it a podcast like it is distributed as a podcast on podcast
Speaker 4:  platforms, but they just think of it as like a show. And I think that's right.
Speaker 4:  Like what is, what is an interview show other than a video
Speaker 4:  podcast, right? Like people talking to people on screen has been around
Speaker 4:  forever. The only difference is like, we show the microphones now. And so
Speaker 4:  I think what's happened is this stuff has all just sort of collapsed
Speaker 4:  where it's like, okay, people talking is interesting. Watching people talk
Speaker 4:  is interesting. These things don't all have to be different.
Speaker 4:  We can just shove them together and just let them be shows like the
Speaker 4:  word podcast is like a relic of iPods, right? Like it hasn't
Speaker 4:  described what this industry is in a really long time. And
Speaker 3:  So, no, I'm telling you this is an exist. You were describing very confidently
Speaker 3:  an existential crisis for the podcast industry.
Speaker 4:  Oh, absolutely. It's happening. It's like
Speaker 3:  The idea that you make radio and you distribute is MP3 files via
Speaker 3:  RSS to it. It an ecosystem of players are all inter
Speaker 3:  independent and can compete with each. That's po. Like
Speaker 3:  if you ask people what is a podcast, they will start with
Speaker 3:  RSS feeds.
Speaker 4:  Sure. And that broke the minute Spotify started spending money on podcasters,
Speaker 4:  right? Like this is, this has been dying for a while. And I think what you're
Speaker 4:  seeing now is everybody just acknowledging that like, okay, this,
Speaker 4:  this doesn't, this distinction doesn't exist anymore. And actually what we're
Speaker 4:  talking about is just a bunch of different kinds of distribution for the
Speaker 4:  same kind of thing, which is people you talk that you care about doing stuff
Speaker 4:  together, talking to each other. It's right. Like it's, I don't know, these
Speaker 4:  things are not that far apart. I
Speaker 3:  Don't think we, again, we obviously are participants in this. I
Speaker 4:  Love video
Speaker 3:  Podcasts. We make videos of this podcast and other podcasts. We put them
Speaker 3:  on YouTube. We should figure out how to put them on Spotify. I didn't even
Speaker 3:  know that Apple Podcast supports video. It does, does it? I don't know
Speaker 3:  anybody who watches video and Apple Podcast, but it definitely supports video
Speaker 3:  only
Speaker 1:  Way I watch video.
Speaker 3:  Just the only
Speaker 6:  Way, no other
Speaker 3:  Way to watch it. Watch who it, I watch RSS fed video and app,
Speaker 5:  But I catch myself on TikTok sometimes watching video clips of podcasts that
Speaker 5:  I've already listened to. Absolutely. And I, I can't even really
Speaker 3:  Explain it. By the way, go subscribe to youtube.com/ver,
Speaker 3:  we'd really appreciate it.
Speaker 4:  It's great. Okay. But wait, wait, Mila, let me, let me just expand this
Speaker 4:  existential crisis slightly. Yeah. So one of my favorite podcasts is the
Speaker 4:  Always Sunny podcast, which is just the three creators and
Speaker 4:  stars of the show. It's always Sunny in Philadelphia doing a podcast.
Speaker 4:  The the show is a podcast. It's also a video podcast on YouTube,
Speaker 4:  often on YouTube on, during their podcast they will play clips of their
Speaker 4:  show and talk about the clips from their show or
Speaker 4:  about the process of writing this show. So you could argue that their podcast
Speaker 4:  has bled into a video podcast which has bled into their television show.
Speaker 4:  And I'm sure they're gonna do an episode where they make a podcast. They
Speaker 4:  did do an episode where they make a podcast. It's like, what
Speaker 3:  Is,
Speaker 4:  What is any of
Speaker 3:  This anymore? What is
Speaker 4:  Content? I don't know.
Speaker 3:  I just, the idea that everything is a video podcast and
Speaker 3:  soon Spotify will try to shove it into a feed that is almost TikTok but not
Speaker 3:  quite. That's where we're going.
Speaker 4:  Yes, absolutely. Yes.
Speaker 3:  Right. Like one of my favorite examples of this is cnbc. All of their
Speaker 3:  hours are published as audio podcasts in Apple Pod.
Speaker 3:  You can go get Squawk on the street as a podcast every day.
Speaker 3:  And it's just CNBC Anchors doing their show with
Speaker 3:  no regard to the fact that it's a podcast. It play, it works perfectly
Speaker 4:  Fine. Yeah. You just have to imagine there's a lower crawl saying stocks
Speaker 4:  down, everybody panics. And that's all
Speaker 3:  Run on your bank. Get out there. Just run at your bank as fast
Speaker 3:  as you can. I mean, I think they're usually, when people
Speaker 3:  think of podcasts, they, they think of not a distribution
Speaker 3:  but like a form. Yes. Right. This thing that we make is
Speaker 3:  a podcast that despite all odds has been going on for over 10 years
Speaker 3:  now. And it, it's just this, right? It's people talking to each other, maybe
Speaker 3:  some format, maybe somewhere along the way seminal commit a murder and we'll
Speaker 3:  figure out who did it. Richard, that's on next season of VER
Speaker 4:  Two, crime is an ideal waiting
Speaker 3:  To happen. Can we get, William, can you start playing like the Tinkly serial
Speaker 3:  piano here? Please.
Speaker 3:  That would be amazing. Right? There's formats in podcasting, but you kind
Speaker 3:  of understand what they are and people riff on them and they expand them
Speaker 3:  in. You do not think of RSS based distribution. And I think once you
Speaker 3:  open the door to, it's a video too. I, I have seen podcasts
Speaker 3:  where everyone's wearing laugh mics and just sitting around on couches and
Speaker 3:  you're like, this is getting, like, this is just a talk show now. This is
Speaker 3:  late night television, but we're calling it a video podcast to get it
Speaker 3:  into all this distribution. I don't know, like there's Spotify is,
Speaker 3:  they're gonna end up competing more with YouTube than I think they understand
Speaker 3:  because YouTube has all of that and it has YouTube videos and it has
Speaker 3:  whatever else, right? I
Speaker 1:  Oh, like I think yeah, they'll kind, they'll compete with YouTube in that
Speaker 1:  the fact that YouTube is creating its own like podcasting setup
Speaker 1:  and everything. But at the same time, I keep going back to this show critical
Speaker 1:  role, which I've only watched like half of, of an episode cuz they're four
Speaker 1:  hours long and that's a terrible thing to do with your day. But it was a
Speaker 1:  show that was four hours long and people were sitting there watching it and
Speaker 1:  they kept begging for a podcast and they got a podcast and
Speaker 1:  some u some listeners go and they listen to the podcast. Some people watch
Speaker 1:  the show and the show's like still gotten like better. The production
Speaker 1:  qualities have improved. It's all like they're investing further
Speaker 1:  into that side of it. So it's like, I think those two audiences are just
Speaker 1:  very different. And this is just a big mad grab to get
Speaker 1:  as much audience as possible as quickly as possible. Right.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I, that's what every platform is always doing. I just think Spotify
Speaker 3:  in particular thinks it's competing with TikTok in As, and it's
Speaker 1:  With
Speaker 3:  YouTube. With YouTube,
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And YouTube is out there. Like YouTube was at Hotpod Summit, our
Speaker 3:  hotpod, our podcasting conference a couple weeks ago, they announced
Speaker 3:  YouTube podcast features. They announced video podcast features,
Speaker 3:  background play like YouTube knows they, they see it coming. They
Speaker 3:  see that opportunity. Yeah. But Spotify I think is, they're headed in
Speaker 3:  a different way and somewhere lost in all of this is, boy, I'd like to just
Speaker 3:  see a bunch of songs in my catalog and pick from them.
Speaker 3:  Right. Which appears to be fully outta favor at this point.
Speaker 1:  It's done.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. No one will ever own any music ever again. All right. We gotta take
Speaker 3:  a break. We'll come back. We gotta talk about David's anger at streaming
Speaker 3:  boxes. This is just a real streaming media episode. And then of course there's
Speaker 3:  a Twitter update. We got some policy updates. There's a lot going on. We'll
Speaker 3:  be right back
Speaker 7:  For years now. It's been very unlikely for a big mega
Speaker 7:  box office hit to win best picture at the Oscars
Speaker 8:  As like c CGI heavy movies sort of started to dominate the top
Speaker 8:  10. That's when you sort of started to see that like the public's taste and
Speaker 8:  the Oscar's taste just like really, really started to part ways.
Speaker 8:  Like, I wish they were more aligned too, but I kind of want the public to
Speaker 8:  maybe like, you know, go see the Fable Mans guys. Yeah. Like it's not gonna
Speaker 8:  hurt you. I don't know
Speaker 7:  What's up with the Oscars and Blockbusters this
Speaker 7:  week on Intuit Vultures Pop Culture podcast,
Speaker 7:  new episodes Tuesdays and Fridays.
Speaker 9:  Hey, it's Newell King, co-host of today, explained here by now you've heard
Speaker 9:  about Scott Adams, the Dilbert creator and interpreter of polling data.
Speaker 10:  Well, Rasmussen Poll had a provocative little poll today.
Speaker 10:  They said, do you agree or disagree with a statement?
Speaker 10:  It's okay to be white.
Speaker 9:  Who spent a career building a comic empire.
Speaker 11:  It spoke to so many people. It was the comic strip that you would
Speaker 11:  see push pinned onto cubicle walls as sort of
Speaker 11:  the corporate culture was changing. We needed humor to
Speaker 11:  survive that time. And Scott hit it perfectly,
Speaker 9:  Then got pulled from newspapers after a racist tirade. So many questions,
Speaker 9:  including why is Rasmussen asking people if it's okay to be white?
Speaker 3:  It's a really
Speaker 8:  Weird thing to ask people. And
Speaker 12:  To be honest, I haven't heard a good explanation for why,
Speaker 9:  But we found answers today. Explained. It's in your feed every weekday at
Speaker 9:  2:00 PM
Speaker 3:  Okay. All right, we're back. So David, you went
Speaker 3:  on leave child cared for the child and then you
Speaker 3:  did the thing that everybody on leave does. Parental leave does is you held
Speaker 3:  a baby who was sleeping, you couldn't move and you just
Speaker 3:  thought deeply about technology and you concluded, I think rationally
Speaker 3:  what most people do, the same television is a disaster and you
Speaker 3:  should tell people about it. Tell us about it.
Speaker 4:  That's basically right. So what I promised I wouldn't do
Speaker 4:  was I was not going to become a dad gadget guy. I
Speaker 4:  was like, I will not come back from parental leave and be the guy
Speaker 4:  who's like, have you heard of the Ki Karu? Like I'm not, I will not be that
Speaker 4:  guy.
Speaker 3:  The ki Karu.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I'm not doing it. You cannot beat me into this. Now I'm not doing
Speaker 4:  it. What did happen was I spent a tremendous amount of
Speaker 4:  time with a child sleeping on top of me watching television. And
Speaker 4:  I watched television on my smart tv. I watched television on my Roku.
Speaker 4:  I watch television on my fire tv. I watched television on my Apple tv.
Speaker 4:  I watched television on my, on my Nvidia Shield because I am a
Speaker 4:  maniac who owns all these things. They're all bad. This is the thing that
Speaker 4:  I have landed on is there was a time, not that many years ago when
Speaker 4:  the TV was going to be like the hub of technology, right? This was when
Speaker 4:  the smart home was really starting to become a thing. This was when smartphone
Speaker 4:  technology was starting to sort of percolate out and everything was getting
Speaker 4:  new processing power and much more sort of sensory awareness. This was the
Speaker 4:  moment when like the game console was gonna shrink all the way down and just
Speaker 4:  become your set top box. Microsoft tried to do it with the Xbox. Everybody
Speaker 4:  was like, the set top box is the future. And what turned out to happen
Speaker 4:  is that set top boxes are bad and getting worse and becoming
Speaker 4:  sort of increasingly commodified because for a bunch of reasons that have
Speaker 4:  to do with how these companies make money, what the streaming services themselves
Speaker 4:  want. And just the fact that this is the world we live
Speaker 4:  in. And smart TVs continue to get cheaper and cheaper, they
Speaker 4:  suck and there's no way for them to get any better. There's no incentive
Speaker 4:  or reason for anyone to try to build a good set top box anymore. And that
Speaker 4:  just made me sad. And I got to the end of this post and I was like, I'm gonna,
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna write an angry thing demanding everybody do better. And I got to
Speaker 4:  the end of it and was like, oh no, it, it's just bad and it's never getting
Speaker 4:  any better.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The, so the ones that you really called out were, it's still very
Speaker 3:  app-based. Yeah. Which is what some of them want. I think Apple's still like,
Speaker 3:  whatever it's app-based, that's fine, but two, so it's app based instead
Speaker 3:  of content based. So
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean that's the, the simplest thing set top box should do
Speaker 4:  for you is take you to the things you wanna watch. Like that doesn't strike
Speaker 4:  you as,
Speaker 1:  But it's never going to, cuz Netflix Complicated doesn't wanna
Speaker 1:  participate in any ecosystem that allows you to, that allows
Speaker 1:  you to find their content anywhere. But the Netflix app,
Speaker 4:  Right? It's like if, if if 30 years ago, you know,
Speaker 4:  one of the cable companies had just been like, no, we don't wanna be in the
Speaker 4:  guide. You have to use a different guide if you wanna get to cnn. This is
Speaker 4:  somehow the world we've ended up in. Yes. It's like, like the, the old
Speaker 4:  spreadsheet TV guide was a much better interface than anything we have for
Speaker 4:  finding stuff to watch now. And like that is a deeply sad state of affairs.
Speaker 3:  So I love Verge readers because a lot of them are like, whatever the Apple
Speaker 3:  TV is fine. Which I think is a reasonable, it's
Speaker 3:  extremely fine.
Speaker 4:  It's fine. I say that in the piece, like it's, it's probably the best one
Speaker 4:  you can buy because it's the only one that has an actually fast
Speaker 4:  processor. And it's like, you know what? If the system is my
Speaker 3:  Nvidia shield, people just lost their minds. I
Speaker 4:  Was like,
Speaker 1:  Whatever. Say that about the shield.
Speaker 4:  The shield is really fast and just utterly decimated by the fact that Android
Speaker 4:  TV doesn't work very well. Yes. But there's a good processor in
Speaker 4:  there. It just isn't very fast and it's not NVIDIA's fault, but the Apple
Speaker 4:  TV is a perfectly fine thing, right? But like, there's
Speaker 4:  so many simple ways it could be a lot better. One of them is
Speaker 4:  just like if Siri weren't trash and Apple had ever made
Speaker 4:  Siri good at anything ever for any reason, the Apple TV might be
Speaker 4:  more useful, but it, it just, it's fine. And if, if
Speaker 4:  you want, fine, I can sell you fine for $15. Like you go
Speaker 4:  buy a Roku stick that's inevitably on sale at Amazon or buy a fire TV that
Speaker 4:  they will just give you for free if you look at them and it's all
Speaker 4:  just fine,
Speaker 5:  Whatever. I feel like, fine. It was better a few years ago. Like when, when
Speaker 5:  the Chromecast originally came out, it felt good to use it. It was, it
Speaker 5:  worked. It was cheap. And I think those are the, the two, the two
Speaker 5:  bars that need to cross.
Speaker 3:  There are a lot of Chromecast fans in the comments of this piece by the way.
Speaker 3:  They were like,
Speaker 4:  Whatever. Oh, there,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's not, it's not nearly as cheap. It doesn't work nearly as well.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You know, like now you get HDR and 4K and all these other things if
Speaker 5:  you want them, but it's not as easy to use. I'm trying to watch an
Speaker 5:  F1 clip like casted to my TV and suddenly the volume just
Speaker 5:  starts going to maximum because my phone is at maximum. And, and
Speaker 5:  I'm like, why would anyone want this? This experience? This should not be
Speaker 5:  like this. Why, why, why am I having these problems?
Speaker 3:  You want to feel the, the beat of the engine thrumming
Speaker 3:  through
Speaker 5:  Your body, not want to wake my wife up at 2:00 AM with the sounds of of
Speaker 5:  F1 engine, but
Speaker 3:  You're like, honey, listen to this engine.
Speaker 5:  It'll be the last time
Speaker 4:  While I was sitting there complaining about set boxes being bad, Anna,
Speaker 4:  my wife just kept saying, I don't care about any of the rest of this. Just
Speaker 4:  why aren't all the apps the same volume? Like I turn on my smart TV
Speaker 4:  and I have to put it, I put it to 25 for Netflix, 35
Speaker 4:  for Peacock, 45 for HBO O. And then I go back to
Speaker 4:  Netflix and it blows my ears out and wakes up my child. And it's like, this
Speaker 4:  is the simplest thing that this hardware could do is just make everything
Speaker 4:  the same volume. But it can't because it's not allowed to. Because the streaming
Speaker 4:  services won't allow the set type the box makers to do anything.
Speaker 1:  Did you notice that Peacock also doesn't, hasn't fixed the,
Speaker 1:  the difference between audio and commercials versus Oh it's horrible. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Regular things like this is the number one thing people always hated. It
Speaker 1:  was a great thing that Soundbar tried to solve and somehow the soundbar could
Speaker 1:  not solve it on Peacock because peacock's like, no, we want you to have this.
Speaker 1:  Like it's, and it's always like condom commercials is all I
Speaker 1:  get on Peacock and it's just like, wow. And I'm like, well
Speaker 3:  This is the connected TV ecosystem has found you Alex,
Speaker 1:  It has failed profoundly.
Speaker 3:  Mark Zuckerberg's listening to you my friend,
Speaker 1:  I was just like, what is happening? Because it's so loud and it's like, do
Speaker 1:  you need condoms? I'm like, no, I, I'm good. Thanks
Speaker 1:  my God.
Speaker 1:  Very, very loudly. And then back to poker face soft whisper.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, great. I like TV that it's a conversation you're having with your tv.
Speaker 3:  You're like, no thank you
Speaker 1:  Because I'm sitting in my house like, nope.
Speaker 3:  So what's fascinating about this is Apple in particular,
Speaker 3:  Everywhere else in its ecosystems has absolute
Speaker 3:  control over its developers. Like the idea that iPhone
Speaker 3:  apps would be this wildly inconsistent or not participate in universal search
Speaker 3:  or whatever. Apple would write the rule, people would complain.
Speaker 3:  European bureaucrats would issue a directive. The whole there, you, you everyone
Speaker 3:  knows the exact cycle I'm talking about if you're a chest listener, right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. We would do a whole episode about it. It would be a thing on
Speaker 3:  the TV side, apple does not have the market share to exercise the
Speaker 3:  control. And they have a lot of fans and people really like it. But apps
Speaker 3:  launch, they launch without support for apples. They sometimes,
Speaker 3:  they don't even launch on the Apple TV right away. They launch without support
Speaker 3:  for features. They launched Features light. I'm specifically thinking about
Speaker 3:  YouTube TV launching 5.1 surround just way after it came
Speaker 3:  to other platforms. And then the apps themselves are still kind of just like
Speaker 3:  HTML five wrappers because there's so many TV platforms
Speaker 3:  that the streaming vendors have just been like, screw it, they're all
Speaker 3:  web apps. Here's the web app package for ties in. Here's the
Speaker 3:  web app package for whatever LG is running Web Os on and on go.
Speaker 4:  Not only are they doing that, it's, they're also on this incredible
Speaker 4:  race to the technological bottom because now that there are all these incredibly
Speaker 4:  cheap smart TVs, you have to build that app in such a way that not only does
Speaker 4:  it work across all these platforms, it works on this unbelievably cheap
Speaker 4:  low end plat processor inside of like a shitty TCL
Speaker 4:  tv. And so you're in this position where you, you are actually
Speaker 4:  incentivized against building something that works because it would break
Speaker 4:  most of the time. Yeah. Like even if you built a really good app for the
Speaker 4:  Apple tv, it would then not work most other places. So of course you're gonna
Speaker 4:  build the lowest common denominator, which is what everybody has started
Speaker 4:  doing.
Speaker 3:  So one of the interesting responses I saw to your piece, David, were
Speaker 3:  the people who said, this is why I've started buying channels inside of Apple
Speaker 3:  TV and inside of YouTube TV and inside of Amazon. Yep.
Speaker 3:  Right? They're like, I don't wanna use a Showtime app. I just bought Showtime
Speaker 3:  inside of YouTube TV or wherever. And that gets me closer
Speaker 3:  to a single interface. We've seen A lot of these companies are starting
Speaker 3:  to think about their products as bundles. Apple does it, Amazon does it,
Speaker 3:  YouTube does it. H b o Max is gonna turn into some something.
Speaker 3:  They're just gonna call it Max. And that's gonna be a horrible day for me.
Speaker 3:  ESPN
Speaker 5:  Has said that it's going to perhaps, or there's been a rumor that s ESPN
Speaker 5:  might allow other sports sports channels to plug into it
Speaker 5:  so that it could become a hub for your sports streaming.
Speaker 1:  That's Plexus big play right now. Every, every couple of
Speaker 1:  years. Plex doesn't new, is that Plexus big play? No, that has become
Speaker 1:  Plexus big play is they said, we wanna be your central hub. So we've found
Speaker 1:  these weird, horrible hacks that are not actually very user
Speaker 1:  friendly to, to let all of the apps work inside
Speaker 1:  our platform because we recognize that everything sucks. And like Apple
Speaker 1:  did that with the TV app, the terribly, terribly named TV
Speaker 1:  app. They try to do that. But again, everybody gets bodied because Netflix
Speaker 1:  or some other big player doesn't wanna listen to him and nobody has
Speaker 1:  the market share to force.
Speaker 3:  Several years ago the Verges office was in Midtown New York and we want to
Speaker 3:  go out after work or a drink or a snack
Speaker 3:  mid. You haven't been to Midtown New York. It's kind of like a weird ghost
Speaker 3:  town. We used to walk into this restaurant, it was a couple blocks away.
Speaker 3:  It was really nice. It looked expensive. There was never anyone in
Speaker 3:  there, ever. Zero people were ever in this
Speaker 3:  restaurant. And like 400 people worked there. That restaurant was a front
Speaker 3:  for the mob. And in this metaphor, that restaurant is
Speaker 3:  Plex.
Speaker 3:  Speak
Speaker 4:  To that Eli.
Speaker 3:  Just put that out there. That's fine man. You can, you can
Speaker 3:  tell me you're doing all kinds of shit, but
Speaker 3:  everybody knows what's happening in the back of that restaurant.
Speaker 1:  It's fast TV back there. That's what they got going on. It's free
Speaker 1:  supported tv.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  The only way to watch
Speaker 3:  No customers.
Speaker 3:  Very odd, very odd situation. Actually. The TV
Speaker 3:  and Apple is like a perfect example of this, right? They wanted it.
Speaker 3:  You can see what it would be if it worked, but no one will play ball.
Speaker 3:  So it barely works. And it's not the home screen of the product.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's, this is the thing is it's not, it's not like, it's not
Speaker 4:  obvious how to do this better, right? Like there's a, there's a big long
Speaker 4:  vision of like the TV as the center of your home
Speaker 4:  in a lot of really interesting ways that are actually really complicated.
Speaker 4:  And multi-user technology is like a thing we actually really have not solved
Speaker 4:  yet. So whatever, we can talk about that later. But the simple thing is like,
Speaker 4:  just make it easier for me to watch things on my TV and
Speaker 4:  everybody knows how that would work. And there's been just enough players
Speaker 4:  who have refused that it's been easier for everybody else to refuse and it
Speaker 4:  has just collapsed. Like it's not unclear what Apple would like to do. It
Speaker 4:  just can't do it.
Speaker 1:  You know, it's gonna fix this, you know
Speaker 4:  It's gonna fix You say Plex, I'm gonna, I'm gonna leave. No, I'm going back
Speaker 4:  on parental leave. If you say Plex
Speaker 1:  ATSC 3.00
Speaker 4:  God,
Speaker 3:  Yeah, that's
Speaker 4:  Even
Speaker 3:  Worse. Nothing like 600 ultra complex channels of
Speaker 3:  infomercials beamed directly to you from your local CBS affiliate
Speaker 1:  In 4k. In
Speaker 4:  We're like one scissor vodka joke away from me filling my V Bingo
Speaker 4:  card on my first day back. This is very
Speaker 3:  Exciting. It's gonna be great. All right. That's streaming. Streaming music,
Speaker 3:  streaming tv, the business models, the money is preventing
Speaker 3:  good user experiences, I think is what we're, yep. What we're getting at
Speaker 3:  here, this brings me to Twitter we're the money is preventing a good user
Speaker 3:  experience in a different way in that all of the people have been
Speaker 3:  fired and so the site keeps crashing. I don't know if there's much more to
Speaker 3:  say, but there's just a lot going on with Twitter, but it's all kind of the
Speaker 3:  same story, which is Elon fired everybody and now all the people
Speaker 3:  who know what they're doing Yep. Are gone. And so
Speaker 3:  Zoe and Casey at Australian platform are, it's on the site
Speaker 3:  basically. They tried to make an API change, brought down the whole site
Speaker 3:  for a several hours
Speaker 1:  Because it was just one guy or one person, there was just one engineer on
Speaker 1:  the project and they broke it and we're like, whoop.
Speaker 3:  And Elon did some tweets about how everything is brittle. That resulted in
Speaker 3:  a lot of software. People being like, the reality of all software is that
Speaker 3:  it's brittle and it, the solution to that is knowing people, knowing what
Speaker 3:  they're doing.
Speaker 4:  I was interviewing somebody a couple of years ago for a, a totally unrelated
Speaker 4:  story and they like paused me at the end of our interview. I did the, like,
Speaker 4:  is there anything I should have asked you? Like what else are you thinking
Speaker 4:  about? Question, which is a good one for reporters to do. And he like looks
Speaker 4:  at me dead in the face and he goes, you need to report on tech debt more
Speaker 4:  because tech debt is the underlying most important story
Speaker 4:  of why everything is broken all the time. Yeah. And like my response was,
Speaker 4:  I, I'm sure you're right. That is a just staggeringly boring story,
Speaker 4:  but this is that, right? Like it's, it's just this, this service has been
Speaker 4:  around for almost 20 years. There is tech debt everywhere
Speaker 4:  and that just is what it is. You can't rewrite the thing from scratch, which
Speaker 4:  is now what Elon is promising to do, which I find deeply hilarious.
Speaker 3:  He also promised to open source the algorithm. He also promised creator,
Speaker 4:  I said promising. This is my point, this that's just as likely as rereading
Speaker 4:  the Twitter code from scratch. Right? Like you just, you can't do it. And
Speaker 4:  this is why at some point you have to employ people who know what they're
Speaker 4:  doing in order to keep making the service that you make work.
Speaker 5:  That's one approach. But Netflix got a lot of mileage a few years ago because
Speaker 5:  they had this technology they called Chaos Monkey where it would test the
Speaker 5:  resilience of their platform. Cause it would go around and like shut stuff,
Speaker 5:  shut stuff off at random and see if it still worked. And that was supposedly
Speaker 5:  how Netflix would keep working mostly everywhere all the time. And now Twitter
Speaker 5:  has a chaos monkey. Yeah. Named Elon Musk. And
Speaker 5:  he is stress testing the app. And when we get through this, it'll be
Speaker 5:  fine. Eventually they'll find every single hole.
Speaker 5:  It's just gonna take probably the rest of our lives.
Speaker 1:  If all the people he fired don't sue it into oblivion.
Speaker 4:  Richard, you've changed since I left
Speaker 3:  Big crypto, crypto, big Elon guy. So there's one piece of the
Speaker 3:  Twitter story we should talk about on the show. We did not write about it
Speaker 3:  on the site cuz the story is so weird and so many of
Speaker 3:  the details are actually quite hard to confirm and have not been confirmed.
Speaker 3:  So say what the story is first and then just talk about why we didn't do,
Speaker 3:  because it's unpleasant.
Speaker 1:  It's just too,
Speaker 3:  So there's a Twitter designer named Harold
Speaker 3:  Dur. Thorleif goes by Holly on Twitter, Holly tweets,
Speaker 3:  Elon, Hey, my laptop got shut off several days ago. I don't know if I'm fired.
Speaker 3:  Am I fired? No one will respond to be Maybe if we tweeted Elon enough. Elon
Speaker 3:  is just incredibly rude. Yeah's, no way to put it.
Speaker 3:  He's just rude. He's like, what?
Speaker 1:  He responds with like, what do you do here? Just tell me right away. Like
Speaker 1:  without any, any kind of politeness, any, let's take this to dms. Let's,
Speaker 1:  let's email this out. He's just like, what do you do here? And then the guy
Speaker 1:  is like, well I can't tell you because that'll break my confidentiality agreement.
Speaker 1:  And
Speaker 3:  Which by the way, watching this as a distance Yeah. You're like, that's oh
Speaker 3:  that's trap.
Speaker 1:  And and and Elon is like, fine, break it. Tell me everything.
Speaker 1:  And so the guy tells him some stuff. Elon laughs at him because he is like,
Speaker 1:  I worked on like a Figma project,
Speaker 3:  Right? He's, he's like, one of the things he did was he negotiated a price
Speaker 3:  of a software as a service product down by 500 K. And he is like, which thing?
Speaker 3:  And he is like, Figma. And I don't think Elon knew what Figma was.
Speaker 1:  Elon just laughed because presumably he didn't know what it was and
Speaker 1:  didn't realize that it's like hugely important for software designers to
Speaker 1:  figure out what this software's gonna actually look like. So he just kind
Speaker 1:  of roasts the guy and then he continues to roast the guy the next
Speaker 1:  day to other people who are like, Elon, you're being kind of a dick. And
Speaker 1:  Elon's like, yeah, but the guy didn't even do anything here. He said he had
Speaker 1:  some sort of like issues so he couldn't even type. So what's even the point
Speaker 1:  of this guy? And it's like, well, oh, because Halle was, is
Speaker 1:  actually like a pretty noted disability activist in Iceland who's building
Speaker 1:  a bunch of wheelchair ramps and had also like
Speaker 1:  then explained in a Twitter thread how he had muscular dystrophy, how he
Speaker 1:  had a wife and he slept in a big bed with, with his wife. Unlike Elon,
Speaker 1:  how he saw his children every day unlike Elon. And just
Speaker 1:  like brutal,
Speaker 3:  Just
Speaker 1:  Brutally goes after Elon while explaining like how every single
Speaker 1:  way that Elon is wrong. And then Elon apparently realized
Speaker 1:  that he had fired someone for disability reasons and then tweeted that
Speaker 1:  he had fired someone for disabilities and that's a good way to lose
Speaker 1:  your company or at least a lot of money. And then said,
Speaker 1:  okay, we're gonna work it all out on the back end. And then there was also
Speaker 1:  this whole thing where a lot of people were saying, well, Halle was actually
Speaker 1:  would be owed a hundred million if he was fired.
Speaker 1:  But that's really difficult to confirm. So there's just a lot
Speaker 1:  like it was just a messy, messy HR dispute
Speaker 1:  happening in real time on Twitter and we all had
Speaker 1:  to watch it and that was just kind of gross.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it was gross. So Elon tweets, he did know actual
Speaker 3:  work. He claimed as an excuse. He had a disability that prevented him from
Speaker 3:  typing. There's a response where he is like muscular dystrophy. I will say
Speaker 3:  that the sort of like Elon take ecosystem went
Speaker 3:  bananas around all of this. And the world of people who were
Speaker 3:  like, he got him, he set a trap now he owes him the money, he got fired.
Speaker 3:  First of all, the guy's in Iceland, we don't know what
Speaker 3:  law his contract is under. We just dunno how he is employed. So we don't
Speaker 3:  even know what law controls here. Two, there is this thing with a hundred
Speaker 3:  million dollars is a founder. There's a lot of
Speaker 3:  reporting that we have that Alex Heath has that Casey and Zoe have at Platformer.
Speaker 3:  That when Twitter acquired founders, they're shares vested
Speaker 3:  faster. They were owed more money. So they had had founders on
Speaker 3:  do not fire lists because it would cost them so much money to fi to fire
Speaker 3:  them on these accelerated investing schedules. But we don't know how that
Speaker 3:  applies to this guy. Then this guy's also Iceland's man of
Speaker 3:  the year. It's a real thing because of his work as a
Speaker 3:  disability activist building the ramps. But most importantly, he did not
Speaker 3:  sell his company for stock. He very famously sold it
Speaker 3:  for cash. So he would pay more taxes because he credits
Speaker 3:  Iceland's social services for allowing him to live, work and thrive with
Speaker 3:  his disability. That's like the wrong person to fight. Yes. And
Speaker 1:  To fight publicly on Twitter.
Speaker 3:  What I'm just getting at is the, the story
Speaker 3:  right, that he got baited Elon would owe him a hundred million dollars.
Speaker 3:  We actually can't confirm like 50 of the
Speaker 3:  dots in between. Boy, that was a real
Speaker 3:  jerk interaction and Elon publicly apologized and
Speaker 3:  said he'd FaceTimed the guy or the head of video call and everything is
Speaker 3:  resolved. The guy's considering saying right and no one's talking. So I just
Speaker 3:  like, I just wanna say this is like kind of why we A, it was gross. It seemed
Speaker 3:  petty and gross and small and sort of, it's just more of the same, right?
Speaker 3:  It's just like Elon's playing the hits of like doing his business like a
Speaker 3:  jerk on Twitter and then b in the middle is just like a
Speaker 3:  what feels like an unconfirmed, unconfirmed
Speaker 3:  story that to do it responsibly have to report out. And I think
Speaker 3:  that's just really telling. Like I think the Twitter story is still really
Speaker 3:  important. I think what happens to this social network that is the architecture
Speaker 3:  of lots of things, like this whole podcast is about Aaron Rods in the New York
Speaker 3:  chats right now, I'm just telling you like, it's on the back of my mind every
Speaker 3:  second of every day. And it's all just playing out on Twitter, right? It's
Speaker 3:  just like the architecture of sports media is still on Twitter. The architecture
Speaker 3:  of politics is still on Twitter. So what happens Twitter is important. It
Speaker 3:  just, right now every day is like these little explosions
Speaker 3:  of chaos that kind of don't mean as much as they should mean
Speaker 3:  or don't mean as much as people want them to me. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  My relationship with Twitter has changed so much the last few months. Like
Speaker 4:  I, I just bailed on Twitter and I have to say I have been shocked by
Speaker 4:  how little I have missed, like the, the thing that felt truist to
Speaker 4:  me of everything that happened the last few months was that thing where Elon
Speaker 4:  forced the engineers to juice his own metrics because it
Speaker 4:  just, everywhere, every time I would open it up, my mentions were filled
Speaker 4:  with people tagging me in crypto scams and my timeline was just
Speaker 4:  Elon replying to people. And it's just like, what is this place now? And
Speaker 4:  I think there's a great piece on our site this week called How a Social Network
Speaker 4:  Falls Apart. That really rang true to me that way. Or was just like, the
Speaker 4:  place just feels worse now. Like forget the fact that it keeps
Speaker 4:  collapsing because nobody works there anymore and like it
Speaker 4:  is just not being run in a competent way as far as anybody can tell. It
Speaker 4:  just, it just feels bad to me. But it, there is still that thing where I
Speaker 4:  think people don't know where else to go and it's like Mastodon is not that
Speaker 4:  thing, at least not yet. And there's nowhere else. So it's like if you, if
Speaker 4:  you are one of those people who wants to know what's going on with
Speaker 4:  Aaron Rodgers and the Jets, a person of, of which I am not one,
Speaker 4:  but if, if you are one of those people, there's, there's just still nowhere
Speaker 4:  else to go. And that's one of the things that is the most surprising to me
Speaker 4:  is that it, it people feel stuck, I think in a realer way
Speaker 4:  every single day.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But it's also like, no, there's a guy who
Speaker 3:  followed the Jets plane to California and then he like went
Speaker 3:  to the airport and like watched the Yeah. Twitter stuff. You know what
Speaker 3:  I'm talking about? It's like someone found the plane, they went and saw the
Speaker 3:  plane, they saw Aaron Rogers walking the plane. Yep. The only place that
Speaker 3:  happens is Twitter. Like there's no replacement for that specifically. Maybe
Speaker 3:  it'll happen a little bit on Reddit, four chan, but the
Speaker 3:  four chan, if sports media moves to four chan,
Speaker 3:  that will be wild. Get ready. But I, I just think like the
Speaker 3:  stuff in the background of Twitter is like, the experiment is how much can
Speaker 3:  you break it? How much can you make people feel bad and they still have to
Speaker 3:  use it. And that's always what Twitter, what Elon that's always the Elon
Speaker 3:  has a banking on right? Is people are addicted to Twitter and he can do anything
Speaker 3:  cuz the guy who's the most addicted to cigarettes bought the cigarette factory.
Speaker 3:  And we're just gonna see how it goes.
Speaker 5:  Well something that I've noticed is that people complain about Twitter and
Speaker 5:  we, we talk about Elon and his strategies and how, how he's working, but
Speaker 5:  he has been effective in one kind of particular way that I've noticed They
Speaker 5:  defaulted everyone to the the four u page to the algorithmic timeline. They
Speaker 5:  have both timelines. People use the algorithmic timeline a lot and
Speaker 5:  that is part of the reason why so many people saw, for example, this story
Speaker 5:  playing out. Because if you are on that one and you follow anyone involved
Speaker 5:  or anyone who is talking about it, it's going to be at the top of your feed.
Speaker 5:  And at least so far that bet has not been a, an incorrect
Speaker 5:  one for Elon in, for Twitter to put to kind of algorithmically juice
Speaker 5:  discontent and unhappiness, whatever, whatever that
Speaker 5:  does for people. I don't know. Yeah. But it has kept their attention and
Speaker 5:  something that, you know, if you're gonna remain on Twitter, I just, I I
Speaker 5:  beg people please don't use the algorithmic timeline. Turn off replies
Speaker 5:  from people who don't follow you. You don't need to see what they say and
Speaker 5:  turn off notifications for likes. You don't need to know whether or not people
Speaker 5:  agree with you.
Speaker 3:  That's true. Turn off most of the features of Twitter is good advice from
Speaker 3:  Richard. Also, if you see a bank run it at it as fast
Speaker 5:  As you can. What could go wrong?
Speaker 3:  Just dead Sprint. Do you know how 17 I drove a Mustang into the bank? That's
Speaker 3:  a real story. We're gonna take a break. We'll be right back.
Speaker 5:  Was it during a podcast?
Speaker 3:  We'll be right back. We got some policy stuff to talk about. It was
Speaker 3:  not during, that was a, technically if you drive a Mustang into a bank in
Speaker 3:  the nineties, that's a video podcast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back a little bit of policy news and we gotta talk about
Speaker 3:  this dish story, which is criminally undercover. And we got some gadgets
Speaker 3:  to close this
Speaker 4:  Out. And weird, weird.
Speaker 3:  It's weird, it's real weird. Policy news. Congress
Speaker 3:  rolled out a bill that would allow the White House to ban TikTok
Speaker 3:  across the nation. Gotta say, it feels like the TikTok
Speaker 3:  ban is coming, right? Like yeah, everybody on both sides is like, what
Speaker 3:  if we get rid of TikTok and states across the country have
Speaker 3:  banned it in for their government devices. The federal government has banned
Speaker 3:  it for government devices. It's gotten weird out there and TikTok has done
Speaker 3:  approximately nothing to solve this problem from what I can tell.
Speaker 1:  Because they know they have teens. They know they have like a, an army
Speaker 1:  of teens for when this band goes down that they can just
Speaker 1:  point at the problem.
Speaker 4:  I mean, Eli, can I interest you in Project Texas, which I think if I
Speaker 4:  understand correctly, is a room where a person says TikTok is
Speaker 4:  great, trust us.
Speaker 3:  So they do have that project Texas, which the CEO of TikTok has talked about,
Speaker 3:  which TikTok has talked about. They have transparency centers.
Speaker 3:  Alex Heath went to one. The transparency centers are like
Speaker 3:  giant touchscreens where you can pretend to be a TikTok moderator.
Speaker 3:  It's very much like a children's museum for content moderation. I dunno how
Speaker 3:  else to describe it. Yes.
Speaker 4:  That's all I can think of. Anytime I hear somebody talk about, it's like
Speaker 4:  going to the museum and you touch it and it's like that's what gravity is.
Speaker 4:  This time it's content moderation.
Speaker 3:  It's like, like there's a part of me that's like, that's good. Like more
Speaker 3:  people should understand like how this works and how hard it is. On the other
Speaker 3:  hand, you're like, this is your answer to the government being like, yeah,
Speaker 3:  China is a threat, is a science museum for content moderation.
Speaker 3:  However, in that, in the transparency centers, there is a room full of
Speaker 3:  servers that Alex and Casey and Taylor, Laurens and everybody else who wanted
Speaker 3:  to, where these things were not allowed to go in were Oracle employees. You
Speaker 3:  remember Oracle is tied up in this, in some Byzantine way, are allowed to
Speaker 3:  review talk's, code, see all the data they're they're using
Speaker 3:  cuz they're in control of it. And then this is the one that I thought was
Speaker 3:  the funniest piece of this. All Oracle will submit the app
Speaker 3:  to Apple in the app store, which will solve all the problems.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. You just need some American capitalists
Speaker 1:  inserted into things and it's fine.
Speaker 3:  Well it's like you guys, you know the app on the phone like sends the data
Speaker 3:  to China. Yeah. It doesn't, it doesn't matter who delivers the
Speaker 3:  floppy to to the spaceship.
Speaker 3:  Problem is the, the network, you know, the internet.
Speaker 3:  It, it's a network that is interconnected. It's just like a very
Speaker 3:  funny piece of that whole puzzle. It's like, what if Oracle was in charge
Speaker 3:  of this app? It's like, yeah, what if the app was totally disconnected from
Speaker 3:  the Chinese government? I'm like, huh, that's challenging. So that's all
Speaker 3:  happening and like Texa is making a big show of it. We're covering it
Speaker 3:  obviously, but this act, the strict act is bipartisan
Speaker 3:  and it would allow the Secretary of Commerce to ban foreign technologies
Speaker 3:  and companies from operating the us They present a threat to national security.
Speaker 3:  So this whole thing, all these companies reacting to TikTok,
Speaker 3:  there might just be like a hole at the center of their strategy. Like you
Speaker 3:  wake up and you're like, what do we do now?
Speaker 4:  I mean, I do wonder if part of the bet from a
Speaker 4:  lot of these companies is that eventually TikTok is going to either be,
Speaker 4:  you know, hamstrung and sold or outright band and all of a
Speaker 4:  sudden there's gonna be this massive gold rush of trying
Speaker 4:  to be the next talkies thing for users in the
Speaker 4:  United States. And they're all just sitting there waiting for this moment
Speaker 4:  to happen. Which I i the part of this that's so strange to me is that
Speaker 4:  every individual move against this seems not
Speaker 4:  like specious, but it's it's also sort of theoretical, right? It's like,
Speaker 4:  it's very hard to prove that TikTok is being
Speaker 4:  nefarious in some way. You, you can talk about what the
Speaker 4:  Chinese government has access to. You can talk about the way the algorithms
Speaker 4:  are being tuned. There, there are all these things that sort of seem
Speaker 4:  sketchy but have proven very hard to prove. And then so you get all
Speaker 4:  these bills that say things like, we can do it if we want to,
Speaker 4:  if we're able to, but only if it's allowed. And they're like, wait, what?
Speaker 4:  And it just, we, we seem to just be sort of like circling this over and over,
Speaker 4:  but it, it does seem like we've gotten to a point where there's enough smoke
Speaker 4:  on this that it feels like there's gonna be fire.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Or at least the attempt, right? Because they gotta prove that it's
Speaker 3:  a threat to national security. And TikTok has done all this project Texas
Speaker 3:  stuff, but it's out there. It's, it's in the background in a very serious
Speaker 3:  way that governments around the country are, you get to posture
Speaker 3:  against China for free. Yep. And you get to say that you're doing it for
Speaker 3:  the kids. Everyone's very worried about the teens at all times. Think of
Speaker 3:  the children. So that's one, two Wait, wait.
Speaker 4:  Move on. Can I just, can I just say one thing like, I just wanna give Congress
Speaker 4:  a lot of credit for the, the, the acronyms in these
Speaker 4:  names where like clearly somebody's like, we wanna call this the restrict
Speaker 4:  act but it has to stand for something. So the RESTRICT ACT stands for the
Speaker 4:  restricting the emergence of security threats that Risk Information and Communications
Speaker 4:  Technology Act or the Restrict Act. Yes. And I just think that's wonderful.
Speaker 4:  Congratulations to
Speaker 3:  Mark Warner and the rest that's a C, that's a b plus.
Speaker 3:  It best starting the restrict act with the word restrict completely ridiculous.
Speaker 3:  Like you just immediately lose points.
Speaker 4:  That's fair. That's fair. Can I interest you in the Data act? The
Speaker 4:  Deterring America's Technological Adversaries Act.
Speaker 3:  Alright, speaking of Congress, we'll we'll have more on
Speaker 3:  this very soon, but obviously we pay a lot of attention to the FCC
Speaker 3:  here because theoretically the FCC regulates the nation's
Speaker 3:  telecom providers. No one's doing a good job. Particularly the
Speaker 3:  Biden FCC has been deadlocked at two, two for a long time. Two
Speaker 3:  Republicans, two Democrats, they've accomplished nothing.
Speaker 3:  Just flat out nothing. The Trump FCC accomplished a lot. Most
Speaker 3:  of it was destructive, but they accomplished a lot. They're like, let's get
Speaker 3:  rid of net neutrality. Did it? What if the government
Speaker 3:  was run by Verizon? Like, did it? That's fine. Biden,
Speaker 3:  fcc, Biden campaigns and all this stuff. They've accomplished nothing because
Speaker 3:  they've been deadlocked at two, two for 16 months.
Speaker 3:  The fifth commissioner has been waiting on, her name is Gigi soon Gigi
Speaker 3:  has been on the Verge House. She's a character on the Verge. She's like this
Speaker 3:  ferocious consumer advocate. She was on the Board of Public Knowledge, the
Speaker 3:  First Amendment organization. She's been sitting there for
Speaker 3:  16 months. No, she's been nominated twice over it
Speaker 3:  expired both times. She's gone to committee twice. There's been hearings.
Speaker 3:  We did an entire decoder episode about this bizarre mystery
Speaker 3:  where they cannot get her confirmation over the finish line. And the
Speaker 3:  answer is, Comcast at and t Verizon
Speaker 3:  furiously spending money to keep the Biden FCC deadlocked.
Speaker 3:  And in particular from keeping a true consumer advocate on there. This is
Speaker 3:  the point of the show where we missed actually disclosures earlier. I
Speaker 3:  should note Comcast is a minority investor in Vox Media or parent
Speaker 3:  company. You might tell from the tone of my voice. That's cool. How do you
Speaker 3:  feel about that? That's fine. It's, it's, there's no
Speaker 3:  love loss there. They're fine. They're all very cool. We also made a Netflix
Speaker 3:  show. We made a Netflix, Netflix show. Netflix show. I, it's called The Future
Speaker 3:  of That's great. You should go watch it on your Comcast internet connection,
Speaker 3:  your overpriced Comcast Internet Connection
Speaker 3:  disclosures. We have some. Gigi quit this
Speaker 3:  week. She withdrew. She's like, couldn't take it. Couldn't take the attacks.
Speaker 3:  McKenna Kelly is reporting on all this. We'll have a lot more on it. But
Speaker 3:  I just wanna point out this is like a policy disaster.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. That is squarely Biden's fault. Like he did not push
Speaker 3:  to have a functional telecom regulator in this country as you, I mean
Speaker 3:  this is just me doing greatest hits now. Americans pay the highest prices
Speaker 3:  for the slowest speeds in the entire world. If you go to Europe,
Speaker 3:  you can get unlimited data send card that works anywhere in Europe
Speaker 3:  for like, I dunno nothing. $2
Speaker 3:  here. It's massive amounts of money and getting more expensive.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna come to Dish Network. Our government approved the merger of
Speaker 3:  T-Mobile and Sprint reducing the amount of competitors in the market
Speaker 3:  and said Dish, they would stand up Dish Network as a fourth competitor.
Speaker 3:  Dish Network has been down for two weeks. Like
Speaker 3:  the whole fucking company had a cyber attack. People couldn't pay
Speaker 3:  their bills. Customer service agents couldn't even respond to people. Installers
Speaker 3:  weren't getting scheduled. Zero coverage except for us.
Speaker 3:  Like just crazy. Like the amount of competition we've reduced and the
Speaker 3:  amount that we've allowed prices to rise. Cuz we do not have a functional
Speaker 3:  telecom regulator in this country. And this, this failure to nominate Gigi
Speaker 3:  is like just a stark reminder that actually,
Speaker 3:  like we talk a lot about tech company corruption and like big tech, it's
Speaker 3:  the telecoms. Like they still own massive chunks of
Speaker 3:  political power and they wield it with absolute like
Speaker 3:  nightmare like efficiency to make sure they get what they want and keep the
Speaker 3:  monopolies in place. It's, I'm furious about it, as you can
Speaker 4:  Probably tell. And Gigi's own really, really, really did not mince words
Speaker 4:  to that effect. Like, I, I just keep reading this quote that she said over
Speaker 4:  and over, which is in our story. She says, it is a sad day for our country
Speaker 4:  and our democracy when dominant industries with assistance from unlimited
Speaker 4:  dark money get to choose their regulators. And with the help of friends in
Speaker 4:  the Senate, the powerful cable and media companies have done just that. It's
Speaker 4:  like, yeah, there it is. Folks like, it's, it's pretty much that simple.
Speaker 1:  It was the most open and shut should have been approved
Speaker 1:  immediately. And instead there was a lot of conversation about how
Speaker 1:  she hated Republicans and that she was gonna take Newsmax and
Speaker 1:  what was it, one America off the air. Even though she wouldn't have
Speaker 1:  had that power, there was a lot of just huge misinformation about her Ted
Speaker 1:  Cruz popping champagne at at her loss. Even though
Speaker 1:  all of his constituents are absolutely destroyed by the
Speaker 1:  terrible broadband in this country and all they want is better broadband.
Speaker 1:  And he's like, yeah, fuck you. Broadband and joy. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And he and his claim is like, he's like a, because she has like previously
Speaker 3:  criticized Fox News
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That she would like do something to free speech. Meanwhile,
Speaker 1:  When, when she had zero control, when,
Speaker 3:  And also like I didn't pay attention to Fox News News lately.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Good entertainment channel.
Speaker 3:  But meanwhile, right, there's no net neutrality in this country. And so
Speaker 3:  things are starting to happen that are really weird. Like state
Speaker 3:  senators in Texas proposing bills to force ISPs
Speaker 3:  to block websites with abortion information on them. Yep. And to
Speaker 3:  make it so that hosting providers in Texas cannot host any
Speaker 3:  website that has abortion information on it. Like I, that's straight
Speaker 3:  up, like fully in the realm of our
Speaker 3:  telecom policy is now allowing
Speaker 3:  infringements on free speech. Like the basics
Speaker 3:  of net neutrality. Even if you go to the big, even if you go to Comcast,
Speaker 3:  I've talked to Comcast about this, right? They're like, yeah, we think no
Speaker 3:  blocking, no locking, that's what I always call it. Right? No blocking of
Speaker 3:  websites, no blocking of devices from the network. Everyone agrees
Speaker 3:  on this. If you write a net neutrality bill and you're like, all right, we're
Speaker 3:  gonna start with no blocking, no locking, no one come jumps
Speaker 3:  out and says, do do this. Like, maybe the exceptions are we'll block devices
Speaker 3:  that are malicious. And everyone's like, yeah, sure, that makes sense. But
Speaker 3:  the basics are like, don't, you can't block websites, you can't block content
Speaker 3:  and you can't block devices. And they, they've been saying this for over
Speaker 3:  a decade that we've been covering this and you get rid of it in just a
Speaker 3:  few years after you get rid of it. You have state senators in Texas saying,
Speaker 3:  actually we got rid of Dobbs too. Now you should block websites to abortion
Speaker 3:  information. But if you're a house, listen, I don't care where you're on
Speaker 3:  the political spectrum, that is just straight up an attack on the first amendment
Speaker 3:  and an attack on how we think the internet should work. Like maybe you think
Speaker 3:  people should get abortions. The idea that you can block the information
Speaker 3:  or block hosting providers from even having the websites like fully outta
Speaker 3:  bounds. And that's what you get without like functional telecom policy anyway.
Speaker 3:  It's outrageous. McKenna's gonna have more on it. There's
Speaker 3:  a lot to this story. It's a, it's a long weaving tale. Like as,
Speaker 3:  as David said, of dark money and corruption. Go listen to the
Speaker 3:  decoder episode about it. One thing I'll note, so little competition,
Speaker 3:  the star of that decoder episode was the CEO of newsmax,
Speaker 3:  which is Chris Roddy is not a liberal by anyone's conception.
Speaker 3:  And he was like, I want Gigi sound on the FCC because she
Speaker 3:  is a fighter for competition. And what I need to do is compete. That's a
Speaker 3:  big deal. So go listen to that episode coder in the next week we'll have
Speaker 3:  more for
Speaker 4:  McKenna. But wait, can I ask a really dumb question before we move on from
Speaker 4:  this subject? What happens now? Like, does the Biden administration have
Speaker 4:  to nominate somebody else? Is it they nominate two two forever? Like what
Speaker 4:  happens now? They'll,
Speaker 1:  They'll nominate somebody else and they probably will not be
Speaker 1:  as like a, as good an advocate for consumers.
Speaker 1:  It'll probably be someone much more palatable to the telecoms because yeah,
Speaker 1:  that's the only way they're
Speaker 3:  Pass through lawyer from Verizon is
Speaker 4:  A cheap PI coming back. Be honest, that
Speaker 3:  Gonna happen. Be someone like that. It'll be someone who's a little more
Speaker 3:  liberal but it's like a democrat who works for at and t
Speaker 3:  like the former general counsel of charter communication. Like
Speaker 3:  that's what we've had for years and that's what which we're gonna get again.
Speaker 3:  And so it, I would just not like when,
Speaker 3:  what's
Speaker 4:  John Ledger doing these days? He could do it.
Speaker 3:  Put him an example of the Biden administration's confidence in fcc,
Speaker 3:  right? They, they did all that rural broadband stuff and
Speaker 3:  they did not do it through the fcc, they did it through other agencies cuz
Speaker 3:  they just don't trust the FCC to be effective. It's maybe, maybe you should
Speaker 3:  shut it down. Like maybe you wanna go full libertarian and be like, my three
Speaker 3:  part plan for America is like to shut this down cuz it's a disaster. Fine.
Speaker 3:  I'm not gonna disagree with you at this moment in time. You gotta replace
Speaker 3:  it with something with some effective oversight of
Speaker 3:  the telecoms, not of the content. Right. I don't think that we should have
Speaker 3:  government speech regulations. I think everybody knows that. I'm saying
Speaker 3:  literally at and t, Verizon, T-Mobile, Comcast, all of 'em
Speaker 3:  are little monopolies. Their markets are not competitive and they do
Speaker 3:  weird shit and raise prices all the time. And that's like, you can't even
Speaker 3:  argue with that. Do we think that ISPs in this country
Speaker 3:  are like great and that people love them? No. Does no one does.
Speaker 3:  0% of the people believe that
Speaker 4:  Long pause.
Speaker 1:  Two members of the s c do. Yeah. They think it's going great.
Speaker 3:  It's going great. The one ISP people love is starlink. Although in
Speaker 3:  the starline credit yesterday I saw someone who said, Hey,
Speaker 3:  I was at the mall the other day and T-Mobile home internet is available
Speaker 3:  in my area and I switched to 5g home internet over
Speaker 3:  Starling.
Speaker 4:  Wow.
Speaker 3:  And ever in the go read the thread. People are like, I do it too.
Speaker 3:  Who
Speaker 4:  Big win for 5g.
Speaker 3:  It's the, the only win for 5g. 5G sister. Okay. Speaking of
Speaker 3:  5g, I mentioned this thing about Dish Network. This is super weird. It's
Speaker 3:  super weird. So Dish is a big company, right? They run Dish, they run the,
Speaker 3:  the satellite television service. They run Boost Mobile that
Speaker 3:  they picked up. They run Project Genisis, their
Speaker 3:  ultra-competitive 5G network for this. Just everybody's striking fears in
Speaker 3:  the heart. Hans Berg CEO Verizon wakes up
Speaker 3:  cold sweat in the middle of night. He's like, project Genisis, where are
Speaker 3:  we
Speaker 4:  On this? Do they still have just the one phone? I know I was out for a while.
Speaker 4:  Is it still just the one phone? They've
Speaker 3:  Been known updates. Okay, cool. They've got the one phone, they got the one
Speaker 3:  tower in Portland. They're doing great.
Speaker 1:  Mitchell is the only subscriber.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. This is the day of their earnings call. This happened several weeks
Speaker 3:  ago and we covered it. We got a tip from an installer just
Speaker 3:  to our general tips line. Hey, like our systems have been down for hours
Speaker 3:  and we think it's a cyber attack. That same day they had an earnings call
Speaker 3:  where they said, this is not a cyber attack. We'll we'll have it
Speaker 3:  back up shortly. Like days went by Richard. I think it was like two
Speaker 3:  full days before any other updates. People couldn't log in and pay their
Speaker 3:  bills on the Boost Mobile website. The dish network.com website
Speaker 3:  was just a weird sorry, message that was it just like
Speaker 3:  a box that said we're sorry we're down. Like you couldn't pay your Boost
Speaker 3:  mobile bill, you couldn't sign up. People's deliveries or service appointments
Speaker 3:  were canceled. There was no coverage of this except for us,
Speaker 3:  basically in a handful of trade publications.
Speaker 5:  And they finally put out a statement eventually saying that there was a cybersecurity
Speaker 5:  incident. They, they still haven't really said what, what is going on?
Speaker 5:  I think the last time this was updated was on March 7th. Where are, where
Speaker 5:  are they now? What have they fixed? What is resolved? This is
Speaker 5:  just kind of nowhere.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. On the third they said they're making progress. Oh,
Speaker 3:  first of all, this is a mystery. We should get to the bottom of it. Second
Speaker 3:  of all, it's wild that this is happening to a major tele,
Speaker 3:  like a telecom company is going through this. There's almost no coverage
Speaker 3:  of it anywhere. And then three, this is the company
Speaker 3:  that's supposed to provide competition in the broadband market.
Speaker 3:  Like
Speaker 3:  Dreams Jeep Pie. Like you're like, there will be four competitors.
Speaker 3:  Dish Network is gonna do it. They can't, they can't even
Speaker 3:  reboot the pc.
Speaker 4:  There is something deeply hilarious to me about the Dish
Speaker 4:  website right now, like dish.com, which at least in my experience so far
Speaker 4:  doesn't always load but does sometimes load. There are, there are
Speaker 4:  three sort of buckets that you can see at the top three parts of the
Speaker 4:  website. The first one says, thank you for your patience. It says, you know,
Speaker 4:  we're we're experiencing a system issue that's been there for what, two
Speaker 4:  weeks now. The second one is customer support. That's good. And
Speaker 4:  the third one is a is a big banner that says Get inflation free
Speaker 4:  TV with Dish. The same price every month for three years.
Speaker 4:  And I just, it's like, it's a super bold move to be like, come pay
Speaker 4:  us for tv. You can't have, but we will not raise the price on the TV
Speaker 4:  that you're not allowed to have and we will never install for you. And
Speaker 14:  We will charge you immediately.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna be, it's only $80 a month for
Speaker 4:  TV that we will never install at your house because of a cybersecurity incident.
Speaker 4:  Welcome to Dish. I
Speaker 3:  Will say Dish is not paying a very big Figma bill looking at this website.
Speaker 3:  That's that's not a cost that they're carrying. Yeah. No one needs
Speaker 3:  to reduce that bill because that bill is currently $0. Everybody,
Speaker 3:  this is a Squarespace template.
Speaker 3:  It's weird. We'll see if it comes back up, but it's just, I want to clock
Speaker 3:  cause it's so weird that no one's talking about it. All right, let's close
Speaker 3:  with the lightning round. I think this is very funny. I think the Bing number
Speaker 3:  is very funny. David, do you wanna talk about the Bing number?
Speaker 4:  Sure. So Bing, which is now probably more in
Speaker 4:  the news over the last two months than ever accumulated in the history of
Speaker 4:  Bing. Would you say that's fair to say? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  This is the most bing that has ever been bung. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  We, we, we have binged bonged, we have binged debunked
Speaker 4:  so hard
Speaker 3:  For
Speaker 4:  Weeks and Microsoft very proudly announced that it
Speaker 4:  now has a hundred million active daily users. Which
Speaker 4:  on the one hand, so Microsoft's credit is not a small number. Like a hundred
Speaker 4:  million people using your search engine every day. Big number, very exciting.
Speaker 4:  I think Google is is substantially over 10 times
Speaker 4:  that size. Yeah. And, and again, let's not forget, this is not
Speaker 4:  like the number of people who are gonna use this forever. This is like being
Speaker 4:  at its absolute buzzies in the history of the product
Speaker 4:  is somewhere in the range of one-tenth the size of
Speaker 4:  Google, which again, it's a big market as, as
Speaker 4:  Sacha Nella said to you, like, they don't have to beat Google to make an
Speaker 4:  awful lot of money from a search engine. Yeah. But it's just like th this
Speaker 4:  was a stark reminder of just exactly how big
Speaker 4:  Google still is in this space.
Speaker 3:  So their math at the event was for every
Speaker 3:  1% of market share they saw 2 billion for
Speaker 3:  revenue. So they've ticked up to something Now I
Speaker 3:  think that math was based on people using being like a search
Speaker 3:  engine and not
Speaker 4:  Like trying to get it to fall in love with them.
Speaker 3:  Right. Not asking it if it needs condoms, if you get what I'm saying.
Speaker 3:  And like, I don't know if that has played out. Like
Speaker 3:  they had to restrict write the number of queries. They're now back up to
Speaker 3:  10 queries. I think they thought most easier to shut up and be like, how
Speaker 3:  many two by fours fit into a Kia? Which is like their big example.
Speaker 3:  And instead it's like, people be like, do you love me?
Speaker 4:  What does your butt look like? Being
Speaker 14:  Like,
Speaker 3:  Are you afraid of death? And it's like, I don't think that you can monetize
Speaker 3:  that.
Speaker 4:  CPMs
Speaker 3:  A real one. So I'm, I'm wondering if there's like actually a cost curve here
Speaker 3:  where the advertising is being delivered at the rate that
Speaker 3:  Microsoft assumed it would be delivered at. But it is, you're right. Like
Speaker 3:  you only get an edge, Deb, you gotta sign up. There's a wait list. But this
Speaker 3:  is the most Bing that is like our friend John Gruber
Speaker 3:  has a headline on Daring Fireball. It says Microsoft Bing is the most exciting
Speaker 3:  product in tech and it's definitely because people are trying to make out
Speaker 3:  with their
Speaker 4:  Laptops.
Speaker 3:  Yes, yes. Not because it's a better search experience than
Speaker 4:  Google, but that that's worth your whatever, 10 billion investment in open
Speaker 4:  AI right there. Like we Bing has gotten more press
Speaker 4:  and juice than ever before. And like you, it's, it's, I
Speaker 4:  suspect they will happily take that investment over and over and
Speaker 4:  over again. Even if they can never figure out how to make this anything more
Speaker 4:  than a novelty. Which it very much still is.
Speaker 3:  It's, it's a fun novelty. I Oh it's
Speaker 4:  Delightful. It's so fun.
Speaker 3:  Is it? But it man,
Speaker 4:  But it's kind of nothing.
Speaker 3:  I was using one called character ai again talking about, this is always talking
Speaker 3:  about like someone's dream. But the short version of the story is
Speaker 3:  someone's showing me character ai so I click on it character dot a I can
Speaker 3:  go on. It's like you chat with like famous characters and I was like, I'm
Speaker 3:  gonna talk to Mario for Mario 64 within two moves
Speaker 3:  I got Mario from Mario 64 to ask me if I felt lucky
Speaker 3:  Punk. And
Speaker 1:  I was like,
Speaker 3:  Like this is spectacular. Perfect.
Speaker 3:  I dunno what's going on. This is as much fun as you can have with the
Speaker 3:  computer.
Speaker 4:  I love it.
Speaker 3:  None of this makes any sense. None of this is good. This isn't like
Speaker 3:  a quality, I guess I'm talking about it now, but like it's not useful.
Speaker 3:  It's not even like that entertaining cuz it just like, it breaks the same
Speaker 3:  way every time. But I'm sure Sacha somewhere is like,
Speaker 3:  just keep that number going up.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. All this stuff is really terrific.
Speaker 4:  Really expensive marketing and no one quite knows
Speaker 4:  for what yet.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Speaking of Google and search, Google's like freaking
Speaker 3:  out. It's like very obvious. They declared a code red, they're
Speaker 3:  like rolling it out. They had the sort of disastrous bard launch. Who the
Speaker 3:  bard got something wrong. Which we now all realize is basically the, the
Speaker 3:  main thing that these generative AI systems do is they confidently lie
Speaker 4:  To you. Yeah. The thing it got wrong was like very low stakes in
Speaker 3:  What?
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like yeah, but report from Bloomberg. Google wants to
Speaker 3:  put AI in all of its products as soon as possible within
Speaker 3:  months.
Speaker 1:  Wasn't, forgive me, what wasn't AI already in all of Google's
Speaker 1:  products. Isn't that what every Google IO is about is how AI
Speaker 1:  is in all of their stuff and it's doing everything and AI will save
Speaker 5:  The day. Yes. And it so it can erase stuff in the background of your photos,
Speaker 5:  but it's not telling you that it loves you. So it has to
Speaker 3:  Get that. No, they demo that. I, well I think Google's mistake again,
Speaker 3:  they invented the technology. Like we, if you are listening to this in your
Speaker 3:  car right now and you slow down just a little bit, a Google PR
Speaker 3:  person will come running out on the highway to tell you that the T in chat
Speaker 3:  g p t was invented by Google and stands transformer, like just pump the
Speaker 3:  brakes a little bit, just feather 'em a little bit. And like someone is gonna
Speaker 3:  leap out of a bush to be like the T in j b t was invented by Google.
Speaker 3:  Like it's their technology. They they should be saying it a lot. Yeah. But
Speaker 3:  it's like, yeah, you didn't realize the value of this technology. Was
Speaker 3:  the robot sounding nuts anything
Speaker 3:  useful?
Speaker 1:  If only they'd realized,
Speaker 3:  Yeah, like, like the value of this technology is like
Speaker 3:  1000 TikTok hustle culture bros being like, here's how to make
Speaker 3:  money with Chad G P T. And they were like, here's what's gonna happen. Sun's
Speaker 3:  gonna demo having a conversation with a Venus fly trap.
Speaker 3:  And you're like, what are you talking about?
Speaker 1:  Should have been Mario,
Speaker 3:  Should have been Mario just openly threatening me, which
Speaker 3:  is all anybody wants. I kept typing and it asked me to sign
Speaker 3:  up and I told James Vincent like, I wanna sign up just so I see if I can
Speaker 3:  get Mario to explicitly call me a coward. You know, like that's how they
Speaker 3:  get you like 1299 and Mario's be like, you're a coward.
Speaker 3:  I didn't sign up. So you like being nagged by the ai. This is what we're
Speaker 3:  learning a lot about each other. Thanks to chat, chat gpc. Mario was like,
Speaker 3:  jump through this painting and come on an adventure with me. And I was like,
Speaker 3:  I don't wanna jump through the painting. Right? Because like saying no to
Speaker 3:  the AI always makes him very mad. And he is like, come on, it'll be fun.
Speaker 3:  I was like, what's behind the painting? And he is like evil. This is so dumb.
Speaker 3:  Every time talking about this, you just, you sound like you're talking
Speaker 3:  about a dream. This is like Addie's point and like you had this like
Speaker 3:  emotional experience with no stakes that no one cares about ai. Everybody
Speaker 3:  that's the big song. But Mario was there. Mario was there.
Speaker 3:  Can you explain this humane thing to me? It sounds
Speaker 3:  very bad.
Speaker 1:  It sounds like Google clips.
Speaker 3:  Speaking of AI technologies that I nowhere
Speaker 1:  From speaking of AI technology,
Speaker 3:  Did you know the t and chat G B T was invented by?
Speaker 1:  Was it, I had no idea. Now I'm about get a bunch
Speaker 3:  Of, have a brake a little bit. If you're on cruise control right now, just,
Speaker 3:  you know, push, you know, you can push the button in a wheel, take it down
Speaker 3:  from 62 to 59 Google employee, you'll come just
Speaker 1:  Running right next to the car as fast as they can.
Speaker 3:  Those like Google shuttle buses will pull up like hold up paper
Speaker 3:  in the windows. We are the T We are the T. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Humane is the company. It was started by some former Apple people.
Speaker 1:  There's a lot of hype around it. It's gotten a lot of investment,
Speaker 1:  including Sam Altman from Open AI has invested a lot of money in it.
Speaker 1:  They've even talked about their I P O not actually talked about
Speaker 1:  what they make at Hu Humane, which is kind of
Speaker 1:  a problem if you're gonna do things like an I P O and a leak of
Speaker 1:  a from 2021 pitch deck suggests that
Speaker 1:  it's some sort of wearable camera. Yeah. Which
Speaker 1:  I think we've all kind of moved past
Speaker 1:  as a thing anybody really wants.
Speaker 3:  So the the league is a very blurry slide deck that was obviously made for
Speaker 3:  investors. Again, John Gruber had it posted on the website.
Speaker 3:  So this is what we're working off of. There's a, a bunch of patents floating
Speaker 3:  around in the world. Like, let's saw it up. There's an awful lot of hype
Speaker 3:  with this company. Yes. And so some of the patents are like, it'll project
Speaker 3:  a virtual keyboard on any surface. You can like type with your hands, but
Speaker 3:  a lot of them are about, okay, it's gonna record everything and like show
Speaker 3:  you stuff. But like, it's basically the core of it from what we can
Speaker 3:  talk on the stack is a camera that you wear all the time that is constantly
Speaker 3:  recording everything, sending it to a cloud, categorizing it with of course
Speaker 3:  ai, what else? 10,000 monkeys typing furiously.
Speaker 3:  And then you can say things like, show me my daughter's home run from
Speaker 3:  earlier today and it will deliver you that video.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean this is, this is Google clips, it's Snap spectacles,
Speaker 4:  it's Facebook's smart glasses thing like this. This is a, a, a
Speaker 4:  rich area that no one has cracked in any kind of way that anyone
Speaker 4:  actually cares about
Speaker 1:  Here. Here's my question. So they, they talk a lot about
Speaker 1:  AI in this. It's a bunch of former Apple people. How much of this is
Speaker 1:  a play to get acquired by Apple
Speaker 1:  for, for ar stuff, VR stuff in the future?
Speaker 1:  Because if you're ingesting all of that data, if this thing goes out and
Speaker 1:  exists and suddenly and people decide to wear a camera all the time
Speaker 1:  that ingests all of this data, now you're getting a lot of data that can
Speaker 1:  be really, really useful if you want to train your facial
Speaker 1:  recognition and all your other fancy like AI
Speaker 1:  components for your Spark glasses.
Speaker 3:  So Gruber had a note about this in the blog post where he leaked the deck
Speaker 3:  and there Yeah, this is like the interpersonal workings of Humane, the people
Speaker 3:  who love to start it. Yeah. Apparently not Beloved at Apple. People thought
Speaker 3:  they took too much credit for stuff that team spilled. Oh.
Speaker 1:  So
Speaker 3:  Maybe that's like gruber sourcing. Who knows? Maybe not. That is
Speaker 3:  the vibe that he reported when he leaked this tech. Okay. Now that doesn't
Speaker 3:  mean they won't get sold to Google or Microsoft like somewhere the Google
Speaker 3:  clips product managers. Like what if we just like bought my idea again? Did
Speaker 3:  it, did it good? Who knows? But they have raised an awful lot of money
Speaker 3:  and they, man the hype here has been like just off
Speaker 3:  the charts, like this is a company that makes videos about like the
Speaker 3:  feelings they hope you have about their products. So
Speaker 5:  Would would you say the hype is taking a a sort of a magical leap? Is that
Speaker 4:  Yes, dude.
Speaker 3:  That's what I keep thinking of
Speaker 4:  Too. But at least Magical Leap made a thing that is like hopelessly impractical
Speaker 4:  and the field of view is only this big. But like, but there was cool technology
Speaker 4:  actually. Very cool. Yeah. This to me is like, I'm not sure they're doing
Speaker 3:  Anything. I'm sorry, can we just back up
Speaker 1:  On that? No, the technology was cool. I'll defend that. Like, beating
Speaker 1:  it directly into your
Speaker 3:  Eyeball. Eyeball. They, they promised that they were gonna hack the GPU of
Speaker 3:  your brain. Those were the words they used.
Speaker 4:  Hell yeah.
Speaker 3:  And then they remember they had that crazy wired story with like the, I mean
Speaker 3:  now I think they just hung up a bunch of like l e d rob lights,
Speaker 3:  like glued them to someone's, they had
Speaker 5:  We making
Speaker 1:  Demos. All the commercials were the whale
Speaker 3:  And the whale and they had the video that no one could tell if it was real.
Speaker 3:  Cause it was like com. It was like they generated it it and handed it out
Speaker 3:  and then in the end they'd use the same sort of LCD wave guide stuff.
Speaker 1:  Like when Beyonce saw it and then decided to invest Beyonce went neat.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, no, the number of celebrities who went to Florida to invest in magically
Speaker 3:  because they're the GPUs of their brains have been hacked is off the charts.
Speaker 3:  I'm just saying this, that feels like this thing, right? Like, it's like,
Speaker 3:  but
Speaker 1:  With ai
Speaker 3:  The first step is what's, isn't there another, there's like another
Speaker 3:  app and their, their pitch is, will record everything you do on your computer
Speaker 3:  so you can find it again.
Speaker 1:  Why
Speaker 3:  Would you? It's called Rewind.
Speaker 4:  You do that, it's like rewind
Speaker 3:  Ai. Like I 1000% too much GenX to be like, yeah,
Speaker 3:  that's a good idea. Like I saw that Will Smith movie with Gene Hackman.
Speaker 3:  I No,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no, the the thing the humane story really reminds me of is when
Speaker 4:  Carl pay left OnePlus and started nothing and spent months and months
Speaker 4:  talking about how we need a hardware revolution and everything needs to be
Speaker 4:  different. And then just launch headphones
Speaker 1:  And a phone with LEDs. That's true.
Speaker 4:  Sure. On the back. Yeah. Con congratulations.
Speaker 3:  That's innovation.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Great headphones. But you can see the headphones. It's like fine. But
Speaker 4:  this feels like it, it just, the fact that no one has
Speaker 4:  learned that hype eventually comes around and crushes you
Speaker 4:  underneath it is mind blowing to me. And Humane just keeps
Speaker 4:  doing this to itself. Like all these companies keep doing it to
Speaker 4:  themselves. Magical Leap was like, we've hacked the GPU of your brain. But
Speaker 4:  if they had just said like, we built this kind of neat thing that you
Speaker 4:  probably can't buy for a long time. Like it, it might be in much better shape
Speaker 4:  now
Speaker 1:  Because they don't have, they don't have editors. This is, this is like,
Speaker 1:  like if those, if the marketing people who wrote all of this stuff had an
Speaker 1:  editor to be like, does it really hack the G p U of your brain?
Speaker 1:  They go, oh
Speaker 4:  No, they don't need an editor. I've always said that when I get out of journalism,
Speaker 4:  my next career is gonna be to be the consultant that you pay a lot of money
Speaker 4:  to sit in the room and tell you all your ideas are bad. Like if you need
Speaker 4:  somebody to tell your boss that this is actually not as cool as they think
Speaker 4:  it is, I will do that for the low low price of $25,000.
Speaker 3:  Like,
Speaker 4:  Like I will sit there, I'll tell you your names are stupid and that this
Speaker 4:  thing isn't as cool as you think it is and you should probably cool it for
Speaker 4:  a minute. And I'm gonna make a fortune. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 1:  I'm so happy for you.
Speaker 4:  I'm just looking through these humane slides and it's deeply hilarious. The,
Speaker 4:  the first slide says, what is it? And then it says cloud connected site enabled
Speaker 4:  AI platform with server side app ecosystem. And then three
Speaker 4:  slides later, you realize it's a camera.
Speaker 1:  It's just so blurry too. That's like,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's the thing. It's like, dear leakers, if you're gonna take pictures
Speaker 4:  of things, just press the focus on your, on your camera. It's so easy.
Speaker 4:  Smartphone cameras are so good though.
Speaker 1:  Any leak, I get super blurry, usually in
Speaker 1:  black and white. Usually like three 20 by 200
Speaker 1:  pixels. You need a microscope.
Speaker 3:  Okay. So Imran Chery, who is the CEO of Humane,
Speaker 3:  he's one of the founders. He just keeps saying things like, this will be
Speaker 3:  the best human experience ever. Humane is the next shift
Speaker 3:  between humans and computing. The best human experience ever. It's technology
Speaker 3:  that improves the human experience that is born from good intention. Products
Speaker 3:  have put us back in touch with ourselves each other and the world around
Speaker 3:  us and experiences that are built on trust with interactions that feel magical
Speaker 3:  and bring joy. That's a lot, right? Like, just like at the end of the day,
Speaker 3:  that's a lot, you know, and it's like, phones are pretty good. So like
Speaker 3:  the the just the hype here of like, what are you gonna deliver? And then
Speaker 3:  the list of partners is crazy. Like they're partnered with LG and Volvo cars
Speaker 3:  and it's like to do what? And I, I just think there's no
Speaker 3:  way you can build up a company like this and not have whatever
Speaker 3:  first version of a first product be a let down a hundred percent. Because
Speaker 3:  the first version of any first product is defined by the compromises you
Speaker 3:  made to ship it out the door. Yep. All right. Last little lightning round
Speaker 3:  piece. David, you were really into Allison's vivo X 90 Pro versus
Speaker 3:  Samsung S 23 Ultra camera comparison.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's just very good and everyone should read it. She basically went
Speaker 4:  to try to figure out in the world of smartphone
Speaker 4:  cameras, is it better to have a lot of pixels or a big sensor essentially,
Speaker 4:  which is the sort of eternal camera war. And she landed in
Speaker 4:  this very funny sort of existential place that I don't wanna totally spoil,
Speaker 4:  but it's basically like everything is actually a hundred times more complicated
Speaker 4:  than you think. And it does without quite saying, it boil all the way down
Speaker 4:  to like, what's a photograph?
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But it's, it's really good. And she ends up sort of meditating on like what
Speaker 4:  makes these things work and why this stuff is hard and
Speaker 4:  sort of how the whole imaging pipeline has changed as this tech has changed.
Speaker 4:  Again, I don't wanna split it, but it's, it's, it's really good and was one
Speaker 4:  of the sort of VIRs things I'd read in a while. Cause you could, she started
Speaker 4:  with one question and ended in like a total explosion of
Speaker 4:  gadgets and technology and it's, it's a really fun read and
Speaker 4:  spoiler alert, the Samsung camera ends up being substantiate better.
Speaker 3:  But
Speaker 4:  It's a good read. Everyone should go read it.
Speaker 3:  All right. We have gone so far over, if you're listening to this in your
Speaker 3:  car, just know that the humane section went on for like 25
Speaker 3:  more minutes and we honestly, we just had to cut it cuz we just kept on looking
Speaker 3:  at their marketing materials and being like, what is this? So if you need
Speaker 3:  to experience the part that was cut, just hit pause. Just, I dunno. Look
Speaker 3:  at a flower, be like, what is this? That's what we did.
Speaker 3:  Well we gazed at Humane for while.
Speaker 3:  We are gonna be at South by Southwest on Sunday. If you are in Texas at the
Speaker 3:  show, we're doing a live vergecast March 12th, 2:30 PM
Speaker 3:  It's free and open to the public. It's in, I believe it's in Slacks
Speaker 3:  space. Yeah, that's gonna be fun. So come see us at South by Southwest.
Speaker 3:  You can call the Vergecast hotline. Eight six six Verge
Speaker 3:  11. David, you're back. You're gonna be with us at So by
Speaker 4:  Southwest. I'm back. I'm gonna be there. Richard, I'm I'm, I'm very sorry
Speaker 4:  to be coming back and to be doing a terrible Richard impression
Speaker 4:  for a long time on the podcast. But for everyone who is very sad that Richard
Speaker 4:  is gonna be on the show, a a little less. Don't worry, Richard, you're gonna
Speaker 4:  be here a lot still. I'd like you better than NEI or
Speaker 3:  Alex. Richard, I've decided that you should take over the Vergecast TikTok
Speaker 3:  account, which doesn't exist, but if it did, it would just be Richard, you
Speaker 3:  down. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Do it. Yes, that is, that's all I'm doing now. As long as I can do it from
Speaker 5:  this room.
Speaker 3:  Ah, that's fine. You gotta do the, the dancing dogs thing.
Speaker 3:  All right, we gotta end this before I have more ideas. So LA this week Alex,
Speaker 3:  what's going on with that?
Speaker 1:  So this week it's gonna be, well, this coming week it's gonna be tiny.
Speaker 1:  Makes Things, who is a key cap
Speaker 1:  designer for? For mechanical keyboards. It's a very fun discussion. Ashley
Speaker 1:  Scada has a wonderful time with it.
Speaker 3:  Very cool. All right, that's it. We've gone so far over. That's ver chest
Speaker 3:  rock and roll.
Speaker 15:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you
Speaker 15:  enjoy the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend,
Speaker 15:  you can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is
Speaker 15:  produced by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 15:  This episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith. Our
Speaker 15:  editorial director is Brooke Min, and our executive producer is Eleanor
Speaker 15:  Donovan. The Verge Cast is a production of the Verge and Box Media
Speaker 15:  Podcast Network. And that's it. We'll see you next week.