# Transcript
ID: d4e11090-9862-11ed-bf67-3f0ce2fff60a
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: 2023's laptops and wearables we may (or may not) see
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/76230589312385834/-6549285972934202536/s93290-US-4149s-1674178574.mp3
Description: The Verge’s Alex Cranz talks with senior reviewer Monica Chin about the laptops she saw at CES this year and what it means for 2023’s computer trends. Verge reviewer Victoria Song joins the show to discuss the FDA regulations behind health tech, and whether the stuff we saw at CES will ever be available in the United States.
Speaker 2:  Hello, and you're listening to The Verge, the flagship podcast
Speaker 2:  of laptops with a ton of screens. I'm your friend Alex
Speaker 2:  Kranz and I am currently walking through the streets of New York to try to
Speaker 2:  tire out my dog after he slept for the last three days on our drive
Speaker 2:  back from Texas. Found a whole bunch of cool gadgets in my
Speaker 2:  mom's house. Really excited to play with them, but first I gotta get this
Speaker 2:  dog worn out and we gotta do a whole Vercast episode about
Speaker 2:  ces. I know, I know we've done a ton of episodes about CES so far,
Speaker 2:  but there's just a little bit more left to do. So we're gonna be talking
Speaker 2:  to Monica Chin about all the laptop sheets saw and when we're
Speaker 2:  gonna actually see them in 2023 and what they mean for
Speaker 2:  laptop trends this year. And then we're gonna talk to Victoria's Song because
Speaker 2:  health technology was a really big deal at the show this year. And she's
Speaker 2:  been looking into what the FDA is doing to make sure that when we use all
Speaker 2:  these new health gadgets, we don't die. But first I gotta
Speaker 2:  go wear this dog out. I'll see you right after the
Speaker 2:  break.
Speaker 3:  Get Disney Plus and Hulu in a brand new bundle. Better together for only
Speaker 3:  9 99 a month. Offer valid for eligible subscribers only terms
Speaker 3:  apply. See disney bundle.com
Speaker 3:  for details.
Speaker 2:  Okay, and we're back. So there was a ton
Speaker 2:  of laptops announced at ces. I know we've talked about a bunch of 'em on
Speaker 2:  the show already, but I had to talk to Monica Chen because
Speaker 2:  she was actually there. She got to play with these laptops
Speaker 2:  and she wrote about almost every single one announced at the show it
Speaker 2:  seems like. So we're gonna talk about the Lenovos and the Razors and the
Speaker 2:  lgs and the suss, all of them. And then we're gonna talk about the state
Speaker 2:  of the laptop business in 2023 and what you're gonna see from all of these
Speaker 2:  companies this year. It's a super fun conversation. Very
Speaker 2:  nerdy. Let's get
Speaker 2:  into
Speaker 2:  it. All right, Monica, have you recovered
Speaker 2:  from CES yet? Did you get a funk?
Speaker 5:  A funk?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The CES funk. Are you like snotty right
Speaker 2:  now?
Speaker 5:  No, actually I was, I was so sure I was gonna come back like deathly ill,
Speaker 5:  but I'm like very fine right now. I'm raring to go, which I think might be
Speaker 5:  the first time that has ever happened to me after CS where I haven't come
Speaker 5:  back with like the flu. So knocking on wood, you never know what could
Speaker 5:  happen. But this was a remarkably good recovery.
Speaker 2:  Awesome. Well that is great because I'm just gonna be like grilling you
Speaker 2:  today about ces. I'm very jealous that I didn't get to go, I didn't get to
Speaker 2:  go to like that weird room that Lenovo always has. It's not weird.
Speaker 2:  It's
Speaker 5:  Fine. We missed you in that room Alex.
Speaker 2:  I know they, they were probably like, where was she?
Speaker 5:  There were laptops with your name on them everywhere and you weren't there.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 2:  So sad. It was I'm oh my god, you're, you're giving me a lot of FOMO
Speaker 2:  right now, but you saw a bunch of stuff. I know there was the really, really
Speaker 2:  kick ass Lenovo that I'm glad I didn't go cuz I would've been just playing
Speaker 2:  without the entire time. What, like what was your favorite thing that you
Speaker 2:  saw at CES this year?
Speaker 5:  I would have to say the, the Lenovo dual screen. Basically what it is is
Speaker 5:  there's a 13.3 inch olet screen on the top. There's a 13 inch olet screen
Speaker 5:  on the bottom, 2.8 K, same size, same resolution. You can fold
Speaker 5:  it in half, you can unfold it. So when you unfold it, it's just like this
Speaker 5:  super tall thing and then you like put it on a kickstand and it's just like
Speaker 5:  this one massive long window with like a hinge in the middle but whatever.
Speaker 5:  And then you can fold it into a clamshell laptop mode where you have
Speaker 5:  like one screen on the top and one screen on the bottom you can put sideways.
Speaker 5:  So it's like a book. You can fold it backwards so that it's a tablet and,
Speaker 5:  but like the keyboard's not awkwardly on the back. There are a lot of ways
Speaker 5:  you can use it. It it, it's like a surface new reimagined kind of like this
Speaker 5:  sort of form factor isn't new. Yeah. But it feels a little more similar to
Speaker 5:  me to using like a foldable, like Lenovo's done a
Speaker 5:  foldable before. Asus has a foldable, various people have
Speaker 5:  foldables. This is like that. But like if it didn't suck because
Speaker 5:  like foldables are like a lot of fun to fold but like they're
Speaker 5:  fun to use as a tablet when you fold them into a clamshell
Speaker 5:  form factor. The problem is that like cuts the screen size you have in
Speaker 5:  half. Yeah And like makes it like really impractical to use often. Like even
Speaker 5:  the 17 inches when you fold 'em they still become like pretty small. Andre
Speaker 5:  pretty cramped because of like the bezel space on the side. Because
Speaker 2:  You're talking about the foldables that are like one big display,
Speaker 5:  Like the Zen book fold. Yeah, the thing pad X one fold. Yeah, this is like
Speaker 5:  that except when you fold it, it actually you can actually still use it and
Speaker 5:  it's just like a regular 13 inch. Oh. Which I really, I
Speaker 5:  really like and I think this is actually like really versatile and practical.
Speaker 2:  I know you only got to spend a little time with it. You didn't get to spend
Speaker 2:  days and days with it. But how was the typing?
Speaker 5:  So there is a keyboard, there's like a keyboard that you can like snap on
Speaker 5:  and off. That is what I would use most of the time just cuz like that's a
Speaker 5:  keyboard. I wanna type on a keyboard most of the time You can also type in
Speaker 5:  it, plug in an external keyboard, which is what I assume some folks will
Speaker 5:  do if they don't like the flat one. I liked the flat one. I thought it was
Speaker 5:  fine. It did not feel like super super flat. I would not say it was,
Speaker 5:  I mean it doesn't feel like using like a great keyboard for me suits or someone.
Speaker 5:  But like I thought it was like acceptable. I would've been happy to like
Speaker 5:  type on it. It had a nice click. You can also use
Speaker 5:  a haptic feedback keyboard on the flat screen on the bottom if you
Speaker 5:  fold it into clamshell mode.
Speaker 2:  But is it good?
Speaker 5:  So obviously I think most people aren't gonna prefer to like type on
Speaker 5:  a flat screen cuz like it's typing on a flat screen. I much prefer it to
Speaker 5:  typing on like an iPad. The haptic feedback is like very good. There's like
Speaker 5:  a real click. The keys are really roomy because it is full size, like it
Speaker 5:  is the size of that. It would be on a 13 inch laptop. So it wasn't like
Speaker 5:  riddled with typos the way that like it often is what I'm typing on an iPad
Speaker 5:  cuz it's so tiny. Yeah. And so it was like usable. It was probably the
Speaker 5:  best on-screen keyboard I've ever tested. Which again, the bar for that is
Speaker 5:  on the floor. But it is, it is like, it is not difficult to meet that
Speaker 5:  standard at all. But it is like a, it is a nice haptic keyboard that like
Speaker 5:  you could use it in a pinch. You, you feel like you are clicking keys a little
Speaker 5:  bit, which again is more than for example, you get from the
Speaker 5:  windows on-screen keyboard most of the time. I
Speaker 2:  Like, I'm honestly not surprised by that cause Lenovo's always been pretty
Speaker 2:  good at keyboards. More so on the think pad than the, than the yoga lines.
Speaker 2:  But like I've always liked a Lenovo keyboard.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, think pad keyboards are very, are legendary. Unfortunately
Speaker 5:  this one not being a think pad does not have a have a haptic little
Speaker 5:  red thing in the middle.
Speaker 2:  That would've been the
Speaker 5:  Best. But you know you can't have everything in life. But it is really fun.
Speaker 5:  And the other cool thing when you've about clamshell mode is when you use
Speaker 5:  that, that onscreen keyboard, regardless of whether you are using the
Speaker 5:  haptic one or the physical one that you like plunk on, there
Speaker 5:  is a touch pad that they put like on the bottom. Cuz like one of my
Speaker 5:  big concerns when I first saw this announcement, I was like where is the
Speaker 5:  touchpad? There's no touchpad on this. Like how do you navigate this? And
Speaker 5:  the answer is that there are a number of different ways, but one of them
Speaker 5:  is there is a haptic touchpad that they put on the bottom. It's
Speaker 5:  the buttons are actually like physical buttons. I mean they're
Speaker 5:  like virtual physical buttons. Like they're not like real buttons but like
Speaker 5:  they, they are outlined as buttons when you click they feel like you're clicking
Speaker 5:  buttons. Oh again, it doesn't feel like you're clicking like great buttons.
Speaker 5:  But it is like I, I would say it is better haptic feedback than like
Speaker 5:  some other haptic touch pads out there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I deeply enjoy Lenovo products. Think pads are like if I
Speaker 2:  had to own a Windows pc that wasn't it when I built myself it'd probably
Speaker 2:  be a think pad but the bloatware can be kind of bad
Speaker 2:  in Lenovo products did this feel like bloated at all?
Speaker 2:  Like all, all this extra software because this isn't Windows stuff. This
Speaker 2:  is like Lenovo made all of this stuff to make it
Speaker 2:  work.
Speaker 5:  So there is one, as far as I know, there's one Lenovo
Speaker 5:  like control center where you sort of control everything and other than that
Speaker 5:  it really is just, it at least in my, what I was doing it was
Speaker 5:  Windows with like a bunch of extra gestures that they put in. So there were
Speaker 5:  not like, as far as I know, it was not like an Acer experience where there's
Speaker 5:  like Lenovo Experience Center and Lenovo Game Center and Lenovo
Speaker 5:  Sound Center. Like I do, I, there might be those but I didn't have to interact
Speaker 5:  with them if they were there. I didn't have things popping up everywhere.
Speaker 5:  Again, this was a pre-production unit so that is somewhat difficult to extrapolate
Speaker 5:  to like what's gonna be on the shelf and like what you're gonna get if you
Speaker 5:  buy one of these. But this really felt very much like
Speaker 5:  using Windows and
Speaker 2:  They actually plan to ship
Speaker 5:  It. Yeah, this is, they were putting this out is their claim like it's not
Speaker 5:  Windows 10 x or it's not like the the fancy Microsoft thing thing that they
Speaker 5:  were gonna ship. Like this is regular Windows. It feels like using Windows.
Speaker 5:  Lenovo has put a bunch of gestures in and the Lenovo control center, which
Speaker 5:  is where you can like play with the haptic touch pad and you can toggle
Speaker 5:  with the keyboard and fool around with some of the, the dual screen stuff
Speaker 5:  that actually seemed pretty responsive. It didn't, again, I only had a little
Speaker 5:  bit of time with it and it was supervised. But sometimes those things are
Speaker 5:  like super glitchy when they first ship and like required to restart the
Speaker 5:  computer when you like do a single thing. This seemed pretty responsive and
Speaker 5:  pretty like well developed and like time was put into it and reasonably well
Speaker 5:  laid out like the part I think you're gonna access the most, which is the
Speaker 5:  please pull up the touch pad part was like really easy to get to and not
Speaker 5:  buried. So that was great.
Speaker 2:  That's very cool. And it comes out what time of this year?
Speaker 5:  It's supposed to arrive in June. Okay. And they gave me $2,000
Speaker 5:  price. So like somewhere in that range we're expecting that's
Speaker 2:  A similar pri what did they talk about processor at all? Like what's the
Speaker 2:  internals on this thing look
Speaker 5:  Like? So yeah it has the 13th gen, intel core I
Speaker 5:  seven U 15 processor. So that's a u serious
Speaker 5:  processor. It's a thin and light processor. It's not gonna be like, you know,
Speaker 5:  your huge gaming laptop stuff. But I have had, I have had a lot of people
Speaker 5:  ask and even some of our video people asked like, could you edit on this?
Speaker 5:  And like I think you could try like I wouldn't, you know, and I think this
Speaker 5:  will be obvious, most people who work in the space but a youer processor
Speaker 5:  isn't gonna give you like the best premier pro experience. But I have had
Speaker 5:  U series machines where I've had to dive into Premiere and like do some quick
Speaker 5:  things or I've had to go do some photo stuff and like it's slow, it's kind
Speaker 5:  of slow to load but like will work And that's like again without
Speaker 5:  making any like strict pronouncements, not having used the thing for it.
Speaker 5:  That's what I would like generally expect out of this kind of
Speaker 5:  category processor. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  No I'm just excited cuz I feel like we've been seeing this
Speaker 2:  form factor. How many times have you gone, I know I've done it a bunch. And
Speaker 2:  you have too. You go to a place and they get really excited and they're
Speaker 2:  like, okay, you can't, you can't share this with anyone. It's not ready
Speaker 2:  yet. It's like three years away. But look and it's, it's, it's
Speaker 2:  what Lenovo's doing right now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They've had prototypes of this thing at their CES
Speaker 5:  booth before in various years and
Speaker 2:  Other people have too, right? Like I feel like Intel was always showing Intel's
Speaker 2:  always like the new way Intel's so good that soon this
Speaker 2:  is gonna be your computer.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean I think what that highlights is like, this is not like a new
Speaker 5:  form factor. Like that's like people have done this before, this has been
Speaker 5:  floating around. I see this really as a software announcement.
Speaker 2:  Oh, interesting.
Speaker 5:  Lenovo has said that they've invested in putting real
Speaker 5:  gesture control on this thing. They've ingested in an ecosystem
Speaker 5:  where this is easy to use. They have put in the work
Speaker 5:  to make, to address the question of where is the touch pad
Speaker 5:  for example. And like the fact that everyone hates onscreen
Speaker 5:  keyboards and doesn't, and virtual touch pads are kind of hit or miss when
Speaker 5:  other companies try them. They really, I think have put thought into that
Speaker 5:  stuff and effort into that stuff. How it's gonna pay off. You know, we're
Speaker 5:  gonna have to see. But that to me is the, the significant thing here.
Speaker 5:  Less so the, the fact that you can like open and close it and there's a screen
Speaker 5:  on the bottom, although that is cool.
Speaker 2:  It is cool. And it's also just $2,000. I say just that is a
Speaker 2:  lot of money for something that is not actually tested with lots of people
Speaker 2:  using it yet. But that feels kind of cheap to me.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean that 2000 is, is more than a lot of people are gonna wanna pay
Speaker 5:  compared to Foldables. That's a bargain. Like the ASU Zen book 17 fold started
Speaker 5:  at like over 4,000 I think like it was like some ridiculous amount of
Speaker 5:  money. So this is like, not that it is, you know, it's still a premium product.
Speaker 5:  In the premium space. We, we hope to see that drop Lenovo prices often
Speaker 5:  do drop very quickly. Lenovo often sets their, their
Speaker 5:  MSPs like much higher than things tend to sell for. So I'm hopeful that we'll
Speaker 5:  see it, we'll see it go for lower.
Speaker 2:  Did at any point you flip it around and pretend like you were in Star
Speaker 2:  Trek?
Speaker 5:  No,
Speaker 2:  Just shut me down.
Speaker 5:  I haven't seen Star Trek so I don't know what you're talking about unfortunately.
Speaker 2:  All right. We're not gonna take a break yet, but that made me wanna take
Speaker 2:  a break real bad. I'll survive, I'll survive. What other cool stuff did
Speaker 2:  you see at ces?
Speaker 5:  So also in the Lenovo booth, one of the things I thought was really cool
Speaker 5:  was they had the Lenovo think phone by Motorola. And this
Speaker 5:  is essentially if a think pad like made a
Speaker 5:  wish on a star to become a smartphone, then that wish came true. Like it's
Speaker 5:  this little smartphone that like is designed to look like a ThinkPad. It
Speaker 5:  has like if you've used a ThinkPad you'll and you see this phone, you'll,
Speaker 5:  you'll sort of get what I'm talking about. Like it has the textured back
Speaker 5:  that it's all black, it has like the little logo with the red dot on it.
Speaker 5:  There is a little red button on the side, which is not a keyboard N but
Speaker 5:  like that's probably the best you can do on a literal smartphone is like
Speaker 5:  a little red button on the side. You can remap it, which if you're a ThinkPad
Speaker 5:  user you may have experience remapping some of their
Speaker 5:  keyboard keys. I certainly do. So it's, it's made
Speaker 5:  to sort of seamlessly interact with the ThinkPad in some similar ways that
Speaker 5:  the iPhone interacts with like Mac computers. So there's
Speaker 5:  like one of the most obvious sort of glaring examples there is the, they
Speaker 5:  have a similar feature to continuity camera where it can use a think
Speaker 5:  phone as like your webcam when you're video conferencing on a think pad.
Speaker 5:  And that's like super easy to set up. I got to try that. There's a number
Speaker 5:  of other connectivity features. There's one called the, I think it's the
Speaker 5:  United Clipboard where you can like take a photo with
Speaker 5:  your phone and then like press Ctrl V on the think pad and it
Speaker 5:  like automatically paste that photo like right into whatever's open on the
Speaker 5:  think pad. So
Speaker 2:  Kind of like what you can do with an iPhone and a
Speaker 2:  Mac.
Speaker 5:  So sort of, yeah and there's, there's a lot of other sharing like find each
Speaker 5:  other really easily over wifi. There's like tethering stuff happening. It
Speaker 5:  was a lot of fun to use and I think it's like, like if I had a think pad,
Speaker 5:  I think it would be like a really, I think it would make my life easier in
Speaker 5:  a lot of ways. So that that was a lot of fun to try.
Speaker 2:  Who is the audience though? Like
Speaker 5:  Think pad lovers, like think pads are like one of the most beloved
Speaker 5:  lines of all time. I mean
Speaker 2:  I know they're beloved but like are there enough people out there who are
Speaker 2:  like, I'm going to get rid of my iPhone or like
Speaker 2:  my fancy Samsung
Speaker 2:  foldable or whatever and be like I'm going to fully embrace
Speaker 2:  ThinkPad.
Speaker 5:  I mean I think the audience is fairly specific in that like it's, it's
Speaker 5:  really for hardcore ThinkPad people who like
Speaker 5:  only use Think pads and really want something that will compliment
Speaker 5:  their ThinkPad use. I think that like those people definitely exist though.
Speaker 5:  And I think I, it'll certainly be interesting to see how many people actually
Speaker 5:  buy this. I mean it's been like how many years in the making since, since
Speaker 5:  Lenovo, Lenovo bought Motorola. So I, I'm not the phone
Speaker 5:  reviewer so I, I didn't spend a ton of time testing like
Speaker 5:  the Dustproof ratings or any, any of that like phone stuff. That wasn't
Speaker 5:  what I was there to do. But I did from the laptop side get a chance to see
Speaker 5:  like how well it interacted with the Think pad and it was pretty well. Awesome,
Speaker 2:  Awesome. Allison's just furious right now. She's like, you didn't take any
Speaker 2:  notes on this? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah it was funny when I was, I was sort talking to Allison about it and
Speaker 5:  she was like, oh yeah it has this, this is such a cool phone, it has like
Speaker 5:  this like military grade durability feature and like this number
Speaker 5:  of, this number of years under warranty. And I was like, oh cool. I just
Speaker 5:  like that you could like take a photo with it past it out with ThinkPad.
Speaker 5:  I thought that was cool
Speaker 2:  Alice, she's like, well she'll be very excited. She's gonna have so much
Speaker 2:  fun reviewing it. We're gonna learn all about Allison's Secret love of Think
Speaker 2:  Pads. It's gonna be great. You're gonna have to be like looking over her
Speaker 2:  shoulder. It's gonna be wonderful. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I'm be like hey do that, do that.
Speaker 2:  You saw a bunch of stuff at the Lenovo booth. What other brands were doing
Speaker 2:  interesting stuff?
Speaker 5:  So Razor has its biggest blade ever. The Razor Blade
Speaker 5:  18. The Razor Blade 16 has a, it's a big boy. The
Speaker 5:  mini l e d display on the razor blade 16 is really cool. These
Speaker 5:  both just look like razor blades. I mean they all, they all same. They're
Speaker 5:  razor blades so
Speaker 2:  Still like just absorbing your fingerprints.
Speaker 5:  Yep. Absorb fingerprints, RGB keyboards. They got the
Speaker 5:  little razor logo on the back that everyone knows and loves.
Speaker 5:  Blade 16 has a mini l e d display, which looks really
Speaker 5:  cool. We sort of were in like a dimly lit hotel room, which is where they
Speaker 5:  had all this stuff laid out. They had their razor edge, which is like their
Speaker 5:  gaming handheld. This wasn't announced here but this was the first time that
Speaker 5:  that I got hands on time with it. Yeah, it's an Android tablet with like
Speaker 5:  little controllers attached to it. It runs stuff from like, I
Speaker 5:  was like what services does it have? It they, they gave me like 20 services,
Speaker 5:  like GForce S now is on there and Steam Xbox Steam
Speaker 5:  links on there. Like all yeah all that stuff is on there. And
Speaker 5:  they were playing some different games with it. It's, it's fun they're, it's
Speaker 5:  gonna come like with 5G and Cellular connectivity and without
Speaker 5:  it. So like if that's something you're interested in, you wanna just be out
Speaker 5:  doing Android tablet stuff with it and you wanna pay more, that's an option
Speaker 5:  for you.
Speaker 2:  So I have a question for you about this. I remember, I think Cameron wrote
Speaker 2:  about it for the site. He is a, he's a giant cloud gaming
Speaker 2:  nerd. He's probably softly weeping that Stadia is dead but
Speaker 2:  not as much as Tom Warren. There's a lot of bere people here about
Speaker 2:  Stadia.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, for sure.
Speaker 2:  But it kind of reminded me, it mainly to me it looked more like they have
Speaker 2:  these little controllers that you can attach to your phone. The, the Kishi
Speaker 2:  I think is how you say it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it looks a little like that
Speaker 2:  And it felt kind of like that. But you're buying a
Speaker 2:  tablet from Razor to stick in it instead of just your
Speaker 2:  phone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean their pitch for this, I sort of asked them, I was like, so like
Speaker 5:  is this just an Android tablet controllers and their pitch is like no because
Speaker 5:  of the, the high refresh rate screen Okay is like much higher than you'll
Speaker 5:  get on like most like Android tablets. It's like specifically for gaming
Speaker 5:  it looks very smooth and because of the the extra
Speaker 5:  like all the gaming services that are like come natively on
Speaker 5:  it. Okay. So those are like the two main different things that you're
Speaker 5:  paying for. But like at minimum it is like an Android tablet. Like you could
Speaker 5:  just buy this and like use it as a very expensive high refresh rate Android
Speaker 5:  tablet with controllers if you wanted to like that option would be open to
Speaker 5:  you.
Speaker 2:  And they have this mini l e d laptop. I know we've seen like
Speaker 2:  apples I think has done some mini l e D laptops. Is this the first we're
Speaker 2:  seeing from like a Windows maker?
Speaker 5:  No. So it's sort of been a trend that has like slowly and gradually
Speaker 5:  been picking up speed over the past couple of years. This is a big year for
Speaker 5:  it. Okay. We had a number of mini l e d displays
Speaker 5:  come out and this one had like, I think they said a
Speaker 5:  thousand local dimming zones, which is higher than we heard from other
Speaker 5:  laptops. Yeah and it looks, it looks very cool. These will not be cheap laptops
Speaker 5:  but razor blades are not cheap but it's cool to look at. And they had a little
Speaker 5:  demo like on the side where they were showing they had a little panel that
Speaker 5:  had all the local dimming zones like arranged in a grid and it would
Speaker 5:  like show each little dimming zone lighting up when the
Speaker 5:  dimming zone on the blade was lighting up or dim. Yeah, concurrently. So
Speaker 5:  that was really cool to just see like how tiny these things actually are,
Speaker 5:  how many of them there are and like how hard they're working basically like
Speaker 5:  while this device is displaying an image, this
Speaker 2:  Is technology we've seen from TV makers for years
Speaker 2:  now. Like they've been doing this a very long time and it's taken a super
Speaker 2:  long time it feels like to laptops to catch up. I mean you saw, you
Speaker 2:  said you saw a lot of 'em this year. Is this gonna be kind of one of those
Speaker 2:  things they're hoping we'll drive upgrade cycles and they're, they're hoping
Speaker 2:  people will see that display and be like, yeah, that's my reason to go get
Speaker 2:  a new laptop I just bought one two years ago.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I suspect so. I mean I think display was definitely a
Speaker 5:  focus of many gaming manufacturers this year. You know in the
Speaker 5:  past couple years it's really been like you could get an OED or you can get
Speaker 5:  a higher refresh rate screen but like you couldn't get both or you could
Speaker 5:  get Q H D or you could get like two 40 hertz but you couldn't get
Speaker 5:  both of them And you're starting to see those converge a little
Speaker 5:  more so that it's the expect, it's not as much the expectation that you'll
Speaker 5:  have to give up like a ton of premium features in order to get one. Okay.
Speaker 5:  So we saw a lot, for example, we saw a number
Speaker 5:  of glasses, free 3D displays and one of the
Speaker 5:  big pitches for those is like you don't have to give up other stuff to get
Speaker 5:  this glasses free 3d. It's also od it's also high refresh rate.
Speaker 5:  So like you can still game on it. We're seeing high refresh rate od we're
Speaker 5:  seeing high refresh rate Q H D, that's definitely a
Speaker 5:  space wear like the arms race is picking up.
Speaker 2:  Do you think we're gonna see a moment where laptop makers
Speaker 2:  stop shipping laptops with absolute garbage displays? I
Speaker 2:  mean they're always gonna do that in the sub thousand dollars category, right?
Speaker 2:  Like they're never gonna put a good display in something like that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I was gonna say but
Speaker 2:  In those more expensive ones, do you think we're gonna see a moment where
Speaker 2:  they just like, you know what, we're done with garbage displays,
Speaker 2:  we're going all in on L led, we're going all in on micro l e d and from
Speaker 2:  now on if you wanna Dell X PS 13, it's gonna be a
Speaker 2:  really kick ass display. You're not gonna have to like look at your wallet
Speaker 2:  and decide what's worth it.
Speaker 5:  What I do think is we will definitely see this stuff start to
Speaker 5:  come to lower price devices. Whether that will
Speaker 5:  completely eliminate the need to have like 1920 by 1200
Speaker 5:  on lower price devices. I, I don't entirely know, but I do think that
Speaker 5:  like while this stuff is in the premium space right now, it will, I would
Speaker 5:  expect that like in the next couple years, like getting a two 40 or
Speaker 5:  it's QD display, like we'll get significantly less expensive. Then often
Speaker 5:  when you see this kind of like fancy
Speaker 5:  stuff debut on fancy laptops, that is an
Speaker 5:  important announcement. Not just because it's going to be on those fancy
Speaker 5:  laptops, but because it, that sort of starts the clock for when we're gonna
Speaker 5:  see it on stuff in the sub 1000 range because that is where most people are
Speaker 5:  shopping. Like stuff like the G 14 stuff like the Asian like that is better
Speaker 5:  selling stuff than like the fanciest ACE or Predator Triton
Speaker 5:  and heli is,
Speaker 2:  I feel like laptops are in this unique space where you have
Speaker 2:  a whole bunch of different model types, right? Like a TV
Speaker 2:  ma manufacturer is gonna be like, okay, you get your 55 or your
Speaker 2:  65 or your 75, that's it. Laptop makers are like, okay, you can get your
Speaker 2:  13 inch now, would you like it with an 1980 by
Speaker 2:  1200 or 1980 by 10 80? You
Speaker 2:  know, like they're, they're asking for, they just ask you for tons of different
Speaker 2:  things to choose and you're inevitably like that laptop that's advertised
Speaker 2:  for a thousand dollars and seems like a great deal, the one that actually
Speaker 2:  makes sense is $3,000 and now you have no
Speaker 2:  money. I'm just curious if we're gonna see it at condensing in the, in at
Speaker 2:  least in the monitors element of laptops
Speaker 2:  as these OLEDs and many LEDs become more popular.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, like I think gamers like in general, what, what I hear
Speaker 5:  from companies that they like to have choice and that part of the reason
Speaker 5:  that many of these models are like, so like that they're like
Speaker 5:  a dizzying number of models compared to like the four options that there
Speaker 5:  are for the XPS 13 or whatever Is that like just gamers are really, really
Speaker 5:  picky about, about the kind of stuff that they want. So I wouldn't necessarily
Speaker 5:  think that we'll see models condensing, but like if the question of like
Speaker 5:  whether we'll see displays get better and
Speaker 6:  Better in the sub 1000 space, I think is like absolutely true. So
Speaker 2:  We're seeing, we're seeing the trickle down we're it's it's happening. All
Speaker 2:  right, well we're, we're gonna take a break and when we come back we're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk about why this is all happening because you have been writing a
Speaker 2:  bunch about how the laptop space is in a, in a difficult spot
Speaker 2:  right at the moment. So we're gonna take a break and we'll be
Speaker 2:  right
Speaker 7:  Dating apps. Whether you're single in a relationship or summer in
Speaker 7:  between, you can't get away from them, but what happens when your romantic
Speaker 7:  life is part of a company's bottom line? How did dating become
Speaker 7:  a multi-billion dollar business? I'm Lakshmi
Speaker 7:  Renin
Speaker 8:  And I'm San Toy Kurtz. We are hosting Land of the Giants,
Speaker 8:  a podcast about the biggest tech companies of our time this
Speaker 7:  Season we're exploring how apps like Tinder, hinge and Bumble impact our
Speaker 7:  search for love.
Speaker 9:  Even though you think you're going to meet someone, you know, you have some
Speaker 9:  endpoint narratively in mind, but actually
Speaker 9:  these companies, they don't really want it to have a
Speaker 9:  resolution.
Speaker 7:  And what happens when we hand our hearts over to corporations,
Speaker 10:  It's all about snap judgment and biases and I'm like, you don't even know
Speaker 10:  me. And maybe if you just like swiped right and messaged me and we talked
Speaker 10:  a little bit and you gave me a an effing chance, you wouldn't
Speaker 10:  reject me cuz I'm awesome or am I not awesome.
Speaker 8:  Land of the Giants dating games from the Verge, the Cut and the
Speaker 8:  Vox Media podcast network subscribe for free wherever
Speaker 8:  you
Speaker 8:  listen
Speaker 2:  And we're back, Monica, you wrote this great piece that
Speaker 2:  should be up by the time people are listening to this episode, we're
Speaker 2:  editing it right now and having a great time. That's all
Speaker 2:  about how laptops are in kind of a bad place at the moment.
Speaker 2:  People aren't buying 'em, nobody wants to buy 'em and the
Speaker 2:  technology, the hardware maybe isn't always keeping up. So laptops are starting
Speaker 2:  to pivot. Is that right?
Speaker 5:  So I wouldn't, I don't know if I would call it a pivot, but one of the
Speaker 5:  big things that that sort of hung over this year's CES
Speaker 5:  going into it was the fact that the PC market is like way,
Speaker 5:  way down. You know, 2020 and 2021 were
Speaker 5:  like huge, huge years for the PC
Speaker 5:  and there's been a lot of decline year over year
Speaker 5:  throughout 2022
Speaker 2:  Because everybody bought their laptops.
Speaker 5:  Every manufacturer besides Apple had declining sales
Speaker 5:  and laptops in particular saw a lot of decline. And there's a lot of, you
Speaker 5:  know, there's stuff about refresh cycles and there's the
Speaker 5:  fact that Apple is like eating everyone's lunch in like the portable laptop
Speaker 5:  space and
Speaker 2:  In the processor
Speaker 5:  Space and in the processor space in for, for the thin and light
Speaker 5:  in particular. So one of the big questions going into the show was
Speaker 5:  like how are, how are manufacturers going to deal
Speaker 5:  with this? Not only like how are they actually gonna deal with it, but how
Speaker 5:  are they going to try to convince me that it's not a problem? And like what
Speaker 5:  angle are they going to take? When I asked them
Speaker 2:  Did they convince you?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So there are a couple different tacts that companies took in
Speaker 5:  general. You know, they, the, the task they have is to like, you know,
Speaker 5:  they have to get people to bot to keep buying laptops even if they may
Speaker 5:  have laptops that they bought in 2020 that still work
Speaker 5:  pretty well and how do they keep the market exciting
Speaker 5:  so that people will be like, oh I need that even though this MacBook Air
Speaker 5:  works fine. And so there are some directions that involve
Speaker 5:  like how cool the laptop looks and like Lenovo is like kind of an example
Speaker 5:  of that with like the fancy dual screen. There are companies like
Speaker 5:  LG that released like really like beautiful color changing
Speaker 5:  laptops. Wait
Speaker 2:  What part of 'em is changing colors?
Speaker 5:  So the LG gram style,
Speaker 2:  What a name
Speaker 5:  Is covered in an irid. It's stylish, it's covered
Speaker 5:  in iridescent finish finish. So like when you hold it up to the light
Speaker 5:  it can look like silver or purple or like
Speaker 5:  orange sometimes depending on like the angle and like where the
Speaker 5:  sun is. It's very, so like there's like cool stuff like that that some companies
Speaker 5:  are trying to do that's like eye popping and just sort of like is something
Speaker 5:  that could jump out at you if you were shopping around. Yeah. Another attack
Speaker 5:  that some companies are taking is like going hard
Speaker 5:  on services, on like AI stuff and on
Speaker 5:  features. So when I spoke to Alex Cho, HP's
Speaker 5:  president of personal systems who is great, his pitch was really hard on
Speaker 5:  like we're not a PC manufacturer, like don't think of us as just PCs.
Speaker 5:  We're building an ecosystem and like we oh okay, this year our big
Speaker 5:  pitches is like services and HP has like
Speaker 5:  their booth that they, their their sort of showcase that they had here in
Speaker 5:  New York before ces, the big front and center thing was like
Speaker 5:  webcam features. And so they had, there's like a dual webcam thing
Speaker 5:  that some of their laptops support now where you can have like two webcams
Speaker 5:  plugged into one laptop and it'll like switch between the feeds depending
Speaker 5:  on like where you're looking cause it's tracking your eyes.
Speaker 2:  Fancy.
Speaker 5:  They had, yeah they have like this present, this new present software
Speaker 5:  that a bunch of stuff is built on that is tracks where your head is
Speaker 5:  and tracks where your eyes are. They have just a lot of different
Speaker 5:  webcam stuff and that's sort of something you're seeing across the line like
Speaker 5:  razor I mentioned earlier, they have this like soundbar that tracks like
Speaker 5:  where your head is and based on that it like adjusts like what the audio
Speaker 5:  sounds like to make it still sound like it's moving with
Speaker 5:  you. Essentially there's, as I mentioned earlier, there's like 3D
Speaker 5:  displays that rely on knowing where you're looking to be
Speaker 5:  able to show you the two different images in order to create the 3d.
Speaker 5:  So you know, HP has this new like concierge
Speaker 5:  service that provides like 24 7 live
Speaker 5:  support. There's a lot of emphasis on cloud gaming this year. I
Speaker 5:  mentioned razor's new like cloud gaming handheld, HP
Speaker 5:  has like integrated GForce now with its
Speaker 5:  HP omen software client thing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, there was the, and there was all that work we talked about in the first
Speaker 2:  segment about Lenovo and, and the stuff they were doing with the phone and
Speaker 2:  the stuff they were doing to make this this dual screen laptop work. So yeah,
Speaker 2:  but these companies aren't known for their software.
Speaker 2:  Like anyone who's used an HP
Speaker 2:  printer is familiar with HP's software.
Speaker 2:  Anybody who's first opened an HP laptop
Speaker 2:  knows that software, why should I be inspired
Speaker 2:  or like want to more regularly engage with them. Especially
Speaker 2:  when Samsung, who's actually pretty good at software and
Speaker 2:  Apple who's made it their deal for a long time now, also kind
Speaker 2:  of struggle with services sometimes.
Speaker 5:  So on the commercial side, they're really pushing
Speaker 5:  it for like the hybrid worker and
Speaker 5:  the freelancer. Oh and that's the pitch they have for their
Speaker 5:  concierge service, which I don't entirely buy, but their claim is like, you
Speaker 5:  know, if you're a, if you're someone who like is running your own business
Speaker 5:  from your laptop and you just don't have an IT department,
Speaker 5:  but you really wanna be able to quickly access service, you can press this
Speaker 5:  button and pull up an HP concierge to service your laptop.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I'm not convinced that that's the target audience as much as like
Speaker 5:  my parents
Speaker 2:  Like
Speaker 5:  Might like buy this laptop and like have no idea why it like won't turn
Speaker 5:  on or something. But the, the pitch they're making is that
Speaker 5:  it's more for like people who, who are a small business or who don't have
Speaker 5:  a huge IT department and want like their Zoom calls to
Speaker 5:  look really professional and wanna have access to all these cool features
Speaker 5:  but like don't have a company doing it for them. Again, I don't know, when
Speaker 5:  I look at this stuff, I sort of, the question I always ask is like, is
Speaker 5:  this new fancy thing addressing a need that is
Speaker 5:  actually there or is it creating a need that I am not
Speaker 5:  sure people actually have right now? What I think is addressing a need that's
Speaker 5:  already there is the Lenovo dual screen. Like I think there are like a ton
Speaker 5:  of times in my life when I'm like doing some work and I'm like, wow, I'd
Speaker 5:  really love to have like a second screen here right now. Yeah. I'm not sure
Speaker 5:  if all this like present sensing, fancy webcam,
Speaker 5:  fancy sound, 3D screen stuff is quite, I I am more on
Speaker 5:  the fence about that kind of stuff.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think like that makes sense. If you're a recruiter and you wanna
Speaker 2:  look just like tip top for all of your remote interviews
Speaker 2:  that you're doing throughout the day, it makes less sense if you're just
Speaker 2:  like using your laptop for and
Speaker 2:  sending emails to vendors, which is assu I assume what small
Speaker 2:  businesses do and
Speaker 5:  Freelancers just email. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well you also, I I know you saw a lot of processors stuff
Speaker 2:  at the show and you, you did like that scathing takedown of the Intel
Speaker 2:  P series last year, which was tiptop you loved it
Speaker 2:  absolutely wild that they were like, what if we just made a processor
Speaker 2:  that was the exact same as our super fast processor Yeah. But kind
Speaker 2:  of tweaked it to go a little slower and use a little less energy and
Speaker 2:  that sucked.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But
Speaker 2:  Were things a little more exciting this year. Do, do you feel like AMD and
Speaker 2:  the, and Intel and these companies are finally gonna be catching up to
Speaker 2:  Apple in that laptop space cuz Apple's just kicking everybody's
Speaker 2:  ass.
Speaker 5:  It's really hard to know from the, the charts we have right now, they definitely
Speaker 5:  both made a splash. A M D released this
Speaker 5:  like absolutely massive 16
Speaker 5:  core chip intel released a 24 core chip, but that
Speaker 5:  is like eight performance cores and 16 efficiency
Speaker 5:  cores. Whereas the a MD chip is like 16 like
Speaker 5:  full firings and four cores. So I think that's, that staggered up
Speaker 5:  to be very competitive. These are, but like I remember I
Speaker 5:  saw and Tom and Sean, I, and we were like looking at these like a m
Speaker 5:  d like the chart that a MD sent us that had all the chips and we were just
Speaker 5:  like, what, how is AMD putting that in a laptop like that
Speaker 5:  is wild. There definitely is exciting stuff coming outta these
Speaker 5:  processor announcements. Will these be laptops that have like any kind of
Speaker 5:  battery life at all? Is really the question. We're gonna have to wait and
Speaker 5:  see will this last longer than 30 minutes on battery? We really don't
Speaker 5:  know. The target audience for these chips doesn't necessarily
Speaker 5:  care about having laptops that last eight hours, but that doesn't mean
Speaker 5:  that they'll be happy necessarily with the battery that only lasts like
Speaker 5:  five minutes. Who,
Speaker 2:  Who, who is okay? Who is okay? Who is the person buying a laptop that
Speaker 2:  is okay with having five minutes of battery
Speaker 5:  Life? Yeah, so I will say whenever I write a review like,
Speaker 5:  and, and I say like, I don't like that this didn't last long, very long on
Speaker 5:  battery for me without fail, there are people in the comment saying, well
Speaker 5:  I don't care about battery life, all my laptops. So yeah, your review's
Speaker 5:  wrong. There are certainly, there are certainly groups of people who don't
Speaker 5:  need very long battery life on their laptops. However, I
Speaker 5:  do think that like there is some amount of battery
Speaker 5:  power a laptop should have in order to justify its existence as like
Speaker 5:  a laptop rather than like a mini, a pc, like
Speaker 5:  a desktop,
Speaker 2:  A PC that you can just pick up and go with.
Speaker 5:  Right. Part of the appeal is that you could like move it around her house
Speaker 5:  or potentially like use it at a friend's house or
Speaker 5:  like, you know, that you don't necessarily need to be plugged in Alan all
Speaker 5:  the time. So that is like a big question mark that we'll have to see. But
Speaker 5:  of course it's not the most important thing about these chips.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So, so they seemed really focused not on battery life
Speaker 2:  where Apple is just crushing them but more on
Speaker 2:  power.
Speaker 5:  Oh, definitely. And they had, I mean they very much hedged that, like when
Speaker 5:  I was talking to Jason Banta from a m d, he very
Speaker 5:  much hedged like, these are not gonna have good battery life.
Speaker 5:  Basically. Like he was like, you know, our tar we're we're really targeting
Speaker 5:  an audience that doesn't care about battery life as much as they care about,
Speaker 5:  you know, X and Y and Z. Which, you know, is a fair audience to target.
Speaker 2:  Are they planning to ever target audiences that
Speaker 5:  Like battery life? Well not with this particular, the 16 court chip. I mean
Speaker 5:  the obvi their, their other chips I think are,
Speaker 2:  But this is where they were announcing their high
Speaker 2:  power laptop chip. So like the H series for
Speaker 2:  Intel and I don't know, what is the series called
Speaker 2:  for amd?
Speaker 5:  So there, the 70 45 series is Zen four. Okay.
Speaker 5:  That goes up to 16 cores and 30 huge threads. There's the seven 40
Speaker 5:  series. Oh wow. Is gonna be, that's the Phoenix that's gonna be for like
Speaker 5:  thinner gaming laptops. Okay. There's the 7 35
Speaker 5:  series, which is Rembrandt r that's
Speaker 5:  for like the premium what thin and light space.
Speaker 2:  Monica, what are these names?
Speaker 5:  These names make no sense. There's the Rise 70 30 series, which
Speaker 5:  is for mainstream, thin and light. Is
Speaker 2:  It called a Picasso?
Speaker 5:  No, that's called the Barcelo R. What
Speaker 2:  Does that mean?
Speaker 5:  I have no idea. And that goes up to eight. The, that goes up
Speaker 5:  to eight core 16 threads as do the previous two that I mentioned. And then
Speaker 5:  there's the rise in seven 20, which is like your alon. So that's gonna be
Speaker 5:  for like very low power budget devices and that goes up to four cores.
Speaker 5:  So there's a whole, there's a whole range of stuff on here.
Speaker 2:  Well I'm very excited for your one minute long battery test for all these
Speaker 2:  HX series. It's gonna be a lot of fun. Was there anything else that, like
Speaker 2:  you saw at ces, any kind of trends that you feel are coming for the
Speaker 2:  laptop space? What do we need to brace ourselves for this year?
Speaker 5:  For, for brands we didn't get to, like I said, LG has the style, which is
Speaker 5:  that really cool color changing one. It has the ultra slim, which
Speaker 5:  is, I think it's, its like thinnest and lightest LG gram
Speaker 5:  ever. It's either the thinnest or the light, but it is so light. Like you
Speaker 5:  pick that up and it's like, it, it feels like you're holding like a
Speaker 5:  dummy chassis. It's like absurdly light. I have no idea who's gonna like,
Speaker 5:  want that, but it like it's, it's re that thing is
Speaker 5:  remarkable. HP has a new, it's called the Dragonfly
Speaker 5:  Pro Chromebook. It has an RGB keyboard because you know,
Speaker 5:  why not put that on a Chromebook that's not for gaming. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I think ne Eli's planning to get that for his
Speaker 5:  Parents. Go for it. Nea I'm the Godspeed, I'm very happy
Speaker 5:  for you. They have the Dragonfly Pro, which is not the
Speaker 5:  elite dragonfly that remains, that also had a refresh. There's
Speaker 5:  the Dragonfly G4 now. But that is for businesses, that's a
Speaker 5:  business laptop. The Dragonfly Pro, despite having pro its name is for
Speaker 5:  consumers. So you know, very simple name that makes sense to everyone. But
Speaker 5:  that is sort of a push from them to target who I mentioned
Speaker 5:  earlier, like the freelancer or like the mobile professional,
Speaker 2:  The contractors,
Speaker 5:  Right. The contract. Yeah. In terms of trends, this is definitely gonna be
Speaker 5:  a big display year, especially on the gaming side.
Speaker 5:  We're seeing like a lot of convergence of, you
Speaker 5:  know, buzzwords like O led and mini l e d and refresh
Speaker 5:  rate and resolution. And, and I can't believe I'm saying this
Speaker 5:  in 2022 or 2023 3D
Speaker 5:  glasses, free 3D is a thing now that is coming to some laptops.
Speaker 2:  I refuse to be excited about it. I refuse to be excited about 3d.
Speaker 5:  Acer had one last year, but it's like, like updated it this year. Dell
Speaker 5:  has like a 3D thing. We're seeing all that sort of come together and,
Speaker 5:  and that we're able to get more of those features on
Speaker 5:  displays than where previously you had to sacrifice some of
Speaker 5:  them togethers. So displays are definitely getting better. I think there,
Speaker 5:  there was a big focus on video conferencing this year as there was last year.
Speaker 5:  And AI and role in that was a huge part of it. A m D and
Speaker 5:  Intel both are planning to have AI architecture on the
Speaker 5:  dyes of some of their processors, which is at
Speaker 5:  the moment the most relevant application of that to
Speaker 5:  like most people is gonna be stuff like Windows studio effects. And AMD
Speaker 5:  had Panos pane on stage to talk about that. But it's gonna be
Speaker 5:  like more webcam, present sensing stuff for now.
Speaker 5:  And then the pitches that later on we're gonna see people come up with more
Speaker 5:  heavy duty AI use cases for that stuff. But that's,
Speaker 5:  that's really other big thing. And there's definitely, as there has been
Speaker 5:  for the past few years, a focus on like
Speaker 5:  how laptops will respond to
Speaker 5:  changing work patterns. So like last year I think there was a lot
Speaker 5:  of focus on work from home and remote work. I think this
Speaker 5:  year it's shifted a little more towards hybrid and people who like want
Speaker 5:  a laptop that they can use both in the office and at home.
Speaker 2:  Isn't that just every laptop?
Speaker 5:  Some companies are trying to pitch it more as like, here you only need one
Speaker 5:  cord to plug this into this monitor. Oh. Where before it was
Speaker 5:  more complicated.
Speaker 2:  They're embracing the doc again.
Speaker 5:  It's that and it's a lot more of a focus on, you know, and there's always
Speaker 5:  kind of a focus on like laptops getting thinner. But this year I think a
Speaker 5:  lot of it's really being pitched as like, this is thin so that you can bring
Speaker 5:  it to the office or like, so that you can bring it to Starbucks
Speaker 5:  and focus on the mobile professional or
Speaker 5:  mobile freelancer.
Speaker 2:  Do you think, so one of the best laptops ever made was
Speaker 2:  the Apple Power book, Pismo
Speaker 2:  G three. This thing came out on like, yeah, you sound
Speaker 2:  so enthusiastic and excited about this question. This thing came out in
Speaker 2:  like 19 98, 19 99, I think, please
Speaker 5:  Tell
Speaker 2:  Me more. It had a dock and all you and all of the ports were on the
Speaker 2:  back. So whenever you wanted to plug in, you just went th and you
Speaker 2:  just shoved it into the dock and it looked pretty and it worked so
Speaker 2:  nice. And every dock since has been like it's a dongle and you
Speaker 2:  plug it in. Do you think we're gonna get back to that point where you're
Speaker 2:  like thump because I, the
Speaker 2:  satisfaction was wonderful.
Speaker 5:  There definitely is a focus I think on making
Speaker 5:  monitors simpler to use, which is great for me cuz the current monitor
Speaker 5:  I have like, I have to plug like four computers into it a week and like yeah
Speaker 5:  it is difficult right now to figure out how to, how to plug 'em all in. So
Speaker 5:  that is definitely, I think a trend you'll see more in in peripherals
Speaker 5:  this year is is simplifying their moving them between
Speaker 5:  use cases and making those more versatile to connect.
Speaker 2:  So we're not quite to thunk yet, but we may be.
Speaker 5:  I'm not sure if we're to that yet.
Speaker 2:  Well Monica, thank you so much. This has been a wonderful conversation. We're
Speaker 2:  gonna take a break when we're back. I'm gonna be talking with Victoria
Speaker 2:  song all about all the health stuff that came outta
Speaker 2:  ces, what's going on with the FDA there and how long it'll take for this
Speaker 2:  health stuff to actually get into our homes. It's gonna be great. Thanks
Speaker 2:  again Monica. Thank
Speaker 5:  You.
Speaker 2:  Down to
Speaker 2:  the
Speaker 2:  break.
Speaker 12:  Hi, I'm John Glenn Hill and I'm the new host of The Weeds,
Speaker 12:  a podcast from Vox all about politics and policy. Our
Speaker 12:  mission is to take deep dives into policies shaping our
Speaker 12:  world. Everything from crypto regulation to immigration
Speaker 12:  to climate change. And this week for
Speaker 12:  my first official episode in the host chair, we're firing up
Speaker 12:  the weeds time machine. And taking a trip back
Speaker 12:  to 1965
Speaker 13:  Today is a triumph for freedom. As
Speaker 13:  huge as any victory that's ever been won on
Speaker 13:  any battlefield.
Speaker 12:  To talk about one of the most significant pieces of civil rights legislation
Speaker 12:  in US history, the Voting Rights Act and with
Speaker 12:  questions swirling around election integrity and the future of
Speaker 12:  American democracy, we figured there's no time like the present to
Speaker 12:  look back on it, subscribe to the weeds for new
Speaker 12:  episodes
Speaker 12:  every
Speaker 12:  Tuesday.
Speaker 2:  Okay, and we're back. Ns, I teased at the beginning of the show, there was
Speaker 2:  a lot of health tech at CES this year. There were the
Speaker 2:  smart watches and the makeup tools and the P sensors
Speaker 2:  and a ton of hearing aids. A lot of this stuff is very
Speaker 2:  cool, it's super exciting, but it almost never reaches the
Speaker 2:  United States mostly because of FDA regulations around medical
Speaker 2:  technology. It's a tricky issue. So I wanted to talk to our Reviewer
Speaker 2:  Victoria song who just wrote a really fantastic piece explaining
Speaker 2:  this regulatory maze behind all that Health
Speaker 2:  Tech Victoria, are you recovered from your c s funk that you
Speaker 2:  got without actually being at ces?
Speaker 14:  That's how powerful CES is. I got the c s flu without going and
Speaker 14:  like, you know, I'm still a little sniffly and I don't know if my voice
Speaker 14:  is a hundred percent back to normal, but I don't sound like Marge Simpson
Speaker 14:  anymore. So good stuff.
Speaker 2:  Level up. Level up. I mean that would've been great. We would've been like,
Speaker 2:  we have Marge Simpson on the verge cast today. Tell us about
Speaker 2:  health tech
Speaker 14:  Would've been nice. Yeah, I mean it was cool. It was, it was
Speaker 14:  interesting at c s this year because a lot of it is very,
Speaker 14:  it's, it's kind of a mix between what's conceptual and what's
Speaker 14:  actually real and everything that's in the gray area in
Speaker 14:  between. So you know, like that's always ces, right? There's always a degree
Speaker 14:  of vaporware at CES where you're like
Speaker 2:  A lot of vaporware,
Speaker 14:  A lot of vaporware. But particularly in the health sector where you're
Speaker 14:  just like, wow, this concept is going to
Speaker 14:  change the medical industry as we know it. Five years later the product
Speaker 14:  comes out and it's Nerf. Yeah and it's not no nowhere near as cool as what
Speaker 14:  they, what they said it was gonna be. And I think the coolest,
Speaker 14:  I don't know about coolest, but the most interesting thing I saw this
Speaker 14:  year was why things you scan, that
Speaker 2:  Was the P sensor. Yes.
Speaker 14:  It is a little sensor that you stick in your toilet
Speaker 14:  and to peon. Yeah. And it's got all these, it's all, it's got all these
Speaker 14:  things in it. Like a thermal sensor and a radar sensor so it
Speaker 14:  can like identify your individual urine stream,
Speaker 14:  which is just like, wow, what amazing technology for your,
Speaker 14:  for your toilet
Speaker 2:  Use a radar. It's like are are P
Speaker 2:  streams different?
Speaker 14:  Yes. Well it claims that it can differentiate people by
Speaker 14:  their pea streams. So like it's one user per P
Speaker 14:  scanner. Okay. So you know, like let's say you have multiple people in your
Speaker 14:  house and you don't want your roommate's urinary
Speaker 14:  test results. You want yours. Yeah. So it can identify you
Speaker 14:  by how you pee and it also can tell the difference
Speaker 14:  between like your pee and the water due to temperature sensors.
Speaker 14:  So it's just really amazing, thoughtful
Speaker 14:  like technology that's gone into this thing that sounds
Speaker 14:  absurd but is actually like medically very cool.
Speaker 14:  Especially like, I think the most relatable use case
Speaker 14:  would be for diabetics, right? Like they have to take urine tests all the
Speaker 14:  time to, you know, make sure they're not in keto acidosis. So this
Speaker 14:  would make things easier for them because first of all, if you've ever had
Speaker 14:  to take a urine sample, I really hope you
Speaker 14:  know what your aim is cuz that could be real messy. And
Speaker 14:  this is just you peeing anyway. Oh my god. The, the number of like P
Speaker 14:  facts that I had to learn while writing. You learned a
Speaker 2:  Lot.
Speaker 14:  I learned so much. Did you know there's 3000 metabolites in
Speaker 14:  your pee? You do now.
Speaker 2:  I didn't even know what a metabolite was until you just said that.
Speaker 14:  It's just stuff that tells you about your metabolism. Like ketones, which
Speaker 14:  are a byproduct of breaking down fat.
Speaker 2:  This actually seemed like a cool thing because we're starting to see more
Speaker 2:  of these tests in people's homes instead of just going
Speaker 2:  to the doctors. Like I, I feel like covid
Speaker 2:  really changed things for us. Oh yeah. And so now it's much
Speaker 2:  more acceptable and people feel okay doing, taking these test
Speaker 2:  at
Speaker 14:  Home. Oh yeah, for sure. Like, you know, I'm sure everyone's really familiar
Speaker 14:  with the rapid antigen tests, but there were actually molecular tests that
Speaker 14:  you could have at home. Like Google sent out the Q hu health test and
Speaker 14:  like of course these were really expensive. Yeah But you know, I had a bunch,
Speaker 14:  I was testing them cuz I was writing about them a few months ago and it's
Speaker 14:  amazing. It's just like this little machine that is there and it uploads
Speaker 14:  your results wirelessly to your phone. And so it really makes things
Speaker 14:  easy because you don't have to send things out to a lab and that kind
Speaker 14:  of instantaneous knowledge can be really helpful for remote patient monitoring.
Speaker 14:  Which a lot of the health tech like that we saw this year was kind
Speaker 14:  of around the idea of remote patient monitoring, which is, you know, it's,
Speaker 14:  it's a big foundational gap
Speaker 2:  But at the same time isn't there like a lot of approval thing we have to
Speaker 2:  do? Cuz right now we do it in the lab because the lab is controlled setting
Speaker 2:  you're not as likely to screw up your results because you pick your nose
Speaker 2:  before you handle something. Don't do that. Just don't do that in general.
Speaker 2:  Wash your hands. But, but like, but there's a lot
Speaker 2:  of opportunity to screw up those tests at home. And, and so there,
Speaker 2:  is there a lot of, is there regulation oversight? Like, you wrote a big story
Speaker 2:  this last week, I believe Yes. On this stuff. Is it happening? Are
Speaker 2:  we getting oversight?
Speaker 14:  So I actually think that the FDA is gonna play a lot bigger role in CAS
Speaker 14:  going forward just because, you know, the FDA exists for a very
Speaker 14:  important reason and that is to protect public health. Right? And that's
Speaker 14:  so that when you get a health tech gadget, it doesn't kill you.
Speaker 14:  Doesn't hurt you. Yeah. It doesn't put your life in danger in
Speaker 14:  any like, shape or form. So like the Y things
Speaker 14:  P scanner, it has to go through the FDA clearance process before it can
Speaker 14:  ever be sold, which is why it's not going to be sold in the US even though
Speaker 14:  it's slated for European release sometime this year.
Speaker 2:  European release,
Speaker 14:  Yeah. You a p. Yes. Yeah. So
Speaker 14:  like, it was really funny because I was writing this story and I was just
Speaker 14:  like, oh my God, here I am again talking about my arch
Speaker 14:  nemesis, the fda. And they're not actually my arch
Speaker 14:  nemesis. They're like, I'm very appreciative of the work that they do. But
Speaker 14:  you know, when you're a health tech writer, when you cover wearables,
Speaker 14:  you just kind of learn a lot of jargon and, you know,
Speaker 14:  FDA clearance is not the same thing as FDA approval, right? So if you ever
Speaker 14:  see like a report that's like the FDA approved this
Speaker 14:  product, or if you're ever shopping for something that says FDA approved,
Speaker 14:  that's the number one tell that they are lying through
Speaker 14:  their pants because the FDA does not approve products,
Speaker 14:  it clears them. It's just like we've cleared that this has
Speaker 14:  gone through the appropriate testing so that you
Speaker 14:  won't likely die. Yeah. Is basically what, what
Speaker 14:  it is. So it, it leaves a really big
Speaker 14:  wide range of things that makes everything
Speaker 14:  really confusing in my beat. Yeah. Especially like, I see
Speaker 14:  products all the time, especially in wearables where they're like clinically
Speaker 14:  validated. N n no it's not, you're not an FDA regulated device. How are
Speaker 14:  you clinically validated? And then if you know, you click on things and
Speaker 14:  you're like, oh, you wrote a white paper that's funded by you,
Speaker 14:  of course you, you're getting positive results on, on X, Y, Z.
Speaker 14:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Shocking.
Speaker 14:  Shocking. Very, very, not shocking really, but like the whole reason
Speaker 14:  why you would want FDA clearance is that you know, you
Speaker 14:  can buy it and you can be confident that it's safe
Speaker 14:  for you, that it's gonna work in the way that it's supposed to work. And
Speaker 14:  we're seeing that right now with over-the-counter hearing aids and hearables,
Speaker 14:  which I'm telling you that's gonna be a really big thing
Speaker 14:  coming out of wearables this year. Well,
Speaker 2:  Let's, let's talk about that. Cuz we talked about the P sensor and it is,
Speaker 2:  doesn't have FDA clearance
Speaker 14:  Yet. Nope. But
Speaker 2:  It's hoping to have it at some point this year.
Speaker 14:  You know, it's really funny. Every single time I'm like, Hey, are you going
Speaker 14:  through the FDA clearance process? These companies, like the, the heads
Speaker 14:  of them, they're always just like, ugh.
Speaker 2:  Yes.
Speaker 14:  I can't tell you when it's coming out. Cuz who knows when the FDA
Speaker 14:  is gonna approve everything. And you know why things is a really good example
Speaker 14:  because they're constantly coming to CES with these really cool health tech
Speaker 14:  products. Yeah. That never make it to the US because it
Speaker 14:  takes like two, three years. Okay. Or like, it'll take two, three years
Speaker 14:  before it ever gets to the us. So I think there's like one smartwatch that
Speaker 14:  I saw at CES 2018 that's still not out here. It's it's really
Speaker 14:  funny.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It, there was like a watch that was like a blood pressure monitor cuff
Speaker 2:  that I feel just never got approval. Or did that one finally get approval?
Speaker 14:  There was the amron blood pressure monitor cough and
Speaker 14:  that got approval like two years later. But it's, it's not like a
Speaker 14:  really fun device for normal people to wear. It's if you have hypertension
Speaker 14:  Yeah. You're gonna wear that. I reviewed it many moons ago for Gizmoto.
Speaker 14:  There
Speaker 2:  You go. I vaguely remember that. Product. Product. But let's talk about,
Speaker 2:  let's talk about the hearables and, and the hearing aid place because I think
Speaker 2:  last year kind of set the stage for that, right? Like was it last year that
Speaker 2:  they said we were gonna do over-the-counter hearing aids? You won't have
Speaker 2:  to go to an audiologist, you won't have to go to a, you just
Speaker 2:  go buy 'em.
Speaker 14:  Yeah, no, this has actually been in the works for five years. Wow. This
Speaker 14:  is what I'm telling you. Tech moves fast,
Speaker 14:  medicine moves slow. So health tech moves
Speaker 14:  at the speed of a snail. Like it's just like
Speaker 14:  inching along all the time. But so this, this has been in the process
Speaker 14:  for over five years. It took like, I think Trump was the
Speaker 14:  first president to be like, yeah, we're gonna do this. And then, I mean,
Speaker 14:  he's gone now, right? Yeah. It just got approved. The, the
Speaker 14:  ruling got approved last year in the middle of the year and then
Speaker 14:  the products didn't start hitting shells until
Speaker 14:  mid-October. Okay. So we're still in the very, very, very, very early stages
Speaker 14:  of over-the-counter hearing aids. But you know, this is a whole
Speaker 14:  minefield because if I tell you over-the-counter hearing aids versus over-the-counter
Speaker 14:  self fitting hearing aids versus hearing aids, these are all different things.
Speaker 2:  They all fundamentally do the same thing. Right? Like they all go in your
Speaker 2:  ear and they assist you in hearing
Speaker 14:  Better fundamentally they go in your ear and you hear better.
Speaker 14:  Okay.
Speaker 2:  Yes. But
Speaker 14:  They do different things To different
Speaker 14:  degrees and it's very confusing. I have been like, I have been reporting
Speaker 14:  on this for like three months at this point talking to a lot of different
Speaker 14:  audiologists and it's, it's a nightmare. Like Yeah. I, I just,
Speaker 14:  it's, it's very confusing and it's going to be confusing until like the
Speaker 14:  dust settles a little bit. But with regard to the fda, it's great that
Speaker 14:  they have over-the-counter hearing aids because now you can go into the
Speaker 14:  store, they'll be at your Best Buy, they'll be at your local, like,
Speaker 14:  I don't know your Duane Reed or Walmart. Yeah. Like those
Speaker 14:  places and yeah, you can buy them and you can know that the FDA
Speaker 14:  tested it and you're not going to damage your hearing because they regulate
Speaker 14:  the output levels of sound. There's gonna be a degree where you're
Speaker 14:  able to kind of self fitting means you'll be able to like have a little
Speaker 14:  hearing test in, in an app and it'll be personalized to you. Okay.
Speaker 14:  So great. Cool. There's already products out here that kind
Speaker 14:  of do that that are not hearing aids and that do not have FDA
Speaker 14:  regulation
Speaker 2:  Like I'm wearing AirPods.
Speaker 14:  AirPods are one of the, the things that are like really interesting,
Speaker 14:  right? Because they have conversation boost, conversation boost,
Speaker 14:  you know, it makes people's voices easier to hear in
Speaker 14:  louder environments. That's what a hearing aid does. The AirPods are not
Speaker 14:  a hearing aid because they have not been regulated for output
Speaker 14:  levels. They don't necessarily do everything that a hearing aid
Speaker 14:  needs to do. And I think what's gonna be interesting going forward is
Speaker 14:  you might see some consumer audio companies just like pull back their,
Speaker 14:  their features.
Speaker 2:  Oh, interesting.
Speaker 14:  Well it's cuz like the, the question, and I get it this get into this in
Speaker 14:  my piece, the question that they have to ask themselves
Speaker 14:  is, well, do I wanna be regulated by the F D A and go
Speaker 14:  through everything that involves an F D A clearance process?
Speaker 14:  There's there's a lot.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 14:  There's a lot that goes into that. Well,
Speaker 2:  Do they have to go into the F FDA clearance process? Like is Apple
Speaker 2:  gonna have to get new generations of
Speaker 2:  AirPods approved?
Speaker 14:  That is unclear at the moment because this is so new and everything is
Speaker 14:  shaking out. But say the FDA were to look at a
Speaker 14:  feature like this is all hypothetical, but say the FDA were to look at a
Speaker 14:  feature like AirPods conversation Boost on the pro, right? And they
Speaker 14:  went, Hey, that's really similar to hearing aids and we think that that
Speaker 14:  should be regulated
Speaker 2:  So that we don't bust eardrums with loud noises.
Speaker 14:  Right. So let's say that they say that aspect is
Speaker 14:  really similar to a hearing aid, an over counter hearing aid. You now need
Speaker 14:  to go through compliance, you need to show us that you
Speaker 14:  are able to meet all of these factors. And you know, that
Speaker 14:  involves a lot. Like I talked to Moo Health and they're,
Speaker 14:  they're a really fascinating company. They're making a smart ring that's
Speaker 14:  for women. Women first. Love this. That's going to be
Speaker 14:  a fully FDA cleared medical device. Which is
Speaker 14:  amazing because you know, you have the Apple Watch that's not an FDA cleared
Speaker 14:  device. It's a device that has an FDA cleared feature. So now you see why
Speaker 14:  I rip out my hair every single time I write about this stuff. It's
Speaker 14:  very nuanced, very complicated. But you know, I was talking to their
Speaker 14:  CEO and he has like a wealth of knowledge because he spent
Speaker 14:  like 30 years making products for people with diabetes. Okay. And
Speaker 14:  those are all medical devices. Right. So he was telling me that, you
Speaker 14:  know, we focus on like accuracy a lot with
Speaker 14:  FDA clearance accuracy is less than 1% of what goes into an
Speaker 14:  FDA filing. They have to be HIPAA compliant. They have to show that, you
Speaker 14:  know, your data is encrypted. They have to show out what the
Speaker 14:  communication protocols are. They have to have that tested by an independent
Speaker 14:  party. They have to have their devices manufactured at a
Speaker 14:  medical device factory. They can't go to like consumer grade. Yeah. For
Speaker 14:  that. That is like a whole nightmare. And even, even
Speaker 14:  even even with the clinical accuracy testing, like he described
Speaker 14:  the process to me and like the hypoxia trial, which is, you know,
Speaker 14:  oxygen deficiency. You basically have to take a person
Speaker 14:  both genders and all skin tones and
Speaker 14:  lower their oxygen levels bit by bit and
Speaker 14:  then blind check all, all the data. So it's, it's like
Speaker 14:  incredibly intense, expensive and like the
Speaker 14:  regulatory paperwork, I just, I don't wanna be the person who handles that
Speaker 14:  paperwork. It's a nightmare. But
Speaker 2:  It also is good in the long run because then we
Speaker 2:  don't like people of various skin tones can go and get a device and know
Speaker 2:  that it will work.
Speaker 14:  I've actually been asking a lot of these wearable makers about skin tones
Speaker 14:  because I think there was a thing that came out a while back that was saying
Speaker 14:  that pulse oximeters were not equally good for people
Speaker 14:  of darker skin. And all these companies will tell you like yeah, that's
Speaker 14:  true. Just because of the way the technology works. It works by reflecting
Speaker 14:  light into your skin and people with more melanin will reflect less light
Speaker 14:  back. That's just kind of a flaw of the, the
Speaker 14:  actual technology itself. Right. But you know, I'm asking them about what
Speaker 14:  their, their protocols for testing with people of
Speaker 14:  different skin tones are. And if you're FDA regulated, you have to prove,
Speaker 14:  you have to prove that you work just as well across all skin tones. If you're
Speaker 14:  not FDA regulated, you don't really have to prove nothing. Right. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  You can say that we're super accurate and we just have to trust that you've
Speaker 14:  done the testing and
Speaker 2:  Then you Victoria have to go find a bunch of people and test it
Speaker 2:  for a wonderful video on the verge.com.
Speaker 14:  I I mean yeah, it's gonna be super unscientific,
Speaker 14:  but yeah, like it's, you know, and you know, I've been asking them
Speaker 14:  recently about tattoos as well because that's another thing where
Speaker 14:  you see all these people online going like, oh my god, my Apple watch doesn't
Speaker 14:  work and
Speaker 2:  It's cuz they have a tattoo
Speaker 14:  Because I have tattoos. And and it's like, yeah, that's actually a, a real
Speaker 14:  problem again because when you tattoo your skin you're,
Speaker 14:  you're putting ink there and making it really difficult for the light to
Speaker 14:  reflect off. So these are, these are problems where if you were
Speaker 14:  FDA regulated they would be less of a problem because before it could ever
Speaker 14:  go to market, you'd have to prove that you are
Speaker 14:  clinically like clinical grade accurate. Whereas, you know, most of the
Speaker 14:  consumer products out there that claim to do SPO two, they don't have to
Speaker 14:  do that. I've tested a bunch of products and you can read my
Speaker 14:  reviews where they say I have an SPO two level
Speaker 14:  of 83%. If you have an SPO two level of 83%,
Speaker 14:  you best be in an ambulance on your way to the hospital that is
Speaker 14:  below what the, what like is acceptable or her people with copti. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  So it's, it's just like, like this, this device
Speaker 2:  Call 9 1 1
Speaker 14:  And they get away with it because they say we're a wellness device, we're
Speaker 14:  not a medical device. So you just like, I guess what I'm getting at is like
Speaker 14:  you're gonna see the lines blurring between what is and what isn't a medical
Speaker 14:  device, which means the FDA is gonna have to, you know, like put on their
Speaker 14:  big boy pants, not that they aren't on already, but even bigger big boy
Speaker 14:  pants and just go like, okay we kind of have to
Speaker 14:  sort out the mess that is the consumer health tech product
Speaker 14:  world because it's, it's a mess. It's a real mess. Like I gotta tell you.
Speaker 2:  Do you think they're going to, I mean they kind of have to with the hearing
Speaker 2:  aids cuz they opened this can of words. So they're kind of
Speaker 2:  stuck with hearing
Speaker 14:  Aids, they're stuck with hearing aids. The, they brought this upon themselves.
Speaker 14:  They have to do that. But I think you're gonna start to see it more and
Speaker 14:  more often. Like Apple was a really good example when they brought
Speaker 14:  out EKGs, right? Right. When they brought out EKGs on the series four, it
Speaker 14:  had to go through the FDA de novo clearance process
Speaker 14:  and basically they had to do that because they were having some
Speaker 14:  sort of diagnostic capability. It's not really diagnosing, but it's
Speaker 14:  saying, Hey you might have AFib, you should go see a doctor.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And it even says when you go and run one, it's like this is
Speaker 2:  not the same thing as going to the doctors. If you feel bad, call 9 1
Speaker 2:  1, don't just check in on your
Speaker 14:  Watch. Yeah. Like there's a lot of like medical descriptions down
Speaker 14:  there, but you know, it does have some sort of a
Speaker 14:  detection capability. Right? Yeah. So the thing with SPO two sensors
Speaker 14:  and why you see all these SPO two sensors, even though functionally they
Speaker 14:  don't do JAK right now at least is, you know, Fitbit
Speaker 14:  has been doing this for a really long time, but they're trying to detect
Speaker 14:  sleep apnea. Yeah. Using your blood oxygen. Now
Speaker 14:  if they were to say that they could detect sleep apnea while the FDA would
Speaker 14:  have to get involved and what they would like to do is for someone
Speaker 14:  else to figure it out and go through the process so then they can ride
Speaker 14:  those coattails basically. Right. And then, you
Speaker 14:  know, have this thing out there. So they have the sensors on there just
Speaker 14:  hoping that someone else is gonna do the dirty work. And I see a lot of
Speaker 14:  that of just these companies going around putting the sensors in for future
Speaker 14:  proofing and then hoping someone else does the dirty work to get the
Speaker 14:  clearance. Because once one, one person gets it cleared, the rest of them
Speaker 14:  will follow. So there, there's a lot of that going on. Just the
Speaker 14:  FDA just sits there and it's, it's very like, I wanna emphasize that it's
Speaker 14:  very good that the FDA does this because, you know, I
Speaker 14:  think the next frontier of wearables is going to be non-invasive
Speaker 14:  blood glucose monitoring. Right. Which will be so
Speaker 14:  great for diabetics, but that's life or death. You
Speaker 14:  cannot f that up. Yeah. You, you cannot screw up someone's blood
Speaker 14:  sugar levels. You
Speaker 2:  Will, you'll kill someone, you
Speaker 14:  Will kill someone, you will be sued. You need the F D A to regulate
Speaker 14:  the hell out of that. And and the same goes for blood pressure. Which was
Speaker 14:  another thing at CES with valent cell, which, you know, I love catching
Speaker 14:  up with valent cell every year cuz nobody knows
Speaker 2:  They, they did the finger one, right?
Speaker 14:  Like I've been talking to Val and Cell for the last five, six years at every
Speaker 14:  CS just going, Hey guys, what's up? Because they make optical sensor
Speaker 14:  tech that goes into a lot of wearables that you may already have
Speaker 14:  like jabs, bows, lg, like their tech isn't a lot of stuff.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. But you've never heard of them cuz they're a B2B company. But you
Speaker 14:  know, this year they're like, we're gonna make our own thing because the
Speaker 14:  gosh dang FDA won't approve our tech unless it's in a commercial
Speaker 14:  product. And we tried to get other people to make it and they wouldn't.
Speaker 14:  So now we're here and we have to make this
Speaker 14:  tech ourselves because this is just the state of things
Speaker 14:  and it's, it's really cool tech. It is a fingertip blood
Speaker 14:  pressure monitor that looks like one of those fingertip pulse
Speaker 14:  oximeters. Right. And you know, it, it's, it's supposedly will be able to
Speaker 14:  take an accurate blood pressure reading without you having to use a cough
Speaker 14:  and without you having to calibrate anything. So that would be like, you
Speaker 14:  know, oh, huge to have in like the consumer world that would, that would
Speaker 14:  just change hypertension treatment. It, it's, it's like
Speaker 14:  mind staggeringly amazing what that could do if
Speaker 14:  it gets FDA clearance. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I mean as, as somebody who has blood pressure issues, I, you know, if
Speaker 2:  I wanna take my blood pressure, I have to like make sure my arm is bare.
Speaker 2:  Because if you take it over a sweater, you'll look like you're dying and
Speaker 2:  then you'll have panic and talk to your doctor who will say no, take your
Speaker 2:  shirt off for it. Like reveal your, your, your arm. And so
Speaker 2:  it seems like a really, really cool thing. But also I was, it seemed like
Speaker 2:  it was also still kind of not accurate just from the reports we were getting
Speaker 2:  out of ces.
Speaker 14:  I mean, you are on a show floor, so there's gonna be
Speaker 14:  a degree of whatevers, but if they pass
Speaker 14:  FDA clearance, that's gonna assure a degree of accuracy. You know, so like,
Speaker 14:  if they get FDA clearance, then you can be like, oh, well maybe that was
Speaker 14:  just because it was on the show floor, it was a prototype. You, you know,
Speaker 14:  it's, it's hard to really gauge what the accuracy is gonna be in
Speaker 14:  like a CS type setting. But, you know, it's, it's, it's
Speaker 14:  like huge. It's innovative tech. It's stuff that we should be pursuing.
Speaker 14:  But you know, companies look at that and they go like, ah, Jesus Christ,
Speaker 14:  I don't got the time. I don't got the
Speaker 2:  Time for this, the time, the money.
Speaker 14:  Hopefully someone else will do it. It's expensive. Yeah. It's so much
Speaker 14:  paperwork involved. It's, it's, and you know, you want that, you want to
Speaker 14:  be safe, you want to not die. Like whenever Elon
Speaker 14:  Musk, if he ever actually does Neuralink, I want the FDA
Speaker 14:  involved like,
Speaker 2:  Oh, you, you don't wanna put a chip in your brain without FDA
Speaker 2:  approval that it won't kill you. Like it's killed mini, mini monkeys shocky.
Speaker 14:  I want documentation to be there that this is like safe for
Speaker 14:  the marketplace. Yeah. I don't wanna have to like, like, and that's, that's
Speaker 14:  the really frustrating thing about my beat because so much of it conceptually
Speaker 14:  is really cool and we have the technology, but the willing, and this
Speaker 14:  is capitalism, like the willingness of companies to invest in
Speaker 14:  this technology versus the effort that's gonna go in
Speaker 14:  to getting through the FDA regulation process is nil. It's
Speaker 14:  just nothing. It's, they would rather play in the wellness
Speaker 14:  space cuz the FDA don't care if you wanna log every night of
Speaker 14:  sleep from now until you die. They're cool with that. Cuz that's just for
Speaker 14:  you. That's yeah, that's for your knowledge. That's not like
Speaker 14:  substantially, if your sleep tracking is inaccurate to a degree, you're
Speaker 14:  not gonna die from that reasonably speaking. You're not gonna die from that.
Speaker 14:  You're just gonna be like, oh my God, it's inaccurate. Which, you know,
Speaker 14:  it's all inaccurate anyway, so yeah. Now, now you know why, like when
Speaker 14:  my editors come to the FDA articles, they're just like, oh
Speaker 14:  God,
Speaker 2:  Okay. You have to brace yourself whenever, whenever I'm about to edit one
Speaker 2:  of your stories and it's got f d in it. I'm like, okay, I have to like, put
Speaker 2:  on my, like, I have to think really hard. It's like reading, it's
Speaker 2:  like editing anything, anything legal. But those f d ones are rough.
Speaker 14:  They're, they're super rough.
Speaker 2:  Wonderful copy though. The copy is beautiful. Thinking about F D
Speaker 2:  A regulations. Terrible. Well,
Speaker 2:  Victoria, thank you so much. This has been a fantastic, very
Speaker 2:  interesting conversation. Maybe you wanna read more. The story is called
Speaker 2:  The Regulatory Maze behind Health Tech Vaporware. It's super, super good.
Speaker 2:  I highly recommend everybody go check it out. It's there on the
Speaker 2:  verge.com com. Thank you so much.
Speaker 14:  Thank you. And I, and I swear the story's more articulate than me.
Speaker 2:  You were wonderful. Okay, that's it for the Verge Cast today. Thank you
Speaker 2:  for listening. As always. There's a ton more coverage on everything we talked
Speaker 2:  about on the verge.com. If you have thoughts, feedbacks feelings, you can
Speaker 2:  always email vergecast@theverge.com and you have questions.
Speaker 2:  Call the hotline. Eight six six Verge 11, send us all your big
Speaker 2:  thoughts and questions about all things tech. This show is produced by Andrew
Speaker 2:  Marino and Liam James Noy. Donovan is our executive producer, and Brooke
Speaker 2:  Mentors is our editorial director of Audio. The Vergecast is a Verge production
Speaker 2:  and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Nelia will be back on Friday to
Speaker 2:  chat with more of the Verge crew about whatever is happening this week. Until
Speaker 2:  then, I'll see you later. Rock and roll.