# Transcript
ID: 5394687b-c682-4e6c-801b-2e1a5ebeb03f
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Samsung fans and video apps: they’re everywhere
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4657793484897012212/7214165218799215946/s93290-US-4876s-1691151165.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss YouTube adding a slew of new TikTok-like features to Shorts, Elon Musk's extravagant 'X' sign, and much more.
We also go through this week's emails. The Samsung fans have spoken.
Speaker 3:  Hello and welcome to Vercast the flagship podcast of Linux on the
Speaker 3:  desktop. It's great. It's gonna happen this year. Here's a
Speaker 3:  stat for you.
Speaker 4:  This is the
Speaker 3:  Year Linux Gamers now outnumber Matt gamers on Steam because
Speaker 5:  Of Steam Deck.
Speaker 4:  That is a stat You're not wrong. That is a stat. It's a
Speaker 3:  Stat and it is because of the steam deck, which is technically not a
Speaker 3:  desktop. We were so close everybody. We're gonna do it next
Speaker 3:  year. It's the flagship podcast of Linnux on the desktop. Hello everybody.
Speaker 3:  I'm your friend Neli. That was David Pierce. Hey David. Hi.
Speaker 4:  I have returned from vacation. I have many new hot takes to share.
Speaker 3:  I'm very excited And it's Alex Cranz. You heard going? It's because of the
Speaker 3:  steam deck. Hey Alex. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I, I use the Steam deck and a Mac to game. I do not use Windows to Game.
Speaker 5:  I'm sorry. That
Speaker 3:  Is an unholy combination. What are you doing?
Speaker 5:  It's great. It's like I get everything I need. I get my Crusader Kings on
Speaker 5:  Mac. I get everything else on Steam Deck. It's fine.
Speaker 4:  Alex refuses to play any game the way it was intended. That's, that's really
Speaker 4:  Alex's thing.
Speaker 5:  It works great.
Speaker 3:  My TikTok feed is entirely tears of the Kingdom videos. That's all it
Speaker 3:  is. And every now again, so, and mostly it's like
Speaker 3:  incredible builds. Like that's like the z i engineering task force video.
Speaker 3:  Like it's so cool. Amazing. Yes. And then every now and again I get the people
Speaker 3:  who are running it emulated on a PC and they're doing mods
Speaker 3:  where everyone's a little too sexy. Yeah. And it's
Speaker 3:  just the, it's like that in general. I'm, you know, pro
Speaker 3:  modding, pro emulation, pro run whatever code you want, wherever you want
Speaker 3:  anti D R M. And then I see those videos and I'm like, all these
Speaker 3:  people should be in jail. Like I don't know how to get too sexy. Too sexy,
Speaker 3:  too sexy. Don't like it. I don't need to see a sexy link.
Speaker 3:  He's always sexy. What are you talking about? He's inherently sexy.
Speaker 3:  Alright, here's what we're gonna do this week. It's a relatively slow
Speaker 3:  Newsweek, but we have been getting just
Speaker 3:  a ton of incredible reader emails lately,
Speaker 3:  which are super fun. So we're gonna do a lightning
Speaker 3:  round, then read a bunch of emails and then do a lightning
Speaker 3:  round. We'll see how that goes. It's the first time we've tried it on the
Speaker 3:  show. I think it's gonna be fun. But before we do that, it is necessary
Speaker 3:  to acknowledge the existence of one Elon
Speaker 3:  Musk who
Speaker 3:  just continues to dominate the news cycle. I'll let you in on some Vergecast
Speaker 3:  inside baseball. We do the show and we like look at what
Speaker 3:  stories are the most popular on our site to be like, this is what people
Speaker 3:  are interested in. And you people will not stop clicking on the Elon
Speaker 3:  stories.
Speaker 4:  Yep.
Speaker 3:  But we are tired. So to split the difference, here's what we're doing. My
Speaker 3:  friend David Pierce is gonna give you the fastest
Speaker 3:  Elon roundup in sports. And I. Believe we have some
Speaker 3:  music. Andrew, can you run the music? This is an incredibly
Speaker 4:  Rude thing to do to
Speaker 3:  Me in my first week back. By the way,
Speaker 4:  Like David, talk as fast as you can for two minutes about Elon Musk.
Speaker 3:  Ready? Go. Go. And to be
Speaker 3:  clear, I'm forcing David to do this against his will. The
Speaker 3:  face that he made at me when I suggested he do this
Speaker 3:  came through the internet. Imagine the amount of engineering and
Speaker 3:  labor and invention and discovery that was required
Speaker 3:  for David's frown to travel hundreds of thousands of
Speaker 3:  miles through fiber optic cables at the speed of light. And then hit me in
Speaker 3:  the face.
Speaker 4:  Can't buy that for $44 billion.
Speaker 3:  I can't do it. It's very important.
Speaker 3:  Anyhow, I'm still making David do it 'cause we we, a bunch of stuff happened.
Speaker 3:  Just none of it's very important. But we should acknowledge it because we
Speaker 3:  know that you, the listeners, even though you sent us email telling us not
Speaker 3:  to do it, you keep reading the stories. But we're gonna make a game a bit.
Speaker 3:  See if we can get through it. Andrew, I believe we have some
Speaker 3:  music.
Speaker 3:  You have to start talking.
Speaker 4:  Here is everything you need to know about Elon Musk this week. Twitter is
Speaker 4:  now X and it's actually called X in the app store. Even though it's still
Speaker 4:  not called X. A lot of places there's X Pro, but it's just tweet deck. Twitter
Speaker 4:  is x, X is Twitter. No one knows where it actually is. There was an X
Speaker 4:  sign on the old Twitter headquarters, which is now the X headquarters. It
Speaker 4:  blinded everybody. It was sandbags, it was dangerous. Now it's gone. The
Speaker 4:  company is now trying to get financial companies like Robinhood and maybe
Speaker 4:  other kinds of stock trading platforms to bring their content and even do
Speaker 4:  stock trading on X but won't pay anybody to do it and actually wants
Speaker 4:  the other companies to pay to do it. They're not gonna do it. So that's not
Speaker 4:  going anywhere. Twitter slash X is suing a group called the Center
Speaker 4:  for Countering Digital Hate Over claims that it tried to drive away advertisers
Speaker 4:  by basically acknowledging that bad things happen on the platform and that
Speaker 4:  people do bad things on the platform. That's not gonna work. And then
Speaker 4:  lastly, Twitter, sorry, X was going to be dark mode only,
Speaker 4:  but now it's not going to be dark mode only because the thing you learn about
Speaker 4:  Elon Musk when you leave for a week is that nothing actually
Speaker 4:  happens. A thing just happens and then UN happens a few days later. And
Speaker 4:  that's the story of Elon Musk.
Speaker 3:  Let's let the solo wrap
Speaker 3:  up.
Speaker 5:  I didn't know the music went so long.
Speaker 3:  It's so good. That was press. That was very good. It defeated
Speaker 4:  The music, the
Speaker 3:  Royalty free guitar, solo music, absolutely choice.
Speaker 3:  This is beautiful. Second only to the animated Transformers movie, which
Speaker 3:  if you listen to it, the, from the eighties I watched it again as an
Speaker 3:  adult and having only ever watched it as a child, that movie is one long
Speaker 3:  guitar solo. Like it just never stops. It breaks into
Speaker 3:  other songs. But then the songs that and the
Speaker 3:  solo continues. I'm just saying we should bring that back. Is
Speaker 5:  It a musical? Does it count as, it counts as a musical, right? If it's just
Speaker 5:  one long guitar solo,
Speaker 3:  I guess it's, it's a very confusing movie and also really heartbreaking in,
Speaker 3:  in various ways. Transformers, everybody, that's the verse cast. Okay.
Speaker 3:  Lightning round one. So lots of little news this week.
Speaker 3:  Lots of glimmers of big ideas, but ultimately small news.
Speaker 3:  David kick us off.
Speaker 4:  Okay, I have two because I was gone for a week, so I think I get to have
Speaker 4:  two. That's fair. My first is a discovery that I made while I was on vacation
Speaker 4:  and feel obligated to come back and tell you about, which is that actually
Speaker 4:  CarPlay is very bad. And what, no, David.
Speaker 4:  No,
Speaker 3:  This is, yeah,
Speaker 4:  This I, I regret that I have come to this place. This is
Speaker 4:  not, this is not a life I wanted to lead, but I,
Speaker 4:  I updated my phone at one point over the week and then it just spent a
Speaker 4:  day and a half deciding not to connect to CarPlay and when it
Speaker 4:  did, it would crash and then it would say, David, would you like to
Speaker 4:  start a thing in Google Maps? And I would say Yes, please Google Maps, that
Speaker 4:  sounds terrific. And it would just do nothing. And it would just
Speaker 4:  say I was sitting at an intersection when I had driven many miles
Speaker 4:  away from that in intersection and then one day for absolutely
Speaker 4:  no reason, it just started to work again and has worked perfectly ever since.
Speaker 4:  So now I've reached a point where like I wish it had been full broken
Speaker 4:  because then at least I would understand what was going on. Yeah, And. I
Speaker 4:  just CarPlay sucks. The thing that is still true is that everything else
Speaker 4:  is still worse. So CarPlay is still the best available option as
Speaker 4:  far as I can tell. I actually think Android Auto is better than CarPlay.
Speaker 4:  My wife is a pixel owner. And I mostly use an iPhone. So we switch back and
Speaker 4:  forth some and the, the Android auto experience was substantially better
Speaker 4:  in most cases. But they're all bad. Yeah, but everything else is worse.
Speaker 3:  It's funny 'cause they're converging. Okay. Oh god. All right. So I have
Speaker 3:  data to back this up. No. So the first piece of
Speaker 3:  data is that I was right to begin with. I hate this and now David agrees
Speaker 3:  with me.
Speaker 4:  These are the rules. CarPlay is now officially bad. I'm really sorry.
Speaker 5:  It's the worst.
Speaker 3:  Here's a piece of news from last week. According to JD
Speaker 3:  Power's automotive performance, execution and layout or
Speaker 3:  appeal study overall satisfaction with car
Speaker 3:  owners is down a decrease of two points from a year ago in three points
Speaker 3:  lower than 2021. First time in 28 years of the
Speaker 3:  study that there's a consecutive year over year decline in owner
Speaker 3:  satisfaction. And it is because of the infotainment systems.
Speaker 3:  Now most people are mad at the actual infotainment systems in their cars.
Speaker 3:  Makes sense. But the finickiness of wireless
Speaker 3:  CarPlay in particular and wireless Android Android Auto Yep. Is absolutely
Speaker 3:  contributing to this. And there is an increase
Speaker 3:  in the Google powered native infotainment systems that some people are shipping
Speaker 3:  like Volvo and others. So cars that have Android Automotive or a A
Speaker 3:  O S score higher in the infotainment categories, then those with no
Speaker 3:  A A O S whatsoever. Okay. But if you have that without Google
Speaker 3:  Play Services, you go down. Yeah. So if you have built
Speaker 3:  in Google Maps, basically people are happy. Yeah. 'cause then they can listen,
Speaker 3:  they can Stream Bluetooth over their phones and look at Google Maps, which
Speaker 3:  is all anybody wants to do. Correct. Right in the car. No one's trying to
Speaker 3:  watch a TikTok in a Mercedes. I don't know why they keep doing it. If you
Speaker 3:  go watch the videos of people trying to scroll TikTok in Mercedes, you're
Speaker 3:  like, that is the slowest shittiest TikTok experience I've ever seen in my
Speaker 3:  entire life. And
Speaker 5:  Also it's like unsafe. Probably shouldn't scroll
Speaker 5:  TikTok while driving. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Also don't do that. Yeah. Is is a good, yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like I definitely got yelled at for watching Gilmore Girls while driving
Speaker 5:  home from college one year and it was great. I had a
Speaker 5:  wonderful time, but I was told I wasn't
Speaker 3:  Like in the car while you were driving. Yeah, I, Rory couldn't wait.
Speaker 5:  She could not, I had to be up early. I was doing like a 12 hour
Speaker 5:  drive in a day. I needed company.
Speaker 3:  This is some real Texas shit. And this road is going to be perfectly straight
Speaker 3:  for 600 miles. Pretty
Speaker 5:  Much
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna do it. The speed limit is 230 miles an
Speaker 3:  hour and I'm gonna watch Gilmore Girls the entire time.
Speaker 5:  Wonderful. No regrets. But yeah, I wouldn't probably do it
Speaker 5:  now most likely. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Only now you can, you know, hit self-driving watch on the center cluster.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. All I'm saying is there's data, actual data, not just me saying it,
Speaker 3:  that that suggests that making the center
Speaker 3:  stack of your car more computer is
Speaker 3:  bad. Yes.
Speaker 5:  I think that's right.
Speaker 3:  Wireless CarPlay is like a maximally computer idea.
Speaker 3:  Yes. Like it's finicky and it doesn't connect and you're trying to meet and
Speaker 3:  you're basically adding a second display to a mobile computer. Like
Speaker 3:  ugh, just bolt the phone to the air vent like God
Speaker 3:  intended open Google Maps and Stream Bluetooth music to the head unit. You'll
Speaker 3:  be fine. You get two screens instead of one. I'm just gonna keep putting
Speaker 3:  that up. But you
Speaker 5:  Can just plug it in and have CarPlay, And, I. I did that this week. I got
Speaker 5:  my MagSafe like little controller thing. I stuck it in the air
Speaker 5:  vent. It didn't flip down too much. And I had like my big
Speaker 5:  screen and my little screen and one was for like text
Speaker 5:  messages that I tried not to look at. And the other one
Speaker 5:  found
Speaker 4:  Out, do we need to start disclaiming? Like no one listened to Alex when she
Speaker 4:  describes how she lives her life because it will, it will end in disaster
Speaker 4:  for you.
Speaker 3:  Alex is like, here's what I did. I sparked my laser bong. I started
Speaker 3:  texting while I was driving. But CarPlay was great. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  We're all
Speaker 5:  good
Speaker 5:  anyway. CarPlay is great.
Speaker 3:  All right. In normal circumstance, I would say we should retake the part
Speaker 3:  where Alex admitted to texting and driving. I didn't text, but here I think
Speaker 3:  it's an important cautionary tale.
Speaker 5:  Don't don't text and drive guys. I looked at it And, I went, oh that's convenient.
Speaker 5:  Ooh, let's not look at that. And then I just kept driving.
Speaker 4:  That's good. Good for you. We're all really proud of you. Alex. That's, that's
Speaker 4:  called personal growth. Thank you.
Speaker 3:  All right. CarPlay sucks. Unless you're Alex, in which case you should throw
Speaker 3:  your phone out the window. And. I. Have someone else use CarPlay.
Speaker 4:  But I just wanna say before I get to my actual lightning round thing, Andy
Speaker 4:  Hawkins wrote about that JD Power thing you were just talking about. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And his headline was just people are getting fed up with all the useless
Speaker 4:  tech in their cars. And, I just read that headline and just like started
Speaker 4:  blowing kisses at my computer. Like it's just Yes. Like what a, what a perfect
Speaker 4:  description of A this study and B,
Speaker 4:  what is happening in the world. I enjoy that very much and thank you Andy
Speaker 4:  for doing that for me.
Speaker 3:  Actually the best part of his story is that he, he notes that happiness with
Speaker 3:  the exterior styling of cars is going down as well because
Speaker 3:  cars look weird now and that's beautiful.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's, it's bad times for cars right now. It's
Speaker 5:  Boring and ugly.
Speaker 4:  Like Neli, you keep talking about like the dongle stuff and we're sort of
Speaker 4:  caught in this awkward middle ground. We're we're caught in the awkward middle
Speaker 4:  ground in like every way imaginable with cars. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  The only two ideas we have for cars are make it look like the sixties or
Speaker 3:  angry robots. The
Speaker 4:  Future. Yeah. It's not great but
Speaker 4:  okay, my actual lightning round thing is this new
Speaker 4:  YouTube announcement this week that they're adding a bunch of new features
Speaker 4:  to Shorts. And the quickest way I can describe them is that they're just
Speaker 4:  TikTok things. So now you can see vertical live
Speaker 4:  previews of videos in Shorts. So when you're scrolling through and in addition
Speaker 4:  to just seeing Shorts, you'll see live stuff. There's a new tool where you
Speaker 4:  can actually like crop and zoom on a regular horizontal
Speaker 4:  YouTube video and use it as a short, which I actually think is very clever
Speaker 4:  and is one of the things that makes YouTube unique is that there's this whole
Speaker 4:  other giant library of stuff and then there's a tool that they call
Speaker 4:  collab, which is just a straight complete rip of duet on TikTok
Speaker 4:  And I think it's very funny that they didn't just call it duet. Like we're
Speaker 4:  all cool with stories being the thing that everybody does, but YouTube is
Speaker 4:  like collab, not like duet at all. Totally different.
Speaker 4:  But I just, we, we've talked about this a bunch on this show, but it's like
Speaker 4:  there is just only one app anymore. Yeah. It's just called like
Speaker 4:  video in all caps. And it's TikTok, it's
Speaker 4:  reels, it's YouTube, Shorts. These, all these things are the same
Speaker 4:  thing and it's kind of, it's just making me tired.
Speaker 4:  Now
Speaker 5:  Do you ever find yourself accidentally scrolling the wrong one and not realizing
Speaker 5:  it for more than 30 seconds? Or
Speaker 5:  is that just me,
Speaker 4:  The thing that happens to me frequently is I'll go onto
Speaker 4:  TikTok, scroll a bunch, be like, why don't I care about any of these
Speaker 4:  videos and then realize I'm actually on Instagram. That's me,
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 4:  Me. This is a thing that has happened to me several times from like usually
Speaker 4:  like I kind of know what my TikTok is gonna be. It morphs over time, but
Speaker 4:  I have a rough sense of what I'm gonna get from TikTok most of the time.
Speaker 4:  And then I go on Instagram and it's just like, here's people playing Spikeball
Speaker 4:  and like random Russian soccer players
Speaker 4:  that you've never heard of and I'm just And I. I like spend three minutes.
Speaker 4:  I'm like, this is boring. And then I'm like, oh, I'm on Instagram. Like this
Speaker 4:  is where I'm at.
Speaker 5:  It's like when I see like three videos in a row of somebody just cutting
Speaker 5:  sand, I'm like, oh, I think I'm on Instagram.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 3:  Or it's, it's particular if you see the the trends from three months
Speaker 3:  ago. Yeah. Yeah. Oh God. That's the real tell on Instagram. But here's the
Speaker 3:  thing about Instagram, which is fascinating. Meta just had earnings. They
Speaker 3:  were boring. Meta's doing great, fine. They basically solved the Apple
Speaker 3:  ad tracking transparency issue with ai. So they're, they're making a lot
Speaker 3:  of money. They also revealed that Reels is making money
Speaker 3:  hand over fist now and is on track to be a bigger
Speaker 3:  business than TikTok, which is wild and kind
Speaker 3:  of a testament to Meta's overall scale and expertise in
Speaker 3:  monetizing things.
Speaker 4:  Yet another reminder that Meta is the only company that is actually good
Speaker 4:  at this. Like it's, it's the thing I've been saying about threads all along.
Speaker 4:  Like everybody can have the same idea and Meta will do it better over
Speaker 4:  time, at least from a financial perspective it just keeps being true
Speaker 4:  and it's, it's truly wild. Like Reels is a objectively worse
Speaker 4:  product than TikTok. Like I don't think there's anybody who would be like,
Speaker 4:  I prefer reels to TikTok as a like user consumer
Speaker 4:  experience, but I'm not at all surprised that it's gonna end
Speaker 4:  up being the bigger business.
Speaker 3:  So here's the numbers. Reel's annual revenue run rate has jumped to
Speaker 3:  $10 billion a year. Wow. Up from 3 billion last fall and a billion last
Speaker 3:  summer. That's from Zuckerberg during his analyst call that means reel's
Speaker 3:  about the size of TikTok business. Last year when TikTok pulled in 9.9 billion
Speaker 3:  and we're allowed to add revenue and reel's about to grow, that's this Reuters
Speaker 3:  story that will like, that's crazy, right? They went from not having this
Speaker 3:  product to being deeply threatened by it to running a bigger and more
Speaker 3:  effective business with it. And, and maybe this is
Speaker 3:  like cautionary tale for threads. This is kind of
Speaker 3:  the meta problem now. They run huge businesses
Speaker 3:  with no cultural relevance. I mean, right? That's what we were talking, that's
Speaker 3:  what you're talking about with reels. You open reels, you like scroll through
Speaker 3:  it, like this isn't what I want. Yep. And you jump to TikTok, which is far
Speaker 3:  more relevant, but they are better at the business. I
Speaker 5:  Think it's, it is culturally relevant and the fact that
Speaker 5:  like all of my online friends send me TikTok, all
Speaker 5:  my normal friends, offline friends, whatever you wanna call 'em, you know
Speaker 5:  what I'm talking about Everybody listening, you've got both sides. They all
Speaker 5:  send me reels. Like my best friend from college, she sends me reels
Speaker 5:  about cowboy girls. Yeah. My, my best friend like that I worked with at
Speaker 5:  my last company, she sends me tos and it's
Speaker 5:  just, yeah, I like And that's a smaller group. Those people that are
Speaker 5:  really online like us, we're a much smaller part of the population.
Speaker 5:  And so the stuff that actually goes out to people and changes the culture
Speaker 5:  is happening on reels even though it's being incubated and and developed
Speaker 5:  on TikTok.
Speaker 4:  Although I think the younger you get the less That's true. That's, and this
Speaker 4:  is the thing that Meta continues to trade on, right? Is that like whenever
Speaker 4:  I come on this show or write about Facebook and say basically nobody's
Speaker 4:  on Facebook, nobody cares. I get a bunch of people responding who are like,
Speaker 4:  no, actually the thing is everybody's on Facebook, they're just old and
Speaker 4:  that's true. Yeah. And there's a lot of money in those people. But the
Speaker 4:  like as you scale down the age group, like truly nobody is on
Speaker 4:  Facebook. And at least in the sort of
Speaker 4:  limited access I have to the world of 16 year olds, like
Speaker 4:  they're all on Snapchat and they're all on TikTok and they're all kind of
Speaker 4:  on Instagram and that's it. Like that is the extent of it. What's
Speaker 3:  Fascinating about this conversation is it, it was prompted by you discussing
Speaker 3:  new features being added to YouTube, which is
Speaker 3:  the most stable scaled social platform to exist.
Speaker 3:  It's still doing the thing. It does except it's also trying to do the new
Speaker 3:  thing.
Speaker 5:  Shorts alarms me every time I click on it, like I get confused and
Speaker 5:  then have to like quit the app. 'cause I don't know where I am and how to
Speaker 5:  get away from it. Is am I the only one?
Speaker 3:  Do you, is it like a feeling like I'm training the wrong algorithm?
Speaker 5:  It's partially that and partially just like the video's big and I'm
Speaker 5:  like, the video's not supposed to be big here. It's supposed to be the other
Speaker 5:  way. What's happening? I don't like it. I just get very old as
Speaker 5:  soon as
Speaker 4:  I, who are these kids and what are they? Why are they eating hot wings? you
Speaker 4:  know? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I just to turn immediately turn 80. But
Speaker 4:  This is why, to your point, Eli, this is why YouTube has been so fascinating
Speaker 4:  to me for so long. Because it is I think the
Speaker 4:  single most like sprawling ambitious platform
Speaker 4:  on the internet, right? Like YouTube wants to be, it wants to eat
Speaker 4:  Hollywood, it wants to eat the podcasting business, it wants to eat the music
Speaker 4:  business, it wants to eat the creator business, it wants to eat the social
Speaker 4:  business. Like YouTube literally wants to be the size of the
Speaker 4:  like creative entertainment internet and
Speaker 4:  it's kind of working and it's really, really fascinating to watch that
Speaker 4:  happen. I think Shorts by all accounts seems to be
Speaker 4:  growing really fast and doing really well, but in the way that you would
Speaker 4:  expect it to because it's attached to YouTube. Like I don't know that it
Speaker 4:  has hit sort of bigger than YouTube escape velocity in the way that like
Speaker 4:  Facebook marketplace is very successful because it's on Facebook but is not
Speaker 4:  sort of successful on its own. Yeah. I think that's kind of what Shortz is
Speaker 4:  doing. But then even just this week,
Speaker 4:  YouTube is getting some of Google's generative AI stuff to
Speaker 4:  get summaries of videos that are in the like in search results and
Speaker 4:  in the video pages so you can see what you're getting. They're adding YouTube
Speaker 4:  videos to the SS g E search, generative experience AI stuff
Speaker 4:  like YouTube is everything to everyone at all
Speaker 4:  times. And then just kind of over here on the side, they're just ruthlessly
Speaker 4:  copying TikTok and paying creators better. And it's just sort of nuts to
Speaker 4:  watch all of that happen simultaneously. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  YouTube and Google generally are in this very odd moment
Speaker 3:  where they, all of their incentives have been about
Speaker 3:  padding things out for so long that now all the
Speaker 3:  results are too long. And like honestly what TikTok
Speaker 3:  offers you as a search customer is like, it'll just
Speaker 3:  tell you the answer like quickly in a way that a
Speaker 3:  webpage that's ss e o optimized or a YouTube video that's
Speaker 3:  padded out to get two minerals, like won't, I'll give you one very stupid
Speaker 3:  example. We bought a jar of Chili Crisp and the lid is too
Speaker 3:  tight. And I was like, what? What? How do you do the thing? you know like
Speaker 3:  is it cold water? Is it hot water? And I had that moment of like, I'm gonna
Speaker 3:  ask a search engine for this. And we picked TikTok and now
Speaker 3:  fully every other video I watch is about opening jars because TikTok algorithm
Speaker 3:  is stupid. But but it like, you know, just a p like
Speaker 3:  someone just like told me the answer in like four seconds. Yeah, yeah. Whereas
Speaker 3:  like I've had watched a 10 minute YouTube video, I would've killed myself.
Speaker 3:  Like you
Speaker 4:  Would've had to watch someone like start the video outside and then like
Speaker 4:  walk into their house and then tell you the history of jars. Exactly. And
Speaker 4:  yeah,
Speaker 3:  Right. Or you like search the regular Google search engine and you're like,
Speaker 3:  okay, here's 40,000 words about jars. Right? And it's
Speaker 3:  like every other heading is a question about jars. Like what are jars made
Speaker 3:  of? And it's like, I just like, this is a very simple question.
Speaker 3:  Like is it hot water or cold water? The answer by the way is hot water and
Speaker 3:  it still didn't work. It doesn't matter. We're gonna get that jar up in Sunday.
Speaker 3:  You
Speaker 5:  Get a butter knife and you jam it under under the lid
Speaker 3:  Everything you say. So, so
Speaker 5:  I mean ignore a bandaid on my finger. That's a
Speaker 3:  Different race. Here's what you do. You start texting and driving while us
Speaker 3:  trying to open a jar with a knife.
Speaker 5:  I still got my hands, my fingers. It's fine.
Speaker 4:  You just put it in the oven, turn it all the way up, see what happens. It's
Speaker 4:  gonna be fine.
Speaker 3:  All I'm saying
Speaker 3:  is turn
Speaker 3:  on all the gas, all your ranges light and walk
Speaker 3:  around with a match.
Speaker 5:  The Chris the chili will be
Speaker 5:  Chris.
Speaker 3:  All I'm saying is it's kind of interesting to think of the internet as a
Speaker 3:  pendulum between long things and short things and like we're, we've just
Speaker 3:  been like YouTube originally started with Charlie bit my finger, right?
Speaker 3:  Like extremely short stupid videos and a pendulum
Speaker 3:  has swung to these like 10 minute videos and now that sort of tos and
Speaker 3:  reels and Shorts are swinging at pendulum back and basically only meta
Speaker 3:  has figured out how to build a scaled business against it. Yeah. It, it's
Speaker 3:  not to say tos $10 billion is not a scaled business, but you know,
Speaker 3:  TikTok rickety for a lot of reasons. Do we
Speaker 5:  Ever hit that middle point though, where it's just like
Speaker 3:  Middle videos?
Speaker 4:  I don't think so. I mean, I I can't think of a time we've been at that point,
Speaker 4:  right? Any I mean you can even look at it like Yeah, the, the streaming
Speaker 4:  has done that right? Everything got everything got bigger and huger and then
Speaker 4:  got smaller and became, you know, big, big TV shows and then we
Speaker 4:  got the limited maybe like the limited series is the perfect middle of
Speaker 4:  the actual like TV movie world and we need the equivalent of
Speaker 4:  that for
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Only that's the thing that's causing the writers.
Speaker 4:  Well yeah, there's that right? Like damn
Speaker 3:  It, there's no series, no syndication, there's no money in limited
Speaker 4:  Series. It turns out
Speaker 3:  Like that's a real problem. This is the worst lightning round of all time.
Speaker 3:  We've done two things. It's been 25.
Speaker 4:  I'm sorry, I'm done. That's it all. I have
Speaker 3:  Alex what's your, what's yours?
Speaker 5:  Okay, mine is, Sean has a really great review of the
Speaker 5:  LG. I'm gonna, I gotta look at this guys LG
Speaker 5:  27 g R 95
Speaker 5:  QE B
Speaker 3:  And when people hear that name it's sex.
Speaker 5:  You wanna go to Best Buy and ask for the LG 27 G R
Speaker 5:  95 QE
Speaker 5:  B It's great. Yeah. Yeah. It's a, it's a new 27
Speaker 5:  inch ole display and he's, he tested some of the other ones. There was an
Speaker 5:  ause one that has like kind of this pretty much the same panel but a
Speaker 5:  little bit different. Like how you control it is different. But
Speaker 5:  he, he really liked this one and feels like we're kind of hitting that point
Speaker 5:  where you can say, yeah I can go buy an OLED monitor instead
Speaker 5:  of a traditional monitor. And that's really exciting
Speaker 5:  because OLED is typically better but a lot of those growing pains OLED
Speaker 5:  have had are still there. It's got some issues like it's
Speaker 5:  local dimming you would think would be really, really good, right? 'cause
Speaker 5:  it's oled and so each pixel is controlled but the minute things start to
Speaker 5:  get bigger and bigger and wider and wider, it needs to start limiting that
Speaker 5:  so it doesn't blow out all those pixels and, and create burn and a lot of
Speaker 5:  other problems. And when it starts to do that, it gets really, really dim
Speaker 5:  and can just be super unpleasant to look at. It sounds
Speaker 5:  like they've, they've done a good job of of fixing that. It's still not perfect
Speaker 5:  but it's gotten a lot better. And so, I don't know, I have two of
Speaker 5:  the previous really good LG monitors on my, on my
Speaker 5:  desk. And I love them and now I have total fomo, And I wish I
Speaker 5:  had this oled even though it's got some issues, it just seems
Speaker 5:  cool.
Speaker 3:  This piece and another one we're gonna talk about, about three D file formats
Speaker 3:  are like the reason The Verge exists in my opinion. Yeah. Like you read this
Speaker 3:  piece, we, we talked last week about knowing people's bylines. You read this
Speaker 3:  piece, it's Sean Hollister just like Yes. Yes. All the way through. It's
Speaker 3:  great and the exasperation that comes through. Yeah because
Speaker 3:  what these ola panels when you use them as monitors do is
Speaker 3:  they, they dimm the entire panel when you have big fields of white
Speaker 3:  Right? Because they don't want to, as Alex is saying, you don't wanna, you
Speaker 3:  don't wanna blow out or burn in. So they dimm the entire
Speaker 3:  panel and Sean is like, the problem is all computer
Speaker 3:  interfaces are mostly white. so like he's like,
Speaker 3:  you can just feel his exasperation in this in this review.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And he, he talked about babying the screen to not have that
Speaker 4:  happen and not get burn in And I. So felt that like the thing
Speaker 4:  you have where you know the potential problem and every time
Speaker 4:  it does that sort of artificial dimm you can feel yourself getting closer
Speaker 4:  to it and so you start to like, you start to just move things around on your
Speaker 4:  computer just to change the pixels and it's like I just, this is, I am thinking
Speaker 4:  about this monitor a lot more than feels necessary.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. There's also a perfect Sean moment in the review where he
Speaker 3:  puts an image slider in and the image slider is just his desk setup
Speaker 3:  with the old monitor and the new OLED monitor. They look exactly the same
Speaker 3:  and he is just excited that it's like exactly the same. It's great. You should
Speaker 3:  just read it. It's great And it's a,
Speaker 5:  It's a really good piece. You're gonna like, you're gonna
Speaker 5:  get FOMO reading it 'cause you're gonna want it even though he like points
Speaker 5:  out every single flaw in it. Yeah. And I think it's should be like a call
Speaker 5:  to arm action for Windows and, and
Speaker 5:  Apple to like fix their shit.
Speaker 3:  We had another piece this week but Victoria's song about how smart watches
Speaker 3:  this year are super iterative and it's actually really interesting to, to
Speaker 3:  read those things together 'cause the iterative smartwatch is boring, right?
Speaker 3:  Right. Like here's some minor updates to the Samsung watches. We've made
Speaker 3:  the letters unsettlingly huge and added teeth to the displays
Speaker 3:  fine. We think the Apple watch is gonna be super iterative this
Speaker 3:  year. Fine. That's the boring iterative what Sean's
Speaker 3:  monitor piece is like this is the best kind of iterative.
Speaker 3:  Like you start with let's put an OLED TV on your desk and here's all the
Speaker 3:  problems and here's like the last step
Speaker 3:  before the next iteration when this idea is complete. Yeah. And this is almost
Speaker 3:  the most exciting version of a product, right? Like yeah if you're into
Speaker 3:  gadgets, this one right when you can clearly and
Speaker 3:  okay it's And I think Sean list, like fix these three things in
Speaker 3:  this category is ready. Like there's something really excited about that
Speaker 3:  version of the iterative process versus the sort of like end state of
Speaker 3:  phones that we appear to be in.
Speaker 5:  And it's nice to see it's happen kind of fast or feels fast to
Speaker 5:  me 'cause we were seeing our first Ola displays what, 20 15, 20
Speaker 5:  16? I think it was like the earliest ones and it didn't work because when
Speaker 5:  you shrink down big TV technology, it's actually really hard to shrink that
Speaker 5:  down into a monitor that makes sense close to your face.
Speaker 5:  That's why the two technologies aren't in lock sync at all
Speaker 5:  times. And it's, and they're starting to figure it out. They're starting
Speaker 5:  to invest in it and, and and really sort it out and people are
Speaker 5:  buying it, which is also good 'cause then the prices will hopefully go down
Speaker 5:  and we can all buy them.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. These are Sean's three things by the way. 100 nets of sustained
Speaker 3:  brightness, which is related to that dimming issue. A warranty
Speaker 3:  update because the warranty doesn't cover burning, which is and a
Speaker 3:  decent sale to your point Alex.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The hundred nets of extra brightness is gonna be like, that's gonna
Speaker 5:  be a real challenge 'cause that's, that's where OLED always falls is
Speaker 5:  is on brightness. It's, it's where it struggles. And so I'll
Speaker 5:  be really curious to see how they do that and if they do that and when they
Speaker 5:  do that. But man I'm excited. Like Sean got me super hyped for this.
Speaker 4:  I think it's great 'cause we're, we're definitely on this path of convergence
Speaker 4:  between small TVs and computer monitors in a way that I think is really
Speaker 4:  fun. Especially 'cause like I I, my assumption is this is
Speaker 4:  driven by people who sit at desks and play video
Speaker 4:  games and want, want something that looks like a TV and
Speaker 4:  a computer monitor in one screen and there are more and more of those people
Speaker 4:  all the time. And this is the kind of thing that is sitting right at the
Speaker 4:  middle of that And I think like Samsung's doing all kinds of wild stuff with
Speaker 4:  like a smart TV in one input and the other input it's computer monitor. I
Speaker 4:  think that's very cool. But like ole is the, is the right answer,
Speaker 4:  right When we get it right it's gonna be ol lead. Yeah and it does, it feels
Speaker 4:  like we're just around the corner from that in a very cool way. It's
Speaker 5:  So close.
Speaker 4:  I'm pumped to have like a 32 inch computer monitor slash television just
Speaker 4:  sitting on my desk. It's gonna be amazing. I cannot wait and it's
Speaker 5:  Gonna be the most I I mean. I think there's still gonna be some challenges
Speaker 5:  there, particularly around d r 'cause right
Speaker 5:  now the software side of H D R sucks still like,
Speaker 5:  like Microsoft and Apple just aren't doing it very well. The game companies
Speaker 5:  aren't doing it very well. Nobody's kind of figured it out and and settled
Speaker 5:  on something consistent and pleasing to the eyeballs. And
Speaker 5:  so I think we're still gonna, that's where it's gonna start to lag for full
Speaker 5:  TV replacement. But most people probably don't care about H D R
Speaker 5:  as much as I do. So most people will probably be fine. It's
Speaker 5:  just gonna be like me and Sean over in a corner being like, oh H D R is still
Speaker 5:  not up to snuff and that's okay. We're gonna have a great time over around
Speaker 5:  corner.
Speaker 4:  Alright Mila, what's yours?
Speaker 3:  I have two on the Vision Pro, which we haven't talked about in a while. So
Speaker 3:  Apple's virtual reality headset, which they really do not wanna call a virtual
Speaker 3:  reality headset. So one is a little one, they have
Speaker 3:  opened up developer registrations and testing. So
Speaker 3:  Mark Erman has some screenshots of the process. You developers need to go
Speaker 3:  through, sign up for this, you pick a headband size, you pick a light seal
Speaker 3:  size, you have to go in physically to their testing centers. You get fitted,
Speaker 3:  you get lenses and you can try your apps on it. That's a lot.
Speaker 3:  And he also reported, and I'm just gonna quote, here's Mark Garman at
Speaker 3:  Bloomberg Hearing so far that the vision pro developer labs to test apps
Speaker 3:  and actual hardware have been underfilled with small amounts of developers.
Speaker 3:  Some developers are emphasizing companies not offering any East Coast sessions.
Speaker 3:  Cupertino is the only option for the entire United States. This makes sense
Speaker 3:  to me. I just wanna be clear about that. This product is so complicated.
Speaker 3:  They have to fit it to you that you of course are starting as small as
Speaker 3:  you can before you like roll it out at scale. Also
Speaker 3:  no one knows what to build for this thing. Yeah. So it just, it doesn't surprise
Speaker 3:  me that development is starting slow, but that's a note I And, I think
Speaker 3:  it's obvious it's gonna start slow. What's equally interesting to me is that
Speaker 3:  coming up in September is Meta Connect where they're probably
Speaker 3:  gonna announce the Oculus Quest three, which is a
Speaker 3:  scaled, you know, sells as many units. The, the Quest line
Speaker 3:  has sold as many units as any game console. So you, you kinda have the two
Speaker 3:  things happening in parallel. Apple's starting very small with
Speaker 3:  a larger base of developers. It's like pretty excited meta already
Speaker 3:  having application and like installed
Speaker 3:  base scale with the Quest. I think I know
Speaker 3:  what's gonna happen. I I think Apple's gonna be very successful with the
Speaker 3:  Vision Pro and you know, compared to the Quest, but I, who knows it's very
Speaker 3:  expensive compared to the Quest, but they're starting really, really small.
Speaker 3:  Do
Speaker 5:  You think there's gonna be like a little like Shadow Apple
Speaker 5:  developer conference around Connect because you have all of those developers
Speaker 5:  down there near Cupertino. Do you think something's like that's gonna happen?
Speaker 5:  Well
Speaker 4:  That's also presumably only a couple of weeks
Speaker 4:  after Apple's big fall event where I suspect
Speaker 4:  it will have a lot to say about things like the Vision Pro,
Speaker 4:  right?
Speaker 3:  I don't know. I think the fall event for Apple looks like the iPhone.
Speaker 3:  Sure. Maybe a Mac and they say nothing about the Vision
Speaker 3:  Pro, it's unreleased headset with no developer support thus far.
Speaker 4:  Maybe, although I don't know. I I I have two competing feelings about this.
Speaker 4:  On the one hand, I think you're exactly right that Apple is starting small
Speaker 4:  in every way. It's gonna run most iPad apps right outta the box. So in that
Speaker 4:  sense it's just like, it's just gonna work and everybody will like check
Speaker 4:  the checkbox to make it work on the Vision Pro and do the clicky interface.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 5:  Gonna work like your iPad works with iPhone apps.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And think about how many apps did that, right? Like that's that Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Will get you through a year or two. And then I think we're gonna get to the
Speaker 4:  point where a lot of these folks start to turn and say, okay, what can this
Speaker 4:  thing be? But I, I was really surprised after the
Speaker 4:  launch just pulling developers I talked to and the number of them who were
Speaker 4:  like, yeah, we'll probably end up doing something, but at this moment it
Speaker 4:  doesn't really feel like a priority for us. So I think there's gonna be an
Speaker 4:  interesting like chicken and egg thing going on over the next six months.
Speaker 4:  And don don't really know how that's gonna shake out. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I feel like Apple probably needs to be a little, like
Speaker 5:  they need to be more proactive. I, I get, I totally get why they're not that
Speaker 5:  makes a lot of sense. But at the same time if everybody's looking at your
Speaker 5:  product willingly and like are like is this a total boondoggle? Is this the
Speaker 5:  Apple boondoggle you probably do wanna be a little aggressive with with getting
Speaker 5:  some really cool killer apps on there and in courting those developers who
Speaker 5:  aren't necessarily based in Cupertino or near to Cupertino to come out
Speaker 5:  and and try it out.
Speaker 3:  I think I just think they got time. I like Yeah, that's true. If in order
Speaker 3:  to try this thing out you need to sit down, have it fitted to
Speaker 3:  your head and special lenses made for your glass,
Speaker 3:  like that is just a slow expensive process that you
Speaker 3:  are gonna try to refine and optimize as much as you can before you
Speaker 3:  like put them in every Apple store. Yeah. And I. I think that's like their
Speaker 3:  first problem. I think this is the inherent problem with every
Speaker 3:  face computer is that you have to wear them on your face. Yeah. And then
Speaker 3:  I think the bigger problem is that Apple itself outside of what
Speaker 3:  if we did cool N B A things has not really demoed a killer
Speaker 3:  app. you know, like the killer app that I hear people
Speaker 3:  talk about is I'm standing at my desk mirroring my Mac Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Onto five G anti virtual displays and it's like, ugh, that's not
Speaker 3:  good enough. you know, like it that's cool.
Speaker 4:  I mean that's not nothing but that's not, that doesn't get Apple where it
Speaker 4:  thinks it's going here. But
Speaker 5:  Isn't that why you wanna court developers is because maybe one of them has
Speaker 5:  the really good idea that's the killer app. Yeah, but
Speaker 3:  You gotta know, you gotta know what your courting That's true.
Speaker 3:  Like you, you can't just be swiping right on all the
Speaker 3:  developers to take this courtship metaphor in a horrible
Speaker 3:  direction. You can't, you gotta, you gotta have a type, I don't know
Speaker 4:  I mean we had years of fart apps and beer pouring before everybody figured
Speaker 4:  out the iPhone app store like, but the difference there was that a lot of
Speaker 4:  people were able to get it and use it and say, oh I understand new things
Speaker 4:  I can do with this. The challenge with this is gonna be that it's really
Speaker 4:  expensive. Their by all accounts aren't gonna be that many of
Speaker 4:  them. It's gonna be super complicated to get set up for
Speaker 4:  and start using. And so just the like the hurdles to getting one in your
Speaker 4:  hands so that you can start to dream about what it might be for are just
Speaker 4:  so much higher than anything Apple has built before that. I wonder how it
Speaker 4:  will change things.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. By the way, that far type era is really instructive, right? 'cause
Speaker 3:  everyone jokes about it. Remember that app? I am Rich Redownload an app and
Speaker 3:  you could just like, it
Speaker 4:  Cost a thousand dollars, right? Wasn't that the thing? It was,
Speaker 3:  I think it might have been more, I think it might been like a hundred thousand
Speaker 3:  dollars, but there was an app called I'm Rich where you could download it
Speaker 3:  and you could hit a button and pay a bunch of money to the developer and
Speaker 3:  it would just put up a badge that said, I'm Rich. One of the greatest ideas
Speaker 3:  for an application in all of history agreed. Like just truly one of the greatest
Speaker 3:  ideas for an application in all of history. And Apple is like, we can't have
Speaker 3:  this. It's a joke. The fart app are joke. And if you just think about where
Speaker 3:  we've come, the two categories that have succeeded and
Speaker 3:  driven the iPhone are social networking and free to play
Speaker 3:  games. Yeah. Yeah. And everything else is kind of around it, right? Like
Speaker 3:  the Ubers and Lyfts of the world are revolutions in their way, but they're
Speaker 3:  just kind of a duopoly that is stagnant. Like all the other
Speaker 3:  stuff to pales in comparison the size of free to play games and social
Speaker 3:  networking apps. And it's hard to see even what the fart
Speaker 3:  apps look like on the $3,500 Vision Pro.
Speaker 5:  I was gonna say, what, what is, what is the the Fart app equivalent gonna
Speaker 5:  be on a face computer? All
Speaker 3:  Right, that's a reader email send us your ideas. Yes, let us know. I'm actually
Speaker 3:  very curious and And, I'm confident that many of our readers have Oculus
Speaker 3:  Quests. They have PS vrs. Tell us what you think the fart apps
Speaker 3:  are gonna be and what you think the tos are gonna be of the
Speaker 3:  Vision Pro. Love
Speaker 4:  That. Because
Speaker 3:  I, I, I truly cannot tell you the answer. And I. I also have a PSS V R two.
Speaker 3:  I don't think Grand Touro VR is going to be the TikTok of
Speaker 3:  the Vision Pro as much as I want it to be. I don't think that's gonna happen.
Speaker 4:  I don't think so either. Neil, what's your other one? So
Speaker 3:  The other one is my other favorite story of the week. Another just
Speaker 3:  perfect Verge story. It's a format
Speaker 3:  Waral Apple announced the Vision Pro platform
Speaker 3:  is going to join the alliance for open U S D, which is
Speaker 3:  a standards body that's developing interoperable three D tools
Speaker 3:  and file formats. That's Nvidia, Adobe, Autodesk,
Speaker 3:  Pixar. They're basically developing interoperable three D tools, file
Speaker 3:  formats, here's the object formats, here's how they're defined. You can move
Speaker 3:  them between these platforms. You can manipulate them between these platforms.
Speaker 3:  I love this. It also means that the apps you use like
Speaker 3:  Maya Houdini, Autodesk three s, Max, Adobe Substance, three D designers,
Speaker 3:  they can interoperate, they can use the same files. Nvidia can accelerate
Speaker 3:  these graphics. This is notably one of the first times you see Apple and
Speaker 3:  Nvidia working together and they obviously have common purpose in doing so,
Speaker 3:  which is surprising. These companies have not historically liked each
Speaker 3:  other. But what's funny is there's
Speaker 3:  another standards group, there's the Metaverse
Speaker 3:  standards forum, which has Epic and meta in it and like
Speaker 3:  they're also working with U S D, they've got working groups to like look
Speaker 3:  at this file format. But here we are. We we did it.
Speaker 3:  We did H G D V D and Blu-Ray again for the metaverse. I'm so
Speaker 3:  happy. It seems like I'm guessing U S D is gonna
Speaker 3:  become the basis of a lot of things just given the people who are supporting
Speaker 3:  it. But this Notion that the
Speaker 3:  three D internet, the metaverse should have interoperable
Speaker 3:  file formats that sort of every computer can use and all these
Speaker 3:  applications can
Speaker 3:  manipulate this big idea. Everyone agrees
Speaker 3:  it's a good idea. They keep calling it like H T M L for three D, it's far
Speaker 3:  from subtle. Like there's a long way from here to there. And so you just
Speaker 3:  see like every other standard, everyone agrees, oh all these computers should
Speaker 3:  use HT M i, all these t v HTM I, who's gonna be in charge of
Speaker 3:  HTM I C E C and should that work well And the answer's like Don
Speaker 3:  more. We'll
Speaker 3:  see.
Speaker 4:  So what to that point, what, what is the right metaphor for this? Because
Speaker 4:  I was trying to figure this out like is it, should we talk about U S D, the
Speaker 4:  way we talk about like coding languages like JavaScript or H T
Speaker 4:  ml and the fact that that works across lots of apps. Should we talk about
Speaker 4:  it like PDFs or JPEGs like file formats that
Speaker 4:  everybody kind of agrees to understand? I
Speaker 5:  Was thinking of like video containers, not even
Speaker 5:  Codex containers. Okay. Like the A V I
Speaker 5:  versus MP four kind of generation of things. Okay.
Speaker 4:  And that turned into a gigantic mess. So that's discouraging. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And then V L C came and saved us all. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Here's the description from Nvidia, which is technical but
Speaker 3:  easy to understand. Open U S D supports the requirements of building virtual
Speaker 3:  worlds like geometry, cameras, lights and materials. It also
Speaker 3:  includes features necessary for scaling to complex data sets. And it's tremendously
Speaker 3:  extensible enabling the technology to adapt it to workflows beyond visual
Speaker 3:  effects. So you've got a three D scene, you need to describe some objects
Speaker 3:  in it, the materials and textures of those objects where the cameras
Speaker 3:  are the geometry of the scene itself.
Speaker 3:  Like that's just a lot of data structures that you
Speaker 3:  can standardize.
Speaker 4:  So that sounds like coding language to me
Speaker 3:  That's more like file. It's like you have a word file and it has some structured
Speaker 3:  data that describes the font and the the line breaks and the whatever and
Speaker 3:  then the sort of the text is standardized dot doc by the way or dot
Speaker 3:  Doc X one of the most controversial file
Speaker 3:  formats of all time, right? Because it's just text. But
Speaker 3:  until a while ago it was a proprietary
Speaker 3:  file format. so like you just got this like issue where you have these
Speaker 3:  proprietary file formats, people developing them and then you've got files
Speaker 3:  that only that application can read. And that creates tremendous lock-in.
Speaker 3:  I think this industry is saying, okay, that's bad. We, we know
Speaker 3:  that's bad for a huge number of reasons, particularly consumer
Speaker 3:  adoption, right? Like you want, if you believe the
Speaker 3:  Matthew Balls of the world that the metaverse will enable you
Speaker 3:  to drop into the already created three D world of a
Speaker 3:  Pixar movie and like swing a lightsaber
Speaker 3:  around the, the thing that the Pixar animators are
Speaker 3:  working in has to be all the way back compatible to the Vision Pro,
Speaker 3:  right? Otherwise you have to go and remake, you have to
Speaker 3:  redo that work in the Vision Pros format. And that I think everybody
Speaker 3:  understands that. That seems like a huge waste of money.
Speaker 4:  Well this is the kind of thing you do when the industry is small and you're
Speaker 4:  still in the like rising tide lifts all boats phase of things
Speaker 4:  and when this gets bigger and there's more money in
Speaker 4:  walling off your, your walled garden like it for that reason, it's not
Speaker 4:  surprising to me that meta is not part of this, right? Like meta has more
Speaker 4:  reason to say we don't need to be compatible. People are already doing our
Speaker 4:  thing than, yep, some others. And I would not be shocked
Speaker 4:  if this becomes more contentious over time for that reason. Oh
Speaker 5:  Man, I really hope they become competing file
Speaker 5:  formats, And I really hope how they open and
Speaker 5:  are broken for the normal consumer is more like
Speaker 5:  doc than it's like video because video files you try to open it just
Speaker 5:  wouldn't work. Whereas Doc, you'd open it and you'd
Speaker 3:  Like and you'd the weird characters,
Speaker 5:  What's happening here? And that's what I want. But like in a three D
Speaker 5:  space scrapped to my face. Yeah that just sounds
Speaker 5:  delightful in a weird way. Oh my god, I want it so
Speaker 3:  Bad. Alex wants to be like lost in a bad trip Laser B b texting while
Speaker 3:  driving.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it that's great. But
Speaker 3:  You know, to that same point, you can see why Pixar is like, okay,
Speaker 3:  we spend millions, hundreds of millions of dollars creating the
Speaker 3:  world of cars and we wanna make a video game where you can race
Speaker 3:  around the cars track.
Speaker 5:  I don't want it, but yeah, well sure.
Speaker 3:  But then we can just re, we can just take all of that rendering work, all
Speaker 3:  of that scene modeling work and put it on the Vision Pro as a video
Speaker 3:  game. And if you don't have some common file formats like that becomes more
Speaker 3:  costly than it's worth. Right? And I, that's just like, that's one vision
Speaker 3:  of the sort of three D future. But you can see why Pixar
Speaker 3:  or Epic or Unreal, which are deep in Hollywood or making that
Speaker 3:  push now. Totally. By the way, lightning round has taken 45 minutes.
Speaker 4:  We should take a break. But first I just wanna say Neli, that anything that
Speaker 4:  allows me to drop into a Pixar movie with a lightsaber is a huge
Speaker 4:  technological
Speaker 3:  Victory and we should all be in favor of it. You
Speaker 3:  gotta go listen to the Matthew Ball episode of Decoder. This is like what
Speaker 3:  he was talking about the whole time. It's it. It is a fascinating vision
Speaker 3:  of the future. I have no idea if it's a good idea. The good news is all that's
Speaker 3:  done by Disney. So is it possible? Maybe we'll see.
Speaker 3:  Alright, we have to take a break from this interminable lightning round.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna come back and read some reader emails. We'll be right
Speaker 3:  back.
Speaker 6:  You're okay, you're okay.
Speaker 7:  Wolves and dogs are pretty closely related. They actually
Speaker 7:  share 99.9% of their genetics
Speaker 8:  Yo sniffles.
Speaker 7:  But even when they're just a few months old, even when they're raised by
Speaker 7:  human scientists, wolves are pretty different from dogs.
Speaker 8:  They start biting you in the ears when you lying down. If you don't sit
Speaker 8:  up fast enough and you hear this wonderful noises with
Speaker 8:  little and then they chomp you in the air and you're like,
Speaker 8:  oh.
Speaker 7:  And when they grow up, these differences get even
Speaker 7:  bigger. Dogs are our friends.
Speaker 3:  Wolves
Speaker 7:  Are hunters.
Speaker 8:  If I had a sore shoulder, I wouldn't go in with the adult
Speaker 8:  wolves, even if I had raised them because it could trigger their hunting
Speaker 8:  behavior.
Speaker 7:  This week on unexplainable, how did we get the nice friendly dogs
Speaker 7:  we know and love today from wolves? Follow
Speaker 7:  unexplainable wherever you listen for new episodes. Every
Speaker 7:  Wednesday
Speaker 9:  In the 1970s, the pill revolutionized reproductive
Speaker 9:  healthcare in the US and for over 50 years, it was
Speaker 9:  only available by prescription until last month when
Speaker 9:  the F D A did something big, it approved over the counter birth
Speaker 9:  control.
Speaker 10:  I was really excited first of all, but I was also not entirely surprised,
Speaker 10:  right? This is something that the field has been working on for over 20
Speaker 10:  years.
Speaker 9:  Reproductive justice advocates and doctors are excited, but some important
Speaker 9:  questions about price and accessibility remain. That's this week on the
Speaker 9:  weeds.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. It's time for some reader emails. So we've been asking
Speaker 3:  for emails lately. It's been really fun reading them all. Please, keep sending
Speaker 3:  us emails. Vergecast at The Verge dot com. We love it. We asked a couple
Speaker 3:  weeks ago for people who are deep in the Samsung ecosystem to email
Speaker 3:  us. It has been a deluge,
Speaker 3:  And I. Just wanna call this out specifically. I've been asking for
Speaker 3:  years for people who are hardcore Android
Speaker 3:  gaming phone users to email us. We have never gotten one
Speaker 3:  email. I asked for people who use the Spen to email
Speaker 3:  us and we get like five a day. You're
Speaker 5:  Gonna get four emails tomorrow about the razor phone.
Speaker 5:  Just get ready.
Speaker 3:  I'm just saying, if you use an Android gaming phone to play
Speaker 3:  games, where are you? Because the Spen people are out
Speaker 3:  in force and we've just never heard from the gaming
Speaker 3:  in front people. Maybe they don't listen to The Vergecast, who
Speaker 3:  knows? But just there's your data point for today.
Speaker 3:  Okay, let's do some emails. I wanna start, I'm not gonna read this whole
Speaker 3:  one at all. I'm just gonna start with an email from someone named
Speaker 3:  Mo for this reason. They call themselves a
Speaker 3:  Samsung fanboy or quote a Sam boy. Yes.
Speaker 4:  And just threw it out there as if that's a thing that everyone knows, which
Speaker 4:  is just perfect.
Speaker 5:  It is now. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So thank you for Sam. Boy. David, do you wanna read Randy's email?
Speaker 3:  Sure. We
Speaker 4:  Got an email from Randy that says, I'm one of those Samsung tablet
Speaker 4:  sickos and wanted to chime in. I really appreciate the extent to which, so
Speaker 3:  Sam Boys and Sickos already Yes, from the jump, incredible emails
Speaker 3:  to receive.
Speaker 4:  They've all really leaned into being Sickos And, I. Really appreciate it.
Speaker 4:  It says, I switched from having surface tablets to using a Samsung Galaxy
Speaker 4:  tab, SS seven plus. And the reason for that is one piece of software clip
Speaker 4:  studio paint. It went, which is like three words to mean the same
Speaker 4:  thing. But anyway,
Speaker 4:  It went from being a desktop only app to being available on Galaxy slash
Speaker 4:  Android. And now I could finally have a normal tablet experience and get
Speaker 4:  to be productive and creative doing illustration on the same slim tablet.
Speaker 4:  Obviously that means I'm using the Spen on it all the time. Thank you Samsung
Speaker 4:  for including it with the tablet and not requiring me to purchase it separately,
Speaker 4:  which is a very good Apple burn. Great job, Randy. Yeah, it's my laptop.
Speaker 4:  Really. I take it to work with me so I can have some videos going while I'm
Speaker 4:  at my desk. Pop open clip studio to do an illustration or get a doodle down
Speaker 4:  on paper, open up Kindle to read the newest mango volume. And when you need
Speaker 4:  to prepare a d d campaign, I'll snap over to Dex to better multitask at a
Speaker 4:  coffee shop and get it all done. It's the best mobile computer I've ever
Speaker 4:  had. And I. Didn't have to give Apple a penny. This person is
Speaker 4:  100% either a Samsung employee or should be a
Speaker 4:  Samsung employee. 'cause what That is the best pitch of all time for
Speaker 4:  Samsung devices.
Speaker 5:  Call Randy now. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Or it's Dan Siefert, the only other Dex fan that I
Speaker 4:  know.
Speaker 5:  He just changed his name, his burner account.
Speaker 3:  Dandy Sefer. This is incredible. So first of all,
Speaker 3:  I just wanna start with the end there. I didn't have to give Apple a penny.
Speaker 3:  This is a real theme in the Samsung emails. Yeah. I
Speaker 3:  don't like Apple, so I'm in the Samsung ecosystem that
Speaker 3:  motivates more people than you could possibly imagine, at least from our
Speaker 3:  emails. Obviously this is self-selecting group, the people who chose to email
Speaker 3:  us about their love of Samsung, but there's a commonality
Speaker 3:  there, which is nobody wants to use Apple stuff. And that's here The
Speaker 3:  flip to Dex, that's the turn for this.
Speaker 4:  It's so good.
Speaker 5:  Oof. Yeah, that's, it's beautiful. I, I love it. We found him, the guy who
Speaker 5:  uses Dex. Thank you Randy.
Speaker 3:  He's a sicko, but
Speaker 4:  I also, I'll snap over to Dex to better multitask at a coffee shop and get
Speaker 4:  it all done. Does that imply that you're bringing a monitor and a keyboard
Speaker 4:  and mouse to a coffee shop plugging it in?
Speaker 5:  I can only hope so
Speaker 4:  I, yeah, that's the correct answer.
Speaker 3:  Or you've got the flippy cover thing. Every tablet is that tablet now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, true. But I will say this makes the right case for Samsung stuff, right?
Speaker 4:  Like Samsung devices do more stuff than anybody
Speaker 4:  else's devices. Does it do it all super elegantly and
Speaker 4:  beautifully? No. Does it do it all?
Speaker 4:  Yes. Like it's,
Speaker 3:  Yeah, like it's somewhere in here I could be like, and then I go home And
Speaker 3:  I Mirror cast my LG tv. It's like, well you can do that. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Get them options. Yeah. It also has an IR blaster for when I need to control
Speaker 3:  my mini split. Like, okay.
Speaker 4:  And there's something to that.
Speaker 3:  There is something to that. I will, I will note that there's a killer
Speaker 3:  app involved here, right? There's clip studio paint,
Speaker 3:  which if you don't have that killer app and it's only on the iPad
Speaker 3:  or it's only on a Windows computer, this all falls apart for you.
Speaker 3:  So next we have Mark who wrote to us. This is a tale of woe.
Speaker 3:  I'm just gonna put this out there. Mark says, I'm a UX designer. Pen displays
Speaker 3:  are helpful in my work. I realize I'm not typical,
Speaker 3:  which Mark my friend. You're not alone,
Speaker 3:  mark. Yeah. There's a community of UX designers using pen
Speaker 3:  displays. We'll hook you up with some subreddits. Mark says, I've
Speaker 3:  tried Samsung tablets and phones with Spens since the beginning of them.
Speaker 3:  The emoji I think of as the Dieter face with, you know, the line.
Speaker 3:  Just the line. I tried to like them. I use an iPad Pro
Speaker 3:  and a Wacom syn take 32 Pro Daily. Now I use a U S P
Speaker 3:  flash drives. So I'm not stuck in Apple's Cloud for my content. I'm done
Speaker 3:  with Samsung Galaxy tabs and notes. Wow. And then he
Speaker 3:  says I should be able to use any device, not this content, but the devices
Speaker 3:  don't last. Nothing's on my devices very long. I want the good
Speaker 3:  pens, which are apple and wack com. I try not to be a prisoner of
Speaker 3:  proprietary clouds. Pretty
Speaker 4:  Good. Yes.
Speaker 3:  That's a Verge cash shirt. That is, I, I want that shirt mark as a designer,
Speaker 3:  if you wanna design a, I'm not a prisoner proprietary cloud shirt for us.
Speaker 3:  We, we'll sell it and we'll, we'll throw you a cut. And then
Speaker 3:  I use an iPad to read or sketch comfortably. I use big screen sketch stuff.
Speaker 3:  Done. This is the counter argument, right, is the Samsung tablets can do
Speaker 3:  everything. People are really attracted to them. Again, my dream is
Speaker 3:  to edit the entire Verge by circling copy in red.
Speaker 3:  If you could make that happen for me, Google
Speaker 3:  Docs, I'm golden. I'll buy whatever tablet you
Speaker 3:  want, but then you actually do it. You're like, oh, this is like pretty wanky
Speaker 3:  Alex. I think this is like your E Ink tablet story. Yeah. Every month.
Speaker 3:  Like, this is my dream. I bought the newest one. Ugh. And
Speaker 3:  we like move on. It sucks. I love it.
Speaker 4:  I also think that model that he describes at the end is kind of a
Speaker 4:  great way to think about a lot of devices. I should be able to drive over
Speaker 4:  any device and not lose content. Love that. I want to use the good
Speaker 4:  pens. Love that. Don't be a prisoner. Proprietary clouds
Speaker 4:  excellent. And then I use big screens to get stuff done. Should also be a
Speaker 4:  verse t-shirt.
Speaker 3:  That's a mug. That's like a, you walk into the meeting and you put your mug
Speaker 3:  back. Its big
Speaker 4:  Screen get, so
Speaker 3:  I love it. That's great. All right, next we have an email from a, a reader
Speaker 3:  named Alexa. I'm gonna have my friend Alex read this
Speaker 3:  email and you decide it's not who actually sent this
Speaker 3:  email to us.
Speaker 5:  It's not me. I don't like the name Alexa because it's not my
Speaker 5:  name. And then the smart speaker always confuses
Speaker 5:  us. I got my Samsung Galaxy S
Speaker 5:  23 Ultra in March April time and was very excited for the
Speaker 5:  built-in SS pin. Felt like a real hark back to the old
Speaker 5:  Samsung champ I had as a young teen with a we stylist. Again,
Speaker 3:  You decide who Alexa is in this story.
Speaker 5:  Not me, but Alexa. We should be friends for the first
Speaker 5:  month or two. It was great. Used it often. Reconnected with my creative side
Speaker 5:  and doodled a bit, took notes in meetings. The usual stuff. The
Speaker 5:  killer app of the pen, however, lies in a more unconventional use case.
Speaker 5:  Seriously. Alexa, we can be besties. It is the absolute
Speaker 5:  perfect size to poke down joints.
Speaker 5:  Yes, the perfect, and this is bold. The
Speaker 5:  perfect width four or five months in the s pin is
Speaker 5:  used every single day. But I can't remember
Speaker 5:  the last time I touched the screen. A perfectly portable
Speaker 5:  pokey. Everywhere you go, it's there for you. I
Speaker 5:  gotta go get a Samsung Galaxy S 23 Ultra is what I
Speaker 5:  learned from this.
Speaker 4:  A perfectly portable pokey sounds like a sentence we can't say on this
Speaker 4:  show is very many times. I love this email. So much so
Speaker 4:  good.
Speaker 3:  I'm such an old man. I read this email. And I was like, or it's her elbow
Speaker 3:  hurt. Like is she just stabbing her
Speaker 3:  joints?
Speaker 5:  Very long, long. Look at it.
Speaker 4:  Listen, Samsung devices do all the things. Yeah, like you, you, you think
Speaker 4:  this isn't on a spec sheet somewhere in, yeah. South Korea. Come on. They,
Speaker 4:  they know it's
Speaker 5:  Important to, to get those, those joints rolled perfectly.
Speaker 3:  All right. My request is we, we should transition away from the Samsung emails.
Speaker 3:  Can we play Laser Bong as a transition song please?
Speaker 3:  I can't see Andrew's face, but I think it's the dieter emoji sheet right
Speaker 3:  now. All right, so we have a couple more. These are some of
Speaker 3:  my favorites. So we've been asking for consumer wars, like
Speaker 3:  product wars, fanboy wars, the rain X versus
Speaker 3:  water versus other brands. Windshield
Speaker 3:  washer fluid continues to rage in our emails. The Rain X people
Speaker 3:  are furious that we've acknowledged anything
Speaker 3:  else. They're very mad at us. Rain x bug wash. By
Speaker 3:  far the, the fans are out of control. I was in the gas
Speaker 3:  station recently. I needed to buy some Windshield washer fluid. I didn't,
Speaker 3:  I just bought whatever was there. And I literally felt bad.
Speaker 3:  That is the weirdest feeling I've ever had as a purchaser of anything. I
Speaker 3:  was like, ah, it's not rain. And it's like they got to me. You just
Speaker 5:  Vindicated all of them.
Speaker 3:  Well no, that's just bullying. I don't think they just, I
Speaker 3:  was just like, I felt, I felt weird about wearing the wrong shoes to elementary
Speaker 3:  school. That was exactly that feeling. I do not think it is any more
Speaker 3:  or less significant to my Windshield wiper performance.
Speaker 3:  However, if you continue to have feelings, email us. I'm dying to know. Here's
Speaker 3:  my favorite email of this entire Consumer
Speaker 3:  Wars conversation. It might be one of the
Speaker 3:  best emails we have ever gotten. It vindicates everything I know to be true
Speaker 3:  about the Birch. So good. It's from Zachary. I
Speaker 3:  run a pool cleaning service in Southern California. I have listened every
Speaker 3:  week since the End Gadget podcast days. And I thought I would share
Speaker 3:  the argument about which high-end carbon fiber pool pole is
Speaker 3:  best. Yes. When you service pools all day long, your
Speaker 3:  pole is your most used tool. Yeah, it's, they have been
Speaker 3:  aluminum for decades, but in the last five
Speaker 3:  years, carbon fiber has hit the scene. This
Speaker 3:  is a huge upgrade causing less back strain during heavy
Speaker 3:  use. And then he lists three
Speaker 3:  categories. There's the wrong, there are
Speaker 3:  those who only care about specs and they
Speaker 3:  choose the primate pool pole. They think the only speck that
Speaker 3:  matters is weight. They ignore a harder to use latch. The
Speaker 3:  poorer construction and the inferior customer service.
Speaker 4:  I just wanna say that the primate pool pole is not like a dig. That's
Speaker 4:  the actual name of the product. That's
Speaker 3:  The name of, and that's, and that's where you spec
Speaker 3:  monsters. Then he lists the best.
Speaker 3:  The hyper pole by ultimate pool tools is the vastly
Speaker 3:  superior pole. Yes, it does weigh a few ounces more than the original,
Speaker 3:  but that leaves out so much. The hyper pole has the cleverly named hyper
Speaker 3:  drain that allows water collected in the pole to flat out instantly is removed
Speaker 3:  from the water. The weight savings from the other pole is quickly outdone
Speaker 3:  by the water weight savings compared with the better latches and the great
Speaker 3:  customer service. Easy decision. Yeah. This man is furious
Speaker 3:  about pool poles. And I love it. And then that's so good. We get to the
Speaker 3:  silly, this is his label. This is the
Speaker 3:  poll that would've been released by Will. I am
Speaker 4:  Incredible. This is the best part of this whole email.
Speaker 3:  Like
Speaker 4:  That tells you everything you need to know and is also will I AM's legacy
Speaker 4:  And that makes me so happy.
Speaker 3:  Just wait until you hear this description. The Skimm
Speaker 3:  light carbon light is needed by no one and
Speaker 3:  solves no problems.
Speaker 3:  Instead of a tried and true circular tube.
Speaker 3:  It is a 10 sided deagon preventing you
Speaker 3:  from spinning it in your hand. It also has pre-drilled set
Speaker 3:  points only allowing it to click into place in certain spots.
Speaker 4:  End of email point made it's silly.
Speaker 3:  End, end of email. We reached out back to Zachary. I'm
Speaker 3:  dying to find the forums where this is all being argued out. If you
Speaker 3:  wanna write 5,000 words about the introduction of
Speaker 3:  carbon fiber into the pool industry and how it's torn
Speaker 3:  that industry apart, just email me
Speaker 3:  anytime. We will commission that story anytime. I
Speaker 3:  love it. I love that this exists. This is the, like in many ways the purpose
Speaker 3:  of the internet is allowing people to be their best selves.
Speaker 3:  Arguing about carbon fiber pool tools.
Speaker 5:  Oh my god, these tools are so expensive. They're so expensive. They're
Speaker 5:  so expensive.
Speaker 3:  It's so good. Read some read surprises. Alex.
Speaker 5:  Okay, so the the the the hyper pole. That's the
Speaker 5:  good one. Yeah, that's 2 75. 2 75. That's the one you five, that's the one
Speaker 5:  you want. It's 2 75 and it's great. It's also sold out. Looks
Speaker 4:  Like a lights saber by the way. Huge fan. I would
Speaker 5:  Get no work done with this. The, the primate three
Speaker 5:  x ranges from 2 54 99
Speaker 5:  to 3 24 99. Which is
Speaker 5:  just,
Speaker 3:  I'm telling you,
Speaker 5:  I think that's the special edition. Kevlar Weave. No, that's only 2 99.
Speaker 5:  Is it the Teal Tiki also 2 99. It's
Speaker 5:  good. I'm trying to figure out which one is so expensive.
Speaker 3:  I'm saying if you are a budding reporter or
Speaker 3:  journalist out there and you're like I can nail this
Speaker 3:  feature about the, the war that has taken over
Speaker 3:  the pool cleaning industry because of carbon fiber. Hit us up. Send me a
Speaker 3:  note. Send me a pitch. We'll run that story First slot in the
Speaker 3:  hero, we'll send it to the awards. I'll send that story to the Pulitzer
Speaker 3:  committee. You just let me know.
Speaker 4:  Alex, I found the most expensive primate poll. It's the psycho
Speaker 4:  Chimp one and it means the poll is decorated
Speaker 4:  with what look like bored ape NFTs. Basically
Speaker 4:  it's, this is so spectacular.
Speaker 3:  Alright, we gotta get off pool tools. I'm just saying if you want to write
Speaker 3:  that story, just hit me up. Alright, we got two more. They're
Speaker 3:  both a plus. David, you wanna take the next one?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Neli. This one I think is, is directed especially to you. This is
Speaker 4:  from Jonathan says there are two big manufacturers of premium
Speaker 4:  woodworking hand tools in North America. Yes. La
Speaker 4:  Nielsen and Lee Valley slash
Speaker 4:  Veritas. you know those the big brands?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. Lai Nielsen mostly makes
Speaker 4:  souped up versions of hundred year olds. Stanley designs Lee Valley slash
Speaker 4:  Veritas make more modern takes on traditional tools with adventurous designs
Speaker 4:  and materials. You can instantly tell why there's a huge like holy war between
Speaker 4:  these two companies by the way. Like yeah. Cool versions of the old thing
Speaker 4:  or new ideas like Hmm those those said never like each other
Speaker 4:  Anyway. Lionel is preferred by the well-heeled
Speaker 4:  traditionalist Lee Valley tools could be at home on the robo
Speaker 4:  workbench in the bat cave hand tool specific.
Speaker 3:  When I think of Batman, by the way, I think of premium handcrafted woodwork
Speaker 3:  game.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's amazing.
Speaker 5:  That's how he
Speaker 4:  Gets his belt hand tool. Jonathan continues there please. There's lots more
Speaker 4:  Jonathan to get through there. Hand tool specific vaporware
Speaker 4:  bonus. Several years ago lying this in showed a sample of a plow plane
Speaker 4:  they were seeking to manufacture. It was based on the highly collectible
Speaker 4:  miller patent plow plan. That's a fun phrase to say. The internet message
Speaker 4:  boards went crazy. Of course. And nothing. Lion
Speaker 4:  Nielsen stopped showing the sample. Eventually if you asked about it at one
Speaker 4:  of their traveling tool shows, the presenter would give you a dirty look
Speaker 4:  and ignore the question. Yes. We are talking about a tool that
Speaker 4:  only makes inset grooves in boards. Yes. This is something you can do
Speaker 4:  with any $99 router with speed and precision. Yes. Lee Valley has
Speaker 4:  since released three different plow prs ranging in price from
Speaker 4:  $160 to $440 before additional cutters or
Speaker 4:  specific attachments End of email. Amazing.
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 5:  Would absolutely buy one. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Just look at this old thing. It's cool.
Speaker 3:  Well you can't get it. It's vaporware. I
Speaker 5:  Know, but I would if, if I could.
Speaker 3:  Okay. I just wanna unpack this email for one second. In order to know
Speaker 3:  this information, people have to go out and get it. So for example,
Speaker 3:  the sentence, the message boards went crazy and then
Speaker 3:  nothing implies quite a bit of
Speaker 3:  monitoring of message boards. Just putting that out there.
Speaker 3:  Second, they stopped showing the sample. If you asked about it at one of
Speaker 3:  their traveling tool shows you would get a dirty look and ignore the
Speaker 3:  question implies that multiple people at
Speaker 3:  multiple tool shows in multiple
Speaker 3:  locations asked about this tool and received a dirty
Speaker 3:  look and then collated that information on the
Speaker 3:  internet such that it is now a fact.
Speaker 4:  This is the Snyder cut of hand tools.
Speaker 3:  I'm just saying it's so good. That's incredible. The, the people who do this
Speaker 3:  are Taylor Swift fans waiting to see when 1989 Taylor's version
Speaker 3:  will come out and fans of the plow claim incredible from Lee Nelson. I
Speaker 3:  love
Speaker 4:  It. I just love that everyone is the same. If you use a tool long
Speaker 4:  enough, like this is why the version is obsessed with like mechanical
Speaker 4:  keyboards and ole screens because that's what we like touch and look at all
Speaker 4:  day. But if you touch and look at plow planes all day, you're gonna get dis
Speaker 4:  obsessed about plow plans. I love it. Everyone is the same. You are all our
Speaker 4:  people.
Speaker 3:  Do you think the lie Nelson people are like forum bombing here? Like we have
Speaker 3:  three of 'em ranging in price that Batman could use
Speaker 3:  'em. All
Speaker 3:  right, one more. When I think of Verge
Speaker 3:  stories, you all know how obsessed I'm with Google and
Speaker 3:  Zelda, the combo platter of Google and Zelda Alex. You wanna take this one?
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So this one's from John. He loves the show. Hey John, we love
Speaker 5:  you and your most recent Friday episode, you were talking about
Speaker 5:  autocorrect and how it's changing in iOS 17 and it reminded me of
Speaker 5:  one of my favorite weird things that I've been seeing happening on Google
Speaker 5:  lately. I've been playing the legend of Zelda Tears of the kingdom far too
Speaker 5:  much. I'm sure I'm not the only one and he's not. I think half of
Speaker 5:  this Vergecast does.
Speaker 4:  How sexy is your link John?
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  That's not where this email's going. Please do not send us emails about
Speaker 3:  sexy link. I'll take your Samsung emails all
Speaker 3:  day. No sexy link. Send
Speaker 5:  Them all to David. I'd be not very good at video games. I've had to look
Speaker 5:  up hints and guides regularly and a shorthand folks are generally typing
Speaker 5:  t o t K for tears of the kingdom plus whatever shrine
Speaker 5:  quest boss battle that they're looking for.
Speaker 3:  I can confirm I do this all the time. So
Speaker 5:  IOS doesn't recognize t o T K as a word 'cause it's
Speaker 5:  not and auto completes it as York. So now on Google, if
Speaker 5:  you start to type the name of a shrine or a quest, one of the auto completes
Speaker 5:  will inevitably include York at the end because people are hitting
Speaker 5:  search too quickly.
Speaker 3:  This is so good. It's true. Yes. By the way you can start typing glia and
Speaker 3:  it'll complete to York.
Speaker 4:  That's amazing.
Speaker 3:  It's incredible. This is like the emer,
Speaker 3:  the layered emergent behaviors here are out of control.
Speaker 3:  Right? It's wonderful. So first you have to iOS, maybe Android
Speaker 3:  two doesn't recognize this thing. Regardless of how much they're claiming,
Speaker 3:  there's machine learning and whatever they haven't figured out. The T O T
Speaker 3:  K is a thing that is happening. So the keyboards are auto completing to
Speaker 3:  York and then they're sending that information to Google, which is collecting
Speaker 3:  millions and millions of searches for things like how to beat
Speaker 3:  the wind temple and and tears the kingdom and saying, okay, it's wind
Speaker 3:  Temple York, Google does not understand that that is
Speaker 3:  an iOS auto complete. And so it's just taking that data as
Speaker 3:  real and turning that into an auto complete suggestion for millions
Speaker 3:  of other people to see, not understand it all and potentially click on
Speaker 3:  this. Well it is bonkers. We're
Speaker 4:  We're like one small step away from there being websites
Speaker 4:  with headings that say how do you complete
Speaker 4:  the wind? Temple York. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Globo. Yeah. This is the Globo situation. There's gonna be AI websites
Speaker 3:  looking at at at Google Trends. I'm gonna tell the polygon people like a
Speaker 3:  huge amount of polygons traffic right now is here's the kingdom guides and
Speaker 3:  I'm be like, you guys gotta start sneaking in some York stuff.
Speaker 4:  Absolutely.
Speaker 5:  It's a lovely place. Really nice Anglican choir.
Speaker 3:  It's perfect. We, by the way, we have gotten a bunch of emails about iOS
Speaker 3:  autocorrect in general. I'll say that now I'm paying attention
Speaker 3:  to it. It does seem worse. Yesterday I, I was actually speaking Dieter,
Speaker 3:  I was texting with Dieter And. I said send it to me and it just auto completed
Speaker 3:  it to Messenger. Yeah. So it just said send it to Messenger.
Speaker 3:  Like it was very confusing. Like why? But I can't tell if
Speaker 3:  that's like, I'm noticing it like whatever that bias is called. But we have
Speaker 3:  gotten lots of emails from people saying it's, it's much worse.
Speaker 5:  Just don't correct it for a few weeks and see how your
Speaker 5:  friends noticed in the group chat. I definitely got called out the other
Speaker 5:  day. They're like, Alex, you're your autocorrects going through it right
Speaker 5:  now. It didn't. It just is just like nonsense.
Speaker 3:  Well we'll see. So we're, we're a month away from the next version of iOS.
Speaker 3:  Maybe it'll get better, maybe it'll get worse. Who knows what'll happen.
Speaker 3:  Keep sending us emails about that one.
Speaker 4:  Ple. Yeah, Please keep sending us emails about especially all if you have
Speaker 4:  specific weird autocorrect things that are happening. We're trying to
Speaker 4:  figure out ways to investigate. This is a weird thing to
Speaker 4:  try and actually pin down an answer on. But
Speaker 4:  one thing we need is lots and lots of bizarre autocorrect examples. So if
Speaker 4:  you get a weird one, send us a screenshot and tell us everything.
Speaker 3:  Also, if you are playing games on your Android gaming
Speaker 3:  phone, send us an email. No one's ever
Speaker 3:  done it. The Spen people are out here just smoking it up to
Speaker 3:  Android. Gaming people, as far as I can tell, don't exist. All right. That's
Speaker 3:  it. We had to take a break. This is really fun. Send us more emails. We're
Speaker 3:  gonna read more emails in the show. We, David's already doing it on Wednesday
Speaker 3:  show all the time. Right?
Speaker 4:  It's great. It's the best part of the show every time. I love it.
Speaker 3:  If all we do for the rest of the show is respond to reader feedback, well
Speaker 3:  we have it. But that said, or
Speaker 4:  Call the hotline. Eight six six vi one one. Call the hotline. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Hotline and email us vi has to vi com. We love it. We'll be back.
Speaker 3:  We'll do another, it'll be a quick lightning round this time
Speaker 3:  we're gonna get through it. We'll be right
Speaker 3:  back.
Speaker 3:  We're back. It's gonna be an actually fast lightning round. We're gonna do
Speaker 3:  it under 45 minutes. It's gonna be amazing.
Speaker 3:  Cranz, I think Alex has the best one. Go ahead.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. I am absolutely obsessed with this. My brother is in the food industry,
Speaker 5:  so anytime like food industry and tech converge, I get really, really
Speaker 5:  excited. MrBeast is suing virtual
Speaker 5:  dining concepts because that's the, the company that kind of
Speaker 5:  ar arranges MrBeast Burger, his Uber
Speaker 5:  Eats takeout delivery hamburger
Speaker 5:  joints and he's suing them because according
Speaker 5:  to the lawsuit, the Burgers are, the food is
Speaker 5:  revolting and likely the worst burger
Speaker 5:  the person had ever had. Also
Speaker 4:  Not just according to the lawsuit, according to people who ordered those
Speaker 4:  Burgers.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And also inedible like, like it's just full of
Speaker 5:  insults and, and the pictures are absolutely revolting. You'll
Speaker 5:  be totally disgusted. And I just keep thinking about this and
Speaker 5:  wondering why this all happened and we
Speaker 5:  understand why it happened. MrBeast, it was 2020 restaurants
Speaker 5:  were in dire straits. Everybody I know was unemployed. Like my brother
Speaker 5:  just didn't work for six months. And so they were like, okay, how can we,
Speaker 5:  how can we help restaurants? Well let's open a lot of ghost kitchens where
Speaker 5:  we can ship food out via Seamless via Uber Eats
Speaker 5:  and you can, you can get your food and the restaurants get to stay open and
Speaker 5:  everybody wins. And so that's what they did. And these Ghost Kitchens
Speaker 5:  just proliferated. They were everywhere. And Virtual Dining Concepts was
Speaker 5:  like, okay cool. We can partner with people and make their brands take off
Speaker 5:  there. Virtual Dining Concepts was started by one of the guys who did Planet
Speaker 5:  Hollywood. So he like knows his way around branding and
Speaker 5:  churning out horrible food to the masses.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I was gonna say but does he know his way around good food?
Speaker 5:  And so of course when you're thinking I wanna start a really cool business
Speaker 5:  project involving food, I'll go to that guy. And that's what
Speaker 5:  MrBeast James Donaldson did. He went to this guy, they were
Speaker 5:  quickly everywhere. I know people who were accidentally ordering him 'cause
Speaker 5:  they'd see like MrBeast Burger and they'd see these gorgeous pictures of
Speaker 5:  Burgers and then they'd get just slop to their houses. Wait,
Speaker 3:  I just wanna call out the Yeah. The Twitter Thread guys, when MrBeast
Speaker 3:  Burger launched had a field day. Oh yeah, right. Okay. They were like,
Speaker 3:  here's the future of all marketing. Here's why MrBeast Burger is poised to
Speaker 3:  take over from McDonald's. One of 945
Speaker 3:  thread. They've been dead silent since this lawsuit
Speaker 3:  came in. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Everybody was obsessed with Ghost Kitchens like it, this was, this was the
Speaker 4:  new thing. Yeah. Because
Speaker 5:  It's really hard to,
Speaker 5:  like, it's hard for one restaurant to cons to be consistent every
Speaker 5:  night. It's really, really hard for one restaurant. Right. It is virtually
Speaker 5:  impossible. And Wendy's and McDonald's and all of them, the
Speaker 5:  food may sometimes be disgusting. You everybody has their own takes,
Speaker 5:  but it's cons. It's fairly consistent. Even they struggle with consistency.
Speaker 5:  And MrBeast was like, yeah, I'm gonna come in with the Planet Hollywood guy
Speaker 5:  and we're also gonna be consistent. Burgers
Speaker 3:  His pitch in the beginning in that, in that covid time was really interesting.
Speaker 3:  Right? Yeah. It was all these mom and pops are struggling. I'm gonna come
Speaker 3:  in with this marketing muscle. Anyone can sign up, we'll send you the
Speaker 3:  kit. Burgers are easy to make, relatively we'll send you the materials and
Speaker 3:  the stickers and the packaging and your mom and Pop can be turbocharged
Speaker 3:  by my marketing muscle. Right.
Speaker 4:  So anyone can make Beast Burgers was the idea. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 3:  A lot of Jimmy's brand is altruism and there's however much
Speaker 3:  controversy associated with that brand and it's whatever. But that is like
Speaker 3:  the core of his thing, right. Is like, I'll help a lot of people and I'll
Speaker 3:  get rich along the way. Cool. What's fascinating here is
Speaker 3:  like it should be relatively easy
Speaker 3:  to make Burgers and have them not be raw and somehow it
Speaker 3:  wasn't. Right. Like if you just open Seamless or GrubHub
Speaker 3:  or whatever in the average city, you don't pick MrBeast Burger and you just
Speaker 3:  pick some restaurant and order some cheeseburger.
Speaker 3:  The chances of it being raw are very low. And
Speaker 3:  somehow the chances of the MrBeast Burger being
Speaker 3:  raw were very high. And I. That's the whole thing here
Speaker 3:  that I just do not understand.
Speaker 5:  So what was happening was Ghost Kitchens, because it's not attached to the
Speaker 5:  restaurant's brand, the restaurant. Oh they don't
Speaker 3:  Have to care as much. Yeah. They
Speaker 5:  Don't have to care. And if You don't care, you're, you're like quality goes
Speaker 5:  out the window and so quality. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You get your like idiot nephew to make the Burgers because they're be Burgers.
Speaker 4:  It doesn't come back on you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You're like, oh, you go over to the Bees burger like kitchen and you
Speaker 5:  do all of that. We're gonna actually go make money and build our brand and
Speaker 5:  just use that to subsidize ourselves. And we've seen that happen. Like a
Speaker 5:  lot of Ghost Kitchens, this was the way it was like there was one in my old
Speaker 5:  neighborhood and you'd walk in and the food's really good and then you'd
Speaker 5:  like go try to order from there on like Seamless. And there were six
Speaker 5:  different restaurants with the exact same address because they were just
Speaker 5:  churning out this slop to keep like their actual core really
Speaker 5:  delicious business going. We have a
Speaker 3:  Great Josh recipe piece about the, the Chuck e Cheese of it all. What was
Speaker 3:  the name? Hold on.
Speaker 4:  The Chuck E. Cheese of it all should be the title of somebody's memoir. I
Speaker 4:  don't know who but it should.
Speaker 3:  So we have a great Josh Trezza story about chicken wings and ghost
Speaker 3:  kitchens. We'll link to it. And how many Ghost kitchens make chicken wings
Speaker 3:  and why Chicken wings are proliferate. It's 'cause they're actually easy
Speaker 3:  to make. Yeah. And they're cheap. Yeah. By the way, the chicken wing story,
Speaker 3:  we talked about our background policy before. you know how we don't let press
Speaker 3:  people be on background? They have to use real names. Chicken Wings story
Speaker 3:  is like what pushed me over the edge
Speaker 3:  because like one of the big food delivery companies would only talk to
Speaker 3:  Josh like in Secret and they would only discuss the
Speaker 3:  popularity of chicken wings. And we were
Speaker 3:  like, why? Why can't we attribute you saying
Speaker 3:  Chicken wings are very popular? That that
Speaker 3:  was the one that like broke me. They
Speaker 5:  Slapped back. Like they're, they're telling, they're saying no. He,
Speaker 5:  he wanted like, he's been bullying us. He's trying to renegotiate the deal.
Speaker 5:  He's bullying us, he's being mean to us. And
Speaker 5:  MrBeast Burger brand will continue on as long as they hold
Speaker 5:  that contract
Speaker 3:  Will never stop. Yeah. So will never stop using your name. And like Mr.
Speaker 3:  Tosche. Very good. I'll tell you my, my lawyer
Speaker 3:  brain is this lawsuit inevitably settles if this lawsuit gets to a
Speaker 3:  jury, the American legal system has completely failed. I say
Speaker 3:  that in the context of the former president of the United States speaking
Speaker 3:  indicted this week. you know, that'll happen.
Speaker 3:  Whatever. If MrBeast Burgers gets to a trial, the American legal
Speaker 3:  system has failed because this, this thing should completely settle. It should
Speaker 3:  never get to a trial. Okay. My lightning round. Chris Welch big scoop
Speaker 3:  this week. Sonos Move two hitting in September with stereo sound.
Speaker 3:  24 hour battery life and importantly u s BBC very audio
Speaker 3:  in hell. Yeah. Which is super cool. We're beginning to see that in more and
Speaker 3:  more places. Also because it's a portable speaker with big battery, U S B
Speaker 3:  C port can charge a phone. Very cool.
Speaker 4:  Well you can charge your phone from your gigantic Bluetooth speaker.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. 'cause it's also a gigantic battery. Oh,
Speaker 4:  That's awesome. That's the first time ever that a Sonos speaker being
Speaker 4:  humongous actually feels like a good idea to me. I'm in on this
Speaker 4:  now.
Speaker 3:  It has two tweeters in it, so it's stereo sound. They've reoptimize the
Speaker 3:  controls, it's got automatic trueplay, all this stuff. But yeah, it's the
Speaker 3:  battery that I, I think is particularly cool. And of course it can
Speaker 3:  do Bluetooth audio as well. And the big upgrade here is it can do Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  and wi simultaneously, which is pretty
Speaker 4:  Cool. Chris Welch as ever living in the AC events
Speaker 4:  at Sonos. HQ, it's a good scoop.
Speaker 3:  That's very good. All right, David, take us home. Mine
Speaker 4:  Is more a recommendation than anything else. I just wanna let everybody
Speaker 4:  know that ESPN is doing, it's the OCHO
Speaker 4:  thing again, the history of this is that it was a joke they made in a dodgeball
Speaker 4:  movie in like 2004. And then like 12 years later
Speaker 4:  ESPN decided, oh we'll actually do it and we'll use this as like a one or
Speaker 4:  two day thing to show all the sports we don't usually show on tv. So it's
Speaker 4:  everything from like spike ball to like
Speaker 4:  musical chairs and all kinds of like insane sports you'd never see on
Speaker 4:  tv. It is the single most fun thing you will ever watch on sports television.
Speaker 4:  And one of the things that they're doing is the Excel World
Speaker 4:  Championships. And. I have found myself deep in the world of
Speaker 4:  competitive Excel over the last few months. Like getting to know some of
Speaker 4:  the folks who called this is, they're doing a huge season this year. They
Speaker 4:  did this on ESPN last summer and it was like a big viral hit.
Speaker 4:  People got really excited because you see competitive Excel on TV and you
Speaker 4:  immediately go, what in the world is going on? So they're having a big season
Speaker 4:  this year. The culmination is gonna be this big thing at the eSports
Speaker 4:  arena in Las Vegas. It's gonna be a whole huge thing. But as you're listening
Speaker 4:  to this on Friday morning, it's airing at 7:00 AM So if
Speaker 4:  you're listening to this very early, you might get a chance to see it live.
Speaker 4:  But otherwise it will be on YouTube. It'll be on ESPN.
Speaker 4:  Competitive Excel is significantly more fun than you think. It's basically
Speaker 4:  like puzzle solving using Excel. And if you're the kind
Speaker 4:  of person who likes to solve puzzles, it's extremely fun. And
Speaker 4:  you've just never seen anybody get so excited about Excel ever in your life.
Speaker 4:  And I. Love it very much. David,
Speaker 5:  In your piece you call it the Sheeter Ball. Is that true?
Speaker 4:  No. God no. They don't call it that. Do they
Speaker 3:  Call it that? No.
Speaker 4:  I came up with with like 30 or 40 different dumb ideas
Speaker 4:  about what you might call this, but I think Merge Madness is is the one
Speaker 4:  that I have come back to as, as my favorite. That in the VLOOKUP
Speaker 4:  Cup. Yeah, I was, I was very proud of both of those. These
Speaker 5:  Are very good. I was really hoping these were all the actual names. Guys,
Speaker 5:  just, just take that from David Free.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, you can have it. That is, that is public domain courtesy of David
Speaker 4:  Beers. Please take that from me. But yeah,
Speaker 4:  it's the, the OCHO I think is running through the weekend if
Speaker 4:  I'm not mistaken. And there's all kinds of wild stuff going on, but the,
Speaker 4:  the ESPN stuff should be up probably as you're hearing this and
Speaker 4:  it's extremely delightful.
Speaker 5:  Competitive belt sanding. Yeah dude,
Speaker 4:  This is what I'm saying. It's the same as the tools like imagine anything
Speaker 4:  in the world and odds are there is somebody who does it for a living
Speaker 4:  and thus has really strong opinions about it. And there are probably people
Speaker 4:  who do it competitively and that kicks ass
Speaker 5:  Mullet championships.
Speaker 3:  Oh my God. This is what's gonna save ESPN. By the way, I should just do this
Speaker 3:  the whole time. Mullet
Speaker 4:  Championships. I'll take Mullet
Speaker 3:  Championships. The
Speaker 4:  Pillow Fight Championship is on this weekend. Like come on,
Speaker 5:  I'm there for it. Tetris.
Speaker 3:  That's very good. I can't believe we haven't been running the fake ESPN music
Speaker 3:  the whole time. We should have started and stopped the show. Andrew, can
Speaker 3:  we get a few more minutes of guitar Solo please? Hard? No from
Speaker 3:  Andrew. Alright, that's it. We've gone way
Speaker 3:  over as always. Bunch of cool stuff on the site. Speaking of Andrew,
Speaker 3:  he's got a great piece on the original Zenith clicker remote, which is
Speaker 3:  ultrasonic. When you push the button, it hit an aluminum rod and that's how
Speaker 3:  it controlled the tv. Super cool tech ancient idea. Of course.
Speaker 3:  Go read that. Really good. We've got a explainer on what's going on with
Speaker 3:  the incandescent light bulb band, which is very like
Speaker 3:  refuses die, but it's also dead, whatever. And there's some news about Nintendo's
Speaker 3:  next Gen console on the site. You should go read that too. And then
Speaker 3:  importantly, we are doing Land of the Giants
Speaker 3:  Tesla with former Verge Transportation reporter,
Speaker 3:  Tamara Warren and Patrick George. They are deep in it. They are
Speaker 3:  getting so much access to all kinds of people who have worked in
Speaker 3:  and around Tesla for years. It is a monster season of that
Speaker 3:  show. The Tesla Shockwave. That's what's called, in fact, it's
Speaker 3:  so good. We're gonna feed drop it on Wednesday in this feed. You'll get to
Speaker 3:  check it out. So that's really cool. Look forward to that. Oh, that site
Speaker 3:  looks great. Go listen to it. I promise you. It's the year of the Linux
Speaker 3:  desktop. It's all happening. That's it. That's
Speaker 3:  Vercast.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 1:  us an email at Vergecast at The Verge dot com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and the Box Media Podcast Network. The show is produced
Speaker 1:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. Our
Speaker 1:  editorial director is Brooke Miners. That's it. We'll see you next week.