# Transcript
ID: 9e9033a1-c0dd-41a8-be4b-a09787a01dbc
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The USB-C Holiday Spec-tacular
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7572661129394779270/-1629826557190547465/s93290-US-6349s-1703341516.mp3
Description: The Verge’s Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz start the final show of 2023 with some chat about the state of USB-C: the ups and downs of charging gadgets, the ubiquity of one cable, and what the future looks like for gadgets with ports.
The crew competes in a few rounds of USB-C Price is Right, a game we completely made up to show how confusing USB-C and its specs can be. Nilay, David, and Alex each play for a Vergecast listener to win an awesome Verge swag basket from our merch store. Check out the video version of the game below.
David and Nilay end the holiday show with Noah Dentzel, the CEO and co-founder of Nomad Goods, to talk about how USB-C on the iPhone has changed his business, the challenges of building cables, and what tech accessories he’s most excited about in 2024.
Have a happy, safe, and fast-charging holiday. We’ll see you in 2024!
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (6 ads detected)
Speaker 5:  IPhone 15 Pro also has the new USB C connector.
Speaker 6:  Happy holidays everyone. And Welcome, To. The, Vergecast, holiday
Speaker 6:  spectacular. The flagship podcast of symmetrical serial
Speaker 6:  bus connectors and holiday spirit.
Speaker 7:  I love it. The two most important things in life,
Speaker 6:  Easily. The two most important. And putting booze in the drinks
Speaker 6:  a critical part of the holiday experience that is under remarked upon.
Speaker 8:  I mean, that's my favorite specs.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, everyone's like, you're gonna drink a thing called eggnog and you're
Speaker 6:  like, put some brandy in it and we'll talk. Here's a hot cocoa
Speaker 6:  little whiskey. Yeah. Holiday party is getting lit at the USB
Speaker 6:  CIF. Anyway, this is a holiday spectacular our, our now
Speaker 6:  yearly tradition where we dive deep on one specification that makes
Speaker 6:  the entire tech industry go. I'm your friend. Neli. David.
Speaker 6:  Pierce is here.
Speaker 7:  Hello. Are we all eggnog people? We should talk about this. We can intro
Speaker 7:  everybody, but I do wanna talk about if we're eggnog people.
Speaker 6:  I think I've had eggnog once.
Speaker 8:  Oh, that's good.
Speaker 6:  But like the, the real stuff. The stuff that comes out of like a jug from
Speaker 6:  the grocery store. I'm just not
Speaker 7:  Yeah, that's fair. Like don don't know how good eggnog is made,
Speaker 7:  but it exists.
Speaker 8:  You have to like whip the eggs. I did it once and it was too rich.
Speaker 8:  I was like, oh, it's like a, it's like a pudding base. I just drank filled
Speaker 8:  with alcohol
Speaker 6:  All. right. And that pudding enthusiast, that's Alex Cranz that you're hearing
Speaker 6:  from right there.
Speaker 8:  I'm your friend who loves pudding in all its forms. Set and onset
Speaker 8:  apparently.
Speaker 6:  So this is the holiday spectacular A now yearly tradition, which is one of
Speaker 6:  my favorite things we do here on The. Vergecast. A chance to let go of the
Speaker 6:  new cycle and be gigantic nerds about one
Speaker 6:  interconnect or standard that we all depend on. Two years ago we did
Speaker 6:  HDMI, which was really fun. Last year we did Bluetooth,
Speaker 6:  which is Bluetooth this year by what I can only describe
Speaker 6:  as popular demand. We're doing USB C.
Speaker 6:  We're gonna have a little talk about the state of USB C to open things up.
Speaker 6:  Set the floor. Andrew has forced us to play a game
Speaker 6:  show. The USB C Price is Right. We did it. I'm not gonna say
Speaker 6:  anything else about it. I don't want to tip your hand on who won or lost,
Speaker 6:  but we did it and it is actually hilarious. It's really fun. And then lastly,
Speaker 6:  we're gonna talk to Noah Dentzel, who is the co-founder and CEO of
Speaker 6:  Nomad Goods an accessory company. They make a lot of USB C products.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Nomad makes like fancy accessories, I would say. And Noah was a
Speaker 7:  good hang. He is kind of eyes open in ways I didn't necessarily
Speaker 7:  expect about the weirdness of USB C, but it is also like
Speaker 7:  psyched about the future of gadget accessories in a way that felt very right
Speaker 7:  for the holiday. Spectacular.
Speaker 6:  Very right for The Vergecast holiday spectacular. The man loves the cable.
Speaker 6:  But let me just say this to open, we're like a decade into
Speaker 6:  USPC and the only way I can really describe it is it's
Speaker 6:  a mess That's
Speaker 7:  Half the story, right? It's like on the one hand, like we got it. Like we
Speaker 7:  did it. Yeah. Somebody, you know, in, in the ancient history of
Speaker 7:  technology was just like, what if all of our stuff plugged into the same
Speaker 7:  stuff and you only needed one cable? And it's like, we did it.
Speaker 7:  It's there. I only need one cable. But we did it in the
Speaker 7:  worst and most backwards and impossibly
Speaker 7:  confusing way possible. I
Speaker 8:  Like that. You can sometimes brick a device or catch it on fire by plugging
Speaker 8:  in the wrong USB cord. That's cool.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's what you want. You're like, this one provides the power of a
Speaker 6:  car battery to my phone. Let's just see what happens.
Speaker 7:  I will say, have you guys noticed my, my gadgets have been much warmer
Speaker 6:  This
Speaker 7:  Year as a result of this. Like I, I genuinely believe that that's true. That
Speaker 7:  like the average temperature of my phone and laptop and tablet has
Speaker 7:  gone up as a result of USB C and the gigantic mess of cables
Speaker 7:  in my life. I am
Speaker 8:  Not cranking my radiator as high this year. Wow. Maybe
Speaker 8:  it's just a better insulated home I'm living in. But I like the theory that
Speaker 8:  my gadgets are just warmer.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's like a, you know, it's like spiritual. You're like, no matter
Speaker 6:  what, I will use this amount of energy. And as the energy usage of LED lights
Speaker 6:  drops for my old halogen, I'm gonna pump this into my cell phone instead.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's like, it's, it's very good. It's like a fixed sum kind of
Speaker 6:  spirituality, you know? Yeah. I
Speaker 7:  Like this.
Speaker 6:  To your point though, David, this has been the dream, right? We're gonna
Speaker 6:  have one cable, one interconnect, and then the reality of
Speaker 6:  the dream that we live in is that there actually isn't
Speaker 6:  one cable, there isn't one interconnect, but they've just
Speaker 6:  used the same plug on lots of different things
Speaker 6:  to make it appear as though there is one cable all life.
Speaker 6:  And that is to some extent, yes, I agree with you
Speaker 6:  ox. There's a, there's a lot of, I wouldn't call it lying, but like
Speaker 6:  wishful obfuscation going on with U USB C.
Speaker 6:  You're like, what if you didn't think about this too hard? Like
Speaker 6:  what if this was almost what you wanted? Huh? Is that good enough?
Speaker 6:  But what's happening inside of it is because very few things are, are labeled
Speaker 6:  correctly. Very few devices will tell you what is going on.
Speaker 6:  It feels more confusing than ever. even that in in one important way,
Speaker 6:  it's gotten much simpler.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think that's right. It used to be back in the good old days that
Speaker 7:  your stuff was either, you know, micro USB or
Speaker 7:  mini USB and you could sort of distinguish them by the way that they looked.
Speaker 7:  And generally, as long as the thing fit in the thing, it was probably gonna
Speaker 7:  work. And it was very annoying because all the things had different things.
Speaker 7:  And in order to bring five gadgets, you had to have five things. Now it
Speaker 7:  does feel like slightly more of a mystery where
Speaker 7:  it's like you, you can plug it in and it fits. Like, you know that thing
Speaker 7:  where you, you have a bunch of keys on a key ring and you, you have the one
Speaker 7:  that fits in the lock but doesn't turn. Yeah. That's very much like the USB
Speaker 7:  C experience where it's like, it goes in doesn't still, that's
Speaker 7:  not the job. It turns out like fitting in the thing is not,
Speaker 7:  that's not the job.
Speaker 6:  But, okay, but here's my question. Has this reduced any amount of frustration?
Speaker 6:  So one of my favorite laptops in the entire world is the
Speaker 6:  PowerBook G four. The titanium PowerBook G four. Do you remember this thing?
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. This is the laptop. I never had one. I've, I've coveted it the most
Speaker 6:  of any, any laptop ever. Like it was just a beautiful thing that I couldn't
Speaker 6:  afford when I was in college. And I'm looking at a picture of its rear panel
Speaker 6:  just because you were talking about different ports and it was wildly more
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. Than just micro and mini USP back then. Right? It's, I
Speaker 6:  bring up this laptop 'cause it was one of the thinnest laptops ever made.
Speaker 6:  It was one inch thick, whereas Apple said one inch thin,
Speaker 6:  it's good marketing. But like, you know, they had done this thing where they
Speaker 6:  had shrunk the computer in a radical way for its time. And you look
Speaker 6:  at the back panel and you're like, the height of this computer has been determined
Speaker 6:  by the ethernet port.
Speaker 7:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  And so here's, here's what's on the back of it. Alex, you're, I know you'll
Speaker 6:  love this as as I do left to right, I'm just looking at a picture.
Speaker 6:  FireWire 400. Yeah. The most important port, the god
Speaker 6:  port as I call it. Yeah. The best port ethernet. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Two SBAs. Oh, giant outlet for its fan.
Speaker 6:  Important what appears to be a DVI connector.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Huge mass. Like massively wide. DVI connector. That's a
Speaker 6:  monitor out, an S video connector. Ooh. And then
Speaker 6:  I shit you not an RJ 11 jack for a 56 K motive.
Speaker 6:  Yes, yes.
Speaker 8:  They don't make 'em like that.
Speaker 6:  This is not happening anymore. But that was the port selection on these computers.
Speaker 6:  And you know, many ports have come and gone since then. But if you, if you
Speaker 6:  think about this is maybe one of the most important laptops of all time,
Speaker 6:  and I'm just going back to it because it's port selection
Speaker 6:  seems insane now. The design of it is
Speaker 6:  driven by the size of some of these ports. And very
Speaker 6:  often you have the wrong cable. And having the wrong cable is
Speaker 6:  a very common frustration. And it's why I'm confident that everyone
Speaker 6:  listening to the show is just like me, has a drawer full of
Speaker 6:  cables, just cables just in case you gotta plug one thing
Speaker 6:  into another thing, you're never gonna throw that cable away.
Speaker 8:  That's how I knew I was an adult was I had like a box of cables.
Speaker 8:  I was like, this is it. Like I was like 22 straight outta college. And I
Speaker 8:  was like, well I'm an adult now 'cause I got this big box of cables just
Speaker 8:  like my parents did.
Speaker 7:  So first of all, one box of cables is not enough boxes of cables. Let
Speaker 7:  22,
Speaker 8:  I was young,
Speaker 7:  But the big change that I made recently in my life was I threw away all the
Speaker 7:  cables that were very old and I didn't know what they went
Speaker 7:  to. So for years I had a whole box just of cables
Speaker 7:  to mysterious things that I didn't know about. Yeah. And I kept
Speaker 7:  them all for all this time because I had one really old western
Speaker 7:  digital hard drive from when I was in college that I
Speaker 7:  knew at some point I was gonna want again, but never actually took the time
Speaker 7:  to do anything with. And I had a bin full of cables that
Speaker 7:  might have been for the hard drive and So I kept the whole bin around. And
Speaker 7:  recently I took the hard drive to Best Buy because I literally couldn't get
Speaker 7:  it to turn on again. They got all the stuff off of it for me and I threw
Speaker 7:  away the whole box of mysterious cables. And it was, it was
Speaker 7:  a truly transformative day in my life.
Speaker 6:  This is an important thing that you're bringing up. You had a product, it
Speaker 6:  may or may not have had a proprietary cable. It probably just had that weird
Speaker 6:  super speed USB three cable.
Speaker 7:  So its problem was its power cable, which was a proprietary thing. Yes.
Speaker 6:  This is the main thing, right? It had weird proprietary power cable with
Speaker 6:  maybe some weird pins or a barrel connector and that
Speaker 6:  power system, there's still a lot of stuff with barrel connectors, but a
Speaker 6:  barrel connector with a a adapter and you don't know how much power is coming
Speaker 6:  at adapter and if you get rid of it then you're screwed. And you gotta get
Speaker 6:  one of those long plastic blister packy things. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 6:  With all the different barrel connectors and you're like sliding the dips.
Speaker 6:  Like that's bad. USB just
Speaker 6:  eliminated that problem from like the jump mini and
Speaker 6:  micro USB started the, the process of eliminating that problem. Micro USB
Speaker 6:  got pretty far along there. And then USB CI think his
Speaker 6:  almost completely obviated this thing like USB C is the
Speaker 6:  world's power connector that is un unequivocally a
Speaker 6:  success.
Speaker 7:  Yes, I agree with that. As the like make it turn on
Speaker 7:  thing USB C is is a huge, huge, huge win.
Speaker 6:  And we're now up to 240 watt USB C
Speaker 6:  chargers. There's some really great material science that's going on
Speaker 6:  underneath that. Gallium nitrate is the thing that replaces silicon and all
Speaker 6:  these devices. There is just a furious effort at
Speaker 6:  GaN Chargers, gallium nitrate chargers, making them carry more and more power
Speaker 6:  in smaller, small spaces with less heat. That is just awesome.
Speaker 6:  Like that's just a bunch of scientists and engineers and physicists making
Speaker 6:  it happen.
Speaker 7:  Is it just my impression that Anchor is way ahead on the
Speaker 7:  gallium nitrate stuff? Like is there a reason Anchor stuff seems to be so
Speaker 7:  popular in that world right now?
Speaker 6:  Right. Anchor's a fascinating company. It was a bunch of people who worked
Speaker 6:  at Amazon. They realized this was an ecosystem they could sell into. They
Speaker 6:  went off and started a company, they saw a lot of things. Now the CEO of
Speaker 6:  anchor Steven Yang was on decoder in 2021 and he told me that they had partnered
Speaker 6:  with a company called Power Innovations, which makes like
Speaker 6:  the bleeding edge Gallium nitrite
Speaker 7:  Also a very Amazon sounding brand.
Speaker 6:  Truly. No, that's, it's like too many real words. Like now
Speaker 6:  it's just like letter like letters and numbers. But basically Anchor has
Speaker 6:  an exclusive on bleeding edge GaN chip sets. Oh. So they get 'em
Speaker 6:  for like a year, six months to a year before everybody else. And you can
Speaker 6:  see that's really cool, right? Just from like a business perspective.
Speaker 6:  They identified that as a competitive advantage, went out and spent the money
Speaker 6:  ahead of it. And now they have a six month exclusive in the same way that,
Speaker 6:  you know, like Sony buys exclusives on PlayStation games like anchors, like
Speaker 6:  we have exclusives on GaN chip sets for a minute. It's
Speaker 7:  Badass.
Speaker 6:  That's obviously changed. Like there's other companies and there are other
Speaker 6:  companies that that are, that are more aggressive. Like you go on Amazon,
Speaker 6:  you're like 600 watt charger, it's the size of a quarter and you're like,
Speaker 6:  I don
Speaker 8:  Will it catch fire?
Speaker 6:  But so just from that perspective, USB C is a huge success
Speaker 6:  because of GaN because of this material science innovation because these
Speaker 6:  companies have identified a, a market opportunity in selling more higher
Speaker 6:  powered chargers can do everything. That means you can get everything from
Speaker 6:  an electric toothbrush to a laptop off the same charger with the same
Speaker 6:  plug over the sometimes the same cables, the cables have to rated.
Speaker 6:  That's a, just an overall like barrel connector should go away.
Speaker 6:  Seems like a big victory.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I agree with that. And I think it has made the like
Speaker 7:  multi-port charger thing like a true must have
Speaker 7:  accessory in life. Yeah. Like the one thing you can plug into the wall that
Speaker 7:  has the three USB slots on it. Anchor cells, I'm sure
Speaker 7:  infinity of them. So do lots of other companies. I started to see them everywhere.
Speaker 7:  Like I noticed this, I was flying last week and it honestly
Speaker 7:  seemed like one in every three people at the airport either had
Speaker 7:  a battery pack or something you could plug into the wall and get
Speaker 7:  multiple USB ports out of And that is just now like how everybody charges
Speaker 7:  everything. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And and that's created the market for battery packs. Right. You just see,
Speaker 6:  okay, the market sort of got created here in a big way.
Speaker 8:  I just call them the flail. The flail because like you plug enough quartz
Speaker 8:  in, it just looks like a little flail. You
Speaker 7:  Swing it around. Yeah, I like
Speaker 8:  That. Ugh.
Speaker 6:  So that's a good thing inside of that, still some problems, right? Right.
Speaker 6:  Not every product supports every charging speed.
Speaker 6:  I still just worry that things are getting hot as we've mentioned a few times.
Speaker 6:  And then there's the problem, which we've talked about in the rich house
Speaker 6:  a few times now, where a lot of companies are doing this in the laziest possible
Speaker 6:  way. They're not adding the pennies of additional costs to
Speaker 6:  their products to put on the two resistors that make USB C
Speaker 6:  power go. So they've effectively just replaced
Speaker 6:  the micro USB port with a USB C port. And
Speaker 6:  if you plug an actual USB C to USB C charger onto it,
Speaker 6:  it doesn't charge because the thing doesn't know how to call for power from
Speaker 6:  USB C 'cause it's not actually USB C you have to use a USB A to USB
Speaker 6:  C cord, which just drives me insane. And I,
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna propose on this, the Holiday spectacular in the holiday spirit
Speaker 6:  in the spirit of Christmas, that all of those people should go to jail.
Speaker 6:  And I, I can't think of a better present for all of us gathered today
Speaker 6:  around the Holiday hearth than jail. But that could be my
Speaker 6:  gift to America and the world. I think we can agree. I will have done the
Speaker 6:  Christmas community at least as much of a service as Mariah Carey,
Speaker 7:  We're skipping right past like coal and everybody's stocking. We're going
Speaker 7:  straight to jail.
Speaker 8:  Straight
Speaker 7:  To jail. I like it. All. right.
Speaker 6:  Th and that I would say represents the best case of USB C right? We've, we've
Speaker 6:  basically solved this power problem. We've created a market for a new kind
Speaker 6:  of product, these battery packs and these multi chargers. There's a lot
Speaker 6:  of innovation and engineering resources and money and invention going into
Speaker 6:  a thing. And it has tangible consumer benefits. And then there's
Speaker 6:  like 4% of it that's bad, which is like the cheapest products. It's a lot
Speaker 6:  of off-brand headphones and speakers. I think I've mentioned the, the milk
Speaker 6:  frother we use to stir protein powder. It's like, that's really annoying.
Speaker 6:  There's just a bunch of that stuff where they just like, USB C will fix it
Speaker 6:  and they didn't do it the right way. So it frustrates everyone. I, we've
Speaker 6:  had people since we've mentioned it the first time, we've gotten a bunch
Speaker 6:  of emails from people who are like, I threw something away 'cause I didn't
Speaker 6:  realize this was the problem.
Speaker 7:  Oh wow. I thought it
Speaker 6:  Was just broken. That's crazy to me. Yeah. And I'm saying this is
Speaker 6:  the best case.
Speaker 7:  So, so far the worst experience I've personally had is kinda
Speaker 7:  what you're describing with the, the A to C connector where you plug it in
Speaker 7:  and nothing happens. I have not had anything problematic
Speaker 7:  happen. I know there are risks. It's like you could plug something in and
Speaker 7:  your phone could explode. That's a real thing that could in theory happen
Speaker 7:  that has not happened to me. Have either of you had sort of actual bad
Speaker 7:  USB C experiences so far? Mine are just all, I plug
Speaker 7:  a thing in, nothing happens. I take it out, I plug it in, nothing happens.
Speaker 7:  And then I get angry at my battery being dead. Feel
Speaker 8:  Like I busted a hard drive. I feel like I busted like an off-brand hard
Speaker 8:  drive by plugging it into the wrong USB C And it just died.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It was just like, nope. No ma'am.
Speaker 7:  That actually kind of makes sense. It like tries to come to life and then
Speaker 7:  just uhuh
Speaker 8:  And like after that, even when I found the right cables, it never worked.
Speaker 8:  And I blame was it maybe because the hard drive was crappy? Possibly.
Speaker 8:  But I like to blame the USB CI
Speaker 6:  Have a similar experience. It is dumber than
Speaker 6:  Alex's. I don don't want to don don't wanna mince words
Speaker 6:  about it.
Speaker 7:  So you were drinking some eggnog one night. Was
Speaker 8:  It a beard
Speaker 6:  Trimmer? It was not a beard trimmer. My beard trimmer is not yet USB. CI
Speaker 6:  don't that that needs a full on barrel connector to get through this forest.
Speaker 6:  You gotta you gotta rev the engine. Max has a like a vtech kid
Speaker 6:  zoom camera. If you have children, you, you know that these things
Speaker 6:  are just, they're everywhere. Every kid has one. They're fun, they're cute
Speaker 6:  and they are notorious for being really finicky about
Speaker 6:  what USB c cables are compatible with them. Even just
Speaker 6:  regular USB a to micro USB cable, real messy. Like some
Speaker 6:  of 'em work, some of 'em don't. And everyone I know just ends up buying a
Speaker 6:  micro SSD card to use because the cable thing is so
Speaker 6:  fussy with these cameras. Yeah, I didn't do that every time I like get,
Speaker 6:  want to get photos off the camera. I remember that. I should buy a micro
Speaker 6:  SD card for this camera. So I don't have to deal with trying 500 cables.
Speaker 6:  And then I forget don don't do it. So I'm trying to get photos off
Speaker 6:  this thing and obviously my laptop only has USPC ports on it. So I'm like
Speaker 6:  going through adapters and the adapters end up effectively
Speaker 6:  corrupting photos on the camera until I finally gave up, came
Speaker 6:  upstairs to this delightful 2015 iMac that I used to Vergecast from
Speaker 6:  and plugged directly into USB a port on the back of it. And I got
Speaker 6:  off whatever photos I could and I was like, this is bad. Yeah, yeah. Right.
Speaker 6:  And that's like a dongle problem. And you know, it's like, it, it's
Speaker 6:  all, it's like kind of all the messes at once. But like you should be able
Speaker 6:  to just plug into what is effectively an SD card reader and get files
Speaker 6:  without thinking, okay, this thing is USB a that
Speaker 6:  thing is USPC, this thing is a really finicky micro SSD
Speaker 6:  implementation. And now I've corrupted some photos that my kid took on our
Speaker 6:  camera. That's by far the worst USB experience I had. And somewhere
Speaker 6:  in there is that I was leaping through Dongle Town.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Well and the the problem with that is it's so sneaky
Speaker 7:  in its problem that it makes everything worse. Right? Like
Speaker 7:  I don't have the right cable for this. It's a very obvious problem. It's
Speaker 7:  a very annoying problem. But you at least know what the problem is. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And then it's like, okay, if I go get the correct cable, everything will
Speaker 7:  be fine. In this case, you're, you're left to like troubleshoot
Speaker 7:  through a bunch of steps that you have no actual visibility into. Because
Speaker 7:  something along the way that seemed like it probably should have worked and
Speaker 7:  all fit together literally and figuratively didn't work. And that's
Speaker 7:  the thing about USB C that has always driven me the most crazy, like the
Speaker 7:  Opal camera came with a USB C cable and would only work
Speaker 7:  with its USB C cable. And it's like my friends that is,
Speaker 7:  we're doing it wrong here. That is like not the spirit of a universal
Speaker 7:  connector at that point. Just have a proprietary barrel connector. What the
Speaker 7:  hell difference does it make?
Speaker 8:  Well that just explains something about my Opal camera. So
Speaker 8:  I learned something.
Speaker 6:  So we, we, I've said it, I've said the magical incantation. We have to talk
Speaker 6:  about it now we gotta talk about Dongle Town.
Speaker 7:  The magical incantation is just the word dongle town. Yeah. And the dongles
Speaker 7:  show up
Speaker 6:  And now we're in Dongle Town. You just like say it three times and then you
Speaker 6:  go to dongle town. So USB C first comes out, I remind everyone it came out
Speaker 6:  first on the Apple MacBook, the, the tiny little
Speaker 6:  MacBook, still the world's best playing computer. Remember that computer
Speaker 6:  only had a single port, it was so tiny. And I, again, I go back to the titanium
Speaker 6:  PowerBook G four that I was talking about. That computer it, a
Speaker 6:  real design constraint for that computer was the height of the ethernet port.
Speaker 6:  Apple says we don't wanna do this. This is also the, what you might call
Speaker 6:  the, the peak Johnny I era. We wanna make the laptop as thin as possible.
Speaker 6:  We're gonna cut it down to just a single port because all you need to do
Speaker 6:  with this computer is charge it. Maybe you wanna do some data stuff. So
Speaker 6:  we'll use USB C we'll figure out how to charge it. They went to the
Speaker 6:  USB C implementers form the USB IF Apple
Speaker 6:  dictates the design of USB C They have had a hand on this
Speaker 6:  wheel since the very beginning and it started with that first MacBook.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, there's a lot of lightning in USB C for that reason.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There's a, there's a lot of Apple ideas in there. The connector is
Speaker 6:  very much their idea. It was designed to be a partner to Lightning, which
Speaker 6:  is how they got, they were able to get there in the end with the iPhone,
Speaker 6:  which we should talk about. But you know, this MacBook comes out and everyone
Speaker 6:  says, ah, dongle town. Like in order to use this computer you will have
Speaker 6:  to have a series of complicated dongles and apple's response to this with
Speaker 6:  that computer in particular was no you won't because no
Speaker 6:  one plugs anything into our laptops. We've, we've done the research, we've
Speaker 6:  done the studies, especially consumer laptops. No one plugs anything in
Speaker 6:  Be Happy with wifi and Bluetooth fine. And this computer is so
Speaker 6:  underpowered that it is true that no one ever plugs
Speaker 7:  Anything in
Speaker 6:  Like when I, I had two of them and I, I truly believe that this is
Speaker 6:  the world's best travel computer. I took this thing on planes I've live logged
Speaker 6:  a million Apple events with with one of them. It had a terrible butterfly
Speaker 6:  keyboard. Many, many compromises. But I never felt like I need to plug anything
Speaker 6:  into this other than a power cable. Yeah. You move through the years
Speaker 6:  and Apple releases many more computers now maybe they have two USB C
Speaker 6:  ports and we are in dongle town. Like in order to have a laptop,
Speaker 6:  you've gotta have one of those like eight in one dongles that has a bunch
Speaker 6:  of useful ports on it. Apple eventually relents their
Speaker 6:  MacBook Pros now have lots and lots of ports. There are literal cheers in
Speaker 6:  the audience. And they're like the SD card reader is back on the MacBook
Speaker 6:  Pro. Yeah. My MacBook Pro is an HDMI port on it. Like we're many
Speaker 6:  ways back to what we, where we started. But all the ports have gotten smaller.
Speaker 6:  And I'm sitting here in 2024. I'm wondering are we, are we in dongle town
Speaker 6:  anymore? Like I, I still carry one around but I don't know why
Speaker 8:  Security,
Speaker 6:  Like maybe Sometimes I need a USB a port and that's it. That's all I can
Speaker 6:  think of.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I I carry mine for the USB A and also like I was always
Speaker 8:  in dongle town because of that stupid dv like
Speaker 8:  if you had a monitor it always was VGA and then your laptop was
Speaker 8:  always DVI. So you were always doing dongles anyway, I didn't have to carry
Speaker 8:  as many of them. Like, it wasn't for little small quick things
Speaker 8:  like SSD card reads and, and oh I need to plug a thumb drive in So
Speaker 8:  I. Don't know I'm still a dongle town. I'm okay with it.
Speaker 7:  So the thing that I wonder, hearing you talk about this though, is whose
Speaker 7:  fault is that? Because like, I'm, I'm sitting here on
Speaker 7:  the computer I use every day as a MAC mini that I have connected to a
Speaker 7:  scepter monitor that I bought for super cheap on Amazon and could tell you
Speaker 7:  nothing about except that it exists and it's my monitor. It uses
Speaker 7:  HDMI, so it's HDMI to HDMI. And that is just the way
Speaker 7:  that It works. And I'm like, whose fault is it that I don't connect these
Speaker 7:  two things to a USB cable? Because I think there's a world in which the answer
Speaker 7:  to the MacBook Pros problem was more USB c ports
Speaker 7:  not let's bring back the old ports. And I think bringing back the old ports
Speaker 7:  was the right call, but I can't figure out whose fault it is that we haven't
Speaker 7:  gotten to the all USB c everything
Speaker 7:  accessory universe faster. It's
Speaker 8:  A lot of cost stuff, right? Like, like it's more expensive
Speaker 8:  to, to put in a lot of these ports. When you talk to the monitor makers,
Speaker 8:  they, they're like, well no our, our people want display port because
Speaker 8:  there's some stuff that USB C can't do that display port can't and vice versa.
Speaker 7:  I refuse to believe that, that anyone on earth wants display port.
Speaker 8:  Oh my
Speaker 6:  God. Well display port is a better standard than HT MI that is maybe for
Speaker 6:  next year. Oh that's
Speaker 7:  True.
Speaker 6:  Next year's holiday spectacular is just display port
Speaker 6:  V-H-D-M-I, you know, like we'll do it as a court case.
Speaker 7:  Love it. But you're,
Speaker 8:  You're, you're seeing it like the monitors I'm on right now are these two
Speaker 8:  like $800 LG monitors that I'm still very upset that I
Speaker 8:  spent this much money on as I did on them. But they've got USB C on the back
Speaker 8:  and, and It works, but they also have USB A and that's the only way you can
Speaker 8:  use the back lights on them to like make the back lights do cool stuff.
Speaker 8:  So it's like they're kind of dumb.
Speaker 6:  Well so you get USB C as a connector might be good and can
Speaker 6:  support all this power USB C is a standard, is
Speaker 6:  not capable of doing all the things that you want. Right? And so if you were
Speaker 6:  to go to an all USB C world to Alex's point, you would
Speaker 6:  increase cost 'cause you'd be basically building in adapters somewhere along
Speaker 6:  the line to move the data into different kinds of
Speaker 6:  standards or different kinds of pin configurations. And I think you do want
Speaker 6:  an HT MI that is focused on being the best
Speaker 6:  display connector up against its mortal rival
Speaker 6:  display port, which is better. And I think you do want a display port team
Speaker 6:  that's like we're taking 'em down Merry Christmas.
Speaker 7:  You're describing like bundling and unbundling, right? Like we've, we, we've
Speaker 7:  been through a bundling phase, which is USB C and then everybody's gonna
Speaker 7:  come to the realization that oh it's great that all of this is in one
Speaker 7:  place, but what it means when it tries to be everything is that it can't
Speaker 7:  be the best at anything. And then we're gonna spend the next decade with
Speaker 7:  like a new series of very specific one-to-one
Speaker 7:  things that are better at one thing than USB C. And then we're gonna do
Speaker 7:  this again in 10 years and be like, wouldn't it be great if we had a standard
Speaker 7:  that just brought everything together and you could just plug it in. I
Speaker 8:  Don? I don't think it's that many things though when you think about like
Speaker 8:  what the ports are being used. It's, it's vi it's visual ports, right? Like
Speaker 8:  it's HTMI and display port and that's because they're really good
Speaker 8:  at at doing visual stuff in a way that USB C just isn't quite as good at.
Speaker 8:  But if you think about most like data transfer, everybody's moved to USB
Speaker 8:  C or they're using Thunderbolt, which is like USB C but more expensive and
Speaker 8:  it's the same port
Speaker 7:  Fancy USB C, it's
Speaker 8:  Fancy USB C and even audio you maybe have an an
Speaker 8:  optical audio out, but typically the 3.5 millimeter jack is like more
Speaker 8:  than enough for most people. And phones, they're like no, we don't even need
Speaker 8:  that. USB is enough.
Speaker 7:  I was gonna say, I can't believe Neil, I just let you get that far into that
Speaker 7:  sentence.
Speaker 6:  No, I hitched that her That's
Speaker 7:  Fine. I
Speaker 8:  Was, I was going as fast as I could to get get there before the hissing.
Speaker 8:  No, but
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think you're right. It's like right the, the really fast data transfer
Speaker 6:  like lives in the world of pci, Thunderbolt and PCI have
Speaker 6:  a connection there that's important. Everything else is kind of on USB
Speaker 6:  and then the thing that is not is the two display connectors.
Speaker 6:  And even that is getting into a realm of silliness, right? Where
Speaker 6:  it's like how many eight K displays can Apple plug into one Mac mini
Speaker 6:  is like, that's how we're measuring how, how, how important those are. And
Speaker 6:  maybe some things over time like additional HDR bandwidth or more colors
Speaker 6:  or whatever is gonna be needed there will come and I'm sure it'll be great.
Speaker 6:  But most everything now can run on USB C and what you're, what you see is
Speaker 6:  Yep. Sometimes you sit in a conference room and there's just a bundle of
Speaker 6:  display adapters sitting on the Yeah. On the table. But they all have USB
Speaker 6:  connectors on the end. That to me just feels like a, a kind of victory.
Speaker 6:  I'm not sure it's the right one. Like we defeated complexity with
Speaker 6:  additional complexity but at least all the connectors are the same. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  But it's smaller complexity I guess. Which is something Yeah. That's a win.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I mean part of me feels like, I think I, I'm torn between these two
Speaker 7:  ideas that this transition is, was always gonna take a long time because
Speaker 7:  it essentially involves replacing every gadget on earth at
Speaker 7:  some point. And that's a lot of work. And you can fix your own
Speaker 7:  gadget and like I've seen this even with the iPhone 15, right? Getting the
Speaker 7:  iPhone 15, fantastic love being able to use USB C
Speaker 7:  my wife and I can now charge our phones with the same thing. She has a Pixel.
Speaker 7:  I have an iPhone. It's great. Huge victories for everybody. I have a
Speaker 7:  new cable that I had to get for my car. My phone now doesn't plug into certain
Speaker 7:  things that used to plug into, I have a bunch of accessories that are now
Speaker 7:  dead. Right? Like that transition's gonna take a long time and I, I get that.
Speaker 7:  But also we've been at this for a decade now and it doesn't feel like
Speaker 7:  we're close. Yeah. And So I, I can't decide if we're running too slowly or
Speaker 7:  if I'm being too ambitious here. Let's
Speaker 6:  Wrap this up by talking about the, the big news of the year for USB C
Speaker 6:  Apple switched the iPhone to USB C. Yeah. This is the big thing in a, in
Speaker 6:  a normal universe when that happened we'd run a
Speaker 6:  headline like USB C arrives or it's finally here, the
Speaker 6:  transition's. And that is just, no one's doing that because of the iPhone.
Speaker 6:  That's what I mean. Instead it's, yeah to your point it's a combo of finally
Speaker 6:  and oh boy this is gonna take a long time. Yeah and I feel that way
Speaker 6:  to be clear, I feel that way about USB A too, but because there isn't some
Speaker 6:  giant company that is switching away from USB A to mark
Speaker 6:  a moment. It's hard to talk about in the same way. but it is true that
Speaker 6:  USB A is I believe in world history, the most
Speaker 6:  popular power port of all time. Like it is the most popular
Speaker 6:  plug outlet in world history. I believe it. It's just everywhere. It it a
Speaker 6:  standard you can be anywhere in the world and you see a USB, a port
Speaker 6:  and you're like, I'm gonna plug these God awful cheap LED strip lights into
Speaker 6:  'em and they're gonna light up.
Speaker 7:  Well first you're gonna have to flip it over 'cause you plugged it in wrong.
Speaker 7:  Exactly. But that the second time it'll work.
Speaker 6:  That's kind of amazing. No other plug outlet has ever, I'm gonna charge my
Speaker 6:  phone. I found a USB, a port God I hope it isn't loaded
Speaker 6:  with malware. I'm gonna carry one of those little adapters that only that
Speaker 6:  cuts everything with the power. That's incredible. But that is also,
Speaker 6:  you gotta take all of those out. We, you know, we're renovating our house.
Speaker 6:  I'm buying plug outlets and I'm buying plug outlets with USB C and
Speaker 6:  one USB A in the middle. 'cause there's enough stuff that I know I'm gonna
Speaker 6:  wanna plug into that plug outlet. That's nuts. And now I've just
Speaker 6:  installed another USB, a outlet into the wall of this house that's gonna
Speaker 6:  be there for 20 years. Right.
Speaker 7:  You're both helping and hurting all at the same time.
Speaker 6:  You're persisting. It's, and it's the same with lightning like apple. There's
Speaker 6:  you know, a billion plus iOS devices out there with lightning ports on them.
Speaker 6:  Apple still selling some phones with lightning ports. Apple still sell some
Speaker 6:  iPads with lightning ports on them. Yeah. They're gonna keep selling 'em
Speaker 6:  for a long time. EU be damned Merry Christmas to the
Speaker 6:  European Commission says Tim Cook happy
Speaker 6:  holidays you bastards. And he ships his billionth iPad.
Speaker 6:  Like that stuff isn't going anywhere and it kind of means the, the core
Speaker 6:  dream of USPC, maybe no connector will ever achieve it. Right?
Speaker 6:  'cause there's always gonna be standard sort of waxing and waning and as
Speaker 6:  everything gets bigger and everything becomes a computer, the installed bases
Speaker 6:  just get bigger and bigger and bigger and bigger and people
Speaker 8:  Are cheap. I mean how long has the PS two port
Speaker 8:  persisted? I think you could probably buy something with a PS two port right
Speaker 8:  now and you shouldn't Yeah, you shouldn't be able to do that. That's just
Speaker 8:  stupid. It's like it's older than half of the people that we
Speaker 8:  work with
Speaker 6:  That said this is true. You can get all the way here. I've seen people
Speaker 6:  assemble just the most bananas USB C dongle chains.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You can get an A PSS two to USB A to
Speaker 6:  USB C connector and use them on a lot of computers. People still use
Speaker 6:  Apple extended keyboard twos. They're very popular. The big clicky keys.
Speaker 6:  Apple desktop bust to USB A to USB C Totally works.
Speaker 6:  It's kind of amazing, you know when software backwards compatibility is so
Speaker 6:  hard yet with USB C in hardware, people almost take
Speaker 6:  it for granted. Which is pretty incredible.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I mean kudos to like the people who did this for making it a continuing
Speaker 7:  standard. But I think now we're at a point where we've agreed that this is
Speaker 7:  the standard and it's gonna keep moving so fast that I wonder if we're gonna
Speaker 7:  end up sort of accidentally at another unrecognizable standard before too
Speaker 7:  long and if maybe we're even there already. Like USB C is a
Speaker 7:  collection of different things that all kind of look the same already and
Speaker 7:  the EU is out here regulating like what the port has to look like. And I
Speaker 7:  think that's good. But I also wonder if instead of that thing you're describing
Speaker 7:  where we've kind of had really good connectivity over
Speaker 7:  the years between the ideas of USB, if instead
Speaker 7:  we're gonna have a bunch of things that look the same and are very different
Speaker 7:  and that's just gonna be where it lands. I have no idea. I
Speaker 8:  Mean that's what we're doing with HDMI right now and and a lot of other ports
Speaker 8:  is there's like that conflict and nobody wants to properly label things.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And if they just properly labeled things and made the labels easy to
Speaker 8:  understand, this would all be solved. But Oh yeah.
Speaker 6:  If you are a member of the United States Congress listening to this The
Speaker 6:  Vergecast holiday spectacular about USB C welcome.
Speaker 7:  I think there's at least 40 or 50 senators listening to this right now. No
Speaker 7:  question.
Speaker 6:  At least half the Senate is listening to this.
Speaker 6:  Look, first of all, if you're listening to this and you're in Congress, you
Speaker 6:  are the most effective politicians s here.
Speaker 6:  I want you to feel great about it. You are here on the ground with the people.
Speaker 6:  You're sharing the holiday spirit with them and you are talking about
Speaker 6:  real problems in America. Second, you have an opportunity
Speaker 6:  to outdo the Europeans if you just pass some labeling standards.
Speaker 6:  Everything in tech right now is being regulated by the Europeans. Yep. You
Speaker 6:  know, and you can, you can do it, you can take weird St Nicholas
Speaker 6:  from France and turn 'em into Santa Claus in the greatest American
Speaker 6:  Christmas spirit. You can do it and you can say, look, you are, you are,
Speaker 6:  you're focused on USB C here in America. We label our wires and
Speaker 6:  you can, you can just take Christmas from them and I want you to do it please.
Speaker 6:  Because that is actually what we just put labels on the plugs that say how
Speaker 6:  fast they can charge and how much data they they can support. And then everyone
Speaker 6:  will be happy will, will lead better lives in America.
Speaker 7:  You have to also make it a Spec that people care about. Like this is the,
Speaker 7:  the learning experience over Christmas. Like sit down and really learn about
Speaker 7:  the charging requirements of all of your individual devices. Take
Speaker 7:  some time instead of reading the night before Christmas, read some instruction
Speaker 7:  manuals to your computers. Yeah. Because like I think about what,
Speaker 7:  what happened to TVs, right? Like everybody got very aware of what seven
Speaker 7:  20 P and 10 80 p and 4K and eight K were and those things get better because
Speaker 7:  people start to care about it and they'll buy the better ones. And now
Speaker 7:  I've become like a, a zealot for telling people to buy expensive cables,
Speaker 7:  which is the opposite of what I used to say. I used to tell people just like
Speaker 7:  buy the Amazon basics, the cheapest thing you can find for whatever cable
Speaker 7:  you need. It'll probably work now. I'm like if you wanna live the as
Speaker 7:  few cables as possible lifestyle, you have to buy good ones and you have
Speaker 7:  to buy ones that are more than most of your devices need in order for it
Speaker 7:  to work for most of your devices. And people just don't know
Speaker 7:  because they've never had to and realistically they shouldn't. Like this
Speaker 7:  should be a solved problem. But we, this has to be a thing people care about.
Speaker 7:  Like I'm the problem because I didn't make sure that my monitor was
Speaker 7:  the right connectivity for what I wanted. And if we don't start to demand
Speaker 7:  that it won't get better.
Speaker 6:  That's wild. Right. 'cause HDMI, which carries much more data on the regular,
Speaker 6:  it needs to be more reliable in order to support all the high end video standards.
Speaker 6:  It is kind of like just buy whatever cable. Right.
Speaker 8:  But it's not truly,
Speaker 7:  But it's close enough. Like for most cases,
Speaker 6:  If you're out there buying the monster cables like you're getting taken for
Speaker 6:  a ride, if you buy a high quality HTMI cable, it's gonna be fine. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Right. In a way that if you don't buy a high
Speaker 6:  quality USB c cable, you, you bone, you're not guaranteed to get life out
Speaker 6:  of it through as like technology progresses. And
Speaker 7:  You'll notice the difference. Like I, I work in my basement and my
Speaker 7:  bedroom is two floors away upstairs. All of my cables are right next to me.
Speaker 7:  The thing I use to charge my phone all the way upstairs is a piece of
Speaker 7:  crap USB C cable that takes a hundred thousand years to charge my phone and
Speaker 7:  I have to change it and I have not because I keep forgetting when I'm upstairs
Speaker 7:  and it's too much work to come all the way downstairs. But it's like it,
Speaker 7:  it's a real thing. And you will notice the difference between a really good
Speaker 7:  cable and a really crappy cable in a way that I think with HDMI like most
Speaker 7:  people are not going to notice the difference. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Most people don't even know like HDMI 2.0 and 2.1 and so they're like that's
Speaker 8:  fine.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And if you're like, let's spend $65 on this cable, like someone will
Speaker 7:  come out and just start screaming at you.
Speaker 8:  But you know if your milk foamer is not charging, it's
Speaker 7:  Exactly right. Neli can't make coffee if his milk foamer is not charging.
Speaker 7:  And that's very important.
Speaker 6:  Okay, here's my last piece on this and then we should go to the game
Speaker 6:  show. This was the year that Apple did the big transition to
Speaker 6:  USB C. The iPhone has it now. The EU has mandated it that
Speaker 6:  this is all big news. I I feel like that's stuff in the weeds of it
Speaker 6:  is less important than how does it feel to use technology that
Speaker 6:  all has this port. So that's what we spend our time on. but it is the thing
Speaker 6:  that happened. Does that feel like it was a success? Does it feel like it
Speaker 6:  will be an enduring success or are we just waiting for
Speaker 6:  USB C USB CD to come along?
Speaker 6:  USB F
Speaker 7:  Six G will change everything you'd like.
Speaker 6:  That's what I'm saying. Will six G change everything or did we get there
Speaker 6:  with this big European regulation? And finally the switch from the iPhone
Speaker 7:  Alex. What do you think
Speaker 8:  It'll change? Nothing.
Speaker 6:  You think it'll change? Nothing. I don't think
Speaker 8:  Anything's gonna change really. I think we're gonna continue this like slow
Speaker 8:  roll.
Speaker 7:  I'm a little more hopeful than that. I think the iPhone changing
Speaker 7:  is a big deal. I think it would've been a bigger deal if the iPhone had switched
Speaker 7:  10 years ago. I think there's a really interesting parallel universe if
Speaker 7:  instead of launching USB C on a MacBook, it had launched it on an
Speaker 7:  iPhone and how the technology world would look different. Now all
Speaker 7:  these years after that I think it would look very different and much better.
Speaker 7:  I've talked to a lot of people in the last say six months who are very
Speaker 7:  excited about this and what it'll mean for the kinds of accessories
Speaker 7:  you can buy. Knowing that they're gonna last more than the life of
Speaker 7:  your phone and the kinds of things that you can put into cars and put into
Speaker 7:  fixtures in your house and like with confidence that this port is going to
Speaker 7:  be around in some way for the next let's say 10 years. There's stuff
Speaker 7:  you can do that is cool and different and exciting for everybody.
Speaker 7:  I think if we are still in this place where I can plug a thing into my devices
Speaker 7:  and I have no idea what's gonna happen in another 12 months,
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna be a lot less optimistic. Join
Speaker 8:  Me.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, either. Either We're gonna spend 2024 like weeding out the
Speaker 7:  crappy stuff on Amazon starting to figure this stuff out The next rev. A
Speaker 7:  lot of of a lot of these gadgets will make more affordances for that stuff
Speaker 7:  and it'll be great. Or we're just gonna be overrun by
Speaker 7:  crappy USB A the USB C gadgets. And I'm gonna be on Alex's side saying
Speaker 7:  actually nothing has gotten better. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I'm somewhere in the middle. And here's what I'll throw out there to just
Speaker 6:  complexify this whole situation. My family has a wide variety of
Speaker 6:  iPhones in it and some of us have a USB C iPhones, some of us have lightning
Speaker 6:  iPhones and the most popular person on my family on our recent
Speaker 6:  family trip was my nephew who had a MagSafe battery
Speaker 6:  pack that worked with everyone's
Speaker 7:  Phones. That's so real.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And it, it was like, oh there's another thing going on here that
Speaker 6:  is interesting. Right? There's another out for Apple, you know, MagSafe and
Speaker 6:  she charging Q2 and MagSafe are really tightly aligned. That's becoming its
Speaker 6:  own little standard right next to USB CII think that's gonna make the
Speaker 6:  ecosystems a little more interesting and a little more compatible. But
Speaker 6:  we'll see. Like that's the only thing I'll throw in the mix. I'm also optimistic
Speaker 6:  that at least one turn of it is done and that
Speaker 6:  USB C seems future proofed in a way. Like it's the thing,
Speaker 6:  it can support everything from a laptop to whatever to change the
Speaker 6:  world's laptops to the next power standard. You need a good reason.
Speaker 6:  Like this is a tiny little connector and you get a hundred watts out of it.
Speaker 6:  240 watts out of it to that's most laptops. You don't need anything
Speaker 6:  like it. The design constraint it imposes is not an inch tall
Speaker 6:  ethernet connector. Like you can get what you want out of it. So I,
Speaker 6:  that's my hope is that it has done what it needs to do for now and
Speaker 6:  the next turn looks like magnetic charging or whatever. And that is gonna
Speaker 6:  make this transition hopefully a little easier 'cause there's something compatible
Speaker 6:  with both along the way. And then if a year or two from now, most
Speaker 6:  things will just have USB C and people will just understand it.
Speaker 7:  And then after that we get to the thing. What was the thing where it was
Speaker 7:  like a, a lamp that sits in the corner of your room and like beams power
Speaker 7:  at you?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, it's the, they're at CES every year and every year they're like, we
Speaker 8:  could do it. And every year it's like, well then do
Speaker 7:  It. That's eight G Baby.
Speaker 6:  One year, one of those companies p promised that they had a foreman grill
Speaker 6:  that was wirelessly powered and I was like, I don't believe you. And I went
Speaker 6:  and I shot a video on a flip cam of them cooking a burger and it was
Speaker 6:  like the thing was just sitting on a giant plate that was, you know,
Speaker 6:  like wireless. I was like, this isn't really, I understand that there's no
Speaker 6:  wire here
Speaker 2:  Sir. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  But this isn't, we haven't gotten very far. All. right. Speaking of the
Speaker 6:  complexity of USB C, we gotta take a break. We're gonna come back with
Speaker 6:  the USB C prices. Right. And probably some sort of lawsuit from the prices
Speaker 6:  Right People. We'll be right back.
Speaker 9:  Here it comes from the Vox Media podcast studios in New York, New York.
Speaker 9:  It's the USB C Price is Right. Neil, I
Speaker 9:  Patel. Come on down.
Speaker 6:  We're gonna get sued. I'm just so worried about that.
Speaker 9:  Alex Cranz. Come on down.
Speaker 10:  I can't afford to be sued right now.
Speaker 9:  And David Pierce, come on down.
Speaker 1:  I always thought
Speaker 6:  I would do a cool dance if I was on the price of trade
Speaker 1:  That was like I
Speaker 7:  Had a whole choreography planned. There was a spin move.
Speaker 9:  Ed, here's your host. Liam James.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Welcome To. The USB C Price is Right. I'm Birch cast producer
Speaker 1:  Liam James. We have a great game for you today, which will consist of four
Speaker 1:  rounds, all themed around the latest industry's standard connector for all
Speaker 1:  your favorite gadgets. Well Neli David Alex.
Speaker 1:  You should all know that each of you will be playing today for a Vergecast
Speaker 1:  listener that we randomly pulled out of a hat. Let's hear who
Speaker 1:  Neli is playing for.
Speaker 11:  This is James Alexander and my favorite USB C
Speaker 11:  Gadget has to be the very first one I ever got. Nexus six
Speaker 11:  P. Yeah. Greatest phone Google ever made. Thank you
Speaker 6:  All, right James? I'm in it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Great. Pick James All. right. Let's hear who David's playing for today.
Speaker 12:  Hey
Speaker 13:  Team, my name is Kir Ali and my favorite USB C Gadget
Speaker 13:  is my ceramic fur grinder for coffee beans that I got on
Speaker 13:  Amazon. Awesome gadget. Thanks so much guys. Hope to win the competition.
Speaker 7:  My fussy coffee people. Let's go. Kabi, I'm in. Let's go.
Speaker 6:  David, you're my sworn enemy now. And Kabir don don't know you, but you're
Speaker 6:  dead to me. We gotta go back and ask a beer if his thing is
Speaker 6:  actually USB A and doesn't have the resistors and can only charge from an
Speaker 6:  A to C cable.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, we'll put that in the follow up for the next show. But for now, let's
Speaker 1:  hear who Alex is playing for.
Speaker 12:  Hi, my name's Terry and my favorite USB C Gadget is my vent.
Speaker 12:  True and Ford Pro. It's three channel 4K wifi
Speaker 12:  dashcam. I put it into my car. I have a key to soul. It's pretty awesome.
Speaker 12:  Also, I would like Alex to represent me.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Bus.
Speaker 11:  Wow
Speaker 6:  Dude. Found his people. He's like, I've got a fussy dash cam Alex,
Speaker 8:  But he also has a Kia that so his like insurance rate is more than his car.
Speaker 1:  Okay, well whoever wins, your listener will be sent an awesome
Speaker 1:  cool Verge swag basket filled with all kinds of goodies. Alright,
Speaker 1:  is everybody ready? Let's go. We're ready. Alright. The first round
Speaker 1:  is, guess the price.
Speaker 1:  Guess the price of each gadget. The closest guest without going over five
Speaker 1:  wins. Get within $5, get a bonus of five points.
Speaker 1:  Let's get started with the first gadget up for bid today.
Speaker 9:  It's a 10 80 P endoscopic camera for your Android or
Speaker 9:  iOS device featuring a 2.0 megapixel camera
Speaker 9:  six adjustable LEDs. This USB enabled tool is great for inspecting
Speaker 9:  hard to reach places like car repairs, sewer may image,
Speaker 9:  oh my God. Dryer vent inspection and more made by PanIN.
Speaker 7:  Can I ask a follow up question? Yes. Can we spelling be this? Where can I
Speaker 7:  ask for like, you know, language of origin? I just wanna know how many megapixels
Speaker 7:  was it?
Speaker 1:  Two.
Speaker 7:  Two mega. Okay. That changes everything.
Speaker 6:  The 10 80 p.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Whoever gets the closest to the retail price without going over
Speaker 1:  gets the most points. Alright. Alex Krantz. Ooh,
Speaker 8:  What do I wanna do? 2 48
Speaker 1:  Alex Cranz with $2 48 cents. Wait.
Speaker 8:  248, not 2 48.
Speaker 6:  Wow. Alex
Speaker 7:  Cranz with an overbid.
Speaker 8:  I believe it in me. It look, it's, it's long. It's one long wire
Speaker 6:  Look. It's at least 3 cents per megapixel.
Speaker 8:  $248.
Speaker 1:  $248 All. right Mr. Pierce. Okay.
Speaker 7:  Do we have the thing where I can like look back at the crowd and ask them
Speaker 7:  to guess for me? I 59. 99
Speaker 1:  All. right? David. Pierce. $59 99 cents.
Speaker 7:  And the thing on Amazon says it's usually 74.99, but it's actually
Speaker 7:  59.99. That's what, that's what I think.
Speaker 1:  And Mr. Patel,
Speaker 6:  Oh, this is very complicated now. 'cause I think Alex is way too high and
Speaker 6:  I think David's way too low. $117.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 8:  That's a good number.
Speaker 1:  Neli Patel $117. Actual
Speaker 1:  retail price is $29
Speaker 6:  96.
Speaker 7:  Let's go.
Speaker 8:  I shoulda gone with, I shoulda have just kept my mouth shut. I could
Speaker 8:  have won. Sorry, Terry.
Speaker 6:  Look, my father was an emergency room doctor. Do not do that
Speaker 6:  with things that cost 29 90
Speaker 8:  Check for. For dryer lint.
Speaker 6:  No,
Speaker 7:  My dryer vents are gonna be so clean. You guys don't even know.
Speaker 1:  Okay. That means all three of you actually bid over the retail price,
Speaker 1:  so no points. Oh yeah. Chris are awarded for this gadget.
Speaker 1:  But let's move on to our next USB C Gadget.
Speaker 9:  It's rechargeable heated socks by Weston. These stockings will keep
Speaker 9:  your feet warm all day. With the power of two small batteries, you tuck into
Speaker 9:  a pocket sewn into the socks, which are rechargeable by the
Speaker 9:  included USB C cable rechargeable socks by Weston.
Speaker 1:  Alright, contestants currently on Weston's website, these socks are
Speaker 1:  actually 50% off. But at what price?
Speaker 6:  Wait, what is the discount price or what is the regular price? What
Speaker 1:  Is the discounted price?
Speaker 8:  That's harder.
Speaker 6:  I feel like this tracks with what David is saying is that these are probably
Speaker 6:  never sold at the real price. Correct. Like you have to psychologically manipulate
Speaker 6:  people into believing they're getting a deal in order to sell battery socks.
Speaker 7:  Normally these are $1,000 and today they're six bucks.
Speaker 1:  Alright, contestants, are you ready?
Speaker 8:  Ready.
Speaker 1:  Okay. This time let's go with David Pierce to begin with,
Speaker 7:  It's one pair of socks. Yes.
Speaker 1:  One pair of socks.
Speaker 7:  $22 and 49 cents.
Speaker 1:  Alright. David Pierce with $22 49 cents.
Speaker 1:  Mr. Patel,
Speaker 6:  I've learned my lesson. $11 flat.
Speaker 1:  $11 flat from Mr. Patel and Ms. Cranz.
Speaker 8:  Ooh. See? 'cause it socks. Socks are sneakily expensive
Speaker 8:  sometimes, so I'm gonna go with $37 and
Speaker 8:  96 cents.
Speaker 6:  You think the socks cost more than the camera
Speaker 8:  Y? Yes.
Speaker 1:  Actual retail price is $79
Speaker 1:  95 cents. Oh my God. Yes. Cranz our winner.
Speaker 1:  That's the half off price. That is the half off price.
Speaker 8:  I told you socks are pricey.
Speaker 6:  I'm just gonna say this out loud. What I've learned from two rounds of USB
Speaker 6:  C prices right, is people respect some parts of their body much more
Speaker 6:  than other parts of
Speaker 1:  Their body. You can get the USB a version of these socks for
Speaker 1:  1 99. Oh
Speaker 6:  My God.
Speaker 1:  I'm kidding. I I totally made that up.
Speaker 1:  Okay, let's get to our final gadget for guess the price.
Speaker 9:  It's the FLIR one Pro thermal imaging camera for Android phones.
Speaker 9:  This infrared camera, mobile accessory has an adjustable USB C
Speaker 9:  connector and lets you find hidden electrical problems, energy loss,
Speaker 9:  water damage, and other heat related issues with its thermal imaging.
Speaker 9:  With the help of the FLIR one app, buy flir.
Speaker 6:  That's so jaunty.
Speaker 1:  Alright, contestants right now on Amazon, you can get this gadget for
Speaker 1:  what price?
Speaker 8:  I, I reviewed the, the lightning version of this in like
Speaker 8:  2017 and don don't think that's gonna help me at all.
Speaker 6:  You gotta factor out the MFI tax.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I gotta, I gotta factor that and also the many years
Speaker 8:  since I last reviewed this.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Inflation. What does omics say this is worth now? $4,000.
Speaker 1:  Okay. First we have Alex. Cranz.
Speaker 8:  Oh I hate it.
Speaker 8:  $268
Speaker 8:  and 42 cents.
Speaker 1:  Alright. $268 and 42 cents
Speaker 1:  from Alex Cranz.
Speaker 8:  I feel like that's a good number.
Speaker 1:  Neela Patel, what is your guess?
Speaker 1:  2 0 7 2 0 7 86 2 0 7 86.
Speaker 1:  We have a last minute correction. David Pierce. What
Speaker 1:  is your guess? $1. $1. Yeah. Price is right
Speaker 1:  baby. Let's go.
Speaker 6:  David's taking the entire middle range there.
Speaker 1:  All, right? Actual retail price is
Speaker 1:  $420
Speaker 1:  and 50 cents.
Speaker 6:  My God.
Speaker 8:  Why didn't anyone guess? Four 20. Oh,
Speaker 8:  I'm sorry, but wait, I still win, right? You do. You
Speaker 6:  Do what?
Speaker 1:  Yes. Wow. You absolutely won. In fact, let's take a look at our
Speaker 1:  scoreboard as it stands now. Rounding out the back is Neli
Speaker 1:  Patel with zero.
Speaker 6:  I'm sorry James, I'll send you a Nexus five man no matter what happens.
Speaker 1:  Joining him is David Pierce with zero. Come here.
Speaker 1:  I'm so sorry. Alex. Cranz, our fearless leader at 10. A
Speaker 1:  commanding lead. All
Speaker 8:  For you Terry. It's all for you.
Speaker 6:  I can't send you a nexus 'cause it's mini USB. I'll figure it out.
Speaker 8:  Get an adapter. Dongle it.
Speaker 1:  Alright contestants, the next game we have for you is called
Speaker 1:  the match game. Match the gadget to its max
Speaker 1:  wattage over USB C two points per correct
Speaker 1:  match. Here we have a list of 10 USB C gadgets
Speaker 1:  and 10 of max power delivery stats in watts.
Speaker 1:  As you all may know, power delivery is a specification on USB C that
Speaker 1:  tells us how much power the gadget is allowed to receive for charging.
Speaker 1:  Use your expert gadget knowledge to match each USB C PD
Speaker 1:  number with the appropriate tech.
Speaker 6:  Can I just say this is proof positive that USB C PD is
Speaker 6:  bananas. I'm just gonna read you the, the numbers that are available. A hundred
Speaker 6:  watts, 45 watts, 140 watts, three watts, 80
Speaker 6:  watts, 18 watts, 30 watts, 96 watts, 27
Speaker 6:  watts, and 45 watts. Many of these numbers are
Speaker 6:  virtually the same
Speaker 7:  Universal standards baby.
Speaker 1:  Let's tell the audience what the devices are first. We have the
Speaker 1:  Nintendo Switch from 2019. We have the iPhone 15
Speaker 1:  Pro, we have the 16 inch MacBook Pro them
Speaker 1:  three. We also have the steam deck OLE model. We have the
Speaker 1:  DeWalt DCB 0 9 4 USB charging kit. We have
Speaker 1:  the PSS five dual sense controller. We have the Samsung
Speaker 1:  Galaxy S 23, the one plus 11 5G.
Speaker 1:  We have a 14 inch MacBook Pro, the M1 model and finally
Speaker 1:  the Pixel eight Pro. Everyone should have a worksheet we provided
Speaker 1:  for them. With all this information, please match the gadget with the
Speaker 1:  appropriate power wattage. You may start now.
Speaker 6:  Again, I'm just gonna point out it's 10 different devices, many of which
Speaker 6:  are exactly the same category in 10 different numbers.
Speaker 7:  Listen, Neil, I stopped stalling
Speaker 6:  All, right? I'm going,
Speaker 8:  Oh, I did this one wrong.
Speaker 7:  Did you guys do the thing that I did where you get almost to the end and
Speaker 7:  you realize the two highest ones you haven't done yet and all that's left
Speaker 7:  are ones that don't need that much power?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. Yes. C and I was like C,
Speaker 6:  CC,
Speaker 6:  C 45. I goofed. No, I I think I nailed
Speaker 6:  this actually. You know. You know what? I nailed this
Speaker 7:  Confidence.
Speaker 1:  Alright contestants, let's see how everybody did. We're gonna take these
Speaker 1:  one at a time starting with a Nintendo Switch at
Speaker 1:  18 watts.
Speaker 6:  Ooh, that's a big no. Anybody get that one? Nope. Nope.
Speaker 1:  Next we've got the iPhone 15 Pro at 27
Speaker 1:  watts.
Speaker 6:  Ah, I was close
Speaker 8:  On that one.
Speaker 7:  Did you guess 30? I guess 30. I
Speaker 8:  Guess 30.
Speaker 6:  You know what's horrible about this is that we keep going the, the more it's
Speaker 6:  guaranteed that I'm wrong.
Speaker 1:  Oh yeah. Yeah. Next we have the 16 inch MacBook Pro
Speaker 1:  M three model at 140 watts. Dang it. Hell yeah. You
Speaker 1:  should have all gotten that one.
Speaker 6:  I knew that was a thirsty bee. No,
Speaker 8:  I knew it was thirsty but I thought something else was thirstier.
Speaker 1:  Alright, next we have the steam deck ole model at
Speaker 1:  45. Wow. Yes.
Speaker 6:  That's low. That feels low Then I got that
Speaker 7:  One.
Speaker 6:  It does feel low. That means I, that means I know nothing.
Speaker 1:  I was surprised by this as well. I got,
Speaker 8:  I put a little line in. Alright,
Speaker 1:  Next item on the list is the DeWalt DCB
Speaker 1:  0 9 4 USB charging kit at a hundred
Speaker 1:  watts. Wow.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I
Speaker 8:  Had it in the MacBook Pro. The 16 inch I switched them.
Speaker 6:  I gotta say I got that one wrong and everything else
Speaker 6:  waterfalled to wrongness after that. There was just a cascade of
Speaker 6:  inaccurate answers after I got that one wrong.
Speaker 1:  Alright, well we'll we'll rip the bandaid off gently here. It's the PSS five
Speaker 1:  dual sense controller at three watts. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Go.
Speaker 1:  Samsung Galaxy S 23 at 45
Speaker 1:  watts. Yeah. One plus 11 5G at 80
Speaker 1:  watts.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's the only thing I know about one plus is that it'll just suck
Speaker 6:  down power. That's what they do baby.
Speaker 7:  I put a hundred because for the same reason I was like one plus is just get
Speaker 7:  after it light that battery on fire.
Speaker 6:  Hey put that shit on a hot plate. Let's go.
Speaker 1:  Alright, the 14 inch MacBook Pro M1 model at
Speaker 1:  96 watts. Oh finally we have the Pixel eight pro
Speaker 1:  at 30 watts. Hey
Speaker 6:  Bang. I got two. I told you I'd take this home.
Speaker 1:  Alright contestants, let's find out how you did a reminder that
Speaker 1:  each one that you got correct here counts for two points.
Speaker 6:  A reminder that this is the winning worksheet and if I had gotten this, the
Speaker 6:  DeWalt thing. Correct.
Speaker 1:  Alright, Mr. Hotshot, tell us how many you got. Right? That's
Speaker 6:  Five.
Speaker 1:  Got five correct guesses. Wow. David Pierce. How many correct guesses
Speaker 1:  do you have on your worksheet?
Speaker 7:  I got a whopping two, right?
Speaker 1:  Two correct. From David Pierce
Speaker 7:  I have probably five other ones that are one
Speaker 7:  rung away. Like should I have put a hundred when I put 96? Yes, I
Speaker 7:  should have. Should I have put 80 when I put 96? Yes. I should
Speaker 7:  have tough beat for David Kabi. I'm sorry, four points for me.
Speaker 1:  Alright, Alex Cranz, how many correct guesses do you have?
Speaker 8:  Well I can't make fun of David 'cause it's the exact same two. I
Speaker 8:  also got two. Right. But I got two right in the last round. So, I'm, I'm
Speaker 8:  winning. Did
Speaker 6:  You both try to do the highest and lowest first? Like I knew that PS five
Speaker 6:  was the lowest. Yes. And then I was just trying to figure out where the highest
Speaker 6:  was and I knew it was the MacBook.
Speaker 8:  I did highest first and then I started to scramble because I realized
Speaker 8:  I'd done it all wrong but it was too late. So I was like, oh, PSPS. I know
Speaker 8:  that one's gonna be low and that's, that's the one I got right.
Speaker 7:  I very confidently, the first line I drew was iPhone 15 pro
Speaker 7:  to 30 watts. 'cause I was sure that was like no question That was
Speaker 7:  correct.
Speaker 8:  Three watts off
Speaker 7:  And then no. I'll tell you what threw me while I'm being angry about this
Speaker 7:  is that the Nintendo switch is famously the hardest gadget
Speaker 7:  on Earth. Yes. To buy cables for So. I looked at this and I was like, what's
Speaker 7:  the most random number on here? Yes. 'cause I bet that's it. And I landed
Speaker 7:  on 27 same for the switch and I was so sure that was right because I was
Speaker 7:  like no other cable except the one done one that Nintendo will sell you.
Speaker 7:  You will work. So it has to be a random one. And I was wrong and I'm furious.
Speaker 8:  I just randomly chose 96 and I was wrong.
Speaker 6:  Do you think the switch takes a 96 watts of power?
Speaker 6:  The switch has the processing horsepower of a phone from 2009.
Speaker 8:  I was like maybe it's just gets thirsty.
Speaker 1:  Well I will just say you guys are doing much better than you did last year
Speaker 1:  on the Bluetooth jeopardy game. So fair
Speaker 6:  Enough.
Speaker 1:  Let's review the points from that round. Eli got 10 points
Speaker 1:  for his five correct guesses. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Worst to
Speaker 1:  First David Pierce and Alex Cranz each got four points for their two
Speaker 1:  correct guesses. Bringing our grand totals to Neli at 10.
Speaker 1:  David at four and Alex at 14.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Santa's back.
Speaker 8:  I got you Terry
Speaker 1:  All right now we go into round three. Round three is
Speaker 1:  madlibs. We have given you a sentence with a bunch of terms
Speaker 1:  missing but all the terms are jumbled. The sentence comes from a recent
Speaker 1:  Android authority article spelling out just how complicated USB
Speaker 1:  C has gotten. Fill in the gaps in the sentence with the provided terms.
Speaker 1:  We'll give you three points each per correct placement and the sentence is
Speaker 9:  Blank is based on blank and aligned with the
Speaker 9:  blank specification. Thereby bundling in blank
Speaker 9:  tunneling support for two blank or a single blank
Speaker 9:  display output and blank capabilities on blank
Speaker 9:  devices.
Speaker 8:  Do we have four hours to complete this?
Speaker 1:  And the terms we have for the sentence are
Speaker 9:  Display port 2.04
Speaker 9:  KPCI express hub
Speaker 9:  Thunderbolt four, USB four, Thunderbolt
Speaker 9:  three and eight K.
Speaker 1:  Alright everyone please use your worksheet to fill out the sentence.
Speaker 6:  I got
Speaker 7:  It. Can I ask for definitions on several of these words? Also is
Speaker 7:  PCI express a trick because no one has used that in 25 years.
Speaker 8:  Are there more words than there are slots?
Speaker 1:  No.
Speaker 6:  Nailed it. By the way, that's how I took the lsat in case you're wondering,
Speaker 6:  I finished the worksheet and just stood up and said nailed it after every
Speaker 6:  section.
Speaker 7:  I'm having deep regrets already but I'm, I'm locked in. I hit the buzzer
Speaker 1:  Cranz ready?
Speaker 8:  Well I guess I'm gonna have to be,
Speaker 8:  I barked something somewhere.
Speaker 6:  I knew the people who took the L set that way too.
Speaker 1:  All right? Let's hear your sentences. Contestants starting with Alex.
Speaker 1:  Cranz.
Speaker 8:  That's rude. That's very rude. Thunderbolt
Speaker 8:  four is based on Thunderbolt three and aligned with
Speaker 8:  the PCIA express specification
Speaker 8:  thereby bundling in. Hmm this is where it goes really
Speaker 8:  bad. USB four tunneling. No that's just
Speaker 8:  wrong Support for up to two hub or a
Speaker 8:  single display Port 2.0 display output
Speaker 8:  and 4K capabilities on eight K devices.
Speaker 6:  You really just ran outta words there. That's how that feels.
Speaker 1:  Okay, let's go with David Pierce next.
Speaker 7:  Thunderbolt four is based on USB four and aligned with the
Speaker 7:  Thunderbolt three specification thereby bundling in PCI
Speaker 7:  express tunneling support for up to two 4K or a single eight K
Speaker 7:  display output and hub capabilities on display Port 2.0 devices.
Speaker 6:  Oh that makes
Speaker 7:  Sense. I'm not sure that it does. You
Speaker 6:  Guys do not spend nearly enough time on the display port Wikipedia page.
Speaker 1:  Sean Hollister is very upset somewhere right now.
Speaker 1:  All right Ne Neli Patel tell us your sentence.
Speaker 6:  USP four is based on PCI express and aligned with a Thunderbolt four specification
Speaker 6:  thereby bundling in Thunderbolt three tunneling support for up to two 4K
Speaker 6:  displays or single eight K display output and display port 2.0 capabilities
Speaker 6:  on hub devices.
Speaker 1:  All right. I believe Neli is gonna be our winning concess here. But
Speaker 1:  let me read this sentence for you. It's actually
Speaker 1:  USB C four is based on Thunderbolt three
Speaker 1:  and aligned with the Thunderbolt four specifications. What?
Speaker 7:  That doesn't make any sense. I got one right.
Speaker 6:  I refuse.
Speaker 1:  Thereby bundling in display port 2.0 tunneling support for up
Speaker 1:  to two 4K or a one eight K display output and
Speaker 1:  PCI express capabilities over hub devices.
Speaker 6:  I just got two words in the and they're the same word Thunderbolt and PCI
Speaker 6:  express are the same. The same thing.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So why didn't you put 'em in the right places? Patel
Speaker 6:  Hominems the power of suggestion.
Speaker 7:  No, I maintain the first clause of this sentence
Speaker 7:  objectively makes no sense and should not be allowed. I refuse.
Speaker 1:  I'd just like to remind you this sentence came from an Android authority
Speaker 1:  article spelling out just how complicated USB C has gotten.
Speaker 1:  I'd
Speaker 7:  Like to have a word with Android authority. Could we bring them on the show?
Speaker 6:  Yes. I'd like to question your authority. Good sir.
Speaker 1:  Alright, so let's review that round of Mad Libs to see how we did.
Speaker 1:  Eli Patel got five correct guesses for a total of 15 David
Speaker 1:  Pierce got two correct guesses for a total of six points.
Speaker 7:  Don't say it like
Speaker 1:  That. And Alex Cranz only got one correct? I
Speaker 8:  Got one
Speaker 1:  For a total of three points. Let's go back to the big board to see our
Speaker 1:  totals. We've got Neli Patel at 25 now taking the lead.
Speaker 1:  Yes, David Pierce at 10 and Alex Cranz at
Speaker 1:  17.
Speaker 6:  And it would be more if it wasn't for the corrupt Android authority whose
Speaker 6:  administration I will bring down.
Speaker 8:  I gotta crush Neli in the last
Speaker 6:  Round. My sets are higher Cranz
Speaker 7:  I think for an extra 10 points. Can Neli be forced to explain this in English?
Speaker 6:  Yes. Now that I have the correct one. So the, the way that I
Speaker 6:  always think about this just very quickly and I know I'm gonna gloss over
Speaker 6:  the details, but the way I always think about this is that
Speaker 6:  Thunderbolt and PCI express are the same thing and PCI
Speaker 6:  is what's in your computer and Thunderbolt is that exact same connectivity
Speaker 6:  over a wire. That means Thunderbolt has lots of bandwidth. It's really fast.
Speaker 6:  You can do expansion with it, which is how you get PCI expansion chassis
Speaker 6:  over Thunderbolt. It all makes sense. So all this is saying is
Speaker 6:  over time you SP four and Thunderbolt, as USB gets
Speaker 6:  faster and faster and faster, it starts to inherit the capabilities of Thunderbolt
Speaker 6:  because Apple and Intel are all mixed up in the standard here. They're starting
Speaker 6:  to align the things so that you can do more thunderbolt things
Speaker 6:  on USB as it gets faster. So here USB three is inheriting
Speaker 6:  a bunch of Thunderbolt three capabilities in alignment with
Speaker 6:  Thunderbolt four, which is itself getting faster. And that means USP four
Speaker 6:  can now do Thunderbolt three things like display Port 2.0 for two 4K or one
Speaker 6:  eight K device and PCI expansion on hubs.
Speaker 1:  I also appreciate that Neli said it in more
Speaker 9:  Words than Andrew authority.
Speaker 1:  So good job Android
Speaker 9:  Authority. Significantly more
Speaker 1:  All, right? Let's go to that final round everyone, which is the showcase.
Speaker 1:  Guess the price of the combined showcase without going over
Speaker 1:  the closest guest wins 20 points. Guess within
Speaker 1:  $250 we'll give you an extra five points. I hate
Speaker 6:  This. Can we go back to Mad Libs?
Speaker 1:  Guess within a hundred dollars get an extra 10 points, guess within
Speaker 1:  $50 and we'll give you a whopping 50 bonus points. All, right
Speaker 1:  Kir, this is our moment. Let's go. Let's see what we have in this showcase
Speaker 9:  In this package. Experience USB C in all of its many
Speaker 9:  uses with this all-inclusive podcasting kit.
Speaker 6:  Oh my god,
Speaker 9:  This cutting edge package would in theory include a 16 inch
Speaker 9:  2023 MacBook Pro with an M three Pro chip 12 core
Speaker 9:  CPU 18 core GPU 16 core neural engine. Of course three
Speaker 9:  Thunderbolt four ports and 140 watt USB C
Speaker 9:  power adapter. Along with that we have the Sony W eight
Speaker 9:  1000 XM five wireless headphones chargeable by USB
Speaker 9:  C and then Roads NT one fifth generation studio
Speaker 9:  condenser microphone which allows connection with both XLR and USB
Speaker 9:  C anchors 5 63 10 and
Speaker 9:  one USB C docking station LGS 28 inch
Speaker 9:  16 by 18. Dual up monitor with USB C
Speaker 9:  and to top it all off a waterless portable essential oil
Speaker 9:  diffuser rechargeable by USB, C by Lytro.
Speaker 9:  So
Speaker 6:  It's a wellness podcast. I just wanna be clear.
Speaker 1:  Alright contestants, please guess the price of this deluxe
Speaker 1:  podcasting kit. We're gonna start with our leader Neli
Speaker 1:  Patel.
Speaker 6:  Okay, 41 79 99
Speaker 1:  All. right? We've got Neli at 4,000
Speaker 1:  179 99. Next on the scoreboard we have Alex
Speaker 1:  Cranz
Speaker 8:  4,856.
Speaker 6:  We don how much that microphone costs at all.
Speaker 1:  Alex Cranz is going with
Speaker 1:  $4,856 and David. Pierce,
Speaker 1:  what is your guess?
Speaker 7:  $1
Speaker 6:  I fucking
Speaker 1:  In a classic price is right.
Speaker 7:  I wrote down an actual number that I will tell you when I find out whether
Speaker 7:  I won or not.
Speaker 1:  Alright, we'll get there at a moment. The actual retail price of
Speaker 1:  this package is 3000 Damnit
Speaker 1:  $847 shit and
Speaker 1:  96 cents. Come
Speaker 7:  Here. We did
Speaker 6:  It but I'm closer.
Speaker 7:  You went over it Doesn't matter.
Speaker 6:  Is that how that works?
Speaker 1:  Because this is prices, right? Rules. If you've gone over,
Speaker 1:  you lose. Which means the
Speaker 7:  Comeback of the century.
Speaker 6:  Ah, no one knows how much that microphone costs. Yeah. Can
Speaker 7:  We get individual prices?
Speaker 1:  Alright, let's break that down in more detail. The 16
Speaker 1:  inch 2023 MacBook Pro with M three chip was
Speaker 1:  $2,499.
Speaker 6:  Got that exactly right.
Speaker 1:  The Sony headphones were $329
Speaker 1:  99 cents. Ah,
Speaker 7:  I was $20 off on that. I was so close, I
Speaker 6:  Was a little high there.
Speaker 1:  The road NT one condenser microphone was
Speaker 1:  $249. Oh,
Speaker 6:  I was just a little high actually. I was only 50 bucks high. I was
Speaker 7:  A hundred bucks low.
Speaker 1:  The anchor 5 63 docking station was
Speaker 1:  $129 99 cents. That's
Speaker 7:  A good deal. I'm way off on that one.
Speaker 6:  Andrew, you you put together a nice little package here. Yeah, it's very
Speaker 6:  affordable.
Speaker 8:  I put it at $50.
Speaker 1:  The LG dual up monitor with USB C was
Speaker 1:  5 99 99.
Speaker 7:  I put six 50. I was pretty close.
Speaker 8:  Why is my LG monitor half that size and twice that price?
Speaker 6:  You love Pixel density. The thing you don't know about the dual up is that
Speaker 6:  it only has 10 pixels.
Speaker 1:  And finally the Lytro 2023 Waterless portable essential oil diffuser from
Speaker 1:  Amazon at 39.99.
Speaker 6:  Oh, nailed that one. Yeah, I know my Amazon garbage.
Speaker 6:  Your company's called Lytro. When you put the year in the, in the product
Speaker 6:  description, you're not going over 50.
Speaker 8:  This is much more affordable than
Speaker 6:  I thought. I was high in the headphones, the microphone and the docking station
Speaker 6:  and that allowed David to win.
Speaker 7:  I had that MacBook at three grand, not 2,500.
Speaker 7:  And I blame Apple for not making any sense with what it tells you. And I
Speaker 7:  was in aggregate, basically dead on with the rest of it. So I ended up the,
Speaker 7:  the number I wrote down was 43 95 61. Ah. And if you take away
Speaker 7:  that 500 bucks, I was like, I was right there. So I'm, I'm feeling good about
Speaker 7:  this, but also I won anyway. So learn how to play the game. Patel David
Speaker 6:  Is fired and what you've won is being alone for the holidays.
Speaker 1:  That's correct. David got 20 points from this round. Our other two
Speaker 1:  contestants with zeros. That makes David our winner today with 30 points
Speaker 1:  Neli just behind him at 25. And finally Alex
Speaker 1:  Cranz with 17 points
Speaker 6:  Rigged by the corrupt Android authority.
Speaker 8:  So sad.
Speaker 1:  Congratulations to our winner who David was playing for Kabir.
Speaker 1:  And let's tell Kabir what he's won in our Verge swag gift
Speaker 1:  bag. We've got a Verge cast T-shirt from the popular
Speaker 1:  what's a photo series? We've got this awesome pair of
Speaker 1:  Verge cast sweatpants, a Verge mug, a Verge hat, and of course
Speaker 1:  a Verge fanny pack. Thank you to everyone for playing and thank you all
Speaker 1:  for listening. Please get your pets paid and neutered to help control the
Speaker 1:  pet population.
Speaker 1:  We'll be right back after this break with more of the USB C holiday.
Speaker 1:  Spectacular
Speaker 6:  All right, we're back. I'm gonna tell you right now, I feel like USB C
Speaker 6:  Price is, Right is rigged and I should have won. David is my mortal
Speaker 6:  enemy now.
Speaker 7:  I also feel like that, I feel like I, I just really
Speaker 7:  didn't deserve to win that like I did it. I did it for Kabir and I did it
Speaker 7:  for everybody, but I didn't deserve that victory. I'll take it
Speaker 7:  to be very clear, but I'm just looking at the sentence that I wrote and I
Speaker 7:  don't, I don't deserve
Speaker 6:  Anything. I was so close. I also can't believe we, we won with a $1
Speaker 6:  anyway, whatever. We we're gonna have some beef next year and also
Speaker 6:  most assuredly trademark lawsuit, it's just coming for us and that's fine.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. Alex in the meantime has gone on vacation. She's just
Speaker 6:  on Santa Slade flying around the world giving out gifts to all the good boys
Speaker 6:  and girls. It's great. I hope she enjoys her break. But David and I are sticking
Speaker 6:  around to talk to Noah Dentzel, who is the co-founder and CEO of
Speaker 6:  Nomad Goods. And this conversation, David, I I really enjoyed it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it was fun. We talked about USB C we talked about wireless charging.
Speaker 7:  We talked about just like what it means to be an accessory company
Speaker 7:  in this new world of USB C and it's very clear that
Speaker 7:  this is a thing he spends a lot of time Yeah. Thinking about and having ideas
Speaker 7:  about and like he didn't tell us as much of the weird stuff that they're
Speaker 7:  building as I wanted him to. But he told us some of the weird stuff.
Speaker 6:  What's fascinating about this is the iPhone switching to USB C created a
Speaker 6:  vast new market for USB C products, which is really interesting. And Noah
Speaker 6:  got all the way into what that means for how he runs the business and how
Speaker 6:  he can build a business around a standard like USB C right, All. right. Without
Speaker 6:  further ado, here's Noah Dentzel, the co-founder and CEO of Nomad Goods.
Speaker 6:  Welcome Noah.
Speaker 15:  Hey, thanks for having me.
Speaker 6:  Thank you for celebrating the holidays with us by talking about USB C
Speaker 15:  Hey, this is a USB c Holiday. I'm sure there's gonna be, it's a good subject
Speaker 15:  for round the round the table discussion. Confusing, not too controversial.
Speaker 15:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Right. Everyone's got an opinion, but none of the opinions matter.
Speaker 7:  Confusing, not too controversial is like the perfect tagline for USB C
Speaker 7:  at this particular moment in time. That's very good.
Speaker 15:  It's definitely confusing. There's a lot of potential. It's a, it's a
Speaker 15:  standard size, but what's going on in that size? There's all kinds of different
Speaker 15:  things going on. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So this is why we wanted to have you on here. 'cause you're, you're
Speaker 7:  somebody who is actually like making this stuff for people in the world,
Speaker 7:  right? And like, just sort of poking around your website, it seems like you
Speaker 7:  went at some point in the last year or so, basically like
Speaker 7:  all in on USB C like I, I had a hard time finding
Speaker 7:  non USB c stuff for sale from Nomad, which I feel like in the past
Speaker 7:  your thing was kind of always like, we have all the cables for all the people
Speaker 7:  and now you're just like, it's USB C time. Get outta here.
Speaker 15:  Yeah. Our customer base tends to be very early adopter and we internally
Speaker 15:  are as well. So like the second that
Speaker 15:  something's even announced, we see this, we, we saw our sales shift from
Speaker 15:  Lightning to USB C before the iPhone 15
Speaker 15:  was shipping for context. Historically, when we've had
Speaker 15:  micro USB stuff or USB C stuff and lightning stuff, we've always been way
Speaker 15:  stronger on lightning and five or seven times more. Wow. And then all of
Speaker 15:  a sudden earlier this, this summer we saw that our
Speaker 15:  USB c we, we launched a product actually charge key. We launched a
Speaker 15:  USB C in a lightning version, and the USB C version was
Speaker 15:  outselling the lightning version that that would typically never happen.
Speaker 15:  This was before the iPhone 15 debuted. That was just based on
Speaker 15:  rumor and speculation. So our customers are living in that forefront.
Speaker 7:  So like as soon as the EU says it's USB C time, people just start going
Speaker 7:  to Nomads website and buying USB C stuff basically.
Speaker 15:  It's wild, it's fun. They keep us busy and that's where we like to play.
Speaker 15:  You know, that's the, that's the fun being on that front edge. When you're
Speaker 15:  at the beginning of a new cable era, obviously USB C's been around for a
Speaker 15:  while, but until the iPhone does it, you know, it doesn't seem to get the
Speaker 15:  recognition. Yeah, it deserves, but it's, it's this future proofing,
Speaker 15:  which is really cool because anything you buy right now, I mean, if I were
Speaker 15:  buying a car right now and it didn't have a USB C port, I would
Speaker 15:  rethink that car purchase, right? That's a massive purchase. I just would
Speaker 15:  not wanna be stuck behind. I mean, I, I honestly personally wouldn't even
Speaker 15:  want it to have a USB a port, but if it did, I'd, I would be
Speaker 15:  okay with that. That's just like we're ripping forward through USB C
Speaker 15:  and it's way better.
Speaker 6:  The car example is really interesting, right? The experience a lot of people
Speaker 6:  have with USB C up until now-ish maybe,
Speaker 6:  is that it's the new charging connector. So they would buy an Android phone,
Speaker 6:  it would come with a cable, maybe even a USB a to USB C cable, and
Speaker 6:  that's how they charge their phone. And that might be how they charged everything.
Speaker 6:  But then it also has this huge data functionality that is very complicated.
Speaker 6:  It can also be a thunderbolt cable. You're an accessory maker. How have
Speaker 6:  you been thinking about just communicating what does what to people? Because
Speaker 6:  that seems like the hardest part about USB C.
Speaker 15:  So we have some materials on our website and some blog information and,
Speaker 15:  and we probably need to do even more to explain what is
Speaker 15:  USB C because to us, we, we get the problem of we're just surrounded by
Speaker 15:  this and we've been thinking about it for years and we assume everybody
Speaker 15:  knows, sometimes we talk about how higher wattage, you know,
Speaker 15:  charging a faster speed, but sometimes a really helpful piece of
Speaker 15:  communication is, is language surrounding like minutes to charge,
Speaker 15:  you know, 20% in 20 minutes that might be more
Speaker 15:  relatable or, or 30% in 20 minutes. So, so like, what is the
Speaker 15:  core thing that the person wants and how is it really helping their life?
Speaker 15:  Because what all these numbers mean, I mean, sometimes these numbers and
Speaker 15:  specs are so high and crazy and you can't even use it. The
Speaker 15:  iPhone can only charge at, I think it's only rated for 20, I think it charges
Speaker 15:  closer to 30. And often that's only for, for a very short
Speaker 15:  amount of time, right? You're not necessarily getting peak speeds at all
Speaker 15:  times. If you're over 80%, if you're really high up on your phone, you're,
Speaker 15:  you're gonna charge slower. So trying to break it down, let people know
Speaker 15:  that sometimes using the like, analogies of like, it's like a hose and the
Speaker 15:  size of your hose versus, you know, these are terms that, that our engineers
Speaker 15:  here will explain it when we're debating internally. But this
Speaker 7:  Makes me think like, I hate buzzwords all the time and this makes me think
Speaker 7:  we like really need some good buzzwords here. It's like, like Tesla did a
Speaker 7:  good job with superchargers, right? Where there's like, yeah, people now
Speaker 7:  understand that there is like a way to charger your car and then there are
Speaker 7:  superchargers and those are faster because super is a big fast word.
Speaker 7:  And now it's like maybe we need like cables and fast cables
Speaker 7:  and like mega cables and it's like people will suddenly understand how these
Speaker 7:  things work.
Speaker 15:  We do in, in companies like Nomad, we, we try, I mean we come
Speaker 15:  up with our own little internal buzzwords often from a marketing standpoint
Speaker 15:  it'd be like, you know, for example, you know, supercharging capability
Speaker 15:  or something. It's, it is kind of nice when, when there's actually a standard
Speaker 15:  'cause then it's like, cool we are, we're building to that Spec. We'd obviously
Speaker 15:  building to a certain Spec and it can be confusing for the consumer too
Speaker 15:  because there's, there's real things that are like from USB,
Speaker 15:  you know, the, the USB system USB standard and there's protocols on that
Speaker 15:  standard. And then there's marketing things that a may be actually
Speaker 15:  helpful because it's like, oh I can make sense of that supercharging
Speaker 15:  B it could just be buzzwords, but from a company. But maybe that company
Speaker 15:  is so big that their language confuses you and sounds official when
Speaker 15:  it's actually not. So, so it's wild. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So that's the, the basic challenge of USB C, right? It can do so
Speaker 6:  many things in so many different permutations that even just
Speaker 6:  talking about it is hard. Which is fascinating, right? You've gotta market
Speaker 6:  the products, you gotta invent new things, you gotta tell people what they
Speaker 6:  can do. But the business is built around something that's pretty
Speaker 6:  amorphous, right? Like Nomad makes USB C accessories. What's your
Speaker 6:  relationship to the standard? Like are you thinking
Speaker 6:  about the next version of how much power can come through a
Speaker 6:  PD cable? Are you saying okay, here's where the base of iPhone
Speaker 6:  owners is, we gotta rush some products to market. Building a company
Speaker 6:  around a standard seems like you need to pay a lot of attention to the standard,
Speaker 6:  but you can't get too far ahead 'cause the market hasn't gotten there yet.
Speaker 15:  Yeah, I think you just brought up a great point mentioning pd. So power
Speaker 15:  delivery was a great example of, of kind of a, of a standard
Speaker 15:  term or or threshold wattage, at which point that
Speaker 15:  is considered kind of the standard of fast charging challenges.
Speaker 15:  USB C has been just ripping and roaring forward. So I think it was
Speaker 15:  20 watts before Maybe it was 18. And so, so at this point,
Speaker 15:  charging at that speed could almost be considered kind of slow. So power
Speaker 15:  delivery, which was fast just a couple years ago and like in my book I'd
Speaker 15:  call that like good, you know, solid. Yeah. So yeah, staying on point with
Speaker 15:  the standards, we absolutely have the problem of chasing the front edge
Speaker 15:  so much. We, that's where the fun is. That's where the, the excitement is.
Speaker 15:  but it also can be like too far out there for sure. We've, we've
Speaker 15:  had that happen. We, we actually launched our first USB C product in
Speaker 15:  2016 I think it was, and I think it came out in 2014.
Speaker 15:  But like that product had a 3000 million up hour integrated battery. It
Speaker 15:  was 12 volt in. So you plug it into the 12 volt, the cigarette lighter thing
Speaker 15:  and it charged itself up it's battery and also had an A and a
Speaker 15:  C out. Everyone was using the A and not the C on it because it was just
Speaker 15:  so early and it was kind of ahead of its time. That was in 2016. So we've
Speaker 15:  been doing this C for a long time. We've been waiting for this moment
Speaker 15:  for a long time. Sometimes it can be really expensive when you're trying
Speaker 15:  to get on that really, really front edge and you might make a product and
Speaker 15:  it's super cool and it's like, do people really need this? And, and
Speaker 15:  to need it, they're gonna need to pay for it, right? Because some of the
Speaker 15:  stuff that's not at the mass scale yet, it can be substantially more expensive.
Speaker 15:  So it can be finding that sweet spot of the front edge or certainly
Speaker 15:  where things are moving. I came across a really great word the other
Speaker 15:  day called extensibility extensible. It's a
Speaker 15:  quality of something that's basically future proofing, right? So the cool
Speaker 15:  thing about USB C is it's extensible. So they have this, this
Speaker 15:  standard size, it's updating and it's growing right? You know, 4K,
Speaker 15:  then eight K, and then the high speed data and this and that. So it's cool
Speaker 15:  that we seem to have come to this standard size that is
Speaker 15:  extensible and it's growing and it means that for an accessory maker like
Speaker 15:  ourselves, we have a big pool to play in and
Speaker 15:  we have a lot of, we can bring forward ideas, we can
Speaker 15:  adapt, we can update, we can be thinking about power, portable power
Speaker 15:  data. What if we want an issue where there's not data for security.
Speaker 15:  Sometimes when you're charging in a public environment, maybe you want to
Speaker 15:  ensure that data's not going through. It's exciting and interesting and
Speaker 15:  it means that there's opportunities and challenges for us to build for it.
Speaker 15:  but it certainly got so many pros and we like that we, we embrace that we,
Speaker 15:  it's, it's annoying as a customer, as a consumer to have six different cables
Speaker 15:  and you always seem to have the wrong one. Those days are kind of over
Speaker 15:  at least largely improved.
Speaker 7:  I'll give you largely improved I think over is, is hopeful. Like I
Speaker 6:  Think that's what you gotta take to the holiday table, David. You gotta,
Speaker 6:  you gotta be like, grandma look, it's largely improved. Do you feel the spirit
Speaker 6:  of Christmas?
Speaker 7:  No. To your point, like the thing all of that relies on, and I'm curious
Speaker 7:  how you feel about this is like getting the connector itself, right? If we're
Speaker 7:  at a point where it is so sort of futureproof and extensible, like you're
Speaker 7:  talking about that we won't regret that choice in a decade. A lot
Speaker 7:  of things will change around it and it like, you know, there will be backwards
Speaker 7:  compatibility stuff or whatever. But like, do you feel like we got the connector,
Speaker 7:  right? Like as somebody who works with it all the time, is it, did we do
Speaker 7:  it correctly?
Speaker 15:  I feel like we did. I've gotta say when we started in
Speaker 15:  2012 with our first product charge card, it was a 30 pin adopter
Speaker 15:  for the iPhone. Okay. So that, I think they switched in 2012 or 2013. So
Speaker 15:  when we started it was the 2012 and they shifted to lightning and it was,
Speaker 15:  it was cool, it was good, it was lightning. It was, it was great. What we've
Speaker 15:  seen, there's been kind of these like, looks like there's kind of a 10 year
Speaker 15:  window. So does this usher in a 10 year window?
Speaker 15:  I think that we're at the beginning of a relatively large window.
Speaker 15:  It's hard to say. I mean it, it makes sense to me that ports would also
Speaker 15:  stay around for charging. But of course we have the whole component as well
Speaker 15:  of, of wireless and Q and the QE two standard that's coming out. And does
Speaker 15:  Apple want to go port list? Do some devices want to go port list
Speaker 15:  and, and drop the port altogether? It nonetheless remaining the port,
Speaker 15:  but with some option of of wireless. So from what I've seen,
Speaker 15:  from what we've seen, it seems like we should probably have a
Speaker 15:  good 10 year window. These are the types of windows you need for it to be
Speaker 15:  useful. 'cause otherwise you're on an airplane and then you're like, gosh
Speaker 15:  darn it. But
Speaker 6:  Aren't we at the end of the 10 year window, right? USB C hit in what,
Speaker 6:  2015?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, there's one version of it that says we're nine years into a 10 year
Speaker 7:  window.
Speaker 15:  Yeah, that's, I guess it depends on the, the level of, of the adoption
Speaker 15:  and the, a big impactor is, look, you know, the United States, the iPhone
Speaker 15:  is the leading smartphone. It's a leading smartphone globally. They just
Speaker 15:  took it on this year. I think that's big, that's a big impactor there and
Speaker 15:  should give us a, a decent window. It's hard to say if they do change, it
Speaker 15:  will be there. There's
Speaker 7:  Nobody like telling you about USB D already, right? Like is is this, is
Speaker 7:  this a thing that's, that's coming next year that we just don't know about
Speaker 7:  yet?
Speaker 15:  Gosh, I not hopefully not yet. We, we need give us a little bit of
Speaker 15:  time to, to get this standard rolled out.
Speaker 6:  So lemme ask you about Apple actually. I'm always curious to ask accessory
Speaker 6:  manufacturers this, for the longest time there was lightning
Speaker 6:  and that was your volume seller, right? You, you pointed out like that's
Speaker 6:  where all the volume was. That's where people were buying and lightning was
Speaker 6:  pretty fixed. Like they rolled it out in 2012 or whatever and it never
Speaker 6:  changed it. It was the thing it was for the whole time. And you were able
Speaker 6:  to build, build the business around that and mostly it was charging, like
Speaker 6:  there were just not a lot of like cool computer things you could do with
Speaker 6:  a lightning port. I had like a, a silly little camera attachment for my iPhone
Speaker 6:  at one point. But like all this stuff fizzled out. Was that because that's
Speaker 6:  how Apple wanted it is because you didn't have the market. I always wonder
Speaker 6:  if that's where all what all the people were buying was lightning accessories.
Speaker 6:  Why were the only lightning accessories like cables in
Speaker 6:  battery packs? Why weren't there anything else?
Speaker 15:  Yeah, it was a very controlled and and somewhat conservative market. So
Speaker 15:  MFI is made for iPhone, that's the, the Apple sort of
Speaker 15:  guidelines and program that manages it and it's very clear
Speaker 15:  and very strict guidelines. There's some wiggle room you could submit
Speaker 15:  exception requests to to products. We actually had a couple products that
Speaker 15:  exception requests that had to do largely with the housing that was holding
Speaker 15:  the connector. So we could make, we made like a carabiner cable. That was
Speaker 15:  really cool. Cool. We made, we made a, the our key, our little charge key
Speaker 15:  short cable. So these were, these were not the most, you know, wild
Speaker 15:  exceptions that are more like a, in a industrial design exception, but it's
Speaker 15:  very controlled environment. And then you think about female, right? So
Speaker 15:  when we think of lightning we tend to think of the male as these are the
Speaker 15:  connectors that you buy and you integrate 'em on cables and this and that.
Speaker 15:  Well I
Speaker 6:  Feel like we just need to explain to people Exactly. You mean the part that
Speaker 6:  you go into, right? There's the plug and there's the socket. And so when
Speaker 6:  you say female you mean the socket?
Speaker 15:  The socket. So it was that the very few products had the female
Speaker 15:  lightning on them from Apple on theirs did, right? The iPhone has
Speaker 15:  anything that takes takes a lightning or the battery pack for example,
Speaker 15:  lightning was really, generally speaking was really a male
Speaker 15:  program, right? It was really just a little, the connector plug that goes
Speaker 15:  in when you think of USB C, it's, it's double universal, right? It, it turns
Speaker 15:  around it's 306, you can turn it on both sides. Lightning did that too,
Speaker 15:  of course. But both ends can go both ways. It's actually one of the things
Speaker 15:  that I'm really excited about is, is that they've enabled reverse charging.
Speaker 15:  And I know I get in trouble in these things. I say like, you know, the iPhone
Speaker 15:  did this. It's like, yeah, well the Android did that years ago. I know,
Speaker 15:  I know it's still, yeah and it's so amazing now in USB C because it can
Speaker 15:  go both ways. So you know, you're out at the bar and your phone's dead,
Speaker 15:  you buy someone a beer, you charge your phone from their phone or vice versa.
Speaker 15:  So if you're irresponsible and your battery's dead, you need one of these
Speaker 15:  on these. If you're responsible, you you need one of these on you so you
Speaker 15:  can charge other people. So, so there's just cool stuff going on
Speaker 15:  with with USB C And so there's things like that that
Speaker 15:  never were really part of the lightning thing 'cause it wasn't going both
Speaker 15:  ways. So there's things like that that just make it better and
Speaker 15:  interesting and again confusing. Yeah, right. If we put power in the mix,
Speaker 15:  which way is it going? What's charging what, you know, you need to kind
Speaker 15:  of choose on the phone or does it just go out If it's to the AirPods, it's
Speaker 15:  just going out. You're not charging the phone from the AirPods. But interesting
Speaker 15:  stuff there.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Well and even beyond just charging, it seems like one of the things
Speaker 7:  we were amazed by with the iPhone was how not locked down
Speaker 7:  its USB C setup is, you can just plug most things into it.
Speaker 7:  Some of them work, some of them don't. But we were sort of consistently surprised
Speaker 7:  by the number of like computery accessories that suddenly worked with the
Speaker 7:  iPhone. Yeah. And I feel like for you, you're now in this position where
Speaker 7:  you can build one set of accessories that works with iPhones, which
Speaker 7:  are obvi, it sounds like the majority of your customers, but also with the
Speaker 7:  whole universe of Android phones. And then also do this gigantic
Speaker 7:  set of things that you've never been able to do before with accessories.
Speaker 7:  Like has it changed the list of things you feel like you can build
Speaker 7:  just because it is this universal port that theoretically you can plug almost
Speaker 7:  anything into and it'll do something.
Speaker 15:  Absolutely. A, from a technical standpoint and b, from an like
Speaker 15:  now we have the opportunity to do it standpoint. Meaning now that everyone's
Speaker 15:  together, one of my best friends is a diehard Android user and when we
Speaker 15:  launched this charge key, he sent me a message, he bought five and he said,
Speaker 15:  you finally made something for Android. And of course, of course I'm
Speaker 7:  Thinking and you're like sort of, yeah,
Speaker 15:  Of course I'm thinking like, dude, we've been making the best cables for
Speaker 15:  USB C for years. But it's true. We are la largely iPhone.
Speaker 15:  So from a customer base standpoint, so, so it's huge for us. And I just
Speaker 15:  say that because we we're all about building portable power, keeping you
Speaker 15:  charged on the go, keeping you protected on the go with our cases and so
Speaker 15:  forth. But we've, it's always been part of us. And now though that it's
Speaker 15:  obviously like this cable without question thought that there's two models
Speaker 15:  and one sells more than the other. There's one model and it goes to
Speaker 15:  everyone. That's huge for us. I mean, from a, from a research and development
Speaker 15:  standpoint, it means let's probably invest more into this
Speaker 15:  because we don't have to build two of them or we don't have to make a judgment
Speaker 15:  call. Is there a market for this one? So it's, it's incredible from
Speaker 15:  that standpoint. We have a lot of great ideas brewing right now. We have
Speaker 15:  a couple products that are in development that, that are gonna be released
Speaker 15:  in 2024 that I think are a little bit ahead of their time, if not early.
Speaker 15:  We're trying to, there's a challenge that it poses as well is the apple
Speaker 15:  lightning ecosystem was a protected kind of
Speaker 15:  ecosystem, right? You, you see products at gas stations so forth that were
Speaker 15:  non MFI, right? But if generally a customer wants to buy
Speaker 15:  something, if you're buying quality product, it's MFI. So it was a
Speaker 15:  controlled environment. So while there were all these annoying rules and
Speaker 15:  stuff, it was a safe environment. one of the challenges at USB C
Speaker 15:  is there's less of that, right? So you go to the gas station, how do you
Speaker 15:  know that that $5 cable is good? Well if you're buying
Speaker 15:  a MFI lightning cable, it costs a lot of money. 20 or
Speaker 15:  $30. But the components are coming through the, from the Apple
Speaker 15:  ecosystem. So these are gonna be challenges that we face from a,
Speaker 15:  what you had mentioned earlier about the standard in marketing
Speaker 15:  and these key terms and buzzwords, but the, these are gonna be challenges
Speaker 15:  that we face. And so from, from our side, that's, I can already see that,
Speaker 15:  that there's gonna be a little bit of a, some fun coming to together
Speaker 15:  and hopefully some things do prevail, some, some solid standards and and
Speaker 15:  so forth. So we can give clarity to customers and what they're buying and,
Speaker 15:  and what they can expect from the products.
Speaker 6:  With all that extra, you know, resource available for research and development,
Speaker 6:  do you, do you see more and different kinds of USB c accessories
Speaker 6:  coming out now?
Speaker 15:  Yeah, great question. I mean, having a cable on you at all times becomes
Speaker 15:  more important than ever before. So, so perhaps portable
Speaker 15:  cables portability could be, could be more important. Especially as there's
Speaker 15:  this universality, it's like there's way more reasons for why you would
Speaker 15:  need it before. Do you wanna bring a cable with you? You might use it for
Speaker 15:  one use case, then you need another cable for another use case that, that's
Speaker 15:  kind of annoying. So So I think we're gonna see more
Speaker 15:  things like that. More, more portable cables and perhaps just
Speaker 15:  maybe some higher quality cables where you're investing in a, because you
Speaker 15:  know, before you're so annoyed, you know, you've already bought 20 cables,
Speaker 15:  you have a drawer in your desk filled with random cables, you know, you
Speaker 15:  don't, the last thing you wanna do is spend $30 on a cable and now it's
Speaker 15:  like, hey, do the research. There's a really incredible high
Speaker 15:  speed data cable. I think it's the thunderbolt one from, from Apple out
Speaker 15:  there. 240 watts. Yeah, this and that. Just, it's nice to know that
Speaker 15:  that's gonna be around for a while and it's gonna have so much universality
Speaker 15:  in, in usefulness. So it could be worth investing. We, we have Kevlar on
Speaker 15:  our cables, you know, that's coming from DuPont light. It's a license thing.
Speaker 15:  It's like the real deal. So our cables aren't cheap, but they're really
Speaker 15:  well made. We have metal tips to them. So, I could understand why
Speaker 15:  someone would be annoyed a few years ago and they just wanna buy the cheapest
Speaker 15:  cable possible. 'cause A, it might break on them. B, the standards are changing.
Speaker 15:  C they need to have five different cables. But now with one you can be a
Speaker 15:  little more thoughtful about it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Do you think I, I was gonna ask you about the Kevlar cables because
Speaker 7:  you were, you were early to the idea of what I would call a ludicrously fancy
Speaker 7:  charging cable. Like the, the Kevlar stuff you started doing like in 2019
Speaker 7:  I think, right? That's which is like ancient history in the charging cable
Speaker 7:  universe. But I think the idea that you should eventually
Speaker 7:  carry the one sort of the cable that charges the hardest
Speaker 7:  thing you have to charge and then kind of scales down to everything else
Speaker 7:  like that seems like where we have to get in this crazy
Speaker 7:  world of charging that we're gonna get into that you either carry a bunch
Speaker 7:  of different USB c cables or you carry like the one, like the
Speaker 7:  epic cable. Yeah. God cable, right? The God cable.
Speaker 6:  It's Christmas, it arrives in a virgin birth.
Speaker 15:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I'm trying to make the Christmas jokes as much as I could.
Speaker 15:  So the the just the universal best cable, we're
Speaker 7:  Calling it the God cable. Cable. It's now officially known as God cable.
Speaker 7:  Cable. Like is the god cable gonna be a thing?
Speaker 15:  Well I guess the God cable is kind of,
Speaker 7:  We already made it a thing. It happened already. This is great.
Speaker 15:  The USB C cable and I mean I would argue I can't, I can't, I love
Speaker 15:  this product. It's the best. Cable is the one you have on you So. I
Speaker 15:  love our chart, our charge key because the best cable is with you when you
Speaker 15:  need it.
Speaker 7:  But isn't that the problem with USB C is that that's not necessarily true
Speaker 7:  anymore?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. How fast is the charge key? You love it. It's great. I mean I understand
Speaker 6:  why you like it. Can it charge my MacBook at a hundred watts?
Speaker 15:  Ours, right? This version right here will just charge up to 60 watts, but
Speaker 15:  we're probably gonna increase the speed. So go a hundred. The MacBook Air
Speaker 15:  tops out at I think 35 watts. So 60 alone. You're charging
Speaker 15:  really, really high speed. I
Speaker 6:  Gotta run these M1 ultras dog.
Speaker 15:  We're we're coming, we're coming for it.
Speaker 6:  So there, there's something else happening there. You mentioned it before,
Speaker 6:  which is MagSafe Q2 just to make this stuff. There's a whole
Speaker 6:  bunch of really hardcore engineering probably for you, a bunch of supplier
Speaker 6:  deals, right? The, the bleeding edge of USB power is all in GaN
Speaker 6:  and getting supply of GaN chips in Q2.
Speaker 6:  I'm sure that the supplier base of people actually making Q2 stuff is pretty
Speaker 6:  limited right now. Let's start with GaN that's what you, you need to have
Speaker 6:  in order to build the most powerful USB C stuff. How does that market work?
Speaker 6:  Are you in it? Do you have exclusives? Do you have to fight off other vendors?
Speaker 15:  Yeah, so gam, gallium nitride is the kind of the high speed
Speaker 15:  dents sort of compact, high speed standard I guess, I guess you could
Speaker 15:  say when you're doing these things at first, earlier on, it's gonna
Speaker 15:  be more expensive. So back to your point on the supply chain and the suppliers
Speaker 15:  and contract manufacturers, they're pretty on this stuff. So we're
Speaker 15:  usually one of the early companies to be excited and be pushing the
Speaker 15:  boundaries of those things. And for GaN that was,
Speaker 15:  that was a couple years ago where it was more really on the forefront. It's
Speaker 15:  certainly become the kind of premium commodity tech let's say.
Speaker 15:  'cause there's still plenty of stuff out there that that's not, and and
Speaker 15:  it, it's gonna be, it's gonna be less expensive. It's gonna be bulkier.
Speaker 15:  And when you think about costs as well in supply chain, there's the cost
Speaker 15:  of freight and air freight and shipping. So it depends.
Speaker 6:  What's the thing you want to build that you can't now, but
Speaker 6:  the next rev of GaN would let you build?
Speaker 15:  Well, I would love to go, we even really compact so
Speaker 15:  we could have the AC to C
Speaker 15:  integrated, right? So AC 120 volt in or
Speaker 15:  or up to 40 whatever for Europe, other places AC to
Speaker 15:  C, extremely compact. Extremely
Speaker 15:  compact. So hyperact, so it's so small it, it fits on your key chain.
Speaker 15:  It's, and it's smaller than a, than a key fob. So it's kind
Speaker 15:  of like game over with this you can charge,
Speaker 6:  You just have a wall plug on your key chain.
Speaker 15:  But it's so tiny that it's elegant, right? We don't wanna be carrying around
Speaker 15:  a punky brick with us.
Speaker 6:  I love this answer. This is completely not what I was expecting. I love that
Speaker 6:  I'm, I was a straight one 10 plug on a key chain is what you're after.
Speaker 15:  You're like where's my 200 like crazy charger thing? Yeah, I was
Speaker 6:  Like 200,000 watts. Let's go like, like
Speaker 6:  you can plug a Tesla into a USB C like and you're like, here's what I
Speaker 6:  want like a wall plug. Like, but that's actually really interesting to think
Speaker 6:  about it that if that's what you can stretch out to, we're kind of just back
Speaker 6:  to having power cables.
Speaker 15:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Right. Only this is a power cable that has intelligence in it's a self negotiator
Speaker 6:  rate. Like we are just back to power cables is that like I I don
Speaker 6:  know I bought a power strip for $7 yesterday. It's a real thing that happened
Speaker 6:  and I did not think, I mean maybe you should not buy one that
Speaker 6:  you're gonna run too many amps on, but like most people do not think about
Speaker 6:  a power strip. They're like, I'm gonna buy a power strip, it's gonna have
Speaker 6:  six plugs in it. Hopefully I can fiddle my wall warts on it and that's how
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna evaluate this power strip. And you don't think about charging speeds
Speaker 6:  or delivery with USB. You have to, and
Speaker 6:  yet USB C is gonna become the power cable for the world. Are we gonna get
Speaker 6:  to a place where we can, we can just stop thinking about it that way because
Speaker 6:  you're gonna integrate a regular power plug on the end and we'll just negotiate
Speaker 6:  it intelligently. Like how is that gonna play out?
Speaker 15:  Yeah. Well you've got me thinking to to your previous question as well is
Speaker 15:  I'm just really hopeful that it becomes as universal
Speaker 15:  as it can become. I'm just thinking about all the products that we have
Speaker 15:  that don't use USB C but do use their own AC to DC wall wart thing and
Speaker 15:  you're plugging in the barrel connector, it's called the little circular
Speaker 15:  plug. And think of your, your Dyson vacuum cleaner, your,
Speaker 15:  you know, any, it's certain mini household products, et cetera. So we still
Speaker 15:  have so many products out there that are using all their weird little
Speaker 15:  power systems. And then if you lose the thing You don't know, I have a charger,
Speaker 15:  I have a little air pump like mattress, air inflator thing and I can't remember
Speaker 15:  where I put that barrel plug. And I like don't buy things if they don't
Speaker 15:  have USB C, if they could have USB C I've been waiting for years to
Speaker 15:  do USB C electric shaver. So there's all these household
Speaker 15:  items and all these things that I'm excited for it to it to come to it.
Speaker 15:  And as that happens, like back to your point on what's your like dream build
Speaker 15:  I guess like don don't know maybe as well, again really boring answer, but
Speaker 15:  building the cables that can supply the wattage for these
Speaker 15:  household appliances and devices that might take a higher
Speaker 15:  wattage to charge, because I don't want to have still,
Speaker 15:  when, when you look at even that US BBC's become universal for all of
Speaker 15:  our portable electronics and so forth, it's not quite universal on
Speaker 15:  household appliances and all these other things that are running
Speaker 15:  on DC anyways and probably should go USB c And sometimes the, the, the supply
Speaker 15:  chain there can be slow to change. I'm sure we all have had the experience
Speaker 15:  where you bought something and you're like, wait, it's still using
Speaker 15:  that cable. Yeah. You know, I'm using a mic. Granted it's an older one right
Speaker 15:  now and it has a mini USB on it, and it's really high quality
Speaker 15:  mic. It's from, it's from years ago. But even when I got it, it was, we,
Speaker 15:  when we got it, it was weird that it had the mini on it. So, so
Speaker 15:  sometimes things can take a while in the deep supply chain. You might go
Speaker 15:  into REI to buy a, a light, a camping light, and it might still have micro.
Speaker 15:  And I'm at a point where I'm not buying that. Like i, I am gonna, unless
Speaker 15:  it's the only one of its kind, it's just, it's gotta be USB. C
Speaker 7:  One of the things I've been wondering is as we get to that
Speaker 7:  universality, like the, the sort of addressable market of everything, USB
Speaker 7:  C goes up in a really big way now that it's kind of universal and available
Speaker 7:  to everybody. Like everybody's just gonna have USB C stuff. And part of what
Speaker 7:  that makes me wonder is if like you're talking about these sort of super
Speaker 7:  niche accessories can start to come back, right? Like I feel
Speaker 7:  like especially in the electronic space, you can spend an outrageous amount
Speaker 7:  of money on like a really fancy case for your iPhone. And that's about it.
Speaker 7:  And I now wonder if like, if Neli is gonna be able to get
Speaker 7:  his ultra fancy many thousands of dollars
Speaker 7:  multi-device charger, because there aren't tons of people in the world
Speaker 7:  who would buy that, but there's just enough. And now they all can totally
Speaker 7:  'cause it's USB C and I wonder like, are we gonna, all of the stuff that's
Speaker 7:  been out there until now has been sort of mainstream on purpose because you
Speaker 7:  have to be in order to sort of be accessible to people who would buy
Speaker 7:  this thing. But now I wonder the market is just so much bigger if it's just
Speaker 7:  gonna get much weirder and nicher and fancier and more luxurious.
Speaker 7:  And part of that is what's really exciting to me that we're gonna get to
Speaker 7:  like the speaker market, right? Where it's like you can buy the $20 speakers
Speaker 7:  everybody has, but you can also spend 50 grand on a pair of speakers if you
Speaker 7:  really want to. And there's just enough people in the world for that, that
Speaker 7:  It works. And like, I wonder if we're gonna get there with some of these
Speaker 7:  accessories too. I kind of hope So
Speaker 15:  I Hope. So I. Imagine it's coming. I was just chatting the other day with
Speaker 15:  our supply chain director, a guy named Darren Total audio file and
Speaker 15:  spends a good chunk of his paycheck going into these really
Speaker 15:  nice speakers.
Speaker 6:  I'm with you Dan, let's hang, let's hang buddy. Our people
Speaker 15:  And I was buying Monitor British company and just
Speaker 15:  really beautiful work that they do on their, on the, the, the
Speaker 15:  metals and the housings and in industrial design just kind of, kind of
Speaker 15:  in that really upper level category.
Speaker 6:  My, my left rights and centers are monitored. I'm with you Darren. We we
Speaker 6:  vibe baby.
Speaker 15:  You guys would love it. And he, it was, it was just funny looking at it
Speaker 15:  and he was getting all excited about these details. And I could just imagine
Speaker 15:  so many companies who are in the broader electronics
Speaker 15:  speaker, consumer space, you know, companies that have been around for a
Speaker 15:  while have really high standards, build really goals. Cool stuff. This is
Speaker 15:  an opportunity for them to go, oh, okay. That, that thing finally settled,
Speaker 15:  all that bs of all the different cables and this and that. And granted before
Speaker 15:  the cables, not only were there different standards, they didn't have the
Speaker 15:  capabilities that USB c has. USB c has a lot of capabilities.
Speaker 15:  So like I was saying, we just got some new monitors in the office and
Speaker 15:  instead we can now get USB c cables for them or, or
Speaker 15:  USB, C-H-D-M-I cables because I'm sort of sick of the whole HDMI thing
Speaker 15:  too. So it's just really cool what what can happen. And I do
Speaker 15:  think that with more universality, it opens the opportunity for people
Speaker 15:  to take it seriously and for, to jump in and to build really cool stuff.
Speaker 15:  I hope that Nomad can continue to be one of those. And I expect we're gonna
Speaker 15:  see some high-end competition and it'll help us help keep us sharp and
Speaker 15:  neli. I I think we're gonna, if we don't make it granted we
Speaker 15:  got some cool stuff in the works. I think we're gonna be seeing stuff like
Speaker 15:  that out there. And we're, and and that's totally up our alley too. So I.
Speaker 6:  Love it. All, right now we gotta let you go. I gotta say in the, in the spirit
Speaker 6:  of the holiday, there's no better place to end this than with some light
Speaker 6:  shit. Talk about HTMI like that. That's a perfect ending
Speaker 6:  for The Vergecast Holiday Spectacular. Just throwing it right back
Speaker 6:  at the HT MI people. They were our first spectacular by the way.
Speaker 15:  Oh my
Speaker 6:  Gosh. A deeply political organization. I have to tell you,
Speaker 15:  I thought we were going non-controversial.
Speaker 6:  No, no, no. It's the holidays, man. We're light this thing on fire. Let's
Speaker 6:  talk politics. No. Amazing. Thank you so much for joining us on The, Vergecast
Speaker 6:  Holiday Spectacular.
Speaker 15:  Thanks guys.
Speaker 16:  Guys, USB c USB C
Speaker 16:  Healthy Folk Car, your transfers
Speaker 6:  All, right, boys and girls. That's it for The, Vergecast holiday
Speaker 6:  spectacular USB C edition. We hope you Have a happy holiday season.
Speaker 6:  We hope your families are safe. We hope you get a lot of charging cables
Speaker 6:  in your stockings that can go at 240 watts and transfer
Speaker 6:  data at 40 gigabits per second. The Jeezy cable, if you will.
Speaker 6:  It's the holidays. We hope you Have a happy new year. Hold your loved ones
Speaker 6:  tight, throw away their lightning cables and move to one
Speaker 6:  universal standard for serial communications. That's it. That's The Vergecast.
Speaker 6:  Holiday spectacular. Safe travels and rock and roll.