# Transcript
ID: edfc3328-2c7d-4baa-9014-ced03ac19c37
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: How Planet Earth — and the Netflix homepage — get made
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5749970406947952433/1287900301963792438/s93290-US-6076s-1701246874.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of multi-drone camera setups:
03:19 - The Verge's David Pierce chats with Planet Earth III producer Alex Walters and director Theo Webb about the gear used to make the latest nature documentary series.
30:13 - Netflix's Pat Flemming joins the show to discuss how Netflix figures out what to show when you open the app, and how to keep you coming back.
1:20:29 -The Verge's publisher Helen Havlak and editor-in-chief Nilay Patel join the show to answer this week's hotline question.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (8 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of multi drone camera
Speaker 2:  setups. I'm your friend David Pierce, and I am currently sitting here at
Speaker 2:  my desk comparison shopping monitors, So I. Do this thing
Speaker 2:  where I would say once every nine months or So I get this
Speaker 2:  idea in my head that what I need is a different number of
Speaker 2:  screens of different size. Sometimes I'm like, I'm just gonna be a laptop
Speaker 2:  guy. I'm gonna be more focused. I'm just gonna sit here and look at
Speaker 2:  this one small screen. It's gonna keep me on task, it's gonna be great. That
Speaker 2:  never works. So then I'm like, okay, I'm gonna have a command station.
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna get a bunch of monitors. One of them is gonna be vertical, one
Speaker 2:  of them is gonna be curved, one of 'em is gonna be humongous. I'm gonna get
Speaker 2:  so much done. You're gonna freak out. You don't even know that doesn't work
Speaker 2:  either. And then eventually I end up back at one monitor.
Speaker 2:  Right now I have 1 24 inch, 4K monitor. I've had this for the
Speaker 2:  last year or so. It works fine, but it's starting to feel kind of
Speaker 2:  small. So what I'm gonna do next is attempt to not
Speaker 2:  swing one way or the other on this pendulum, but just add one more
Speaker 2:  monitor, maybe 27 inches, maybe 24. Everything's on sale.
Speaker 2:  Who knows? Anyway, we have an awesome show coming up for you today. Today
Speaker 2:  turned out to be one of those episodes where we're kind of accidentally on
Speaker 2:  a theme, and I would say the theme is How Stuff Appears on
Speaker 2:  your television. We're gonna talk to the folks who made Planet Earth,
Speaker 2:  the documentary series from the B, B, C, all about the technology it takes
Speaker 2:  to make that show and to get into the lives of
Speaker 2:  animals and the Planet. Then we're gonna talk to Pat Flemming, who is
Speaker 2:  one of the heads of product at Netflix, all about recommendations and basically
Speaker 2:  what it takes to show you exactly what you wanna watch
Speaker 2:  at exactly the right time. It's much harder and much higher stakes
Speaker 2:  than you might think. All of that is coming up in just a second. But first
Speaker 2:  I have to figure out if this Asus monitor I'm looking at is different
Speaker 2:  from this other assu monitor I'm looking at, because I've been staring at
Speaker 2:  these two pages for 10 minutes and I just realized they might be the same
Speaker 2:  monitor. That's how this is going. This is The Vergecast. See you in a sec.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. The thing you should know before we get into this segment
Speaker 2:  is that I'm kind of obsessed with the TV series, Planet Earth.
Speaker 6:  We can now show life on our Planet in entirely new ways.
Speaker 6:  Bring you closer to animals than ever before
Speaker 6:  and reveal new wildlife dramas for the
Speaker 6:  very first time.
Speaker 2:  The truth is, I'll watch anything that's just like slow moving drone
Speaker 2:  shots of beautiful landscapes and then super tight shots of animals
Speaker 2:  while someone talks in a cool accent about a whole part of the
Speaker 2:  earth I've never heard of before, and there are a lot of those shows out
Speaker 2:  there, but Planet Earth does it better than everybody else. I mean, just
Speaker 2:  like listen to this clip for a second from Planet Earth too.
Speaker 6:  He listens carefully to pinpoint his target.
Speaker 6:  It's moving
Speaker 6:  a vo.
Speaker 2:  I mean, come on. That is the stuff right there. I love it. Anyway, the
Speaker 2:  third Planet Earth series is out now. It's been seven years since season
Speaker 2:  two aired, and now we get more Planet Earth and I mean, this is not a spoiler
Speaker 2:  and it's not surprising, but it's awesome. And it's actually a really fun
Speaker 2:  snapshot of technology progress too. These folks spend years
Speaker 2:  trying to access new places and get new kinds of shots and tell
Speaker 2:  new stories about the world in different kinds of ways. And so much of that
Speaker 2:  is actually about technology. So I called up two of the people who worked
Speaker 2:  on Planet Earth, three Theo Webb and Alex Walters. To get into the
Speaker 2:  weeds a bit about the tech involved in making a series like this.
Speaker 7:  I'm Theo Webb. I am a producer director on the Extremes
Speaker 7:  episode of Planet Earth three.
Speaker 8:  My name's Alex Walters and I'm an assistant producer on Planet Earth.
Speaker 8:  Three
Speaker 2:  Between them, they've basically seen how all of the sausage gets made.
Speaker 2:  I had this theory when I started watching Planet Earth three, that the big
Speaker 2:  difference is going to be how much less gear was involved in making every
Speaker 2:  episode. Maybe they'd shoot everything on smartphones, and certainly the
Speaker 2:  big cameras would be smaller and more maneuverable. Maybe you can shoot with
Speaker 2:  like a phone, A-D-S-L-R and a DJ I drone and boom,
Speaker 2:  you're done. But then you watch the behind the scenes at the end of every
Speaker 2:  episode and no, it's still a ton of gear.
Speaker 2:  There's one whole thing that's just a panning shot of all the
Speaker 2:  batteries they had to charge, and it's terrifying to look at. And Theo
Speaker 2:  said, actually, if anything, it's more gear this time.
Speaker 7:  Oh, and like a hundred percent we need, we needed so much stuff. We wanted
Speaker 7:  to film macro, we wanted to kind of get as much moving imagery as possible,
Speaker 7:  sliders, et cetera. We weren't quite sure what tool would be, right. And
Speaker 7:  actually we took a lot of stuff, but almost all of it we used actually
Speaker 7:  for at least one shot. Some of the times, yes, you take a bit of kit out
Speaker 7:  to a location and you know it sits in a box and you're like, well, that
Speaker 7:  was a waste of time and effort. But on this occasion, actually,
Speaker 7:  the poor people that carried it round the cave, they did not do it in vain.
Speaker 7:  It was worthwhile. Like there was so much reused. But the funny thing is
Speaker 7:  a lot of that behind the scenes segment that was actually shot
Speaker 7:  with iPhone. And we found that because
Speaker 7:  there's that inbuilt software that's processing the images so much more
Speaker 7:  clearly than let's say, a camcorder, which is just basically built for, for
Speaker 7:  outdoor use that we would normally take as a behind the scenes camera. The
Speaker 7:  iPhone was processing it and you could just get that live feedback of what
Speaker 7:  you're filming and it dealt with the noise and with the low light so well
Speaker 7:  that that actually became the easiest thing. It meant you've got it in your
Speaker 7:  pocket. And I dream of the day that we can just take that out as our main
Speaker 7:  make off camera. So easy.
Speaker 2:  Maybe by Planet Earth four, when I guess we'll be on the iPhone 22,
Speaker 2:  it'll be fully up for the task. Probably not, but we can hope for
Speaker 2:  now though, making a show like this is still an incredible amount of work
Speaker 2:  and an incredible amount of specialized equipment like the microphones
Speaker 2:  that Alex and a crew use to capture these tiny things called
Speaker 2:  tree hoppers. In an episode titled Forests,
Speaker 6:  This Tree Hopper mother communicates with her young,
Speaker 6:  encouraging them to stay together so that she can protect
Speaker 6:  them.
Speaker 2:  These things are the size of a pinhead, so they're not easy to find
Speaker 2:  or capture at all. So what Alex and the other producers do
Speaker 2:  in a situation like that is they talk to researchers and scientists who
Speaker 2:  know these animals really well and know where they'll be and how to
Speaker 2:  interact with them. They're actually, as a result, sometimes able to storyboard
Speaker 2:  the shots they're going to get knowing how these animals work. But to be
Speaker 2:  fair, it really never seems to go to plan at all.
Speaker 8:  I was talking to a scientist in America called Rex Kroft, who
Speaker 8:  is an absolute genius and he spends his life listening
Speaker 8:  in on conversations between animals, specifically tree hoppers.
Speaker 8:  So he was really key to this and he helped us develop the technology
Speaker 8:  to be able to listen in on them. And then alongside that, we had
Speaker 8:  Javier, who was our specialist, he's a, he's a photographer
Speaker 8:  actually, and he was the one who brought this story to us about the tree
Speaker 8:  hoppers interacting with this symbiotic relationship with
Speaker 8:  bees. They're like bodyguards. These bees come in and protect the tree hoppers.
Speaker 8:  So actually it was a combination of different scientists and I
Speaker 8:  spent a lot of time talking to them and planning in advance for the shoot.
Speaker 8:  But the tree hoppers, it's inaudible to the human ear. So we use
Speaker 8:  these pizo discs that we would attach the microphone
Speaker 8:  and we would put them on the branches to be able to listen in on this
Speaker 8:  world of these tiny little insects while they communicate to each other.
Speaker 8:  They all have different language. There's over 3000 species and they all
Speaker 8:  communicate with different sounds and they mean different things. So some
Speaker 8:  of them talk to each other about finding a mate. Some of them
Speaker 8:  tell at each other where food sources are. Others will talk about where
Speaker 8:  predators are, which is part of the sequence that we filmed. So they are
Speaker 8:  absolutely fascinating and their sounds are really bizarre. They sound like
Speaker 8:  they're out of space or something.
Speaker 2:  There are stories like this for basically every single frame
Speaker 2:  and moment of Planet earth. Like there's this one shot in the extremes episode
Speaker 2:  where we're inside this huge colony of butterflies,
Speaker 2:  hundreds of thousands of them all hunkered down for the winter.
Speaker 2:  And if you disturb these butterflies, you're gonna send thousands of them
Speaker 2:  flying off, which A ruins the shot. And B also probably
Speaker 2:  kills a lot of the butterflies. So you end up having to get creative
Speaker 2:  trying to figure out how to get in there.
Speaker 7:  The fun thing about this shoot is it relied on a very specific
Speaker 7:  bit of technology, which is socks. Without socks,
Speaker 7:  the whole shoe would've been ruined. So these butterflies, they
Speaker 7:  can't really afford to lose too much energy over that winter
Speaker 7:  period, otherwise they won't make it through. So the crew had
Speaker 7:  to be as quiet as possible, which literally meant taking off their
Speaker 7:  shoes and walking around in socks. So they'd be setting up cable dollies
Speaker 7:  on a tree without butterflies on, et cetera, you know, put one on it
Speaker 7:  and then they'd be kind of moving this cable dolly silently through.
Speaker 7:  They'd have their socks on and they'd just be, they'd just be waiting. Meanwhile,
Speaker 7:  it's, it's not actually that warmer place. It looks kind of quite nice and
Speaker 7:  warm and cozy, but it's actually quite a high altitude. Forest in Mexico
Speaker 7:  drops below freezing easily at night, which is half a problem for the
Speaker 7:  butterflies. But the butterflies, they have this, you know, perfect little
Speaker 7:  ecosystem in, in the canopy there, which keeps them nice and warm. But for
Speaker 7:  the, for the crew on the ground that was less comfy, but socks who knew it,
Speaker 2:  Some shots, they know they can get, animals have patterns. Big
Speaker 2:  caves are probably still going to be there next year. One thing I've heard
Speaker 2:  from a lot of nature filmmakers over the years is that if you just show up
Speaker 2:  and stay there, eventually most animals will get used to you and
Speaker 2:  just carry on living their lives so you can get what you need as long as
Speaker 2:  you're patient enough. That's why you see a lot of hides and camera
Speaker 2:  traps. Really, a camera trap is actually a staple of Planet earth. You set
Speaker 2:  up a camera in some slightly hidden but very central place, turn it on
Speaker 2:  and just wait. And knowing where to put those cameras and
Speaker 2:  actually how to place them and angle them and focus them is a real skill.
Speaker 2:  Like when you're prepared to capture 8,000 hours of footage trying to catch
Speaker 2:  a glimpse of a snow leopard in Mongolia,
Speaker 7:  The guy who did that, a guy called Jake Davis, he's really specialized
Speaker 7:  in these camera traps and he has this amazing
Speaker 7:  ability to get into the, the head of the animal. And you know, when you're
Speaker 7:  setting up a camera trap, it's gotta be the right height. You set up, you
Speaker 7:  know, the height of my head. You're never gonna, you don't film anything.
Speaker 7:  It's gotta be down at the right, the eye line, you know, you wanna make it
Speaker 7:  cinematic as well as functional. So you get it down, you get it set
Speaker 7:  up, and then you have to crawl through the frame, right, pretending you're
Speaker 7:  a snow leo to kind of mimic the, the action.
Speaker 2:  But also, and this is the thing you hear from nature filmmakers over and
Speaker 2:  over, is sometimes you just get lucky.
Speaker 7:  But actually my favorite shot in that sequence was one actually
Speaker 7:  designed by the snow leopard themselves. The camera trap was placed down,
Speaker 7:  but the cat decided, I didn't really like the position of that. So they like
Speaker 7:  it rubbed themselves on it, they'd carried it, they'd moved it, and they
Speaker 7:  just put it down, right? And then a couple of days later, I think it was
Speaker 7:  the ca same cat walked down right in front of it. But what the, what the
Speaker 7:  frame had done was, because it had been put a slight angle, but also pointed
Speaker 7:  to the ground, there was a super shallow depth of field and the cat just
Speaker 7:  placed its foot right in the middle of that depth of field. And it's like
Speaker 7:  the most perfect snow leopard shot you could have imagined. But you know,
Speaker 7:  he can't take credit for that 'cause it was a snow Leo that did it.
Speaker 2:  There are a lot of moments in making something like this where you just prepare
Speaker 2:  as best you can and then wait as long as possible. But sometimes you're
Speaker 2:  literally only going to get one shot. Like there's this one moment
Speaker 2:  in the forests episode where a tree almost 200 feet tall, goes
Speaker 2:  crashing down in the middle of a forest. You know, if a tree falls in the
Speaker 2:  forest and you're not there to film it, does it? Nah, nevermind. That's a
Speaker 2:  terrible joke. Anyway, it's a really hard thing to film. It turns out
Speaker 8:  The tree fall was really complicated and took a huge amount of
Speaker 8:  planning, as you can imagine, and a, a big risk assessment that I had to
Speaker 8:  write. But yeah, so that one, we had quite a big
Speaker 8:  crew. We had three drone operators who were flying at the same time.
Speaker 8:  So two of the drones were static to keep it, you know, simple and, and so
Speaker 8:  they, you know, no disturbances within each other's shots. And then one that
Speaker 8:  was moving and reacting with the tree as it fell. So that's like a sweeping
Speaker 8:  shot that pulls back. And then we had ground cameras. So
Speaker 8:  myself and Yuri van and another camera operator, we were operating the ground
Speaker 8:  cameras. We had six of them placed. We knew this tree was around 60
Speaker 8:  meters high. We'd measured it with the drone and sort of seen how high it
Speaker 8:  was with that. And then we'd measured on the ground how far we need the
Speaker 8:  cameras to be away to get this whoosh of all the leaves and
Speaker 8:  everything breaking, coming up towards the camera, which is one of the shots
Speaker 8:  you'll see in the forest episode. But you know, not having the cameras completely
Speaker 8:  smashed the Smith rains, which was a real risk. You know, some of the
Speaker 8:  cameras were GoPros and we were like, you know, if we lose a GoPro then it's
Speaker 8:  not the end of the world. But you know, some of them are these red cameras
Speaker 8:  that'll, you know how much they, they're very expensive cameras with very
Speaker 8:  expensive lenses. So they were based more at the base of the tree, sort of
Speaker 8:  where we knew it definitely wasn't gonna fall in that direction. We then
Speaker 8:  worked with some locals who allowed us to film them, fell,
Speaker 8:  they selectively fell the tree. They told us, we know that when we take
Speaker 8:  this route off, it's going to fall in that direction. So we knew the direction
Speaker 8:  it was going to fall. So there was a lot of planning, a lot of talking
Speaker 8:  with the local people and that was key. And none of the cameras
Speaker 8:  got smashed, which was absolutely amazing.
Speaker 2:  I could do this forever, honestly. There are fun technology stories behind
Speaker 2:  basically everything in the show. But let's just do two more here. First,
Speaker 2:  there's this section of the Extremes episode filmed in a cave in Vietnam
Speaker 2:  that is thought to be the world's largest cave. It's called Hang Sun Don
Speaker 2:  the crew spent more than two weeks in this cave filming it in all sorts of
Speaker 2:  different ways, but the most remarkable thing I think that they did is
Speaker 2:  a two drone setup to try and capture the true size
Speaker 2:  and scope of this place.
Speaker 7:  We had a team of fourth cinematographers, but we chose one in particular
Speaker 7:  because he'd been down inside Ong Don Cave, he, he's been down like
Speaker 7:  almost 15 times or something like that. So he knows the cave really well.
Speaker 7:  He shot a lot for himself, but he'd never done what we wanted to do, which
Speaker 7:  is take sort of cinema cameras down there and show the cave off
Speaker 7:  in a, in a different, in a different way. He'd also never spent, I don't
Speaker 7:  think, more than three or four days there. So the fact that we were gonna
Speaker 7:  spend 18 days underground in that cave
Speaker 7:  sort of blew his mind and also made him incredibly excited at the same time.
Speaker 7:  He was like, oh my God, think about what I can do out here. So first of all,
Speaker 7:  what he thought about was how, how to light it, right? Because as you say,
Speaker 7:  the paradox of filming underground is that unless you're so light, there
Speaker 7:  is nothing to see. And yet you want to keep some of it
Speaker 7:  dark to keep it like mysterious, but also it helps with that sense of scale.
Speaker 7:  If you like the whole thing, you lose that scale, you lose the texture, you
Speaker 7:  lose everything. So what we, what we decided to do and, and with his
Speaker 7:  assistance, we built these kind of four panel arrays of custom LEDs,
Speaker 7:  which are super bright LED panel and they have a cone attached to them
Speaker 7:  and you can bolt them together, which is how we created this sort of four
Speaker 7:  panel array. We tucked that underneath this heavy lift drone, so A
Speaker 7:  DDI matri 600, which is, you know, 10 kilos heavy,
Speaker 7:  about a meter wide. It's a huge beast. We'd put that up in the air
Speaker 7:  and the 15 minute timer would start ticking. So the lights outta their own
Speaker 7:  battery source and they were the weak link if you like. They ran out about
Speaker 7:  15 minutes at the same time, we'd send up A-A-D-G-I Mavic
Speaker 7:  three pro and, and that would be our filming camera. I
Speaker 7:  see that the other kind of fun thing about filming inside a cave, right,
Speaker 7:  is that obviously you've got no GPS on the drones, right? GPS is
Speaker 7:  non-functional, and when you take that away from a lot of consumer
Speaker 7:  drones, they freak out. They have this inbuilt cap, right? They only
Speaker 7:  go 10 meters high, so you can't do anything crazy with 'em. So
Speaker 7:  we actually had to work with DGI to take those caps off for this very
Speaker 7:  specific case. Didn't work with the DGI MA three. So we had
Speaker 7:  to hack it in the cave by, by doing these crazy flight stunts.
Speaker 7:  So we'd worked out that if you use the topography of the cave, it would
Speaker 7:  baffle the drone and it would think that it was above or below
Speaker 7:  10 meters, whatever. Anyway, so we'd fly over this bit of topography, it
Speaker 7:  would think, oh, it's cool. I I I'm still within my 10 meter zone anyway,
Speaker 7:  we could fly at a hundred meters high, which is crazy in itself because we're
Speaker 7:  underground in this, well, a hundred meter plus cavern, right? Huge thing.
Speaker 7:  So we take our fly around with that and, and meanwhile we're, whilst we're
Speaker 7:  filming with this Mavic, we would swing the lighting drone around
Speaker 7:  in arcs around the object that we are trying to film. What it would do, it
Speaker 7:  was, it would move the pool of light to both reveal and hide
Speaker 7:  certain areas of the cave, which would also enhance the shadows
Speaker 7:  and, and the textures of the cave features. And it was a way that
Speaker 7:  we could introduce scale into the cave and also
Speaker 7:  just show this underworld like has never been shown before.
Speaker 2:  One cool thing, by the way, about that drone footage and about a lot of the
Speaker 2:  stuff in the cave is that you see people in the shots a lot. The crew members
Speaker 2:  are actually in this series much more than in previous Planet Earth, which
Speaker 2:  Alex and Theo both said was a deliberate choice. They both wanted to show
Speaker 2:  scale, but also to remind people that humans are part of
Speaker 2:  and change every single one of these stories. It works really well in actually
Speaker 2:  both ways and is pretty wild in particular in the cave. So
Speaker 2:  that's the big stuff. And then all the way on the other end of the spectrum,
Speaker 2:  there are two sequences in the episodes we're talking about where we actually
Speaker 2:  get to see inside of nest. One is inside a
Speaker 2:  termite mound in the grasslands of Australia where parrots are hatching their
Speaker 2:  eggs and another with oriental pied hornbills
Speaker 2:  burying into a tree to make a nest In Borneo,
Speaker 6:  Once settled inside, the female does something
Speaker 6:  truly bizarre.
Speaker 6:  She pulls out her flight feathers,
Speaker 6:  she is not going to need them because she will be
Speaker 6:  staying in here for quite some time.
Speaker 2:  Both times you're in this teeny tiny space that is somehow well lit,
Speaker 2:  shot in high resolution, and doesn't drive the animals totally
Speaker 2:  insane. It's wild. And it's really hard to put together
Speaker 7:  These parrots, these golden shoulder parrots like beautiful. They live in
Speaker 7:  these grasslands in, in Northern Australia, they're super rare. You got,
Speaker 7:  they, you gotta be super sensitive, right? You, you know, one failed nest
Speaker 7:  equals a whole generation for that family not pledging and
Speaker 7:  replenishing the population. So we had to work with a
Speaker 7:  landowner who has, who has loved, who has studied,
Speaker 7:  who has looked after and cared for her land. And these
Speaker 7:  parrots for like decades. She works with this amazing scientist, Steve
Speaker 7:  Murphy, who allowed us to make a small hole in the
Speaker 7:  back of the termite mound once the chicks had hatched.
Speaker 7:  So they're much more relaxed, so they're feeding, they're feeding. So when
Speaker 7:  the mom and dad are away, we need this small hole in and using, using our
Speaker 7:  probe blends, this lower probe blends, we are able to, to get it through.
Speaker 7:  And it's super wide lens. So you can, you can see the whole, whole nest.
Speaker 7:  The, the nest is probably only the size of like a don don't know a grapefruit,
Speaker 7:  right? So it's, it's actually pretty small. So you're getting this really
Speaker 7:  intimate view in, and then of course the lighter, it, it's, it's super important
Speaker 7:  because if you, if you just rely on the lighting from the, from the hole,
Speaker 7:  you just, everything's really back lit and, and dark and bright and it's,
Speaker 7:  it's awful. So you've gotta make another tiny hole for the tiny little, little
Speaker 7:  LED lights that we could, we could shine through it at creative angle and
Speaker 7:  and light it inside. And then we'd run a cable away to a hide 20,
Speaker 7:  30 meters away. And, and then it'd be remote triggered. So once it's there,
Speaker 7:  it was, it was all set, but we wanted to film at, at different stages. So,
Speaker 7:  so we would, you know, we'd we'd film for a day go, yeah, pretty much we've
Speaker 7:  got enough kind of feeding moments. We'd, we'd withdraw the camera. We thought,
Speaker 7:  okay, two weeks later we'll come back and stick it in and get the next part
Speaker 7:  of the life stage. By which time, by which time the, the termites, they're
Speaker 7:  so industrious, right over that short period of time, they'd sealed back
Speaker 7:  that hole. So they're like, oh God, So I had to make that hole again, do
Speaker 7:  this whole thing. But anyway, once we learned how to do that, the, the camera
Speaker 7:  op Mitch decided to put a cork in it. I think actually it just,
Speaker 7:  just a plug, which, which meant the, the termite sealed around the plug.
Speaker 7:  So it was with air tie and everything, but it meant they could just pop it
Speaker 7:  out and put the lens back in. It was a super privileged look into these super
Speaker 7:  rare parrots and, and I'm really pleased to say that they all fledged absolutely
Speaker 7:  beautifully. It was joyous to see them all fly away. But
Speaker 7:  Alex your story and the horn bell, it's amazing, right?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So we use a very similar setup to Theo's. We, we've actually
Speaker 8:  used some of the same lighting and the same lens. So we sent all of that
Speaker 8:  to Borneo for our team in Borneo, to use And. what they had to do, because
Speaker 8:  it's, it's such a long process's nesting period is very
Speaker 8:  long. First of all, we had to guess which nests that these
Speaker 8:  hornbills would use because we didn't want to disturb them. So we
Speaker 8:  chose five nests and the guys out there worked with scientists who studies
Speaker 8:  the Hornbills. So they went out and they set up tree platforms attached
Speaker 8:  to the side of the trees for the camera to go on eventually if that
Speaker 8:  female chose that nest hole. And then they waited for them to
Speaker 8:  sort of, for their behavior to start happening where they could see which
Speaker 8:  nest they would be choosing. And then just like the termite mounds with
Speaker 8:  Theo, we, we drilled very, very tiny holes and used this almost
Speaker 8:  endoscopic laa probe to sort of film
Speaker 8:  inside the nest. So we inserted, we'd made a hole for that. And then we also
Speaker 8:  made I think three holes for lighting because you know, endo, these
Speaker 8:  endoscopic cameras, they need a lot of lighting to get the light into these
Speaker 8:  very dark cavities. And then what we had to do is
Speaker 8:  again, the cameras were tethered and the lights were tethered. So once she
Speaker 8:  decided which nest she was in, we had to wait sort of a week or so
Speaker 8:  for her to settle in. And then in the nighttime, well in
Speaker 8:  the very early morning, they then unplugged the hole,
Speaker 8:  which they'd plugged up with clay because obviously it's a living tree and
Speaker 8:  you don't want to add any bacteria or anything. So they used clay and then
Speaker 8:  they would gently put in the probe blends and then they would
Speaker 8:  also put in the lights and then will foster Grundy. Our camera
Speaker 8:  operator would also gradually turn up the lights as the
Speaker 8:  daylight started coming up. They've got quite big eyes, these birds and they're
Speaker 8:  very sensitive to their surroundings. And so there were times she definitely
Speaker 8:  muddied, you know, she's, she's expert, you know, muddying up herself into
Speaker 8:  this tree hole and creating this little gap for her to live in. But she would
Speaker 8:  then muddy up the lights and the camera. It
Speaker 8:  was frustrating but like they work so delicately and they
Speaker 8:  managed to get the full behavior of her. And yeah, she accepted it
Speaker 8:  eventually and we got this absolutely incredible intimate view of inside
Speaker 8:  the nest, which you know, without that the story wouldn't have been half
Speaker 8:  as good, you know, to be able to see her perspective, you know, almost as
Speaker 8:  if she's in this pri this prison and it's just, yeah, I think it
Speaker 8:  made for an excellent sequence.
Speaker 2:  Ultimately in talking to Theo and Alex, it didn't sound like there was much
Speaker 2:  they couldn't do technologically speaking. It's all a lot of work and a
Speaker 2:  lot of gear. It takes forever and this show is expensive
Speaker 2:  to make, but most of it is doable still though Alex
Speaker 2:  and Theo said they both have some ideas about how tech could make life easier
Speaker 2:  for say, Planet Earth four in a few years. And even beyond that,
Speaker 8:  I think personally I would like the camera equipment to be a bit lighter
Speaker 8:  because you know, it is getting smaller but actually we end
Speaker 8:  up with just as much clobber, we have just as much here, even though
Speaker 8:  it's becoming smarter because you know, you have this specialized bit of
Speaker 8:  cable that's used for this camera but not for that camera. So you end up
Speaker 8:  with loads nodes of stuff. So it would be nice if things actually just became
Speaker 8:  a bit smaller and a bit lighter, but then sometimes things like tripods,
Speaker 8:  you need them to be heavy for that stability. But that for me that would
Speaker 8:  be great. But then for the making of, you know, as Theo was saying earlier,
Speaker 8:  having an iPhone to film, that has changed and I think that will
Speaker 8:  continue changing.
Speaker 7:  Okay, I've got two. One is drones with telephoto
Speaker 7:  capability. That will change everything because
Speaker 7:  as soon as you can start getting stabilization good enough to get like
Speaker 7:  10 times zooms on, plus you know you are, you're starting to
Speaker 7:  be able to film really, really cool behavior in a really
Speaker 7:  cinematic way, right? You'll be able to get incredible language shots which
Speaker 7:  are moving and yet compressed because you're at a 300 mil or whatever
Speaker 7:  that will be game changing. The miniaturization of zone of drones is a
Speaker 7:  part of that as well. And that will definitely kind of fill that space
Speaker 7:  and it'll be great. My rogue prediction, maybe not for six years but maybe
Speaker 7:  slightly longer, is utilizing space imagery more. We had a great
Speaker 7:  series a few years ago called Strom Space, which which utilized
Speaker 7:  space imagery to get images of something happening on the ground at pretty
Speaker 7:  high, super high resolution, which would then merge with
Speaker 7:  drones filming that same event. And you'd have this crazy interface
Speaker 7:  right from from outer space down and you could fly
Speaker 7:  effectively straight into the action from space. And it was brilliant,
Speaker 7:  it was super cool and I think that was way more innovative than the kind
Speaker 7:  of time should allow for. And I think that imagery from space,
Speaker 7:  the more resolution you can get, the more focus will allow us to do so much
Speaker 7:  more. Both in a filmmaking perspective but also from a science perspective.
Speaker 7:  Counting animals, you know, that's super important what they do with
Speaker 7:  satellite imagery now for like counting penguin colonies is crazy.
Speaker 7:  You know, they look for shit, basically they look for penguin shit on the
Speaker 7:  ice and they go, oh look, there's a whole new colony there. We had no idea
Speaker 7:  there was that many more penguins or that many less penguins. And they can
Speaker 7:  tell how close they are to being like, well
Speaker 7:  wiped off by kind of by ice loss basically. And so
Speaker 7:  that kind of technology will feed into science and it'll feed
Speaker 7:  into what we do as wildlife filmmakers so much more and and I'm super excited
Speaker 7:  about that. And then filming on Mars,
Speaker 2:  You heard it here first. Friends Planet Earth for the Mars edition.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we have to take a break and then we are gonna come back and talk
Speaker 2:  about TV algorithms and how to get recommendations, right? We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back, we're gonna stay on the theme of, like I said,
Speaker 2:  how stuff appears on your television, but I wanna take a look at it in a
Speaker 2:  really different way. For years I have been trying to figure out how
Speaker 2:  streaming apps are supposed to work the way they do work,
Speaker 2:  where you open the app and you're presented with like a hundred million tiles
Speaker 2:  of shows and movies you might like and then you spend forever scrolling through
Speaker 2:  them and never find anything to watch and you eventually just give up and
Speaker 2:  throw your TV into a river and move on with your life. That can't possibly
Speaker 2:  be the best way, but what is the best way? A bunch of years ago I
Speaker 2:  asked somebody at Hulu what the goal was, like the North Star for how they
Speaker 2:  think about this. And he said it was just like a play button.
Speaker 2:  You open the app and it should just know what you wanna watch and maybe even
Speaker 2:  start playing it for you. I'm not sure that's the answer either. So
Speaker 2:  what is the answer there are in the world? Few people better
Speaker 2:  equipped to know the answer to that question than Pat Flemming.
Speaker 12:  I am a senior director of product management here. So I Lead the member
Speaker 12:  experience PM team. Think of that as the group responsible for how
Speaker 12:  profiles work, how the core browse and discovery experience works. How
Speaker 12:  you watch something great tonight or play something great if you're playing
Speaker 12:  games across iOS and Android. And that's across TV devices,
Speaker 12:  the website, iOS and Android phones and tablets,
Speaker 2:  In case you're counting, that's a lot of jobs, but one of them is very much
Speaker 2:  to figure out what should happen when I open the app. Netflix
Speaker 2:  is famous for all the time it spends thinking about these recommendation
Speaker 2:  systems. Do you remember a bunch of years ago when it offered a million dollars
Speaker 2:  to any developer that could improve the system in a meaningful way?
Speaker 2:  Even now picture the app, there's that huge banner that shows up whenever
Speaker 2:  you open Netflix and then below it there's all those endless rows
Speaker 2:  of increasingly specific genres and what's popular And, what you've watched
Speaker 2:  before. And there are a million ways, big and small
Speaker 2:  that Netflix is choosing and influencing what you see and in
Speaker 2:  what order as a result, I guess more than most companies, I found myself
Speaker 2:  often sitting there wondering why Netflix is showing me what
Speaker 2:  it's showing me. So that's what Pat and I talked about. I started by asking
Speaker 2:  him that big picture question I've been asking people for years, the one
Speaker 2:  that I asked that guy at Hulu all those years ago. What is the best case
Speaker 2:  scenario here? When I open Netflix, is the goal to show me a million
Speaker 2:  options? Is it to show me three options, 300 options?
Speaker 2:  Is it to get so good at recommendations that it does get
Speaker 2:  everything right immediately, every time and just starts playing the
Speaker 2:  exact perfect thing? Is that the plan?
Speaker 12:  That would be so cool, but it's, it's quite hard. Okay, right? So people
Speaker 12:  have such diverse tastes and interests. So it's not just that you might
Speaker 12:  love sports documentaries and dramas and
Speaker 12:  baking shows for example. It's also that tonight you might be interested
Speaker 12:  in watching Beckham, but tomorrow you might be interested in watching The
Speaker 12:  Crown. And it's quite difficult for us to know that when you sit down on
Speaker 12:  the couch, so by definition that hit the button on your remote and
Speaker 12:  Beckham or the Crown starts playing. Like that's those, that's a hard, that's
Speaker 12:  a hard game for us to win at at very high frequency and So
Speaker 12:  I think the other thing to say is people like to browse. It's not that people
Speaker 12:  don't like browsing, it's that people don't like bad browsing experiences.
Speaker 12:  So if we can deliver a great discovery experience, that's the word we would
Speaker 12:  use internally and make that browsing experience feel great, feel
Speaker 12:  the right amount, fast, the right amount, compelling, give you the right
Speaker 12:  amount of options, then you're satisfied when you land on one that's that's
Speaker 12:  perfect for you. The other thing to know is that you might not know what
Speaker 12:  you love. So let's take those, those genre examples. So let's say I'm into
Speaker 12:  sports stocks and dramas and let's say many folks
Speaker 12:  who use Netflix are into sports docs, dramas and baking shows.
Speaker 12:  Let's say I haven't tried a baking show yet. The beauty of personalization
Speaker 12:  is that it's nearly a certainty that we would then try to recommend baking
Speaker 12:  shows to me because there's lots of folks out there for whatever reason,
Speaker 12:  who happen to share many of the same similar tastes and preferences I do
Speaker 12:  and this one that I haven't demonstrated yet, but it's plausible that I
Speaker 12:  might. And so we would make that recommendation, hopefully you find it.
Speaker 12:  That's hard for us to do if we're just gonna go for that most likely thing
Speaker 12:  on any given night,
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah, it does seem like a, if you were to do that you would end just
Speaker 2:  playing for me like the safest thing where it's like if I just booted it
Speaker 2:  up and it like you just showed me community every single time I turn on Netflix,
Speaker 2:  like that's a, I'd have an okay time with that, right? Like if, if it was
Speaker 2:  just a community machine for me, like I'm very rarely gonna be mad at that.
Speaker 2:  But there's also no way to ever find me anything new in that world. And
Speaker 2:  it also seems like one theory I have that I can't prove because no one has
Speaker 2:  ever tried it, but I hope somebody does So I can see if it's true is that
Speaker 2:  even if you showed me the right thing, like if I was deciding do
Speaker 2:  I wanna watch the Crown or do I wanna watch Beckham, I think I would reflexively
Speaker 2:  not wanna watch whatever you showed me. Hmm. There's just something about
Speaker 2:  being sort of force fed that makes people not
Speaker 2:  want to do it. I kind of can't describe it but there's something that feels
Speaker 2:  bad about the UI of being told what I'm gonna watch even when
Speaker 2:  it's the right thing.
Speaker 12:  I like that theory. I think it's very plausible. I think we probably hear
Speaker 12:  that in research from time to time that giving me options and then the right
Speaker 12:  amount of what we would call evidence by the way to help me make an informed
Speaker 12:  decision feels more satisfying than us just pushing something to you and
Speaker 12:  that that is the truth of it members and and our incentives are completely
Speaker 12:  aligned. We want to find you something awesome to watch and also make it
Speaker 12:  delightful for you to get there. The simplicity of the Netflix business
Speaker 12:  model is its subscription and so towards the end of the month
Speaker 12:  if you find something, the odds are you're gonna subscribe again tomorrow
Speaker 12:  for the next month. And so that's, that's what we're after and whatever
Speaker 12:  way works best for you, we wanna make that happen. So to the point of making
Speaker 12:  that decision feel good to you. So to your question on like, well would
Speaker 12:  it be better just to kind of push the one thing or do people like the choices?
Speaker 12:  Something you might not know is that the way the choices are
Speaker 12:  presented to you or in any particular country might be a little bit
Speaker 12:  different. So take Squid game for example. You know we would try a variety
Speaker 12:  of different ways to position Squid game to you.
Speaker 12:  And so we would have different sets of static artwork, slightly
Speaker 12:  different synopsis, slightly different ways to promote via video.
Speaker 12:  So like a trailer for example. And then we would try those different ways
Speaker 12:  perhaps in different countries to different groups and they would all be
Speaker 12:  reflective of what Squid game is about, but they would be oriented to try
Speaker 12:  to find what would be best for you to understand what a particular title
Speaker 12:  is about and then make a very informed decision. So that's another element
Speaker 12:  of the personalization again to help you be super satisfied with whatever
Speaker 12:  you click play on so that we're doing our best job we can being a matchmaker
Speaker 12:  for you.
Speaker 2:  That's really interesting. So yeah, let's actually talk about Squid game.
Speaker 2:  'cause I think the question I've always had about Netflix, right is like
Speaker 2:  how something goes from sort of appearing on Netflix
Speaker 2:  to suddenly being everywhere. And I think we talk about it like it's a
Speaker 2:  certain kind of either accidental magic or like brute
Speaker 2:  corporate force from Netflix. And I think that the truth is probably somewhere
Speaker 2:  in the middle. But I do think that the last sort of big picture question
Speaker 2:  I have and then I want to kind of tell this good game story. One of the things
Speaker 2:  I've always wondered about Netflix is it seems to me like you're talking
Speaker 2:  about being a subscription business. All that really matters is that
Speaker 2:  I find something to watch as long as I'm
Speaker 2:  satisfied. Every time I open the app, everybody wins. Odds are I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  keep subscribing and it sounds like that's the case. So what is the upside
Speaker 2:  for Netflix and having these kind of cultural
Speaker 2:  moments. We talk a lot about sort of the the death of the like show everybody's
Speaker 2:  watching. If you're on Netflix, do you care? As long as I'm finding something
Speaker 2:  I like what does it matter if it's the same thing that everybody else is
Speaker 2:  watching?
Speaker 12:  I mean isn't it so fun when something like Squid Game or Wednesday
Speaker 12:  or La Casa de Propel happens? I mean that it's fun. Is it required?
Speaker 12:  No, probably not. And that's the beauty of personalization. So when when
Speaker 12:  you open the app and when I open the app, we're gonna see completely different
Speaker 12:  home experiences 'cause we probably have completely different tastes and
Speaker 12:  preferences. But when it happens it sure feels magical. And so take
Speaker 12:  Squid Game as the example, the beginning of any of these sort of large phenomenons
Speaker 12:  is phenomena is an incredible story. So Squid game,
Speaker 12:  very Korean, you can define it as violent as a
Speaker 12:  a commentary on society. It's funny at times, it's certainly dark,
Speaker 12:  it's exciting, it's thrilling, it's a game show. It's all these different
Speaker 12:  things packed together, created distinctly for a Korean audience. There
Speaker 12:  was no illusions at the outset that that would necessarily be a huge global
Speaker 12:  hit. But what happens is that starts to play incredibly well in
Speaker 12:  Korea. So we start with an audience that is likely to be quite highly qualified
Speaker 12:  in terms of delivering impressions, recommending Squid game for that group.
Speaker 12:  And then because Squid Game and other Netflix
Speaker 12:  originals are available globally, we've got dubs and subtitles
Speaker 12:  and often over the 30 languages. So in the case of Squid game
Speaker 12:  for Brazilian Portuguese and for Latin American Spanish, it
Speaker 12:  started to take off in Latin America. And from there it's sort of difficult
Speaker 12:  to know the causality because it's lots of things are happening outside
Speaker 12:  of Netflix. So people started talking about Squid Game and this became kind
Speaker 12:  of a global thing on social and then people are searching for Squid game
Speaker 12:  on Netflix and that provides us another signal to further change
Speaker 12:  how we're recommending Squid game. And from there the fire just continues
Speaker 12:  to burn and all of a sudden everywhere you're hearing about Squid Game and
Speaker 12:  you open Netflix and you find it happens to be there. And so that's a pretty
Speaker 12:  good example of how it would work. I think La Casa de Papell would probably
Speaker 12:  be another example. Our goal is not necessarily to
Speaker 12:  have titles like Squid Game be the one thing everyone is talking about
Speaker 12:  globally. We want to make titles that are authentically local and can potentially
Speaker 12:  find great audiences all around the world. And that's incredible when they
Speaker 12:  do, it's not always the case. In fact it's more rare than not, but it's
Speaker 12:  super exciting when it does happen.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So you just breeze through a bunch of, I think really interesting like
Speaker 2:  personalization and discovery things. So take the squid game thinking, go
Speaker 2:  like rewind all the way back to the beginning. So like not the why we think
Speaker 2:  the show is interesting thing like that. I get you make the show 'cause you
Speaker 2:  think it's gonna be cool at the very beginning. It seems like with something
Speaker 2:  like that, like I'm assuming sort of from your perch, the job is to figure
Speaker 2:  out like who are we confident? This is gonna be interesting to
Speaker 2:  when you're at the point nobody has seen it. You can either just like beat
Speaker 2:  people over the head with it and make them see it. Or you can try and guess
Speaker 2:  who you think is most likely to like it and show it to them first. Is that,
Speaker 2:  am I thinking about that the right way?
Speaker 12:  Totally the right way. So like two good examples to give you on this one.
Speaker 12:  One, let's keep it with Squid Game. You can go find out about
Speaker 12:  titles that are going to launch on Netflix in an area on Netflix,
Speaker 12:  either on mobile, across iOS and Android or on tv. You can see
Speaker 12:  coming set of coming soon titles, right? And so is
Speaker 2:  That a popular thing? Like do people interact with that a lot? People
Speaker 12:  Love watching trailers and finding out about what's coming, whether it's
Speaker 12:  with us or with other services. So I'd say generally yes, of course. I think
Speaker 12:  people love to sort of anticipate what, what will be fun for them next on
Speaker 12:  Netflix. And so you can tell us directly I'm
Speaker 12:  interested in this thing. So you would, you would literally click remind
Speaker 12:  me and then we would remind you we'd, we would follow up on that obligation.
Speaker 12:  So we'd send you a push notification or an email or remind you in in the
Speaker 12:  app when you open up Netflix. But in addition, that gives us this very
Speaker 12:  explicit signal of the kinds of members who are likely to
Speaker 12:  be interested. Now it's not perfect 'cause you could say, you know, remind
Speaker 12:  me for let's say you know the next season of the Crown, but you have no
Speaker 12:  intention of watching it. You haven't watched the prior seasons, it was
Speaker 12:  like an accident or like you think your partner might wanna watch it with
Speaker 12:  you. So it's not a perfect correlation that when you hit Remind me, you
Speaker 12:  will definitely wanna watch. But it's a pretty good signal for us to work
Speaker 12:  from. And then we would use that to extrapolate. If people like
Speaker 12:  David are hitting remind me at very high rates and people like David watch
Speaker 12:  these kinds of things, then we would probably expand that initial audience
Speaker 12:  to reflect people like you, whether or not again, people like you based
Speaker 12:  on what they watch, we would then recommend. And then from there it just
Speaker 12:  builds. And the beauty again is that it's quite pure and
Speaker 12:  that all we really care about is being a great matchmaker. We worship
Speaker 12:  at the altar of customer satisfaction. So for us to deliver a bad recommendation
Speaker 12:  is for us to have missed out on delivering you a great recommendation. So
Speaker 12:  at the beginning we know very little. And so the other example I would give
Speaker 12:  you here is if you're a brand new member to Netflix, we know
Speaker 12:  almost nothing about you, right? We know where you are, the device, whether
Speaker 12:  it's a phone or TV or laptop that you signed up on. And then
Speaker 12:  all you have to do is tell us just a very little bit about your interest.
Speaker 12:  So we ask you tell us a few titles that you're interested in. And that
Speaker 12:  is the initial spark for personalization where we'll say, okay, based on
Speaker 12:  those expressed stated tastes of preferences, here are the
Speaker 12:  kinds of things that folks who watch those things also like, right?
Speaker 2:  And it seems like, I was reading through the guidelines to the recommendation
Speaker 2:  system that are on your website and it seems like basically everything about
Speaker 2:  the system is either metadata about the thing itself or
Speaker 2:  your viewing activity and that there's almost nothing else that
Speaker 2:  you're thinking about in that. Like I expected my age and zip code
Speaker 2:  and ethnicity and don don't know net worth, whatever. Like I, there are
Speaker 2:  million signals that we've been trained by the internet to believe are super
Speaker 2:  relevant and targeting to us. And at least from what the stuff I
Speaker 2:  was reading says, you don't care about most of that.
Speaker 12:  That's the beauty of it is that our goal is just to match you with something
Speaker 12:  you are going to love watching tonight. And the best input for what you
Speaker 12:  might love watching tonight or tomorrow or next week is what you've watched
Speaker 12:  or spent time with before. And those other signals might be
Speaker 12:  additive, but the thing that really matters is what have you demonstrated
Speaker 12:  that you're really interested in via your behavior? And that's sort of the
Speaker 12:  beauty of it. So yes, as you point out, you could think of titles as being
Speaker 12:  broken down into these constituent components, this metadata, it's, is
Speaker 12:  it a movie or a film? What's its originating country? How long is it?
Speaker 12:  What language is it available in genre? Perhaps some tagging about
Speaker 12:  attributes of the title. And those things all help to sort of round out
Speaker 12:  what a title is like, and then you match that against member
Speaker 12:  tastes and preferences. And again, take that sports docs,
Speaker 12:  drama, baking shows, if you watch any two of those things and
Speaker 12:  lots of people watch all three of those things, then it's a pretty good
Speaker 12:  chance that that third genre might be interesting to you. And so some point
Speaker 12:  in time you'll discover some genre that what wouldn't otherwise have been
Speaker 12:  your consciousness and try it out on Netflix. Now the thing that we
Speaker 12:  also do is inject some randomness into these recommendations
Speaker 12:  because again, to the point of tonight when you sit down on the couch, don
Speaker 12:  don't know what mood you're in necessarily or who's on the couch with you.
Speaker 12:  And it could be just something different tonight would be better for you.
Speaker 12:  And in that case we inject just a little bit of serendipity because we know
Speaker 12:  it's quite hard for us to get it right every time. And that also helps continue
Speaker 12:  to broaden what could be recommended to you.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, what is the right balance there? I think about like the great innovation
Speaker 2:  of TikTok was that it made it really low stakes for
Speaker 2:  TikTok to be wrong. Which because it's so easy to scroll, it's so easy to
Speaker 2:  just flip past something you don't like that TikTok can just show you stuff.
Speaker 2:  Everything in there is just pure randomness and you
Speaker 2:  don't really penalize it because it's so easy to scroll. I don't think you
Speaker 2:  have quite the same permission because by the time I'm like 20
Speaker 2:  minutes into a show and decide that I hate it, that's a much bigger commitment
Speaker 2:  than one and a half seconds on a TikTok thing. So I would think there's less
Speaker 2:  room to just sort of throw something at me just on the off chance I might
Speaker 2:  like it to see how I react. How do you think about that? Like you could make
Speaker 2:  the safe recommendation, you could just throw spaghetti at the wall and
Speaker 2:  see what sticks, but neither of those feels exactly right for Netflix.
Speaker 12:  We're definitely trying to not throw spaghetti at the wall. Okay, so we're,
Speaker 12:  we're trying to make recommendations, think about it as we're doing our
Speaker 12:  best to predict what might be interesting to you based on everything that's
Speaker 12:  known about your taste and preferences before you open Netflix tonight.
Speaker 12:  But if
Speaker 2:  You follow that all the way out, you just show me community every time, right?
Speaker 2:  Like,
Speaker 12:  And then we're trying to help you find, always have something great to watch.
Speaker 12:  So, so yes to your point like that, that you know, the, maybe you might
Speaker 12:  generalize that community challenge. And for me it might be like,
Speaker 12:  let's see, what could I watch every night? I mean, Seinfeld would be fun
Speaker 12:  for me most nights, right? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I'm not mad at community. No. It's just like, I'm just only gonna like, yeah.
Speaker 2:  Or it's like, I think about the, the one that happens to us all the time
Speaker 2:  is we watch one trashy and I don't use that as an insult
Speaker 2:  reality show. And then it's just infinite trashy reality
Speaker 2:  shows. And that actually makes a lot of sense. But at the same time there's
Speaker 2:  a finite amount of trashy reality TV that I actually wanna watch.
Speaker 2:  And so, but then to just show up and be like, oh, you like trashy reality
Speaker 2:  tv? Would you like the Great British Baking Show? That seems like a hard
Speaker 2:  leap to make, but when you eventually kind of have to make,
Speaker 12:  I think customers might say they would watch community every night,
Speaker 12:  but when we, as I say, add a little bit of serendipity,
Speaker 12:  what we find is customers are more satisfied when they have a little bit
Speaker 12:  more breadth in terms of what they watch. And I think if intuitively
Speaker 12:  when you run that by members and you talk to them and you ask qualitatively
Speaker 12:  like how does it feel when you, when you've been watching a greater breadth
Speaker 12:  of things versus more narrowly say only a couple of genres. I
Speaker 12:  think intuitively it makes sense. And I think qualitatively you would hear
Speaker 12:  that from from people as well if you just ask them. And so what we find
Speaker 12:  in the data as well is that when we diversify slightly beyond
Speaker 12:  your very narrow tried and true, David always loves
Speaker 12:  community types of recommendations, we find that you'll eventually
Speaker 12:  try one or multiple. And by the way, those will be a great fit. And
Speaker 12:  that's sort of the fun of it, is that especially when we're
Speaker 12:  introducing new stories to the world, like there's never been something
Speaker 12:  like squid game before. No one would say, oh, I was hoping I could watch
Speaker 12:  Squid Game tonight. But you find it and you get into it and you're lost.
Speaker 12:  Whether it's for a handful of hours tonight or more than a handful of hours
Speaker 12:  or over the next couple of weeks. That's kind of the magic of great storytelling.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So that, that's part of the squid game story that I think is really
Speaker 2:  interesting. And you're talking about this and you know it, it's starts in
Speaker 2:  Korea, it's doing super well. It's doing, it sounds like better
Speaker 2:  than expected even in the place where you expected it to do very well. What
Speaker 2:  happens next? Like is there a meeting where somebody's like, people love
Speaker 2:  this show, this might be huge. We have to like turn up the randomness
Speaker 2:  knob on the wall and start showing it to more people. Like what, how do you
Speaker 2:  take it from It's doing well among the people we thought it would do well
Speaker 2:  among to, let's show this to people
Speaker 2:  who have not necessarily shown us they would like something like this.
Speaker 2:  But the early signals say that they might,
Speaker 12:  The, the beauty of this approach to personalization is
Speaker 12:  no knobs, no buttons, no nothing needed to happen.
Speaker 2:  I'm convinced there's a knob. You can't convince me there's not a knob that's
Speaker 2:  just, it's the viewer's knob that you're just like show this to everybody,
Speaker 12:  It it, sometimes it appears that way, but that's, that's what's so sort
Speaker 12:  of magical about it. As I was saying, in the case of Squid Game, it's a
Speaker 12:  little difficult to know for sure how much the conversation outside of Netflix
Speaker 12:  drove what we saw, sort of some of the behavior. So sure, as soon as people
Speaker 12:  started to talk about Squid game, then we start to see as I say, some
Speaker 12:  signals of increased demand that we wouldn't otherwise be able to
Speaker 12:  observe. And so the the
Speaker 2:  Meaning like people searching for it more,
Speaker 12:  Exactly A great example that would be searching. So if people are,
Speaker 12:  most members at that point probably wouldn't, especially English primary
Speaker 12:  members of folks in the US for example, wouldn't necessarily have spent
Speaker 12:  lots of time watching original language, Korean content before they
Speaker 12:  were introduced to Squid Game. And so it would not necessarily have been
Speaker 12:  something that would've been high up there list of say stated preferences
Speaker 12:  or stated, I'm excited to watch a dark gritty
Speaker 12:  game show oriented thriller series from Korea. But once
Speaker 12:  people started talking about it and we started to see some again for example
Speaker 12:  that search activity that helps then reinforce for
Speaker 12:  the algorithms that it's time to maybe open up the audience a little
Speaker 12:  bit. And as I say, that's automatic in nature. There's no need
Speaker 12:  for for dials or buttons. And what we're doing all the time is
Speaker 12:  trying to tune more generally. So we would like to always be improving
Speaker 12:  the way we're making recommendations. So for example, we have a view that
Speaker 12:  maybe not necessarily every say half an hour you spend with Netflix
Speaker 12:  is worth the same to you as a customer. So we would like to be able to learn
Speaker 12:  a little bit more and be able to recommend say a half hour
Speaker 12:  episode of something that you would love tonight versus a half hour of something
Speaker 12:  you would be just okay with. So community for you might be a good example,
Speaker 12:  like you'd be satisfied with community tonight but you would love if you
Speaker 12:  found something new. And helping to tune finding that what you might love
Speaker 12:  and be able to make those recommendations with better precision is, is something
Speaker 12:  that we're always after.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. So is there really, there's no human interaction
Speaker 2:  in this process where like something like Squid Game starts?
Speaker 2:  'cause the, one of the funniest things about Squid Game to me is you could
Speaker 2:  look at it at some point early in the process and think, oh the
Speaker 2:  algorithm has gone completely haywire here. There's no way this
Speaker 2:  many people in this many places wanna watch this specific show
Speaker 2:  that we never in a million years would've put on this particular trajectory.
Speaker 2:  And on the other hand, it's obviously like a smashing success for the system
Speaker 2:  that it essentially, I'm assuming at some point basically told every person
Speaker 2:  on Planet Earth, you should probably watch Squid Game. Everybody else is
Speaker 2:  watching it and seems to like it. So is is there not a moment where you're,
Speaker 2:  it's like jumping up the graph and you you have to have a meeting where you're
Speaker 2:  like, what is happening here? Is this what's supposed to be going on?
Speaker 12:  This is the beauty of it. We, it wasn't even necessary for Squid Game. It
Speaker 12:  became big on its own. I think suits in the US is another good
Speaker 12:  example where you maybe wouldn't have necessarily expected in advance
Speaker 12:  how big suits could be at this point in time. And it's been
Speaker 12:  huge. And so that's kind of the beauty of it where there's no need to be
Speaker 12:  in the background pulling a separate lever. It's just again,
Speaker 12:  try to think about from how do we be the best possible matchmaker
Speaker 12:  between all the possible options you could have on Netflix and other services
Speaker 12:  you might subscribe to and make the best, most compelling
Speaker 12:  recommendations and the easiest, most hopefully fun To the extent browsing
Speaker 12:  and finding something to watch tonight can be fun way so that when you do
Speaker 12:  settle in on what you're gonna watch, you hit play and it's like ah,
Speaker 12:  this was perfect for me.
Speaker 2:  I would assume though that at some point kind of popularity begets
Speaker 2:  popularity that like the bigger something gets the more comfortable the
Speaker 2:  system gets recommending it more widely to people, maybe even
Speaker 2:  further out of sort of the traditional strike zone of a show like that.
Speaker 12:  Well I think again take, we can just focus on Squid game there as an example
Speaker 12:  where yes of if you're thinking about that randomness
Speaker 12:  or serendipity, imagine you're a member who's again never watched
Speaker 12:  any Korean language content before. We can more
Speaker 12:  confidently make that recommendation to you the more popular something
Speaker 12:  is, especially among folks who are also members of Netflix
Speaker 12:  who watch similar things to you. So yes, I'd say that's fair.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And is there, is there any upside to having kind of
Speaker 2:  human or editorial or or curatorial input here? I mean I
Speaker 2:  think about like we, we talk to a lot of the folks at music services. We
Speaker 2:  talk a lot about you have this giant corpus of stuff, we can do some really
Speaker 2:  interesting personalization but also maybe what you want to know is what
Speaker 2:  a person you think is smart likes or we can
Speaker 2:  recommend don don't know, like Halloween is a good example, right? It was
Speaker 2:  just Halloween. Let's put together a thing that is like some of our favorite
Speaker 2:  old school Halloween movies. People love that kind of stuff. And if you do
Speaker 2:  that at Netflix, you do it less obviously than some others.
Speaker 2:  Is that kind of just not something you think is, is necessary at your scale?
Speaker 12:  We, we do from time to time do things like that where we're offering
Speaker 12:  collections that are representative of a moment in time. So
Speaker 12:  Halloween would be, you know, that would be a very good example or other
Speaker 12:  collections seasonally. So those kinds of collections do exist on Netflix
Speaker 12:  and you can either seek them out yourself or from time to time you might
Speaker 12:  find them, those kinds of recommendations promoted either on TV or on other
Speaker 12:  platforms. You should think of those collections as still
Speaker 12:  personalized in nature. So I, imagine you've had say a hundred candidates
Speaker 12:  for a, some kind of a seasonal collection. We would still want to present
Speaker 12:  titles to you in a personalized way. So whether that's what order they would
Speaker 12:  be presented in or how they're positioned to you. As I was mentioning earlier,
Speaker 12:  we've got a incredible creative production team that's thinking about what
Speaker 12:  are all the possible ways you could represent a title, whether that's with
Speaker 12:  art or the synopsis or video promotional assets. And
Speaker 12:  we would still wanna do that in a way that positions any of those particular
Speaker 12:  titles within a say more curated seasonal set in a way that would
Speaker 12:  really hopefully resonate with you individually.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, one of my favorite things to do on Netflix is scroll around and
Speaker 2:  try to guess why the system picked that particular
Speaker 2:  poster to show me for any given thing. 'cause I know there's a bunch of options,
Speaker 2:  it shows them in lots of different ways. And I saw one that was just like,
Speaker 2:  I forget what movie it was, but it was a movie in which Tom Cruise was like
Speaker 2:  the fourth most important character in the movie, but the poster I saw was
Speaker 2:  just Tom Cruise. And I was like, you know what? Like you're not wrong Netflix,
Speaker 2:  but I wonder what it says about me as a person that it was like, you know
Speaker 2:  what, David wants to watch this movie as Tom Cruise.
Speaker 12:  You might be a huge Tom Cruise fan. You might have just revealed that. Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's not wrong to be clear, it's not wrong at all, but it's, it was,
Speaker 2:  yeah, it's just a very funny thing. And I think actually to that point, one
Speaker 2:  of the things that I think has always been tricky about personalization over
Speaker 2:  the years is pairing that with transparency. Like
Speaker 2:  I think there's, there's a, an interesting thing that we found, and this
Speaker 2:  is especially true I think on social media where we, we have these ranked
Speaker 2:  feeds and people are like, why am I being shown this thing
Speaker 2:  this way in this order? And there's, there's something about kind of
Speaker 2:  understanding the order that is being presented to you that actually is really
Speaker 2:  comforting and makes people feel better. And to some extent on Netflix, like
Speaker 2:  you've done a bunch of work, it seems like making even just like the rows
Speaker 2:  are fairly self-explanatory. Like here's what's trending, here's what's this
Speaker 2:  category. But do you think about trying to sort of telegraph the reasons
Speaker 2:  behind what you're showing people as you go? I
Speaker 12:  Love this question because I think we've got opportunity to do better here.
Speaker 12:  So we would call all the ways that we would position a recommendation or
Speaker 12:  set of recommendations to you evidence for why something might be
Speaker 12:  compelling to you. Right? And so explaining that evidence,
Speaker 12:  there's good thinking behind that that is helpful for folks. So
Speaker 12:  why is something presented to me, So I think we've made some good progress
Speaker 12:  there on broadening the candidate set of reasons why something could
Speaker 12:  potentially be a good fit for you. So I've hit on a few of those whether
Speaker 12:  it's the art being tailored to you or the synopsis
Speaker 12:  or other individual pieces of evidence, for example the cast or other
Speaker 12:  folks involved in bringing that title to life and how that might resonate
Speaker 12:  with you. But I think we can do even more, which is to say make the connection
Speaker 12:  between here's really specifically why we think this might be a good fit
Speaker 12:  based on whatever the meaningful to you reason might be. Whether it's
Speaker 12:  for example in the Tom Cruise case, you've binged everything we have on
Speaker 12:  Tom Cruise and this is why we think this would be awesome for you. Or it
Speaker 12:  looks like you're ready to break out of your community Rutt here's what
Speaker 12:  folks love, here's to cruise just broken, broken, here's Tom Cruise. Exactly.
Speaker 12:  And when you wanna break outta your community rut, Tom Cruise is the
Speaker 2:  Solve that's So I tell people that all the time. That makes sense and I think
Speaker 2:  that it's another really interesting UI question over time.
Speaker 2:  One of the things I love talking to people about on Netflix is the thumbs
Speaker 2:  up, thumbs down system. don don't know if this is true. I haven't quizzed
Speaker 2:  random strangers on this in a while, but for a long time I think the thing
Speaker 2:  where it would say, you know, it would have the green thumbs up and it would
Speaker 2:  be like 89% match, I think most people would read that
Speaker 2:  as a sort of rotten tomato score that's like most people like this thing.
Speaker 2:  That's not what it is, is my understanding. It is something closer to like
Speaker 2:  the likelihood that you're gonna like this thing, but it's just a really
Speaker 2:  fascinating thing of trying to telegraph. You have all this information about
Speaker 2:  what I'm likely to like and why and to some
Speaker 2:  extent all of that is useful for me to see as I'm browsing
Speaker 2:  because by the time I've been doing this for a while, I have a fair amount
Speaker 2:  of faith in Netflix's ability to show me something I'm gonna like. But the
Speaker 2:  more you can tell me about it, the faster you can help me make those decisions.
Speaker 2:  But A, you don't wanna overwhelm people I wouldn't think. And B,
Speaker 2:  it just gets confusing at some point. There's just only so much you can show
Speaker 2:  me. Especially if it's like you liked Beckham and the Crown, we think you'll
Speaker 2:  love the great British speaking show. People are like, what the hell are
Speaker 2:  you talking about? And so, so like I wonder even just from a UI perspective
Speaker 2:  how you think about putting that stuff in front of people. Well
Speaker 12:  You're absolutely right that it's, you've gotta make hard trade offs and
Speaker 12:  that's, that's a hard design challenge when you're constrained
Speaker 12:  in the UI. And so for the many tens of
Speaker 12:  possible reasons why a title could be a great fit for you, if you think
Speaker 12:  about this in the weeds a little bit on how someone's actually experiencing
Speaker 12:  Netflix when you're browsing, you've got that first glimpse of a title
Speaker 12:  and you're somewhat more restricted in what can be shown to you there. We
Speaker 12:  want to try to present the evidence that is most compelling
Speaker 12:  individually for you. So imagine again, there's tens of possible options
Speaker 12:  say we'd wanna hopefully think about how we might rank those
Speaker 12:  and then present the ones that are most compelling initially, which would
Speaker 12:  then generate a little bit more interest from you. And then if you're one
Speaker 12:  level deeper in that discovery journey revealed a little bit
Speaker 12:  more, that would then be helpful. So as you're for example watching a trailer,
Speaker 12:  you might learn a little bit more about the title just by watching the trailer,
Speaker 12:  but there may be also additional longer form synopsis evidence or a
Speaker 12:  little bit more on the cast or a little bit more on why this title is similar
Speaker 12:  to others you've watched and why that might be a compelling match. So it's
Speaker 12:  for sure a hard challenge. It tends to be great dividends for members
Speaker 12:  to know a little bit more 'cause they're excited to know about well why
Speaker 12:  would this be a good fit for me? And the way it manifests for us is
Speaker 12:  hopefully we observe then better matches between our recommendations
Speaker 12:  of what ultimately gets played and then ultimately higher member satisfaction.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. So again with, not to keep coming back to Squid Game, but with
Speaker 2:  something like Squid Game, how do you tell that story to people? Do you eventually
Speaker 2:  just turn it around and it's like just everybody's watching this like shut
Speaker 2:  up hit play. Everybody's watching this show
Speaker 12:  On that one. It's a, again, it's a good example of the
Speaker 12:  robot in the art became particularly compelling and sure visually
Speaker 12:  interesting. I think there's just something about that that was intriguing
Speaker 12:  to folks And then for sure popularity plays a role there. So as something
Speaker 12:  gets bigger and bigger and it's for example high up the top 10 list
Speaker 12:  also your friends are talking about it, that social
Speaker 12:  proof is often super compelling. And again, that's happening. You know,
Speaker 12:  we don't wanna take too much credit in Netflix that's happening outside
Speaker 12:  with your friends when you're on a run on a walk on social media, you're
Speaker 12:  hearing about things and so that's happening just as much if not more off
Speaker 12:  Netflix and the biggest versions of success when something is really blowing
Speaker 12:  up.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Where do you see signals of that? I mean you mentioned searches increasing
Speaker 2:  but also this elusive sort of sense of buzz is a very hard thing to
Speaker 2:  quantify, but if you can becomes really useful. So like how, how
Speaker 2:  do you, especially in that sort of growth moment before a show
Speaker 2:  like Squid Game or Wednesday or whatever kind of takes over the world, what
Speaker 2:  do you look at as those moments that like somebody is telling me on
Speaker 2:  a run that I should go watch this show? Like you, you want to capture that
Speaker 2:  and I, and the best case scenario would be when I go sit down on my couch
Speaker 2:  there it is the thing that my friend just recommended to me, right? How do
Speaker 2:  you, how do you bridge those two things?
Speaker 12:  You should think of those, those things as like super indirect, right? And
Speaker 12:  So I mentioned a couple of ways that would manifest the, the first before
Speaker 12:  something launches that would be you come to Netflix and maybe in the case
Speaker 12:  before Squid Game launches you say, oh I heard, I heard someone told me
Speaker 12:  about this and you search for it and then you get to watch the trailer in
Speaker 12:  advance and you find out it's not available yet you, you click remind me
Speaker 12:  that same would be true on something like the Netflix Cup next week where
Speaker 12:  not available yet. You can learn a little bit if you open the app and you
Speaker 12:  hit remind me. So that's one indirect way. And then the other
Speaker 12:  one would be search. And that tends to be great at
Speaker 12:  indicating what people are excited about. And the great thing
Speaker 12:  about the search results experience is it's also personalized and will
Speaker 12:  continue to improve over time as behavior indicates what
Speaker 12:  are the right responses to particular queries. So at the outside,
Speaker 12:  for example, when someone first searches for Squid Game, maybe the results
Speaker 12:  would not have Squid Game in precisely the first results position. But over
Speaker 12:  time we would learn as people are playing Squid game after they type
Speaker 12:  ssq and then immediately Squid game gets played at very high rates, then
Speaker 12:  we would change those, the ordering of those
Speaker 12:  recommendations and search results and hopefully match you very quickly
Speaker 12:  with the thing that you actually have intent for.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. One of the smartest things I think Netflix has always done
Speaker 2:  is that when you search for something that isn't on Netflix, it tries to
Speaker 2:  recommend you. Things like that thing which is just the, the most like
Speaker 2:  subtle devious stroke of genius, it's great. It's like we don't have this
Speaker 2:  movie, don't worry about that. Watch these other movies. And I suspect that
Speaker 2:  works. It's worked for me many times where it's like it picks something
Speaker 2:  spiritually close enough that I'm like, oh okay, I'll, I've been meaning
Speaker 2:  to watch that anyway. I had not really thought of search results as a discovery
Speaker 2:  engine, but it kind of is one
Speaker 12:  Very meaningful discovery source of discovery and you're right that it it,
Speaker 12:  it can be frustrating if you're searching for that thing that is either
Speaker 12:  not available yet or isn't available on Netflix and in your country and
Speaker 12:  we still really want to help you have an incredible
Speaker 12:  night tonight with Netflix and so hopefully we've got something if not exactly
Speaker 12:  that thing that would be a good fit.
Speaker 2:  What do you call the thing at the top, the super big thing? Is it like the
Speaker 2:  hero? Is it the marquee? What do you call it? We
Speaker 12:  Call that internally the billboard. The billboard.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Let's talk about the billboard. The theory I hear about the billboard
Speaker 2:  most often is that a, it is an unbelievably powerful piece of
Speaker 2:  streaming real estate. That whatever you put there a lot of people are going
Speaker 2:  to interact with in some way, shape or form. And that B, that
Speaker 2:  is where Netflix brute forces things to be popular by force feeding it to
Speaker 2:  a hundred million people whenever it feels like it, just because it wants
Speaker 2:  to make a show popular. I have questions about both parts of that, but start
Speaker 2:  with the beginning is that as powerful a piece of screen real
Speaker 2:  estate as it seems like it might be that whatever you put there is going
Speaker 2:  to be more noticed by people
Speaker 12:  Certainly meaningful. But if you think about how members are spending time
Speaker 12:  with Netflix, they're coming in with something in mind and going to
Speaker 12:  search or they have a category in mind, whether it's a film or a genre
Speaker 12:  or this is the kind of mood I'm in tonight. So it's one of many
Speaker 12:  ways that folks do find what they wanna watch it. I won't disagree. It's
Speaker 12:  important, it's the first thing you see after you select your profile. Is
Speaker 12:  it the most important. There's lots of ways folks are expressing what they're
Speaker 12:  interested in to watch watching tonight.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And do you think this is a total aside, I'm gonna get to my second
Speaker 2:  question in a second, but I think that the way you just described that is
Speaker 2:  really interesting 'cause it sort of assumes people come in with like one
Speaker 2:  data point about what they're looking for, which sort of makes sense. But
Speaker 2:  also III can imagine there's a set of people out there who just open Netflix.
Speaker 2:  Like I think this is the unique thing about Netflix at this point is that
Speaker 2:  you're big enough to essentially just be the thing and I'm just gonna open
Speaker 2:  it and see what happens. Does that behavior exist and do you have to treat
Speaker 2:  those people differently who sincerely have no idea what they want, they
Speaker 2:  just wanna watch something
Speaker 12:  That would be nirvana for us where you're, you're, you're so confident that
Speaker 12:  we're gonna have both options and make great recommendations
Speaker 12:  among those options that when you wanna relax
Speaker 12:  and you're ready to watch or play something that you
Speaker 12:  think of us first. And so you sit down on the couch and
Speaker 12:  you just hit the Netflix button on your remote because you're so confident
Speaker 12:  you're gonna find something great on Netflix, you are
Speaker 12:  completely right that there's this spectrum where some nights
Speaker 12:  you know exactly what you're excited about. So when you're
Speaker 12:  right in the middle of the newest season of, for
Speaker 12:  example now for me right now it's the crown where I'm, I'm watching it on
Speaker 12:  our internal employee preview and I'm like, I am so excited tonight
Speaker 12:  to sit down on the couch and and watch, watch the next episode. So that's
Speaker 12:  gonna be more likely that I'm gonna continue watching something as opposed
Speaker 12:  to be looking for something new. And then there's lots of nights where
Speaker 12:  folks sit down and they have no idea and they just want
Speaker 12:  to find something great and they're willing to sit down and and go on a
Speaker 12:  discovery journey. And that's the fun, quite challenging problem we have
Speaker 12:  is how do we make that the right amount fun, serendipitous
Speaker 12:  but also efficient so that it doesn't feel like I'm slogging through it.
Speaker 12:  So we, we want to go from inexperience that can at times feel
Speaker 12:  overwhelming to an experience that feels most of the time incredibly
Speaker 12:  delightful so that when you do finally land on the thing that's a perfect
Speaker 12:  fit for you, you look back on that discovery journey and it felt great.
Speaker 2:  Is that a thing you can discern in real time that like if
Speaker 2:  I open up the app and I scroll past continue watching
Speaker 2:  and I'm now five rows deep, you can suddenly like assume that I'm
Speaker 2:  on a more open-ended discovery experience and show me different stuff. Like
Speaker 2:  is that, can you be that sort of responsive to what people are doing?
Speaker 2:  Even like button click to button click
Speaker 12:  We're humble and we, we know we can always do better on that front but
Speaker 12:  I think you make a good, you know, your hunch there is probably a good one
Speaker 12:  where if you're completely in in the mode for the thing that you were
Speaker 12:  watching last night and you're ready to watch the next episode, then it's
Speaker 12:  a pretty good chance you might go straight to it. But if you skip over it
Speaker 12:  and you start to demonstrate interest more broadly than that, a job
Speaker 12:  we want to do much better is be able to pick up on what
Speaker 12:  you might be in the mood for tonight more quickly and adapt our
Speaker 12:  recommendations accordingly right in the moment so that like if
Speaker 12:  you're, seems like oh tonight might be a movie night for David
Speaker 12:  and based on his browsing right now it might be a Tom Cruise movie night.
Speaker 12:  We want to accordingly adjust and make it easy for you to then
Speaker 12:  satisfy that interest. And you might not have known that before you, before
Speaker 12:  you showed up, but it might have as you sort of browsing is like, oh this
Speaker 12:  is, this is a Tom Cruise movie night for me,
Speaker 2:  I really like the idea that the longer I spend browsing Netflix, like the
Speaker 2:  weirder the recommendations would start to get that it's eventually just
Speaker 2:  like don don't know just, just watch this. You, you clearly don't know what
Speaker 2:  you want, we don't know what you want. Like here's some stuff, let's see
Speaker 2:  what happens. I kinda enjoy that.
Speaker 12:  The magic would be the longer that you spend, the better that the, that
Speaker 12:  final recommendation would be because we would then have known so much more
Speaker 12:  about the things you could have been interested in and might not have been
Speaker 12:  interested in. So one thing that's a little more challenging is extracting
Speaker 12:  say negative feedback from you. So it would be nice for us to know with
Speaker 12:  a little bit more precision when you skip over something, whether you spend
Speaker 12:  a little bit of time with a trailer and you say, oh that's not for me
Speaker 12:  tonight. Sometimes that's a little more challenging for us to know precisely
Speaker 12:  in the moment and that's an area where we wanna spend a little more time.
Speaker 12:  That's
Speaker 2:  Interesting the question of like is this something that's not interesting
Speaker 2:  to me or just not what I wanna watch tonight but like show this to me
Speaker 2:  again in a few days kind of thing?
Speaker 12:  Exactly. What a fun hard problem where it's like it's very difficult to
Speaker 12:  necessarily parse, I never want to see this again. So a thumbs down means
Speaker 12:  please never show this thing to me again or I'm just not in the mood for
Speaker 12:  it tonight. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. The second question is, I think the overarching
Speaker 2:  theory about the billboard is that that is where Netflix like
Speaker 2:  flexes, its originals and says we spend a bunch of money on this
Speaker 2:  show, you're gonna watch it so we're gonna show it to you every time you
Speaker 2:  open the app whether you want to or not. Here it is, watch it. We
Speaker 2:  demand is that how It works?
Speaker 12:  Follows the same approach that we've been talking about for, for the last
Speaker 12:  40 minutes or so personalized to you. We want to, our, our goals
Speaker 12:  every time you open the app are to match you with something compelling and
Speaker 12:  whether that's a Netflix original or not, something we license
Speaker 12:  from a studio supplier doesn't matter to us at all. We want you
Speaker 12:  to be incredibly satisfied. I
Speaker 2:  Really want to believe you. Like I, I really earnestly wanna believe you
Speaker 2:  but I can also see a bunch of really good reasons it would be the other way,
Speaker 2:  right? Like it makes sense for Netflix as of service
Speaker 2:  to prioritize the stuff that it owns for lots of reasons that it's not gonna
Speaker 2:  leave the service anytime soon. You have control over the ip, you can do
Speaker 2:  all kinds of stuff with more popular shows that you make than something that
Speaker 2:  you've licensed from somebody else. Also there are costs associated with
Speaker 2:  these things and you wanna recoup the costs and you made them because you
Speaker 2:  think people are gonna like them. So you wanna put them in front of people.
Speaker 2:  So I guess why not put some of that in there? Like
Speaker 2:  are the, is there an internal balance that you have to strike in how to get
Speaker 2:  that stuff right even if you're not showing it to people?
Speaker 12:  If you again come back to our business model, the nice thing is we have
Speaker 12:  really good alignment here. So with the subscription business model, you've
Speaker 12:  got a choice every month and the trade is your hard earned money
Speaker 12:  for incredible entertainment every month. And so our, our end of the bargain
Speaker 12:  is match you up with hopefully something great among an increasingly
Speaker 12:  broad catalog. And so if we have a choice between something that's
Speaker 12:  less good for you but is a Netflix original or something that is better
Speaker 12:  for you and not a Netflix original, we're gonna take that better for you
Speaker 12:  every single time because our goal is for you to be
Speaker 12:  incredibly satisfied and to be entertained. And so at any given night,
Speaker 12:  if that's less likely to be an Netflix original based on what you like to
Speaker 12:  watch or what you're in the mood for tonight, that's okay with us.
Speaker 2:  So do you think the people who feel like they're being sort of, you know,
Speaker 2:  bludgeoned over the head with squid game or whatever else, is that mostly
Speaker 2:  due to like having a hard time reading those negative signals where it's
Speaker 2:  like okay you skipped past this, is that because you hate it and never wanna
Speaker 2:  see it again? Or just because it's not what you're in the mood for right
Speaker 2:  now? Like as it as you get better at understanding what people are doing,
Speaker 2:  sort of click to click, do you think people will feel less and less of that
Speaker 2:  sense of like this thing is here every time I open the app even though I
Speaker 2:  don't wanna watch it?
Speaker 12:  Some of that could be popularity oriented. Okay as you mentioned earlier.
Speaker 12:  So if something is quite popular and it's not for you then you might
Speaker 12:  see that in something like the top 10 list, which is quite literally what
Speaker 12:  are the series and films in your country that are top 10? That one
Speaker 2:  I think is fairly understandable. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  So those sorts of popularity signals can be hard to get around. I think
Speaker 12:  as I mentioned earlier, I think we have more to do on incorporating both
Speaker 12:  more major and then that more modest negative feedback like please don't
Speaker 12:  recommend this to me anymore. And So I think think there's more we can do
Speaker 12:  there for sure
Speaker 2:  All right. I have two more questions for you. One question people ask a lot
Speaker 2:  about kind of anything that is algorithmically curated like this is
Speaker 2:  how do I exert some control over it, right? I think like
Speaker 2:  I, I want to teach Netflix what I like and don't like and I think,
Speaker 2:  I'm assuming the first thing you're gonna say is like watch stuff you like,
Speaker 2:  which fair enough. But what else do you look at as sort of strong
Speaker 2:  like actual user action signals that
Speaker 2:  can push Netflix in the direction of stuff that they like?
Speaker 12:  Let us know when you really love something and the best way you can do that
Speaker 12:  is when you really love it, give it two thumbs up when you love it,
Speaker 12:  give it a thumbs up and if you didn't like it, that's okay. Let us know.
Speaker 12:  Give it a thumbs down. So that's one very concrete way I
Speaker 2:  Would think the thumbs down is a very strong signal
Speaker 12:  That is generally a strong signal, but that's okay. Yeah, we, we, we would,
Speaker 12:  like I said, as I said we'd like to hear it because that then helps us know
Speaker 12:  what resonated versus what didn't. So that's probably the best place to
Speaker 12:  do it. And then generally speaking, we don't want to force
Speaker 12:  effort on members. We want to make it effortless for you to both find
Speaker 12:  something to watch and then enjoy watching it. So that's have an incredible
Speaker 12:  discovery experience, have an playback experience that never
Speaker 12:  rebuffs and always feels wonderful and makes it easy for you to
Speaker 12:  turn on subs for a night that you want subs on and
Speaker 12:  have, you know, hopefully magically know that for this particular
Speaker 12:  language and content type combination you would never want subs. So, so
Speaker 12:  we wouldn't automatically do that but that's it. Literally just watch as
Speaker 12:  you, as you guessed, watch things that you like and then give us the feedback
Speaker 12:  and, and then the best way you can do that is thumbs up, thumbs down or
Speaker 12:  double thumbs up.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Why not give people tons more tools to
Speaker 2:  show you what they do and don't like. I know there's the don don't know if
Speaker 2:  you still do it, I haven't signed up for Netflix in a long time, but the
Speaker 2:  thing where you would sort of solve the cold start problem by saying just
Speaker 2:  like rate a few things that here, here are some things, do you like these
Speaker 2:  or not? And that's a decent way of the Cold Start problem. But I know there
Speaker 2:  are a lot of tools where you can like make lists and some people have sort
Speaker 2:  of stolen the Tinder mechanic of like right and left swiping stuff you like
Speaker 2:  and don't like. Why not give people access to sort of all that
Speaker 2:  kind of stuff that is just like, tell us everything you want to tell us about
Speaker 2:  what you like so that we can tune it for you. Do
Speaker 12:  We still do that taste tuning when you first sign up for Netflix? Okay,
Speaker 12:  so you tell us a little bit about a handful of series or films that you
Speaker 12:  like so that we can do a little bit better with that cold start problem
Speaker 12:  and get you started with good recommendations. I think it's a fair question
Speaker 12:  could from time to time you be asked to maybe retune
Speaker 12:  every now and then and members might have an interest in that. So that's
Speaker 12:  there's, we've tried things like that in the past. We don't have anything
Speaker 12:  running right now or that does exactly that, but you could imagine for example,
Speaker 12:  if you've got a, a list of titles you watched and you want to provide
Speaker 12:  ratings on those titles, then that might be a way for us to improve your
Speaker 12:  recommendations even more so we can get that explicit feedback. So you've,
Speaker 12:  you've got a queue of 10 things you've finished over the last handful of
Speaker 12:  months, why, why wouldn't we ask you a little bit more directly? Give us
Speaker 12:  a thumbs up, thumbs down, et cetera. So possible, you know, nothing on the
Speaker 12:  horizon there precisely, but I like the idea.
Speaker 2:  Okay, fair enough. And then the last thing I'm curious about is how
Speaker 2:  specifically it is useful to personalize, like we talk about personalization,
Speaker 2:  but there's a whole spectrum of things that that means. So like when you
Speaker 2:  think about Netflix personalization, is that to me David,
Speaker 2:  is that to my house? Is that to people like me? Is that to
Speaker 2:  don? Don't know. Are there a million people in the cohort that I'm a part
Speaker 2:  of? Like how specific is it even sort of useful and
Speaker 2:  valuable to go as you're thinking about this stuff?
Speaker 12:  Incredibly individual. Okay, so it's, it's to your profile. So if you've
Speaker 12:  got multiple profiles set up on your Netflix account, each of those profiles
Speaker 12:  is, has an individually tailored set of recommendations.
Speaker 2:  And if you're not doing things like demographics and all that stuff, they
Speaker 2:  should have essentially nothing to do with each other, right?
Speaker 12:  All we know about each of those profiles is literally the pattern of
Speaker 12:  of watching or gameplay. Okay. And that's, that is the, the only input and
Speaker 12:  the the purest input that we can take to then make the next great
Speaker 12:  hopefully recommendation for you.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. So yeah, I mean, and that winds me all the way back to like
Speaker 2:  how much data is it useful to have part of this? 'cause I think don don't
Speaker 2:  know, presumably there are things you could know about me as a person that
Speaker 2:  might make some of it better. But then I guess at the scale you're working
Speaker 2:  at like that, that eventually becomes untenable to try and
Speaker 2:  like individually identify every single person based on like their eye color
Speaker 2:  And, what that might mean. They'd like,
Speaker 12:  Quite honestly we've, we've got more than we can handle more ideas than
Speaker 12:  we can handle with just how members are using Netflix today. So just by
Speaker 12:  revealing their tastes and preferences based on among the recommendations
Speaker 12:  we show, what do you try, what do you not finish, what do
Speaker 12:  you finish all the way to completion? What do you finish quickly, as I was
Speaker 12:  mentioning earlier, if there are ways for us to have a little bit better
Speaker 12:  sense for what you loved versus you just liked. So one way you could tell
Speaker 12:  us that would be two thumbs up versus one thumb up and doing that more frequently
Speaker 12:  for example. But if there might be other ways where we could extract a little
Speaker 12:  more signal with respect to time, even better spent and time, you're super
Speaker 12:  thrilled to have spent with Netflix that those would be great ways for us
Speaker 12:  to continue to enrich the way we improve our recommendations for you.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. All, right, this is my actual last question. I swear I've said
Speaker 2:  this three times now. This is my actual last question. Tell me about thumbs
Speaker 2:  versus stars. I find this totally fascinating and I think you've been at
Speaker 2:  Netflix long enough to have seen both sides. So, I will just lay on my
Speaker 2:  cards on the table. I think five star scales are the stupidest thing on the
Speaker 2:  internet and I think they, they essentially mean nothing. But I'm curious
Speaker 2:  about how you think about like the one thumb, two thumb thumbs down
Speaker 2:  thing versus a five star recommendation and why the thumbs works better.
Speaker 12:  Thumbs is a simple way for you to provide
Speaker 12:  feedback on whether you like something or didn't like something. The the
Speaker 12:  trick on stars, and it sounds like you're not in the Stars camp So I don't
Speaker 12:  have to persuade you. The trick on stars is sometimes you might rate
Speaker 12:  something very highly on the stars because that's how something you think
Speaker 12:  something ought to be perceived. So it's critically acclaimed and, and so
Speaker 12:  you feel like it deserves many stars as opposed to how did you actually
Speaker 12:  feel about it? And that's what's more meaningful to improve your
Speaker 12:  recommendations is the reflection of how you actually felt about something
Speaker 12:  and whether it was good for you. And so thumbs as the benefit of
Speaker 12:  one being simpler and two, hopefully being a better reflection of
Speaker 12:  what you actually love or didn't love about what you're watching on Netflix.
Speaker 12:  That's
Speaker 2:  Interesting. That's actually a more like emotional answer than I was expecting.
Speaker 2:  'cause I think to me the problem is always that if I like something, do I
Speaker 2:  give it five stars or four stars or three stars? Literally no one knows
Speaker 2:  and everybody has different ideas. So you end up with a totally meaningless
Speaker 2:  scale. So, I've always liked the thumbs up, thumbs down because did I like
Speaker 2:  this or not? Is a much easier question to answer I think.
Speaker 2:  But you're describing something really different where it's like I, we want
Speaker 2:  you to tell us how you feel not is this good? And that's actually
Speaker 2:  like a really different thing.
Speaker 12:  Is it good for you? I mean that's the response that we would like. And so
Speaker 12:  that's the benefit of the simple two thumbs up, one thumb up and one thumb
Speaker 12:  down is that it's pretty clear to most people. What does, what does that
Speaker 12:  mean to you?
Speaker 2:  I love it. All, right? I promise. That was my last question. So I will let
Speaker 2:  you go, but thank you for doing this. This was really fun. I really appreciate
Speaker 12:  It. Very fun David, great to spend the time with you and I look forward
Speaker 12:  to catching up again soon.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna get to the hotline.
Speaker 2:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  We're back. Let's take a question from The Vergecast hotline. As a reminder,
Speaker 2:  you can always email Vergecast at The Verge dot com or call 8
Speaker 2:  6 6 Verge one one to reach us. We try and answer at least one question on
Speaker 2:  the show every Wednesday. Thank you as always. To everybody who calls and
Speaker 2:  emails, it's so fun. Oh, and speaking of which, we're actually planning to
Speaker 2:  do an all hotline episode next week all about buying
Speaker 2:  advice specifically. So if you're trying to figure out what to buy this holiday
Speaker 2:  season or you're deciding between two things, or you want to talk to me about
Speaker 2:  monitors, get all your questions in now we're gonna take as many as we can
Speaker 2:  next week this week though, no buying advice. Instead we have a
Speaker 2:  super fun, super wonky question that we got in The Vergecast email and I
Speaker 2:  have the world's two foremost experts here with me to answer it. Helen Havlak
Speaker 2:  is the verges publisher and Neli Patel is our editor in chief. Between them,
Speaker 2:  they run everything. Helen Havlak, Welcome To, The Vergecast.
Speaker 14:  Thank you. Excited to be
Speaker 2:  Here. Neli Patel is here too. Hi Neli. Hey, how's it going?
Speaker 2:  You know, I dial up my enthusiasm based on how excited I am for the guest.
Speaker 2:  Okay, this question is kind of long, so bear with me. But then we have a
Speaker 2:  bunch of stuff to dive into here. The question comes from Anthony, and here's
Speaker 2:  what it says. I feel like the effects music streaming has had on income for
Speaker 2:  artists is fairly well-defined or at least better known, but as an avid reader
Speaker 2:  of various journalists and publications such as yourselves. I have similar
Speaker 2:  questions about journalism on the internet, maybe supporting journalism isn't
Speaker 2:  talked about as much because of the overwhelming rise in news consumption
Speaker 2:  on social media platforms. But for those of us who try to consume news from
Speaker 2:  dedicated aggregators like Apple News, Flipboard, et cetera, I find myself
Speaker 2:  asking what do those platforms do for journalist readership and pay from
Speaker 2:  a user perspective, it's a good balance between the convenience of a single
Speaker 2:  source for all my news and interests, but also intentional about seeking
Speaker 2:  news and not just Instagram filtering my news based on my likes. For example,
Speaker 2:  is there a significant difference in how well a Verge article does when I
Speaker 2:  read it from Flipboard? Instead of going to the site directly, some of these
Speaker 2:  aggregators filter out ads. So that has to have an effect on the money The
Speaker 2:  Verge makes, right? I also wonder if there's a cost benefit of having articles
Speaker 2:  available on those aggregators because it expands readership again in an
Speaker 2:  age where fewer people are seeking out news and just passively consuming
Speaker 2:  it on social media. So the question if I'm gonna boil this all the way down,
Speaker 2:  is basically how does a website like The Verge
Speaker 2:  think about where you read our stuff, And, what that means to
Speaker 2:  us as a publication? Is that a fair summary of of all of that, would
Speaker 2:  you say? Yeah, I think
Speaker 14:  So. And maybe also, how does our publication make money
Speaker 14:  and support the work we make
Speaker 2:  True? Two good questions. Okay. So if I understand this correctly, you two
Speaker 2:  have thought about this and talked about this every day forever for all of
Speaker 2:  your adult lives. Helen, why don't you start at this from a sort of business
Speaker 2:  perspective, obviously this is the thing we think about a lot where our stuff
Speaker 2:  is who we work with, how we distribute things versus people coming to the
Speaker 2:  site. Is there a good sort of simple rubric of how you think
Speaker 2:  about all of that?
Speaker 14:  Yeah, absolutely. I think it helps to start with the basic of how does The
Speaker 14:  Verge make money? The Verge is a free website, so the single most important
Speaker 14:  way we make money today is advertising. We also make money from other
Speaker 14:  things like affiliate commerce on our excellent product reviews. If
Speaker 14:  people subscribe to our paid newsletters like Command Line and Hotpod. If
Speaker 14:  people become loyal subscribers to things like this, our podcasts, but a
Speaker 14:  bit of nuance on that ads, business ads are worth the most if you serve
Speaker 14:  them inside your own ad technology. We serve many of our ads inside
Speaker 14:  Vox media's ad technology concert. And I'll also say a loyal reader
Speaker 14:  who comes back many times is worth a lot more than someone
Speaker 14:  who just comes by once via search. For example, to
Speaker 14:  use the music metaphor from this question, someone who consistently
Speaker 14:  buys your entire album and then lines up for tickets to
Speaker 14:  your concert and buys your merch, that person is worth a lot more money
Speaker 14:  to you than someone who listens to your hit single on the radio or a
Speaker 14:  Spotify playlist. It's kind of the same for a news publisher
Speaker 14:  where the single most valuable thing to a news publisher is a
Speaker 14:  loyal reader who comes back over and over again no matter what kind
Speaker 14:  of business you run. Is it an advertising business, a subscription business?
Speaker 14:  So the kind of like guiding north star of this
Speaker 14:  conversation is, okay, to what extent do platforms help us
Speaker 14:  build that loyal readership?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, Neli, this is something you and I talk a lot about, right? Like in
Speaker 2:  just sort of day-to-day coverage. This question of like what's the trade-off
Speaker 2:  of sort of trying to be everywhere that people are understanding that the
Speaker 2:  world in which we live is not one where people like spend a lot of time typing
Speaker 2:  URLs into desktop browser bars and all of that versus like
Speaker 2:  we want the website to be the thing kind of even more so with this
Speaker 2:  redesign we did a year ago. Like how do you sort that out in your head at
Speaker 2:  this point?
Speaker 15:  So I do think about this all the time. Our entire redesign is basically
Speaker 15:  a response to this and it's why I lured David
Speaker 15:  back to The Verge because if you look at most publishers
Speaker 15:  on the internet, they just give their stuff away all the time.
Speaker 15:  They're like, here's what we do, people type and then we give their words
Speaker 15:  away to other people's apps and hopefully they'll pay
Speaker 15:  us. And that hopefully is a huge problem, right? Because it has just
Speaker 15:  never come true for anyone. And then you look at their websites, the
Speaker 15:  products they actually make, and it's just amalgamations of other people's
Speaker 15:  software, other people's ad software, very commonly Google and Facebook
Speaker 15:  and other people's ad software, other people's tracking software, very commonly,
Speaker 15:  other people's video players just glomming up pages and
Speaker 15:  you're like, why would anybody come back to this? Why would anybody choose
Speaker 15:  to have this experience? Of course they're gonna go to Flipboard or Apple
Speaker 15:  News or Google Discover or any of these other platforms where you're giving
Speaker 15:  your stuff away for pennies on the dollar. And of course that is
Speaker 15:  a doom loop for the media and the music industry and the
Speaker 15:  movie industry have figured this out and they figured it out because they
Speaker 15:  have collective leverage, right? There's only so many big labels, there's
Speaker 15:  only so many big studios. They figured it out in different ways. The
Speaker 15:  studios funded Spotify basically, and they have a tremendous
Speaker 15:  amount of leverage over Spotify. Taylor Swift is writing letters to the
Speaker 15:  Wall Street Journal about streaming rates. You know, five or six years ago
Speaker 15:  the studios just built their own apps. They're like, we screw it, we're
Speaker 15:  going away from Netflix, we're gonna build our own apps. And that pendulum
Speaker 15:  is swinging back and forth and I'm not sure that they've landed on the right
Speaker 15:  conclusion. But then you look at the news industry and no one's tried
Speaker 15:  any of it, right? It's, it's just been giving stuff away left and right.
Speaker 15:  Very few publishers have stood up and said, we need to make a product that
Speaker 15:  competes on the merits for user experience to actually capture attention.
Speaker 15:  The New York Times has done a good job of this and we e everybody recognizes
Speaker 15:  it, but we cannot live in a world where the New York
Speaker 15:  Times makes news and everyone else reacts to the New York Times.
Speaker 15:  I think that is an unhealthy place to be. So Helen and I have spent a lot
Speaker 15:  of time thinking about one, we do have a loyal audience. The Verge audience
Speaker 15:  is our great asset. Very few publishers have an audience like we do, okay?
Speaker 15:  We have to build that audience a product that is worth coming back to several
Speaker 15:  times a day so that even if you encounter us on all the
Speaker 15:  other platforms that we distribute, we can make a offer to you that coming
Speaker 15:  to us directly is a better and more rewarding experience for
Speaker 15:  you. The consumer of news, not just for us, the collector of revenue.
Speaker 14:  I'll get a little technical though. We do participate in a lot of news
Speaker 14:  readers and there's two kinds of news readers and I think it's helpful to
Speaker 14:  understand the difference between the two in terms of how we think about
Speaker 14:  them driving our business. So one kind of news reader is basically an
Speaker 14:  RSS feed. We give them an RSS feed, it runs on their platform.
Speaker 14:  If someone clicks to read that article, what they get is a Verge page. They
Speaker 14:  get a VERGE page with VERGE advertising and Verge commerce links and all
Speaker 14:  of that. And ideally what we're doing with that is either someone is
Speaker 14:  hitting that page and they're deciding to read more VERGE content in that
Speaker 14:  news reader. And I think this audience question proves you can have a
Speaker 14:  loyal Verge reader who primarily reads us somewhere like Flipboard. That
Speaker 14:  is possible, that's valid, that's still pretty good for business. There
Speaker 14:  is a second kind of news reader and you know, I think we've talked probably
Speaker 14:  quite a lot on The Vergecast about Google Amp or the now defunct
Speaker 14:  Facebook instant articles, which rather than giving people content as
Speaker 14:  an RSS feed, which serves your own page, you would put your
Speaker 14:  content in some proprietary code format that then is native
Speaker 14:  to that platform. And the promise of that was, okay, you're
Speaker 14:  gonna make less money per article maybe because you don't have your fancy
Speaker 14:  ad formats all of the rest. But the product that then runs
Speaker 14:  natively in Facebook is gonna load so fast and it's gonna be such a great
Speaker 14:  experience that the kind of volume you will get by participating there
Speaker 14:  will make up for lost revenue. That in particular turned out
Speaker 14:  not to be a great business to be in. For example, many publishers
Speaker 14:  got way too dependent on Facebook, call it circa 2016,
Speaker 14:  the height of Facebook traffic. Everyone was serving instant
Speaker 14:  articles, everyone was gaming the algorithm. And then Facebook decided
Speaker 14:  basically to shift the algorithm, prioritize family and friends content
Speaker 14:  deprioritize, news content, and a lot of publishers straight up died, like
Speaker 14:  went out of business, died. So that kind of dependence on a
Speaker 14:  single platform to mediate your audience relationship, that
Speaker 14:  is super dangerous. And that is part of why as we evaluate,
Speaker 14:  you know, what readers do we wanna be on, I think a good rubric is
Speaker 14:  one, does that send people back to our website or let us create a loyal
Speaker 14:  relationship with that person inside that app. And if not, it better
Speaker 14:  have some other kind of value For us here we're primarily talking about
Speaker 14:  like text content, but we also make things like video. I think
Speaker 14:  TikTok iss a good analogy for the purpose of that. Platform's a little bit
Speaker 14:  different. You know, I think about TikTok as primarily a marketing
Speaker 14:  platform. A marketing platform to bring The Verge content and brand to
Speaker 14:  younger audiences and initiate them to The Verge. And so it is valid
Speaker 14:  to approach platforms from different perspectives, but I would say
Speaker 14:  it either better convert on loyalty or it better have a really different
Speaker 14:  value for us, or it's not gonna be somewhere we're gonna wanna participate.
Speaker 14:  That
Speaker 15:  TikTok thing is really interesting because if you have a big TikTok channel
Speaker 15:  and you're a creator, people come to you and say, Hey, help me sell my product.
Speaker 15:  Like do some ads for us. If we have a big TikTok channel,
Speaker 15:  what we should be saying is, Hey, visit our website where we make money
Speaker 15:  because we can't really do the advertising that creators can do on TikTok
Speaker 15:  'cause we have this irritating wall between journalists and sales
Speaker 15:  creators don't. So that whole platform is built on like integrated advertising
Speaker 15:  with the content and that's fine, right? More power to the people doing
Speaker 15:  that work. That's not what we do because we are very precious about making
Speaker 15:  journalism. So our product that we have to sell is our website,
Speaker 15:  right? You're, you're watching these talks, you like our people come find
Speaker 15:  us on our, on our platform. Our platform had better be good enough to
Speaker 15:  convert, right? If our product isn't any good and we're saying come to
Speaker 15:  our website that is loaded up with junky ads and SEO spam,
Speaker 15:  the whole premise of doing TikTok falls apart so that I think there's a
Speaker 15:  forcing function, okay, we're gonna do TikTok and reels and
Speaker 15:  YouTube and all these other things, but underneath it there had better be
Speaker 15:  a product that's really worth it that we are marketing the same way that
Speaker 15:  anybody would go to any other creator and market their product,
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. What, what you're describing in a funny way is not that different
Speaker 2:  from what a lot of the folks who are building paywalls around
Speaker 2:  stuff say, right? Which is that essentially it aligns incentives. We want
Speaker 2:  you to engage with our product and we want you to support
Speaker 2:  us directly. And what we're saying instead of give us money for a subscription
Speaker 2:  is like come hang out on our platform. And that is like ultimately
Speaker 2:  that is how we win and how you win because it'll
Speaker 2:  makes us give you the best experience. And like that's a good alignment
Speaker 2:  of incentives. It seems like everybody wins if we get there. But I do. There
Speaker 2:  is one more thing I wanna talk about, which is the like Netflix for news
Speaker 2:  kind of thing that has come and gone at various times. Apple News is
Speaker 2:  probably the most obvious version of that right now, but there are others
Speaker 2:  where it's like, give us some money, take all the news and we'll figure out
Speaker 2:  how to split the revenue. Is that a real thing that's gonna work for anybody
Speaker 2:  Helen? Well,
Speaker 14:  It's interesting to see what Apple is doing. If you are in Apple News today,
Speaker 14:  as someone who does not pay for Apple News, plus what will you will
Speaker 14:  find is that Apple is doing an awful lot of work to promote the Apple News
Speaker 14:  plus subscription. And that seems to be their primary focus
Speaker 14:  because historically Apple's not that great at advertising. And so
Speaker 14:  Apple News is an interesting one because the business model there is a little
Speaker 14:  bit different than the promise of just ads can make it
Speaker 14:  And. what they seem to be doing is going after a subscription bundle,
Speaker 14:  which your Netflix metaphor I think accurately describes.
Speaker 14:  And then in that, you know, if you as a publisher can have a good piece
Speaker 14:  of that, that's a good business to be in. It's trickier if you are an ad
Speaker 14:  supported publisher to figure out how to effectively participate in Apple
Speaker 14:  News and make that work.
Speaker 15:  To be clear, I think all these Netflix for news ideas are gonna run into
Speaker 15:  the same exact trap as the music industry and it maybe this is
Speaker 15:  a good place then. 'cause we started with a direct comparison to the music
Speaker 15:  industry. The music labels are doing great. Artists
Speaker 15:  are not, the music labels have a big share of Spotify. They own a big
Speaker 15:  percentage of Spotify. They can negotiate rates as collectives. Their
Speaker 15:  job is to basically churn artists up and out through the
Speaker 15:  system, right? What is the shelf life of Jack Harlow? Who knows? But they,
Speaker 15:  the music industry is good at finding the next Jack Harlow and spamming
Speaker 15:  him onto your feeds. That's great that, I mean that, and that is the history
Speaker 15:  of music industry. I, I'm not even making a judgment there. That is just
Speaker 15:  the whole history of the music industry. The news industry
Speaker 15:  doesn't have any of the protections, doesn't have any of the cultural relevance
Speaker 15:  of the music industry. If The Verge decided to pull a
Speaker 15:  Metallica and start suing every TikTok creator that read one of our articles
Speaker 15:  to camera for copyright infringement, this is a disaster. No one can do
Speaker 15:  this. So we are just in this less strong
Speaker 15:  position as people who make text than the music or me. Movies
Speaker 15:  industries are, there's no content id for text. There's no
Speaker 15:  sense that reading an article out loud should pay us.
Speaker 15:  Whereas everybody knows if you make a famous cover of a famous song, the
Speaker 15:  songwriter should get paid. None of that is there. None of it exists. So
Speaker 15:  we have to come up with something else. And then on top of it, you add these
Speaker 15:  aggregators to the mix and it's obvious they're gonna extract more value
Speaker 15:  than they pay back to the publishers because that's what they have done
Speaker 15:  in music. That's what they have done in movies. And again, it's the, the
Speaker 15:  middlemen are great. The, the record labels are doing great and maybe
Speaker 15:  some of these big holding companies will do great, but the idea that
Speaker 15:  you're gonna get a famous writer or a famous journalist or a
Speaker 15:  famous author from an aggregation platform that
Speaker 15:  is like well compensated and feels like a star, don, don't think that's
Speaker 15:  remotely possible. I think the economics of that are totally stacked against
Speaker 15:  the deck. I think all of these platforms would prefer to deal
Speaker 15:  with an infinite supply of young individuals than
Speaker 15:  companies that might exert leverage. And I think that alignment mismatch,
Speaker 15:  like you said, David is so real. Every millennial media
Speaker 15:  company, let's call them buzzfeed, vice, whatever, our own all
Speaker 15:  thought that they would become these like institutional
Speaker 15:  brands and the Facebook's of the world would pay
Speaker 15:  carriage fees like the cable companies paid ESPN carriage
Speaker 15:  fees because their brands are so strong and people would want them And.
Speaker 15:  What the platform figured out is they don't need to do that if there's
Speaker 15:  always another 22-year-old creator on the, on the come up and you can
Speaker 15:  pay everyone the, the same rates and all the creators figured out there's
Speaker 15:  no money in the platforms and they need to go start selling energy drinks
Speaker 15:  and sneakers, which is exactly what happened. And so like stuck in the middle
Speaker 15:  of that is like, how do you pay for the news, right? Like maybe we
Speaker 15:  should tell Parker to start selling energy drinks and sneakers. We've already
Speaker 15:  got great t-shirts, but like most publishers are not
Speaker 15:  individual brands like this that can just hawk a product to you and they
Speaker 15:  probably shouldn't be. So Helen runs the business she has being nicer than
Speaker 15:  I do about the platforms. I just see this dynamics in a very
Speaker 15:  clear way for us, which is if we wanna make the journalism, we wanna make,
Speaker 15:  we wanna hold power to account, we want to do the reporting, we want all
Speaker 15:  the stuff, we wanna have fun on our website and not write for algorithms,
Speaker 15:  instead write for our audience. We have to build a business that is independent
Speaker 15:  of these platforms, especially for, especially we for us because we cover
Speaker 15:  the platforms. Do you know how weird it would be if we had an existential
Speaker 15:  financial dependency on Meta? I just think like we have to build something
Speaker 15:  else over here. And so it's great. You should go read us wherever you want.
Speaker 15:  The question is like, how do we make money? We're on these places because
Speaker 15:  we want to find our people there and these algorithms are good at at matching
Speaker 15:  us with audiences sometimes. But once you're there and if you really like
Speaker 15:  us, the thing to do to support us right now is come to
Speaker 15:  our website three times a day. And the thing to do in the future is like
Speaker 15:  pay for command line and take our survey about what other paid products
Speaker 15:  because that's gonna help us continue to be independent and honestly
Speaker 15:  make it easier for us to go report on the platforms without this like
Speaker 15:  existential dread that we're gonna like piss off Mark Zuckerberg and he's
Speaker 15:  gonna turn our traffic to zero, which has happened to many publishers
Speaker 15:  many times over the past few years.
Speaker 14:  Because I am the money. I will say you do not need to feel guilty
Speaker 14:  for reading The Verge on Flipboard podcasting. What all of you are
Speaker 14:  listening to right now, you are listening to in someone else's app that
Speaker 14:  we happen to distribute to with our own advertising and that's a great business.
Speaker 14:  So there are a lot of these news readers where we can have loyal
Speaker 14:  readers who are following The, Verge reading us, reading our page
Speaker 14:  experience with our advertising. It is a great business to be in. But
Speaker 14:  as Neli says, the primary place we need to go is
Speaker 14:  to have that direct audience relationship, not to be too dependent on
Speaker 14:  any one platform or algorithm and to offer things on our website
Speaker 14:  that you won't get anywhere else. Notably quick posts, our
Speaker 14:  live streams, none of that goes to any of these distributed publishers.
Speaker 14:  So if you wanna hear like Alex Heath and Eli's real time
Speaker 14:  reporting on OpenAI last week, you wouldn't get that if you were just
Speaker 14:  reading us in Flipboard. You would only get that if you were on The Verge
Speaker 14:  dot com looking at our homepage, looking at the story stream about the drama
Speaker 14:  going down. And so that is a big part of it is, yeah,
Speaker 14:  what can, what can we offer in the website that you can't get anywhere else?
Speaker 2:  I like it. So as always the answer is download every episode of The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  60 or 70 times and everything will be fine. Awesome.
Speaker 2:  Thank you both. Appreciate it. The Verge dot com. It's a good website. You
Speaker 2:  should read it. The only website left. Alright, that's it for The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast today. Thank you to everyone who's on the show and thank you as
Speaker 2:  always for listening. There is, as always lots more on everything that we
Speaker 2:  talked about at The Verge dot com. Go watch Planet Earth, we'll put some
Speaker 2:  links into the show notes and you know, read The Verge dot com. There's a
Speaker 2:  lot going on even when open AI chaos isn't happening every minute of every
Speaker 2:  day. And as always, if you have thoughts, questions, feelings,
Speaker 2:  or just please want to tell me which monitor to buy, you can always email
Speaker 2:  us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or keep calling the hotline.
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 Verge one one. I love hearing from you and we're gonna do
Speaker 2:  that episode all about buying advice next week. So get your questions in
Speaker 2:  now. This show is produced by Andrew Moreno and Liam James Vergecast is Verge
Speaker 2:  production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Meli Alex and I will
Speaker 2:  be back on Friday to talk more about what's going on in open AI
Speaker 2:  because that just won't stop happening. Plus AI sports
Speaker 2:  reporters, Amazon computers, and lots more. We'll see you then. Rock and
Speaker 2:  roll