# Transcript
ID: 13a57ca0-d281-11ed-b68f-23967f0df63a
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The best laptops for school, tablets for reading, and routers for home
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4712425437892399951/5755094644010121587/s93290-US-4096s-1680568729.mp3
Description: The Verge answers questions from The Vergecast Hotline.
We hear from David Pierce on balancing privacy and modern conveniences for digital journaling, Alex Cranz on tablets for reading, Dan Seifert and Allison Johnson on tech reviews at The Verge, Jennifer Pattison Tuohy on smart home routers and doorbells, and Monica Chin on laptops for college.
Speaker 2:  Hey hotline, it's your friend David Pierce just calling to say
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Vercast, the flagship podcast of 800 number
Speaker 2:  management. I am calling you from the Alexandria Amtrak station in
Speaker 2:  Alexandria, Virginia and I'm just calling to tell you about the show we have
Speaker 2:  coming up for you today. We are gonna send a whole episode talking
Speaker 2:  about your questions from the Vergecast hotline. We've got a ton of good
Speaker 2:  ones. Thank you so much for calling in with all of your questions. We're
Speaker 2:  gonna get questions about laptops, questions at the smart home, questions
Speaker 2:  about privacy, all kinds of good stuff. And as always, please
Speaker 2:  keep calling the hotline 8 6 6 Verge 11, or you can just
Speaker 2:  email questions to vergecast the verge.com. We'd love your questions, we'd
Speaker 2:  love answering them on the show. Please keep 'em coming. Anyway, that's all
Speaker 2:  coming up in just a sec, but I have a train to catch just the first test.
Speaker 2:  See you in a second.
Speaker 5:  Welcome back. As I said, we're gonna spend this whole episode
Speaker 5:  answering your questions from the Vergecast hotline. 8
Speaker 5:  6 6 Verge 11. By the way, keep 'em coming. I wanna start with
Speaker 5:  this question that we got from Chris.
Speaker 2:  Hey Verge, my name is Chris. I'm from the US from Iowa.
Speaker 2:  For several years now I've been struggling to find the right balance between
Speaker 2:  mobile, online privacy and modern conveniences.
Speaker 2:  Everything you do on your phone is being tracked nowadays and it feels like
Speaker 2:  the more you go toward privacy, the more you compromise on convenience
Speaker 2:  and vice versa. My question is, what is the best approach
Speaker 2:  to have the best of both worlds? Is it iPhone? Is
Speaker 2:  Apple really the customer privacy advocate that they claim to be?
Speaker 2:  Is it a tracker blocking vpn? Is it a D Googled
Speaker 2:  custom Android rom like e foundation's, e os? Is it something like
Speaker 2:  light phone, a flip phone, no phone at all. This has been a real struggle
Speaker 2:  for me and I can really go on and on about it, but thank you for taking the
Speaker 2:  time to answer this and I really love the show. Have a good one. Bye.
Speaker 5:  I love this question and it's actually something I've been thinking a lot
Speaker 5:  about personally. Two things happened to me recently that made me ask a
Speaker 5:  lot of these same questions. First, I had my first kid in December and
Speaker 5:  suddenly had a million people asking for photos and videos and
Speaker 5:  information about how he's doing and a million photos and videos
Speaker 5:  and information about how he's doing. And two, my 2023
Speaker 5:  resolution was to start a personal journal again, I've written in a journal
Speaker 5:  every day of 2023 so far, which is maybe the best I've
Speaker 5:  ever done on a New Year's resolution. Honestly, I'm very proud of myself.
Speaker 5:  So like I said, this made me start asking questions about private spaces
Speaker 5:  and personal spaces and what it means to have stuff that
Speaker 5:  you care about be yours on the internet. And the thing about all this
Speaker 5:  is it ends up being surprisingly philosophical. Some
Speaker 5:  people are really worried about privacy and they don't wanna do anything
Speaker 5:  that's even remotely close to risking losing or leaking data.
Speaker 5:  Other people are like, well I have nothing to hide. Who cares? I don't really
Speaker 5:  agree with that last take and I'm not here to pick fights on any of that,
Speaker 5:  but let me just say this. What I know about myself is that I do things
Speaker 5:  differently when I have full trust that something is private, I
Speaker 5:  rate differently in my journal if I know that maybe someday someone
Speaker 5:  will see this versus I'm just gonna burn this thing and it's gonna be gone
Speaker 5:  forever. My Instagram feed and my camera roll are filled with really
Speaker 5:  different kinds of photos because people might see one and might not see
Speaker 5:  the other. The truth is we just act differently in public
Speaker 5:  than in private. We just do so personally, I've become worried
Speaker 5:  about the companies who sell my preferences and know my whereabouts. Yes,
Speaker 5:  but I'm maybe more interested in finding places that I can
Speaker 5:  trust to just be for me so that I can be completely
Speaker 5:  myself in all of this. There's really private spaces and there's
Speaker 5:  personal spaces. They're similar but they're not the same thing and I'm trying
Speaker 5:  to find both. Anyway, when I started journaling, I downloaded day one,
Speaker 5:  which is like the giant of the digital journaling space. I didn't want
Speaker 5:  a paper journal because I also like to save photos and links in my diary.
Speaker 5:  Plus my handwriting is borderline unreadable. My wife likes to say
Speaker 5:  I write like a serial killer. Also, I work for the Verge, I like technology.
Speaker 5:  So I downloaded the app, paid for day one premium and started writing
Speaker 5:  and I noticed a few days later that day one was storing kind of a wild
Speaker 5:  amount of data about me. It has all the journal entries I type obviously,
Speaker 5:  but it was also pulling in all my calendar events for the day, all the locations
Speaker 5:  I'd been to, all the photos I'd taken, I gave it all these
Speaker 5:  permissions, but I kind of did it without thinking about it. And on the one
Speaker 5:  hand it makes for a great journaling system. I have these really cool,
Speaker 5:  really complete records of all of my days automatically, but also,
Speaker 5:  you know, yikes, that's a lot of really personal
Speaker 5:  private information for one app to have even more. So when you factor in
Speaker 5:  that my day one journal, the thing I actually type in is maybe the
Speaker 5:  one thing on earth I most want to keep private. That to me
Speaker 5:  is the perfect encapsulation of what Chris mentioned in his voicemail. Sure,
Speaker 5:  a paper journal under my mattress would technically be more private, but
Speaker 5:  I want all the modern niceties and upsides of an app like day
Speaker 5:  one. Is it even possible to have it both ways? So I called up the folks
Speaker 5:  at day one to ask him about this
Speaker 6:  Paul main head of day one at Automatic
Speaker 7:  Murphy Randall, lead of the web client team on day one
Speaker 7:  at Automatic.
Speaker 5:  Paul told me that when he was first starting day one, the features and
Speaker 5:  privacy trade off was right at the top of his mind.
Speaker 6:  I wanted something that I trusted myself to capture and
Speaker 6:  store all of these memories that would exist like even after me,
Speaker 6:  but mostly around the comfort of knowing that I could put whatever I wanted
Speaker 6:  there and it's unlikely or impossible for anyone
Speaker 6:  else to even see it. And that manifested in the early
Speaker 6:  days where it was we were scrappy and just bootstrapping an
Speaker 6:  idea to be offline first where everything was basically
Speaker 6:  a web page and apps just synced with a server.
Speaker 6:  So day one was starting with the Mac to be stored locally on your file
Speaker 6:  system where by default only you, whoever has access to
Speaker 6:  your computer would see it. The downside being, if you lost that computer,
Speaker 6:  you lose all of those memories.
Speaker 5:  Early on with day one there was no way to sync your stuff between
Speaker 5:  devices because there was no way to do it privately. Then for a while you
Speaker 5:  could sync through Dropbox, but eventually Day one built its own end-to-end
Speaker 5:  encrypted service because it didn't want to just offload everything and
Speaker 5:  trust Dropbox. But again, even that is a trade-off end-to-end
Speaker 5:  encryption is a good thing and something you should look for, but it's still
Speaker 5:  a risk. And Murphy who recently led a whole project
Speaker 5:  building a day one web app said that day one is constantly making
Speaker 5:  trade-offs between privacy and convenience features and
Speaker 5:  personality and every one of those choices has consequences.
Speaker 5:  Sometimes ones you don't see,
Speaker 7:  That's the line we walk all the time and we've really messed ourselves up
Speaker 7:  by being a little overzealous with the privacy at times, like for example,
Speaker 7:  we originally locked up so much about entries
Speaker 7:  that like we didn't even allow ourselves to see the date on which the entry
Speaker 7:  was written. Like you know, the entry date you say like I'm writing a entry
Speaker 7:  on Christmas. The server that we have didn't know that you said it was on
Speaker 7:  Christmas because we wanted to say as much as possible is invisible to
Speaker 7:  us. But it turns out like if you wanna make a web app that can pull
Speaker 7:  down a few entries, you kind of gotta know the dates. And so that's a
Speaker 7:  line that we had to walk and we are limited in the features
Speaker 7:  we can offer now in some ways because of the stuff that we locked up
Speaker 7:  in the past. And so now you know, we can release an app upgrade that would
Speaker 7:  say like, well okay, maybe we'll just decrypt that one date and make it so
Speaker 7:  that we can let the user say, what journal entries do I have for Christmas?
Speaker 7:  And then you know, get it from the web app. But we do what we can
Speaker 7:  to work within the confines that are set. So
Speaker 7:  the new web client that we're releasing very soon that's in private beta
Speaker 7:  right now. Originally we wanted to make something kind of like Evernote,
Speaker 7:  the Evernote experience where if you go to Evernote you can just see a few
Speaker 7:  of your most recent notes and edit them and it's a very lightweight
Speaker 7:  experience. But since our stuff is end to end encrypted, we ended
Speaker 7:  up having to to go all in and write like a, a more advanced client
Speaker 7:  that would pull all your entries down from the server, decrypt all of them,
Speaker 7:  index them so that you can interact with them in the day
Speaker 7:  one way you know you can't just like fetch a few entries and work on
Speaker 7:  them. That's a technical cost that we incurred by
Speaker 7:  opting for privacy.
Speaker 5:  One example I really like here is passwords and encryption keys.
Speaker 5:  The most private thing an app can do is say here's your
Speaker 5:  encryption key, we don't have it so write it down and if you lose it you're
Speaker 5:  host and we can't help you Privacy wise that feels great
Speaker 5:  convenience wise it's a total pain in the ass. Here's how Paul
Speaker 5:  explained how day one thinks about all that.
Speaker 6:  What we do is we rely on the device
Speaker 6:  manufacturer or or os manufacturer in this case Apple
Speaker 6:  and Google to store in their private key storage
Speaker 6:  solutions. They have a key store that only day
Speaker 6:  one can access this key and then we put it in there and then the app
Speaker 6:  automatically fetches it from there. When you go sign in on another device,
Speaker 6:  it'll, it'll find it in there because you're authenticated with your Apple
Speaker 6:  account. So less secure than managing your own private
Speaker 6:  key and Apple's continuing to advance their security around
Speaker 6:  these things as well. So as they get better, our
Speaker 6:  encryption is better but it's more of a consumer-friendly way of
Speaker 6:  offering end to end encryption, private key storage without the
Speaker 6:  user. The downside of like managing that key in a physical
Speaker 6:  way that if it's lost all is lost like it is with the
Speaker 6:  wallet.
Speaker 5:  I also asked Wesley Rosh the developer of another journaling app called Ever
Speaker 5:  Log about the same stuff. He said, he's also trying to figure out how
Speaker 5:  to do secure sync because that turns out to be the first privacy
Speaker 5:  feature trade off that you really want to get right?
Speaker 8:  Right now the way it is your data, it's secure on your
Speaker 8:  device so it's secured by Apple Secure Enclave and
Speaker 8:  everything. But the moment you sync with Cy Cloud there's a
Speaker 8:  a small chance that the could be breached by, I don't know, someone
Speaker 8:  Apple or so that's pretty important right now.
Speaker 5:  I asked Wesley if there are any features he just straight up can't add
Speaker 5:  to ever log purely for privacy reasons and he said yeah, there are lots of
Speaker 5:  them. The big one is ai.
Speaker 8:  One big thing will be sentiment analysis. Like it would
Speaker 8:  give the AI your entries and it would say this, this entry
Speaker 8:  is positive, this entry is happy, this entry is
Speaker 8:  you're anxious or whatever. That could be great for stats
Speaker 8:  and but again, I don't think people will be interested in sharing
Speaker 8:  their, their stuff with third parties.
Speaker 5:  The more I thought about this trade off between privacy and convenience,
Speaker 5:  between having lots of features and having something that feels like it's
Speaker 5:  just yours, the more I started seeing it everywhere, like in another
Speaker 5:  app I use Obsidian, which is a super popular new note taking app.
Speaker 5:  Part of obsidian whole appeal is that the files it's working with are just
Speaker 5:  markdown files saved on your computer. They're not stored on a server
Speaker 5:  somewhere, they're just there in a folder on your device. Obsidian does
Speaker 5:  have end-to-end encryption but you don't have to use it to use the app. But
Speaker 5:  Obsidian also has this big ecosystem of third party
Speaker 5:  plug-ins where anyone can write code and post it on GitHub
Speaker 5:  that changes the way obsidian looks or adds new features that
Speaker 5:  can get really messy really fast and be a weird privacy
Speaker 5:  thing if you let it. Stefan Ango, the CEO of Obsidian
Speaker 5:  told me he thinks control is the key. He likes the idea of starting
Speaker 5:  with a totally private experience and then letting users
Speaker 5:  choose how much they're willing to give up in exchange for new features.
Speaker 9:  That means that if you wanna build a chat G p T plugin, I think there's like
Speaker 9:  four or five of them already out there that are slightly different
Speaker 9:  variations on how you might want to use chat G P t with your, with your notes.
Speaker 9:  And it comes with you know, caveat enter like
Speaker 9:  there's like a little bit of, because we give you so much freedom, it
Speaker 9:  means that the user has to make their own choices about
Speaker 9:  what they're willing to give up.
Speaker 5:  The trade off here is that obsidian is kind of awkward to figure
Speaker 5:  out when you first set it up. It doesn't do that much. It's just a text editor.
Speaker 5:  Basically you have to figure out how to allow yourself to have
Speaker 5:  plugins and then find and research and add and explore
Speaker 5:  all these additional features basically by yourself. But to some extent I
Speaker 5:  think that's probably a better strategy privacy wise than just dropping you
Speaker 5:  in the deep end and forcing you to figure out how everything works. You might
Speaker 5:  notice by the way, that AI keeps coming up here for good reason. If you
Speaker 5:  wanna look ahead to where all of this goes next, look at chat G P T. There
Speaker 5:  are a bunch of companies out there trying to build tools that apply chat
Speaker 5:  G P T to your life, which sounds great, right? You could ask a
Speaker 5:  chat bot to find that link you were looking at yesterday or remind you what
Speaker 5:  your dentist's name is or I don't know anything else you can think of. But
Speaker 5:  that means giving a tool like chat g p t access to a vast
Speaker 5:  amount of your personal data. Dan Roker, the c o of a company
Speaker 5:  called Rewind is trying to figure out how to bring AI chat bots to life
Speaker 5:  while still getting that privacy convenience balance, right?
Speaker 5:  Rewind is an app that records everything you do on your computer. It takes
Speaker 5:  screenshots every two seconds. It records all your meetings, it stores all
Speaker 5:  your web history and much more. And now you can use chat g
Speaker 5:  P T to interact with all that info. You might think that's useful, you might
Speaker 5:  think it's a total privacy disaster. Dan said he's trying to
Speaker 5:  find a way to get as much of the upside as possible with as little of the
Speaker 5:  downside as possible.
Speaker 10:  I think using privacy as the main constraint and
Speaker 10:  respecting people's privacy is the key technological insight
Speaker 10:  here that will allow this to be adopted by not just sort of tech
Speaker 10:  enthusiasts but mainstream users. Because the reality is, you know, we live
Speaker 10:  in a world where more and more of your data is for sale, you know more and
Speaker 10:  more of your privacy is being, you know, you could could say even compromised
Speaker 10:  for utility. And I think in that world, finding
Speaker 10:  a solution that strikes the right balance and and respects your privacy
Speaker 10:  doesn't just, you know, pretend it doesn't exist, is I think
Speaker 10:  the key unlock to this.
Speaker 5:  The way Rewind does it is to send only the relevant bits of your data to
Speaker 5:  open AI in order to make chat g p t work. So instead of uploading all
Speaker 5:  your data, rewind is first curating just the stuff that matters, turning
Speaker 5:  it into text and then sending it for processing. This feels to me like a
Speaker 5:  pretty good middle ground but it's still a big trade off and I'm not sure
Speaker 5:  I know if the usefulness outweighs the intrusiveness,
Speaker 5:  ultimately I come back to something obsidian. Stefan Ango told me that
Speaker 5:  the best answer is probably lots of answers. Everybody has different principles
Speaker 5:  and needs around privacy and the best thing tech companies can do is give
Speaker 5:  you the information you need to make choices rather than trying to make them
Speaker 5:  for
Speaker 9:  You. It's the same thing as kind of the right to modify,
Speaker 9:  right to extend right to repair. Like those types of
Speaker 9:  ideas I think are are strong within the obsidian community. We want
Speaker 9:  to give the user control, you know, respect the
Speaker 9:  user's ability to work with the software in whatever way
Speaker 9:  they want.
Speaker 5:  Anyway, let me get back to Chris's initial question for a second. I think
Speaker 5:  the answer is complicated, but Chris, to your specific points based on what
Speaker 5:  I've learned here are a few things I would say. One is that most people seem
Speaker 5:  to agree that on balance the iPhone is a more secure ecosystem
Speaker 5:  than Android. I don't think you need a VPN for most everyday web browsing,
Speaker 5:  but if it makes you more comfortable, go for it. There are some good ones
Speaker 5:  out there and I would encourage you to keep different kinds of information
Speaker 5:  in different places and keep your most important, most private,
Speaker 5:  most personal stuff in a place all its own. Ideally, one you
Speaker 5:  control and understand as completely as possible, be wary of things
Speaker 5:  that automatically share stuff with other people. Make sure you understand
Speaker 5:  how the sharing and publishing and collaboration settings work and go for
Speaker 5:  end-to-end encryption anywhere you can. I started out thinking that maybe
Speaker 5:  the only really good answer here is just as little tech as possible.
Speaker 5:  Throw your phone into the river, move into the woods and like write on parchment
Speaker 5:  paper or whatever. But I'm actually encouraged by the potential here that
Speaker 5:  as more people start to care about privacy, there will be more products that
Speaker 5:  actually start with privacy and then build from there. But it's very clear
Speaker 5:  that there will always, always be trade-offs, especially
Speaker 5:  many more hotline questions all of them much more quickly than the one
Speaker 5:  that we just did. First up, Alex Kranz is here. Hi Alex.
Speaker 13:  Hi. I bet I know what it's about.
Speaker 5:  There's like two things you come here for and it's, it's great. And this
Speaker 5:  one's not about Plex so there's only one possible option. Okay, but let's
Speaker 5:  just get to it. We have a question. I believe it is from Andrew.
Speaker 14:  Hi, my name is Andrew, I'm a longtime listener and reader of The Verge
Speaker 14:  and I'm a law student now. I've been thinking about buying an iPad or
Speaker 14:  potentially an EIN tablet but can't seem to decide which might be
Speaker 14:  better for reading and taking notes. So interested to hear some pros and
Speaker 14:  cons. Thanks.
Speaker 5:  Do you see why you're here Alex?
Speaker 13:  I see why I'm
Speaker 5:  Here. So there's two questions here and we, we should take them in turn.
Speaker 5:  The first question is do you buy an iPad or do you buy an E Ink tablet?
Speaker 5:  And then there's gonna be the which one question. But let's start with just
Speaker 5:  that breakdown. Do we, should this person buy an iPad or an E Ink tablet?
Speaker 13:  I feel really bad for saying this, but they should buy the iPad cuz
Speaker 13:  they're going to law school, right? Yeah. If they were just digging around
Speaker 13:  at home like reading and sometimes marking stuff up, I would say get the
Speaker 13:  E Ink tablet. I would have no regrets but they actually needed to work all
Speaker 13:  of the time consistently and not be probably messing with a bunch
Speaker 13:  of like fighting the user interface all the time.
Speaker 13:  And so they'll have a much better time with an iPad if they do that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I was thinking about this and I, I think the way you just laid that
Speaker 5:  out is exactly right cuz like my, my heart says by a remarkable
Speaker 5:  tablet because it is a truly lovely thing to read PDFs on a
Speaker 13:  Hundred percent and
Speaker 5:  In the actual moment of reading the Ink
Speaker 5:  tablet is much better, right? Like I still have not used a Kindle scribe.
Speaker 5:  You have but my guess would be that literally in the like I am highlighting
Speaker 5:  a page of a PDF thing, the Ink tablet is gonna be better
Speaker 13:  A hundred percent. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Managing all of those things, getting them on and off your device, moving
Speaker 5:  them around, submitting them to things, sharing them with people.
Speaker 5:  Total disaster on anything not called the iPad and for
Speaker 5:  like, that's where I end up with like the iPad is pretty good as a reading
Speaker 5:  experience and really great as like a life management experience
Speaker 5:  and the ING tablets are really good for reading and just full hot garbage
Speaker 5:  for the other side of things.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, I would honestly say get the iPad but then
Speaker 13:  do what Dan did which is get like that that matte Yeah
Speaker 13:  screen protector so it feels a little bit more like writing on
Speaker 13:  paper and it look, it doesn't have the glare like I think that'll probably
Speaker 13:  be the best for the majority of people who actually need to get work
Speaker 13:  done on the device.
Speaker 5:  I think that's right. We did a whole segment on that on last week's vergecast.
Speaker 5:  So if you haven't listened to it, Dan was very helpful.
Speaker 13:  But then once you get your law degree and you get your signing bonus
Speaker 13:  at whatever big fancy firm you're at, go by the E Ink tablet, you're gonna
Speaker 13:  have a great time with it. You're gonna love it.
Speaker 5:  The EIN tablet is like you make partner and there's like a person who
Speaker 5:  will do all the file management for you and then all you have to do is just
Speaker 5:  like kick back at your desk with your loafers up and read some
Speaker 5:  PDFs. Like that's when you get the EIN tablet and life is incredible.
Speaker 13:  Like you're just marking up other people's briefs. I assume that's a thing.
Speaker 13:  Lawyers do you
Speaker 5:  Just chuck your tablet across the room at them? Yeah,
Speaker 13:  Throw it at their heads.
Speaker 5:  Ferguson read this. Yeah,
Speaker 13:  That's why you have one Ls you throw, throw the tablets at them
Speaker 5:  And do we, what do we think like the, probably either the the
Speaker 5:  iPad error or the iPad Pro depending on how you feel about
Speaker 5:  money and keyboards.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, I think the iPad error is enough for most people. I think they'll
Speaker 13:  have a great time with like an iPad error that Matt screen protector
Speaker 13:  and a nice little pencil that'll get everything they need to get done done.
Speaker 5:  I think that's right. All right, we've, we've helped Andrew You're welcome.
Speaker 5:  Let us know how it goes. Let's move on to the next one. Thank you Alex. You're
Speaker 5:  welcome. For our next question, I have two people here. Dan
Speaker 5:  Seifert. Hello. Hello Allison Johnson. Hello. Welcome back from vacation.
Speaker 13:  Hello. Thank
Speaker 5:  You. And our question I believe is from Nick
Speaker 5:  so let's hear it.
Speaker 15:  Hey Verge, my name is Nick. I had a question about
Speaker 15:  how phone reviews work at the Verge, who reviews it,
Speaker 15:  how you decide who reviews it and then what that process looks
Speaker 15:  like. Love what you do.
Speaker 5:  So I love a good meta verge question
Speaker 5:  and I feel like this is a fun one. We like reviews just sort of like magically
Speaker 5:  appear and it's like let's talk about this. Yeah,
Speaker 16:  They just magically happen. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah, they're they're just there on the website. Yeah, but I, phone
Speaker 5:  reviews I feel like are actually a pretty good one cuz the, our process I
Speaker 5:  feel like has gotten much better for it over time. But Dan you run our reviews
Speaker 5:  program Allison. You do. I would say most of our phone reviews so
Speaker 5:  let's talk through it. New phone comes out or new phone is coming out. What
Speaker 5:  happens we're the Verge people kind of want us to review their stuff, right?
Speaker 5:  Like what, how does this stuff start?
Speaker 16:  Yeah, I guess we could, we'll start right at the beginning. So let's take
Speaker 16:  the example of Samsung, which recently Ren announced the S 23
Speaker 16:  line. So Samsung announces a phone, their PR department will
Speaker 16:  generally contact us and say we've got a new device coming out.
Speaker 16:  And a lot of times they will require what's called an embargo, which
Speaker 16:  means that we say we agree to not talk about this thing until after a certain
Speaker 16:  date and then they will provide the device to us for testing
Speaker 16:  purposes and review so that we have access to it ahead of
Speaker 16:  when it goes on sale. And then we are able to publish our review before
Speaker 16:  or on the day of when it goes on sale, which is usually around the timing
Speaker 16:  when the embargo lifts. And so that is like kind of like a
Speaker 16:  a working relationship that we have with lots of companies with their PR
Speaker 16:  departments. The unique thing there is that we agree
Speaker 16:  to the embargo and that's about it.
Speaker 16:  Beyond that, companies don't have any influence on what our review
Speaker 16:  looks like. They don't get to see a preview of it, they don't get to really,
Speaker 16:  the only time the, that they see the review is the same time is that the
Speaker 16:  audience sees it when it publishes live on the site. And then sometimes
Speaker 16:  they send notices if we you know get a factual error wrong, they give us
Speaker 16:  a heads up or sometimes they just say we don't like your score and we're
Speaker 16:  like tough nooks, you know, that's the kind of relationship there that's
Speaker 16:  all detailed in our ethics statement if you're curious about it on the site.
Speaker 16:  So you can go check that out. Determining who gets to review something is
Speaker 16:  actually pretty straightforward now because we have folks like Allison
Speaker 16:  who are really assigned a beat. So Allison's main job is to cover phones
Speaker 16:  at the Verge. That's what she does all day in, day out. She's our lead phone
Speaker 16:  reviewer. So she's the one that really reviews the vast majority of
Speaker 16:  things. Occasionally other people will review phones. I think the best
Speaker 16:  example is John Porter over in the uk. He has access to devices that
Speaker 16:  we don't get here in the us they don't sell them here in the us they only
Speaker 16:  sell them in Europe or uk. And so he will review those devices cause it
Speaker 16:  makes most sense for him to review it. He can get access to them, he can
Speaker 16:  test it on their networks. Half the time those devices don't even work on
Speaker 16:  our networks. I know Allison has a few inner possession now that are
Speaker 16:  like, yeah good luck getting a signal and forget about 5g. But that, that's
Speaker 16:  kind of like of like the split there. And then because Allison is one person
Speaker 16:  and this is a very large beat to cover, occasionally other folks around
Speaker 16:  the team will help out if Allison's got a really swamped workload and we
Speaker 16:  feel that we need to get a review out in a quicker amount of time
Speaker 16:  than Allison's able to get to it. So occasionally I play kind of like a
Speaker 16:  floater across the team. If someone's swamped or on vacation or something
Speaker 16:  like that, I might pick up a review to so that we have it up on the site
Speaker 16:  and things like that. But really Allison has right of first refusal and
Speaker 16:  really the the the first expectation that she's going to be the reviewer.
Speaker 16:  And you could see that across all of the categories of
Speaker 16:  products that we review. Monica Chin is our laptop reviewer. She's the one
Speaker 16:  reviewing vast majority of our laptops and is like write a first refusal
Speaker 16:  on those. Whereas we're recording this today on Monday. Chris Welch just
Speaker 16:  published two Sonos reviews. He's our speaker and TV and home
Speaker 16:  audio reviewer and headphone reviewer. So he focuses on that. So like when
Speaker 16:  these products get announced we kind of know who's gonna review it already
Speaker 16:  and there's like just kind of like extenuating circumstances where it might
Speaker 16:  be somebody else occasionally NEI likes to like swing
Speaker 16:  in.
Speaker 5:  I was gonna say when a big iPhone comes out, ni Eli magically appears out
Speaker 5:  of the woodwork to review it. He
Speaker 16:  Appears he likes to do his iPhone review once a year. We like to let him
Speaker 16:  do that. You know, and what, who, who am I to argue
Speaker 5:  Right? Keeps him off our back the rest of the year. It works out fine. Yeah,
Speaker 16:  Exactly. And you know, the funny part is generally that is actually
Speaker 16:  a very good example of like where Allison can't really review
Speaker 16:  all the devices that are released at that point in the timeframe that we
Speaker 16:  have. Going back to like when we're getting devices ahead of release, a
Speaker 16:  lot of times we have as little as one week or sometimes less to review a
Speaker 16:  device before that embargo. And if it's an iPhone review, there's a lot
Speaker 16:  of moving parts involved with that. Allison's gotta test the device, she's
Speaker 16:  gotta take a lot of photos, she's gotta take photos of the device, she's
Speaker 16:  gotta take photos with the device. She's gotta kind of like formulate her
Speaker 16:  thoughts and write it all. And then generally she's working with the video
Speaker 16:  team so there's gotta be a video that's gotta be shot, they need to shoot
Speaker 16:  B-roll of it, they need to edit it. All these things generally have to happen
Speaker 16:  within a five to six day span, oftentimes over a weekend. So like it's,
Speaker 16:  it's a very compressed type of schedule. So when Apple releases two, three
Speaker 16:  new iPhones at a time, having somebody like Nii or somebody else on
Speaker 16:  the team that's able to pick up one of those helps us able to be a little
Speaker 16:  bit faster with our publishing and have it out there in time when all of
Speaker 16:  our wonderful competitors will be publishing as well or ahead of the release
Speaker 16:  date or the in-store date. So that's kind of like the general process.
Speaker 16:  But Allison, once it gets passed off to you, then what happens?
Speaker 17:  Yeah, so I've, I've kind of figured this out over the past couple of
Speaker 17:  years but I, I've settled into kind of a method when I
Speaker 17:  get a phone and it has to do with like, I really like to have
Speaker 17:  my sim card and make whatever phone it is my
Speaker 17:  phone for the week or two weeks or however long
Speaker 17:  I can't make it work. You know, having like a personal phone that I'm texting
Speaker 17:  on and in a review phone. So that's possible with all the
Speaker 17:  major Samsungs and iPhones.
Speaker 5:  So you must spend like a quarter of your time just switching phones at some
Speaker 5:  point. Like I feel like we've all been through this pain and it's, it's a
Speaker 5:  lot. Yes. I I feel you
Speaker 17:  On that. And EIM has ruined my life.
Speaker 17:  Oh yeah, just slowly and I have a lot of
Speaker 17:  thoughts on eim but anyway, one way or another I get my
Speaker 17:  sim and my plan onto the phone. I'm reviewing, I have a
Speaker 17:  password manager, I would be totally lost without it. So I
Speaker 17:  set everything up kind of from scratch, download the password manager,
Speaker 17:  download my handful of apps that I actually really use,
Speaker 17:  which is a shockingly small number.
Speaker 5:  I was gonna ask what are the like yeah when you first get a phone you're
Speaker 5:  like I need these whatever six apps.
Speaker 17:  It's go, it's a little embarrassing. Starbucks is always on there.
Speaker 17:  It's like sure without fail day one I need to download Starbucks.
Speaker 17:  I put Strava on there even though I don't really work out. But I like
Speaker 17:  to, I like to try and do a GPS kind of like walk or run or
Speaker 17:  something. Spotify always and then the
Speaker 17:  social networks. But yeah, that's, I I try to like,
Speaker 17:  I make a phone call with the phone, which is something you can
Speaker 17:  easily forget about but like I use it
Speaker 17:  as a phone, I use it to listen to music. I, I just do
Speaker 17:  everything with it that anybody would do with the phone
Speaker 17:  and I try to do it all within a week.
Speaker 16:  I think that's a, that's a great point there Allison is like you do a lot
Speaker 16:  of the testing that may not show up in the end product, the end review,
Speaker 16:  you might not have a line in there being like phone calls sound fine, like
Speaker 16:  exactly as you expect or like it played the music but the still part of
Speaker 16:  your testing process because if it didn't work then it would be
Speaker 16:  part of the story for
Speaker 17:  Sure. Yeah, exactly. Nobody needs to hear about how I
Speaker 17:  watched a bunch of succession, you know, sitting on my bed
Speaker 17:  on a device and it worked fine.
Speaker 5:  What kind of like specific tests do you run every time? Like do you
Speaker 5:  have a, do you have a picture you take every single time you review a phone
Speaker 5:  or like a place you go to try something?
Speaker 17:  I have a couple scenarios. I really try and I try and do
Speaker 17:  one day where I really stress test a battery and I,
Speaker 17:  I leave my house, which is whoa very difficult
Speaker 17:  to do in this day and age. But like I like getting on the light
Speaker 17:  rail train in Seattle and just kind of using that as like a
Speaker 17:  commute, just cosplaying someone who goes into an office.
Speaker 17:  So I, yeah I scroll things on the phone, I take pictures of
Speaker 17:  my toddler cuz I think that is the ultimate stress
Speaker 17:  test of a smartphone camera system. Still
Speaker 17:  haven't really found one that can keep up with the toddler
Speaker 17:  and the cat. I think taking pictures of cats is probably the
Speaker 17:  most important thing I do.
Speaker 5:  I would, I would agree with that. Video is obviously a big part of this,
Speaker 5:  so how does that all factor in, especially now like if we're gonna get real
Speaker 5:  meta about the verge, we all used to work in an office and it, it was easier
Speaker 5:  to make these things now if we're gonna do like a big cool video, how does
Speaker 5:  it work?
Speaker 17:  It's changed a little bit since I started. I was being directed
Speaker 17:  over Zoom for some of them, which I think by the
Speaker 17:  time I came on you guys had all been doing that for like a year and a half
Speaker 17:  so it went, so it went very well. I think, you know, Becca and Veen
Speaker 17:  and Phil at that time had a really good grasp of like how to get someone
Speaker 17:  like me to shoot usable video of me
Speaker 17:  talking about a phone. But with the return of in-person
Speaker 17:  things, you know, I get to go to San Francisco and
Speaker 17:  we have, you know, Veens out there and we shot some things when I was there
Speaker 17:  for Samsung. So yeah, it's changing. I, I'm excited
Speaker 17:  for what it looks like when I can be face to face
Speaker 17:  with someone and, and we can shoot these things in real
Speaker 17:  life.
Speaker 5:  I d what a world that's gonna be.
Speaker 17:  Yeah,
Speaker 16:  I think that, I mean you, you kind of highlighted some of the challenges
Speaker 16:  of creating video now that we didn't have the
Speaker 16:  same challenges before but I think ultimately it's allowed us to have a
Speaker 16:  lot more variety in our videos and they look different generally in different
Speaker 16:  set setups, different locations and things like that. Whereas when we were
Speaker 16:  all in the office, we got really used to shooting in the same studio all
Speaker 16:  the time and our videos frequently looked very similar from from shot to
Speaker 16:  shot. So that's kind of one of the upsides of the, the the new format now.
Speaker 5:  So Allison, you say you try to only have one phone at a time. Realistically
Speaker 5:  how many phones do you have at a time?
Speaker 17:  Oh my god. So something will happen and I'll need to like
Speaker 17:  check, you know, some software update on one phone and then
Speaker 17:  I have a que I'm like, well what does it look like on this one? And our
Speaker 17:  dining room table will be like seven phones at any given
Speaker 17:  time and my husband is so patient like
Speaker 17:  an alarm will go off. I'm like, shit, I don't know which of
Speaker 17:  these seven phones it is. You know, like I live in fear that I'm
Speaker 17:  forgetting to turn my wakeup alarm off cuz I'll just gotta
Speaker 17:  like pull into the dining room and be like, stop it. Which one is it?
Speaker 17:  So the answer is a
Speaker 5:  Lot. I remember years ago getting a phone call from
Speaker 5:  the security guard at the office saying there's something
Speaker 5:  in your desk that has been playing semi charmed life by third eye blind
Speaker 5:  for like two hours. And it was, I had, I had set that
Speaker 5:  as the alarm on the phone because I thought that was the thing I wondered
Speaker 5:  for my alarm for some reason. And so from like 6:00 AM to the time I showed
Speaker 5:  up, it was just
Speaker 5:  Welcome back. We have a
Speaker 5:  so, so much.
Speaker 19:  How long have we got? Right?
Speaker 5:  So, okay, I think first of all Hayes, congratulations. I hope your new
Speaker 5:  apartment is awesome. This is a good moment to like build from the ground
Speaker 5:  up here, right? Because we spend a lot of time talking about like the best
Speaker 5:  mesh networks and should, which fancy routers should you buy? But like
Speaker 5:  very beginning, you wanna start with a thing that works. Where
Speaker 5:  would you tell our friend Hayes to start? What's the answer here?
Speaker 19:  Oh, well wifi is, it can be quite subjective,
Speaker 19:  but he said he's moved into his first home, so I'm assuming it's not
Speaker 19:  a 1500 door, 2000 square foot house. It's probably
Speaker 19:  a, a smaller apartment. Although you know in Idaho they do have a lot of
Speaker 19:  space so it could be sizable, but if you're in an apartment maybe
Speaker 19:  800, a thousand square feet, you know you are base, you just just need to
Speaker 19:  start with a good router. And now this is different
Speaker 19:  from a modem in most instances, depending on
Speaker 19:  your I S P quite often your i p will supply you with
Speaker 19:  a modem router. So it's both to throw in the gateway phrase
Speaker 19:  I think gateway is, is less relevant. Your the most
Speaker 19:  important tool you need to know are modem and router gateway is sort of
Speaker 19:  something that you may use in other parts of your house.
Speaker 19:  Like you might have additional gateways throughout your house, but modem
Speaker 19:  router are the two important ones and they are very different even though
Speaker 19:  they may be in the same box, which can cause confusion. But if you have
Speaker 19:  a smaller, smaller home, you are fine to have both in one
Speaker 19:  device but you probably do not want to stick with whatever
Speaker 19:  your I S P has sent you. That is kind of the, the rule of
Speaker 19:  thumb because generally these devices aren't as high powered
Speaker 19:  or as feature rich as something you might buy off the shelf. If
Speaker 19:  you have a slightly larger home and or if you are interested in
Speaker 19:  smart home, which we know you are, it's worth considering a mesh
Speaker 19:  router because devices like doorbells security
Speaker 19:  cameras aren't gonna be very close to your router and they still need
Speaker 19:  strong wifi. That's where mesh comes in. But as David said, we're starting
Speaker 19:  at the beginning so we can get to mesh a little later. But to start with,
Speaker 19:  you want an I S P modem and then you wanna buy
Speaker 19:  your own router, which gives you generally a stronger signal,
Speaker 19:  better features.
Speaker 5:  Okay, I'd like to argue with this advice. Okay. I would like to pick one
Speaker 5:  very small fight with you about this advice, which is that I think
Speaker 5:  generally speaking, if if they're just gonna give you a modem, great because
Speaker 5:  I think in general as long as you get like a pretty good modem, your router
Speaker 5:  ends up being the much more important piece of technology. Yes, but at least
Speaker 5:  on my bill, my cable company, Comcast disclosure
Speaker 5:  Comcast is an investor in the Fox media and
Speaker 5:  socks at providing internet to my house. The Comcast
Speaker 5:  router to me is I think like $10 a month and that's a terrible deal.
Speaker 5:  And if you buy an even pretty good modem for yourself,
Speaker 5:  it will pay itself off very quickly.
Speaker 19:  Modem as opposed to a router. Yes,
Speaker 5:  Because
Speaker 19:  Some ISPs won't let you use your own modem. That's true to
Speaker 19:  Comcast's credit, they will let you. That's fair. They have
Speaker 19:  a long list on their website of ones that will work. I for many, many
Speaker 19:  years was with at and t who will not let you, you have to use
Speaker 19:  their modem. So it will depend who you use. And knowing
Speaker 19:  Idaho as I do, I am guessing it's Cox Internet, if they still exist
Speaker 19:  as that brand of, they may have changed names, but Cox was what
Speaker 19:  I use when I was there and it was sort of your only option. So yes, depending
Speaker 19:  on your I S P, yeah if you can bring your entirely your own equipment,
Speaker 19:  go for it. But if you're limited, at least bring your own
Speaker 19:  router. One because you don't have to pay the monthly fee and you end up
Speaker 19:  saving money in the long run. And two, because you can make sure your router
Speaker 19:  has some much more interesting features. For example, some of
Speaker 19:  the things that a few of the router companies I was gonna recommend here
Speaker 19:  offer will help with your smart home. For example, both
Speaker 19:  Google Nest and Arrow who both have mesh routers
Speaker 19:  offer thread, which is a very key part of the
Speaker 19:  Smart home, the new standard matter and even if you're not involved with
Speaker 19:  Matter Thread is a great local protocol that will
Speaker 19:  help make smart home devices like sensors and light bulbs
Speaker 19:  work speedier in your home rather than having to rely on the cloud. And
Speaker 19:  if you're looking at starting the smart home, you are in a great place right
Speaker 19:  now because this is the time where you can go out and buy thread enabled
Speaker 19:  devices and not have to worry about relying on the cloud or wifi.
Speaker 19:  So you want thread in your router. You also want dual band.
Speaker 19:  If we are starting with basics, you want a 2.4 and a five
Speaker 19:  gigahertz band, don't worry too much about six E, which
Speaker 19:  is the Try band six gigahertz. You probably don't need to worry about that
Speaker 19:  yet. That's, that would be your next router upgrade. I would also
Speaker 19:  recommend wifi six Capable router because that will
Speaker 19:  help if you have multiple devices on your network, which most
Speaker 19:  people these days have, even if you don't have a smart home. So that can
Speaker 19:  help with speed and connectivity in your home. One
Speaker 19:  key feature to look for when you are considering a buying a
Speaker 19:  router and you want to use Smart home devices is the
Speaker 19:  ability to split your bands and or pause
Speaker 19:  the five gigahertz band because frustratingly still
Speaker 19:  far too many smart home devices rely on the 2.4
Speaker 19:  gigahertz band and they sometimes can't connect your network if you
Speaker 19:  have a door band. So Arrow for example,
Speaker 19:  has a neat option in its settings where you can just disable five gigahertz
Speaker 19:  for five minutes and help onboard your devices.
Speaker 19:  A number of other manufacturers don't offer that option, so that's
Speaker 19:  something to look for. TP link or B
Speaker 19:  net, net gear Arrow, those are all
Speaker 19:  good places to start. Arrow and Google are only going to
Speaker 19:  offer mesh. If you don't think you need mesh, then TP Link
Speaker 19:  Netgear are great brands to look at. We haven't done
Speaker 19:  a awful lot of testing at the Verge, but we have a lot of
Speaker 19:  anecdotal information from our staff based on
Speaker 19:  standalone routers. I've done a lot of mesh testing
Speaker 19:  in the smart home because I believe mesh is really key in the smart
Speaker 19:  home. And I've tested the arrows and the Google Nest wifi
Speaker 19:  and also the new wise router, which has been very good and is
Speaker 19:  relatively inexpensive, which if you're starting out in your first
Speaker 19:  home, I'm guessing budget is probably a large consideration. So I
Speaker 19:  would recommend checking out wisers new routers. I have found them to be
Speaker 19:  pretty reliable. Just don't put it on anything that might melt because they
Speaker 19:  do get really hot.
Speaker 5:  Okay, I, I agree with everything you just said. I think the one
Speaker 5:  thing I was gonna say is that I think it is
Speaker 5:  almost always worth it in my anecdotal experience
Speaker 5:  to go mesh over the other things. I've talked to so many people over the
Speaker 5:  years, especially if you have a slightly goofy layout like a,
Speaker 5:  you sort of have two walls between you and your router at some points a lot
Speaker 5:  of people will buy the extenders and the repeaters and those just don't work,
Speaker 19:  Don't do
Speaker 5:  That. Yeah, it's just, it's a waste of money. Like it, it just, it is worth
Speaker 5:  the slight extra expense to buy the mesh network.
Speaker 5:  And the other part of it is you can buy the basics of the mesh network
Speaker 5:  and then test it for a little while and if you're like, oh I don't have anything
Speaker 5:  in my kitchen you can add to it. So sort of starting small with one of these
Speaker 5:  modular networks as opposed to buying a bunch of repeaters and it's just
Speaker 5:  gonna set you up much better for a much longer time. But
Speaker 5:  I agree with you wholeheartedly. And my last question about this and then
Speaker 5:  we should move on is between the mesh ones, like you were saying, I think
Speaker 5:  for most people's purposes the best thing to do is probably
Speaker 5:  just kind of deal hunt, right? Like I think for an average person's use
Speaker 5:  case, they're all pretty good and the best thing to do is just kind of look
Speaker 5:  out for the one that feels like the right price at the right moment as opposed
Speaker 5:  to like deep progressive brand loyalty. Do, do you agree with that or is
Speaker 5:  there one that you think is drastically better?
Speaker 19:  No, I agree that deal hunting is, is definitely worth doing Euro because
Speaker 19:  it's now owned by Amazon constantly is on major sales and
Speaker 19:  Google Nest often will sort of price match at the same time you'll, you'll
Speaker 19:  notice the sales all happen simultaneously. However, if you are
Speaker 19:  a dedicated Google Home user or a dedicated Amazon Alexa user,
Speaker 19:  there are some benefits. I would say Arrow because I actually
Speaker 19:  is a ZigBee hub for Amazon Alexa Smart Home. So
Speaker 19:  if you're thinking that you are going to want to use that voice assistant,
Speaker 19:  I'll try not to keep saying the name, sorry. If you think you're gonna want
Speaker 19:  to use that voice assistant then Arrow is definitely worth considering.
Speaker 19:  On the Google Nest side, there is similar integrations,
Speaker 19:  although I feel like the Arrow Alexa integration is a lot tighter
Speaker 19:  and it does things like you can turn on in the Alexa settings,
Speaker 19:  the option to automatically look for devices as they join your network.
Speaker 19:  So they just join your Amazon network without you having to do anything,
Speaker 19:  which is a very seamless user friendly setup. I also really like
Speaker 19:  the Arrow app. One of the things that's changed in recent years with these
Speaker 19:  mesh networks is that you control your entire system through an app and
Speaker 19:  that is actually so much easier than having to go onto a web browser
Speaker 19:  and type in your routers code and and start fiddling
Speaker 19:  in the backend. And those apps are much easier to control and you can
Speaker 19:  set up lots of useful features like parental controls, which probably isn't
Speaker 19:  gonna be Hayes's thing right now, but maybe in the future. The one downside
Speaker 19:  of the era one though is once your network goes offline, it's very hard
Speaker 19:  to troubleshoot because everything's through the app and you don't have
Speaker 19:  internet. Oh true. That's been something I have found a bit of a frustration,
Speaker 19:  but these, I'm getting in the weeds a little bit here. I agree with your
Speaker 19:  point. Generally most of these are somewhat interchangeable.
Speaker 19:  Personally I would suggest looking for, for your first router, your
Speaker 19:  first mesh network, don't, you don't need all the bells and whistles, just
Speaker 19:  look for some good security features. Those are gonna be key, especially
Speaker 19:  if you're adding smart home devices and don't think you have to
Speaker 19:  spend the most money to get the best performance. You do want to focus
Speaker 19:  on the speeds that you have coming into your home.
Speaker 19:  There's no point in buying a router that supports, you know,
Speaker 19:  multi gigabit speeds. If you're only getting 500 megabits, you're just kind
Speaker 19:  of wasting your money there. So that's something you need to check with
Speaker 19:  whichever I S P you have. But if you are getting speedy speeds
Speaker 19:  there in Idaho, then you wanna max out as much as possible and and
Speaker 19:  go for multi gigabit speeds, which both APRO and
Speaker 19:  the Google Nest Wifi Pro do offer. And then back to the
Speaker 19:  why's, they also have the Wise Pro, which I believe supports
Speaker 19:  gigabit speeds, but if you don't have gigabit, you can go with the
Speaker 19:  non-pro versions and save a little bit of money.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, got it. All right. Well hey is good luck. Let us know how it goes.
Speaker 5:  Send pictures. We have one more for you before we let you go here Jen,
Speaker 5:  we have a question about doorbells.
Speaker 19:  Yay. My favorite thing, let's
Speaker 5:  Hear it.
Speaker 20:  This is Stephen Robles and I have a question for Jennifer Tuey, your smart
Speaker 20:  home expert just got an ACA G4 video doorbell, would love to
Speaker 20:  know her thoughts on it, maybe a quick review and how does
Speaker 20:  she feel about the whole chime hub situation? Kind of a weird
Speaker 20:  setup. Also, what about matter matter's been out, there's some matter devices
Speaker 20:  out there. Do we still care about matter? Can it actually do anything for
Speaker 20:  those of us just in the home kit space? Thanks a lot.
Speaker 5:  Okay. We're not talking about matter because we don't Darn, we don't have
Speaker 5:  time. We will do that another day. We're gonna come back to matter. This
Speaker 5:  has to end at some point, so we're gonna leave matter. We'll do that another
Speaker 5:  time. But you just wrote a long review of the aara G4 video doorbell.
Speaker 5:  So what's the take? Jennifer two, a smart home expert, what do you think?
Speaker 19:  Yes, I did just write a long review and I'm guessing it hadn't posted when
Speaker 19:  Stephen called because Stephen and I have worked together before on podcast.
Speaker 19:  He's actually the host of the Home Kit Insider podcast and I know he just
Speaker 19:  picked up one of these and is probably really anxious to find out more about
Speaker 19:  what I thought about it. And my review is it's
Speaker 19:  a great battery powered doorbell for home kit, but it has
Speaker 19:  some flaws. And one actually as
Speaker 19:  he points out is this chime box, which is an interesting workaround
Speaker 19:  and I, I guess is a little back story here. There are
Speaker 19:  no battery powered doorbells that support Apple Home
Speaker 19:  and Home Kit secure video, which is Apple's version of
Speaker 19:  a sort of cloud storage for your videos but your own
Speaker 19:  iCloud. So you don't, you're not sharing your data or worried about
Speaker 19:  having your data in someone else's cloud. It's in your own I iCloud. And
Speaker 19:  so it's a very popular service because people obviously have concerns
Speaker 19:  about videos going into the cloud and
Speaker 5:  Correctly. So as we've seen over time
Speaker 19:  Correctly, so Home Kit Zuki video CIR navigates that
Speaker 19:  and provides a very secure, as the name implies, a
Speaker 19:  way of using a video doorbell. But you've only ever
Speaker 19:  been able to use a wire at once. You had to have doorbell wires, which you
Speaker 19:  know is is tricky. A lot of, I'm sure Hayes, back to our last question.
Speaker 19:  You know, you know when you move into an apartment quite often you can't
Speaker 19:  swap out your doorbell or you don't have doorbell wires. Having a battery
Speaker 19:  powered device to stick on the wall would be great. So this was very
Speaker 19:  exciting. Everyone was excited to see a battery powered home kit doorbell,
Speaker 19:  but it turns out the way a Cara got around this because battery
Speaker 19:  powered doorbells are not supported in home kit is they developed a
Speaker 19:  chime box that has to be plugged into power and that is essentially
Speaker 19:  the battery powered doorbell that is connecting to Apple
Speaker 19:  home and then it uses a, a proprietary wireless network
Speaker 19:  to talk to the doorbell, which is essentially just a camera with a bunch
Speaker 19:  of batteries in it. There's nothing else in it
Speaker 5:  That's very clever actually. It
Speaker 19:  Is very clever but the downside is if someone unplugs
Speaker 19:  your chime box, your doorbell stops working as I discovered after someone
Speaker 19:  was vacuuming my house and had to unplugged it to plug in the vacuum
Speaker 19:  cleaner and no my doorbell wasn't working anymore. So you know, you've got
Speaker 19:  a bit of a potential floor there and it doesn't work with your
Speaker 19:  existing chime, which is something a lot of people want. So when you press
Speaker 19:  your battery powered smart doorbell, you'd like your existing
Speaker 19:  doorbell chime to go off as well. It doesn't, which is a bit of a bit of
Speaker 19:  a shame, but it does. What is kind of neat about it, you can stick
Speaker 19:  a microSD card in this little time box and record video locally
Speaker 19:  from your doorbell and then you've got a little microSD card that you can
Speaker 19:  either pop in your computer or you can view through the Cara app and it
Speaker 19:  will record 24 7, which very few doorbells do.
Speaker 19:  Not that everyone really needs that, but personally I love being able to
Speaker 19:  watch the possums go across my front door at night and some reason
Speaker 19:  motion detectors don't catch them.
Speaker 5:  Everybody has their thing. There's like a whole TikTok genre of that I'm
Speaker 5:  sure. Yeah.
Speaker 19:  So yeah, the chime is is an interesting workaround. It's unique in the
Speaker 19:  doorbell space. It's actually very similar to what a lot of door locks use
Speaker 19:  because they don't like, they don't want to use wifi radios in
Speaker 19:  their door locks because it's incredibly battery draining and
Speaker 19:  by using a backup power source that's plugged in, you are able
Speaker 19:  to do the heavy lifting in this separate device. But yes, you need
Speaker 19:  to have it plugged in. That is a bit of a floor. It does though play
Speaker 19:  tunes so you can, you can download an MP3 file to the
Speaker 19:  chime box and then when you come home, cuz it has facial recognition, it
Speaker 19:  can play your theme song as you walk up to the front door.
Speaker 5:  It's like walk up music and baseball but for just life. That's awesome.
Speaker 5:  It is cool. What's yours? What does it play when you come home?
Speaker 19:  It's the Taylor Swift anti-Hero. It's me.
Speaker 5:  It's so good. Oh I like that very much.
Speaker 19:  You know, and so Dave, if you came to my door you could have your own theme
Speaker 19:  song but yeah this doorbell has so many features and as I say, my
Speaker 19:  review, I loved a lot of them. They were great, they were innovative. When
Speaker 19:  I come home and it recognizes my face, it can set the home and my home
Speaker 19:  automation systems to the way I like it, which is really neat. But
Speaker 19:  sadly it has a 16 by nine ratio and this means
Speaker 19:  it can't see packages on your doorstep, which is one of the reasons
Speaker 19:  many people buy video doorbells is to stop potential
Speaker 19:  package thiefs. And so this was a bit of a letdown. The also the video
Speaker 19:  quality was not very good. It's a very inexpensive doorbell though,
Speaker 19:  $120 which in the scheme of doorbells with these
Speaker 19:  types of features is a bargain. So there were definitely trade-offs
Speaker 19:  and the video quality wasn't great in my experience because I have a covered
Speaker 19:  porch and there's no HDR imaging so you couldn't really make out
Speaker 19:  the faces that clearly unless I kind of, you know, stick your face right
Speaker 19:  up at the doorbell, which is not something a package thief is probably going
Speaker 19:  to do. Fair. Yeah, it had some trade-offs but for their first effort at
Speaker 19:  a doorbell it was good. I did like it. I would recommend it if you have
Speaker 19:  Apple home and you need a battery powered doorbell, especially if you want
Speaker 19:  Taylor Swift to sink to you when you come home,
Speaker 5:  That's very important. Yeah, I mean that tricks me is the kind of thing that
Speaker 5:  like good concept probably needs a couple of like
Speaker 5:  little revisions but I like the idea of separating
Speaker 5:  the smarts out of the doorbell itself and into
Speaker 5:  like the chime that actually makes sense to me as a, as a system
Speaker 5:  that you could be more upgradeable over time it'll be easier to replace the
Speaker 5:  batteries and to hang and all this stuff. So I can see why that might be
Speaker 5:  really useful but yeah it seems like it needs a little bit of fine tuning
Speaker 5:  over time.
Speaker 19:  Yeah, I mean it was a, it's a new concept, a new entirely new category
Speaker 19:  for this product as well and for the first attempt I think they did a really
Speaker 19:  good job but there's definitely, as you say, some, some issues to work through.
Speaker 19:  But I do have a very long extensive
Speaker 19:  review on the site if you wanna find out more about all the
Speaker 19:  different features and I actually didn't even mention it does work with
Speaker 19:  everyone else too. It's not just home kit, it works with Amazon's
Speaker 19:  assistant, it also works with Google Home and it can stream to those smart
Speaker 19:  displays and it can use any of those smart displays or speakers as your
Speaker 19:  chime. So even though you can't use your existing chime, you can have
Speaker 19:  your speakers say hey there's someone at the door and you can hardwire it
Speaker 19:  so it has the option of battery or hardwire and you actually need to hardwire
Speaker 19:  it if you want the 24 7 recording cuz otherwise you'll be changing your
Speaker 19:  batteries like every day,
Speaker 5:  Right? Yeah, I mean that's, that's just, this is the life that we leave.
Speaker 5:  I like it. All right, well thank you Jen. We, we should keep rolling through
Speaker 5:  some of these questions but this is very helpful. Thank you.
Speaker 19:  Thank you.
Speaker 5:  All right, let's get to our next question which is about subscriptions.
Speaker 21:  Hey David, this is Vijay. I recently had a bad
Speaker 21:  experience trying to cancel my cable TV subscription service. I was
Speaker 21:  wondering why they make it so easy to sign up but
Speaker 21:  so hard to cancel. You know in this day and age if I can sign
Speaker 21:  up over the phone I should be able to sign out directly, right? And they
Speaker 21:  want me to call to cancel. It was a complicated process. I was
Speaker 21:  wondering why in 2023 we still have to deal with this.
Speaker 21:  Thank you.
Speaker 5:  Okay, the answer to this one is very simple and very frustrating and it's
Speaker 5:  just because they can, there's nothing preventing these companies from
Speaker 5:  making it really easy for you to sign up and really hard to cancel. And so
Speaker 5:  most of them do. The good news is streaming services and such
Speaker 5:  have made it easier over time because there's so much competition. One of
Speaker 5:  the things they have going for them is how easy it is to kind of come and
Speaker 5:  go from a service as you want to. So it's much easier to cancel Netflix or
Speaker 5:  YouTube TV than it is to cancel your cable subscription. So in that sense
Speaker 5:  it's getting slightly better but it mostly still sucks. And the only
Speaker 5:  reason these companies make it hard for you to do is because they can, the
Speaker 5:  FTC is actually in the middle of proposing a formal
Speaker 5:  ban on that. Basically when you call and they say you know, we'll make
Speaker 5:  it cheaper or give you a special deal in order to keep you as a customer,
Speaker 5:  there has to be a thing if this ban goes through upfront where you can just
Speaker 5:  say, no, shut up, leave me alone, I want to cancel and you should be able
Speaker 5:  to get out. And that'll go for things like gym memberships which are notoriously
Speaker 5:  hard to cancel and your cable bill and basically any
Speaker 5:  subscription. For me it's like news organizations are often really hard.
Speaker 5:  You can sign up online but then you have to make 11 phone calls to cancel
Speaker 5:  your newspaper subscription. That kind of stuff might start to get better
Speaker 5:  but the only way it's ever gonna get much, much better is regulation. But
Speaker 5:  the good news is it seems likely that that regulation is coming. It's kind
Speaker 5:  of like robocalls in the sense that it's an easy win for some of these agencies
Speaker 5:  because everybody hates it and it's worth fighting against. So that's
Speaker 5:  that. Stay tuned. It might get slightly better over time. All right, let's
Speaker 5:  move on to our final question for today, which is about laptops, which means
Speaker 5:  we gotta talk to Monica Chin. Hi Monica. Hello. Everybody at turns out has
Speaker 5:  questions about laptops but this one comes from Kevin. Let's hear it.
Speaker 20:  Hi, my name's Kevin. I'm an engineering student and I'm a
Speaker 20:  diehard Apple user. But my friend asked me the other day what kind of laptop
Speaker 20:  you should get and as an engineering student, you know running CAD
Speaker 20:  software, I can't really tell 'em to get a Mac but then I was also like
Speaker 20:  I have no idea what PC to recommend. There's so many
Speaker 20:  options out there. So you know, what would you say for like battery
Speaker 20:  life college student running cat software, what would you say is your topic
Speaker 20:  for a new laptop these days?
Speaker 5:  Okay, so I just wanna say before we get into this to your listeners,
Speaker 5:  if you have a question like this, you gotta tell us your budget. Yeah because
Speaker 5:  that's the first question is how much money do you have to spend? So I would
Speaker 5:  say for our purposes here, let's try to keep it like reasonable, right? Like
Speaker 5:  we're gonna, we're gonna say we have some money to throw at this problem
Speaker 5:  but not all of the money in the known universe. And it seems to me this
Speaker 5:  is like a classic Windows computer problem. It's like
Speaker 5:  power versus portability. Cause like you're still a student, you still wanna
Speaker 5:  do stuff but you also like wanna run the hell out of cad. Where
Speaker 5:  where does your head go? What would you recommend for our friend Kevin here?
Speaker 22:  Yeah so look, I mean looking at the current landscape, this is a tough
Speaker 22:  question and there's not really a great answer to be able to give you that
Speaker 22:  doesn't ask like some amount of compromise, especially if if we're not
Speaker 22:  going into the crazy budget realm. So it depends a little bit on what
Speaker 22:  software your friend is trying to run. I will say, I know I'm not
Speaker 22:  supposed to answer this way, but a lot of good
Speaker 22:  3D software does run on max these days. I
Speaker 22:  know that like not all of it does. If there is a way he can
Speaker 22:  run the software on a Mac if he can he dual boot windows like has he looked
Speaker 22:  into every single option and made absolutely sure that he can't get
Speaker 22:  an Apple silicone Mac because that is really in the current laptop
Speaker 22:  landscape the best way to make sure that you're getting both power
Speaker 22:  and battery life and portability and there really are not a ton of other
Speaker 22:  great options that measure up to that. I will say like
Speaker 22:  one of the more powerful Mac, like with the M two PRO and the M two max
Speaker 22:  or the Mac studio, we've used these with stuff like Maya, like 3D S max,
Speaker 22:  they all run very well on them. These are basically the only, some of the
Speaker 22:  only laptops is if you're looking at the laptop space they would be able
Speaker 22:  to get that can run these programs well that have like any kind of battery
Speaker 22:  life at all.
Speaker 5:  That's the main trade off, right? It's like cuz I think to some extent,
Speaker 5:  you know you can litigate power versus sort of physical size
Speaker 5:  and stuff like that but it seems to me that the main thing is just especially
Speaker 5:  on the window side, if you want a lot of power, battery life is going to
Speaker 5:  go to absolute hell and that that is like the real thing that Mac has solved
Speaker 5:  is being able to do both of those at once.
Speaker 22:  Yeah, I mean that's, that is really the only one that
Speaker 22:  I've tested that I can recommend that I think will not have you
Speaker 22:  needing to plug in like probably at least once a day, if
Speaker 22:  not multiple times. Now I do know that for an engineering student there
Speaker 22:  will be use cases for which running windows on a Mac isn't necessarily
Speaker 22:  gonna be ideal and I know that a lot of engineering departments do recommend
Speaker 22:  that you not get an Apple silicon MacBook. So I understand why
Speaker 22:  you're trying to steer away from that direction. I will say I do know
Speaker 22:  engineering students who use MacBooks who have like no problems with them,
Speaker 22:  but I know that you still may not wanna go in that direction. I do understand
Speaker 22:  that. So as a college student, as someone who went to college,
Speaker 22:  as someone who talks to college students a lot about what their, what their
Speaker 22:  laptop needs are, portability and battery life are really, really
Speaker 22:  huge because if you're gonna be out eight, nine hours a day,
Speaker 22:  you know having to search for an outlet all the time is
Speaker 22:  gonna be a huge pain. Having something really bulky, taking up your entire
Speaker 22:  backpack is gonna be huge pain. If you're going to four to five classes,
Speaker 22:  you may have a ton of other stuff you need to fit in there. So
Speaker 22:  my advice would be is to think about whether having
Speaker 22:  tons of power that can run these graphically intensive
Speaker 22:  applications really, really fast or having
Speaker 22:  battery life that can get you through the day is more important. I think
Speaker 22:  you should, if, if I were in this student's position I would go a little
Speaker 22:  more towards the battery life side just because as I said before, the college
Speaker 22:  lifestyle you're really, really benefited by having a
Speaker 22:  lot of battery life. And the other thing I will say is I think using
Speaker 22:  these programs on a small screen can get get really,
Speaker 22:  really tough just if you have lots of windows open, if you have a lot of
Speaker 22:  little text using those on a 13 or 14 inch screen, it gives me a
Speaker 22:  headache after doing it for a couple hours. I really think they should be
Speaker 22:  looking at at least a 15 if not a 17 inch screen. My best
Speaker 22:  recommendation for something that will give you battery life. And I
Speaker 22:  know you mentioned that that is a priority Yep. For your friend is the LG
Speaker 22:  gram 17 among Windows laptops that I tested last year
Speaker 22:  that showed some of the best battery life that you can get. It's
Speaker 22:  not close to what you get from Apple but compared to most Windows laptops
Speaker 22:  with its level of power, it is a pretty solid contender.
Speaker 22:  The downside is this is not as graphically powerful. It can only come
Speaker 22:  with up to a GTX gpu, which is not like,
Speaker 22:  it is not anywhere close to NVIDIA's top gpu. It can help out with
Speaker 22:  basic graphic tasks and I would expect you'll be able to run the
Speaker 22:  software that you need to. It will be a little bit slower than if you had
Speaker 22:  something with an RTX GPU or way more powerful processor and a
Speaker 22:  big chunk of your laptop. But it is a thin laptop that will be easy
Speaker 22:  to carry and it is light and it will probably give you more decent battery
Speaker 22:  life he'll get from other Windows options if instead you think that's not
Speaker 22:  a GTX isn't enough power for you. And I would encourage your friend to look
Speaker 22:  up if they're not familiar, if he's not familiar, like how much power each
Speaker 22:  of these gps will give him in what exactly he needs. If he thinks he needs
Speaker 22:  an R T X gpu, I would go for the Dell X PS 15 or the Dell XPS
Speaker 22:  17. These are very thin laptops. They're not super, super light, but they
Speaker 22:  are not as chunky as like a giant workstation. These will not
Speaker 22:  get used super great battery life. They do get very hot if you
Speaker 22:  are running super intensive programs on them for long periods of time. But
Speaker 22:  they are quite powerful and I think they will run these
Speaker 22:  programs much faster than you would see in something like the
Speaker 22:  Gram.
Speaker 5:  Okay. What about like money is no object power
Speaker 5:  is more important than anything else. Is there a laptop that's
Speaker 5:  kind of satisfies the brief there on the Windows side that it's like it's
Speaker 5:  still needs to work, right? We're not saying like buy a gaming rig and bring
Speaker 5:  it to Starbucks with you every day, but like on the sort of super powered
Speaker 5:  Windows laptop world right now, is there one that you like
Speaker 5:  more than the rest?
Speaker 22:  Well if you're, if you're going for portability, then I think the XPS is
Speaker 22:  what you want to go for.
Speaker 5:  Okay. But let's just say I need, I need like this much portability and like
Speaker 5:  this much power, you know what I mean?
Speaker 22:  Yeah, I that the XPS is still my answer because any anything else I around,
Speaker 22:  like for example, if portability is not an object and you really want something
Speaker 22:  you can keep on your desk all day and maybe move once or twice, then I would
Speaker 22:  say you could go for something like the Acer concept D easel, which is like
Speaker 22:  a giant like seven pound laptop that has a screen that can fold like
Speaker 22:  seven different ways. Oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I've seen this thing.
Speaker 22:  I love that thing. It's so cool. It's, it's honest. It's one of my, the
Speaker 22:  most fun laptops I've ever tested. I think that would be great for, for
Speaker 22:  engineering students. It can come with, you can get it with a cuadro, all
Speaker 22:  kinds of super powerful chips,
Speaker 5:  But then you're basically the guy who like plugs in the iMac at Starbucks
Speaker 5:  every morning.
Speaker 22:  I mean that's kind of what it is. Like it, it has a stylist you can draw
Speaker 22:  on the screen. It's really, really cool. It comes with like there, there
Speaker 22:  are these like 3D screen options with like glasses free 3D that it comes
Speaker 22:  with. It's so, so cool. If price and portability are no object, that's what
Speaker 22:  I would get. But if you, assuming that you want more portability
Speaker 22:  and less money than that, I think, you know, XPS or the LG gram
Speaker 22:  is what I'd be looking at.
Speaker 5:  All right. I like it. Kevin, let us know what your friend picks and if they
Speaker 5:  like it. Monica, thank you. Appreciate it. You're
Speaker 22:  Welcome. Thank you.
Speaker 5:  All right, that is it for the Vergecast today. Thanks to Alex, Allison, Dan,
Speaker 5:  Monica, Jan for being here and thank you so much for listening. Also, thank
Speaker 5:  you for sending us questions. Like I said at the top, this is my favorite
Speaker 5:  thing to do on this show is talk about your questions and the stuff you're
Speaker 5:  thinking about. So please keep it coming. 8 6 6 Verge 11 is
Speaker 5:  the hotline and you can always email questions to vergecast verge.com. There's
Speaker 5:  a whole lot more on everything we talked about from ein tablets to weird
Speaker 5:  laptops to privacy stuff@theverge.com. We'll put some links in the show notes,
Speaker 5:  but make sure you go check it out. As always, if you have thoughts, feedback,
Speaker 5:  or feelings or bought one of these weird laptops and wanna talk about it,
Speaker 5:  email us vergecast the verge.com. This show is produced by Angel Marino and
Speaker 5:  Liam James Brooke Mentors is our editorial director of audio. The Vergecast
Speaker 5:  is Verge Production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. We'll be back
Speaker 5:  on Friday with a bunch more stuff on all of the news.
Speaker 5:  It just continues to be a weird world in the tech world out there. We have
Speaker 5:  a lot to talk about. We'll see you then. Rock and roll.