# Transcript
ID: 3211b67b-f99e-4a98-ab10-f23c9976fa52
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The next Macs and the next Twitter
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-821351861076060960/-5299873468998278152/s93290-US-5431s-1698400524.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss the next Apple event, a Twitter successor, and Windows Phone regrets.
Speaker 4:  Hello and Welcome. To Vergecast. The flagship podcast of Samsung Decks, powered
Speaker 4:  by Knox, supported by Android. It's real.
Speaker 4:  When you turn on a Samsung phone, the the logos are outta
Speaker 4:  control. Powered by
Speaker 5:  NOx. I mean it has always been thus powered by Android. Nobody is better
Speaker 5:  at logos than Samsung.
Speaker 4:  It's very good. Is
Speaker 6:  Some touch whizz in
Speaker 4:  There? Hi, I'm my friend Eli David. Pierce is here. Hi.
Speaker 5:  We're in the studio together. Yeah, this is very exciting.
Speaker 4:  You can just reach over and smack Alex. He wants.
Speaker 5:  Thank God. Honestly, Alex
Speaker 4:  Franz is here.
Speaker 6:  I'm just really excited to hear Neli talk about Dex.
Speaker 4:  It's a full hour of talking about Dex. That's
Speaker 6:  All we're doing today.
Speaker 4:  There's quite a lot. Apple has a surprise event in Prime time up
Speaker 4:  against Monday night football. That's
Speaker 6:  Choice. That's,
Speaker 4:  That's a real thing that's happening. There's some AirPod leaks,
Speaker 4:  price hikes on services. A real theme of our show lately. David wants
Speaker 4:  to talk about one year of X and I, I believe we're gonna put social
Speaker 4:  networks on the go. 90 scale. We are. In fact it's just gonna be incredible.
Speaker 4:  Yes. And then we got a lightning round including I would say the funniest
Speaker 4:  recurring lightning round element of all time, which is Microsoft
Speaker 4:  executives either bemoaning or being proud of the fact that they killed Windows
Speaker 4:  Strong and the me the needle just swings back and forth between
Speaker 4:  those two things. Right? The same people every couple years.
Speaker 4:  It's coming up on The Vergecast. But first let's talk Dex.
Speaker 5:  Can I just read everyone two messages from Slack? Yeah. That Neli send
Speaker 5:  at 11:28 AM on Tuesday, October 24th. Neli sends, we
Speaker 5:  have a Verge cast room for all of us to make the show. Neli just says
Speaker 5:  also hello from Dex. And then a a moment later I have paired it to
Speaker 5:  a mechanical keyboard. So that's the worst for everyone in this office. And
Speaker 5:  there are two typos of that message. So this, this is
Speaker 5:  now, this is now an important part of my life is tracking your decks
Speaker 5:  situation and in general your ninja train situation. Yeah. Okay. So how are
Speaker 5:  we doing?
Speaker 4:  Here's this here. The basic updates. I have AZ fold
Speaker 4:  five. A really cool Z fold five. It has our D brandand skin on it.
Speaker 4:  So that's cool. It
Speaker 5:  Does look good.
Speaker 4:  It looks really good. Putting
Speaker 5:  Those skins on is not a small amount of work is a thing I discovered. But
Speaker 5:  they do look very cool.
Speaker 4:  It looks very cool. Boy do I dislike this phone?
Speaker 4:  Boy do I just not like it and it's not Android. I like a number of Android
Speaker 4:  phones. Android's great. Specifically trying to use a
Speaker 4:  folding phone for what I'm trying to do is not
Speaker 4:  good.
Speaker 5:  Are you one of those people who's like really mad about the crease in the
Speaker 5:  middle?
Speaker 4:  No, So. I don't mind the crease. Okay. The Z fold five. So the Pixel fold
Speaker 4:  and Z fold five are kind of the same folding display, but they fold in in
Speaker 4:  different directions. Yeah. So and Samsung went with tall, skinny and
Speaker 4:  Google went with short and wide the correct way. Yeah. So
Speaker 4:  using this phone when it's closed is ridiculous.
Speaker 5:  It's a TV remote. Yeah, it's, it just really is and
Speaker 4:  It nothing quite works. Right. And then when you open it you have to use
Speaker 4:  two hands. Yeah, always. Which is fine. So I'm on the train, I got my tablet
Speaker 4:  and it Jelly Scrolls. So the display controller I think
Speaker 4:  is on the left and So, I scroll off my finger on the right. So the left side
Speaker 4:  of the screen moves up faster than the right side of the screen. Oh it's
Speaker 4:  super gross. And so the text, I can just see it go whoop. Yeah. And I can
Speaker 4:  see Dan can't see it. We just argue. We just argued about this in the office.
Speaker 4:  He's like, I dunno what you're talking about. And I was like, I'm on a rollercoaster.
Speaker 4:  I don't, I don't like this.
Speaker 5:  It's such a funny thing. 'cause this is one of those things with phones that
Speaker 5:  we largely solved like back 10 years ago on this show.
Speaker 5:  Like I bet if you go back to Verge casts from like 2013 and 2012,
Speaker 5:  there were a lot of people mad about wonky scrolling stuff on
Speaker 5:  Android phones. And the thing where like you can't scroll and read the text
Speaker 5:  at the same time, which is kind of how I always describe it to people. And
Speaker 5:  we're back at this somehow we're back at, although I will say Nila just
Speaker 5:  opened his phone and got immensely distracted. The scrolling. The scrolling.
Speaker 5:  So Samsung, she doing something right here.
Speaker 4:  It doesn't have a, doesn't have a ringer switch. I had an open it and like
Speaker 4:  monkey with one UI to turn off the ringer. So that's the phone. Yeah. So
Speaker 4:  the first part of this where I just roll up on the train, I've got one device.
Speaker 4:  I don't like using this phone. I understand why it's sick as hell.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. And in that blissful moment when I've got it open
Speaker 4:  and I'm reading the Google doc and someone's like, what is that? That's that
Speaker 4:  rules. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But then I Do you get that? Do you get a lot of like people looking at your
Speaker 5:  rear shoulder being like, well foldable phone on the
Speaker 4:  Train. It's a flashy thing to do to unfold a phone for even in
Speaker 4:  2023 people have seen them but you're still just like, ha whoop.
Speaker 5:  Oh don't mind see this larger. No problem. Just make eye contact
Speaker 4:  As you do that. So that part's cool. Ask
Speaker 5:  For your train ticket. You're just like, one second, let me open up my phone.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And you're always just kind of like in a fight, whatever. But that
Speaker 4:  part is fine. Like it's a phone. It works. It's a good fast Android
Speaker 4:  Samsung phone except I find the display scrolling
Speaker 4:  to be extremely distracting. That might just be me, a noted Pixel density
Speaker 4:  enthusiast might just be me. Some people can't see it. Okay, fine. Then you
Speaker 4:  get to decks. So you roll in the office, you
Speaker 4:  have A-U-S-B-C doc and a Bluetooth mechanical keyboard. And
Speaker 4:  I'm just pulling stuff out of our reviews closet.
Speaker 6:  I like how many keyboards did you go through? Because I kept going in and
Speaker 6:  out of meetings.
Speaker 4:  I'm at, I'm at the third now I'm at a log MX mini or whatever it's called.
Speaker 4:  They
Speaker 6:  Were just stacking up on your desk
Speaker 4:  On it was not great. And I've got a, a razor gaming mouse,
Speaker 4:  like a wired ultra high DPI gaming mouse. Like
Speaker 6:  20 buttons on it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  There's a lot of buttons on the side. All of which appear to be mapped to
Speaker 4:  something in Android for some reason, which is not great 'cause I'm whatever.
Speaker 4:  So you plug in the US PC doc hdm I display, then
Speaker 4:  you get to Dex and then Dan Ds expert,
Speaker 4:  Dan ert
Speaker 5:  The
Speaker 4:  Dexperts
Speaker 6:  The masthead.
Speaker 4:  He told me that you have to install an app called Good Luck.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Which is made by Samsung to ultra
Speaker 4:  customized Samsung one ui. And his characterization of
Speaker 4:  this app is they made this app to get around Google's restrictions.
Speaker 5:  Oh.
Speaker 4:  'cause they have to ship one UI not too far away from
Speaker 4:  Android. Right.
Speaker 5:  Because Google doesn't, because Samsung for a decade completely lost its
Speaker 5:  mind with software design. Right. And tried to shove apps called Milk music
Speaker 5:  at you. Yes. Google was like, stop doing
Speaker 4:  That. So now all that stuff is in good luck. It's called Good
Speaker 4:  Luck.
Speaker 6:  Is milk music in there?
Speaker 4:  Good luck has two tabs at the bottom. Do
Speaker 5:  You think, it sounds like good luck on purpose where they're just like, here's
Speaker 5:  some stuff, good
Speaker 4:  Luck. It's what it feels like. Look, I know there are extremely hardcore
Speaker 4:  Galaxy fans out there who think I'm crazy for only now discovering. Good,
Speaker 4:  good luck. And I apologize, I'm just saying this is an app where
Speaker 4:  at the bottom of the screen, the two tabs are Makeup and Life Up. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And then you can install various plugins. Sick to one ui.
Speaker 6:  Did you life Up?
Speaker 4:  I lifed up a little bit and I installed the plugin that let's decks run
Speaker 4:  at 1440 P. So now I'm running Dex. Yeah. Looking
Speaker 4:  good. Dex runs Android apps. It turns out. So
Speaker 4:  Slack doesn't have a sidebar. So gross. Just like you're just using the
Speaker 4:  Android app wider right. On your desktop. It
Speaker 5:  Desktop computer doesn't like tablet apps. It it just makes of them as many,
Speaker 5:  many, many phone apps.
Speaker 4:  No. So then I, I solve this problem by running Slack as a web app in
Speaker 4:  Chrome in which it is very broken because it's running an Android Chrome
Speaker 4:  and desktop mode.
Speaker 5:  This is the thing
Speaker 4:  About, I was so close to this working. This
Speaker 6:  Is okay. It is the thing
Speaker 5:  About the whole Android and Google universe is it's
Speaker 5:  all there. They've made all the things. Yeah. It's just like they're, they
Speaker 5:  refuse to have the meeting where they're like, what if your thing and your
Speaker 5:  thing both existed in the same place? Yeah. And they're like,
Speaker 5:  we would never do that.
Speaker 4:  So again, Dan's advice to me was treat this like a Chromebook and
Speaker 4:  use Samsung's internet browser because it's better on this than
Speaker 4:  Chrome So I switched to Samsung's browser moderately better.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  It's just not quite there is what I would say. You can see how it
Speaker 4:  would rule
Speaker 6:  Like your, your desktop looked like a very functional
Speaker 6:  desktop from afar. Yeah. When I, when I last saw it, I didn't see
Speaker 6:  a keyboard attached. I just saw you were using the, the phone as a touch
Speaker 6:  pad.
Speaker 4:  Yes, that's true. Before I had a mouse you can just use the, the fold as
Speaker 4:  a touchpad. So that was, that was my touch pad with like my little mechanical
Speaker 4:  keyboard next to it. Green looked,
Speaker 6:  The monitor looked. I was like, oh that looks like a computer monitor with
Speaker 6:  like computer stuff happening. Yeah. That what's normal.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Wait, can we, can we get to the thing you were gonna do in the lightning
Speaker 5:  round, but we should just talk about right now, which
Speaker 4:  Is talk about Metal Gear, Solid You know
Speaker 5:  Delta You know. Yeah you can talk about that in the lightning round. But
Speaker 5:  no, Satya Nadella gave an interview this week to Business
Speaker 5:  Insider in which he, like every other Microsoft executive in history said,
Speaker 5:  giving up on mobile and Windows phone was a mistake. And like You know
Speaker 5:  who could have done a good job at The thing you are describing is
Speaker 5:  Microsoft.
Speaker 4:  They sort of tried, they have tried with
Speaker 5:  The, they're trying now. They stopped trying for a long time. They're like
Speaker 5:  sort of pushing in back in that direction. But like all the stuff you're
Speaker 5:  describing where it's like oh I want a thing that like runs Android apps
Speaker 5:  when it's my phone, but then I sit down and I have something that is much
Speaker 5:  closer to a full desktop operating system. It's like You know who could have
Speaker 5:  built that starting 12 years ago but instead did a bunch of weird shit and
Speaker 5:  then shut all their platforms down and fired their CEO. It's Microsoft All.
Speaker 4:  Right. Let me just read, I'll read you the quote. Here's N Nadella quote.
Speaker 4:  'cause Boyd, does he agree with you? He was asked
Speaker 4:  what about a mistake or a wrong decision that you might regret? Nadella says
Speaker 4:  the decision I think a lot of people talk about and one of the most difficult
Speaker 4:  decisions I made when I became CEO was our exit of what I'll call the
Speaker 4:  mobile phone as defined. Then in
Speaker 4:  retrospect, I think there could have been ways that we made it work by perhaps
Speaker 4:  reinventing the category of computing between PCs, tablets and
Speaker 4:  phones.
Speaker 5:  You're totally right. I read that as him saying there's another category
Speaker 5:  of devices that we didn't do, didn't think about. But
Speaker 5:  he's definitely saying there is a version of a phone that
Speaker 5:  is kind of all of those things and we should have built it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Or we or he is hinting that they're gonna try yet again. Sure.
Speaker 6:  But they aren't
Speaker 5:  PAOs Panay. He tried so hard.
Speaker 6:  Well that's not gonna happen. They just get, because they
Speaker 6:  either have to do Android or they have to do the thing everybody else has
Speaker 6:  to do, which is build an entire OSS from scratch.
Speaker 4:  Look, I'm just gonna say this directly to, to our friend Satya Nadella. If
Speaker 4:  you're listening Satya, you made the right decision. It was
Speaker 4:  strategic catastrophe to buy Nokia. Yeah. And then to do Windows
Speaker 4:  phone instead of, it looked
Speaker 6:  Cool though. It
Speaker 4:  Was all stupid.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. The bad calls were made before him.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. He was just like, You know what the platform is on fire into the ocean
Speaker 4:  with you. Yeah. That is a very deep cut. I'm not gonna explain it, but for
Speaker 4:  the people who Gannett into the freezing Finish Ocean with you
Speaker 4:  is basically what Sachin Nadella said much to these people. Pretty much.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And that's, I think that was fine. I think the company's doing much
Speaker 4:  better. What I think he's hinting at here is, and we're gonna talk about
Speaker 4:  Humane later too. Yeah. There's like suddenly a bunch of people are like,
Speaker 4:  what comes after the phone? And there's a lot of action around what comes
Speaker 4:  after the phone. Mostly because none of these people have businesses I was
Speaker 4:  say,
Speaker 5:  Takes
Speaker 4:  30% away from them
Speaker 5:  Who say all of that are not Apple and not Google really like phones.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's just, there's just a lot of heat around what comes after the phone
Speaker 4:  again comes up every so often and this is when the pendulum swings
Speaker 4:  for Microsoft executives to, oh should we have quit on the phone?
Speaker 4:  And like a year ago you asked Della this question and he was like, that was
Speaker 4:  the best decision I've ever made is getting away from this dinosaur and saying
Speaker 4:  we sell services across everyone's platforms.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean I think in general Alex, I think you're right that this
Speaker 5:  is never gonna work and Microsoft to be foolish to try now. Yes. And I think
Speaker 5:  has been foolish to try really for the last five years to start building
Speaker 5:  towards that again. But I do think there's a really interesting tech
Speaker 5:  history alternate universe. Yeah. In which we tried to do this. Right.
Speaker 5:  Because I think even if
Speaker 4:  I'm holding people trying to do it, even if DS
Speaker 5:  Were
Speaker 4:  Amazing, I unfolds into a bigger screen. Have you seen it? It's amazing.
Speaker 5:  Even if Dex were amazing, I don't think there's ever gonna be a mainstream
Speaker 5:  use for it because it's just not how we've like learned to use technology.
Speaker 5:  It's just not how It works.
Speaker 4:  Well. So here's the actually be, besides all the little problems in the
Speaker 4:  software, there's one deeply hilarious problem with this entire
Speaker 4:  approach to having just one thing. I come to the office,
Speaker 4:  the whole point of this is I don't have a desk anymore. If I had a desk,
Speaker 4:  I just put a laptop on the desk and I would leave, which is what I did for
Speaker 4:  years. But now, because we're like roaming desks, hybrid work, da da da So,
Speaker 4:  I don't have a desk. So I'm like, I, I can't just leave my laptop on this
Speaker 4:  like hotel desk would steal then I have to get up.
Speaker 4:  I know
Speaker 5:  I would,
Speaker 4:  I have to get up and go to meetings all the time where having my computer
Speaker 4:  is often useful and instead of this little guy, I'm just
Speaker 4:  like, me, me, me, me. What am I doing? Nothing
Speaker 5:  Cooler than sitting on your phone in a meeting being like, no, I'm taking
Speaker 5:  notes on the meeting. Don't worry. Everybody's like,
Speaker 4:  Open the spreadsheet with my little folding phone and laptop mode. Like this
Speaker 4:  is the worst. Yeah. So anyway, I'm gonna, I'm gonna try this for another
Speaker 4:  week just for the comedy of it all. And because I, I feel like I should write
Speaker 4:  down some of these experiences Agreed about the future of computing and
Speaker 4:  jolly scrolling to be quite honest. And then I think my, my
Speaker 4:  solution is gonna be, I'm just gonna leave my laptop in the reviews closet
Speaker 4:  where I found this one. That
Speaker 5:  Feels right. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And then we'll I'll just buy another computer for home. Okay. And
Speaker 4:  that's the real solution to this phone. Your
Speaker 5:  Homework for next week though is you're not allowed to bring your laptop
Speaker 5:  to The Vergecast. You have to do The Vergecast. Ooh. From with only
Speaker 5:  your, you can bring your whole damn deck setup. If you want to
Speaker 4:  Bring, bring the mechanical
Speaker 5:  Keyboard, bring the razor mouse, no laptop allowed next week.
Speaker 4:  You do not want me to bring a mechanical keyboard to the ver Chest.
Speaker 5:  I mean I do
Speaker 4:  For our audience's sake alone, you do not want that amount of noise in this
Speaker 4:  room.
Speaker 6:  Our audio engineer would not be a fan.
Speaker 4:  Now he can AI it right out.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's no problem. NVIDIA's got a thing for
Speaker 4:  That All. right. Let's talk about some actual news. There's a bunch of actual
Speaker 4:  news. We should start with Apple 'cause there's a bunch of Apple News including
Speaker 4:  an event. Yep. So there was some rumor
Speaker 4:  buildup late last week, early this week that Apple's gonna have some max.
Speaker 4:  A lot of people didn't believe it. 'cause we're just,
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 4:  Late in the year. It's late in the year. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We have passed the point typically where Apple is commonly going
Speaker 5:  to release products and there have been some rumors that there were gonna
Speaker 5:  be no iPads for the rest of the year and no max for the rest of the year.
Speaker 5:  And then Apple did the thing where they launched that stupid pencil that
Speaker 5:  we talked about last week. So everybody was like, okay, well if they were
Speaker 5:  gonna have another event Yeah. Where they were gonna launch the pencil, why
Speaker 5:  would they do this this way? I think it's just 'cause it's stupid. They wanted
Speaker 5:  to Gannett outta the way. So yeah, there were a lot of good reasons to think
Speaker 5:  there wasn't gonna be an event. And then all of a sudden out of nowhere we
Speaker 5:  have an event. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So Monday night at night. Yeah. The night before
Speaker 4:  Halloween it's called Scary. Fast. That's the
Speaker 4:  name on the invite. Streaming only. And we believe it's gonna be
Speaker 4:  Max.
Speaker 5:  We assume it's gonna be Max because it's like the most likely thing. And
Speaker 5:  there's been some reporting about it. The M three we think coming to
Speaker 5:  MacBook Pros. Okay. Yeah. And potentially a new 24 inch iMac. All of that
Speaker 5:  stuff is kind of overdue.
Speaker 6:  No. 27 inch,
Speaker 5:  Which drives me insane.
Speaker 4:  I think there John, John Gru believe believes it'll be a 27 inch.
Speaker 5:  I hope So I think John Gruber might be the witch casting. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Which is a term that I love very much. I hope he's right. I really
Speaker 5:  do. But yeah, the, the 24 inch iMac is pretty overdue for
Speaker 5:  an update at this point. And I think the 27 inch iMac is just the studio
Speaker 5:  display and the Mac Studio. Now I think that's how Apple sees it. It's wrong.
Speaker 5:  And I hope they changed their mind. But yeah, that and MacBook Pros, which
Speaker 5:  doesn't really seem like it merits a whole event. They don't seem to
Speaker 5:  have invited anybody to this. It's a purely
Speaker 4:  Virtual, here's what I believe event, here's what I believe about this event.
Speaker 6:  I've heard this theory already.
Speaker 4:  Apple is looking at its own streaming numbers. They know it's probably
Speaker 4:  just chip bumps to existing form factors. A reasonable guess. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 4:  And they know that people will watch their events no matter what. So
Speaker 4:  they're gonna do a primetime infomercial that millions of people are gonna
Speaker 4:  watch. And it's just gonna be a weird spooky Halloween themed TV
Speaker 4:  show about the Mac.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I have several questions. Yeah. Question number one, does Tim Cook
Speaker 5:  come out in costume?
Speaker 6:  Yes. Frankenstein or Frankenstein's Monster.
Speaker 4:  You think he's gonna be Frankenstein's monster? Like
Speaker 6:  I just wanna see, I mean mainly because I wanna see Tim Cook with like a
Speaker 6:  green face just like presenting products. 'cause
Speaker 6:  it'd be funny.
Speaker 4:  What do you think the maximum amount of costume Tim Cook would wear is probably
Speaker 4:  not, I think about this 'cause my, my parents are coming this weekend to
Speaker 4:  do our first Halloween with Max in the new town. And I told my mom, I was
Speaker 4:  like, I'm gonna buy you costumes. And she was, she just made this noise
Speaker 5:  Like,
Speaker 4:  She was like, like, and I was like, okay, what if I just get you like a witch's
Speaker 4:  hat? And she's like, okay, what about a witch's cloak? I got my dad a big
Speaker 4:  silly haggard beard and I'm just seeing how far I can push it. Like how many
Speaker 4:  additional elements I can add. And like suddenly they will just be in
Speaker 4:  full kit and I don't think I'm gonna get there. I think I'm gonna get to
Speaker 4:  two elements and we're gonna stop.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I feel like you can do like hat and beard. Yeah. And that's about as
Speaker 5:  far as you're gonna get. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So what, how many elements do you think we can get on Tim Cook?
Speaker 6:  Oh, I think he goes all the way. You
Speaker 4:  Think, you think he's just a full commit?
Speaker 5:  No, Craig goes all the way. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I know Craig goes
Speaker 5:  All way, way that Craig would be unrecognizable. Craig
Speaker 4:  Full Dracula is my belief.
Speaker 5:  Ooh, that's good. Ooh.
Speaker 6:  With the hair.
Speaker 4:  Because the hair, because you get the big flowy Dracula You know and
Speaker 6:  Like the, the little cavader whatever that, that Dracula always wears.
Speaker 5:  I think Tim Cook is gonna be more like,
Speaker 4:  I want come back to Dracula always wears a Ava.
Speaker 6:  Is it whatever the thing is. He wears
Speaker 4:  Fashion. I only, I only recognize the Blade Dracula. Drake, please
Speaker 4:  continue. Dick.
Speaker 5:  I have Drake. So for Dracula,
Speaker 4:  That's what they call him in this movie.
Speaker 5:  That rules, I think Tim Cook is more like the, like in the office they
Speaker 5:  have a Halloween episode and Jim shows up with a, just a name
Speaker 5:  tag on that says Dave
Speaker 5:  and Dwight's like what are you for Halloween? And he points at it and goes,
Speaker 5:  I'm Dave. I feel like that's about the level of costume out Spectrum Tip
Speaker 5:  Cook. Yeah. He's gonna wear like a full zip instead of a quarter sip and
Speaker 5:  be like Dave Halloween
Speaker 4:  All. right. But this is just my general theory here Yeah. Is that Apple
Speaker 4:  owns a streaming service. They have Hollywood stars and celebrities
Speaker 4:  at their beck and call and they know their numbers. They know they can attract
Speaker 4:  attention on Prime time on a Monday up against Monday night football. And
Speaker 4:  that's gonna be fine for them. So no other company can do this. I
Speaker 5:  Agree with everything you just said. I just don't understand tactically why
Speaker 5:  you would do it for a boring event and not the iPhone.
Speaker 6:  This is, this is what I keep getting stuck on is like
Speaker 6:  why now?
Speaker 4:  So I. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Why, why make your Ultraflex spec bumps to laptops? Unless,
Speaker 6:  Wait. No, no. Tim Cook goes for because
Speaker 4:  Because the stakes are low. They have to, when it's the iPhone,
Speaker 4:  all the analysts have to come, the partners have to come, the
Speaker 4:  stock price has to go up or down. They have to do, we have to be there.
Speaker 4:  The press has to be there and do the hands on, like there's a whole bunch
Speaker 4:  of stuff you gotta do with the iPhone. And they're still veering that towards
Speaker 4:  full infomercial. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 4:  This, if it's just a bunch of spec bumps to a Mac, they
Speaker 4:  don't have to do any of that stuff.
Speaker 6:  Who was the last I I, I was trying to
Speaker 4:  Think about this. So you, you can test the conceit that you can move the
Speaker 4:  event to Prime time. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Right. Whereas if you try it with the iPhone and it flops, you've made a
Speaker 5:  huge mistake. Right. Whereas
Speaker 4:  This is just like, we're just having fun in Halloween. That's interesting.
Speaker 4:  But I think their events are headed inexorably in this
Speaker 4:  direction.
Speaker 6:  Who was the last person to do a primetime infomercial? Because all I could
Speaker 6:  think of was the Victoria's Secret fashion show. And like it's a good,
Speaker 5:  There's a reason
Speaker 4:  If Apple brings out Taylor Swift and Fallout Boy for this thing, it's all
Speaker 4:  of,
Speaker 5:  I mean, what this makes me think of is that event Apple had, Jesus,
Speaker 5:  I dunno five years ago when they brought out the all the Apple TV people.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it was just a parade of celebrities with nothing to show. It was
Speaker 5:  the worst Apple event I remember that ever. We're all just sitting in the
Speaker 5:  room and it was a bunch of people being like, here's a TV show we're talking
Speaker 5:  about making remember, do you have anything to show us? And then they like
Speaker 5:  had a couple of trailers at the end, but it was just a lot of like Camille
Speaker 5:  Najani being like, I might make a TV show.
Speaker 6:  Remember there was one like an acting exercise and they were like, listen
Speaker 6:  to the wind. Yeah. The theater.
Speaker 5:  Some
Speaker 4:  Deeply, this was before they had shows. They didn't show a lot of trailers.
Speaker 4:  They, they were just like, Oprah's here. And she's like, they're in a billion
Speaker 4:  pockets. Right.
Speaker 5:  And the pitch was, look at all these celebrities who will do stuff with us.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I would guess if you're gonna do something like this again, I would
Speaker 5:  not be shocked if there are musical guests, which Apple really hasn't done
Speaker 5:  in a while. If there are
Speaker 6:  Lots of Heidi celebrities, what Kme is there?
Speaker 5:  It's just because
Speaker 6:  Goes
Speaker 5:  All out. It's a Victoria's Secret fashion show. No,
Speaker 6:  No. She goes all out for Halloween. Like remember the year she dressed as
Speaker 6:  a worm?
Speaker 4:  Tim Cook there with a, a name tag that says Dave and then it's Heidi Klum
Speaker 4:  in full Worm.
Speaker 6:  That's all. Like, that's This is how you tv.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. See this is how you make a spectacle on television. I think I watched
Speaker 4:  that. This is just my theory. It could just be a, a bogged standard Mac
Speaker 4:  event. I just think if you're gonna program something of this in prime time
Speaker 4:  the night before Halloween course, you definitely have CVAs. That's,
Speaker 4:  that's a given. Yeah. But I think the most important piece of the puzzle
Speaker 4:  is like, does Apple think that it is primetime entertainment?
Speaker 5:  Oh, I absolutely think it does. Yeah. No. Hundred percent. I I think that's
Speaker 5:  right
Speaker 4:  Because you, you have to believe that about yourself in order to attract
Speaker 4:  eyeballs at this time. And I think they'll be successful. I think a lot of
Speaker 4:  people are gonna watch this thing. All of us are gonna be weight on Pin pins
Speaker 4:  and needles success for 27 inch max, 27 time max. There's only
Speaker 4:  one metric of success. That's true. Do I buy a new 27 inch iMac? Well,
Speaker 6:  No. If they do it at primetime, are they truly competing, competing with
Speaker 6:  primetime tv? Are we gonna see like, like is that what we need to measure
Speaker 6:  them against or just other Apple events? Like do we need to measure them
Speaker 6:  against money?
Speaker 4:  Well, there's no measure. I have no idea how many people watch that.
Speaker 5:  You see like the concurrent numbers on YouTube or whatever. But that's only
Speaker 5:  part of it. I think there's been a bunch of interesting news this week. Like
Speaker 5:  Apple TV plus got more expensive as a lot of their services did. There was
Speaker 5:  the news from Bloomberg that Apple is making yet more effort to
Speaker 5:  consolidate everything into the TV space. It just feels like we are definitely
Speaker 5:  at this moment where Apple is trying to flex itself as an entertainment company.
Speaker 5:  And I think the idea that it's, it's going to treat its stuff as like
Speaker 5:  huge TV and they're gonna start to have like Apple event upfronts I think
Speaker 5:  is like not true. But there's definitely a thing that's happening that Apple
Speaker 5:  believes everyone will pay attention no matter what it does. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I still don't understand why that leads you to say, let's do this at 8:00 PM
Speaker 5:  Eastern on a Monday night. Just 'cause we can like Yeah, that's weird.
Speaker 5:  But I think it'll work like it, it's, it's gonna work in the sense that a
Speaker 5:  lot of people are going to pay attention because people always pay attention
Speaker 5:  because it's Apple. And the funniest part of this is no other company has
Speaker 5:  been able to get to where Apple was like 10 years ago in terms of making
Speaker 5:  their events an event. Sony tried really hard for a long time. Samsung continues
Speaker 5:  to try.
Speaker 4:  Sony did have Taylor Swift. I just won't put that out there. That's the
Speaker 5:  Bar. Yeah. Sony literally had Taylor Swift.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But it wasn't good. It was like deeply uncomfortable.
Speaker 4:  It was it They were doing three D TVs. It was not like a great time.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They said look at the tv. Taylor Swift is on instead
Speaker 4:  Of Taylor Swift, instead
Speaker 5:  Of looking at
Speaker 6:  Taylor Swift. Swift. And she wasn't like Taylor Swift yet. She was like Taylor
Speaker 6:  Swift.
Speaker 5:  Taylor Swift has always been Taylor Swift. Oh.
Speaker 6:  But there's like different degrees.
Speaker 4:  I'm so afraid
Speaker 6:  I'm so
Speaker 4:  Swift. There was this conversation where
Speaker 6:  I confused her with Jessica Simpson and that's where she was at. Then you,
Speaker 5:  That feels like a problem. I
Speaker 4:  Why you? I'm worried about your physical safety.
Speaker 6:  I love Taylor Swift. I'm a huge fan of the Aras Tour.
Speaker 5:  The the cool move for Apple because it's going against Monday night football,
Speaker 5:  would be to bring Taylor Swift and Travis Kelsey. That's how you won up
Speaker 5:  Sony.
Speaker 4:  You
Speaker 5:  Get them to publicly announce their relationship.
Speaker 4:  So we think it's chip bumps. We're not doing that.
Speaker 6:  No, it's, it's, I like this plan better.
Speaker 4:  It's Tim Cook is dressed up as Taylor Swift
Speaker 5:  And Craig is Travis Kelsey.
Speaker 4:  You see what I'm saying? It's, and it is a very obvious
Speaker 5:  One. All. right? Well we figured it out.
Speaker 4:  We figured it out. So we think we, we think we're getting m threes and MacBook
Speaker 4:  Pros. We think we're getting a 24 inch iMac refresh. We'll see.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Then there's some other stuff leaked. Germin had new
Speaker 4:  AirPods. Apparently the third gen AirPods are not selling well people are
Speaker 4:  just buying the cheaper older ones. 'cause if you're in that middle, why
Speaker 4:  not go all the way to the pros is basically my feeling. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think there are basically two kinds of AirPod buyers right now. There
Speaker 5:  are people who buy the newest pros because they're the best ones and they're
Speaker 5:  very good. And there are people who buy the thing that goes on sale at Costco.
Speaker 5:  Yep. Yep. I am the person who bought them on sale at Costco. I literally
Speaker 5:  could not tell you what generation of AirPods I have. And I don't care because
Speaker 5:  they're AirPods. Right. I don't like the pros because I don't like the sticking
Speaker 5:  them in the ear canals. That just feels bad in my ears. But I think that's
Speaker 5:  the case now. There's, they have entry level AirPods and new pros and
Speaker 5:  anything in between. I
Speaker 4:  Don't know that there's, there's yet another kind of buyer. Okay. And I have
Speaker 4:  seen them. And it's not Costco. It's the people who buy the knockoff AirPod
Speaker 4:  Maxes at Home Depot, which are just in the middle of the store at
Speaker 5:  Home Depot.
Speaker 4:  I see, I see. People pick this. I met, we bought a new house, I mean Home
Speaker 4:  Depot every weekend.
Speaker 6:  That's where you live now.
Speaker 4:  It's just like where I'm going. And I watch people walk by this display
Speaker 4:  of knockoff AirPod Maxes at the Home Depot and they pick up the box
Speaker 4:  and I look at them and I, I've seen at least two people do like a
Speaker 4:  furtive look around. 'cause 'cause they know, and then they walk
Speaker 4:  away with the box and I'm like, oh. All the, there's a lot of people on the
Speaker 4:  New York City subway wearing the Home Depot Bare Black Maxes. Wow. And I
Speaker 4:  don't even know like why is Home Depot allowed to sell how fully counterfeit
Speaker 4:  products? But it's happening every weekend. I see this. They're like 20 bucks.
Speaker 4:  Like David's scrolling through them right now. Okay. I
Speaker 5:  I can, I can offer you a pair of a hundred dollars skull candies
Speaker 5:  or I can offer you a $20 pair of Zoomy sound play wireless
Speaker 5:  over ear headphones. They
Speaker 4:  Look exactly like AirPod
Speaker 5:  Maxes for 1997. And do look alarmingly.
Speaker 4:  I'm telling you on the New York City subways, a lot of people are wearing
Speaker 4:  $20 Home Depot. AirPod Maxes. This
Speaker 6:  Lady's just vibing. She's having a great time.
Speaker 5:  Neli, I have great news. They have HD sound for an immersive music experience.
Speaker 4:  This is, I'm just telling you, I think there's, I think this is a third category.
Speaker 4:  You've got the people, you've got the two categories of AirPod buyers. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And then, and then you have the whatever that looks fine. It looks
Speaker 4:  like the thing Oh sure. That's expensive. And I,
Speaker 5:  That's why like you, you go to Walgreens and they just like sell headphones
Speaker 5:  in line and it's like who buys these? And it's like some, some people buy
Speaker 5:  them.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And So I. I think that those middle, the third gen AirPods, like the
Speaker 4:  good ones in the middle. I think Apple expected those to be the big seller.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But actually you're, you're being squeezed by Home Depot on the bottom
Speaker 4:  and at the top people actually give a shit and they're gonna buy the best
Speaker 4:  ones. Right.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. No, I think that's right. But I do think it's exciting to see, frankly
Speaker 5:  Apple like continue to push what AirPods can be. 'cause it sort of seemed
Speaker 5:  like for the last couple of years they were just like, well we won.
Speaker 5:  AirPods are like everywhere. Everybody has them. You either have AirPods
Speaker 5:  or you have the other ones.
Speaker 4:  But the problem is they're now commodified.
Speaker 5:  Yes, exactly. And now it's like they're, they're pushing on some of the stuff.
Speaker 5:  I think the new ones supposedly are gonna get, they're gonna have
Speaker 6:  Shorter noise cancellation, which is very upsetting if you like
Speaker 6:  to use Bluetooth headphones for audio stuff. Like for talking Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I had like longer stems.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I want, I was like, I, that was the part I was like, no. At my, my
Speaker 6:  desk. I
Speaker 5:  Would like AirPods that are basically like dental headgear that kind of go
Speaker 5:  all the way down around your chin. It's just one piece.
Speaker 4:  Wow.
Speaker 5:  Is a good idea.
Speaker 6:  Get the Ray band metas. That's what you
Speaker 4:  Do. They still make neck buds. Those like things that you
Speaker 5:  Were Oh yeah. You can still get 'em back buds.
Speaker 4:  That's you baby. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  The Walgreens checkout counter where you
Speaker 4:  Get those All. right. So that's the, we we don't know when that's happening,
Speaker 4:  but they're coming. Yep. You see them reinventing that lineup because
Speaker 4:  I, I think wireless earbuds total commodities now. Yeah. They have to keep
Speaker 4:  pushing 'em up. Alex you, we've been talking about price hike with you
Speaker 4:  I think every week now it's like, it's another one. Throw a dart at the board
Speaker 4:  of streaming services and it's like the price is going up 9 99
Speaker 4:  for Apple TV plus. Yeah. Seems very high.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I really enjoy Apple TV Plus there's one show on it that's one
Speaker 6:  of my top 10 shows of all time. I'll watch it like every six months. It's
Speaker 6:  like my office.
Speaker 5:  I think Apple TV's hit rate is higher than any other stream service.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But it's also got 12 shows. I mean
Speaker 4:  No, it's got more now. It's got more now, but I disagree that it's hit rate
Speaker 4:  is higher. Really? I think it has hits, which is unlike other streaming
Speaker 4:  services.
Speaker 6:  Is this because you watch the Octavia Spencer show and it's not very good.
Speaker 4:  Most of the show. That's what I mean. They make a lot of
Speaker 4:  brilliantly produced excellent looking nothing c Yeah.
Speaker 4:  See a show in which if you just go look at the Reddit for the show C
Speaker 4:  starring Jason Momoa, the most common question in that Reddit is
Speaker 4:  can they see? Because the show is not committed to its own
Speaker 4:  conceit.
Speaker 6:  It's complicated guys. It just depends on who, which character you're talking
Speaker 6:  about. But it
Speaker 4:  Is beautiful.
Speaker 6:  It's beautiful. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But are you looking at the Reddit?
Speaker 5:  No, no. I'm looking at the, I mean I, I honestly, I stand by this like,
Speaker 5:  there are very few disaster shows on
Speaker 5:  Apple
Speaker 6:  Tv. That's true. That's true.
Speaker 5:  Everything on there with the exception of the morning show, which is full
Speaker 5:  honest to God garbage.
Speaker 4:  No, it's, wow.
Speaker 6:  It's it's a soap opera. It is so soap opera, so
Speaker 6:  melodramatic that like we know where Reese Witherspoon
Speaker 6:  was on January 6th.
Speaker 5:  It
Speaker 6:  But like that's a spoiler. I'm so sorry. It
Speaker 5:  It's, it's just like, what if you spent all the money in the world to make
Speaker 5:  a soap opera?
Speaker 6:  Yes. That's why I love it. I'm like, wow, we're finally getting prestige
Speaker 6:  show soap operas. But but yeah, there the prices are
Speaker 6:  $10 a month is, is hard to, to stomach. Especially one of our
Speaker 6:  commenters after we put the story up, just broke it down. And by percentages
Speaker 6:  Apple TV is going up about 43%. Wow. Apple Arcade is
Speaker 6:  40%. Apple News is 30% overall average. It's 37%.
Speaker 6:  Does it feel like you're getting 37% more service? I
Speaker 5:  Would say can I get a 37% raise?
Speaker 6:  Gotta gotta maintain no sense.
Speaker 4:  No. Only if you're bundled with three other people.
Speaker 5:  To me, what's very obvious here is Apple is trying to get everybody to subscribe
Speaker 5:  to Apple One.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no, you can see it. Yeah. The Apple one is only going up five bucks.
Speaker 4:  Apple one Premier for families is going up five bucks.
Speaker 5:  And if you use Apple Arcade and Apple
Speaker 5:  TV plus that's that price right there. Done. Everything else is
Speaker 5:  gravy. You could all have Apple Services. Like it's so transparently a better
Speaker 5:  deal to be on Apple one than to be on some other missed patch of their
Speaker 6:  Services. Only became a, a better deal. Like this program like right now.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Yeah. Because, because I was actually trying to switch
Speaker 6:  over to Apple one like two or three weeks ago and I did all the math and
Speaker 6:  I was like, well I don't use some of this stuff. Right. So I'm not gonna
Speaker 6:  do this.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. If you like, if you use News Plus and fitness and all of that stuff,
Speaker 5:  it's been a better deal for a while. But right now it's like if you use two
Speaker 5:  things,
Speaker 6:  It's a much better deal. It's better. Yeah. Now I'm really
Speaker 4:  Mad. I have to say, there's no way anyone should pay
Speaker 4:  1299 a month for Apple News Plus. No,
Speaker 5:  That's absurd.
Speaker 6:  Someone out there is doing it. I mean it's Tim Cook,
Speaker 4:  Someone else. I think it's just coming. It's gotta be coming in the bundle.
Speaker 4:  But as an all la cart subscription, unless you are
Speaker 4:  extremely committed to reading PDF's, exterior review, which I am. And
Speaker 4:  that's a bad deal. Yeah. Like that just, that's so expensive.
Speaker 4:  That's more than the TV service. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And you get pay walled news, which is good. Yay for money for the news industry,
Speaker 5:  but there are not very many people for whom that's gonna be worth $13 a month.
Speaker 5:  Just don't see
Speaker 4:  It. Right. And that so that now we're just like fully in the bundle. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Other bit of Apple News. iOS
Speaker 4:  17.2 Beta is out. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  This is the other thing we'll probably hear more about on Monday. I would
Speaker 5:  guess. It's a lot of little things. The big thing is the Journal app is finally
Speaker 5:  coming. I don't know why it took this long. I'm not sure anyone caress
Speaker 5:  that the Journal app exists.
Speaker 6:  I I forgot about the Journal app until you just said that.
Speaker 5:  I think. I think you and a lot of people, but now it's coming. My guess
Speaker 5:  would be, so the developer Beta is out now. My guess would be we'll get some
Speaker 5:  kind of public Beta pretty fast or it'll just hit like it's a 0.2
Speaker 5:  update. It's not Yeah. Ultimately all that exciting. But they will probably
Speaker 5:  talk about the Turtle app on Monday would be my
Speaker 4:  Guess. I don't think So I think it's all, all Max and Gotcha. It's a, it's
Speaker 4:  gonna be a TV show. Yeah. Ooh, ooh.
Speaker 4:  Spooky fast. 27 inches. Just trying to manifest
Speaker 4:  it. And then we have a big story this week about double tap hit the Apple
Speaker 4:  watches. V has a story about how It works, which is pretty cool.
Speaker 6:  It seems really,
Speaker 4:  Really cool. I don't buy that, it can't come to my Apple Watch Ultra, by
Speaker 4:  the way,
Speaker 6:  Or my, my series six
Speaker 4:  Or my series two.
Speaker 4:  But it, it does seem really cool. The one thing that's interesting is you
Speaker 4:  have to have your display on for it to work. Yeah. I hate that.
Speaker 5:  And it doesn't seem to be super reliable. Like it's definitely a work
Speaker 5:  in progress, this feature. But it's a cool idea. And it seems to be
Speaker 5:  like these stories really interesting just in getting into how complicated
Speaker 5:  something like this is to make and just like, if you think about what your
Speaker 5:  hands are doing all the time, it's a noisy Yeah. Input
Speaker 5:  mechanism. So it's, it's just, it was neat to read her story and see all
Speaker 5:  the stuff it takes to do it.
Speaker 4:  I'm, I dunno about you, but I'm constantly clenching my fists
Speaker 6:  Just sitting there like the, the, the meme of Arthur just,
Speaker 4:  Just furious. Bring me Drake. What if they have
Speaker 4:  actual Drake? What if they had Drake dressed up as Dracula? That's my prediction
Speaker 4:  for the Apple event. Everybody there. It's there. It's no 27 inch iMac. Drake
Speaker 4:  dressed up as Dracula.
Speaker 6:  No, no actual Apple stuff at all. It's just gonna be Tim hanging out with
Speaker 6:  his friends. That
Speaker 5:  Would be the true flex. No new products. Yeah. Just hanging out. Or
Speaker 6:  They show off the apple pens. The new pencil. Oh
Speaker 7:  God.
Speaker 6:  Just the pencil.
Speaker 5:  Death first.
Speaker 4:  All. right. We gotta take a break. We're gonna come back and David's gonna
Speaker 4:  execute this idea of putting social networks on the go 90 scale. We'll be
Speaker 4:  right back.
Speaker 7:  Sure.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back on The Vergecast. The show that we make every week.
Speaker 4:  We
Speaker 5:  May have just been watching Blade Trinity.
Speaker 4:  I'm still thinking about Blade Trinity. It's a great movie.
Speaker 6:  It's a really good movie. No, I mean it's a watchable movie. That's
Speaker 5:  It's a movie.
Speaker 6:  It's a movie. You will have a good time watching but you probably
Speaker 6:  won't like earnestly recommend to another person.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So you're just one of those people who really likes bad things. Yes.
Speaker 6:  I like it when
Speaker 5:  A bad thing or like because they're bad. Yeah. You're like, I'm glad that
Speaker 5:  this is terrible and exists.
Speaker 4:  No, it's bad. It's bad in the right way. Right, right. Like, like it's a
Speaker 4:  it's a well made bad movie.
Speaker 6:  It's entertaining. It's just not good. Like the morning
Speaker 6:  show.
Speaker 5:  No. See I disagree with every part of that about the morning show. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  There's some things that are like bad and sloppy and Ill considered and not
Speaker 4:  coherent. Every lifetime movie Blade Trinity is like, they had an
Speaker 4:  idea and they executed the hell of the idea and it just wasn't a
Speaker 4:  good idea.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. All, right? Yeah. That I can appreciate. Yeah. Right. Like you, you
Speaker 5:  executed your whole vision perfectly. Yeah. And you shouldn't have, there's
Speaker 5:  not
Speaker 4:  A, there's not a frame of Blade Trinity where they weren't like, this
Speaker 4:  isn't exactly what I wanted.
Speaker 5:  You just should have wanted something else.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It should have just gone a different way.
Speaker 5:  Understood.
Speaker 4:  All. right. David, you, this is your baby and I believe a a,
Speaker 4:  a listener has requested that we do this. This
Speaker 5:  Was specifically requested. Okay. It's been a year as
Speaker 5:  you're listening to this on Friday, it has been exactly one year since the
Speaker 5:  Elon Musk acquisition of Twitter was made final. Obviously
Speaker 5:  Twitter is no longer both literally and
Speaker 5:  metaphorically it's dead. We've had a year full of new ideas about
Speaker 5:  social. We've had a year of like would be coming and going. We've had a lot
Speaker 5:  of change. We've been talking about it a lot. And So I think what we haven't
Speaker 5:  done a lot of a over the last year is just talk about Twitter
Speaker 5:  as a product. Like we've talked a lot about the machinations of the company
Speaker 5:  and all the weird stuff going on, but like, is it still a good,
Speaker 5:  vibrant, thriving, potentially successful social platform?
Speaker 5:  And it seems like a good time to check in on all of the other ones that
Speaker 5:  are trying to be this thing of which there are an alarming number. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You made some of these up, but an increasingly smaller number. Spoiler alert
Speaker 5:  for what we're about to get to. So what I figured we should do first is just
Speaker 5:  like, let's do, let's do the state of Twitter a little bit a year after
Speaker 5:  Elon Musk. Got it. Took it over. I actually don't think this is gonna take
Speaker 5:  very long because I don't think it's a particularly complicated opinion to
Speaker 5:  have anymore. I think if we'd had this debate three months ago, reasonable
Speaker 5:  people could disagree about the vibrancy of Twitter or X or whatever you
Speaker 5:  wanna call it. I think at this point it is pretty much undeniable and
Speaker 5:  unavoidable that it is a worse platform and a dying one.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But there's a lot of jackasses in the world that really like to use
Speaker 6:  x. Sure. Like what I want is it to be at an 80,
Speaker 6:  but I think the jackass factor brings it down to like a 45
Speaker 6:  or a 50
Speaker 5:  All. right. Well let, let's get to the scale in a sec. Okay. Sorry. 'cause
Speaker 5:  firstly I got excited NE's gonna have to give us a speech about what the
Speaker 5:  Go 90 scale is. Yeah. Sorry. Sorry. A bunch of
Speaker 4:  Disclosures. I have to remind a bunch of people what go 90 is
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be a whole thing. Yeah. But, but I think like at this point
Speaker 5:  I, and I do think the question of is X going to continue to be around for
Speaker 5:  a long time is separate than is it vibrant and
Speaker 5:  cool and useful and like, is it culturally relevant in the way that it was?
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Very
Speaker 5:  Different. I already feel like it is drastically less culturally relevant
Speaker 5:  than it was even 12 months ago.
Speaker 6:  Yes, a hundred percent. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  No, without question. And the, there's a way to measure it. Twitter was never
Speaker 4:  very big.
Speaker 5:  Right.
Speaker 4:  It was always the smallest of the social companies. It was a bad business.
Speaker 4:  I will once again issue our disclaimer. That criticism of
Speaker 4:  X under Elon Musk is in no way praise of Twitter under Jack Dorsey.
Speaker 4:  It was a badly run company. And again, they
Speaker 4:  sold it 'cause they didn't have any ideas on how to make it that valuable
Speaker 5:  Clown carne goldmine.
Speaker 4:  Yep. Yep. That's the Zuckerberg quote about, about Twitter. So bad company,
Speaker 4:  but outsized influence in the media, in sports and politics.
Speaker 5:  I mean, the joke for years that was, that cable news was just host reading
Speaker 5:  to tweets to each other. Yeah. Which was not untrue for a very long time
Speaker 5:  that I don't see anywhere.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's gone. So the the notion that you could solve every problem by
Speaker 4:  tweeting or create vastly more problems than tweeting
Speaker 4:  is gone. Like it's just that sort of over in a big and
Speaker 4:  important and probably healthy way.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Is there even a Twitter person of the day anymore? You know that person.
Speaker 6:  Everybody would dunk on.
Speaker 4:  It's Elon Musk. That's he, it's it's Eternal's. That's what he spent the
Speaker 5:  Money on. It's actually, that's such an interesting point there. Yeah. For
Speaker 5:  so long, you just
Speaker 6:  Knew
Speaker 5:  A random person. There was always like the main character of Twitter and
Speaker 5:  everybody would be talking about it and then you would forget about them.
Speaker 5:  Like the, the bird watching woman is always the first one that comes to mind.
Speaker 5:  Yes. It's just Elon every day. It's
Speaker 4:  Just Elon. Every day his, the reach of his tweets is dramatically increased.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Because he said, make my tweets. Sure.
Speaker 4:  And, and if I bought Twitter I would do the same thing.
Speaker 5:  But then recently, apparently it's gone down. Did you see this? He, he tweeted
Speaker 5:  something in a reply, which is how he tweets a lot. And his stuff
Speaker 5:  gets huge reach because he's Elon Musk and on and on. But then at one point,
Speaker 5:  I might get this slightly wrong, but I think he quote tweeted his own tweet
Speaker 5:  onto his timeline saying, bringing this to my main timeline
Speaker 5:  so that it gets more reach. Yes. I remember that. And it's like, oh, even
Speaker 5:  Elon can't get the view counts anymore.
Speaker 5:  And yeah, it just, I don't know. I, again, I, I don't think we need to like
Speaker 5:  dwell on this forever, but it's, there's just nothing about that
Speaker 5:  product that feels like it has gotten better in 12 months.
Speaker 4:  And there was like a relationship between Twitter's size
Speaker 4:  and its influence that kept it relevant. Yeah. 'cause
Speaker 4:  it was never its size that made it relevant. Yeah. Like TikTok is very
Speaker 4:  relevant because it is huge and
Speaker 6:  Everybody
Speaker 4:  Uses it and everyone uses it and, but it's still pretty insular. Like
Speaker 4:  your average TikTok trend does not break into the mainstream too
Speaker 4:  much.
Speaker 6:  Everybody's gonna be doing that slip slide soon. Just, just you wait out
Speaker 6:  on the streets.
Speaker 4:  Oh, I've seen it with the, the Skippy dance. Yeah. It's
Speaker 6:  A lot. Oh yeah. I tried to do it. Don't do it. You'll die. Did
Speaker 5:  You try to do it had
Speaker 6:  In my house? Tell
Speaker 4:  Us more. I'm I'm at the,
Speaker 6:  That's as far as I got
Speaker 4:  Point in my, my golden years here where I look at something, I'm like, that's
Speaker 4:  that's a young man's game.
Speaker 6:  I'm in my midlife crisis phase. You're
Speaker 4:  Like, I'm skipping. I'm still like,
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  Try. But no, TikTok is really fascinating and just in that way 'cause it's
Speaker 4:  the phenomena are large. Yeah. But they are contained. Yeah. And the
Speaker 4:  whole user base does not see everything by definition. And so
Speaker 4:  TikTok itself has a lot of cultural import individual things that are happening
Speaker 4:  on TikTok are pretty siloed. Twitter was just like, all of Twitter, well
Speaker 4:  now look at this. Right. We'll talk about this. We'll be together, be engaged
Speaker 4:  with this and that for too long that thing was covid. Right. But like, it
Speaker 4:  was the driving force of a lot of that debate. Even it like massive
Speaker 4:  worldwide influence. And now Twitter, even if it keeps the users,
Speaker 4:  the influence is gone. Right. Yeah. And that's the danger. And so the
Speaker 4:  advertisers are leaving. We, we've seen reported the users are
Speaker 4:  fleeing and I, I think Elon's sort of like raging against it.
Speaker 6:  He's just trying to like scream his way out of it, but on online. So it's
Speaker 6:  not as aggressive. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I mean look, he, he take, he took Twitter and he turned it into Parlor.
Speaker 4:  He did it. He did it. Yeah. That's what it is now.
Speaker 5:  And now I, I do wonder there's an interesting, like the, the conspiracy theory
Speaker 5:  has always been that he's trying to just bankrupt it. Like it's the equivalent
Speaker 5:  of like burning your house down for the insurance money. Seems to be Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The, the theory, I don't think that's what he's trying to do. It does seem
Speaker 5:  very clear that what he wants is to build the like
Speaker 5:  finance app and thought he could just bolt that onto Twitter and it
Speaker 5:  would make sense. Yeah. He thought he could just dunno what that is. Convert
Speaker 6:  All of those users and instantly have his app.
Speaker 5:  Right. He's just like, I'll just let Twitter users pay each other and then
Speaker 5:  that's how I'll get my finance super app. I do wonder if this all falling
Speaker 5:  apart might just accelerate his, like, I'm gonna go make PayPal again. Plans
Speaker 5:  So. I think like X is already very different than it was 12 months ago. I
Speaker 5:  have a feeling 12 months from now it's gonna be even more
Speaker 5:  unrecognizable to what it was when he bought it. Well, because in a bunch
Speaker 5:  of weird directions
Speaker 6:  By that point, we'll all be paying a dollar just to have an account on it.
Speaker 6:  And so none of us will have an account on it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Truly one of the most hilarious
Speaker 4:  Or the European government will find it out of existence. Yeah. I that it,
Speaker 4:  but the thing that is just obvious to me one year in, is
Speaker 4:  it the cultural relevance of Twitter? That everyone is gonna talk about it,
Speaker 4:  that the news will be driven about it, that the politicians are worried about
Speaker 4:  it, that you name it
Speaker 5:  Gone. Yep. And I think the, the thing that most immediately accelerated
Speaker 5:  that recently was what's going on with Israel and Hamas
Speaker 5:  and all of the misinformation stuff that was happening, like the, the flooding
Speaker 5:  of people out of Twitter and into new platforms
Speaker 5:  really took off in a big way just in the last few weeks, which was
Speaker 6:  Fascinating. I thought it was really interesting that everybody flooded out
Speaker 6:  of Twitter and into new platforms. None of which actually also did a good
Speaker 6:  job. Oh
Speaker 5:  No. Everybody, everybody's
Speaker 6:  Like, we wanna figure out, TikTok will tell us the real news.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. God. And there was like a story this week about how TikTok did not
Speaker 6:  in fact do a very good job of it. Yeah. I think New York Times did that with
Speaker 6:  Taylor Lorenz and so like no, nobody just go read
Speaker 6:  the, the news You know
Speaker 4:  There are whole places. The news got it pretty wrong.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The news also got it pretty rough. It's,
Speaker 4:  It's not been a great time. But like if you're starting from a that
Speaker 4:  baseline, right. Which is the New York Times issuing major
Speaker 4:  corrections. Yeah. Well then the secondary information ecosystem
Speaker 4:  is gonna be bad too. And I, we've definitely seen that. And the thing
Speaker 4:  is that Twitter at least in its Jack Dorsey period
Speaker 4:  had an inkling of wanting to be like, neutral.
Speaker 4:  Neutral is the wrong word, but it, it just wanted to be like,
Speaker 6:  There felt like there was a level of like peer review happening on Twitter
Speaker 6:  before where like generally the accurate stuff would, would crawl
Speaker 6:  to the top eventually, or, or the context would arrive and you'd be like,
Speaker 6:  okay, I, I understand what I'm reading here. And that doesn't happen anymore.
Speaker 6:  Where somebody will just be like, yeah, this is crazy, isn't it?
Speaker 4:  I would, I would say it's, it's like the opposite of that, but the word,
Speaker 4:  it's almost like neutral, but it's not neutral. 'cause Twitter was never
Speaker 4:  neutral, but it was, it was never, it was, it was level and there was things
Speaker 4:  that were out of bounds. Yes. And the new version X is like,
Speaker 4:  what if we just amplify the things that are out of bounds? So I, I, and that
Speaker 4:  is a distinct shift in the character of the platform.
Speaker 5:  I actually think it's even simpler than that. Yeah. And I think one of the
Speaker 5:  things that is working for Threads right now is that
Speaker 5:  the people in charge of it are believably trying their best. And I think
Speaker 5:  that was a thing that people believed Twitter for a long time was it was
Speaker 5:  a lot of people trying to do a very hard thing, but generally trying their
Speaker 5:  hardest to do it. Right. Yes. And reasonable people can disagree about. Right.
Speaker 5:  But I think the, the reason Mark Zuckerberg became a bad guy for a long time
Speaker 5:  was that a lot of people believed he was not trying to do
Speaker 5:  good things. And in a truly masterful PR
Speaker 5:  campaign, mark Zuckerberg has won many of those people back. But I
Speaker 4:  Think, wait, the Masteral PR campaign, by the way, is making Adams compete
Speaker 5:  With Elon Musk. No,
Speaker 4:  It's, it's, it's make Adam ery the face of this product. Oh,
Speaker 5:  Absolutely. And I think, I think Adam er and the, the team running Threads
Speaker 5:  has done a really good job of being out there and being present and
Speaker 5:  appearing at least to be trying hard to do the right thing. And it's
Speaker 5:  very clear now that the leadership at X is not Yeah. Interested in
Speaker 5:  what the right thing is. And so it just changes the feeling that you get
Speaker 5:  from being here. Like I am no longer in good hands. And that feels bad.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Which is weird. 'cause these products at scale, all of them have the same
Speaker 4:  incentives. Yeah. Which is to increase engagement and be sticky. Right.
Speaker 4:  But you see Adam constantly try to thread the needle
Speaker 4:  on is there news here or not? And his answer is like, ah, I really don't
Speaker 4:  want there to be, and people are gonna do it anyway, but we are gonna show
Speaker 4:  you other happy stuff. Right. Zuckerberg this week on their earnings call
Speaker 4:  said there should be a text-based social network of a billion people that
Speaker 4:  is more positive. And so you see them, they're actively trying to
Speaker 4:  make it. So you can't talk about Israel and Hamas. You definitely cannot
Speaker 4:  talk about Covid. Which again, I think is a defining moment in the,
Speaker 4:  the Twitter. Yep. This is the thing that broke Twitter the most. We'll see
Speaker 4:  if the other platforms survive, but I that thing where all of
Speaker 4:  the influential people are using one platform and it's crazy and you can
Speaker 4:  just yell at them directly, which is was a delight. Yeah. Is gone. Yep. I
Speaker 4:  do not think it is ever coming back. And
Speaker 6:  I think that's okay.
Speaker 4:  I think that is e easily for the best. Yes,
Speaker 5:  I agree. So, which is a good segue Yeah. To our next bit, which is all of
Speaker 5:  the would be successors. Mila, will you explain the Go 90 Scale
Speaker 4:  All? right. So Verizon started as a video streaming service called Go 90.
Speaker 4:  They were early to the idea of starting a doom streaming service credit to
Speaker 4:  Verizon. We profiled it, you can read that
Speaker 4:  story. But eventually, like all streaming services, it died. It went
Speaker 4:  90. So the scale is the go 90 scale of Doom streaming services, which
Speaker 4:  we're repurposing here for Twitter clones. But the Go 90 scale
Speaker 4:  of Doom streaming services is Zero is alive, zero is
Speaker 4:  alive. And then you can go 90. You can go 90. Yeah. And you can die. Right?
Speaker 4:  Like go 90. You
Speaker 5:  Fall over and die.
Speaker 4:  I encourage you to read this story about Go 90. Ben Papa wrote it. It's a
Speaker 4:  lot of, it's a lot of telecom executives thinking they understand
Speaker 4:  teenagers.
Speaker 6:  I understand that
Speaker 4:  You could join a video crew on Go 90. Yeah. My friends,
Speaker 5:  I just feel like somebody, the minute someone came out of a meeting and was
Speaker 5:  like, we've decided to call it Go 90, whoever that person's boss was should
Speaker 5:  have been like, nevermind. We're not doing strike of service. Yeah. Like,
Speaker 5:  we're out. But, okay. So that's the scale. Let's just start
Speaker 5:  with X. It's a good balancing point to start with. Where do we
Speaker 5:  think, again, remember this is between Fully Alive,
Speaker 5:  crushing it totally vibrant and like full dead. Yeah. Like
Speaker 5:  end of platform gonna be gone. Where do we feel like X is?
Speaker 6:  Okay, I said it earlier, but I think it's gonna be at 80. Like that's
Speaker 6:  where it should be. But I think it has such a high like kind of jackass
Speaker 6:  quotient on the platform right now that it's more like a 50 to
Speaker 6:  45 at the moment.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I would say 45. It's at a 45. Yeah. Right. Dab in the middle. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  For a lot of people it's an 80. It's, it's like most people, it's an 80 almost,
Speaker 6:  but there's just enough that it's like a, it's
Speaker 5:  Four, five. Yeah. My instinct would be to put it a little higher except a,
Speaker 5:  like you're saying, never underestimate the number of people who are the
Speaker 5:  worst. And B, these things just take longer than we give them credit for.
Speaker 5:  Right. Like, I spent a lot of time thinking about the people who still pay
Speaker 5:  for AOL that they got on discs. It's like that stuff doesn't die as
Speaker 5:  quickly as we think it does. We stop talking about it and most people move
Speaker 5:  on. But like most things die slow. Yeah. And I think
Speaker 5:  Twitter has begun what is probably like the inexorable slow
Speaker 5:  death, but it has not died. So I, I think that's right. 45. Somewhere
Speaker 5:  in the 45 range feels about right. Yeah. Where do we put Threads? Which,
Speaker 5:  so the Threads news this week was also on the earnings call. Like you were
Speaker 5:  saying, Neli, they announced that Threads has almost a hundred million monthly
Speaker 5:  active users. What does almost mean in this context? Who knows? But it's
Speaker 5:  a big number. The number has been growing. All the people whatever, two months
Speaker 5:  ago who were like, Threads is struggling to keep users, have less to say
Speaker 5:  Now Thread seems to be doing fine. Where do we put it on the list?
Speaker 4:  45.
Speaker 5:  Really?
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Why?
Speaker 4:  I put just like a different color of 45. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 4:  You know.
Speaker 6:  Happy 45. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's like, it's a happy 45. Like happy 45. Most products
Speaker 4:  fail. I don't, there's, that's just the nature of them. Most
Speaker 4:  new products just fizzle out. Meta has launched a lot of products.
Speaker 5:  I was just about to say. Yeah. So the, the case for and against Threads
Speaker 5:  is that it's Meta. Yeah. My immediate instinct for Threads is to put it at
Speaker 5:  like 25 because a Zuckerberg is out here now saying
Speaker 5:  we see a path to a billion users, which is what he's been saying all along.
Speaker 5:  I think he's enjoying this competition. I think he likes how much Threads
Speaker 5:  has made him the good guy. And I think that's gonna buy Threads a pretty
Speaker 5:  long runway. Threads also I think seems to be working like we're gonna get
Speaker 5:  to a bunch of other ones, but Threads is, Threads
Speaker 4:  Has the heat.
Speaker 5:  It has the heat. That's exactly right. And I think that can be
Speaker 5:  fickle, but it very much has the heat right now. Yeah. So, I.
Speaker 5:  I would put it lower than 20 or lower than 45. I'm in the like mid twenties
Speaker 5:  fridge
Speaker 6:  That Yeah, that's, that's where I'm in. I'm in the twenties. Okay. It feels
Speaker 6:  very, very likely that it's gonna last a little while,
Speaker 4:  But that's not Okay. Fine. Yeah. I like, like, like, okay. Is it gonna last
Speaker 4:  a little while? It's kind of a different question, but I
Speaker 6:  It feels like it's, it's got some legs to it. Yeah. It feels like of
Speaker 6:  a lot of these we were gonna talk about, I think this is the one.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. All the rest of 'em are dead. Yeah. And some of them are like literally
Speaker 4:  dead this week.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like, like this is the one I'm ranking closest to zero. It feels like
Speaker 6:  it's gonna have the one that lasts the longest.
Speaker 4:  I, I think the danger here is when you do that, you call it the winner. And
Speaker 4:  I don't think it's actually
Speaker 6:  The winner. I don't think it's the winner. That's true.
Speaker 4:  That's, and that's why I'm at 45. It has the potential, it's like a happy
Speaker 4:  45. Yeah. But it very much has the potential to be the winner. Some, but
Speaker 4:  some of the decisions they've made and some of the, the postures they have
Speaker 4:  struck are actually dangerous for them. Yeah. Right. So
Speaker 4:  it's not real time. Like there's a bunch of people lately doing tests to
Speaker 4:  see how like real time Threads is. Right. Even in the
Speaker 4:  following feed, it's like algorithmic where it's keeping you
Speaker 4:  from real time posts from people you follow. I
Speaker 6:  Mean, but the EU is gonna fix that for us
Speaker 4:  Short,
Speaker 5:  The danger for Threads would be at least culturally, is essentially that
Speaker 5:  it turns into Facebook. Right. Right. Yeah. Which is like, there's a version
Speaker 5:  of Threads that is hugely successful and totally culturally irrelevant. Yep.
Speaker 5:  And that's what Facebook is. But Facebook is zero people's Facebook, it's
Speaker 5:  a really good business. Sure. But it's not like, it's not
Speaker 5:  ever going to get to what Twitter was. Right. Like that thing where people
Speaker 5:  on cable news are reading tweets at each other, which
Speaker 4:  By the way might have been bad for democracy. Oh sure.
Speaker 5:  Society. I think a perfectly reasonable case to make is that every tech choice
Speaker 5:  we've made in the last 15 years was wrong. And we should just go back to
Speaker 5:  2006
Speaker 4:  And do it again. But specifically, CNN is a bad podcast of people reading
Speaker 4:  tweets to each other was a bad moment. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. In world history. A hundred percent agree.
Speaker 4:  And I think this is what Zuck and Messer are talking about when they're like,
Speaker 4:  this shouldn't be, we don't want to do news. They have a million reasons
Speaker 4:  to not do news or governments around the world or making them pay for news.
Speaker 4:  They're blocking it and they're like, there's a lot of complication there.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But I think if you look at the most negative impact of Twitter, it
Speaker 4:  was the news became Twitter and Twitter lacked
Speaker 4:  all nuance and was just a dog fight.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  All the time. And I don't think they want Thrones to be that. So I'm saying
Speaker 4:  it's just like a ha It's is almost certainly gonna be the winner.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Yeah. All. right. Well, we'll split the difference. We'll put it at
Speaker 5:  like
Speaker 4:  35.
Speaker 5:  35. There we go. Mastodon,
Speaker 4:  Maston's A zero. It's, it's alive necessarily by default. Alive.
Speaker 4:  It depends on what you're talking about with Mastodon. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Let's,
Speaker 4:  Because it is definitionally uncurable, if you talk about the decentralized
Speaker 4:  network of things, that is Mastodon. No,
Speaker 5:  We're not talking about Activity Pub.
Speaker 4:  I'm not talking about Activity Pub. I'm talking about Mastodon, the social
Speaker 4:  network Sure. Of many, many, many Mastodon servers. The
Speaker 6:  Speed that David got there,
Speaker 4:  She know everyone knows what I'm talk about, but I'm No, I mean, I mean specifically
Speaker 4:  Mastodon, the social network made up of decentralized servers that people
Speaker 4:  can run and federate however they want. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I feel like that's less
Speaker 4:  Definitionally un killable.
Speaker 5:  Sure. But I also feel like that's less and less what Mastodon is. Mastodon
Speaker 5:  has leaned into Mastodon social being the thing, like
Speaker 5:  they made this very intentional choice in the name of getting more people
Speaker 5:  onto the platform and making discovery easier to default people to
Speaker 5:  what amounts to a centralized platform. You don't have to stay there. You
Speaker 5:  can leave if you want. You can federate, but like Mastodon and Mastodon
Speaker 5:  social, which is one instance of Mastodon, are increasingly the same thing.
Speaker 5:  And I, I don't know what that means. I think they're, they're continue to
Speaker 5:  be open questions about what happens when Mastodon gets a hundred million
Speaker 5:  users. If literally the people running it can afford to do that. I think
Speaker 5:  you're probably right that it's pretty close to zero at the moment. But I
Speaker 5:  also think, I think the idea that it is un killable, I don't think is true.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I think the concept of Mastodon is a zero. I think execution is
Speaker 6:  like in the forties or fifties because because we're
Speaker 6:  we're so early in this conversation about decentralization and stuff. We're
Speaker 6:  so, or in the movement or whatever you wanna call it. We're so early on in
Speaker 6:  it that I don't know if Mastodon is necessarily gonna be the most successful
Speaker 6:  one. I don't know if like it's theories for, for how to do de
Speaker 6:  decentralization is gonna work. Yeah. Especially when you have threats just
Speaker 6:  out there. I'm trying not to talk about it. I I got too close to activity.
Speaker 6:  Close So, I flying So I close
Speaker 4:  The activity Pub
Speaker 6:  Sun. I'm so sorry. But Mastodon, I'm not
Speaker 4:  Sorry.
Speaker 6:  David
Speaker 4:  Is keeping us in the truth.
Speaker 5:  That was specifically notorious activity. Pub hater. David Pierce. That's
Speaker 5:  me.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, I think, I think mast on social and, and that concept and stuff
Speaker 6:  is, is much higher on the scale because we're, we're already seeing this.
Speaker 6:  This is something that Dan talks about a lot. He, he's our, our big mast
Speaker 6:  on user in the office. And, and he's seen it a ton where everybody's like,
Speaker 6:  well, I don't wanna be on my little servers that I'm on. It's actually more
Speaker 6:  complicated and I wanna be on the main mast on server. And that's death for
Speaker 6:  that whole platform whenever I wanna be on the main one is everybody's
Speaker 6:  desire. Then, then the whole, the whole conceit falls apart.
Speaker 4:  Then you've recentralized the service. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like then what have you done? You've done, you've made a crummier Threads.
Speaker 5:  Well, yeah. Right. And then you become something that Threads can eat. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And
Speaker 6:  So I'm, I'm, I'm like at a, I'm like at a 45, 50.
Speaker 4:  I think this really depends on whether you think Massillon is mass on social
Speaker 4:  or not. Because I, the Yes, there's one platform.
Speaker 4:  I think they're opportunistically trying to grow users on that one. But
Speaker 4:  You know they're a very idealistic bunch over at Mastodon.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  I, I'm rooting for them, but I'm like, whoa. Like
Speaker 4:  Yuin was on decoder and he was basically like, I don't know how to
Speaker 4:  make money and I don't want to. Right. Like that's
Speaker 5:  Not, and actually believe what, that's not,
Speaker 4:  He's not his posture. Yeah. Yeah. And I think he just wants to grow the service
Speaker 4:  'cause there's an opportunity to grow the service. But I think fundamentally
Speaker 4:  they're into the decentralized approach to the network, which thread
Speaker 4:  could federate into and could either crush or flood with
Speaker 4:  users or who knows.
Speaker 6:  I will say this, when we're, when we're talking about all of these and talking
Speaker 6:  about the scale and survivability, we think a lot in that concept of growth.
Speaker 6:  But that growth itself, like the growth at all costs is a very like Threads
Speaker 6:  financially incentivized thing. And a lot of these, particularly something
Speaker 6:  like Mastodon, that's not their interest. It is about that decentralization
Speaker 6:  and stuff. So I think for a lot of those users, they'll probably be there
Speaker 6:  Yeah. For ages.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Well, and I think part of the reason I wanted to do this on the go
Speaker 5:  90 scale is like streaming services. This won't be a winner.
Speaker 5:  Takes all. Yeah. Right. Like there, there can be lots of these that exist
Speaker 5:  ideally.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's the ideal state, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's, yeah. Again, activity pub
Speaker 6:  All. right. Although some of these on here,
Speaker 5:  Next one up on the list Blue sky. Yeah. We're going in order from like
Speaker 5:  possible to less possible Blue sky. It's about to get real ugly, but let's,
Speaker 5:  let's, it's
Speaker 4:  A hard drop.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Blue Blue Sky's a 70 for me. Yeah. And it's, it's, it's a vindictive
Speaker 6:  70. Mainly because I'm on blue sky, I never use it.
Speaker 6:  And a bunch of my friends in like academia use it a lot. And they're always
Speaker 6:  like, why aren't you ever on blue sky? Mm. So I want it to go away. So they
Speaker 6:  stop asking. Blue
Speaker 5:  Sky is definitively wear the weirdos went. Yeah. It's
Speaker 6:  Where
Speaker 5:  The weirdos connected. And whether that's a, whether that's an insult or
Speaker 5:  a compliment thinking of is irrelevant. All the weirdos went to Blue Sky.
Speaker 5:  Just
Speaker 6:  Thinking of our coworkers who are active Blue Sky users. I'm like, yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's the weirdos. Yeah. And that's like, that's where the shit posters went.
Speaker 5:  Like if you mostly just went to like,
Speaker 5:  cause low stakes trouble for other people. Blue sky. Yeah. That's,
Speaker 6:  And you have 40,000 followers there right now. Nice.
Speaker 5:  Look at
Speaker 6:  You. No, I don't. I have four.
Speaker 5:  Oh, nice. That's less than, and
Speaker 6:  It's all my friends saying, why aren't you chatting here? Why I using Blue
Speaker 6:  Sky? I was like, because look at Threads
Speaker 4:  Blue Sky. I I agree. It's 75. A little, little higher than Alex.
Speaker 6:  And it's not even, and it's also not even active in that thing we're not
Speaker 6:  talking about today. That's totally not related. Well, no,
Speaker 4:  They have their own decentralized idea that
Speaker 6:  Makes it like that. That gives it like a plus five. You see closer death
Speaker 6:  modifier. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I blues if the, the tension from Masson is between Ma on
Speaker 4:  the decentralized social network idea and ma on social decentralized
Speaker 4:  server that you can log onto. Blue Sky is at the far end of the tension where
Speaker 4:  they're like, we made a decentralized social network. It has one server.
Speaker 4:  We won't even tell anyone else how to set up their own server. The protocol
Speaker 4:  isn't finished and we're standing up trust and safety on this server. Also,
Speaker 4:  Jack Dorsey is an investor in our company. Like
Speaker 6:  You just kept, like, you just are trying to shoot it to 90,
Speaker 6:  which is modifier after modify.
Speaker 4:  I'm, it, it's there. Yeah. But all of these companies are gonna run into
Speaker 4:  a revenue problem. I think Threads will solve it very quickly.
Speaker 4:  Again, Maston I think is just ideologically un killable, blue
Speaker 4:  sky. How are they gonna make a dollar? What's the plan? Are
Speaker 4:  they're
Speaker 6:  Gonna
Speaker 4:  Start. This is a group of people that advertisers do not want to be
Speaker 4:  near.
Speaker 6:  They're gonna open a Patreon.
Speaker 4:  Right. It's gonna, it's gonna be some weird mix of subscription and,
Speaker 4:  and contributions. And the, and the goal of it is not
Speaker 4:  to run the centralized server, at least from their white paper, from
Speaker 4:  like, they're just very far away from where they started. Yes. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They're running a clubhouse. That's fine. They're
Speaker 6:  Running Clubhouse and we that Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Clubhouse is also dead. I would point out, I
Speaker 6:  Was like, that's on the nine, that's 90 on the scale.
Speaker 4:  And I they just have to make some decisions along the way there. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think that's right. I I would put it about that high too. They did
Speaker 5:  a couple of things really. Right. Like the way they thought about usernames
Speaker 5:  was very smart. Yeah. They had some, some nifty ideas about custom
Speaker 5:  timelines that I continue to think is very cool. But I think they're gonna
Speaker 5:  end up having the legacy of being like, like friend
Speaker 5:  feed. Right. Where they're like, we had a bunch of ideas before the products
Speaker 5:  took off and they're gonna be like, we did that first. Right? Like, everybody's
Speaker 5:  like, oh, they invented the newsfeed. And there's like some developer out
Speaker 5:  there who's like, actually it was me first. Everybody's like, I don't care.
Speaker 5:  'cause Facebook destroyed you. That's gonna be the legacy of,
Speaker 4:  There's already some like connector software that connects Blue Sky's
Speaker 4:  decentralized approach to the activity pub decentralized approach. And
Speaker 4:  you can see how that thing Ugh. It's gonna be like, it's just designed
Speaker 4:  to piss everyone off. You know like
Speaker 6:  The, the app when you need to move music services Yeah. And you're always
Speaker 6:  think it'll work and it never does.
Speaker 4:  Well we'll just see how this goes. But my, my feeling is that it's successful
Speaker 4:  now because it has a bunch of investor money in it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And the the turn is coming. Yep.
Speaker 5:  All. right. Bunch more. These are all gonna be fairly quick. I'm gonna change
Speaker 5:  the order up here. CK Notes is the next one I wanna talk about, which is
Speaker 5:  slightly different.
Speaker 4:  Oh, CK is a company right now. Is it easily at 65 or 70?
Speaker 6:  So notes is even higher, right.
Speaker 4:  Notes Notes are just like a long for the ride. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's a 70, 75 for me.
Speaker 4:  What notes or sub ck
Speaker 6:  All of
Speaker 5:  It make the briefcase against ck
Speaker 4:  Cks entire business is taking a cut of other
Speaker 4:  people's businesses. The number of people who have started successful
Speaker 4:  cks is not large. Like it's large in the context of the
Speaker 4:  internet or like, maybe like the media. Casey has a really successful CK
Speaker 4:  more power to Casey. They're taking 10% of his revenue.
Speaker 4:  This is a business that is founded on whales. So you just need, and
Speaker 5:  It does not seem to be creating new ones. Yeah. Right. Very quickly
Speaker 4:  Anymore. And then the ones that it has created, some of them are like,
Speaker 4:  again, large amounts of money, large amounts of subscribers,
Speaker 4:  cultural relevance, shaky. The Barry Weiss of the world.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Andrew Sullivan's of the world. I I I came up as an Andrew Sullivan
Speaker 4:  reader in the nineties. Yep. Fine. Right. But they've got a handful
Speaker 4:  of those that are making a bunch of money. They're taking a huge amount.
Speaker 4:  You take 10% out of Andrew Sullivan. Yeah. Or
Speaker 4:  Heather Cox Richardson or Barry Weiss. The, the top of the
Speaker 4:  charts at ck. You're taking an awful lot of money from those people to send
Speaker 4:  emails to just what you're doing. That's the service you are providing.
Speaker 4:  They are not bringing new customers onto the platform. Most new
Speaker 4:  subscribers on cks are subscribers to other cks.
Speaker 5:  Yep. The recommendations thing seems to
Speaker 4:  Have worked. So they, they, they're just moving, they're taking more money
Speaker 4:  out of the existing CK base and not bringing new people on CK
Speaker 6:  Nevermind, I'm at 80 now.
Speaker 4:  And then in April they are hitting up retail
Speaker 4:  investors for cash in like a
Speaker 4:  pre-public round of investment. They won't really sell the numbers,
Speaker 4:  but we know CK had negative revenue last year. It's just
Speaker 4:  like CK is in a place where the next thing they have to do
Speaker 4:  is introduce advertising their platform because they need a big new source
Speaker 4:  of revenue to make that go because they can't convince new millions
Speaker 4:  upon millions of more new people to pay them. And I know people are gonna
Speaker 4:  say that. I'm like biased against CK 'cause I had Chris best on decoder and
Speaker 4:  I yelled at him about not moderating CK No, I'm whatever you think of
Speaker 4:  that. I'm looking at the math of their business. Yeah. And I'm saying
Speaker 4:  there's a cliff coming and that's why you're hitting up retail investors
Speaker 4:  for cash. Yeah. With negative revenue. Yeah. Like that's however
Speaker 4:  you think about the trust and safety function of sub stack notes. When you're
Speaker 4:  in that position and you're charging your, your most popular
Speaker 4:  creators the most money to send emails,
Speaker 4:  eventually one of them is gonna wake up and say, I wonder how much MailChimp
Speaker 4:  costs. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  There's
Speaker 6:  You know there's other
Speaker 5:  Services they can use WordPress. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There's so much free stuff that they can go and do this on and
Speaker 6:  it's just doesn't seem
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's bad. I agree. All. right. So we're, we're all in agreement on
Speaker 5:  that one. I'm just gonna read you a bunch and I want you to tell me if any
Speaker 5:  of these are not at least an 85. And then after that
Speaker 5:  we can, we can go to break. I have Pebble, which is objectively a 90. It
Speaker 5:  died. I didn't even RIP Pebble know what Pebble was. It was called T
Speaker 5:  two for a a minute because they just straight up were like, this is the new
Speaker 5:  Twitter and then it was Pebble, it's gone.
Speaker 5:  There's also Noster, which is the other decentralized thing that Jack Dorsey
Speaker 5:  is invested in. And then we have things like spout and Counter social and
Speaker 5:  post and WT social and co-host.
Speaker 6:  I thought these were all Mastodon instances.
Speaker 5:  Nope. Sadly. Do we have any reason to not put any
Speaker 5:  of these things at at least an 85?
Speaker 6:  I wanna put WT social at a zero just because I'm, I think it's funny.
Speaker 4:  It's your own list. I
Speaker 6:  Wanna root for it. Just pick up I'm root Root for you. Wtt social. You
Speaker 5:  Gotta believe in something. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's my Tinker Bell. So
Speaker 4:  I. They all have the same problem. They all have the same problem.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's not users, it's not technology. Yeah. It's how are you gonna make
Speaker 4:  money? Yeah. What's your plan? Let's say, let's say you have a hundred of
Speaker 4:  the world's most dedicated spout users. Spout has a hundred people who are
Speaker 4:  logged onto it and they have 24 hours a day of user engagement from its a
Speaker 4:  hundred people. What's the, what's the plan? Is it charge the money?
Speaker 6:  They'll make flower crowns.
Speaker 4:  I just think all these have a sort of blinkered view of what it would take
Speaker 4:  to replace Twitter, which is
Speaker 5:  So does Mastodon. To be fair,
Speaker 4:  You just need a place to post.
Speaker 5:  We didn't levy that against Mastodon. It's true of Mastodon too.
Speaker 4:  Mastodon first of all, is a company is like two people funded by a
Speaker 4:  government grant in Europe. Sure. And one contractor who manages billing,
Speaker 4:  you should go listen to that episode of De
Speaker 5:  Dakota. No, that's that's real. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I was like, what's your org chart? And he is like, well, there's me and Claire
Speaker 4:  and that's looking for, and obviously they have server costs and
Speaker 4:  I'm sure they're gonna grow in different ways. Yeah. But as a company, this
Speaker 4:  is just a social experiment. I think if you're wt
Speaker 4:  social, you might believe you're a company.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. If you believe hard enough, it could be a zero.
Speaker 4:  And I, and I think if your company is modeled after Twitter a
Speaker 4:  notoriously poorly run company, you've just got some problems coming
Speaker 4:  your way. Yeah. I think the Cold start problem of how do we get a network
Speaker 4:  effect or how do we get a bunch of users is actually, and they're all trying
Speaker 4:  to compete on weird ideas about what people had a problem with
Speaker 4:  on Twitter. And I think they all miss the fact that a lot of people liked
Speaker 4:  how drama that a lot of people liked how dramatic Twitter was.
Speaker 5:  Or at least couldn't look away from it. Yeah. Right. Like it was, it had
Speaker 5:  that car crash appeal.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. It's like, what if we made Twitter without car crashes? And it's
Speaker 4:  like, yeah, no, no one's coming.
Speaker 6:  Look at it anymore. I just want my Twitter person of the day. Yeah. I love
Speaker 6:  telling people who don't use Twitter about it. And they're just like, okay,
Speaker 6:  yeah. Anyway, here's what's going on with my kids.
Speaker 4:  Did you see Kevin Durant tweeted, I'm on Threads with a burner, come find
Speaker 4:  me. No way. And it's like, that's what people are here for. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like, I respect that
Speaker 4:  He's not tweeting. I'm on wt social with a burner. Wait,
Speaker 5:  So this is Threads to lose basically like, nobody has won this yet, but it,
Speaker 5:  it very much feels like the next 12 months are Threads to screw up.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I, I would put it just, the mirror image is, it's a
Speaker 4:  negative 45 for Twitter and it's a positive 45 for Threads,
Speaker 4:  but it's about to be an election year. A lot of weird
Speaker 4:  stuff is gonna start happening on these platforms. Just a lot of
Speaker 4:  weird stuff. Yeah. And I, those numbers can move,
Speaker 4:  but I, I think Threads their attitude about news and realtime
Speaker 4:  information is just the, the pressure on that is just increasing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And that's gonna collide with an election in a pretty real way. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And sport and just sports. The NBA season has started, we're still in the
Speaker 4:  middle of the NFL season. Yeah. Like that audience is wanting to move to
Speaker 4:  Threads and it's just like not happening.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I think that's right. Yeah. The next 12 months I think are gonna
Speaker 5:  be really fascinating. Like, I think many of these we will not even mention
Speaker 5:  in a year. And I think the stakes are going to feel
Speaker 5:  super high for a lot of these folks as we want towards an election. I,
Speaker 6:  I'm still rooting for WT social, which I've learned a lot about. It's got
Speaker 6:  two stars on Product hunt out
Speaker 5:  Of five. Okay. We, that's, yeah, that's,
Speaker 6:  Lifewire has got a
Speaker 5:  Great, this segment has gone 19 on
Speaker 6:  How to use it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'm just like, it's the non-toxic social, like that's great. I'm happy
Speaker 4:  that there's a non-toxic social network.
Speaker 5:  Okay. We, we've officially Alex is now googling wt social, which means we're
Speaker 5:  talking, this segment has gone 90.
Speaker 4:  It's it's all over baby All. right. We're gonna take a break. We'll wrap
Speaker 4:  with the lightning round. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  right, we're back. It's lightning round time. We're still open for sponsors
Speaker 4:  as we know, the lightning port has been deprecated. Yeah. Some people have
Speaker 4:  been posting at various Ford executives on my behalf. Thank you
Speaker 4:  very much. I appreciate you. I'm still looking for a major American
Speaker 4:  ship company sponsor the Thunderbolt floor round and just trying to will
Speaker 4:  things into a, you have to make the media company you want.
Speaker 5:  Neil as Vision board is just Thunderbolt four cables.
Speaker 4:  They're very expensive. All. right. I'll take the first one, which
Speaker 4:  I'm the, the only thing I wanted to talk about this week is Metal Gear.
Speaker 4:  Solid Delta. Snake Eater. You have now running an N reel. The top. It
Speaker 4:  was the first thing on the rundown. The first thing. And David moved it.
Speaker 6:  I watched. It was great just watching it highlighted. And
Speaker 4:  In our editorial meeting today. So there's a lot of weird passive aggressive
Speaker 4:  stuff that happens in enterprise software. And, what I was thinking about
Speaker 4:  was David rerunning the rundown every week.
Speaker 5:  Can I just say, just before you get into this, this might be the greatest
Speaker 5:  video game title of all time. Metal Gear Solid Delta Colon Snake
Speaker 5:  Eater. Yeah. Just whips to like, that's so good.
Speaker 4:  This is one of the greatest video games ever made. It was a PS two game.
Speaker 4:  It just ruled. It ruled. And now it still looks like a video game.
Speaker 4:  Like You know, like you get new gameplay footage now. New engines that You
Speaker 4:  know it's still super, looks like a video game. But this game ruled. This
Speaker 6:  Used to be called something else though. This was Metal Gear Solid Snake
Speaker 4:  Eater. Yeah. It was Metal Gear. Solid three. Snake Eater.
Speaker 6:  I didn't get past one.
Speaker 4:  Oh my God. Alex.
Speaker 6:  I'm still in a box somewhere. Plays
Speaker 4:  Station. The, the number of things that you and I just have to stream together,
Speaker 4:  right. Just on this show alone. Yeah. It's, it's all of the Metal gears now.
Speaker 4:  Just a full on week long Twitch stream. Yeah. Blade Trinity.
Speaker 4:  And I believe Pump Up the volume is still,
Speaker 6:  This is gonna be a good time. Everybody come join us. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 4:  This is our, this is our, we're
Speaker 5:  Gonna start a podcast called Copyright Infringement in which we just watch
Speaker 5:  all the things
Speaker 4:  That we have to watch. I'm more excited about this game than I think happen.
Speaker 4:  This a defining video game.
Speaker 6:  Are you gonna take that day off
Speaker 4:  And just burn through Metal? Gear. Solid? Yeah. Probably. Yeah, that's my
Speaker 4:  idea. All, right. David, what's your love
Speaker 5:  That mine is a little tidbit of information we got. So we've talked a lot
Speaker 5:  about the Google Antitrust trial and one of the big open questions has been
Speaker 5:  how much money does Google pay Apple to be the exclusive search
Speaker 5:  engine on all the Apple devices? We knew it was billions of dollars.
Speaker 5:  I had heard numbers as low as five and as high as 20. But these
Speaker 5:  numbers have come out. But they've only come out in closed court and they're
Speaker 5:  not being given to reporters. Like the, the access to information has been
Speaker 5:  a huge open question during all of this trial. The New York Times head of
Speaker 5:  report on Thursday that the actual number is
Speaker 5:  $18 billion, or at least in 2021, Google paid $18 billion to
Speaker 5:  Apple to be the default search engine in Safari. There was
Speaker 5:  also some interesting stuff in there that when Satya Nadella
Speaker 5:  testified, he said, and it seemed like he was kind
Speaker 5:  of guessing at the time, that one thing Apple might be
Speaker 5:  worried about is that if it took the deal away from Google, Google would
Speaker 5:  use all of its many powerful and popular iOS apps to do things like
Speaker 5:  promote Chrome. Like if, if every time you went to Gmail it was just like,
Speaker 5:  Hey, download Chrome, a better browser. Like a lot of people would download
Speaker 5:  Chrome and they were very afraid that Google was gonna do that if it lost
Speaker 5:  the search deal. Satya said this like it was a possibility, but not that
Speaker 5:  he was certain, but the Times Report said that in fact Google was thinking
Speaker 5:  about doing exactly that and was building things to compete with Spotlight
Speaker 5:  and was gonna start to get people to use Chrome by using its other tools
Speaker 5:  on iOS. How
Speaker 6:  Is that any different from right now if I go, if, if one of you send me a
Speaker 6:  Google doc and I try to open it on my phone on Safari, my phone
Speaker 6:  flips out. Yeah. Unless I go and I download the stupid Google
Speaker 6:  Docs app and log in and and use that. How is that
Speaker 5:  Any different? Google might be the single worst mobile program.
Speaker 5:  No,
Speaker 4:  No, no, no, no. It's slides. Google Slides is the single. Okay.
Speaker 5:  No, you're right. Mobile program. Google, Google Slides. Sheets and docs
Speaker 5:  are all Yeah. They're
Speaker 4:  Bad obsessed. But I'm saying slides is You know how every year the iPhone
Speaker 4:  comes out or any other phone comes out, we're like, this processor is crazy
Speaker 4:  fast. Like it's, oh, it's just there for headroom. I'm like, can this run
Speaker 4:  Google Slides? Because it probably can't. My phone's gonna get hot and it's
Speaker 4:  gonna slow down and crash. Google Slides
Speaker 6:  How slides on decks
Speaker 4:  Didn didn't wanna think about, let me unfold this stupid one. All. right.
Speaker 4:  But keep going.
Speaker 5:  But Well, so to answer your question though, it would be, it would be kind
Speaker 5:  of like, this is not a perfect analogy, but if you were to like open
Speaker 5:  a pages document on your phone and Google just threw a popup being
Speaker 5:  like, wouldn't you rather use Google Docs? Or if it was like,
Speaker 6:  It does that currently?
Speaker 5:  No. If you try to open a Google doc, it'll take you to
Speaker 6:  Google Docs. Okay. But if it does for anything, I'm
Speaker 5:  Saying if you, if you opened any webpage in Chrome and Chrome was like, wouldn't
Speaker 5:  you rather use Google Docs?
Speaker 6:  I'd set it on fire.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Probably
Speaker 6:  That, that like, that's my, that's my villain story. That's that's how you
Speaker 6:  get me to never wanna use your products again.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But also it's how you get a lot of people to download your stuff. This
Speaker 5:  is
Speaker 6:  True. And, and Google kind
Speaker 5:  Of, I bet you also have the Google Docs app on your phone now.
Speaker 6:  I had to, it bullied me for so many years.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. This is the thing. They're not to, they don't care. I needed to,
Speaker 6:  I needed to put my notes in for a story on the train.
Speaker 5:  This is, this is the thing. Right. And if you're Google, if you're Google
Speaker 5:  and you can say, stay logged into YouTube, in the YouTube app by
Speaker 5:  logging into Chrome. I hate it. They're gonna get people to download Chrome.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's FTC do something about this. And,
Speaker 5:  And
Speaker 4:  Truthfully, well they, they have put Google in John trial.
Speaker 5:  I think it do
Speaker 6:  More.
Speaker 5:  I think it's possible that Google would never have actually done this. But
Speaker 5:  the threat of doing it, right, at least the DOJ would tell you is
Speaker 5:  enough to keep Apple along with $18 billion
Speaker 5:  from walking away from Google.
Speaker 6:  I wanna just talk about that for a second. Google, if you're listening, I
Speaker 6:  will also make you the default search app on my phone for 18.
Speaker 4:  I'm here for you. Yeah. So it's interesting. The context of this is fascinating.
Speaker 4:  So in Europe Digital Services Act is in force.
Speaker 4:  Apple's gonna have to let people pick Chrome. Google will have to
Speaker 4:  let people switch default browsers in various ways. We'll just see if this
Speaker 4:  regulatory intervention actually does something. Notably for the past decade
Speaker 4:  it has not. Right? Right. Like there have been browser ballots and search
Speaker 4:  ballots on Windows PCs and Android phones in Europe,
Speaker 5:  They
Speaker 4:  Don't do anything. They don't do anything.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. There's a lot of evidence that shows that. The, the thing where
Speaker 5:  you boot up the phone and it says, what search engine do you wanna use? Everybody
Speaker 5:  picks Google. Right.
Speaker 4:  Here's what I'm curious about. Everybody
Speaker 5:  Picks Google in large part, the DOJ would argue because they've never heard
Speaker 5:  of any other search engine because of the way that Google does it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So people are like, what's kosher and why would I use that? I'm just gonna
Speaker 5:  pick Google. And so, and this is the hard part of the DO j's case is they
Speaker 5:  have to wind this all the way back and essentially argue that Google has
Speaker 5:  made it so that you've never even tried another search engine because it's
Speaker 5:  impossible. And that is a very hard case to argue
Speaker 5:  when Google is like, they're just, they're just right there. Like, just go
Speaker 5:  do it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Here's what I'm curious about though. The only browser bot I could
Speaker 4:  see working, you turn on your iPhone and it says you want Chrome or Safari.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I think that's a coin flip and that's in this case too that Yep.
Speaker 4:  People think that that's a coin flip.
Speaker 5:  That's two brands everybody's heard of. Yep. Which, which is, I I agree.
Speaker 5:  I think it'll be really fascinating and I would bet in somewhere in Apple
Speaker 5:  Park in Cupertino is Safari for Android. It's just sitting there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They made Safari for Windows once. Yeah. It didn't, didn't go well.
Speaker 5:  I think they would pick this fight backwards if they had to. Like they, they
Speaker 5:  will, they will bring it to Google if Google's gonna bring it to them. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And they're like, there's this like mutually assured destruction thing that
Speaker 5:  has worked for everybody for a long time. Again along with 18 billion bucks.
Speaker 5:  And either it's gonna stay that way or it's gonna get all
Speaker 5:  unwound and I think it's gonna get Yeah.
Speaker 4:  The other piece of this puzzle, which I think is a pretty important wrinkle
Speaker 4:  right now, is just a bunch of reporting this week that apple's behind an
Speaker 4:  AI or feels like it's behind an AI or needs to get better at AI and put
Speaker 4:  it in all the products as you would expect. And the Apple's privacy
Speaker 4:  posture. We'll keep it from going and hoovering up a bunch of data or sharing
Speaker 4:  a bunch of data. And You know what would be a good source of data for an
Speaker 4:  AI tool is search queries. Yep. We know this 'cause they're a
Speaker 4:  great source for Google. And that's how Apple gets a bunch of differential
Speaker 4:  privacy shielded input. Totally.
Speaker 4:  For an AI system. It's on
Speaker 6:  Some little chip just right on the board so you don't have to worry about
Speaker 6:  it
Speaker 4:  Getting Yeah. You can see how they would do it. That's my Tim
Speaker 5:  Cook. That
Speaker 4:  Was good. Thank you. That's good.
Speaker 4:  He's full vampire. Thanks
Speaker 4:  Vot. We'll see, I I, the dynamic there is interesting 'cause it might be
Speaker 4:  an Apple's long term interest to not take the
Speaker 4:  $18 billion
Speaker 5:  No. Said no one ever.
Speaker 4:  If there's one company that can look past $18 billion. It's Apple,
Speaker 5:  It's Maston, Claire. Those are the only two
Speaker 4:  I really bad Everyone should go listening to Claire. He's a fascinating guy.
Speaker 4:  It was
Speaker 5:  A good one.
Speaker 4:  All, right. Cranz, what's yours?
Speaker 6:  Okay, so mine is, shout out to Mia Sato. She has a really, really great story
Speaker 6:  up on the site right now called is my coworker, AI Bizarre product
Speaker 6:  reviews leave Gannett staff wondering. It's really, really good story. It's
Speaker 6:  basically Reviewed, which is one of the, the sites for Gannet Gannett does
Speaker 6:  like USA today. And a lot of local newspapers reviewed as their kind of wire
Speaker 6:  cutter and a bunch of new reviews appeared on it.
Speaker 6:  And everybody's like, I didn't write that. And then when they went and they
Speaker 6:  looked up the people, a lot of 'em didn't seem to exist.
Speaker 6:  Oh boy. And so it seems that this was all per, like
Speaker 6:  this was stuff that Gant went partnered with another company who's using
Speaker 6:  AI to just write AI churn and then try to like, oh my God,
Speaker 6:  sell you stuff.
Speaker 4:  Why don't I have these ideas?
Speaker 6:  Well, it's, it's not going great. The reviewed staff is, is pretty upset
Speaker 6:  about it. They just recently went on strike Over Union stuff
Speaker 6:  with, with Gannet, so with News Guild. So no disclaimer needed You
Speaker 6:  know. Wow.
Speaker 4:  Wow.
Speaker 6:  Alex you were, I could see you getting ready for it. So yeah, it's the, the
Speaker 6:  story is really good. It's, it's really, really why there's a bunch of stuff
Speaker 6:  we still don't know Yeah. About this, the rationale and everything like that,
Speaker 6:  but sucks for the folks that work there.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying if you work at a business and any one of your business thinks
Speaker 4:  we should just get some AI chum to get Google search results to make
Speaker 4:  pennies, you should leave that business.
Speaker 6:  There's a product pros and cons and apparently instead of like
Speaker 6:  pros and cons, it's just specs.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Did it just, or I mean on the flip side, if
Speaker 4:  you are the scammer using AI to cheat Google out of pennies, you're You know
Speaker 4:  buy another Lambo You know. Live it up like head. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I was like, I was like, it's going great for you. These
Speaker 4:  Are the last days of Disco Brother. It's just like, but that
Speaker 4:  Internet's sending and this, this is the force that will end it. Yep. All
Speaker 4:  right. Here's mine. I'm very excited about this one. It's Humane's ai Pin.
Speaker 4:  Oh God. It was named Times Gadget of the Year.
Speaker 6:  Time
Speaker 5:  One, one of many to be fair.
Speaker 4:  It's just no one's ever seen it You know, like
Speaker 6:  I also have named it My Gadget of the Year. It's really serious.
Speaker 6:  Is
Speaker 4:  It? Sure. We learned that it has some integration with
Speaker 4:  GPT somehow in it and it has a light called the Trus
Speaker 4:  Light that lights up when it's listening. Which I would remind you is apparently
Speaker 4:  all the time
Speaker 6:  That's so it's just silly. A little glowing. There's
Speaker 4:  A little yellow light. You,
Speaker 5:  It's even a light. It's just a piece of yellow.
Speaker 5:  I will say this time thing is interesting in that it has a couple of new
Speaker 5:  details like the trust light and the fact that it has a magnetic attachment.
Speaker 5:  That's something I like that part. That's cool. It also has one of the
Speaker 5:  funniest disclosures in history. So again, you're putting
Speaker 5:  an unannounced product that really no one knows anything about on your
Speaker 5:  best inventions of 2023 List Bold strategy. And then it's
Speaker 5:  his at the end. Investors in Humane include Time Co-chairs and owners,
Speaker 5:  mark and Lynn Benioff. Yep. It's just a tough look
Speaker 5:  like disclosure is our brand. We love a disclosure. That's
Speaker 5:  a tough one. This product you've never seen. It's so sick.
Speaker 5:  It's funded by my boss. You're gonna love
Speaker 4:  It. Best inventions of 2023. Well, I will say this,
Speaker 4:  the owner of Time Magazine is scheduled to be on Decoder soon. There you
Speaker 4:  go. I'm gonna ask him about the Pin.
Speaker 5:  If he brings the AIP I'll I ask him Wear I'll it back. I'm gonna Yeah,
Speaker 6:  He he better
Speaker 4:  I ask him. We do. I hope he
Speaker 5:  Has it.
Speaker 4:  He won't do it. He's not gonna betray the Ohana. Are you kidding me?
Speaker 4:  Come on.
Speaker 5:  I'm fascinated by that thing though. It's, it's supposed to launch November 9th.
Speaker 5:  There's so much we don't know. They have done this like what,
Speaker 5:  eight month long hype cycle at this point. Humane, they've been out there
Speaker 5:  talking about this. I think the, that original TED Talk where he showed
Speaker 5:  off and or lied about a bunch of demos was in April.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So we've been talking about this for a long time and this thing is
Speaker 5:  either going to be great or it's gonna be a total disaster. And I have a
Speaker 5:  very hard time imagining anything in between and I have a much easier time
Speaker 5:  imagining total disaster.
Speaker 4:  So there was some reporting that, again, open AI
Speaker 4:  integration. Sam Altman might be an investor in this thing. There's also
Speaker 4:  some reporting that Sam Altman and Johnny Iiv are working on their own thing,
Speaker 4:  which is fascinating 'cause Humane is a bunch of ex Apple
Speaker 4:  designers.
Speaker 4:  That's gotta be be a weird email chain. Yeah. Just
Speaker 4:  in general, just a weird email chain. A
Speaker 6:  Lot of ellipses in that
Speaker 5:  One.
Speaker 4:  Just a lot of thoughtfully considering materials. And then also you
Speaker 4:  betrayed me. You know, it's like it's all in there. I know, man. I'm, I'm
Speaker 4:  still stuck on the basics. You you wanna call Bethany? How does it know Bethany's
Speaker 4:  phone number
Speaker 5:  And how does it call Bethany?
Speaker 4:  Does Yeah. Does it have a service plan? How do you configure the, the
Speaker 4:  IMEI magic. Just, just the basics. I just wanna know. Yep. It's
Speaker 5:  All magic.
Speaker 4:  And it, I'm telling you, if this thing requires an app on your phone to function
Speaker 4:  disaster.
Speaker 5:  Yep.
Speaker 4:  And it it ha it definitely does.
Speaker 5:  I'm so excited for this one. It's, it, it's gonna have to be 15 hours long
Speaker 5:  and it's just them explaining how it does basic things. I cannot wait.
Speaker 4:  It's very good. I should disclose that we are also owned
Speaker 6:  By human. By
Speaker 5:  Human.
Speaker 4:  No, that's not true. There was a number of disclosures we could've made on
Speaker 4:  this episode, but I leave those as an exercise to the viewer. No,
Speaker 4:  I don't think there were any. No problem.
Speaker 5:  No, we did good
Speaker 4:  This time. Yeah, we did. Good. All. right? Yay.
Speaker 5:  We should end the show Before we scripted this
Speaker 4:  Up, if you think we missed one, send us a note. You know we we're here for
Speaker 4:  it. I closed the tab with all that
Speaker 6:  Quick. Somebody talk about Netflix
Speaker 6:  FTX trial is, or no shout out is Lurker
Speaker 4:  All. right. A few things to mention before we close. Sam Bankman Fried
Speaker 4:  was on the stand in the FTX trial today. Liz Lato has been there
Speaker 4:  every day. She's having the time of her life covering this trial. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Never. We're gonna have her on the show in the next week or so. Yeah. To
Speaker 5:  come talk about it. David,
Speaker 4:  I went to the premiere of the Bloomberg doc about FTX yesterday
Speaker 4:  and people walked up to me and were like, Liz is doing a great job covering
Speaker 4:  the trial. That's incredible. So she's having the time of her life and I'm
Speaker 4:  eager to see what Sam had to say today. And then we have
Speaker 4:  incredible, I guess you could say a spooky story about
Speaker 4:  someone who has been tormenting professors
Speaker 4:  online. And it is one of our best layouts ever. It's very cool.
Speaker 4:  Go read it. It's, it's great. And then lastly, as you all know,
Speaker 4:  we've been covering Google obsessively this year. Just the culture Google
Speaker 4:  made, like I said, the last day's of disco, you gotta put the marker down
Speaker 4:  and see like this is the world we made before we move on. So we've been covering
Speaker 4:  Google and Google's SEO web and
Speaker 4:  we have a really great one this week from Mia, who's been on a run lately.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's called The restaurant. nearest Google. It's about a restaurant
Speaker 4:  called Thai Food Near me in New York City, which is, that's the whole
Speaker 4:  name. The SEO has broken out of the internet people. Yep. And she found a
Speaker 4:  bunch of other businesses around the country. Notary near me is very popular.
Speaker 4:  Barbershop near me is very popular. And she just went and talked to these
Speaker 4:  folks about why they named their business as this. And we got a lot of comments
Speaker 4:  like this is like when people named them the A one Auto Shop. Yep. They're
Speaker 4:  just trying to beat the discovery algorithm. But this is, this is a new way
Speaker 4:  of doing it. And then of course, Google's in the story being like, that's
Speaker 4:  not how It works. Which is a lot of our Google coverage involves that
Speaker 4:  dynamic. But the story is great. The pictures are incredible. And Mia said
Speaker 4:  the food was good, which is important. So go check that out. It's on the
Speaker 4:  site now. That's it. We're way over. Subscribe to installer,
Speaker 4:  listen to decoder, listen to all of our shows. Yeah. Verge
Speaker 4:  is a cool, it's
Speaker 1:  A cool website.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's the only one left. That's it. That's The. Vergecast. Rock and
Speaker 4:  roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. We'll see you next week.