# Transcript
ID: e16c27f0-d38b-11ed-a653-d747bb8dd039
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: How to use Microsoft’s AI Copilot, laptop microphones, and Amazon Sidewalk
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-1874375847886498894/-1414942641784700211/s93290-US-4489s-1680683323.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of peer-to-peer wireless networking:
02:31 - David Pierce talks with smart home reviewer Jennifer Pattison Tuohy about Amazon’s network of smart home devices called Sidewalk and the state of Matter, the promised smart home standard.
Amazon just opened up its Sidewalk network for anyone to build connected gadgets on
32:16- Monica Chin brings six laptops to Times Square in New York City to test out the microphones.
48:47 - Tom Warren joins the show to explain how AI is being integrated into Microsoft’s products, which may be more promising than Bing’s chatbot.
Microsoft’s new Copilot will change Office documents forever
Microsoft Security Copilot is a new GPT-4 AI assistant for cybersecurity
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
Vote for us in the People’s Choice Webby Awards for Best Technology Podcast!
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Peer-to-Peer wireless
Speaker 2:  networking. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am currently in my
Speaker 2:  basement, which is now technically also my home office. And I am
Speaker 2:  doing some cable organizing because it's April, it's spring cleaning
Speaker 2:  time. And I have reached the point where I now have four
Speaker 2:  large bins full of cables. Most of them are
Speaker 2:  u s BBC cables. So I tell myself that I need them all because u s BBC is
Speaker 2:  the future and you can never have too many. But I also have some that are
Speaker 2:  like printer cables from the nineties that I don't think I ever
Speaker 2:  used for anything. So the point is it's time to go through some stuff.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, once I finish, we have a great show coming up for you today. We're
Speaker 2:  gonna dig into two big things about the future of the Smart Home Amazon
Speaker 2:  Sidewalk Network and the matter standard. And we're gonna try to figure out
Speaker 2:  where both of those things stand now. Then we're gonna head out into New York
Speaker 2:  City and test some laptop microphones to see if the mic inside of
Speaker 2:  your laptop can hold up to calls and video chats. And lastly, we're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk about Microsoft's many adventures in AI and what
Speaker 2:  Microsoft is up to says about the future of G P T four
Speaker 2:  office windows and like what it means to use a
Speaker 2:  computer. All of that's coming up in just a second, but first I have to
Speaker 2:  find my headphone cables. So wish me luck on that. This is the Verge Cast
Speaker 2:  scene sec.
Speaker 3:  The H B O drama succession is in its fourth and final
Speaker 3:  season and for diehard fans, some of the characters have
Speaker 3:  achieved pop star status
Speaker 4:  That just feels like, so like you know, you're that bitch for you. Cause
Speaker 4:  of that conversation like that, like he's it.
Speaker 4:  I just kind of like, mm.
Speaker 3:  Did you just compare Logan Roy to Beyonce?
Speaker 4:  Well, I mean why not?
Speaker 3:  Oh, let's keep this going. We talk succession this week
Speaker 3:  on Intuit Vultures pop culture podcast.
Speaker 1:  Welcome
Speaker 2:  Back. Last week a sort of strange thing happened.
Speaker 2:  Amazon told millions of people that surprise we just turned
Speaker 2:  on a nationwide network of smart home devices to which millions
Speaker 2:  of people responded. I'm sorry, what?
Speaker 2:  It turns out that sidewalk or something like it could be a really
Speaker 2:  big deal for the smart home and the smart city and this
Speaker 2:  big connected world everybody's been telling us about for years. It
Speaker 2:  might even be as big a deal as matter, which is the universal smart home
Speaker 2:  standard that actually we're overdue for a check-in on. So here to dig
Speaker 2:  into both of those things is the verges Jen Pattison Tui. Hi Jen.
Speaker 5:  Hello. So happy to be back so soon.
Speaker 2:  We promised the people we were gonna talk about matter. I
Speaker 5:  Know, I bet there were a lot of angry people when we just glossed over it
Speaker 5:  there.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna do that second because I just like to make the people wait for
Speaker 2:  the matter talk. Fair enough. But first I wanna talk about, you wrote this
Speaker 2:  piece about Sidewalk, Amazon's network, which I
Speaker 2:  was shocked at how many people have read this story? It's like one, our most
Speaker 2:  popular story this week. People paid a lot of attention. It, it like sparked
Speaker 2:  a lot of thoughts and feelings about all this stuff. We should probably start
Speaker 2:  at the very beginning just because part of the story is that a lot of people
Speaker 2:  didn't know what this thing is or that it existed or
Speaker 2:  that they were part of it at all. So let's just rewind all the way to the
Speaker 2:  very beginning here. What is Amazon Sidewalk and how did it come
Speaker 2:  into the world without anybody really noticing?
Speaker 5:  Okay. Yes. So this does go back to 2019. Well
Speaker 5:  actually it began even earlier than that, which is something I only just
Speaker 5:  discovered. Amazon developed a local
Speaker 5:  connectivity protocol for its own devices.
Speaker 5:  So very early on it realized that ring devices like
Speaker 5:  doorbells and cameras were outside your house. Your wifi router was inside
Speaker 5:  your house and sometimes the connection between the two was very bad. And
Speaker 5:  no matter what they tried, they really struggled to get
Speaker 5:  some people's cameras to work the way they promised them. So they
Speaker 5:  actually developed internally a system that would send
Speaker 5:  low bandwidth, low power messages between
Speaker 5:  the router and the device so that you would still get a notification
Speaker 5:  if someone pressed your doorbell even if your wifi wasn't working.
Speaker 5:  Because you know if you have a doorbell and you press it and it doesn't work,
Speaker 5:  you get mad.
Speaker 2:  That is kind of a one job situation. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Exactly. So it that's how Amazon Sidewalk started as
Speaker 5:  a way for Amazon to fix a problem it had for its customers. But what
Speaker 5:  it's developed into is something way bigger. It's
Speaker 5:  essentially a low bandwidth, long range wireless network
Speaker 5:  developed to support low power devices. And this is
Speaker 5:  perfect for the smart home because the smart home is full of sensors.
Speaker 5:  So basically what Amazon did was they developed this network, they just said,
Speaker 5:  okay, we're gonna go turn it on and it's actually inside all your devices
Speaker 5:  in your home, all your Amazon devices and some of your ring devices have
Speaker 5:  this secret network that we've been developing and we're just
Speaker 5:  gonna switch it on. And everyone was like, what?
Speaker 5:  What are you doing here? Why are you doing this? And the thing that really
Speaker 5:  upset a lot of people completely justifiably is it actually
Speaker 5:  uses some of your internet bandwidth. That's how Sidewalk works.
Speaker 5:  It uses these low power radios including
Speaker 5:  Laura and Bluetooth low energy and Laura is like a
Speaker 5:  900 megahertz frequency radio. But in order to communicate to the
Speaker 5:  internet, it actually needs the internet. So it uses a little bit of your
Speaker 5:  bandwidth. So when Amazon first turned on sidewalk, basically
Speaker 5:  everyone was opted in and that's never a good move. I mean tech
Speaker 5:  companies come on. Yeah, you know, just look at the history. Opt-in
Speaker 5:  is never the solution. The option has got to be for the customer. You
Speaker 5:  can't just automatically opt people in. And that's where it all went a little
Speaker 5:  sideways, but they did walk it back and now whenever you
Speaker 5:  buy a Ring device or a Amazon device, which is
Speaker 5:  sidewalk enabled, which is not all of them, but a large majority of them,
Speaker 5:  you do get to choose to turn it on. But that backlash is still
Speaker 5:  strong and people are still kind of mad about it because Sidewalk does use
Speaker 5:  your bandwidth. So basically it's kind of a toss up here between
Speaker 5:  are the benefits of what Sidewalk is offering something that you are interested
Speaker 5:  in and that you think is going to be good for you slash your community?
Speaker 5:  Or do you think this is Amazon just kind of making a power grab for
Speaker 5:  your internet and you just wanna switch it off?
Speaker 2:  Okay, so there's sort of two things going on here that I think are interesting.
Speaker 2:  One is that I feel like from that like first use case you described, right,
Speaker 2:  where it's like I need a way for my doorbell to connect to
Speaker 2:  my device when the wifi is not working is like a very
Speaker 2:  common thing. These are the sorts of things we're trying to fix. There's
Speaker 2:  also this bigger sort of community angle that I have a
Speaker 2:  slightly harder time wrapping my head around that it's like one of their,
Speaker 2:  the big announcement this week was Amazon is like, we're rolling this network
Speaker 2:  out completely. It covers 90% of US citizens. And to me it's like
Speaker 2:  who cares? Like why I don't need my doorbell to access my
Speaker 2:  neighbor's doorbell. I just wanted to access my phone. So what's the like
Speaker 2:  big network case here? Because part of me thinks if you wanna go sort
Speaker 2:  of full conspiracy brain, this is like Amazon, sort of
Speaker 2:  Trojan Hoing. Its way into essentially building like a national
Speaker 2:  network on which it can do anything and it's now an I S P and it doesn't
Speaker 2:  have to play anybody else's games. And it's like you can sort of spin out
Speaker 2:  in this if you want to. Is there a smaller version
Speaker 2:  of what Amazon is trying to do here? Like what, what's their argument for
Speaker 2:  why this needs to be a gigantic nationwide network instead of just existing
Speaker 2:  inside of your home?
Speaker 5:  Their argument is that there are already
Speaker 5:  billions of connected devices, but the future is
Speaker 5:  hundreds of billions of connected devices. That is a pretty
Speaker 5:  likely outcome. You know, the internet of things is not getting smaller.
Speaker 5:  There are sensors everywhere. Everything that anyone wants to connect to
Speaker 5:  the internet needs some form of a sensor. The problem right now is if you
Speaker 5:  are outside of wifi, so if you're outside your home or outside of business,
Speaker 5:  the only reliable connectivity you get is from
Speaker 5:  cellular, cellular data, be it lte, 4g,
Speaker 5:  5g, whatever we, whatever comes next is expensive. And most
Speaker 5:  of these sensors don't need the amount of data that a cellular
Speaker 5:  network provides. They only need really small
Speaker 5:  packets of data to send their signals, minuscule
Speaker 5:  amounts of data and very low power cellular radios
Speaker 5:  require more power. So their argument is we need to connect more
Speaker 5:  devices to the internet. We know there are more devices coming online, we
Speaker 5:  need an infrastructure and they're not wrong. We do need an infrastructure
Speaker 5:  that will connect devices outside of our homes and outside of our businesses.
Speaker 5:  Because ultimately if the Internet of things is going to bring everything
Speaker 5:  it's promised from, you know, decentralized power stations to
Speaker 5:  helping us find our lost dog, to
Speaker 5:  tracking packages, to keeping tabs on
Speaker 5:  food waste. I mean there's so many things that adding a sensor to
Speaker 5:  products or devices or people or
Speaker 5:  pets, there's so much that can be done. But you don't wanna spend $15
Speaker 5:  a month to track. For example, I've had a whistle dog
Speaker 5:  tracker for about five years to help keep track of my dog
Speaker 5:  and it costs $10 a month. That is a lot of money.
Speaker 5:  And there are so many use cases where we really need connectivity.
Speaker 5:  It's so embedded into our daily life now that when you leave your
Speaker 5:  house, you know you lose that connectivity with your home unless you have
Speaker 5:  a cell phone. So that's the argument. Their argument is
Speaker 5:  when you say, well why are you doing this? Because this is free. Let's not
Speaker 5:  forget, sidewalk is a free to connect network. So unlike at
Speaker 5:  t and Verizon, if you have a device that connects to a sidewalk network,
Speaker 5:  the user's not paying for it and neither is the developer. It's a free network.
Speaker 5:  So I asked Dave Limp, who is the VP of services and
Speaker 5:  devices at at Amazon, well why are you doing this? Because it's
Speaker 5:  kind of an, you know, a bit of a, is this altruistic? And they said,
Speaker 5:  well we need it. Dave said, you know, Amazon needs this. I mean
Speaker 5:  who has packages all over the country at any one minute?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, fair. So and also what's in it for them is
Speaker 5:  he, he explained that in theory some of the customers that are gonna use
Speaker 5:  the network, so like developers who build devices that are used on
Speaker 5:  the network potentially will use their cloud services aws.
Speaker 5:  So there's potential revenue stream there, right? Amazon sidewalk is
Speaker 5:  not the only option. Obviously there are other power wide area
Speaker 5:  networks out there. People mention, you know, apple air tags,
Speaker 5:  that's ecosystem is is one example
Speaker 2:  And functions basically exactly the same way, right? That is
Speaker 5:  Kind
Speaker 2:  Of a sneaky device to device thing that you don't necessarily know. And
Speaker 2:  if you think about it's sort of sketchy, but then if you think more about
Speaker 2:  it, it's really not that bad. Like I feel like that's the path a lot of these
Speaker 2:  are going down.
Speaker 5:  The really key thing here is use cases. Once it becomes
Speaker 5:  obvious how this benefits people, that's where you kind of reach tipping
Speaker 5:  point. And whether or not this is a good thing it that's when we will know.
Speaker 5:  And that's why Amazon announced this because they want
Speaker 5:  developers to build things. Once there are devices on the network,
Speaker 5:  then we can see is this worth what we are
Speaker 5:  sacrificing? I mean it's not entirely different from what from using Gmail.
Speaker 5:  Sure you get a great service but you are giving your data,
Speaker 5:  you know, nothing's free on the internet as we know. So you have to decide
Speaker 5:  is it worth it to you to be able to track your dog or
Speaker 5:  one example is Care Band is is on Sidewalk and so that's
Speaker 5:  a wearable tracker for elderly patients and it's sort of the
Speaker 5:  idea is used someone with dementia leaves their home and wanders off,
Speaker 5:  you're able to track them down rather than having to pay for one of these,
Speaker 5:  you know, cellular devices that would cost a lot of money in the long run.
Speaker 5:  You know, so use cases, and this is where the fall down has happened
Speaker 5:  with previous systems similar to Sidewalk. There's one called
Speaker 5:  Helium. Helium is exactly this and it is, it has very similar use
Speaker 5:  cases, it's very similar network, but where it sort of failed
Speaker 5:  is very few devices use it. So when you don't have the use cases
Speaker 5:  then things start to fall apart. So that's why you know, Amazon's
Speaker 5:  pushing this so aggressively to start, you know, they're giving it away for
Speaker 5:  free. They're giving away these little test kits for free. I had one and
Speaker 5:  I drove around my neighborhood to see what the signal
Speaker 5:  strength was and I live in the southeast in a corner of Charleston, which
Speaker 5:  is not a rural area, but there are rural areas near me. And I was actually
Speaker 5:  very impressed at how strong the coverage was considering,
Speaker 5:  you know, I am in the east, which is much more populated. If you look at
Speaker 5:  the map that they released once you start getting out west, there's definitely
Speaker 5:  large gaps in coverage.
Speaker 2:  The thing I've really been trying to sort through my feelings on this is
Speaker 2:  how I feel about the fact that it's Amazon
Speaker 5:  Doing Amazon
Speaker 2:  Because on the one hand you, you can sort of talk yourself into like Amazon's
Speaker 2:  as good a steward of it as anybody, right? Like I'm trusting Verizon with
Speaker 2:  all my data in one way. I'm trusting Comcast with it in another, like why
Speaker 2:  not Amazon? All that, all the internet goes through AWS anyway. So
Speaker 2:  like my life runs on Amazon's networks whether I
Speaker 2:  want it to or not regardless. So it's like I end up in that sort of position
Speaker 2:  of like eh, Amazon's as reasonable a steward of data as
Speaker 2:  anybody and has made as far as I can tell, pretty strong promises
Speaker 2:  and assurances about like the security of this network that seems to have
Speaker 2:  made most people feel pretty good, right?
Speaker 5:  Yes. Yes it has. It's published a white paper, it has you know,
Speaker 5:  three layers of encryption. None of the network traffic is visible to
Speaker 5:  Amazon. Devices that actually connect on via sidewalk
Speaker 5:  don't have internet access themselves. So it's not like they're coming into
Speaker 5:  your network. There are a lot of privacy
Speaker 5:  and security layers here. But as
Speaker 5:  with anything connected to the internet in any way, shape or form, there's
Speaker 5:  always potential for some kind of workaround or a hack. But in terms
Speaker 5:  of trusting Amazon from what they've presented and what we
Speaker 5:  know and obviously we haven't been able to test yet cuz this hasn't been
Speaker 5:  deployed at mass scale, whether you aren't giving your data
Speaker 5:  to Amazon by using sidewalk, unless you are using a
Speaker 5:  ring device to an Amazon Echo device, then you're just all in the Amazon
Speaker 5:  ecosystem
Speaker 2:  Anyway that you, you've, you know what you've signed up for at that point,
Speaker 5:  Right? So if you decide to enable sidewalk on any of your devices, you can
Speaker 5:  actually, you have the choice to show location or not. So
Speaker 5:  a device trying to connect to you can know where you are
Speaker 5:  or not. So there are tools that the user can control,
Speaker 5:  but as we know from going back to when this first started,
Speaker 5:  no one really knows about Sidewalk. So you know, people don't know
Speaker 5:  to go and turn this off if they're not not comfortable with it. But now going
Speaker 5:  forward and has been for about a year, maybe two years now, if you
Speaker 5:  buy an Echo on a ring device, it does make you opt in.
Speaker 5:  You c it's not on by default. Right? But looking at that map,
Speaker 5:  a lot of people have opted in. I mean there is a large coverage
Speaker 5:  across the country, 90% of the US population they say
Speaker 5:  and it's impressive. And it is a little scary though like, like we've just
Speaker 5:  turned this on and hey look yeah, we're everywhere.
Speaker 5:  So yes, I'm with you, I'm, I'm conflicted. I really
Speaker 5:  want the connectivity. I have no cell service in my house so when my wifi
Speaker 5:  goes down, nothing works.
Speaker 5:  And it's, it's frustrating and you know, if you live in big cities and you
Speaker 5:  have great cellular service, it's not so much of an issue but the rest of
Speaker 5:  the country it's an issue. But yes, having one company, whether it's
Speaker 5:  Amazon or Apple or anyone else that came up with this is concerning. Not
Speaker 5:  because necessarily there's nefarious intent but because they can
Speaker 5:  just change it like it's free now. But in a year's time
Speaker 5:  they might decide to charge and now you've been depending on this and
Speaker 5:  oh now what do I do?
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah, I mean like welcome to the problem of how we've set all of this
Speaker 2:  stuff up in so many ways. But the other part of it I wonder is the
Speaker 2:  fact that it's Amazon, this is actually probably a good segue into the like
Speaker 2:  platform wars we're about to talk about in the like inter-operating
Speaker 2:  standards that we all wish would exist. It seems to me that since Sidewalk
Speaker 2:  exists, say Google is less likely to support Sidewalk than it is to
Speaker 2:  build something like Sidewalk out of its own devices, apple already has the
Speaker 2:  fine my ecosystem that it could pretty easily sort of flip into the way that
Speaker 2:  that it's home kit stuff works, Z-Wave exists, thread exists.
Speaker 2:  Like you, you could, I'm, I'm imagining a world where instead of having
Speaker 2:  one thing sipping off a little piece of my network for the common
Speaker 2:  good, I have 12 things sipping off of pieces of my network for the common
Speaker 2:  good and suddenly half of my bandwidth is used by my neighbor to make their
Speaker 2:  doorbell work. Like are we, are we headed down the road of like instead of
Speaker 2:  one good version of this network we're gonna have 50 just because Amazon
Speaker 2:  built the first one or is there a version of this that actually kind of
Speaker 2:  inter-operates for everybody?
Speaker 5:  So and and I think I said this in my article, Amazon feels like
Speaker 5:  at right now the only company that could have done it because as
Speaker 5:  much as we like to think they're not a monopoly, they have so many
Speaker 5:  devices out there, they gave away those echoes for free basically.
Speaker 2:  But there are more iPhones than there are Echos. No,
Speaker 5:  But an iPhone isn't gonna work as an always on powered little radio
Speaker 5:  in your home. That's true. Right? That's fair. That's that's the thing, this
Speaker 5:  is like a little mini cell tower in your home and if you have two or
Speaker 5:  three of them or if you have a Ring floodlight cameras on the side of your
Speaker 5:  house, you know, I don't see a way that Apple's gonna be able to do this.
Speaker 5:  There aren't enough HomePod minis out there or Apple TVs
Speaker 2:  Definitely not. Not even close.
Speaker 5:  No. And the same with Google Nest minis and hubs. I mean they gave 'em away
Speaker 5:  for free but you know, I think the orders of magnitude between what
Speaker 5:  Apples and Google have out there versus Amazon is
Speaker 5:  significantly different. So yes, I think there is a concern there though
Speaker 5:  that if Google and Apple don't want to jump on the Amazon
Speaker 5:  bandwagon, that we could end up with competing. We do have competing
Speaker 5:  networks. I mean there we mentioned Helium and then we've got the fine, my
Speaker 5:  Samsung has, it's also Samsung has a similar sort of tracking
Speaker 5:  protocol for its tags and then its Little Bridge is a
Speaker 5:  a hub for that in your home. So that we could have multiple ones.
Speaker 5:  I don't know that it's necessarily worth it for the other companies at this
Speaker 5:  point because there's a big difference and this is the difference I think
Speaker 5:  between say Sidewalk and wifi or Matter is
Speaker 5:  Sidewalk is about, and the way I see it's bridging the smart home
Speaker 5:  with like the smart city, it's taking your home, connecting
Speaker 5:  the gap between the two. Whereas most of these other protocols like
Speaker 5:  Z-Wave thread and design for the Smart Home itself. And what we need is,
Speaker 5:  is just that gap between once we step outside our home
Speaker 5:  and get into our business or wherever we are going, we need something to
Speaker 5:  cover that. And that's, that's why they called it Sidewalk. That's kind of
Speaker 5:  the purpose. Although the way it's been deployed initially,
Speaker 5:  it does seem more of a competitor to things like Thread and Z-Wave
Speaker 5:  because they at launch they have like smart locks and smart sensors
Speaker 5:  in your home. So it there is crossover there, which is what kind of
Speaker 5:  muddied the water a little bit for me. I'm like why? Why should this work
Speaker 5:  for Smart Locks? I get that it's gonna work for like a mailbox sensor or
Speaker 5:  for a dog tracker. But I think as we said at the beginning of this
Speaker 5:  conversation, Amazon just wants anyone and anything to start using this
Speaker 5:  network so that we can start seeing the benefits of helping, you know, of
Speaker 5:  helping our smart homes. Because a lot of these networks that are
Speaker 5:  already exist that we've discussed briefly are more industrially
Speaker 5:  iot. They're more about reading your smart meters or
Speaker 5:  they're being used for like wildfire tracking, for inventory management,
Speaker 5:  package tracking, a lot of industrial use cases. Sidewalk
Speaker 5:  is much more squarely focused at consumer use cases but we just don't,
Speaker 5:  we haven't seen a lot of them yet. So we are waiting, waiting to see what
Speaker 5:  developers come up with now that they've sort of opened this up.
Speaker 2:  Okay, fair enough. And that's a good segue into the second part of this I
Speaker 2:  wanna talk about, which is why nobody is building cool smart home stuff and
Speaker 2:  that's not actually what it is. It feels like that sometimes, but that's
Speaker 2:  not actually I talk about what I wanna talk about is matter because it feels
Speaker 2:  like we were here, I don't know, six months ago and it was like
Speaker 2:  Matter, matter is here, this is matter's moment. And then I went on
Speaker 2:  parental leave and forgot about Matter for a while and then lucky you, you
Speaker 2:  went to CES and everybody was talking about Matter and Matter was the thing
Speaker 2:  and Matter was like the story of CES and it felt like momentum was
Speaker 2:  really good. And then I feel like, and maybe this is just me over the last,
Speaker 2:  I don't know, three or four weeks, it feels like there have been cracks
Speaker 2:  in the the matter world that that it feels like it's losing
Speaker 2:  some of the momentum that some of the big players are starting to say, well
Speaker 2:  maybe, maybe either now is not the time or this is not the thing.
Speaker 2:  Or some combination thereof. So am I reading the
Speaker 2:  vibes correctly there? What are the vibes around matter right now?
Speaker 5:  So as my esteemed former colleague at, I used to
Speaker 5:  work for a website called The Ambient that covered the smart Home
Speaker 5:  very succinctly put it, he posted this week all the
Speaker 5:  major matter players are singing the same song but in their own key at
Speaker 5:  different times and with vastly different words. And that's
Speaker 5:  essentially that's good. What he says is so true.
Speaker 5:  Everyone is on board, everyone is still working towards a solution
Speaker 5:  that was promised, which is buy a smart home device, plug it
Speaker 5:  in, it just works, right? That was the big promise. Yep. But
Speaker 5:  we are still a really long way until we're in
Speaker 5:  the Albert Hall with a concert and everyone's singing a beautiful song together.
Speaker 5:  It is a bit of a mess right now. Nothing is working to
Speaker 5:  go back to, originally we talked about it how matter is an
Speaker 5:  infrastructure, it's the plumbing, right? It's the roads for the smart home,
Speaker 5:  it's something we can build on. The problem is plumbing doesn't work when
Speaker 5:  you don't have a toilet and the highways fall apart when there's no bridges.
Speaker 5:  And that's where we are at right now. We have all these pieces and parts,
Speaker 5:  but then crucial bits are missing. So
Speaker 5:  the connections are not working. For example, Amazon doesn't
Speaker 5:  support thread. So thread devices will only work with
Speaker 5:  Google, Samsung, and Apple. So if you go buy thread devices that work
Speaker 5:  with Matter and you use Amazon Smart Home system, it's not gonna
Speaker 5:  work. That's a big missing chunk. We've got no
Speaker 5:  support for Google Home or Amazon Alexa on iPhones
Speaker 5:  right now. So you can use, obviously you can use Alexa app and
Speaker 5:  the Google Home app on iOS but not with matter devices. So again,
Speaker 5:  these major pieces of the infrastructure are missing. Once they are
Speaker 5:  there things will should proceed as promised. I think
Speaker 5:  essentially to boil it all down, they should have waited another six months
Speaker 5:  to launch Matter Matter should have come out this summer, but
Speaker 2:  It also seems like it needs like a flagship thing
Speaker 2:  that it doesn't have. Because one of the things that really jumped out to
Speaker 2:  me was the Hugh announcement and basically like the Hugh lights are, I feel
Speaker 2:  like one of the great success stories of the smart home. Like they're, they're
Speaker 2:  very good, they're very successful, lots of people have them. And Hugh was
Speaker 2:  basically, if I'm remembering the announcement correctly, basically like
Speaker 2:  we're still probably gonna do this but not right now and we're
Speaker 2:  suddenly not feeling the need to be in a giant hurry to turn this on because
Speaker 2:  there's really nothing that people gain from it. And I read that and it's
Speaker 2:  like, well you're kind of right. Like there's nothing that I as a Hugh user
Speaker 2:  seem to be standing to gain from them
Speaker 2:  doing all of this work to support matter right this minute. So you're either
Speaker 2:  relying on somebody just like out of the, the goodness of their heart and
Speaker 2:  the belief in the future to build in a bunch of stuff that doesn't really
Speaker 2:  work yet or there needs to be a thing like somebody needs
Speaker 2:  to make something that is matter specific and it just doesn't seem like that
Speaker 2:  thing is coming.
Speaker 5:  No, I don't think it is. The biggest issue with matter right now is
Speaker 5:  what is the benefit that is the problem. The consumer can't see the benefit.
Speaker 5:  The manufacturers are struggling to see the benefit other than this
Speaker 5:  is for the greater good and we need to have a great strong infrastructure
Speaker 5:  to build on. But the problem is the smart home is about experiences
Speaker 5:  and there are many experiences that companies like Hugh and Nano
Speaker 5:  Leaf and door lock manufacturers like Yale and August
Speaker 5:  offer to their users like auto unlock when you approach your door,
Speaker 5:  that's a neat smart home use case. Having your lights automatically
Speaker 5:  change with the sun during the day. That's a great smart home
Speaker 5:  use case matter doesn't support any of those features Matter is just very
Speaker 5:  basic. And this is intentionally the way it was created
Speaker 5:  because companies, manufacturers want to be able to distinguish
Speaker 5:  their products and this was where Bekin comes in. If you
Speaker 5:  recall a few weeks ago, Belkin who produces Wemo
Speaker 5:  products said we're not gonna make matter stuff anymore.
Speaker 5:  We said we would now we've changed our mind. And essentially they said we
Speaker 5:  changed our mind because our products don't have anything that
Speaker 5:  necessarily makes and stand out in the new matter landscape. Right?
Speaker 5:  So this is where there's a big tension right now. We're trying to,
Speaker 5:  you know, cause you still don't, we were promised we weren't gonna have to
Speaker 5:  use like seven different apps or have five different bridges right when
Speaker 5:  Masha arrived. And right now we do matter doesn't cha doesn't
Speaker 5:  fix those problems. So this is where the companies you know, are still need
Speaker 5:  to work together and figure out how they're gonna make these experiences
Speaker 5:  work. The way it's likely to happen is it's gonna come down to the platforms
Speaker 5:  again, which means, again, you're gonna still have to be stuck
Speaker 5:  in ecosystems like in little Ward Gardens if you want certain
Speaker 5:  features, but matter will mean that you can easily
Speaker 5:  switch between them. So just like you have to choose a cell phone carrier,
Speaker 5:  you have to choose an ecosystem, but it should be pretty easy to
Speaker 5:  switch.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, and I think the, the Bekin thing is so funny to me because I, I read
Speaker 2:  that whole announcement and it, it just comes off like the most
Speaker 2:  epic self own of all time where it's just Bekin being like, well
Speaker 2:  we can't figure out how to make good interesting products that are better
Speaker 2:  than anybody else. So we're just gonna, we're just gonna stop and we're gonna
Speaker 2:  force you to buy our products because we have like pretty
Speaker 2:  good distribution and we sell our stuff in Apple stores so we're just gonna
Speaker 2:  con you into buying our crap that doesn't work with anybody else because
Speaker 2:  if we did the thing everybody else is doing, you would just buy cheaper versions
Speaker 2:  of it on Amazon. I still think it's mostly a cell phone, but I do see at
Speaker 2:  least a little bit of Belkin's point here.
Speaker 5:  I mean the initial reaction was, oh bad Belkin, but it was
Speaker 5:  kind of brave and kind of like, okay yeah we, we
Speaker 5:  we're kind of in a rock and a hard place and we don't really know what to
Speaker 5:  do so we're just gonna stop. These companies in the smart home are scared
Speaker 5:  of commodification. That was always gonna be an issue with matter like from
Speaker 5:  the beginning. But commodification is actually what we as
Speaker 5:  consumers want.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's great news.
Speaker 5:  It's good. Yes. Yeah, we want, I would like Belkin to produce Wemo
Speaker 5:  products that work with everyone and only cost $5.
Speaker 5:  Yes. But just turn on and off and just give me the basic features that I
Speaker 5:  need. I mean the smart home is a natural evolution of the home. So eventually
Speaker 5:  when you go into a Home Depot or you go to Amazon to buy your light
Speaker 5:  bulb, you don't need to see whether it works with one voice assistant or
Speaker 5:  this protocol. You just buy it like you would any light bulb and
Speaker 5:  it will be connected to your home. That's where we need to go.
Speaker 2:  One undercurrent of the stories you've been writing about this stuff is that
Speaker 2:  Apple seems to be, if not the holdout then at least like
Speaker 2:  one of the more sort of complicated parts of this
Speaker 2:  strategy that Apple obviously has this big focus on security that has
Speaker 2:  made a, made it harder for companies to work with other stuff and also home
Speaker 2:  kit over time. And Apple also I think has a, a long history and
Speaker 2:  vested interest in things not being super interoperable. What is
Speaker 2:  Apple's role in kind of this moment as we're making
Speaker 2:  this transition? Like is it, is it the stick in the mud, is it moving stuff
Speaker 2:  along? How is Apple doing here?
Speaker 5:  I think it's been very interesting. Apple is probably the most
Speaker 5:  vocal supporter of matter of all of the
Speaker 5:  ecosystems. Okay. But vocal in Apple's way in that they never actually say
Speaker 5:  anything,
Speaker 2:  Right?
Speaker 5:  So that's why it's been kind of hard to pass. But from talking to people
Speaker 5:  who sort of are in the discussions and, and sort of know what's going on
Speaker 5:  behind the scenes, basically Home Kit was not really a success
Speaker 5:  for Apple. It was complicated. It was hard. So to them matter
Speaker 5:  is the solution for the smart home for them. That's why they, they're sort
Speaker 5:  of phasing out home kit. They've rebranded themselves, they're now Apple
Speaker 5:  Home, right? And they want everyone to work with Matter so that they can
Speaker 5:  work with Apple. They don't want to have to deal with this separate ecosystem
Speaker 5:  anymore, but they're, they're a stick in the mud in that they keep their
Speaker 5:  cards close to their chest and matter requires
Speaker 5:  openness so that developers can figure out how to
Speaker 5:  connect. And this is, from what I understand, one of the holdups with the
Speaker 5:  Google Home and the Amazon Alexa apps coming to iOS.
Speaker 5:  Mm. Apple has changed things every time they release a new
Speaker 5:  iOS update. And then there's also some struggles as we've
Speaker 5:  seen with 16.4 that just came out, which is the first time they've brought
Speaker 5:  back the new home kit architecture,
Speaker 2:  Right? There was the new architecture and then the old architecture and then
Speaker 2:  now it's the new architecture.
Speaker 5:  Now we're back to the new one because the, the rollout of the first one was
Speaker 5:  kind of a mess. That's a holdup. So I don't think Apple is stonewalling
Speaker 5:  anything here. Certainly not on purpose. I think
Speaker 5:  it's a complicated process for them to kind of untangle themselves from home
Speaker 5:  kit and reopen their platform to matter. And that's what they're
Speaker 5:  trying to do. And again, this is why all of this is taking so long crucial
Speaker 5:  parts of the infrastructure just have not connected again
Speaker 5:  six months. They launched in November matter, they probably should have launched
Speaker 5:  it this summer or next November. It is going to be a long time
Speaker 5:  until I come back on the Vergecast and say, Hey Matt just works.
Speaker 2:  It's gonna be a great day. That will be a great, great day on the Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta move on Jen. Thank you. Appreciate it as always.
Speaker 2:  We'll see you again to yell about manner six months.
Speaker 5:  Sounds good.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna take a really quick break and then we are gonna come back and
Speaker 2:  we're gonna go into New York City and test some laptop mics with Monica
Speaker 2:  Gin. We'll be right back.
Speaker 6:  Support for this podcast comes from Slack. Some of you might remember work
Speaker 6:  before the internet. Some of you might not. Either way, work today relies
Speaker 6:  on the internet and if your team hasn't made the switch to Slack, you might
Speaker 6:  find it just as vital a tool for staying connected and getting work done.
Speaker 6:  It's built to make work simpler and more connected. Not to mention
Speaker 6:  more pleasant. Slack is a productivity platform that connects all your team
Speaker 6:  members together instantly. It's built to help your team with a host of features
Speaker 6:  like huddles for quick check-ins and clips for recording and sharing video.
Speaker 6:  Slack also makes it easy to search and find the right information you need.
Speaker 6:  You can even integrate the apps you use in your normal workflow
Speaker 6:  like your calendar or project management tools so you can stay focused on
Speaker 6:  the work that matters and get more done. So if you wanna make sure your team
Speaker 6:  has all the tools they need to work well then check out Slack. Learn more
Speaker 6:  at slack.com/productivity.
Speaker 7:  Well folks, here we are, former president Donald Trump
Speaker 7:  has been indicted by a Manhattan grand jury. I'm Preet
Speaker 7:  Barara, the former US attorney in Manhattan. My podcast
Speaker 7:  stay tuned is about law, justice, power and democracy.
Speaker 7:  Recently I broke down the indictment with a group of former federal prosecutors
Speaker 7:  who understand how the justice system really works.
Speaker 7:  Joyce Vance, Barb McQuaid and Eli Hoig.
Speaker 7:  We discuss the questions on everyone's mind like
Speaker 8:  Can you directly tie Donald Trump to the way these
Speaker 8:  payments were booked and logged?
Speaker 9:  Are prosecutors considering additional defendants or additional charges?
Speaker 7:  Is this the kind of conduct that merits a charge of a former president of
Speaker 7:  the United States? I
Speaker 10:  Think this is a serious crime freak and I think it's one that I would charge.
Speaker 7:  And where do we go from here?
Speaker 9:  The presidency from prison, right? I mean add to the crazy
Speaker 7:  Add to the crazy to listen. Just search. Stay tuned
Speaker 7:  wherever you get your podcasts. New episodes drop every Thursday.
Speaker 7:  Stay tuned.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back every now and then on this show we like to do a microphone
Speaker 2:  test because we spend a lot of time worrying about our headphones
Speaker 2:  and how things sound to us, but not enough time testing
Speaker 2:  our microphones and how we sound to others. Last year we stress
Speaker 2:  tested the microphones on a bunch of flagship wireless earbuds to
Speaker 2:  see which sounded the best for voice calls. You should go listen, it's all
Speaker 2:  over the vergecast last year. But the short version is this, the Sony Link
Speaker 2:  Buds, apple AirPods and Google Pixel Buds Pro are all pretty good. The
Speaker 2:  $20 Apple EarPods, the ones that actually plug in are amazing.
Speaker 2:  Everything else we've tested is less good. But the thing
Speaker 2:  is not everyone uses earbuds for Zoom and meet and teams
Speaker 2:  or whatever else you use for calls and video chats. So for this
Speaker 2:  test we're checking out how the microphones on a bunch of laptops sound to
Speaker 2:  figure out which is the best for taking calls, meetings, and even just
Speaker 2:  recording audio with the built-in mic. You might remember that when
Speaker 2:  we tested earbud microphones with Chris Welch last year, we sampled what
Speaker 2:  the laptop mic sounded like too and it, well it sounded like
Speaker 2:  trash.
Speaker 11:  You hear everything, the whole world,
Speaker 11:  there's, there's a truck
Speaker 2:  But things change fast. So we head to see can laptops handle
Speaker 2:  a voice call? Can you get away with no extra gear
Speaker 2:  whatsoever? The next time you get on Zoom or meet Monica Chin is
Speaker 2:  the verges laptop reviewer and she helped us stress test a few of these laptop
Speaker 2:  microphones. So while I sit comfortably at my desk at home in Virginia,
Speaker 2:  we sent Monica with our producer Andrew Marino, to the single
Speaker 2:  most chaotic spot we could think of in New York City.
Speaker 12:  So we are walking through the middle of Times Square, which is
Speaker 12:  probably the loudest place in New York City that you can go besides a concert.
Speaker 2:  What you're hearing there is the 2021 MacBook Pro. It's the 16
Speaker 2:  inch one, the one with the Mpro chip.
Speaker 12:  This is like the laptop that our video team
Speaker 12:  really loves to record stuff on. The mics are pretty good, I
Speaker 12:  would say. How does it sound?
Speaker 2:  I cannot believe how good you sound. This is blowing my mind
Speaker 12:  Right now. Really?
Speaker 2:  Well I'm used to say these microphones being like really good but they catch
Speaker 2:  everything, right? So you get tons of background noise, you get tons of everything.
Speaker 2:  We could just have a video call with you doing this.
Speaker 12:  We could, except that I can barely hear you. But that
Speaker 2:  There's that. An important detail I should mention here is that Monica
Speaker 2:  did not wear headphones for this test. We found that a lot of people don't
Speaker 2:  have wired headphones with them when they're outta their house. So you're
Speaker 2:  going to hear a lot of my voice being picked up in the laptop's microphone,
Speaker 2:  which spoiler alert is actually one of the biggest takeaways
Speaker 2:  here. Mics are getting better, but echo cancellation mostly
Speaker 2:  still sucks and causes a lot of problems for the mics themselves
Speaker 2:  though. The biggest problem we came across with basically all laptop
Speaker 2:  microphones is when the wind picks up. Really no surprise there.
Speaker 12:  Okay, so we're getting to the most iconic part, which is the big
Speaker 12:  pkts booth where everyone hangs out.
Speaker 2:  Look, this is probably the least realistic test we've
Speaker 2:  ever done. Not many of you are walking through Times Square holding your
Speaker 2:  laptop in front of you. If you are, I have like a lot of follow up
Speaker 2:  questions for you and feel like we would be very good friends, but I
Speaker 2:  am sure that you've tried to take a call in a crowded coffee shop or
Speaker 2:  at a park in a city or in your backyard with airplanes
Speaker 2:  flying over. Not that long ago, I would've told you that. Doing
Speaker 2:  that and trying to talk into your laptop Mike was a horrible idea and
Speaker 2:  you're gonna hurt the ears of whoever you're talking to. But I kind of
Speaker 2:  couldn't believe how easy it was for me to hear Monica. So clearly
Speaker 2:  it's not amazing but it works. Now tell
Speaker 2:  me what you had for breakfast this morning.
Speaker 12:  This morning I had a K-pop from Starbucks on the way
Speaker 12:  to work.
Speaker 2:  Part of this balanced breakfast?
Speaker 12:  Yeah, exactly. I'm not a breakfast eater really usually. So that was
Speaker 12:  like a, I guess like my dessert from the night before basically.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so that's the MacBook. Next up Monica pulled out the Dell XPS
Speaker 2:  13, which has long been our go-to Windows laptop recommendation and it
Speaker 2:  held up pretty well here too.
Speaker 12:  This is one of the best Windows laptops you can get, but
Speaker 12:  it's obviously a good bit smaller than the MacBook Pro
Speaker 12:  16. We got an Intel processor inside, we got a
Speaker 12:  teeny little webcam on the top. We got downward firing speakers
Speaker 12:  on the bottom. It's a, it's a much smaller, much smaller little deal.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, so I'm hearing more and more detailed
Speaker 2:  background noise. Like I can sort of pick out individual people talking instead
Speaker 2:  of just like the Whooshing background sound that was in the MacBook
Speaker 2:  but even still your voice is coming through pretty well. I can pick you up
Speaker 2:  fine. It's definitely more processed than the MacBook. Interesting. But even
Speaker 2:  still I would, I would rank this in like mid-range headphones to be using
Speaker 2:  Interesting. In a crowd of people. Yeah, I'm like blown away by how good
Speaker 2:  this is in all cases.
Speaker 12:  One of the big things with Intel's 12th generation, which is
Speaker 12:  what's in this and the 13th judge, well which just came out, is like they
Speaker 12:  make a big deal out of AI noise processing.
Speaker 12:  So it makes, it makes sense that it would sound more processed I
Speaker 2:  Think. Yeah, it's definitely working hard to do it but it's doing a pretty
Speaker 2:  good job. Okay. Prepare herself for this one. The next laptop
Speaker 2:  Monica pulled out. She didn't tell me about before we sent her to Times Square
Speaker 2:  and when she joined our video call, it just had a sketchy name like surprise
Speaker 2:  laptop. It definitely surprised me.
Speaker 13:  Okay,
Speaker 2:  That was literally you just caused physical pain
Speaker 13:  In my headphones when you did that.
Speaker 2:  I hear everything.
Speaker 13:  Okay, so this is the Gateway 14. It is a
Speaker 13:  $400 laptop that I picked up at Walmart because I was
Speaker 13:  curious if it would work at all.
Speaker 2:  That was the first one in all of these tests that we've done that was
Speaker 2:  like actually physically painful. As soon as
Speaker 2:  Monica entered our chat here and I started hearing sound,
Speaker 2:  I like literally did the thing where you have to go like ah and just pull
Speaker 2:  your headphones off because that's what happened. That was awful.
Speaker 2:  Before we go any further, I should say that the way we recorded this was
Speaker 2:  the same as our other tests. We use an app called Riverside FM and we like
Speaker 2:  it. It because it records your local audio and then uploads it so you don't
Speaker 2:  get any of that internet artifacting or echoes. It does mean
Speaker 2:  these tests are gonna sound slightly different from what you'll sound like
Speaker 2:  on Zoom or Meet or Teams because those apps all apply their
Speaker 2:  own kind of filtering and noise canceling. This is much closer to like
Speaker 2:  the pure audio coming out of the microphones that said that Gateway
Speaker 2:  laptop was worse than just the microphones. In addition to sounding like
Speaker 2:  a metal band playing inside a scratchy tin can, while a
Speaker 2:  lawnmower goes full blast right next to my head, the computer itself
Speaker 2:  could barely even keep up with having that one Chrome tab open right
Speaker 2:  out of the box and it initially lost the recording because the
Speaker 2:  computer literally couldn't keep up. The point is it's not a very good computer.
Speaker 2:  I wouldn't use it for this or anything if you have another option.
Speaker 2:  Okay, let's get back to better sounding things. The next laptop we tested
Speaker 2:  out was a Chromebook. The Lenovo idea Pad five I gaming Chromebook. To
Speaker 2:  be specific, lots of people use Chromebooks, especially in education and
Speaker 2:  we live in a remote world and lots of people take classes online and this
Speaker 2:  actually seems like something you'd hope Chromebooks specifically would be
Speaker 2:  good at.
Speaker 12:  All right, we are here. Ugh,
Speaker 2:  This is so much better.
Speaker 12:  We are on a 15 inch gaming Chromebook.
Speaker 2:  Where does this fall in like the range of Chromebooks?
Speaker 12:  I mean it's not terrible, it's got a little bit of a plasticy build but
Speaker 12:  you know it's got a big screen, it's got a nice little numb pad
Speaker 12:  here on the right side of the keyboard. The audio is way too quiet to be
Speaker 12:  using a Times Square, but you know if you're gonna be using headphones all
Speaker 12:  the time then maybe that doesn't matter so much to you.
Speaker 2:  This is a good middle ground of like the good ones that we heard at the beginning
Speaker 2:  and the horrible garbage one that we heard before. This one is like I can
Speaker 2:  hear a bunch of background noise, there's definitely more wind and
Speaker 2:  stuff coming into the mic than before, but I can still hear you and if we
Speaker 2:  had a call like this, I would not hate your guts. Whereas like three minutes
Speaker 2:  of that last one and like I don't wanna be friends with you anymore,
Speaker 12:  Could you hear, there was a man wrapping in front of me just now, but it
Speaker 12:  sounds like it wasn't. No that wasn't quite coming through.
Speaker 2:  It does seem like I'm picking up a lot more behind you
Speaker 2:  than behind the computer, which is interesting
Speaker 12:  I guess. Yeah, the microphones are facing that way.
Speaker 2:  So this is actually a good example cuz as I'm looking at you, a crowd of
Speaker 2:  people just walked up behind you and I could hear all of them talking,
Speaker 2:  but then when somebody walked right in front of you behind the computer,
Speaker 2:  I didn't hear that at all. That's very
Speaker 12:  Interesting. Interesting. So I guess if I'm doing call in Time Square, I
Speaker 12:  want to be sitting at the back of Times Square facing
Speaker 2:  The X face your back to a building or something. Exactly,
Speaker 12:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Laptop number five also falls into the, probably ought to be good at
Speaker 2:  this category. It's the Lenovo ThinkPad X 13. It's kind of a classic business
Speaker 2:  laptop, but this one is actually built with mobility in mind, which is all
Speaker 2:  the more reason that the mic should be good.
Speaker 12:  This is a Lenovo thing pad. It's super, super light and it actually
Speaker 12:  is a Snap Dragon chip inside. It's powered byd, snap Dragon eight, CX
Speaker 12:  gen three.
Speaker 2:  This is one of those computers that's like trying to kind of be a tablet
Speaker 2:  and it's like very mobile on purpose. Correct. Right. So it should be good
Speaker 2:  at this. It's
Speaker 12:  Super, super thin. It's like, it feels like it weighs nothing, but
Speaker 12:  I don't know how good the speakers are. It's very, very thin. So there's
Speaker 12:  not a ton of room for great great microphones necessarily.
Speaker 2:  It's doing less processing than most. So like your
Speaker 2:  voice actually sounds really good. Oh, okay. I'm also picking up a lot more
Speaker 2:  background noise.
Speaker 12:  Can you hear, there's like a, there's like a party happening down and a
Speaker 12:  bunch of people cheering I think. Oh, people are screaming at Mickey Mouse
Speaker 12:  down the block. Can you hear
Speaker 2:  That? No. Spin me around. Let's see if we can hear.
Speaker 12:  Oh I think Mickey Mouse. There he is. Yeah, Mickey Mouse and
Speaker 12:  Sonic are walking into the levees store and people are very excited
Speaker 12:  about it, but I can hear you much better as well, which is, this is
Speaker 12:  a big relief.
Speaker 2:  Okay, let's wrap this up. One more test subject. Let's go back to Apple.
Speaker 2:  That first one we tested, we kind of knew was gonna be the best
Speaker 2:  mic of the group, but this one's probably the most common laptop
Speaker 2:  you're gonna see out there. This is the newest MacBook error with the M two
Speaker 2:  chip. It's the laptop. I just tell everyone to buy it because it's great
Speaker 2:  and you'll like it fine, but it turns out having a better mic array in the
Speaker 2:  pro really does make a difference.
Speaker 12:  We are here with the M two MacBook Air, tiny little,
Speaker 12:  tiny little guy and it is about to get a lot louder cuz we're gonna walk
Speaker 12:  to the subway station. How are we sounding on this one?
Speaker 2:  This is, I would put like right in line with the
Speaker 2:  ThinkPad in Dell, like that first really MacBook is clearly better than everything
Speaker 2:  else.
Speaker 12:  Oh, interesting. Because that's one of the things that, you know, sometimes
Speaker 12:  you wonder like how much of the microphone performance
Speaker 12:  is the physical hardware and how much of it is the software, and
Speaker 12:  presumably these are using the same software. So it sounds like the hardware
Speaker 12:  does make a difference. In this case
Speaker 2:  It must because that one is, is like a one order of
Speaker 2:  magnitude better than this. Like this is pretty good. It's kind of like
Speaker 2:  the think pad we were just on in the sense that it's like not a ton of
Speaker 2:  processing, which means I'm getting a little more background than usual.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, this one is definitely harder to hear than the 16 as well. The 16,
Speaker 12:  the MacPro 16 was the one where I really didn't have to lean in at all.
Speaker 12:  It is impressive to me being in an environment that's so loud
Speaker 12:  and knowing that these tiny things are filtering
Speaker 12:  out all that noise around me. Like I would not expect it's
Speaker 12:  technology, man.
Speaker 2:  We should say, as a general rule, don't do
Speaker 2:  conference calls from the middle of Times Square, but I guess it's encouraging
Speaker 2:  to know that this is a thing you can pull off if you absolutely need to.
Speaker 12:  It sounds like if you're on the 16, you can probably do it. Just don't do
Speaker 12:  them on the, don't do them on something that only costs $400 that you picked
Speaker 12:  up at Walmart and is
Speaker 2:  Blue and is and is called Gateway, which is a brand I legitimately did not
Speaker 2:  know still existed. Definitely
Speaker 12:  Don't do them when you're walking through Times Square to the subway
Speaker 12:  like I am because Andrew has had to shepherd
Speaker 12:  me across the crosswalk several times. But
Speaker 2:  All right, well you guys go don't, don't die, don't become, we'll try not
Speaker 2:  to the new spectacle in Times Square. But thank you for doing this, this
Speaker 2:  was great.
Speaker 14:  Thank you. This was really fun.
Speaker 2:  Okay, three thoughts on this before we go. First, I'm still kind of
Speaker 2:  amazed at how good these sound. I've typically told people to
Speaker 2:  avoid their built-in mics except in really quiet spaces
Speaker 2:  because even when they're decent mics, they're made to pick up audio from
Speaker 2:  a much larger area. So they tend to get much more background noise
Speaker 2:  than your average headphones because those can just point their mics right
Speaker 2:  at your mouth because they're always situated in the same place. That's still
Speaker 2:  true. A good pair of headphones will sound better than any of the laptops
Speaker 2:  we just tested, but it's much less true than it used to be. And most of
Speaker 2:  these at least fall into the totally usable in a pinch
Speaker 2:  category. Second thing, my rule is that you should always, always, always,
Speaker 2:  always, always wear headphones on a call and that rule still holds
Speaker 2:  without echo cancellation. If you're not wearing headphones, you're gonna
Speaker 2:  hear your own voice a ton with it. The computer has to
Speaker 2:  do a lot more processing so audio gets worse and you get that thing where
Speaker 2:  you can only talk one at a time, it's just a lot worse.
Speaker 2:  So even if you're using the built-in mic, you should still use headphones
Speaker 2:  also for like basic human etiquette reasons. You don't want
Speaker 2:  the world to listen to your phone calls. Another reason to wear headphones,
Speaker 2:  by the way, is that one of the most interesting things about our testing
Speaker 2:  was that Monica could barely ever hear me. I could hear her
Speaker 2:  okay through the mic, but even with the volume all the way up,
Speaker 2:  she was always having to hold her head right down by the speakers.
Speaker 2:  And even then she could barely hear me. So again, for so many
Speaker 2:  reasons, wear headphones whenever humanly possible. And third,
Speaker 2:  the hardware really does matter here. It's not an accident that the max,
Speaker 2:  which have three mics and are set up to do noise cancellation, sounded better
Speaker 2:  than the other ones, which mostly have two, or in some cases even just one
Speaker 2:  mic. But there is also a fair amount of software work here, which you can
Speaker 2:  hear in some of the audio processing, especially on the Dell and the Lenovo.
Speaker 2:  And that's really good news actually over the last couple of years. It looks
Speaker 2:  like laptop manufacturers started to care about the quality of their
Speaker 2:  microphones for basically the first time ever. So things have
Speaker 2:  gotten a lot better really quickly. Maybe someday I'll ditch this fancy
Speaker 2:  mic and just make a podcast by yelling at my computer. But here's
Speaker 2:  what that sounds like right now. So yeah, maybe not yet. Anyway,
Speaker 2:  we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and talk about Microsoft's
Speaker 2:  many adventures in ai. We'll be right back
Speaker 14:  Over the past several weeks today, explained has been going
Speaker 14:  downtown, downtown Seattle drug
Speaker 15:  Activity, like when spring and summer, you know, when they hang out all
Speaker 15:  night, it's
Speaker 14:  Worse downtown Chicago now.
Speaker 16:  It just happens anywhere, anytime of day, morning, night. Like it's just
Speaker 16:  way worse.
Speaker 14:  Philadelphia,
Speaker 17:  Lot more violence, more homeless
Speaker 14:  People. And New York City,
Speaker 18:  I see a lot of people just going and grabbing people's bags,
Speaker 18:  hitting them, they, it's like they don't
Speaker 14:  Care one through line in all these cities. Crime, the number one
Speaker 19:  Barrier that we heard from people was that fear of crime
Speaker 19:  was what was preventing them from going downtown, particularly within the
Speaker 19:  central business district itself. And on their commutes there.
Speaker 14:  Americans are scared of their downtowns, but should they be,
Speaker 14:  we're gonna find out in our city limit series on today,
Speaker 14:  explain
Speaker 20:  From New York Magazine in the Box Media Podcast network. This is the Joe
Speaker 20:  Rogan experience with a thousand percent more experience.
Speaker 20:  Or is it the Don Lemon Show with a hundred percent more understanding of
Speaker 20:  women in their prime. Just kidding. This is
Speaker 20:  on with Kara Swisher. And I'm Kara Swisher. Every Monday and Thursday I
Speaker 20:  take on big names in tech, media and politics to understand what makes
Speaker 20:  them tick and to hold their feet to the fire. A bit on
Speaker 20:  with Kara Swisher. Listen wherever you get your podcasts,
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. One of the questions I'm personally
Speaker 2:  most interested in in tech right now is, what is AI
Speaker 2:  actually good for? We've talked a ton about G P T four and chat,
Speaker 2:  G p T and Bing and Bard, but a lot of the things that we talk about are
Speaker 2:  neat novelties or there are glimpses at like a far out future
Speaker 2:  for when these products get a lot better. But the truth is AI
Speaker 2:  is much more than chatbots and Microsoft is being much
Speaker 2:  more aggressive than most in figuring out how exactly to
Speaker 2:  put AI into all of its products. The verges Tom Warren has been
Speaker 2:  writing about and testing as much of it as he can get his hands on over the
Speaker 2:  last several months. So he's here to tell us how AI is going to change the
Speaker 2:  way we do everything, at least the way Microsoft sees it. Hi
Speaker 2:  Tom.
Speaker 21:  Hello.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. It's been a while.
Speaker 21:  Yeah, it has. There's a lot happening right now.
Speaker 2:  This is why I wanted to do this cuz it feels like Bing has gotten tons of
Speaker 2:  coverage and we've talked about it a lot and it's like really interesting.
Speaker 2:  But if the question is what is AI actually good for? I feel like it's all
Speaker 2:  the other stuff that Microsoft has done, which we have not talked enough
Speaker 2:  about.
Speaker 21:  Yeah, it's, that's the promising stuff. The search engine stuff is cool,
Speaker 21:  but having it everywhere is cooler.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so let's, let's start with co-pilot, which I think is probably the
Speaker 2:  sort of biggest version of what Microsoft is thinking about here. And I was
Speaker 2:  reading a bunch of stories and realized I have a hard trouble figuring out
Speaker 2:  exactly what copilot is. It's kind of a chatbot, but it's not totally
Speaker 2:  a chatbot. It's different things in different apps, but it's kind of one
Speaker 2:  thing like frame copilot for me. What is this thing?
Speaker 21:  Yeah, so it is essentially think of like clippy or like
Speaker 21:  you call all the promises of Cortana. Sure. It's like basically an
Speaker 21:  assistant, so a virtual assistant. So yes, it can spring
Speaker 21:  up and be a chat bar and you can, you know, converse with it and stuff.
Speaker 21:  But it can also just sort of like magically appear
Speaker 21:  almost with AI magic it documents and like say,
Speaker 21:  say you highlight a paragraph and you're like, Hmm, I wanna rewrite that
Speaker 21:  or reword it or whatever. Then it'll just sort of like hint in
Speaker 21:  a way that, you know, you know when you, you goof up and you get a typo
Speaker 21:  and word comes along and underlines it, that sort of thing, it'll just sort
Speaker 21:  of gently appear and be like, I can rewrite this for you. So that's kind
Speaker 21:  of the interesting way that co-pilot works. So you can say, you know, create
Speaker 21:  a document, create a PowerPoint, create an Excel based on a bunch of
Speaker 21:  prompts, or you can drag a file into a PowerPoint or a Word
Speaker 21:  file. And then based on that, all that text, it'll generate a bunch of slides
Speaker 21:  so you can do that sort of stuff. But I think the interesting part is where
Speaker 21:  it just shows up or like in Excel, let's say it does something like you
Speaker 21:  say, here's a bunch of data, here's you know, financial earnings for this
Speaker 21:  company in the past six months. Put it into a table or pivot table
Speaker 21:  or whatever, or something you don't really know how to do. It'll then tell
Speaker 21:  you how it did it and show you how it did it. So it's like training you
Speaker 21:  as well. So it's like, it's an assistant but it's also a tutor I guess
Speaker 21:  as well. So it's like there there's a bunch to it really.
Speaker 2:  That's actually really clever cuz I think one of the things I, I was looking
Speaker 2:  at as I was reading your story is like the sort of famous office problem
Speaker 2:  over the years is that office is this like hideous mishmash of
Speaker 2:  menus because there's so much that all these apps can do that it's impossible
Speaker 2:  to figure out how they work. And Microsoft is like, we made the ribbon better
Speaker 2:  and everybody's like, all my buttons are gone. And like it's just, it's an
Speaker 2:  impossible problem and it feels like if they can get this right, like there's
Speaker 2:  somebody at Microsoft being like we can finally get rid of the ribbon, right?
Speaker 2:  Like that's has to be what's happening here.
Speaker 21:  It's the complexity of the the interface, right? And just
Speaker 21:  excels the worst for this because it's just like you can open it up and
Speaker 21:  it looks relatively simple but the stuff you can do with it, like the difference
Speaker 21:  between me using Excel and like some power user is like you know, massive
Speaker 21:  and it's just reducing that complexity and making it more available to people
Speaker 21:  and, and just easier to use. I think that's kind of like half the story
Speaker 21:  behind Copart and the other half is like, yeah you can chat to this thing,
Speaker 21:  have a back and forth, get it to do stuff and you can say to it
Speaker 21:  like you really chat G B T really. And then Bing and stuff you could
Speaker 21:  say like write this and you know, you could prompt it afterwards to, to
Speaker 21:  tweak it and make it better or make it into a list and all that sort of
Speaker 21:  basic stuff. But it's really interesting where it takes that complexity
Speaker 21:  out of office apps and then you know, just surfaces it in really interesting
Speaker 21:  ways and I think they're really at the beginning of that so there's not
Speaker 21:  like a ton of examples yet. So I was trying to like kind of get that out
Speaker 21:  of them like you know, where is this heading? But I think for me it's like,
Speaker 21:  it sounds like it's just gonna be the virtual assistant they've always promised
Speaker 21:  or the beginnings of it at least because they tried, they said that Cortana
Speaker 21:  would do this stuff. Right.
Speaker 2:  Well that's part of what I think is so interesting here cuz there's, I mean
Speaker 2:  you go back and like you mentioned Clippy and there's Cortana and there's
Speaker 2:  like one of two things that's happening here. Either Microsoft has
Speaker 2:  been right all along and finally the technology is starting to catch up to
Speaker 2:  kind of this thing that they want to build or Microsoft has been wrong all
Speaker 2:  along and just refuses to acknowledge that like, this sucks and nobody wants
Speaker 2:  it. And Clippy was either a great idea that it was too
Speaker 2:  early, Cortana was either a great idea that was too early or a total disaster
Speaker 2:  of an idea. And this feels like the same. Like why can't Microsoft let go
Speaker 2:  of this idea?
Speaker 21:  They they just all love as an assistant, don't they? I
Speaker 2:  Guess.
Speaker 21:  So it's kind of interesting cuz obviously Clippy was, it was interesting
Speaker 21:  at the time but then it got annoying cuz it would pop up when you didn't
Speaker 21:  want it to and that was obviously the meme and then Cortana was like supposed
Speaker 21:  to be this thing that would do everything for you and it just failed over.
Speaker 21:  And I think Satin Adela recently said it was dumb as a rock, right? And,
Speaker 21:  and, and all of them like, you know, Alexa and the rest, so they, they they
Speaker 21:  obviously and they, they went, they went down the route of going for bots
Speaker 21:  as well. Chatbots initially a few years ago, obviously before
Speaker 21:  Open AI models were ready. So there's always been this promise and they've
Speaker 21:  always been obsessed with it, but it does kind of feel like, okay, now's
Speaker 21:  the time where it might actually work. It's just they have to be careful
Speaker 21:  they don't go down the sort of clippy route where it pops up annoyingly,
Speaker 21:  right? And just kind of gets in the way and it's more like actually a useful
Speaker 21:  assistant that you call upon when you need stuff. But it's also like
Speaker 21:  what's the interaction model there? Like when do you call on the assistant
Speaker 21:  or the assistant appears rather you just click a button to bold something
Speaker 21:  or you know, like the user interface is still there. Like how do they lean
Speaker 21:  back from that basic user interface into this, into the complexity?
Speaker 21:  So it's a bunch of different challenges and they like customize it per
Speaker 21:  app so it doesn't do everything you'd expect in each app. So that's another
Speaker 21:  kind of like learning curve to it almost, is that you might think it's gonna
Speaker 21:  do something in this app, but then it's obviously being customized heavily
Speaker 21:  for like PowerPoint and because PowerPoint's completely different to Word.
Speaker 21:  So Yeah. So they, they have to manage a bunch of a bunch of that as well.
Speaker 21:  But from what they showed me and I have played around with it on my
Speaker 21:  own PC in Word, but it's very basic now. But from what I can see
Speaker 21:  what they've shown is it does, it is pretty impressive. I was kind of impressed
Speaker 21:  with it and I don't, and I'm old now and you know, I
Speaker 21:  I don't get excited about things.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 21:  So like this stuff is like, oh okay, this is actually interesting. So it's
Speaker 21:  not like it's not one of the city fu future vision things, it's like oh
Speaker 21:  it's actually working.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. How does it give me a sense of kind of what those demos are like? Because
Speaker 2:  I think one of the things you mentioned that jumps out to me the most is
Speaker 2:  the thing where it's like it pops up when you write a paragraph and it's
Speaker 2:  like you did this thing wrong. And I think honestly even tools like
Speaker 2:  Grammarly go too hard in a space like that. Yeah. Where it's like I'm writing
Speaker 2:  an email that I'm like deliberately writing like a person because
Speaker 2:  I'm a person and it's like, you should potentially use more formal language
Speaker 2:  in this email. And I'm like, no, Grammarly like shut up, leave me alone.
Speaker 2:  And I can imagine with all of this stuff tuning that thing between like
Speaker 2:  how do you sort of get involved and be helpful and how do you avoid being
Speaker 2:  clippy just popping up every two seconds being like, look at this thing that
Speaker 2:  you're doing. Can I help? That's a super hard line to walk and Microsoft
Speaker 2:  is going ham, doing all of this stuff. I can imagine,
Speaker 2:  yeah. A world in which they would kind of way overshoot and have to pull
Speaker 2:  it back over time. But what have you seen so far?
Speaker 21:  Yeah, so the, the basic stuff that I've seen so far is that like you highlight
Speaker 21:  a paragraph and then it kind kind of like, it does like a purple sort of
Speaker 21:  outline to the paragraph and then you, you kind of go to that purple
Speaker 21:  outline and then it's like copilot sort of like gradually appears almost
Speaker 21:  Okay. It appears like as like a prompt that you can click and then it obviously
Speaker 21:  comes into the sidebar from there and you, you know, you interact with it
Speaker 21:  and tell it how you want to rewrite the paragraph. Or it might even
Speaker 21:  actually, I think in that particular instance it comes up and says like,
Speaker 21:  here's 12 examples or whatever, I've rewritten this paragraph for you and
Speaker 21:  you can just flick through them and you can just see them, you know, the
Speaker 21:  text. So that's like, okay, because you have to take action on it. It's
Speaker 21:  there like, it's always kind of in the background so it's not like trying
Speaker 21:  to jump out or it's not trying to like suggest, you know, text to you
Speaker 21:  without you, you know, prompting it to do that. So I think that's probably
Speaker 21:  the way they will go about it, that that's the, the main one that I saw
Speaker 21:  of that sort of use case that they showed. There's some other stuff
Speaker 21:  like PowerPoint where you can add a file and then it will say,
Speaker 21:  you know, do you wanna match the colors across the slides and stuff like
Speaker 21:  that, which is kind of useful but I think right now it's like, it's less
Speaker 21:  trying to jump out at you and, and and trying to interact with you and
Speaker 21:  more like you call upon it, you know, for example, if you wanted to in
Speaker 21:  PowerPoint you wanna create a file based on that Word document you were
Speaker 21:  working earlier, it'll know what you had recently. So it'll kind of suggest
Speaker 21:  that, oh do you wanna pick this file? And you go, yeah, okay. And then it'll
Speaker 21:  take a few seconds to do that and then you, and then it'll sort of have,
Speaker 21:  you know, like in Bing where it says suggested responses after you've, you've
Speaker 21:  started talking it does that, it's oh do you wanna, you know, customize
Speaker 21:  this based on that? And the way that they're doing it right now seems to
Speaker 21:  be very, you know, baby step, step by step being careful with it. So I think
Speaker 21:  they're obviously cautious of the whole clippy stuff. So Yeah, because
Speaker 21:  did they mention Clippy on the, on the stream? I don't think they did but
Speaker 21:  I definitely asked them about that and they said, you know, they're proud
Speaker 21:  of the fact that they've tried this stuff of like helping people in the
Speaker 21:  past but yeah it to, to me it looks like they're being cautious.
Speaker 2:  Yeah and it does seem like if I'm Microsoft this is a tough spot
Speaker 2:  to be in cuz on the one hand I did get the sense reading your stories that
Speaker 2:  they think this is the moment, right? That like all the stuff we've been
Speaker 2:  trying to do, this idea of like how do we bake in these sort of helpful additional
Speaker 2:  tools. Like they're, they're not shy about how sort of big a moment they
Speaker 2:  feel like this is. I mean obviously you don't invest 10 billion in open AI
Speaker 2:  if you don't think this is the moment, right? But then on the flip side,
Speaker 2:  like the long history of Microsoft says most people
Speaker 2:  don't wanna change their workflows. People who do these things all
Speaker 2:  day every day don't want help. And yeah, what they
Speaker 2:  want is for you to like leave them alone so they can do your job. And that
Speaker 2:  has making it really hard to, you know, change the interface to change how
Speaker 2:  things work. To even add things like collaborative features has been tough
Speaker 2:  because it just screws with the way that people have been doing for things
Speaker 2:  for 30 years. Is Microsoft wary of that or is this
Speaker 2:  just kind of a like we're just gonna push through the pain because this is
Speaker 2:  the future moment?
Speaker 21:  I think they are because the way that it shows up right now is it's, it's
Speaker 21:  literally a button in the ribbon so it's not like trying to replace that
Speaker 21:  ribbon, it's just another command that you kind of summon almost for now
Speaker 21:  anyway and it comes up in a sidebar and it's been a, you know, sidebar in
Speaker 21:  office for years. So, so none of that is completely different to what
Speaker 21:  you'd expect in office. Whereas if they'd gone, you know, pulled out the
Speaker 21:  ribbon and said this is how you're gonna use it. Like they do like the exports
Speaker 21:  one with Connect, they were like, you've gotta talk to your Xbox and then
Speaker 21:  they had to like walk that all back and make it work for a controller. Yeah.
Speaker 21:  So like they haven't gone that drastic with it. So I think they're definitely
Speaker 21:  aware of that. But I think like you said, it is the moment for them, you
Speaker 21:  get a sense that they feel like they're ahead of Google right ahead of
Speaker 21:  competitors that, that are trying to do similar stuff in this, in this space
Speaker 21:  and that they're poised to sort of, you know, take on that
Speaker 21:  across everywhere. They've done a co-pilot in, they've had it in GitHub
Speaker 21:  for like a year or so now, right? Yeah. Which obviously wasn't quite as
Speaker 21:  powerful as what they showed, but then they, you know, a week later they
Speaker 21:  were like here's GitHub, Kai X or whatever. So they're going fast
Speaker 21:  everywhere and I'm sure and they announced the security co-pilot as well.
Speaker 21:  Well,
Speaker 2:  So this is what I'm trying to figure out. There's the, there's the security
Speaker 2:  co-pilot, there's co-pilot on all the apps, co-pilot exists in teams,
Speaker 2:  there's like business chat, which is kind of co-pilot kind of not
Speaker 2:  is like, is the big vision that there's this like one
Speaker 2:  assistant that you sort of interact with everywhere or is it like lots of
Speaker 2:  different little AI things across your different apps? Like how does, how
Speaker 2:  does Microsoft see it?
Speaker 21:  Yeah, I, I did ask that and I think that the basic sort of gist of the,
Speaker 21:  the co-pilots is that they're, they're tailored to each sort of instance.
Speaker 21:  Like in Word for example, it's obviously customized for, for writing and
Speaker 21:  you know, in certain imagery and stuff and PowerPoints obviously a bunch
Speaker 21:  of commands to make your slide decks look nicer and, and you can pull in
Speaker 21:  sort of, they're gonna pull in like Dali images and stuff into there and,
Speaker 21:  and Excels obviously very command driven. So it is very different per
Speaker 21:  app. And then obviously GitHub you don't want, like they, they don't have
Speaker 21:  like the G PT four chatbot sort of interface where you are
Speaker 21:  in line in your code because that's slow, you know, the, the latency there
Speaker 21:  would be too slow for them to do those automatic suggestions that they
Speaker 21:  do with the GitHub co-pilot there. So like they, they're tweaking it and
Speaker 21:  customizing it where it makes sense. Which, which I think does make sense
Speaker 21:  right now because we're still in the early phases, this stuff is still a
Speaker 21:  little bit slow for you know, that rapid response stuff that you might want
Speaker 21:  in certain scenarios but who knows long term will it
Speaker 21:  become this sort of corino sort of assistant? I think it probably will but
Speaker 21:  I think that's probably a ways off from the initial stuff that they're
Speaker 21:  adding over the next couple of years. But yeah, it makes sense
Speaker 21:  cuz like the, like you said the business chat stuff that is co-pilot but
Speaker 21:  it's only in teams. So you go to that and it sort of
Speaker 21:  scours across your whole M 365 stuff. So all your documents.
Speaker 21:  So it kind of can take actions all those individual
Speaker 21:  copilot actions in that interface. Let's say you said, oh I
Speaker 21:  wanna find this Word document, can we make it into a PowerPoint? You could
Speaker 21:  do that there. Whereas if you said that in the word copilot, it
Speaker 21:  doesn't have that broad view cuz it's very tailored. That's kind of a hint
Speaker 21:  of where they will go and I, I think there, there probably will be, you
Speaker 21:  know, 10 years there'll be a co-pilot that's, that can do all your personal
Speaker 21:  stuff and help you out, all that sort of stuff and then it just switches
Speaker 21:  over to work mode and does all that sort of stuff. So I mean that's, they
Speaker 21:  haven't quite laid out as a vision but it seems like that would be the way
Speaker 21:  Right.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I wonder even if that's why it's called co-pilot and not like,
Speaker 2:  you know, John the co-pilot, like it seems very obvious to me that
Speaker 2:  Microsoft has been like deeply burned by having too many sort of silly
Speaker 2:  characters that everybody grows to hate. And it's like whether it was Cortana
Speaker 2:  or Clippy or like Tey, it's like Microsoft has done this thing where it's
Speaker 2:  like interact with the machine like it's a person and everybody's like, this
Speaker 2:  person sucks and I hate them, get them out of my face. And co-pilot
Speaker 2:  is just much more of like a, it's a, it's a set of tools rather than
Speaker 2:  your new best friend and I feel like that's probably a much saner way to
Speaker 2:  go about the future.
Speaker 21:  Yeah and it's also then it doesn't also feel like it's replacing you right?
Speaker 21:  True. Yeah like as a Cortana. So I think that's definitely part of it
Speaker 21:  and the co-pilot name kind of lend to what it's, you know, the
Speaker 21:  way they've designed it so it is there alongside you to help you rather
Speaker 21:  than again replace you. So yeah, like it, I think they've
Speaker 21:  been very careful with that and apparent, apparently Satya loves the name
Speaker 21:  co-pilot so there go which obviously GitHub kind of started using initially.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, so you mentioned business chat, which I think if, if I were to pick
Speaker 2:  like one thing that feels like the sort of big picture,
Speaker 2:  like if I'm, if I rewind you know, a few years and it's like this is when
Speaker 2:  Microsoft really got interested in what OpenAI is up to, like business chat
Speaker 2:  feels like that thing, right? Where it's like plug all of your company data
Speaker 2:  in and use this model to essentially like query
Speaker 2:  and talk to your company's information. And for Microsoft it's like
Speaker 2:  it's been, it's experimented with you know, a million different ways
Speaker 2:  of storing company information. SharePoint Yeah. OneDrive and
Speaker 2:  Yammer and there's just a billion ways to communicate and share stuff and
Speaker 2:  never quite gotten it right. But it feels like business chat, especially
Speaker 2:  with coming with this like redesign of teams that's coming out now and it
Speaker 2:  seems like Teams is very clearly working. Like is is that combination
Speaker 2:  as central to the future of Microsoft is it seems like
Speaker 2:  it is to
Speaker 21:  Me. I dunno if it's necessarily like essential to to the future, but I
Speaker 21:  definitely with teams they've always viewed that as like the work hub do
Speaker 21:  you know, like where you sort of start your day essentially and then then
Speaker 21:  you go into your office. So it kind of makes sense while they've done business
Speaker 21:  chat there but the yeah, they're like the redesign teams, they're definitely
Speaker 21:  like, they've gone head on into like fully being just web
Speaker 21:  on that. Like it's just a web, like it was Electron anyway but now like
Speaker 21:  they, they they could have gone to a native app, you know, they haven't,
Speaker 21:  so you can tell that they're gonna fill that with loads of AI experiments
Speaker 21:  and there already is a bunch in there anyway. So they, they're definitely
Speaker 21:  prepping that as the platform that perhaps they'll push more of this stuff
Speaker 21:  too. Cause everyone's, if everyone's spending their time more in that and
Speaker 21:  then jumping in and out of these office apps, that would probably be the
Speaker 21:  hub where they can experiment more with this AR stuff like that. Yeah, that
Speaker 21:  makes sense. That definitely feels
Speaker 2:  Like it and probably the safest place to do that just because fewer people,
Speaker 2:  like we were talking about before have nobody has a 20 year history of how
Speaker 2:  to use teams in the way that people are like really married to how Excel
Speaker 2:  works. So you can kind of, you can have your cake and eat it too a little
Speaker 2:  bit there.
Speaker 21:  Yeah. You can play around with with it there. And they, they have done a
Speaker 21:  bunch of that, like they've done a bunch of features in teams over the years
Speaker 21:  that they've added in pretty rapidly. Especially when since the pandemic
Speaker 21:  kicked off they really started adding stuff to teams then they were like,
Speaker 21:  zoom can't beat us.
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah, totally.
Speaker 21:  They just, they just went crazy with that sort of stuff. So Yeah, like I
Speaker 21:  I, if they move stuff around there like moving people's cheese, I
Speaker 21:  think that's less of an issue with teams. Cause I think it's, that interface
Speaker 21:  is pretty, pretty basic, you know, you can move the buttons around.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it feels like that app has changed every few months for like three
Speaker 2:  years now. Yeah and it seems to be fine. Yeah, it does. People are over it.
Speaker 21:  Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 2:  Okay. What do you make of the, the security stuff around all of
Speaker 2:  this? Because obviously I think one of the interesting trends of the last
Speaker 2:  few years for Microsoft has been it's doing like the, the work analytics
Speaker 2:  and it's just showing people sort of more of the information it has about
Speaker 2:  them and all of their information and making use of all their documents and
Speaker 2:  all this stuff and now to say, you know, pour all of your
Speaker 2:  most sensitive data into this large language model
Speaker 2:  that will spit information back to you, that is like sometimes true and sometimes
Speaker 2:  a lie. And I think the idea of like telling chat G p T to make
Speaker 2:  sense of my company's financials is like a great idea in theory, but it's
Speaker 2:  gonna be wrong half the time. And it's like, are we just gonna tank the stock
Speaker 2:  market by letting chat G P T look at people's Excel spreadsheets? I know
Speaker 2:  Microsoft's answer to this seems to be like, oh we're taking it slow, whatever.
Speaker 2:  But what is your sense of how they're thinking this stuff through right now?
Speaker 21:  Yeah, like my personal opinion on this is that I think the Bing stuff is
Speaker 21:  more dangerous because you go to being you to a search engine, you want
Speaker 21:  to find answers that are accurate, right? Like you, you, you don't have
Speaker 21:  that feedback loop there available for it to go wrong. Like it
Speaker 21:  needs to be right most of the time, right? If that's wrong, you are putting
Speaker 21:  misinformation out into the world, right? Whereas if I generate a document
Speaker 21:  at work, I use this co-pilot thing, if it's wrong, that's not me.
Speaker 21:  You know, that's not like I'm putting the, essentially the misinformation
Speaker 21:  and it's my name on that document when I submit it to my boss or whatever,
Speaker 21:  right? So it's up to me to fact check it and it's less, it's less
Speaker 21:  of an issue I think in that context. But financial data, if it
Speaker 21:  screws that up, there's some dangerous scenarios where this could go very
Speaker 21:  wrong. So they have to be obviously very careful there. And I did ask them
Speaker 21:  like, is Excel like a case where you are, you know, treading carefully
Speaker 21:  considering it powers the world's economy but they, they gave the, the general,
Speaker 21:  you know, we're being careful in preview that sort of thing. Which
Speaker 21:  is like yeah but then they must be right, they must be going careful there
Speaker 21:  with, with the features that they go in certain apps
Speaker 2:  And they're doing the thing that Google is doing too, right? Which is just
Speaker 2:  like have constant banners that are like this thing will lie to you.
Speaker 2:  Like do not trust anything this thing says.
Speaker 21:  Exactly. Yeah. And it's like, yeah this is your confidential information
Speaker 21:  going. It says make sure you fact check it and those warnings only go so
Speaker 21:  far, right? Like cuz you, you see them and then you ignore 'em after a while.
Speaker 21:  So they're kind of, those warnings are kind of irrelevant but
Speaker 21:  it is definitely dangerous I think. Well I think the speed because
Speaker 21:  now we've got Microsoft going up against Google, those two biting heads
Speaker 21:  over this stuff, it just keeps pushing. So until there will be like some
Speaker 21:  disaster scenario that that will happen where it screws up like some big
Speaker 21:  bangs data or something like that and then, you know, that will be a,
Speaker 21:  a lesson to be learned sort of thing. Yeah. Where they need to slow down.
Speaker 21:  But I think it's very different to the search stuff, like the search stuff.
Speaker 21:  I think I'm personally not happy that they're going so fast with that stuff
Speaker 21:  because that stuff is can do real wor world harm outside
Speaker 21:  of your organization. Yeah. Like it's, it's really down to people
Speaker 21:  using the co-pilot stuff alongside there. It's,
Speaker 21:  it's like it should be a tool, right? You shouldn't rely on it to write
Speaker 21:  your whole document for you cuz that's, that ain't gonna be accurate.
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. And I think the question of kind of where one ends and the other
Speaker 2:  begins is for Microsoft and for everybody gonna be really interesting, right?
Speaker 2:  Because I think like take this document and turn it into a
Speaker 2:  PowerPoint or like you use the example in one of your articles of like, I
Speaker 2:  have blue titles on every slide in my deck and I would like them all
Speaker 2:  to be orange is like, yeah that's the kind of thing that takes a long time
Speaker 2:  and is like a lot of people essentially do that for a living and then
Speaker 2:  you can make that a just a simple command that I think is like universal
Speaker 2:  victory. Like let's let's solve the interface by asking questions of technology,
Speaker 2:  right? Like into that love that sold. I don't know that it's great at all
Speaker 2:  that yet, but I'm very excited about the path that all that is on. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  But then this question of like how much information
Speaker 2:  can it give me? How much should I rely on it and how much should
Speaker 2:  I allow it to make? Stuff for me is just a mess. There's
Speaker 2:  the lowest stake stuff there is all I think fine the highest stake stuff
Speaker 2:  there. Like if you, if anyone ever reports AI generated earnings
Speaker 2:  from their company, like we're hosed but somewhere in the middle is
Speaker 2:  that cutoff. And I wonder if there's gonna have to be things that it's like
Speaker 2:  Microsoft is sort of artificially, you know, dumbing down some of the stuff
Speaker 2:  these systems can do until they're much, much better than they currently
Speaker 2:  are. Or if we're just gonna get into a place where it's like the data lies
Speaker 2:  sometimes do with it, which you will. And in that case I think you're right
Speaker 2:  that we're in trouble.
Speaker 21:  Yeah. I think it's, it's also whether we get to the point where it like
Speaker 21:  makes so little mistakes where it's almost like making human
Speaker 21:  mistakes. Like when it gets to that level, which is far away,
Speaker 21:  but then do we accept that cuz we, we can't, you can't expect the machine
Speaker 21:  to be a hundred percent like you wouldn't expect a human to be. So it's
Speaker 21:  like when does it get to that level as well, which I think is some interesting
Speaker 21:  questions around it. But it's definitely like that blurred line between
Speaker 21:  what is acceptable and in what context and in what app and
Speaker 21:  wherever you're using it and how you're using that data as well because
Speaker 21:  it's, it's some of this stuff could be a bit freaky as well where it starts
Speaker 21:  like, you know, like all the AI tools we have right now, sometimes they're
Speaker 21:  a bit like alarming. You can look yourself up on Bing and it's like it pulls
Speaker 21:  out so much data you can kind of forget that's out there.
Speaker 2:  Right. Bing thinks I'm four different people, which I enjoy very much. This
Speaker 2:  is the delightful thing about having an incredibly common name is it thinks
Speaker 2:  I'm, I'm the Texas, the University of Texas baseball coach.
Speaker 2:  I'm an actor who was on Frazier. I think I'm like an attorney in Phoenix
Speaker 2:  and I'm the editor at large at the
Speaker 21:  Verge, like a Marvel superhero or something different backstory.
Speaker 2:  It's,
Speaker 21:  Yeah, that's, that's what I don't like about this being stuff. It is just,
Speaker 21:  it pulls out so much information. Like I, I put up my girlfriend's
Speaker 21:  name on it and it's like, it just lifts off so much stuff and even like
Speaker 21:  gets to the point where it's about to give out her like mobile number. Oh
Speaker 21:  wow. Whoever, because obviously she's had her CV out and Sure, yeah. Like
Speaker 21:  Cashs and that stuff. But it's just like, I think for normal people, like
Speaker 21:  she's not, you know, in the public eye for having normal people's
Speaker 21:  data out on it. It is, yeah. It's gonna get strange.
Speaker 21:  So
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Agreed. So last thing before I let you go here is, in the stuff you've
Speaker 2:  been writing over the last few months, there have been like little sort of
Speaker 2:  glimmers of what all of this might look like on Windows
Speaker 2:  and there's like, there's the new Bing button Yes. In the task bar, but I
Speaker 2:  had this moment of reading this story of like, is the future of Windows that
Speaker 2:  you just hit the Windows key and just up pops a
Speaker 2:  chatbot and that's like how you use your computer from now on? Like is that,
Speaker 2:  is that where we're headed? What's your sense?
Speaker 21:  Yeah, I think so because I think like they have the search stuff, right?
Speaker 21:  Like you just mentioned, but it's, it's just basically a link that just
Speaker 21:  froze you into Edge and into
Speaker 2:  Bing. Yeah. Like opens edge. Yeah. That's not that,
Speaker 21:  Yeah. So it's not like even really integrating into the search experience.
Speaker 21:  So I think obviously the logical next step is to fully integrate that into
Speaker 21:  the search experience and into File Explorer and all the sort of like touchpoints
Speaker 21:  that you use daily. The start menu, which has some AI stuff already,
Speaker 21:  but yeah, like I, it wouldn't be surprised me if like if they did
Speaker 21:  something like Alfred for Windows, but it was just like the chat
Speaker 21:  button, you know, pulled out to everywhere. Oh
Speaker 2:  Man, that's the dream. That just made me very excited. That would be awesome.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 21:  That would be awesome. Right, like an actual search interface that was universal.
Speaker 21:  I know what a world and could just, yeah, you don't have to worry like where
Speaker 21:  your favorites are or like your app links, any of that stuff. All of that
Speaker 21:  uni user interface stuff just goes out the window. You just have the search
Speaker 21:  prompt.
Speaker 2:  That's another one where I would assume Microsoft is gonna have to tread
Speaker 2:  pretty carefully, although, I don't know, they've fully redesigned the start
Speaker 2:  menu like 16 times in the last decade. So like what's one more?
Speaker 21:  Yeah, they could do a Windows, couldn't they again? Yeah, just have a full
Speaker 21:  screen chat in their face
Speaker 2:  That went so great the last time. Like what
Speaker 21:  Could go wrong? Yeah, as long as they make it mouse and keyboard friendly,
Speaker 21:  it could work.
Speaker 2:  This is what I'm saying, Microsoft, you heard it here first. Just forget
Speaker 2:  Windows. Just one, it just boots to a chatbot.
Speaker 21:  It's, it's like going back in time. Like a command prompt.
Speaker 2:  Exactly. Yeah. This is, it's everything from the 1970s is is new again.
Speaker 2:  It's just like the screens are better now. That's all that's changed. Awesome.
Speaker 2:  Tom, thank you. I appreciate it. This is not over anytime soon, so we'll
Speaker 2:  have you back shortly.
Speaker 21:  Okay. Thanks for me.
Speaker 2:  All right, that's it for the Vergecast today. Thanks to Monica, Tom and Jen
Speaker 2:  for being on the show. And thank you as always for listening. There's a whole
Speaker 2:  lot more from all of these conversations@theverge.com. There are a bunch
Speaker 2:  links in the show notes, but also lots more on the website. It's good website
Speaker 2:  and if you have thoughts, feedback, feedback, feelings, or Taylor Swift tickets
Speaker 2:  you wanna sell me, you can always email us@vergecasttheverge.com or
Speaker 2:  call the hotline eight six six Verge 11. Send us all of your
Speaker 2:  questions, all of your thoughts. We love hearing from you. This show is produced
Speaker 2:  by Andrew Moreno and Liam James. Brooke Min is our editorial director of
Speaker 2:  Audio. The Vergecast is a Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast
Speaker 2:  network. We'll be back on Friday with Alex and Eli to talk about
Speaker 2:  Elon Musk, Twitter's chaos, and everything else happening at Tech.
Speaker 2:  See you then. Rock and roll.