# Transcript
ID: 573d53ab-ea23-448e-af26-47dfb7b99c95
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Twitter rebrands as X, and Samsung's Galaxy Flip 5 and Fold 5 event
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5966577599992437329/2049341569093554177/s93290-US-4438s-1690537928.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and Richard Lawler discuss Twitter being rebranded as X.
Allison Johnson joins the show to discuss everything announced at Samsung’s Galaxy Flip 5 and Fold 5 Unpacked event.
Also: we read your emails!
Speaker 1:  The 14th season of The Real Housewives of New York just premiered
Speaker 1:  with an entirely new cast. And yet the show is just
Speaker 1:  as addictive as it's always been.
Speaker 2:  The thing about Housewives is it's a little bit like
Speaker 2:  Saturday Night Live. As much as people kind of come in and go out of it,
Speaker 2:  the franchise is stronger than any of the players.
Speaker 1:  We break down the lasting influence of The Real Housewives
Speaker 1:  and we rank our favorites this week on Intuit
Speaker 1:  Vultures Pop Culture podcast.
Speaker 4:  On criminal, we bring you true crime stories told
Speaker 4:  by people who know them best.
Speaker 5:  We didn't believe in setting fires 'cause that was too dangerous. We were,
Speaker 5:  you know, a, a kind, a gentler kind of crooks, so to speak.
Speaker 4:  So the best plan you had was that you'd lasso it?
Speaker 6:  Yes. Never imagined I'd use it for a camel.
Speaker 4:  I'm Phoebe Judge, and this is criminal. Did you have to say
Speaker 4:  what was in the box,
Speaker 3:  Phoebe? We told lies.
Speaker 4:  Listen to criminal every week, wherever you get your podcasts.
Speaker 3:  Hello
Speaker 7:  And welcome to the Rich Cast, the flagship podcast of rebranding your company
Speaker 7:  from one name to nothing. It's great. It's, that's what you want
Speaker 7:  when you have a company, is to pick one of the most common letters
Speaker 7:  for naming things for teenage boys. It's great. I'm your friend Neil. I'm
Speaker 7:  in a hotel room in San Francisco for this episode of The Vergecast. I'm gonna
Speaker 7:  try not to look at my laptop 'cause I think it'll look bad on, on the YouTube
Speaker 7:  video. So, Alex Cranz is here. Hey Alex.
Speaker 8:  I'm your friend who's really upset that their college nickname was stolen
Speaker 8:  by a social media company. It's fine.
Speaker 7:  That was your college nickname. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  It was like, it was a dumb joke when I had to rush sororities. You get
Speaker 8:  tired of introducing yourself. So I'd be like, just call me X it's faster.
Speaker 8:  And it was a terrible joke, but it worked. And then everybody called me X
Speaker 8:  and then people thought I really wanted it. Like, and it wasn't a joke. Oh
Speaker 7:  No.
Speaker 8:  Elon and Joy.
Speaker 7:  Were you super straight edge in college? No,
Speaker 8:  I was in a sorority.
Speaker 7:  Fair enough. David Pierce on vacation this week. Richard Lawler coming back
Speaker 7:  in like a hero to step in. Hey Richard. Hey,
Speaker 9:  I have takes, I also, for a moment there thought that Alex's college nickname
Speaker 9:  was Orchid, which
Speaker 7:  Is
Speaker 9:  Gonna be weird, but
Speaker 7:  It's, yeah, for a, for my second year in college, I went by Google Plus.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. No one liked it. It was just a thing that I did. It was my punk rock
Speaker 7:  name.
Speaker 8:  Stop stealing our names. Come on guys.
Speaker 7:  All right. A lot to talk about this week. There is the big rebrand from Twitter
Speaker 7:  to X. A number of people have asked me to explain Trademark law, which is
Speaker 7:  a blessing and a curse really. If you're me. Then there's a huge Samsung
Speaker 7:  event. The the flip five, the Fold five hit, Allison Johnson's gonna join
Speaker 7:  the show. Talk about that stuff. Bunch of lightning round stuff to get through.
Speaker 7:  And then we asked people for consumer
Speaker 7:  debates last week. We've gotten so many
Speaker 7:  responses to this. I do want to point out that some people told
Speaker 7:  us straight out that they have very strong preferences for
Speaker 7:  Windshield washer fluid. I love, I love all of you.
Speaker 7:  We have some people who go by color. They're, they're very strong proponents
Speaker 7:  of blue. A lot of people loving Rain X.
Speaker 9:  Oh, rain X has a hive.
Speaker 7:  I didn't know. I didn't know. And we poked that hive
Speaker 7:  and the Rain X people came to us and then at least
Speaker 7:  two people were like, what are you doing? Just use water.
Speaker 8:  What
Speaker 7:  Strident emails from people saying you should just use water. I don't know
Speaker 7:  what they're talking about because where I live it, it gets cold outside.
Speaker 7:  It it, it won't solve the problem for many months of the year to
Speaker 7:  spray more water onto the snow covered Windshield.
Speaker 8:  Just covering it in sheets of ice every time.
Speaker 7:  Just straight icicles shooting out of the Windshield washers. But yeah, the,
Speaker 7:  the Rain X people very strong. This is a real email we got. Rain
Speaker 7:  X is the only acceptable washer fluid. It is orange.
Speaker 7:  Don't be blue. Your choice is the original or the bug
Speaker 7:  wash. That is a strident opinion about what, what color it.
Speaker 7:  I'm telling you it's all based on colors. Anyhow, we've got more to come
Speaker 7:  later in the show. We have a massive list of ones people send to us.
Speaker 7:  X versus y I suspect we'll be talking about this for months
Speaker 7:  to come. It's gonna be, it's gonna be pretty good. But let's start with And.
Speaker 7:  I Promise. We'll move through this quickly. The, the weirdest news of the
Speaker 7:  week, which is Elon, sort of flippantly renaming Twitter to
Speaker 7:  X basically by, by tweet Fiat Like. he just tweeted it
Speaker 7:  into existence and then everyone had to pretend it was the plan. Richard
Speaker 7:  even on top of this, tell me what's going on here.
Speaker 9:  It kind of started this weekend. Elon has been talking about rebranding Twitter
Speaker 9:  as ex pretty much since he started to take over, take it over. He made hi
Speaker 9:  this ex company, its parent company a while ago. And then this weekend
Speaker 9:  he just went ahead and did it. He said, we're X now. He hadn't changed anything.
Speaker 9:  Everything on the site still said Twitter. And even now it still kinda says
Speaker 9:  Twitter all over the place. But he says that they're not tweets anymore.
Speaker 9:  They're, they're X's or I, I don't know. I don't know how you pronounce that.
Speaker 9:  I haven't really gotten that far into it. We've got a logo that is a letter
Speaker 9:  X. It might just be a font. It might have changed a little bit. We don't
Speaker 9:  know. It's gone. It, he changed it back and then he changed it to another
Speaker 9:  thing. It got wider, it got narrower. But this is where we live now. It's
Speaker 9:  X, it's not Twitter. It's it's X. Even though it says Twitter everywhere,
Speaker 7:  It says Twitter everywhere. The domain is still Twitter. No one knows what
Speaker 7:  to call a tweet anymore. There's some argument that you have to call them
Speaker 7:  zits.
Speaker 8:  No, no. That's
Speaker 7:  What the people say. I know
Speaker 8:  I'm a big proponent of calling them all tweets. Even the
Speaker 8:  Threads into the other ones. And I've come around. They're all posts now.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, now the Twitter's dead. They're all posts now. I'm not calling them
Speaker 8:  zits. Don't, don't come at me with that. Well no,
Speaker 7:  Your argument makes more sense now. You can call anything a tweet now because
Speaker 7:  they don't care. But
Speaker 8:  That's like, I dunno, I'm just like having
Speaker 8:  to be like having to differentiate and be like, oh yeah, did you see that
Speaker 8:  thread tweet? Did you see that X?
Speaker 7:  Oh right. Did you see that post? Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Like I'm like, okay, I guess posts it is. You guys wore me down.
Speaker 8:  I'm, I'm like I couldn't hold strong. Yeah. Much like everyone who
Speaker 8:  works at X now, they couldn't stop him.
Speaker 7:  We've talked a lot about how Elon has said he wants Twitter now X to be an
Speaker 7:  everything app along the lines of China's WeChat. That's a big concept to
Speaker 7:  unpack. But I just want to call out Linda Yao, who is the
Speaker 7:  C E O of X. Nominally in charge of this. This company
Speaker 7:  had a tweet thread, an X thread about what she
Speaker 7:  thinks this thing is gonna turn into Alex. I just want you to read it to
Speaker 7:  us. It is incredible.
Speaker 8:  I'm not gonna read the entire thing, but I'm gonna read one of the relevant
Speaker 8:  posts because we're not calling 'em tweets anymore. Yeah, tweets are dead.
Speaker 8:  X is the future state of unlimited interactivity centered in a
Speaker 8:  audio video messaging, payments, banking, creating
Speaker 8:  a global marketplace for ideas, goods, services
Speaker 8:  and opportunities powered by AI X will
Speaker 8:  connect us all in ways. We're just beginning to imagine.
Speaker 7:  Now I understand that Linda was the former head of advertising
Speaker 7:  for N B C Universal. This is ad copy.
Speaker 8:  It's like I think everyone understands she was the former ad
Speaker 7:  Once you're everything, you are nothing. I just, I I I believe in focus
Speaker 7:  more than anything. What this reminds me of more than anything,
Speaker 7:  I swear to God the first thing I thought of when I read this is the speech
Speaker 7:  that Big Brother gives in apple's 1984 ads where he's
Speaker 7:  like with the information purification directive, we have achieved total
Speaker 7:  world domination. You will be free from the shackles
Speaker 7:  of conflicting thoughts like workers of the world unite.
Speaker 7:  And then the lady throws the hammer through it and they're like, we made
Speaker 7:  the Macintosh. Go watch that ad. Which side of that story
Speaker 7:  do you wanna be on? Like the big brother's side or the lady with
Speaker 7:  the hammer? Like we're the lady with the hammer. That's where The Verge has
Speaker 7:  always lived.
Speaker 8:  I love that they just like announced that they basically want like a,
Speaker 8:  some sort of monopoly. They're like, we are out to build a monopoly for
Speaker 8:  everything and control all things. And it's like well that's actually a bad
Speaker 8:  pitch.
Speaker 7:  I mean it's, it's a great pitch if You can pull it off. But this idea that
Speaker 7:  you're gonna start by rebranding the company to X
Speaker 7:  and then you will with somehow with ai. But like you know she's a
Speaker 7:  marketer 'cause she's like powered by ai.
Speaker 8:  That was the best part.
Speaker 7:  Like a minute ago she would've been like powered by NFTs X will be the future
Speaker 7:  state of an Eric. Like whatever it is today, five
Speaker 8:  G, five G
Speaker 7:  Tell
Speaker 9:  Me you're a marketing executive without telling me you're a marketing executive.
Speaker 7:  Yes, X is a self-driving car. Like whatever it's
Speaker 7:  centered in audio, video, messaging, payments and you know what's not in
Speaker 7:  there? Is tweets centered in audio?
Speaker 7:  Isn't that messaging? I don't think that's messaging.
Speaker 9:  Whatcha talking about this is the best app to watch the Super Mario Brothers
Speaker 9:  movie on, right? That's, it's that one
Speaker 7:  Just incredible. And Linda will be at the code conference this year. Julie
Speaker 7:  Stein's gonna interview her. That's in September. We're very excited about
Speaker 7:  it. Many questions to ask but you just look at this
Speaker 7:  vision for what they want X to be. And it's funny
Speaker 7:  to make fun of it and it is a lot of marketing but You can see why they're
Speaker 7:  saying this. This is WeChat. Like there are apps like this,
Speaker 7:  super apps all around the world. Facebook pursued a super app model for
Speaker 7:  a long time. They have discovered that in the United States market
Speaker 7:  in particular you need multiple apps. Like you just can't do it
Speaker 7:  the way that You can do it. In China, I think Line is an app like this
Speaker 7:  in Japan. There's other countries where this model works.
Speaker 7:  So you see why you'd say it. You want a messaging app that does payments
Speaker 7:  and banking and hotel reservations and all the other stuff that WeChat
Speaker 7:  can do. It has an extensible plugin architecture. There's actually a long
Speaker 7:  argument that the cell phone market in China is more competitive than
Speaker 7:  anywhere else because the application layer is in WeChat, right?
Speaker 7:  So it's easier to switch between platforms because then you just download
Speaker 7:  WeChat and run everything in WeChat and it doesn't matter. And You can pick
Speaker 7:  like a camera or a form factor or whatever. 'cause at the end of the day
Speaker 7:  all your apps are running in WeChat. You can feel any way you want about
Speaker 7:  that including that the Chinese government is almost certainly scanning WeChat
Speaker 7:  at all times because it's like an oppressive whatever. But that's the argument,
Speaker 7:  right? That this exists somewhere at scale and makes them a lot
Speaker 7:  of money and has all kinds of weird downstream effects on on like
Speaker 7:  gadgets. Cool. You have Twitter, you're starting from the
Speaker 7:  base of Twitter, which is so creaky right now. You had to
Speaker 7:  impose rate limits on the a P I and it like kind of doesn't work
Speaker 7:  and it's like full of like weird blue check spam. Elon's doing anti-vax
Speaker 7:  conspiracies like this week he's
Speaker 9:  Having a great time.
Speaker 7:  How are you gonna get from here to there? There's no plan as far as I can
Speaker 7:  see.
Speaker 9:  Well I think the first step is that you reveal that your
Speaker 9:  executives will allow people to look into the back end of people's accounts.
Speaker 9:  Pretty much it will. And that's how you're going to get that trust for people
Speaker 9:  to use this as a banking and payments app. Like just to say that we're gonna
Speaker 9:  do the files and we're gonna let people have administrative access and look
Speaker 9:  into accounts just whenever they want to.
Speaker 7:  I mean that's that's true. That's what you want. Again, if your plan is WeChat,
Speaker 7:  you're like how do we do some Chinese government stuff That's like the selling
Speaker 7:  point. Let's, let's begin. So that's that. That's like the broad strokes.
Speaker 7:  I I think that he did it to get attention. I think Elon is a master of getting
Speaker 7:  attention. I also think that he makes all of his Twitter news on the
Speaker 7:  weekends say what you want about him. Like he's obviously not, doesn't give
Speaker 7:  a shit about Twitter Monday through Friday, right? He's like worried
Speaker 7:  about his companies that make money and then like the white wine starts
Speaker 7:  flowing on Friday night and Twitter's plans change by Sunday evening. Like
Speaker 7:  that's the news cycle we're in with pretty, pretty enforced
Speaker 7:  consistency. I think he's good at getting attention. I think that he sees
Speaker 7:  what's happening with Threads. We can talk about Threads in the following
Speaker 7:  feed and stuff they introduced, but he's gotta keep continuously recapturing
Speaker 7:  attention for Twitter 'cause that's the entire game he's in. So I'm gonna
Speaker 7:  change the name to X screw. We're doing it tonight. Send me some logos. It's
Speaker 7:  a great way to capture it. Has kept him in the conversation. Even
Speaker 7:  as Threads rolls out a following feed, I think in a few weeks, federal will
Speaker 7:  out a web app. That's what adversary is saying. By the time Threads rolls
Speaker 7:  out a web app, Elon's gonna be like, it is a self-driving car. Yeah, X is
Speaker 7:  making a self-driving car. I've merged it with Tesla. Like that's just where
Speaker 7:  his brain is to capture attention. I just don't think
Speaker 7:  he's got the capability to do any of this stuff 'cause he fired everybody.
Speaker 8:  He has zero capability to do it and it's like okay,
Speaker 8:  you renamed it, you're capturing attention. Is that attention turning
Speaker 8:  into users and or money
Speaker 9:  As measured by user seconds in the app? Yes. Oh is it
Speaker 9:  the statistic that is so great that absolutely no one other than Elon, Musk
Speaker 9:  uses and no one seems to understand exactly what it is, but judging by that
Speaker 9:  statistic, yes he is winning I mean. I think my big question is can he use
Speaker 9:  that X logo for Twitter? Neil, you know, you, you have to explain this to
Speaker 9:  the people. All right, you
Speaker 8:  Just queue him up. We're
Speaker 9:  Arguing all over the internet. He's got this logo, what is it? Can he actually
Speaker 9:  do that? We're
Speaker 7:  11 minutes in and we're at, we're at IP law. Okay, so I just speed
Speaker 8:  Run.
Speaker 7:  This is my, again, this is just what I do. I'm this boulder's going up the
Speaker 7:  hill. Please, I beg you if you're a Vergecast listener, before you type the
Speaker 7:  word copyright, trademark or patent into a text box on the internet, just
Speaker 7:  ask yourself, do I know what this word means? And if it applies to this concept,
Speaker 7:  I, I beg you because this is exhausting. So we talk a lot about copyright
Speaker 7:  law on the show lately because of ai. That's one thing. Then there's trademarks
Speaker 7:  which are for business, right? They signify the origin of goods
Speaker 7:  and services. That's all they're meant to do. You buy a thing, it has the
Speaker 7:  name of a company on it, you know that company exists, you trust them. They're
Speaker 7:  a market tool, right? That and there's lots of rules about it. They're not
Speaker 7:  copyrights. Totally different thing. So I just wanna start there. This is
Speaker 7:  like a whole different world, whole different body of law, whole different
Speaker 7:  set of legal standards. It's just the relationship is like
Speaker 7:  can you own an idea and then people like lose their minds. I just wanna start
Speaker 7:  there. Totally different than copyrights. Totally different than patents.
Speaker 7:  Different standards, different ideas, different whole thing. Okay, so
Speaker 7:  trademarks like many different people can own the same trademark
Speaker 7:  just applied to different goods and services. And the standard
Speaker 7:  is likelihood of confusion. Will people get confused by seeing this
Speaker 7:  stuff? Then there's stuff like distinctiveness is this mark distinctive such
Speaker 7:  that it when in the market, when people see this trademark, they will understand
Speaker 7:  this is coming from you and then not be confused. It might be coming from
Speaker 7:  somewhere else. So X, the letter X is not
Speaker 7:  very distinctive. You have to do a lot of work to make
Speaker 7:  it distinctive in a particular category.
Speaker 8:  Rude to my college. Me though. Yeah
Speaker 7:  Like when you hear the letter X, what you think of is Alex just at a rager
Speaker 7:  in the basement of a sorority house. That's what you should think of. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Shrugging. Shrugging Everclear out of a Fiji bottle. And if we repeat
Speaker 7:  it enough times we can say you can't use the X
Speaker 7:  trademark. 'cause everyone associates it with that image of Alex Cranz.
Speaker 7:  Let's do it guys. Make it happen. But that's the entire game. Can you make
Speaker 7:  people associate this word or this logo with this company
Speaker 7:  and this product? And once You can You can go get a trademark and there's
Speaker 7:  ways to short circuit that process. You can file what's called like an intent
Speaker 7:  to use application, this whole thing. But that the core idea is, is there
Speaker 7:  an association between this word, image, logo,
Speaker 7:  whatever and this product and company. So Twitter very
Speaker 7:  distinctive from the jump, the logo very distinctive. There's
Speaker 7:  not another thing called Twitter. So they file the trademark for Twitter.
Speaker 7:  They say we have an intent to use it over time they build up a
Speaker 7:  huge amount of equity in the brand such that if you launched anything else
Speaker 7:  named Twitter you would say they would be able to say there's a huge likelihood
Speaker 7:  of confusion. People will think your Twitter product comes from us. Twitter
Speaker 7:  the company. You can't use that trademark. That's the whole game.
Speaker 7:  So X, there's lots of things named X, there's lots of
Speaker 7:  companies named X, there's lots of products named X, famously
Speaker 7:  Elon's, other companies have X's in them. It's great he can
Speaker 7:  use it 'cause no one else can stop him because there is so much latent
Speaker 7:  noise around the letter X. Then Richard, I think what you're getting to
Speaker 7:  is the logo might just be like a Unicode character or the
Speaker 7:  X from a foundry called Monotype. That seems really unclear like
Speaker 7:  Unicode will let him do it. But if it turns out they're actually using the
Speaker 7:  Monotype character, they gotta pay some licensing fees. That's just money.
Speaker 7:  That's fine. You can solve that problem. It might be a lot of licensing fees.
Speaker 7:  That might be a huge mistake for a company like Twitter that's in trouble.
Speaker 7:  But it's a money problem. It's not like a legal problem. Then there's the
Speaker 7:  last piece of it. Whichever one has like gotten completely wrong in just
Speaker 7:  horrific ways is that meta and Microsoft have
Speaker 7:  trademarks on things with X's in them as they relate to social
Speaker 7:  networking. And so when you file for a trademark, you have to say what the
Speaker 7:  trademark is for. So I could file for a trademark on the letter X
Speaker 7:  as it relates to selling fruit by the roadside and it would've nothing
Speaker 7:  to do with the trademark for X as it relates to social networking. So you
Speaker 7:  go and you list a class of what you wanna do with a trademark. So You
Speaker 7:  can get definition in the market. This is gonna relate this to that. So if
Speaker 7:  you very famously, the Apple logo on the side of N
Speaker 7:  Y C taxis, the city of New York and Apple had to define the class
Speaker 7:  they to negotiate to say this logo is about taxis
Speaker 7:  and like taxis being eco-friendly and not about Apple. The computers
Speaker 7:  fine. It's a negotiation, but you just make the definition, you move on your
Speaker 7:  way. Here. Microsoft had one for Mixer that was just,
Speaker 7:  it's the logo X. So they trademarked the logo, the
Speaker 7:  drawing, and if you use that drawing or anything that looks substantially
Speaker 7:  like that drawing, you get in trouble. But they're not using that drawing.
Speaker 7:  So it doesn't matter. Then if you'll remember, Microsoft launched Mixer,
Speaker 7:  remember they pulled Ninja over, tried to get everyone off of Twitch. Mixer
Speaker 7:  failed Ninja went back to Twitch, Microsoft divested this whole thing to
Speaker 7:  Facebook gaming and assigned this logo to Facebook as part of that deal.
Speaker 7:  So now Meta owns this logo as it relates to social networking, but it's just
Speaker 7:  the logo, it's not the letter X, it's the drawing, not the letter. Meta
Speaker 7:  owns another thing called X, it doesn't matter 'cause they're just logos.
Speaker 7:  So everyone's getting confused about the letter X and what it
Speaker 7:  protects and it's really nothing like at the end of the day it's, he's
Speaker 7:  not gonna use those logos. No one's gonna confuse this X logo for that logo.
Speaker 7:  And so many people are already using the letter X for everything else that
Speaker 7:  his problem is actually making anyone associate the letter X
Speaker 7:  with the thing that used to be Twitter as opposed to all of the other things
Speaker 7:  that are named X. Right? Which is probably a bigger problem than his legal
Speaker 7:  challenges.
Speaker 8:  So this is why the Twitter Japanese account is just called
Speaker 8:  Japan currently instead of Xan because Xan is
Speaker 8:  the name of one of the most famous bands in Japanese history.
Speaker 7:  So I, I've seen people report on this. I do not know enough about Japanese
Speaker 7:  trademark law.
Speaker 8:  They definitely haven't called Japan. So
Speaker 8:  I I I think there's still a lot of confusion there, but I know the ex Japan
Speaker 8:  like lead composer was Like, he can't call it Xan.
Speaker 8:  That's the name of our band. I'm looking into it. And I think that's kind
Speaker 8:  of where we're at. And Twitter notably is not calling Twitter
Speaker 8:  Japan Xan anymore, they're just calling it
Speaker 8:  Japan.
Speaker 7:  So, but there's a huge difference in Twitter handles and trademarks,
Speaker 7:  right,
Speaker 8:  Right, right.
Speaker 7:  Xan, the band might have a trademark in Japan for the name of its band,
Speaker 7:  but that's for the name of a band, right? I don't know if they have a trademark
Speaker 7:  on social networking company like You can probably start a company in Japan
Speaker 7:  called Xan because it won't be the band. This, and this is the thing that
Speaker 7:  everyone gets confused with the trademark law. Like you it, as long as people
Speaker 7:  aren't confused that one thing is the other. Like usually trademark callouts,
Speaker 7:  you have the same name for two things.
Speaker 8:  Could you?
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 8:  Of course You can. Like if I went and started a car company called D M X,
Speaker 8:  I feel like someone's estate would probably have something to say to me.
Speaker 7:  You could definitely start, I, I don't know if D M X has a trademark registration
Speaker 7:  for D M X cars. Like that's the, the trademark
Speaker 7:  law is just not like copyright law. Okay. It's not the same thing where like
Speaker 7:  any copy gets you in trouble. Yeah, it's like narrowly if you
Speaker 7:  start D M X cars, I love that we're using this example. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  if you start D M X cars and like you have nothing to do with D M
Speaker 7:  X, you don't trade on any of his likeness and You don't use his lyrics and
Speaker 7:  it's totally different and you say this is distinctive and he doesn't have
Speaker 7:  a trademark registration in cars. You can probably do it. You should talk
Speaker 7:  to a lawyer. I'm not giving you this legal, I don't think you should start
Speaker 7:  D M X cars more hassle than it's worth. So your
Speaker 9:  Legal advice as my lawyer is that I can start D M X cars. I just can't use
Speaker 9:  the tagline. It's dark and held is hot.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think that's bad. Like you'll get in trouble. Like the standard is
Speaker 7:  likelihood of confusion. Is it likely that by using the name
Speaker 7:  D M X cars people will be confused that D M X has anything to do with it?
Speaker 7:  I don't know the answer to that question. I don't think anyone should find
Speaker 7:  out the answer to that question. I'm just telling you what the standard is.
Speaker 7:  So if you're in Japan, And, I, dunno what the standard in, in Japanese trademark
Speaker 7:  law is. I'm just telling you that it is almost certain that You can start
Speaker 7:  a company called X Japan because people will not confuse the company for
Speaker 7:  the band. Right. I do not think that has any
Speaker 7:  relationship at all to Twitter handles. If they
Speaker 7:  wanted to take the Xan Twitter handle they could
Speaker 7:  because it belongs to them. And we know that they think this because they
Speaker 7:  just took the X Twitter handle from some guy and the guy
Speaker 7:  was like, that sucks. And he's not a world famous band and so
Speaker 7:  they're not in trouble. But
Speaker 8:  They couldn't have taken it like they, if they had taken it from the Xan
Speaker 8:  band, they just would've looked like Monster Jackass.
Speaker 7:  Even more worse monsters than they are. Yeah. Like, you know, like I don't,
Speaker 7:  I I think that's what's stopping them, not Yeah, the law, the trademark love
Speaker 7:  of Japan. It's their platform. They can take any handle they want and there's
Speaker 7:  really no relationship between the handles and the trademark law.
Speaker 7:  There. There's like some minor relationship, like the platforms
Speaker 7:  will respect Trademark law to keep, to keep impersonation off their
Speaker 7:  platforms. Like if someone shows up and makes a Verge handle and starts
Speaker 7:  tweeting and it looks like us, like we show up to the platform and say,
Speaker 7:  this is our trademark that's impersonation. Like make it go away. Twitter
Speaker 7:  notably a lot looser on the impersonation situation
Speaker 7:  than it used to be. so like I, I just think like everyone's getting
Speaker 7:  these concepts like fairly mushy and confused that the
Speaker 7:  handles in the actual trademarks, no relationship really whatsoever
Speaker 7:  unless Twitter decides there should be a relationship. And then the trademark
Speaker 7:  laws of different countries are slightly different, but all of them are
Speaker 7:  pretty focused on, you're in the supermarket, you look at the label,
Speaker 7:  you see Kellogg's and you know that that is actually from Kellogg's and you
Speaker 7:  have relationship and that's market information You can trade on. And if
Speaker 7:  you go outta the supermarket and you go to a cloning store and
Speaker 7:  you see t-shirts made by another company called Kellogg with a
Speaker 7:  radically different logo and it's a radically different product, you're not
Speaker 7:  gonna associate with Serial Maker. And so both of those companies can have
Speaker 7:  those names fine. Like that. That's basically fine.
Speaker 7:  And I think that's the situation Elon is in and everyone just wants to find
Speaker 7:  a gotcha. But the gotcha here is that it's a shit name that means nothing.
Speaker 7:  Like the market will handle this problem.
Speaker 8:  Here's my next question. He, he, he, they're famously using something that
Speaker 8:  looks a lot like a very specific Unicode for
Speaker 8:  X, like a Unicode symbol for X. Generally speaking,
Speaker 8:  you get yelled at if you use somebody's logo in like your name or something
Speaker 8:  like that because it's their logo. How does that work if I
Speaker 8:  decide to use that X as the end of like my name, just,
Speaker 8:  I wouldn't ever do that because that's dumb. Oh, like
Speaker 7:  The Unicode X? Yeah.
Speaker 8:  If I use that same Unicode X, if it starts being comes
Speaker 8:  associated with this other thing, even though it's like openly licensed and
Speaker 8:  theoretically anyone can use it. If they copyright it
Speaker 8:  specifically, if they like copyright that logo specifically for them. What
Speaker 8:  happens if we start using that Unicode or does the u Unicode? You're killing
Speaker 8:  me X have to get
Speaker 7:  Rid of that. They trademark, they trademark the Oh
Speaker 8:  My gosh. So
Speaker 7:  Confusing. This is the thing. It's driving me bonkers. Yeah. Imagine being
Speaker 7:  me on a plane just freaking out 35,000 feet
Speaker 7:  while this is going down.
Speaker 8:  So can I use the X or am I like Yeah, I can use it anytime. Of course
Speaker 8:  You can.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Like they can't stop unless you're holding yourself out as x
Speaker 7:  the company, they're not gonna be able to stop you. They can, they can send
Speaker 7:  you letters. Well, the fame, my my favorite letter that we ever got, Richard,
Speaker 7:  I don't even remember this. We used to run a site called Eng Gadget Mobile.
Speaker 7:  It was pink. So Eng Gadget was Blue Eng Gadget Mobile
Speaker 7:  was pink. What was Eng Gadget hd Richard, that was yours. Gray. I think it
Speaker 7:  was gray. And so it was hot pink and T-Mobile when they started using
Speaker 7:  Magento a lot sent us a letter that was like, we own the shade of pink. And
Speaker 7:  we're like, no you don't bro. Also we're gonna publish this
Speaker 7:  letter. And then we, and like Ryan Block and Peter Rojas published the letter
Speaker 7:  and then they were like, oh, that was really stupid. Our lawyers will never
Speaker 7:  do that again. And that was the end of it. And that's like how it goes.
Speaker 8:  So we can all use the X anytime we want. The one, the Unicode X,
Speaker 7:  There's not a situation in which you typing a letter
Speaker 7:  implicates their trademark.
Speaker 8:  Right. But if I like use it as part of my name on a
Speaker 8:  whole bunch of different social media apps, like I start using, 'cause You
Speaker 8:  can use, you know, Unicode symbols in a lot of different ones. Yeah. They
Speaker 8:  all print it. And, I start using that X could they eventually come after
Speaker 8:  me being like, stop it. Like if you started using the Netflix
Speaker 8:  Inn for your first name for some reason that was in Unicode and you
Speaker 8:  started using that all the time, wouldn't Netflix eventually be like,
Speaker 8:  Hey, stop.
Speaker 7:  I don't know why the Netflix Inn would be in Unicode. It would just be the
Speaker 7:  letter N Hypothetical,
Speaker 8:  Hypothetical. Not everyone takes their logos from Unicode
Speaker 8:  because that seems deeply
Speaker 7:  Stupid, right? This, I guess you, you've now landed on the answer to your
Speaker 7:  question. Yeah. The Unicode X is just X you know how
Speaker 7:  like emojis are not standardized, they're just Unicode and you, they're meant
Speaker 7:  to represent something like Yeah, right car and then like Samsung
Speaker 7:  and Apple have different cars. Unicode just represents letters. Like
Speaker 7:  here's a character and then your typeface on your computer. Your font
Speaker 7:  is like, okay, that's an A I'm gonna represent this. A it's, there's not
Speaker 7:  like a Unicode font. So this X that they're pulling from that's in
Speaker 7:  Unicode, You can render it in any font you want.
Speaker 7:  It just ha it's just because of the, the way the lines work. It looks
Speaker 7:  like a thing. Yeah, but it's just a, you know, I mean, it's like literally
Speaker 7:  a series of numbers that say to a computer, make this character
Speaker 7:  and then between that instruction and you is the computer saying, okay,
Speaker 7:  in this font,
Speaker 8:  Okay, it just happens to look like the logo
Speaker 8:  of this company that will presumably be trademarked at some point.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think it will be very difficult for them. Like, especially if
Speaker 7:  the design is, if they were just like, the letter A
Speaker 7:  conceptually is our trademark. That's this X as it relates to
Speaker 7:  Unicode, right? Yeah. so like who, who the hell knows it? It is remarkable.
Speaker 7:  And I know we're gonna get emails about this. People are gonna say, you're
Speaker 7:  like, we are spending so much time talking about this dumb thing. It's so
Speaker 7:  dumb. And it's one i i am a sucker for
Speaker 7:  a trademark law conversation. So here we are, welcome to our show. This has
Speaker 7:  always Happens. Two, this is the dismantling
Speaker 7:  of what was one of the most influential
Speaker 7:  information networks that has ever existed. And so you, you have to
Speaker 7:  talk about it because what Twitter meant, like what the word Twitter
Speaker 7:  meant to make this about trademark law, what that word meant, what the word
Speaker 7:  tweet meant to people conveyed so much. Meaning
Speaker 7:  this celebrity tweeted an apology. You already know
Speaker 7:  the whole story. I don't even need to say a celebrity, I don't need to say
Speaker 7:  what the apology was about. I don't need to tell you that. It was a screenshot
Speaker 7:  of notes sap, right? Like the meaning was Im the word was
Speaker 7:  imbued with meaning that had emotional resonance throughout the culture that
Speaker 7:  has been dismantled. And it is, it is worth discussing
Speaker 7:  why that is happening and to what end And I think the end is, is
Speaker 7:  nonsensical, right? It's an audio video platform that will enable banking
Speaker 7:  and put AI in your bones or whatever the hell it's gonna do. But the thing
Speaker 7:  itself was important if it gets there. But yeah, the, the
Speaker 7:  people freaking out about trademark law is like at Eng Gadget, I wrote so
Speaker 7:  many of these stories that I just had the, the middle part of it and a text
Speaker 7:  expander, you know, I was just like t m l
Speaker 7:  and it would just like spit out 150 words of trademark law explainer.
Speaker 8:  Emma's gonna ask for that tip. Like she's gonna be like, you still got that
Speaker 8:  boiler? Play it for me.
Speaker 7:  I did it. you know, in Apple versus Samsung time, I wrote so many patent
Speaker 7:  loss stories that we're effectively just explainers about how patents work,
Speaker 7:  which we won't do here, but we're just in that time when the idea of like
Speaker 7:  how to own an idea is very complicated because that's all the internet
Speaker 7:  is. There's a bunch of people sort of ephemerally sending ideas around without
Speaker 7:  any like, limits on scarcity. And that just like the,
Speaker 7:  the AI copyright conversation is like a big deal here in Trademark Law.
Speaker 7:  It's like people search the trademark database and they're like, meta already
Speaker 7:  owns X and it's like, okay, let's step back to figure out what trademarks
Speaker 7:  are even for, right? And then you just have to start at the
Speaker 9:  Start. And that brings us to now where we've got all these things. He's sort
Speaker 9:  of changed the name. He has, he has mostly changed. The name has changed
Speaker 9:  on Android, but not on iOS as I'm speaking. Maybe by the time you hear this,
Speaker 9:  it will have changed in the iOS app, Twitter has tried to push
Speaker 9:  businesses into buying more ads so they can stay, or I'm sorry, X has tried
Speaker 9:  to push businesses into buying more ads so they can stay verified. We had
Speaker 9:  Esther Crawford characters coming back from past seasons
Speaker 9:  suddenly pop up talking about what it was like to work at Twitter until she
Speaker 9:  was fired and sleeping on the floor. And how Elon listens to
Speaker 9:  whoever just happens to be around and takes random ideas. Is there, is there
Speaker 9:  anything else we haven't discussed?
Speaker 7:  The one thing I wanna point out is Threads rolled out its following feed
Speaker 7:  this week. Great, it's cool. It immediately showcases how little
Speaker 7:  volume there is on Threads. Like I've got a lot of people on Threads. Everyone's
Speaker 7:  still posting on Twitter, so that hasn't happened yet. I think it won't happen
Speaker 7:  until they roll out the web version, which both Zuckerberg and Adversary
Speaker 7:  have said they're gonna do Emery in response to Casey
Speaker 7:  Zuckerberg in response to Lauren Goode. So Verge alumni network
Speaker 7:  out there getting us what we need. But if you don't have the web version,
Speaker 7:  it's, it's very hard for true posters to keep up the pace. So I think that's
Speaker 7:  like coming, but you can't leave the app stuck in the
Speaker 7:  following feed. It's not a sticky preference. It defaults you. If your app
Speaker 7:  gets pushed outta memory or reboots in any way, or even it seems like just
Speaker 7:  whenever it feels like it, it'll drop you back into the algorithmic feed,
Speaker 7:  which is just a pure pain in the ass. And they should just make that setting
Speaker 7:  sticky. And that's just respecting user preferences. Like I don't, I don't
Speaker 7:  feel like I'm being a diva about this. It's like I set the preference, leave
Speaker 7:  it alone. Like my car is not like I've moved the seat around to what I think
Speaker 7:  will be more appropriate for you. It's like, just leave it. It seems very
Speaker 7:  simple to me. It's
Speaker 10:  A real clippy move.
Speaker 7:  It's a real, it sounds, it seems like you, what you want is the Nugget account.
Speaker 7:  Like, here it is again. All right, we should take a break. That's, that's
Speaker 7:  been a lot of x talk. Again, if you're, if you're mad at us, I'm just telling
Speaker 7:  you Twitter was massively important. I'm very excited
Speaker 7:  about the reset moment of the internet. If you listen to other episodes of
Speaker 7:  show, you know, I think there's a reset moment on the internet. I think search
Speaker 7:  and ai Sunar Phai this week said the search generative experience
Speaker 7:  is the future of search. That's the clearest and most crisply he has said
Speaker 7:  that that's a big deal. We're in a moment of reset for the internet.
Speaker 7:  Taking a second to talk about the thing that was before you
Speaker 7:  go onto the next thing. I think it's, I think it's fine. Also, You can just
Speaker 7:  hit Skip on your podcast player because right now we're gonna talk about
Speaker 7:  gadgets in a serious way with Allison Johnson 'cause it was Samsung event
Speaker 7:  this week. We'll be right back.
Speaker 11:  Support for this episode comes from owned with Rex Chapman. The
Speaker 11:  richest sports team owner in 2023 is worth more than $80 billion.
Speaker 11:  That's a truly unimaginable amount of money, but it's not hard to imagine
Speaker 11:  what a sports team owner actually does. They make deals, sign checks and
Speaker 11:  hobnob with all the stars. That's all right. Well there's a lot more to
Speaker 11:  it From Campsite Media and the Minds That Brought You Smart List,
Speaker 11:  join Rex Chapman for this new podcast owned every week.
Speaker 11:  Rex takes you behind the luxury boxes where you'll hear the backroom stories
Speaker 11:  of owning and operating a professional sports team. Rex talks to
Speaker 11:  athletes and super fans and sometimes owners themselves about the
Speaker 11:  responsibilities that come with this compelling power one, which they don't
Speaker 11:  always wield wisely. The show examines owners colorful
Speaker 11:  backstories, the rise to fame and fortune, and the ins and outs of being
Speaker 11:  at the helm of a sports franchise. Listen to owned on the Wondery app
Speaker 11:  or wherever you get your podcasts. You can get owned episodes early and
Speaker 11:  ad free on Wondery Plus join Wondery Plus in the Wondery app or
Speaker 11:  on Apple Podcasts.
Speaker 10:  Hi everyone, this is Kara Swisher. And I. Just interviewed Fran Drescher,
Speaker 10:  a k a, the nanny or more Pertinently, the president of SAG
Speaker 10:  aftra, which is the actor's union that's on strike. I think you'll wanna
Speaker 10:  hear it. She's got a lot to say. Here's a taste.
Speaker 12:  We stand at a time when
Speaker 12:  big business feels like it's
Speaker 12:  okay to marginalized
Speaker 12:  people and systematically squeeze them
Speaker 12:  out of their livelihood while those at the
Speaker 12:  top are fat cats and the people
Speaker 12:  that are the shareholders and major and minor
Speaker 12:  investors are also getting rich off of the
Speaker 12:  backs of the people that actually are the
Speaker 12:  product.
Speaker 10:  Listen to our full conversation now. Just search for on with Kara Swisher
Speaker 10:  wherever you get your podcasts.
Speaker 7:  We're back. Allison Johnson has joined us. Hey Allison. Hello Big Samsung
Speaker 7:  event this week. Lots of noise around the Samsung event. Samsung's
Speaker 7:  finances are in disarray. They had earnings as well.
Speaker 7:  Profits are down. There's some data I saw that said iPhone sales in South Korea
Speaker 7:  are up, which is weird, not great to lose in your home turf,
Speaker 7:  but the phones look good, right? It's the, the flip five and the Fold five,
Speaker 7:  the launch, it Unpacked what's going on here?
Speaker 13:  Yeah, the, I guess the big story is that they Fold flat now,
Speaker 13:  so yeah, we got got a new flip style and Fold
Speaker 13:  style phone. They finally figured out how to make the, the
Speaker 13:  hinges Fold totally flat. And the flip five is really,
Speaker 13:  is the one I'm most excited about. I think it, it's the more
Speaker 13:  interesting kind of update of the two. It comes with a
Speaker 13:  much bigger, like still small, but a lot bigger cover screen.
Speaker 13:  It's 3.6 inches now, which is just gonna
Speaker 13:  totally change what You can do with the phone as opposed to the like
Speaker 13:  really tiny screen on the flip floor. So that, that's a big
Speaker 13:  story I think.
Speaker 8:  Was it really that tiny? The previous
Speaker 13:  One? It was tiny. Yeah, because one of the cool things is You can like
Speaker 13:  frame a selfie and use the rear facing cameras and get a preview.
Speaker 13:  I held up a postage stamp to the, the preview you get, it's
Speaker 13:  the exact same size as a postage stamp. It's like So
Speaker 13:  Hard to see yourself.
Speaker 8:  Okay, nevermind. That is tiny.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. Yeah. Like the screen itself was bigger than a postage stamp, but
Speaker 13:  in it like not even
Speaker 8:  A good postage stamp. The little ones
Speaker 13:  Not even the like forever stamps like yeah, the old school
Speaker 13:  ones with no barcode. But yeah, the Fold five is
Speaker 13:  like an extremely minor update aside from the hinge
Speaker 13:  thing, which is exciting. But that's, that's even saying a lot I mean the
Speaker 8:  HCH thing is exciting though, right? Like, like this is
Speaker 8:  a big deal 'cause everybody, was it a couple weeks ago Pixel we got the with
Speaker 8:  a Pixel Fold and oh my God, it's so flat and, and it was like, well we're
Speaker 8:  certainly gonna get this. And we did and these, but Samsung's been doing
Speaker 8:  this a lot longer. They've got a lot more other stuff that's polished Yeah.
Speaker 8:  In that way. Like you haven't gotten ahold of it yet, right?
Speaker 13:  I am awaiting my review units. No, they
Speaker 13:  were supposed to be here yesterday and we're having conversations.
Speaker 13:  I should get phones tomorrow. I'm anxiously awaiting, but
Speaker 8:  You're ex like pumped. You're kind of excited to like check it out and like
Speaker 8:  see how this works when it's flat and made by someone who's been doing this
Speaker 8:  a while.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. Yeah, that's the thing. I mean like the Pixel Fold
Speaker 13:  really like the form factor and really like, thought it folds flat,
Speaker 13:  but when I was using it, I just kind of kept having these feelings of like,
Speaker 13:  oh, well Samsung is like doing this a little better. You can, there's more
Speaker 13:  multitasking. There's just more customization
Speaker 13:  and you definitely just get the feeling like Samsung is way ahead
Speaker 13:  and foldable. So when they do make that little upgrade, it's just
Speaker 13:  kind of like putting a stamp on something that was already
Speaker 13:  pretty good. Yeah, so it is exciting if, well like the,
Speaker 13:  a little boring
Speaker 7:  Samsung just isn't constrained by having to run Android. Like
Speaker 7:  their ability to just mess with the software to support
Speaker 7:  folding is just Google has to do it for everybody, right?
Speaker 7:  You can see Google's like very careful. They're trying to like make standards,
Speaker 7:  make it universal so that anybody makes a folding phone, kind of gets it
Speaker 7:  for free. That's their job, I think is the OS vendor. Like
Speaker 7:  that's, they have to, Samsung's just like, I don't know, Bixie is gonna make
Speaker 7:  the app bigger. Like they just don't have to give a shit. And so they, I
Speaker 7:  think they're able to experiment more or iterate faster that just watching
Speaker 7:  the, like the little bit of the keynotes that I've been able to see, they,
Speaker 7:  they're just able to take bigger risks with like, what does it mean for the
Speaker 7:  screen to get bigger?
Speaker 9:  So Samsung can force Instagram into making an app that fills up the whole
Speaker 9:  screen and Google can't,
Speaker 13:  Or they'll, they'll put the option to make it bigger or
Speaker 13:  run to Instagram side by side. you know, like somewhere in the,
Speaker 13:  in deep in the menu settings, they're, they're happy to put something in
Speaker 13:  the menu settings for you to do what you want.
Speaker 7:  Why are you more excited about the flip?
Speaker 13:  I maybe just coming off of the Razor plus the Motorola Razor Plus,
Speaker 13:  which has the really big cover screen, it was kind of a light bulb for me.
Speaker 13:  It, it felt like, oh, I finally get what these flip style
Speaker 13:  phones can do. Just with being able to interact more with the front screen.
Speaker 13:  You can write texts on it, which you couldn't do before
Speaker 13:  with the smaller cover screen. You can go into the settings and let
Speaker 13:  it run full apps for you, which is like, not generally
Speaker 13:  recommended, but if you're a sicko, if you're a sicko like me,
Speaker 13:  you could do that. And then that's where I was just having a lot of fun,
Speaker 13:  like finding things like You can run Google
Speaker 13:  Translate on it and it's, it's not a super experience,
Speaker 13:  but I can like type in a word in Spanish and just get
Speaker 13:  a translation without like doing a whole thing on my phone. So
Speaker 13:  I'm, I'm excited to see what Samsung's take on this is
Speaker 13:  and if they're, I have a hunch that like their
Speaker 13:  software is gonna be ahead of Motorolas here,
Speaker 13:  but I, I don't know, I'm, I'm just excited to check 'em out side by side.
Speaker 13:  Are you gonna watch the Oppenheimer trailer on it?
Speaker 13:  I guess so. I, I haven't watched it at all. So
Speaker 13:  see how big it's, I'll flip it open and watch Barbie after that.
Speaker 13:  There you go
Speaker 7:  As Christopher Nolan intended. It's funny. So you're saying like
Speaker 7:  the, it's a light bulb moment with the Motorola one and now the Samsung one
Speaker 7:  isn't that just having a phone, like the whole point of the flip
Speaker 7:  phone factor to me was like, I will close this and my
Speaker 7:  phone will go away and now you're like, okay, they solved it by putting
Speaker 7:  a giant screen on it. And I can use my phone without opening
Speaker 7:  my, I I have to be missing something.
Speaker 13:  That's a fair point. But here's the thing. So I've been, I've been wearing
Speaker 13:  a smartwatch Yeah. Cutting edge technology here and
Speaker 13:  there. I'm just finding there's like a middle ground between stuff I can
Speaker 13:  do on my smartwatch where I just like, I just wanna see a text and like
Speaker 13:  dismiss it and then there's the things you want your full phone for
Speaker 13:  and then the cover screen is like in between these two things
Speaker 13:  where I can't like Google translate a word on the
Speaker 13:  smartwatch or I can talk to Siri, And I, I don't know. I don't wanna do
Speaker 13:  that. So that's where I was finding it was really interesting and
Speaker 13:  helpful. And I think, I think more of those
Speaker 13:  kind of use cases will emerge. It did have the effect of like,
Speaker 13:  you don't get sucked into scrolling Instagram on your phone because
Speaker 13:  it is just terrible. Like You can
Speaker 13:  tap on, You can tap on the Instagram notification and just mindlessly
Speaker 13:  you'll start like looking through stuff and you realize like, this is awful.
Speaker 13:  I either need to stop or open the phone. So that's where I was like,
Speaker 13:  aha.
Speaker 7:  Were you having moments of like, I am not going to open this phone. I will
Speaker 7:  feel guilty if I open the phone. I did.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. I mean I had plenty of moments where I was like, yeah, I'm gonna
Speaker 13:  go for it.
Speaker 13:  Gonna just dive right into the Instagram feed. But
Speaker 7:  H how is Samsung software at switching you from that little screen to the
Speaker 7:  big screen? Because that's been, like, these phones are effectively mid-range
Speaker 7:  phones, right? That it feels like the, the seamlessness of
Speaker 7:  moving between modes has been held back by the
Speaker 7:  sort of mid-range Qualcomm chips in them.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. And Samsung's a little further ahead here too. They have the eight
Speaker 13:  gen two in this one, which is has been very good in all the phones
Speaker 13:  I've tested. Yeah, I think they're still figuring out what do you, what
Speaker 13:  do people want when they, when you close the phone, do you wanna
Speaker 13:  keep running the app that you were running? Should, should it prompt you
Speaker 13:  to open the app? Motorola has a setting
Speaker 13:  where you'll just get a little icon on the cover screen
Speaker 13:  when you're using an app on the big screen. You close it, it'll kind of
Speaker 13:  be like, tap this to keep running on the outer screen, which I thought was
Speaker 13:  clever and pretty useful and You can ignore it if you don't wanna do that.
Speaker 13:  So I think they're still figuring it out and it's definitely
Speaker 13:  different kind of, you know, app by app. Yeah. So
Speaker 13:  we'll see what Samsung thinks.
Speaker 7:  And then the, the difference with the Fold five is that
Speaker 7:  it really is just a phone on the front, right? And then you like open it
Speaker 7:  and you Yeah. And then you have a tablet. Is there any relationship between
Speaker 7:  sort of like, it's a phone and it switch goes down to a widget
Speaker 7:  on the flip and it's a phone and it opens to a tablet
Speaker 7:  on the Fold. Like those are two wildly different paradigms, but it seems
Speaker 7:  like they share some like conceptual behaviors.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, I think they are really kind of splitting a little more now.
Speaker 13:  Like the Fold format feels like if you want
Speaker 13:  Phone plus Yeah. Rather than like a little
Speaker 13:  bit less phone. Then you want the the tablet one I mean our, our
Speaker 13:  good friend Dan Seaford will recommend a full
Speaker 13:  tablet style for you. That's how he watches Oppenheimer actually.
Speaker 13:  That's his favorite way to watch every movie, I guess.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, haunts me
Speaker 13:  That he does that with Instagram running on the side. Yeah, it, it's, I
Speaker 13:  see the appeal And I, I appreciate it for stuff that
Speaker 13:  I'm like sitting on the couch using the phone, you know, closed And.
Speaker 13:  I'm like, oh, I need to do this thing that I would normally
Speaker 13:  go get my laptop for. Like, I need to make an Amazon fresh
Speaker 13:  order and it's just like obnoxious to do it on a small screen. Yeah, those
Speaker 13:  moments where you're like, I either I need to put this phone down and go
Speaker 13:  get my laptop, that's when you Fold it open and you're like, no, I
Speaker 13:  can, I can run two things on the same screen. I can have,
Speaker 13:  I don't need to be like tabbing between apps. I can, I can figure out
Speaker 13:  where I'm gonna have lunch, you know, and Google Maps and read the restaurant
Speaker 13:  website that I, I get all that And I respect it and
Speaker 13:  it's very cool. I'm excited about the flip.
Speaker 9:  The flip also costs a lot less.
Speaker 13:  It's like a thousand bucks because
Speaker 9:  I'm excited about those things, but I'm not $1,800 excited, which is how
Speaker 9:  much the like Fold and the Pixel Fold costs.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. For $1,800 I'll get off the couch and go look
Speaker 13:  at my laptop. I think That's enough money.
Speaker 13:  So I, I think it's an interesting moment for the flip phones
Speaker 13:  just being at that nine ninety nine price point is like,
Speaker 13:  we're used to paying that much for phones or like having our carriers pay
Speaker 13:  that much and paying them back with our contracts. So
Speaker 13:  I think those are positioned a little better to take off.
Speaker 13:  And. I'm curious how the, how the kind of like
Speaker 13:  minimalist aspects of the phone are gonna appeal to people
Speaker 13:  or I don't know, maybe, maybe we all just do really
Speaker 13:  want phone plus maybe we all want more phone all the time.
Speaker 7:  Everyone just wants bigger screens. That's my theory. Yeah. Although e even
Speaker 7:  in this case, you're like, you know what really unlocked these flip phones
Speaker 7:  for me was when they added bigger screens to the front.
Speaker 13:  It's, it's true. All
Speaker 7:  Of all of tech is figuring out where you'd make the screen bigger to make
Speaker 7:  people buy. The next one is the inside. No, this time it's the outside. Like
Speaker 7:  that's, that's, that's the tech industry.
Speaker 13:  Next time around the back we'll have a screen and then I'm sold.
Speaker 13:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Do they say anything about durability? I mean this is what people are afraid
Speaker 7:  of the most with these phones?
Speaker 13:  Yeah, it's kind of this a little more the same this year. The
Speaker 13:  new hinge has a slightly different structure that's supposed to take
Speaker 13:  impacts a little better personally. That's another thing I'm worried about
Speaker 13:  with a folding bone. I'm worried about like a speck of dust getting under
Speaker 13:  the screen, but they're, they have gotten better
Speaker 13:  generation after generation. They say it's, it's still rated
Speaker 13:  to like 200,000 folds, which is like five years of use and
Speaker 13:  it's IPX eight rated. So they're both fully like water
Speaker 13:  submersible, but it's just a question mark like four years down the line,
Speaker 13:  how, how good is it at like
Speaker 13:  holding up, you know, how's the hinge? Did you get like a little bit of
Speaker 13:  dust underneath and ruin everything? That's the question mark.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. That IP X eight, that X is not dust protected. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like it's like very obvious. Like we're not gonna make that promise. Like
Speaker 7:  yeah,
Speaker 13:  It's just a nope.
Speaker 7:  There's some other stuff that happened at Samsung. What else did they announce?
Speaker 8:  You know, what is dust rated? The new tablets.
Speaker 7:  Oh my god. Alex.
Speaker 8:  That was, wasn't that the best segue you've ever heard?
Speaker 13:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  It's good. Some, yeah, sometimes you gotta just do it like a truck
Speaker 7:  just rumble into the, the frame with a Samsung tablet.
Speaker 8:  You know what's really dust rated
Speaker 8:  IP six eight baby. Yeah. These new, they're s
Speaker 8:  nines, right? That's that's the name of these. They are outrageously
Speaker 8:  expensive it sounds like. And everybody else is releasing cheaper
Speaker 8:  Android tablets. Are, are you excited about them at all? Allison
Speaker 8:  as like a person who uses Android more than I ever will.
Speaker 13:  No, I am a terrible person to ask about tablets. I
Speaker 13:  literally just bought like a three-year-old iPad for my toddler
Speaker 13:  and that's like the most I've thought about tablets in the past
Speaker 13:  few years. I think
Speaker 8:  That's like most people At this point,
Speaker 8:  right? Yeah. Like most people are kind of, we're we're happy to have them.
Speaker 8:  We want them, but they're not something that people get enthusiastic about
Speaker 8:  unless you're really concerned about dust rating and waterproofing
Speaker 8:  on your new tablet. In which case, and these have OLED screens,
Speaker 8:  like OLED displays, there's the Tab SS
Speaker 8:  nine, which is 11 inches. The Tab SS nine
Speaker 8:  plus, which is 12.4 inches and the
Speaker 8:  Ultra, which is 14.6. And at that point
Speaker 8:  do you just buy a tv?
Speaker 7:  You buy a laptop? Yeah. I mean, so this is the, and Google
Speaker 7:  has made some like new investment in Android tablets. Like they, they're
Speaker 7:  talking about it again, right? They've got the Pixel tablet, obviously
Speaker 7:  the, the foldable phones, particularly the Fold and the Pixel Fold.
Speaker 7:  The point of those is you put them in a tablet mode, so there's like a lot
Speaker 7:  of action on this side of the house and you just look at these Samsung tablets
Speaker 7:  and you're like, these are little laptops, especially at the bigger sizes.
Speaker 7:  They've got all those sort of iPad pro surface like
Speaker 7:  docs and adapters and keyboard, all the stuff is there and then you're like,
Speaker 7:  but I'm using not just Android, like Samsung,
Speaker 7:  Spen Android. Maybe some people like it send us emails. If you're like
Speaker 7:  a hardcore spen person and you
Speaker 7:  trust your workflow to that, I just, that just feels tenuous
Speaker 7:  to me. Yeah. Even though Samsung's been doing it for years, it's like, I'm
Speaker 7:  gonna get backed into a corner of Samsung's weird pen ideas and
Speaker 7:  then if they ever go away or Samsung like pulls the report and changes it,
Speaker 7:  like I'll be unsettled. Like I'm, I I don't like that.
Speaker 7:  Like going
Speaker 8:  From the little tiny pen to a proper stylist with an iPad is gonna like
Speaker 8:  blow those people's minds.
Speaker 7:  I won't even, I won't like, part of the reason that I won't put my workflow
Speaker 7:  on the iPad is every year apple's like, here's a new
Speaker 7:  multitasking idea and they just like rip it out and replace, you know, it's
Speaker 7:  like where they glue stage manager onto it And. I'm like, I got work to do.
Speaker 7:  I I I can't be on this journey with you. Call me when you settle
Speaker 7:  down.
Speaker 8:  I just feel like these Tab ss nines, like, they've kind of settled into a
Speaker 8:  lot of it. Like the the changes here Yeah. Are pretty small. They, they've
Speaker 8:  seem to have figured it out. They seem comfortable with their price point
Speaker 8:  even though it's more than everybody else. But they've also been at this
Speaker 8:  price point in this space for a lot longer, more
Speaker 8:  consistently than other Android tablets.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I I I'm just putting at the call, if you are a hardcore
Speaker 7:  Samsung tablet person and you saw this and you thought,
Speaker 7:  one, I need to switch from an iPad to the Spen ecosystem,
Speaker 7:  like, I want to hear for you in particular, I'm looking at you straight through
Speaker 7:  the barrel of the camera right now. I want to know you
Speaker 8:  Right into their soul.
Speaker 7:  Just please reach out. Or if you are an existing
Speaker 7:  like Spen person and you're like, oh shit, I gotta upgrade.
Speaker 7:  I just wanna hear from you like, what's it like in your brain?
Speaker 7:  Is it cool? Like, let me know. I'm just like dying to know. I think we're,
Speaker 7:  we're past that point even with the, the, the market leaders. Like I don't
Speaker 7:  think people are dying to upgrade from one surface to the next. Right. I
Speaker 7:  think their surface break or they get slow and then they like just get the
Speaker 7:  new one. Allison. I think that's your point about the iPad. Like
Speaker 7:  At this point. You, you cannot tell me what a new iPad can do that my existing
Speaker 7:  iPad can't do.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. It it's gonna run cocoa melon just fine.
Speaker 7:  Exactly. And, I get it right. Like with some of this vision Pro
Speaker 7:  stuff with Apple, like there's a whole suite of, I like the
Speaker 7:  iPad app ecosystem is the foundation of a bunch of things for
Speaker 7:  Apple in a way that Apple's good at managing the ecosystem. And on the Google
Speaker 7:  side that Android proper, like they are making this investment in tablets.
Speaker 7:  Like I think they see a slow step
Speaker 7:  path that way. I'm just very curious. Specifically Samsung
Speaker 7:  tablets, like if you're hardcore in a Samsung, like I just, that's what The
Speaker 7:  Verge is for.
Speaker 8:  You gotta pixel tablet, get out, don't email.
Speaker 8:  How
Speaker 7:  Many members are in r slash Samsung tablets? Is that even
Speaker 7:  a subreddit? Is there like forum drama in the r slash Samsung
Speaker 7:  tablet subreddit? Like, I just wanna know.
Speaker 8:  All right. I can't transition this one as well as the last one, but I do,
Speaker 8:  what's
Speaker 7:  An IP 68 rated?
Speaker 8:  I don't know. The IP 68 rating on the new Galaxy Watch
Speaker 8:  six series. 'cause there's more than one. God, there's not a pro
Speaker 8:  right now. There was a pro last year, but there is, there's a watch and
Speaker 8:  there's a classic. And the big thing Victoria is Oh, so excited
Speaker 8:  about it is they've got rotating bezels.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Bring 'em back. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  They're
Speaker 13:  Huge. Just the classic though.
Speaker 8:  Just the classic.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. And which is the one that's a hundred dollars more
Speaker 8:  And it's bigger. It's like comes in like a 44 and a 47
Speaker 8:  millimeter, which I don't got the wrist for that. No, my wrist
Speaker 8:  can't support that. Like I gotta, I gotta go to the gym a lot more if I'm
Speaker 8:  gonna wear the watch that big. Yeah, like that's rough. But it seems
Speaker 8:  cool. V I know is like, she's just terrifically excited about
Speaker 8:  it. And it sounds like other watch fans, Samsung watch
Speaker 8:  fans are excited 'cause they can't have Apple watches, so this is what they
Speaker 8:  have to get excited about.
Speaker 7:  I mean they're cool. They look cool the the round. Like I, I love a
Speaker 7:  rotating bezel. I think that's just like, it's so funny that I love it.
Speaker 7:  Like I think the digital crown is so silly, but I'm like rotating bezel.
Speaker 7:  Yes. That's what sings to me because
Speaker 8:  It's like, it reminds you of when you'd get that first watch with a rotating
Speaker 8:  bezel as a kid and it had that click and that, oh my gosh. That click was,
Speaker 8:  oh my god. Yeah, that's a good click. The,
Speaker 13:  The digital crown is annoying with fingernails too. Like yes, I have to
Speaker 13:  really get my fingernails on it.
Speaker 8:  And you ship your finger, like if you have paint on your nails, it'll chip
Speaker 8:  a little. Yeah. And then you're like, why should I even manipulate this stupid
Speaker 8:  crown? I'm gonna go get my phone. Yeah. Yeah. If it only had
Speaker 8:  had a rotating bezel like get on this apple, it could be square.
Speaker 8:  It works. So
Speaker 9:  The big new feature is not these new funny face watch faces that are extremely
Speaker 9:  creepy. That's
Speaker 8:  Not it. That's also there. you know
Speaker 7:  How like big things are unsettling? Like things that are slightly too big
Speaker 7:  or unsettling? Yeah, that's these watch faces.
Speaker 8:  It's just a little Ooh. I don't, Hmm.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, they're just, I'm like, I'm looking at this seven on this watch
Speaker 7:  face. I'm like, I don't Too big. Too big too. Like
Speaker 7:  they, I don't wanna look at it anymore.
Speaker 8:  What if it's just a quick glance at your wrist? I mean that'll keep you from
Speaker 8:  like looking at your watch all the time.
Speaker 7:  And, I. No, they've kept the hands at the same size. Actually telling the
Speaker 7:  time on this face in particular is more difficult. The numbers
Speaker 7:  are big and the hands are small. It's a very odd choice. You're
Speaker 8:  Just gonna be like this checking your watch in meetings. It's gonna be
Speaker 7:  Great. Famously using hands to check the time is so intuitive that You can
Speaker 7:  have big hands and no numbers. Rarely do you see
Speaker 7:  big numbers and no hands. It's gonna be fine guys. I
Speaker 7:  think it's cool. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  Some of them have mouths that I don't like.
Speaker 14:  They all, yeah,
Speaker 7:  It's all about how you get attention in a Best Buy. It's like you walking
Speaker 7:  down the aisle, there's like a big apple display that they co-brand. There's
Speaker 7:  whatever. There's like all the carrier noise and it's like, does that watch
Speaker 7:  have a mouth? It'll work. That's the
Speaker 3:  One. It'll work.
Speaker 7:  It'll super work to get your attention. All right,
Speaker 7:  we gotta end this. We, we've talked about watches with teeth for too long.
Speaker 7:  We'll be right back with a lightning round.
Speaker 15:  You are the man who gave them the power to destroy themselves
Speaker 15:  and the world is not prepared.
Speaker 14:  Oppenheimer opens in theaters today. Christopher Nolan's
Speaker 14:  feverishly anticipated film about the brilliant but troubled father
Speaker 14:  of the atomic bomb. Do you guys
Speaker 3:  Ever think about dying?
Speaker 14:  Yeah. No, I don't wanna talk about Oppenheimer today. You can go back to
Speaker 14:  your regular life or You can know the truth about the universe.
Speaker 14:  The choice is now yours. The first one. Okay ladies,
Speaker 14:  let's do this. And I,
Speaker 3:  Let's do this.
Speaker 14:  I'm ready to flip on those heels. Fall off your roof. We're having a giant
Speaker 14:  blowout party with planned choreography and a bespoke song. And we're gonna
Speaker 14:  sleep over tonight because we're girlfriend, boyfriend. It's today. Explain
Speaker 14:  and it's the best day ever and so is yesterday and so is tomorrow. And
Speaker 14:  every weekday at 2:00 PM when we drop a new episode of today, explain.
Speaker 16:  Listen, even if you don't have student loans yourself, you
Speaker 16:  probably know someone that does. Which means you also know the system
Speaker 16:  is broken. But have you ever wondered how
Speaker 16:  exactly it got this way?
Speaker 17:  There's a high demand for college because of this huge economic shift in
Speaker 17:  the US economy and the global economy and that you have this
Speaker 17:  like, you know, free flowing access to credit
Speaker 17:  and then you head uninformed consumers. I mean this is just a recipe
Speaker 17:  for disaster.
Speaker 16:  Your student loan debt. And then some explained that's this week on the
Speaker 16:  weeds. Listen wherever you get your podcasts,
Speaker 7:  We're back. We're gonna do a quick lightning round and then I just wanna
Speaker 7:  read some of the responses we got to consumer product
Speaker 7:  Turf wars. I'll tell you, we're gonna talk about DeWalt versus Milwaukee
Speaker 7:  on The Vergecast today. It's gonna be incredible. But we got some great responses.
Speaker 7:  And, I want, I wanna talk about them. But first let's do a little lightning
Speaker 7:  round. Cranz, you're up first.
Speaker 8:  All right. OpenAI has been working on a system to detect AI
Speaker 8:  written content and it's not going well. So they said we're, we're
Speaker 8:  just gonna stop doing that.
Speaker 7:  The blog post, they put up a blog post silently. They didn't even tell anyone
Speaker 7:  about it. Yeah, they just like updated the blog post where they had announced
Speaker 7:  this tool and they're like, we've discontinued the tool because the tool
Speaker 7:  doesn't work very well.
Speaker 8:  They're like, nevermind. Yeah. Nope. Not doing it. And yeah,
Speaker 8:  so So that's a little disconcerting because there's a lot of, obviously a
Speaker 8:  lot of use cases for where it'd be nice to quickly check if something is
Speaker 8:  written by ai, but it turns out that's a lot harder than getting in AI
Speaker 8:  to like write stuff.
Speaker 7:  I feel like I am good at detecting when something is written by ai.
Speaker 8:  Yes. A friend sent me, this is so horrible. A
Speaker 8:  friend sent me an obituary for a friend of theirs who had passed
Speaker 8:  and it was very clearly written by AI and it said things Like.
Speaker 8:  he worked in the Atlantic Ocean
Speaker 8:  and the guy apparently would've thought this was absolutely hysterical and
Speaker 8:  would've found it very, very funny. But it's just like somebody take a pass
Speaker 8:  at that.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 9:  It's one of those things I feel like it comes from editing so many people,
Speaker 9:  so many times you start to recognize people's phrase and their styles. Yes.
Speaker 9:  It's sort of humanlike in that way in that everyone has favorite phrases
Speaker 9:  that they don't even know they have and it has
Speaker 7:  That. Yeah, particularly chat, g chat g p D has like tropes in construct
Speaker 7:  like You can s You can, it has a style. It's a boring
Speaker 7:  robotic style, but it has a style. And like Richard said, if you, if you
Speaker 7:  are in the business of constantly editing other people's writing, you start
Speaker 7:  to recognize style like very quickly. Like I think
Speaker 7:  I could probably read The Verge of that bylines and get it 90%
Speaker 7:  right. Who wrote what, right. Like just on a day-to-day basis. I can, I can
Speaker 7:  tell you when Liz Lipato has written something,
Speaker 8:  Oh, next week on The Verge
Speaker 7:  Cast, it's just me guessing a bylines. I can, I can
Speaker 7:  probably pick David Pierce out of a block of copy in two seconds flat.
Speaker 7:  Like I've edited David for so long. I I know David so well. I think a lot
Speaker 7:  of our listeners can like read us into our writing and it's so that we get
Speaker 7:  a, you just do a chat G p t now it's just funny that OpenAI can't do it.
Speaker 7:  Like they're like, we can't do this. The robot can't see itself.
Speaker 7:  It's like a very funny outcome. It's very good. All right. Richard, what's
Speaker 7:  your lightning round?
Speaker 9:  This na, this charging network announcement from seven automakers. We've
Speaker 9:  got B M W, gm, Honda, Hyundai, Kia, Benzs
Speaker 9:  and STIs. Nice. They combined, they said they're gonna put it, they're gonna
Speaker 9:  build 30,000 charging locations by 2030.
Speaker 9:  The first ones shouldn't be here until next year, but like some of them,
Speaker 9:  they're planning to put along highways and then kind of the high traffic
Speaker 9:  spots are gonna make sure that there are places where You can go get food
Speaker 9:  and do other things while your car is charging and just kind of revamp the
Speaker 9:  North American charging infrastructure.
Speaker 7:  Are they doing by 20, are you using the Tesla, the n a c s connector or are
Speaker 7:  they doing c c s? Do they say they
Speaker 9:  Will At least right now the plan is to have both the c
Speaker 9:  c s, the combined charging system, like the older style that most cars have
Speaker 9:  so far and also the N A C SS standards that Tesla and most,
Speaker 9:  at least some of these automakers and some several other automakers have
Speaker 9:  said they'll use kind of starting in 2025. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Well I guess they have to support their existing cars. I guess they need
Speaker 7:  c c s. It's just a was a weird time like for all
Speaker 7:  of this infrastructure. Like we were thinking about buying a new
Speaker 7:  charger for our house And I was like, which standard do I
Speaker 7:  like? Do I buy the one for the car I have now or the car I might get in it.
Speaker 7:  It's a very weird time.
Speaker 8:  Real micro mini U s b well
Speaker 7:  Like, but like a mini U S B cable. Like I'll just buy this cable. It was
Speaker 7:  like $3 off. I'll do some e-waste to like move on with my life. This is like
Speaker 7:  I need to spend $500 And I might only last like it, it's only
Speaker 7:  gonna last this car, you know. Very strange. Okay, Allison, what's
Speaker 7:  yours?
Speaker 13:  Mine's a two-parter. So Wess wrote up some
Speaker 13:  T-mobile news, which is like cool, exciting T-mobile news. They
Speaker 13:  successfully, they have reach speeds of 3.3
Speaker 13:  gigabits per second with four carrier aggregation. And this is,
Speaker 13:  this is like in the wild their their actual working five
Speaker 13:  G network. They can do this because they have a standalone network that
Speaker 13:  they bought from Sprint. Not from Sprint. They bought Sprint.
Speaker 7:  It's true.
Speaker 13:  Cool. so like cool. Yay. Good job. T-Mobile. The other news
Speaker 13:  that Sheena wrote up earlier this week is that they're now charging
Speaker 13:  people $5 to pay their bills in the store.
Speaker 13:  So if you don't, if you can't pay online or if you
Speaker 13:  don't want to or whatever reason you have, you go into a T-Mobile
Speaker 13:  store to pay them money for your phone service,
Speaker 13:  they're gonna charge you extra money to do that. So
Speaker 13:  there's the dark side of T-mobile news.
Speaker 7:  Do they explain why they're doing that?
Speaker 13:  They call it a payment support charge.
Speaker 7:  Oh sure.
Speaker 13:  Yeah.
Speaker 9:  It's, it's innovation. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  It should be called a Boomer support charge.
Speaker 13:  Like, oh boy, this is
Speaker 8:  Just, that's rough. This is, I say this, my mom I think is a T-Mobile customer
Speaker 8:  and she definitely is like, I'm going to the T-Mobile store today. And. I
Speaker 8:  was like, you got more than once a month. What's happening there?
Speaker 13:  I go to the Verizon store, like more than the average person
Speaker 13:  and they're, they're not that busy. Like I think they can handle
Speaker 13:  a few boomers coming in to pay their bills. I don't know.
Speaker 13:  All
Speaker 9:  They need to do is add a credit for every single time they get hacked and
Speaker 9:  leak your information. And then no one would get charged this for like the
Speaker 9:  next two or three years. And, I could just ease it in. It would be great.
Speaker 9:  I
Speaker 7:  Wish we had any data on how many people are going in these stores to pay
Speaker 7:  their bills. Like they're obviously trying to deter you from doing it. It
Speaker 7:  must cost them more somehow. I, I guess I think, I don't know,
Speaker 7:  maybe
Speaker 8:  There's not that many and they're like, you know what, this is an extra like
Speaker 8:  $500 a month for us. why not? They're there but
Speaker 13:  Like what are they doing? They're just load, they're like loading your
Speaker 13:  profile on a tablet that they're holding at the store and like
Speaker 13:  punching in numbers. Like I, I
Speaker 8:  Don't know. They're taking your card. Yeah. Or your cash.
Speaker 13:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I will never forget. This is not about T-Mobile. I'll take any chance to
Speaker 7:  dunk on at t. I can get At this point. A long, long time ago I was complaining
Speaker 7:  about something with at and t and an at and t spokesperson called me.
Speaker 7:  This is ages ago. I'm out of my own background policy. This was like on
Speaker 7:  background. They called me, I was like a little baby reporter and they dressed
Speaker 7:  me down because they're like, you do not understand how complicated
Speaker 7:  the at and t billing system is. If we, if you want to make any
Speaker 7:  changes, it requires 60,000 people to work for a year
Speaker 7:  to change the font on this website and like propagate the billing
Speaker 7:  system changes. And I was like, oh that sounds right. And now I'm like, oh,
Speaker 7:  they were just flying.
Speaker 9:  They, they probably weren't And I. And I can tell you why. Because again,
Speaker 9:  reaching into my own past working at Comcast, woo, I don't know if it's still
Speaker 9:  like this, but within 10, 15 years ago,
Speaker 9:  it essentially was still a Doss system that the billing system ran on and
Speaker 9:  then they came out with another system that was on top of that. But you've
Speaker 9:  got, you're talking about a billing system that was written in like Cobalt
Speaker 9:  or something. Yeah. So they cannot change anything. All right. But I think
Speaker 9:  with T-Mobile it's, they don't want to have anyone spending time doing this
Speaker 9:  in store 'cause they want them upselling you on phones. Yeah. They're
Speaker 7:  Like, have you seen this case? Also,
Speaker 9:  They're really trying to push people into auto pay because like
Speaker 9:  those direct bank authorizations and those kind of auto payments, it's good
Speaker 9:  for their bottom line and also it's cheaper than like authorizing a card,
Speaker 9:  doing a check or even handling cash or something like that. Yeah. So they're
Speaker 9:  just really trying to push auto pay.
Speaker 8:  I just think all the T-mobile employees actually have to be COBOL like
Speaker 8:  programmers and that's why they're charging the extra 'cause
Speaker 8:  it's to offset
Speaker 9:  It'd be more secure. Yeah. If they were,
Speaker 7:  It's that's the Coble bonus that they're, they're like, there's one wizard
Speaker 7:  and they owe him more money every year and they're like, we gotta fund this
Speaker 7:  Coble bonus. Yep. Who knows. Allison, while I have you here and we're talking
Speaker 7:  carriers, can I, can I get a quick Gen five sis update? Oh yeah, we mentioned
Speaker 7:  Sprint so we gotta do it. So T-Mobile bought Sprint. We brought our
Speaker 7:  nation's carriers down to three. We were supposed to invent a new carrier
Speaker 7:  out of Dish network. What's going on? Do we have a fourth carrier yet?
Speaker 13:  We do not. We still have project gen fives,
Speaker 13:  which is still kind of in beta. They say that they met their,
Speaker 13:  their June F C C deadline, which was like
Speaker 13:  70% of the population. They needed to cover the
Speaker 13:  one in I wanna say 2020. Yeah, I think next year is like
Speaker 13:  the big one, which would be, it's a certain amount of
Speaker 13:  covering like a certain amount of the places where they hold spectrum licenses,
Speaker 13:  which is trickier and more expensive I guess. So the short answer
Speaker 13:  is no. Something I did write up this week
Speaker 13:  is that You can sign up for Boost Infinite through Amazon Prime
Speaker 13:  now. So that's what we got.
Speaker 7:  That's good. That's really the big three carriers quaking in their boots.
Speaker 7:  'cause You can sign up for Boost Infinite with Infinite, Amazon Prime. All
Speaker 7:  right. My lightning round, just a really quick one. Verin reviewed
Speaker 7:  the D G I Mavic Air three this week. It's new drone
Speaker 7:  and he actually sparked a really interesting conversation on YouTube, in
Speaker 7:  our YouTube comments about how drones have gotten kind of boring. Like the
Speaker 7:  innovation cycle of drones has started to slow down and we're kind of the
Speaker 7:  same place with phones where we're just talking about pretty
Speaker 7:  incremental camera upgrades every year. And the actual
Speaker 7:  part of like the camera can fly by itself is no
Speaker 7:  longer interesting. Which is just a remarkable place to be.
Speaker 7:  Go check out that YouTube con. It's like really good. Vera is very proud
Speaker 7:  of the review. It's a great review. He flew the drone into a storm, which
Speaker 7:  you're not supposed to do. The shots are beautiful, but it's just a really
Speaker 7:  great example of like the community that we have on our site and on our platforms.
Speaker 7:  Just like talking about a thing altogether really great, like super into
Speaker 7:  it. And that brings us to fighting.
Speaker 8:  Yes.
Speaker 8:  I got too excited. Sorry.
Speaker 7:  So last week we were joking about the cyber truck and whether or not people
Speaker 7:  had strong opinions about Windshield washer fluid. It turns out they
Speaker 7:  do. Okay, whatever. We're gonna set that aside for like a full,
Speaker 7:  I, I can't even begin to evaluate that situation
Speaker 7:  except to say you should not use plain water. I just can't. That's
Speaker 13:  A thing. I
Speaker 7:  Don't do it. Yeah, a bunch of people email us like the only answer is plain
Speaker 7:  water. And it's like if maybe if you live in the desert, I don't know man.
Speaker 7:  I live work at school. We're
Speaker 8:  Gonna do Soda Mountain Dew,
Speaker 7:  Coca-Cola, Coke Heavy. Just spray that on your car. It's gonna be
Speaker 7:  great. And we asked all of you to send us what your favorite like
Speaker 7:  versus R, so there's iOS versus Android. We said you can't do
Speaker 7:  that too easy. Just pure engagement, right? Like you walk out in the street
Speaker 7:  and you say iOS versus Android and like a hundred people form a circle around
Speaker 7:  you and start arguing Mac versus Windows. It used to be the thing. I think
Speaker 7:  it's declined. We're like, what are the other ones? So we got this one. Haven't
Speaker 7:  evaluated it, but Rob tells us that V H s versus beta
Speaker 7:  is still going. Yes.
Speaker 13:  Wow.
Speaker 7:  Which is incredible. I'm super into that. This one
Speaker 7:  is pure Vergecast bait. Richard. I'm dying for your thoughts here. Chase
Speaker 7:  tells us I'm in a discord for the A M C A-list subscribers.
Speaker 7:  And the fight between IMAX and Dolby fans is so intense
Speaker 7:  that they make you choose forum flare to show which side
Speaker 7:  you're on. And then he says the answer of course is IMAX
Speaker 9:  Of co. Of course there are fan boys. Of course there are stands. I've never
Speaker 9:  actually been to Dolby Theater. Like I would've to drive like 30 miles out
Speaker 9:  out my way to go to Dolby Theater. Will I do it? Yes. Because I need to get
Speaker 9:  into this battle.
Speaker 7:  Andrew wrote to us as apparently Bose versus Sony Noise canceling
Speaker 7:  just like four Wars left and right. Like how can you have an opinion on this?
Speaker 7:  You,
Speaker 8:  It's Sony.
Speaker 7:  The noise is canceled.
Speaker 8:  Sony, okay.
Speaker 7:  DeWalt versus Milwaukee Power Tools. We should do an entire episode on
Speaker 7:  this. Like people really care about this. I follow a TikTok
Speaker 7:  er who's like a Ryobi power fan and it's just a gadget blog
Speaker 7:  for Ryobi tools on TikTok. Like an old school
Speaker 7:  gadget blog. If you're a longtime broadcast listener, you know that
Speaker 7:  the tool guide, G U Y D is one of my
Speaker 7:  favorite blogs. It's still going. It is just old school and
Speaker 7:  gadget for power tools. It is incredible. Chainsaw journal. My
Speaker 7:  favorite trade publication. It's good, it's good. I'm just telling you it's
Speaker 7:  good. There are more Ableton versus Freude studio. Apparently a hardcore
Speaker 7:  battle. Did
Speaker 13:  We get Canon versus Nikon?
Speaker 7:  Canon versus Nikon? Incredible. Cannot believe I forgot about it. Although
Speaker 7:  I will say Canon, I'm a Nikon person so I'm gonna say this,
Speaker 7:  it's, it seems like they have figured it out in a way that Nikon is not,
Speaker 13:  I feel like it's one of those, the Mac versus PC thing where it's like
Speaker 13:  everybody's just, you've picked your side by now, right? Like are peoples
Speaker 13:  switching between Canon Nikon is, isn't it more
Speaker 13:  mirrorless? D S L? I don't know. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  That's what I mean. It's like on in the mirrorless world, it's like Sony
Speaker 7:  and Canon, right? Like they're the winners and that and they're like pro
Speaker 7:  space and then they're sort of Nikon and I'm much like rooting for 'em.
Speaker 7:  They are, You can do it buddy. you know, like you're,
Speaker 8:  They're not rooting for themselves.
Speaker 7:  They don't appear to be rooting for themselves. At this point in time. But
Speaker 7:  that's a great one. I think
Speaker 8:  My favorite is Shimano versus SRAM to bite components.
Speaker 7:  That's Dieter. I don't know if that And I don't know if a hundred percent
Speaker 7:  if that's Dieter sent that to us, but that sounds like Dieter sent that to
Speaker 8:  Us. Yeah, Dieter is just, just little ghost, ghost email
Speaker 7:  Richard. What's yours? Mechanical
Speaker 9:  Keyboards versus ones everyone else in the office tolerates.
Speaker 7:  Especially we, these hybrid workplace. Very good. Sugary, very heated debate.
Speaker 7:  All right, we got a lot of these we're I keep sending 'em to us. They're
Speaker 7:  so good. These are good. I, you know, as you know, Liam's dream is that we
Speaker 7:  make entire episodes like diving deep into these subcultures.
Speaker 7:  I love getting these emails 'cause it's really funny to hear people's explanations.
Speaker 7:  I will say the best one we got this week was Vergecast versus waveform.
Speaker 7:  I think that's very obvious. It's waveform. No, it's The. Vergecast.
Speaker 7:  Come on. We love 'em. That's great. Competition is the, is, you know, the,
Speaker 7:  the, the driving force of, of of interest on this show. So I love
Speaker 7:  these, these are really great. If you know why V H Ss versus beta is still
Speaker 7:  going and you want to pitch crayons on writing 1500
Speaker 7:  words on it, by all means.
Speaker 8:  I kind of know a little bit. I have a vague idea. There's still like a
Speaker 8:  really, there part of it's like archival purposes and stuff and there's a
Speaker 8:  whole subculture around V H Ss tape still because so much stuff got
Speaker 8:  released on V H s that didn't get released on any other platform. And
Speaker 8:  Beta back actually has higher resolution. It's like higher
Speaker 8:  fidelity. And so ripping and stuff like betas are superior to rip,
Speaker 8:  generally speaking than v h s. But the
Speaker 8:  ripping technology for v h s is better. This is all crisp person And I
Speaker 8:  talk about in our dms. I don't understand 70% of our dms. It's great.
Speaker 7:  1500 words on the website, v h s versus
Speaker 7:  beta is still going. I think it's important. Like this is why The
Speaker 7:  Verge exists. I just, I cannot be clearer about what our
Speaker 7:  purpose here is. We write about the Samsung phones to pay the bills so we
Speaker 7:  can write the VHSs beta story, like
Speaker 7:  very clear what what, what our like flow is. I demand it.
Speaker 7:  I must know. It's good
Speaker 8:  Stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Alright, send us more if you have, if You can possibly explain the
Speaker 7:  Rain X thing to me, it's just very good. Like this is what the
Speaker 7:  internet's for. Lots more of these. Send them, send them to us as again,
Speaker 7:  Liam's dream is to do an entire episode on these. They're really fun to hear.
Speaker 7:  It's really fun to hear your opinions on, on just Vercast of The Verge dot
Speaker 7:  com. We love it. That's it. That's the show. I gotta get outta this hotel
Speaker 7:  room. I've been in it for like 95 hours straight. There's lots of stuff on
Speaker 7:  the site you should read. We wrote a look back at the I River MP three player,
Speaker 7:  which is like a true gadget nerd MP three player. Great blast from the past.
Speaker 7:  The Chromecast turned 10 years old. Sean Hollister wrote about the original
Speaker 7:  Chromecast referencing the review of the Chromecast that I wrote that I had
Speaker 7:  completely forgotten about. He's like, Zaro new And. I was like, Hey, Z,
Speaker 7:  NELI, Pilson, And. I was like, did I say that? Incredible. We have a great
Speaker 7:  piece on the indie game scene in Japan, which is really cool. And then our
Speaker 7:  Google coverage, we're really covering Google search a lot this year, really
Speaker 7:  thinking about what it means for the internet to be architected around Google
Speaker 7:  search and how that might change is AI rolls out our very own. David Pierce
Speaker 7:  wrote a story about Neva. It's a profile of Neva, the paid search engine
Speaker 7:  that was meant to compete with Google. It's a bunch of ex Googlers and they
Speaker 7:  couldn't do it. And that's a story from beginning 10, A startup
Speaker 7:  to failure of a startup really unpacking why Google is so dominant and
Speaker 7:  all the ways that it uses its dominance. Really great story, really fun profile
Speaker 7:  to read. And just like a, like I said, a marker of something that's
Speaker 7:  changing. So just go read that story. Look at our Google coverage. If you
Speaker 7:  have ideas on how we should cover Google and Google search in particular
Speaker 7:  through this matter of change. Love to hear those too. Okay, Allison, thank
Speaker 7:  you for putting up with us. Richard. Thank you for letting in for David.
Speaker 7:  That's it. That's rich cast, rock and roll.
Speaker 11:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 11:  us an email at Vergecast at The Verge dot com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 11:  production of The Verge and the Vox Media podcast network. The show is produced
Speaker 11:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. Our
Speaker 11:  editorial director is Brooke Miners. That's it. We'll see you next week.