# Transcript
ID: 97cb8f50-bc02-11ed-a221-c3faa5a664bc
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Solo Acts: Madison Karrh on her adventure puzzle game 'Birth'
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5905574260684741500/239556613568653848/s93290-US-1859s-1678095479.mp3
Description: On episode three of our Solo Acts miniseries, Ashley Esqueda chats with Madison Karrh, an indie game developer who launched her most recent game Birth a few weeks ago. Birth is an adventure puzzle game about constructing a creature from spare bones & organs found around the city in order to quell your loneliness. Madison explains the challenges of making an entire game on your own and why that path is so important to her.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  Support for this podcast comes from Toyota Crown, the all new Toyota Crown
Speaker 1:  wants to help you make a statement each and every time you drive. Find yourself
Speaker 1:  immersed in the premium driver focused interior that puts you in control.
Speaker 1:  Not to mention that the Toyota Crown is equipped with Toyota Safety Sense
Speaker 1:  3.0 featuring lane tracing, assist full speed range,
Speaker 1:  dynamic range cruise control, automatic high beams, and so much more.
Speaker 1:  Toyota says, wherever you go in the all new Toyota Crown, you make a
Speaker 1:  statement, the car that says so much. Visit
Speaker 1:  toyota.com/crown to learn more. Toyota,
Speaker 1:  let's go places.
Speaker 4:  Welcome to the cast, the flagship podcast of playing really
Speaker 4:  good independent games on the steam deck. It's, it's my personal favorite.
Speaker 4:  I'm your friend Alex Kranz, and today we're gonna have a new episode of our
Speaker 4:  Solo Act miniseries, which features interviews from people who are working
Speaker 4:  independently to create great things on the internet. And every Monday on
Speaker 4:  the Vergecast, our friend Ashley Esqueda is curating and hosting these interviews
Speaker 4:  and sharing with us what she's learned. And Ashley is here right now. Hello
Speaker 4:  Ashley.
Speaker 5:  Hi.
Speaker 4:  You've been working on a really cool episode. It sounds like
Speaker 4:  all about video games. All about a video
Speaker 5:  Game. A video game. Well, a video game developer. Okay. I
Speaker 5:  love video games and I love indie games.
Speaker 5:  The joy, the thrill of discovering a cool indie game
Speaker 5:  is just, there's nothing else like it. And so I am talking today
Speaker 5:  to solo game developer Madison Carr.
Speaker 4:  Well, why Madison?
Speaker 5:  I first met her last year at Summer Game Fest in June. I
Speaker 5:  was immediately drawn to her game, which is called Birth.
Speaker 4:  What's birth about?
Speaker 5:  Birth is a point and click adventure puzzle game. You gotta
Speaker 5:  make a friend basically out of spare bones and organs you
Speaker 5:  find around this very strange city because you're lonely.
Speaker 5:  It's a game about loneliness. Okay. And it's all hand drawn. Madison
Speaker 5:  Draw, she draws everything, draws everything herself. She does everything
Speaker 5:  herself. And it has this very kind of organic dream-like
Speaker 5:  quality to it. And to me it is just so creepy and so
Speaker 5:  beautiful. Like it's a, it's a Frankenstein's monster thing, but in a good
Speaker 5:  way.
Speaker 4:  Well, I personally am very much looking forward to hearing more of your conversation
Speaker 4:  with Madison.
Speaker 5:  Hi Madison. Thank you for coming on the show.
Speaker 6:  Hi Ashley. Thank you so much for having me.
Speaker 5:  I've given a very broad description of birth, but Madison,
Speaker 5:  do you mind explaining to the listeners in a little more detail
Speaker 5:  what kind of game birth is?
Speaker 6:  Sure, yes. Birth is a puzzle game about
Speaker 6:  living alone in a large city. It was inspired by my
Speaker 6:  move to Chicago at the very beginning of the pandemic and
Speaker 6:  living alone in a tiny studio apartment. And in order to
Speaker 6:  call your loneliness in birth, you have decided to construct a creature from
Speaker 6:  spare bones and organs that you find while traversing the new city that
Speaker 6:  you've moved to.
Speaker 5:  I am very curious about your journey as a solo game developer
Speaker 5:  because it's a, it's a very interesting path that many people
Speaker 5:  like to think that they could attempt or that they are
Speaker 5:  interested in attempting. And I wanna hear a little bit about how that got
Speaker 5:  started for you. So when did you start making games and
Speaker 5:  why did you start making games?
Speaker 6:  I got into games via playing the Rusty Light games and
Speaker 6:  realizing that I think seeing something that's just art that you're clicking
Speaker 6:  around on that felt very accessible and I just
Speaker 6:  had a very strong desire to try to make something similar. I'm a
Speaker 6:  programmer by trade and so that part came easy learning.
Speaker 6:  The C sharp, it's the art that I did not have a ton of experience in.
Speaker 6:  And so I had just made it my New Year's resolution one year to draw every
Speaker 6:  day and try to get better. My first game is very rough
Speaker 6:  in terms of, I definitely was, was learning as I made
Speaker 6:  stuff. And there's a beauty in not knowing how little,
Speaker 6:  you know, therefore you're okay with releasing something. So my first game
Speaker 6:  that I ever made definitely just came from blissful ignorance of thinking
Speaker 6:  that something was, was better than it was, I think, and not being embarrassed
Speaker 6:  to show off what you made. Yeah. So that was in
Speaker 6:  2018 that I started maybe late
Speaker 6:  2017 and I was working a full-time job at a
Speaker 6:  financial software, which was very boring. And so it was a,
Speaker 6:  a lot of early mornings and late nights and I think it was just really the
Speaker 6:  obsession of starting making something and seeing something on the screen
Speaker 6:  that wasn't there before and you made it. And that was just a
Speaker 6:  very addictive thing I think. And that like kept me coming back
Speaker 6:  every day, every morning wanting to work on it. And so that was through
Speaker 6:  2020, early 2021, I got funding from
Speaker 6:  Wings and then was able to quit my full-time job. And so now I work on
Speaker 6:  my stuff full-time, which is amazing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, this is, you're a full-time solo game developer,
Speaker 5:  this is your day job now. You made it your day job, which is the, that's
Speaker 5:  the dream, right? You're living the dream.
Speaker 6:  Absolutely. It feels like a dream for
Speaker 5:  Sure. So to be clear to everybody, you mentioned
Speaker 5:  the art, your programmer by trade, everything in this game
Speaker 5:  is made by you.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Yes, that is true.
Speaker 5:  So what tools, you mentioned C Sharp, what other tools do you
Speaker 5:  use? What, what are your preferred tools of your trade?
Speaker 6:  Yes. So I use Unity as a game engine program in C
Speaker 6:  Sharp and then I use Clip Studio, clip studio Paint for drawing.
Speaker 6:  And that's only because I bought a Waycom tablet and it
Speaker 6:  came with a subscription to Clip Studio and it's just what I learned on and
Speaker 6:  I'm afraid of change. So I haven't switched yet, but I've looked into procreate
Speaker 6:  a little bit cuz it seems really fun. And then just notebooks in terms of
Speaker 6:  like idea, making sure that I have something to write, to write down
Speaker 5:  Sketching things out. How long did it take you to make birth from start
Speaker 5:  to finish?
Speaker 6:  Birth took 18 months, I think a year and a half.
Speaker 6:  And that was the longest I'd worked on something. And that I think most of
Speaker 6:  that time was a surprise just because I ended up pushing the release date.
Speaker 6:  It was supposed to come out a few months ago. But doing the events, going
Speaker 6:  to summer Games Fest where we met, and then Gamescom and other
Speaker 6:  events throughout the year, that takes a lot of, it takes a lot of time to
Speaker 6:  do the PR part of making a game. So there's the
Speaker 6:  Making the Game, which is fun cuz you get to sit at your desk, you get to
Speaker 6:  be quiet. And then there's the PR and like showing people the game and hoping
Speaker 6:  that they like it.
Speaker 5:  Now is that something that required you to step out of your comfort zone?
Speaker 5:  Are you more of an introvert? Do you, were you excited to get out there and
Speaker 5:  really, I mean obviously you wanna show off the thing you made.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I definitely fall towards the more introverted side of
Speaker 6:  the spectrum. I think that's the only way that you can make a game on your
Speaker 6:  own is if you're comfortable living a lot of your life by yourself. If you're
Speaker 6:  comfortable sitting your desk in silence, which I think could be said for
Speaker 6:  a lot of creative crafts, there's two parts. There's going out and
Speaker 6:  talking and being social and that can be draining as an introvert. There's
Speaker 6:  also the fact that birth is so extremely personal and
Speaker 6:  close to me that it feels a little embarrassing to talk
Speaker 6:  about in that way. And I am so thankful that so many people
Speaker 6:  resonated with the premise of Birth of Living alone in a tiny
Speaker 6:  studio, especially after The Pandemic. Not that I want anyone to feel lonely
Speaker 6:  and I would love for everyone to have their person, but yeah, there, I think
Speaker 6:  that part was a little weird to talk about just because it was basically
Speaker 6:  like me being like, hi, I was so lonely that I had to make a game
Speaker 6:  about it, which is like, wow, you really care about it. You
Speaker 6:  really, really care. You really were lonely. So I think that's part of it
Speaker 6:  too, is the vulnerability of saying like, hi, I put my whole heart
Speaker 6:  into this and I hope that's enough. I hope that's enough for you. Also, really
Speaker 6:  just like a very humbling experience to having people play it
Speaker 6:  and give you compliments about it and and tell you that it
Speaker 6:  resonates with you is just like, I don't know, it just made me feel like
Speaker 6:  my heart was gonna explode the, the whole time
Speaker 5:  I, I would imagine there is something cathartic or
Speaker 5:  validating about hearing the interpretation
Speaker 5:  of yes, the gameplay from people who did not build it
Speaker 5:  and did not have that very close connection because the idea of
Speaker 5:  loneliness is very universal, right? Or the feeling
Speaker 5:  of not having those resources, those friendship
Speaker 5:  circles and everybody collectively. It's very interesting that
Speaker 5:  you were working on this game and then the pandemic hit
Speaker 5:  and it's very much a reflection of everybody got that
Speaker 5:  experience really to some extent. And so it's, it's interesting that there
Speaker 5:  is that shared loneliness. There's an understanding there
Speaker 5:  that maybe, I don't know, was there before for a lot of people.
Speaker 6:  Absolutely. I do think birth is coming out at a good time in
Speaker 6:  terms of, of course there's never a good time for everyone to be spending
Speaker 6:  so much time in their apartments, but I do think that that did
Speaker 6:  form a more universal or or a greater percentage of humans
Speaker 6:  that had had experience with that where before, I don't know, it was a
Speaker 6:  lot easier to mask loneliness and a lot easier to go out and spend time with
Speaker 6:  people in order to cover that up. So I think you're right that I think the
Speaker 6:  pandemic made it a little bit more relevant.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I, I would argue a lot more relevant. I so much more relevant.
Speaker 5:  So walk me through what it is like on a typical
Speaker 5:  day for you as a solo game Dove. Do you impose crunch on yourself?
Speaker 5:  Like what is, what is your process?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's kind of weird because crunch seems so negative when
Speaker 6:  someone's working on someone else's game, when someone's making a game for
Speaker 6:  a different studio. But when you're working on your own thing, it feels more
Speaker 6:  like an obsession and there's more of a, I don't know, romanticized vision
Speaker 6:  of it I guess. I don't think French should ever be romanticized, but I, I
Speaker 6:  am just so obsessed with making things that I do spend. I would say majority
Speaker 6:  of my weekdays are spent sitting at my desk and it does not
Speaker 6:  feel like work. So my typical schedule is I wake up between six
Speaker 6:  to eight depending on how I'm feeling I guess. And
Speaker 5:  How late you were coding the night before.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, make copies, sit down at my desk. And for the most part,
Speaker 6:  when you're working on your own, I think there's this beauty of being able
Speaker 6:  to come up with an idea and then implement it then in that moment.
Speaker 6:  And so there's like a lot of, each day feels like there's this chance for
Speaker 6:  amazing things to happen because you don't have to have permission from someone
Speaker 6:  else. There's no red tape in terms of like getting someone's opinion or getting
Speaker 6:  someone's approval to put something in the game. And so a lot of times I'm
Speaker 6:  thinking of things that day and can implement them within like hours. And
Speaker 6:  so it typically depends, but usually I am drawing and programming in the
Speaker 6:  same day. The way that I work is I know that there's advice that
Speaker 6:  you should prototype an ugly version of your game first to know if the
Speaker 6:  gameplay is fun. But I struggle with having ugly things on my screen.
Speaker 6:  And so I typically draw final art from the start. I
Speaker 6:  will draw like a very rough draft and then for the most part it is like final
Speaker 6:  art. So that is just the most joyful way for me to work, I think as if I
Speaker 6:  can make something that looks really good the first time and be able to
Speaker 6:  see, so that way when I set up the physics or the programming for that object,
Speaker 6:  it feels finished in that moment. Any day that I have to do audio, any
Speaker 6:  day that I have to record any amount of music is not tho those are not my
Speaker 6:  best days. But usually I chunk those into like, okay, these will be my audio
Speaker 6:  days and then I will be done with it for the time. So usually programming
Speaker 6:  and art are my, my happy spaces and those are the two that I work on every
Speaker 6:  day.
Speaker 5:  I would imagine having close to final art as you're working is very
Speaker 5:  motivating to be able to Yes. To keep going. It's sort of like the, it's
Speaker 5:  the carrot that keeps you kind of going f moving forward.
Speaker 6:  Yes, absolutely. I, I agree with you.
Speaker 5:  Okay, we're gonna take a break, but when we come back we'll talk about the
Speaker 5:  logistics of making your way as a solo game developer.
Speaker 1:  This episode is sponsored by Toyota Crown Crown's available hybrid,
Speaker 1:  max powertrain and standard all-wheel drive makes this sedan a leader in
Speaker 1:  the field from the premium driver focused interior that says you're always
Speaker 1:  comfortable in the spotlight to the stylish exterior that says Trendsetter
Speaker 1:  Toyota says, wherever you go in the all new Toyota crown, you make a statement,
Speaker 1:  the car that says so much, visit toyota.com/crown
Speaker 1:  to learn more. Toyota, let's go places.
Speaker 5:  Okay, we're back. And I have Alex crayons with me.
Speaker 4:  I have to butt in because I have one question, how the money happened.
Speaker 5:  The eternal question. The eternal question. Well, Madison
Speaker 5:  has a publisher as an indie game developer. She is given
Speaker 5:  an advance, much like a book deal, she's given an advance
Speaker 5:  to make a game that she either has a working prototype of or
Speaker 5:  if she has a working relationship with a publisher or any other solo game
Speaker 5:  developer has a working relationship, a lot of times there's an understanding
Speaker 5:  that she's making her next project. This is kind of the top
Speaker 5:  line idea, go forth, make game. And then once that
Speaker 5:  advance is set in stone, it's doled out in
Speaker 5:  pieces as the project meets milestones. So you can't just
Speaker 5:  wallow in concept art land for 10 years and you gotta ship something.
Speaker 5:  Well you gotta just show some progress, right? Yeah. It's like you gotta,
Speaker 5:  you gotta show 'em something. And then when the game comes out, publisher
Speaker 5:  usually usually sets the pricing and then the
Speaker 5:  publisher usually wants to recoup that advance, they
Speaker 5:  wanna get back some of that money or all of it. And that
Speaker 5:  amount of percentage when the game launches depends on the agreement between
Speaker 5:  the game developer and the publisher. So it could be a hundred percent of
Speaker 5:  an advance has to be recouped before the developer makes anything. Or it
Speaker 5:  could be a percentage, a split in there and then the developer
Speaker 5:  keeps the ip, it doesn't ever belong to the publisher. Okay. So that's nice.
Speaker 5:  And then there's a publishing agreement. So there's a set period of time
Speaker 5:  where the publisher is collecting on profits.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So given kind of the economics of it in,
Speaker 4:  in a lot of those challenges, why, why does Madison go down this route rather
Speaker 4:  than going towards a more stable kind of consistently
Speaker 4:  lucrative thing? Like as a AAA game developer?
Speaker 5:  That is a great question and one she answered. So let's take a listen.
Speaker 6:  So I think there obviously is a lot of safety in having a
Speaker 6:  corporate job and making the decision to quit. My job in
Speaker 6:  2021 was very scary and it was not like something that
Speaker 6:  that was easy at all. And, and I feel like for the first few months I was
Speaker 6:  just terrified all the time of like, have I made a terrible
Speaker 6:  financial decision? Because then you're also in charge of taxes. There's
Speaker 6:  a lot more than just like, how big can the number be? You know, what is the
Speaker 6:  number I need per month? I had no idea how hard it was gonna be to do your
Speaker 6:  taxes when you are not having a w2.
Speaker 5:  Yes, it is hard,
Speaker 6:  It's terrible, it's terrible. And then health insurance, you have to figure
Speaker 6:  that out. There's a lot more than just choosing salary, you know, based
Speaker 6:  on, on that number. And also just from a mental health perspective of
Speaker 6:  having that safety net. But I think in terms of, and not to be so
Speaker 6:  extremely philosophical, but the way that I will measure my life
Speaker 6:  at the end of it is how well did I love my partner
Speaker 6:  and how many works have I
Speaker 6:  created that I'm proud of? And working at a studio, making someone
Speaker 6:  else's games, obviously that's a much easier and safer feeling
Speaker 6:  life to have, but there is a direct limitation on
Speaker 6:  how many of your own things you get to make. So it's definitely scarier
Speaker 6:  to be on your own, but I think it's worth it if you have that obsession with
Speaker 6:  your own creative work and getting better. But I definitely see how people
Speaker 6:  could want to just stay at a, at a job cuz it's safe and that's good. And
Speaker 6:  I, my best friend, she will work corporate forever and she, she lives a very
Speaker 6:  nice, a nice, safe, easy life and I'm happy for her, but that
Speaker 6:  is just not what I, what I want. It's hard to, hard to live a creative life,
Speaker 6:  I think.
Speaker 5:  So birth is a game about loneliness and a pandemic
Speaker 5:  happened in the middle of it. And one of the biggest parts
Speaker 5:  of the indie game dev community is those connections
Speaker 5:  between other indie game devs and obviously,
Speaker 5:  you know, conventions and other networking opportunities were not available
Speaker 5:  for a big chunk of births development. How did
Speaker 5:  you personally pivot during the pandemic and did you find
Speaker 5:  that your choices were different or the same as the rest of the game Dove
Speaker 5:  community? Were there still, you know, masked up outdoor game
Speaker 5:  jams going on? Like what did you find happened in the community
Speaker 5:  at large and then what was your individual response to the pandemic?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so I think mine might be a little bit different because I feel like
Speaker 6:  my first two games were so small and I did not go to any shows.
Speaker 6:  So birth is the first game that I'm showing and taking out
Speaker 6:  into the world. And so to me it felt like as the
Speaker 6:  pandemic was, as restrictions were being lifted, it was like right when
Speaker 6:  I was like ready to show birth. And so Summer Games Fest, that was like a
Speaker 6:  lot of the, a lot of people's first events back after the Pandemic and
Speaker 6:  that was my first time ever showing a game ever. And it just so
Speaker 6:  happened to be birth and luckily it was like really good timing. And so for
Speaker 6:  me it almost felt like the pandemic kind of, maybe I would've shown my
Speaker 6:  second game somewhere, but I'm kind of glad that I didn't because I'm like
Speaker 6:  very happy that Birth was my first one that is kind of getting any amount
Speaker 6:  of recognition just because of, I think as creators we are most proud of
Speaker 6:  our latest work. And you can look at something you made a year ago
Speaker 6:  and think, oh no, that's terrible. I would've done so many things differently
Speaker 6:  if I was making it now. So for me there wasn't a huge difference. I
Speaker 6:  did love coming into showcases that is a,
Speaker 6:  a brand new thing for me. So that was like very, very fun and I'm glad that
Speaker 6:  it lined up with everyone's excitement to kind of get back into things.
Speaker 6:  So I do think we are moving more towards having more online
Speaker 6:  stuff. I hope that's something that happens throughout, you know, even, even
Speaker 6:  as restrictions get lifted. I do hope that that stays, because I think that's
Speaker 6:  a very accessible way for humans to be involved in things when they can't
Speaker 6:  afford to go to shows because they're expensive and or
Speaker 5:  Physically can't.
Speaker 6:  Yes, right.
Speaker 5:  The indie game space, it has never been harder to
Speaker 5:  discover certain indie games like Discoverability
Speaker 5:  because of the, the proliferation, just the absolute
Speaker 5:  mountain of games that are available
Speaker 5:  on many different platforms and storefronts.
Speaker 5:  It makes it hard for any indie game developer, whether you're
Speaker 5:  a solo game developer or studio to be discovered.
Speaker 5:  Hopefully products like the Steam Deck seem to be helping.
Speaker 5:  I am really curious about how you have seen
Speaker 5:  discoverability within the space change since you started Game Dev.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so I think that when I started, I also didn't realize how
Speaker 6:  small the industry felt. And so it feels really big
Speaker 6:  from the outside, but there's, it seems like there's so many tie-ins
Speaker 6:  between most of the, the bigger games for sure. I think your
Speaker 6:  point about the Steam deck helping discoverability is really important
Speaker 6:  because porting is hard and so you don't get
Speaker 6:  to see a lot of those niche indie games on consoles that maybe do have
Speaker 6:  a little bit more curation. And so I'm glad that people are able to
Speaker 6:  play weird, unfinished things on Steam on their couch now that
Speaker 6:  is like, I think the barrier to, at least for me to playing a lot
Speaker 6:  more steam games is that I don't wanna sit at my desk after I've been sitting
Speaker 6:  at my desk for so long. And so having a steam deck has helped me play
Speaker 6:  a lot more just like smaller, smaller games. I do think you're
Speaker 6:  right though that, especially with Steam, and I know this has been discussed
Speaker 6:  a lot, but there's so many games that come out on Steam
Speaker 6:  and I know that I have missed so many games that I would
Speaker 6:  love to play. I know I'm missing out and I know it's, I think about when
Speaker 6:  I started, I didn't know how to tell people about my thing and I would
Speaker 6:  just put it on steam and not, I didn't have a Twitter, I wouldn't tweet about
Speaker 6:  it. I would just put it on steam and hope that people found it. And that's
Speaker 6:  just, it just doesn't work like that. And I didn't know at the time, of course
Speaker 6:  I was ignorant. And so I do think there's a lot more, I'm seeing a lot more
Speaker 6:  smaller showcases pop up, which is nice. I think Day of the Devs is a great
Speaker 6:  one. And that's not a small showcase by any means of course, but I'm seeing
Speaker 6:  a lot more indie is the, I guess the word you would use for it. It's
Speaker 6:  almost like indie showcases independently run showcases.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So I think just hopefully they're, you're finding things from your
Speaker 6:  community, but you definitely can't just, there's just so much chance involved
Speaker 6:  with putting something on steam and hoping that someone finds it. So
Speaker 6:  I think it's really just about like following curators that you like that
Speaker 6:  hopefully will hype up other indies. But it really takes people
Speaker 6:  caring about indies in the indie space to like make sure that that as many
Speaker 6:  of them get the attention that they deserve, but there's no way that they
Speaker 6:  can, you know, there's so many people creating things and as indie, indie
Speaker 6:  development gets more accessible, which is amazing and we're getting way
Speaker 6:  more diverse stories than we've we've ever had, there's not enough people
Speaker 6:  that can afford to talk about them and write about them.
Speaker 5:  All right, let's take one more break then I'll be back with Alex Kranz and
Speaker 5:  more of my interview with Madison.
Speaker 1:  This podcast is sponsored by Toyota Crown. The all new Toyota
Speaker 1:  crown is breaking new ground when it comes to the premium sedan with an
Speaker 1:  available hybrid max powertrain. The Toyota Crown is the perfect combination
Speaker 1:  of power, style, and elegance, making it the car to glide in
Speaker 1:  from a driver focused interior that says you're always comfortable in the
Speaker 1:  spotlight to the stylish exterior that says I have arrived.
Speaker 1:  Toyota says, wherever you go in the all new Toyota crown, you make a
Speaker 1:  statement, the car that says so much. Visit
Speaker 1:  toyota.com/crown to learn more. Toyota,
Speaker 1:  let's go places.
Speaker 5:  Okay, we're back. Alex is here too. Hi Alex.
Speaker 4:  Okay, Ashley, so typically on, on this last act
Speaker 4:  of the Solo Acts podcast, we get a little nerdy, we get pretty
Speaker 4:  in depth. Where are you taking us in this last act?
Speaker 5:  The only place we can go, which is the future, I love it. The future
Speaker 5:  specifically of the solo game dev space. I think 15
Speaker 5:  years ago you could make a moderately successful breakout hit as a
Speaker 5:  solo or a really small game dev, right? And
Speaker 5:  now, you know, if you do that, the opportunity to
Speaker 5:  parlay it into a mid to senior level role at a
Speaker 5:  mid-size studio is not as prevalent as it used to be because
Speaker 5:  all of these mid-size studios have been snapped up by first party
Speaker 5:  developers. We've seen Microsoft, Sony, and Nintendo, I mean, they're all
Speaker 5:  just, they're just buying up studios, they're hoovering them like
Speaker 5:  Kirby. And I wanted to know
Speaker 5:  what Madison's thoughts were on the current and future landscape
Speaker 5:  of small and indie game development, because it's a weird place to be
Speaker 5:  right now. And I was dying to get that first person perspective
Speaker 5:  from her.
Speaker 6:  So I've seen the, I'm not sure exactly who had posted
Speaker 6:  this, maybe Romi Ismail about the amount of money that it
Speaker 6:  takes to acquire a mid-size studio or a larger studio and how
Speaker 6:  that could fund so many indies. You know, so many indies just need 60
Speaker 6:  or $70,000 to make their game. And you know, there's,
Speaker 6:  there's billions going around and I think that speaks to how much money there
Speaker 6:  is just in gaming in general, in terms of where
Speaker 6:  it's going. What I would love to see is more people and
Speaker 6:  you know, hopefully this is just the world in general, that more tasks, more
Speaker 6:  general tasks are automated, therefore more humans have more time
Speaker 6:  for enjoyment. You know, hopefully the, the general populations
Speaker 6:  amount of free time goes up and with that comes more time to enjoy games
Speaker 6:  and also more time to make games. And so hopefully as our world becomes more
Speaker 6:  automated, we have more time and more games that are getting made.
Speaker 6:  But I don't have a good prediction on what's gonna happen to indies.
Speaker 6:  I hope that, I hope that self-publishing is stays as accessible
Speaker 6:  as it is and that there's enough people that care about indie games.
Speaker 6:  I've been shocked at how many people just care about
Speaker 6:  indies since becoming one. IT people really care and people
Speaker 6:  want indies to exist. I want indies to exist and so hopefully
Speaker 6:  there's enough people. You know what I, I like to think about indies doing
Speaker 6:  well. So solo developers doing well and feeding back into another solo developer
Speaker 6:  doing well. So hopefully there's like enough indie devs wanting other indies
Speaker 6:  to survive that we all find funding somehow, but that is
Speaker 6:  hard to, hard to imagine happening. But that's what I hope, that's my hopeful
Speaker 6:  prediction.
Speaker 5:  I wanna hook back to something you mentioned, which is automation. And
Speaker 5:  we've seen so much in the news about chat, G B T and OpenAI
Speaker 5:  and all of these other artificial intelligence apps and
Speaker 5:  you know, platforms. How do you think
Speaker 5:  automation might help you as a solo game developer
Speaker 5:  specifically?
Speaker 6:  Hmm. If it could automate any amount of the
Speaker 6:  admin task that I have to do, the biz dev stuff brings me no
Speaker 6:  joy. Other than that, I do think I value the human
Speaker 6:  aspect of work and I know that is a big argument
Speaker 6:  for or against AI art and I value that in
Speaker 6:  my work just because I love, for the most part, everything I get to do,
Speaker 6:  everything that goes into making a game. I love that part. Maybe localization,
Speaker 6:  maybe if it could, if it could localize into every single language for me,
Speaker 6:  that would be amazing.
Speaker 5:  That's a good one. Yeah. I hadn't thought of localization, but that
Speaker 5:  does seem seem at least a good starting point, right? Yeah. And then you,
Speaker 5:  you can spend maybe a little less having a translator
Speaker 5:  refine a translation as opposed to Right. Doing it from
Speaker 5:  scratch, right?
Speaker 6:  Absolutely.
Speaker 5:  You mentioned your sort of, again, not to be macab,
Speaker 5:  but we are talking about birth here. You did mention you're like, at the
Speaker 5:  end of my life, these are the things that I, I will feel good about. Yes.
Speaker 5:  How do you measure success when you launch an indie game? Because obviously
Speaker 5:  it is a very different metric. So when you launch birth
Speaker 5:  birthed out, how do you measure the success of this game?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think if we were in it for money, we would be in
Speaker 6:  a, there are way more efficient ways to make money for sure.
Speaker 5:  You'd be programming for a hedge fund or something?
Speaker 6:  Yes, absolutely right. I would be having a much more boring life for sure.
Speaker 6:  Obviously numbers matter, because numbers indicate whether you
Speaker 6:  can make the next game or not, or what you need to be asking for from funding
Speaker 6:  or publisher next time. So numbers do matter a little bit. Those numbers
Speaker 6:  are important. The same way wishlist numbers are important before you launch,
Speaker 6:  even if there's no guarantee. But for me, I think what
Speaker 6:  has brought me joy and what makes me feel like I did
Speaker 6:  the job that I set out to do is, is watching people play it
Speaker 6:  specifically. I love watching streams of it and seeing
Speaker 6:  small interactions because it's taken so many thousands of
Speaker 6:  hours to make birth. And so if someone has a really good time
Speaker 6:  for two hours of their life, I have to make up those thousands of hours that
Speaker 6:  I've spent. So I need so many people to play it and know that you're
Speaker 6:  improving someone's life, at least a tiny, tiny bit for it to be worth it.
Speaker 6:  And so positive reviews help, but I really think it's seeing someone
Speaker 6:  play, play through it and enjoy it and other people can
Speaker 6:  like vocalize what it makes them feel. And you in
Speaker 6:  return are learning more about yourself or what you've created through that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so I think it's how much joy it brings other people. That sounds really
Speaker 6:  cliche and naive almost, but as long as the numbers
Speaker 6:  are good and as long as it's not a flop,
Speaker 6:  yeah, it is important how much joy it brings people.
Speaker 5:  My last question is, what is your best advice
Speaker 5:  for anybody who feels like they have a great game in them? Like
Speaker 5:  what is, what is your best advice there?
Speaker 6:  Make it, start making stuff. It will be so bad at
Speaker 6:  first. Everything that I made at the beginning was so bad and still things
Speaker 6:  that I make sometimes I'm like, oh my God, that's atrocious that I made that
Speaker 6:  and I feel like I'm, I'm getting better every day at things. And so you just
Speaker 6:  have to start. The scariest part is having total creative freedom and having
Speaker 6:  no restraints whatsoever and having a blank canvas that is really scary.
Speaker 6:  What is not so scary is having a little bit of something on a canvas that
Speaker 6:  you're editing a little bit. So yeah, start now. You'll wish that, I wish
Speaker 6:  that I started way earlier. I wish I had found Game dev when I was like four
Speaker 6:  or something. I don't know.
Speaker 5:  My son's about to turn four, so I'm gonna get him started.
Speaker 6:  Oh my gosh, you should,
Speaker 5:  This year started immediately
Speaker 6:  A new indie game Dev
Speaker 5:  A new one right now. Yes.
Speaker 4:  Okay. That is it for the Verge Cast. Thank you so much, Ashley.
Speaker 5:  Ugh, it's my pleasure.
Speaker 4:  I've been having so much fun on this series with you and we've got even more
Speaker 4:  episodes of the Solo Act series coming. This was episode three, we have two
Speaker 4:  more, so you gotta tune in next Monday to hear even more about it.
Speaker 4:  Ashley, what's going on next week though?
Speaker 5:  I have heard that mechanical keyboards are very
Speaker 5:  popular.
Speaker 4:  Oh my God, are they? I am
Speaker 5:  Shocked. I received a telegram and I've heard
Speaker 5:  that the technology community loves mechanical keyboards, so I decided
Speaker 5:  to talk to Tiny Makes Things Tiny is
Speaker 5:  a mechanical keyboard custom key cap
Speaker 5:  creator. Yes. Yeah, she makes custom key caps,
Speaker 4:  Like the cute little ones that always like look like food or like little
Speaker 4:  characters and
Speaker 5:  Stuff. Yes. And she also even makes accessories for them, so talk to her.
Speaker 5:  And she is a very interesting person with a
Speaker 5:  lot of really cool things to talk about in the, in the mechanical keyboard
Speaker 5:  space. I think if you are a longtime enthusiast of mechanical
Speaker 5:  keyboards, you will enjoy it. But also if you're new to mechanical keyboards
Speaker 5:  or just thinking about it, you may find her her talk. Interesting. All
Speaker 4:  Right, well Vercast listeners, please stay tuned. That's gonna be next Monday,
Speaker 4:  but this is all, all we've got for the show today. The show is produced by
Speaker 4:  Andrew Marino and Liam James Brooke Mentors is our editorial director of
Speaker 4:  Audio. The Vergecast is a Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast
Speaker 4:  network. If you've got thoughts or feelings or feedback, you can always email
Speaker 4:  us@vergecasttheverge.com or you can call the hotline at
Speaker 4:  eight sixty six eleven. We're gonna be back on Wednesday for another
Speaker 4:  episode, and then Eli and I are gonna be back on Friday. It's gonna be a
Speaker 4:  lot of fun. Until then, stay classy.
Speaker 3:  Thanks
Speaker 1:  To Toyota Crown for supporting this episode. The all new Toyota Crown lets
Speaker 1:  you separate from the crowd as soon as you step inside the car. It's equipped
Speaker 1:  with a cutting edge design with an available hybrid max powertrain that generates
Speaker 1:  an exceptional 340 combined net horsepower. The dynamic
Speaker 1:  placement of the electric motor between the engine and the transmission allows
Speaker 1:  for power to be transferred without any lack. The result, zero
Speaker 1:  to 60 seconds in 5.7 seconds. Toyota says,
Speaker 1:  wherever you go, in the all new Toyota crown, you make a statement, the car
Speaker 1:  that says so much. Visit toyota.com/crown to learn more.
Speaker 1:  Toyota, let's go places.