# Transcript
ID: 27937e80-a90d-11ed-bbdc-43f038e19f6d
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: We tried Bing powered by ChatGPT AI and things got dark
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-3332087417946112367/-4968080198430933647/s93290-US-5863s-1676010941.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, Richard Lawler, and James Vincent discuss Microsoft's upgraded Bing search engine with ChatGPT AI. Can Microsoft beat Google at search? Is it actually an upgrade? Also: Disney layoffs, Elon's Twitter reach is dropping, and more of this week's tech news.
Speaker 2:  Today on the Vergecast, we got Eli to install Microsoft's Edge browser
Speaker 2:  just so we could play with the new Bing powered by chat, G P T, ai,
Speaker 2:  all that and so much more coming up right after this.
Speaker 3:  Support for today's show comes from Deloitte. In the business world, it can
Speaker 3:  be a especially crucial to innovate. You can either build your own future
Speaker 3:  or bet on someone else's. No one knows what tomorrow will bring, but you
Speaker 3:  push forward and create enterprise anyway. That's why Deloitte's mission
Speaker 3:  is to help engineer advantage for their clients by harnessing the latest
Speaker 3:  innovations in technology while exploring the ideas and opportunities that
Speaker 3:  can look beyond today. Transform what's next into what's now.
Speaker 3:  See how you can engineer advantage with Deloitte at
Speaker 3:  deloitte.com/us/engineering advantage.
Speaker 4:  Hello, welcome to VER has the flagship podcast of generative
Speaker 4:  AI solutions for your small business. Please use this promo code,
Speaker 4:  it's promo code and sign up for an informative seminar today about how AI
Speaker 4:  can replace most of your workforce, but not you because you're
Speaker 4:  important. Hi, I'm Neil. I'm your friend. I don't mean to start on a down
Speaker 4:  note, I'm just saying I've already gotten that email. Basically
Speaker 4:  we have big show. It's the Microsoft versus Google
Speaker 4:  War is underway. I was at Microsoft
Speaker 4:  this week to see the launch of the new Bing powered by not chat G
Speaker 4:  P T. We'll get into it, but I have an all star lineup here to start with.
Speaker 4:  Alex Kranz is here.
Speaker 3:  Hello. I'm your friend who doesn't know what's going on right now,
Speaker 3:  but is very excited to learn more.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, you were just on vacation, you just came back and like the whole world
Speaker 4:  has changed. You're like, there's robot now. I think
Speaker 3:  It's changed. Yeah, that's great. Whole new world.
Speaker 4:  Richard Lawler is here.
Speaker 5:  Hello. I do not believe in the future of AI until it gets into
Speaker 5:  Bitcoin.
Speaker 4:  No, here's what I'm saying, Richard, I, I said this to Richard and Slack
Speaker 4:  today. Richard's reflexive skepticism about Bitcoin is bleeding
Speaker 4:  into the AI conversation. Look,
Speaker 5:  I was right once and it's going to just carry me through like the next five
Speaker 5:  years.
Speaker 4:  I was like, no, this is stupid too. So it's good. Well, we need that. The
Speaker 4:  industry needs that. James Vincent Verge senior reporter focused on AI here.
Speaker 4:  Hey James.
Speaker 6:  Hello. Hello. I'm glad to see that I was
Speaker 6:  Bing's favorite reporter in one of the screen screenshots you shared.
Speaker 6:  I feel like I've been sucking up to Bing by accident, by writing about ai.
Speaker 6:  I didn't realize.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I asked Bing who was the best reporter of The Verge and I just named
Speaker 4:  some people. It was like Dan, Casey, Addie and James.
Speaker 4:  It did not realize Casey doesn't work here anymore. And I said,
Speaker 4:  no, no, who's your favorite? And it's like, well, I can't choose. But James
Speaker 4:  reports an ai and that's, and then if you look at
Speaker 4:  screenshots of Bing, and I want people to pay attention to this whenever
Speaker 4:  it knows or susses out that the answer might be controversial.
Speaker 4:  It uses a smiley, but it's a blushing smiley. So it looks
Speaker 4:  like it's doing this every time. And so it's
Speaker 4:  like either flirting with you or just like doing this super innocent face.
Speaker 4:  Like I asked it why Beyonce did not win Best album. And let me tell you,
Speaker 4:  this robot knew that it was in very dicey territory answering
Speaker 4:  this question. It was like, I don't know, here's 95
Speaker 4:  citations to other sources. People have a lot of different
Speaker 4:  opinions. The Grammys are a subjective award. No music is best. I gotta get
Speaker 4:  outta here. Smiley face.
Speaker 4:  Is
Speaker 6:  That better or worse than clippy? You know, do we do we need is
Speaker 6:  is the winner of the AI war gonna be who comes up with the most Punchable
Speaker 6:  AI and lets you punch it?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, well, so we'll get into it. We'll get into it. I have access to it.
Speaker 4:  We can use it. We ask the audience for some prompts. We'll see how those
Speaker 4:  go. But let's start with what Microsoft actually announced. It's a new
Speaker 4:  version of Bing. Microsoft has had this long relationship with Open
Speaker 4:  ai. The company makes chat. G P T Open ai ceo
Speaker 4:  Sam Altman was on the stage at this event. There's actually quite a lot,
Speaker 4:  even before we start with this, Microsoft announced this event without telling
Speaker 4:  anyone. So they were like, come to Redmond. This is our only
Speaker 4:  in-person event. It's a big deal. And we're like, is there a live stream?
Speaker 4:  And they're like, no, but you're gonna want to be there sore. Like okay,
Speaker 4:  we're gonna go. And we all kind of sussed out what it was gonna be. And I
Speaker 4:  was like, man, if they show me a new version of Bing and I call them be mad.
Speaker 4:  And they're like, no, no, you're gonna love it. So the whole press is there.
Speaker 4:  Google freaks out. It gets word of this, it announces its
Speaker 4:  own chat bot integration called Bard and Google
Speaker 4:  with just a blog post. But no details, no access.
Speaker 4:  They
Speaker 3:  Just are like, we've got Bard. Bard
Speaker 4:  Is coming. Yeah, they obviously made up that name just like the day before.
Speaker 4:  They
Speaker 6:  Were like, I don't, an hour an hour's notice as well. I mean
Speaker 6:  maybe some outlets got more than that. But in inside baseball here we got
Speaker 6:  an hour's notice that this is coming, which I think says about their panic.
Speaker 6:  A
Speaker 4:  Rush. Yeah. And then they had another event in Paris, which was
Speaker 4:  by all accounts, just like a pure disaster. And the stock fell like, we don't
Speaker 4:  cover stock prices normally, but I was like, Google's lost a hundred billion
Speaker 4:  off its valuation because of what happened with Microsoft
Speaker 4:  in the middle and how they reacted to it. So this is just the context. So
Speaker 4:  we go there, we don't know what we're gonna see. We're Microsoft's first
Speaker 4:  event, we're in their executive briefing center, they have a
Speaker 4:  little sage set up, lots of chairs, lots of reporters there. Obviously it
Speaker 4:  was fun to see everyone and they just got into it, right? This is the
Speaker 4:  most focused tech event I have seen in years. It
Speaker 4:  was not, we're putting AI in everything. It was not, here's you can tell
Speaker 4:  Excel to make you a pivot table, which is obviously the end goal for all
Speaker 4:  ai. It was, here's a new version of Bing, it's powered
Speaker 4:  by chat G P T technology. Here's Sam Altman from OpenAI to talk about it.
Speaker 4:  Here's our responsible AI researchers to tell you like how we're
Speaker 4:  gonna keep it safe and trustworthy and what the guiderails are. Here's a
Speaker 4:  new version of Edge that has a chatbot
Speaker 4:  sidebar. They can read the webpage you're on and like summarize it for you
Speaker 4:  and like help you browse the web, which is really interesting. And we're
Speaker 4:  out and here's Sasha Andela to say we're taking a fight to Google. And then
Speaker 4:  that was it. And then we like went downstairs and we waited it a
Speaker 4:  while, like an oddly long time. And then they gave us all access to it.
Speaker 4:  All the people who were there got access with their Microsoft accounts. So
Speaker 4:  it's not, I think open to everyone yet, but we have access to it
Speaker 4:  and it will slowly come out to everyone in the next, in the weeks
Speaker 4:  to come I think is what they're saying. Google is like effectively nowhere.
Speaker 3:  How fast is that rollout gonna be
Speaker 4:  That we don't know. Okay. Oh my God, what is going on with Bing?
Speaker 4:  I'm sorry. Like in the background, like Bing is just like losing its mind
Speaker 4:  with me. The rollout is a is a few weeks. They said they are very aware that
Speaker 4:  they have this lead and they want to take it, right?
Speaker 4:  They, like Nadela said to me, we know Google's 800 pound
Speaker 4:  gorilla, but they have to come to the dance. And I want people to know that
Speaker 4:  we made them dance, which is a very aggressive thing. Like I've talked to
Speaker 4:  a lot of big tech CEOs, they usually do not refer
Speaker 4:  to their competitors directly in this way, right?
Speaker 4:  But they think they have an opportunity to change how search works. Nadella
Speaker 4:  keeps saying search is the biggest software category on earth and they,
Speaker 4:  you know, their opportunity is to just peel off a couple points of market
Speaker 4:  share, which is worth billions upon billions of dollars. And
Speaker 4:  they have this new paradigm of chat and chat, G P T, which chat g p t
Speaker 4:  is like the fastest growing software product in in history, right? Like that
Speaker 4:  they're very proud of this. They have the,
Speaker 3:  It's like faster than TikTok.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean it's in many ways that's like, it's a weird thing to say, right?
Speaker 4:  Like yeah, yeah. You just have to sign up for it and type at it. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I just keep seeing that comparison and I'm like, that sounds big.
Speaker 3:  What?
Speaker 6:  But, but, but there's been like, you know, there was a Reuters news
Speaker 6:  post which cited some SimilarWeb analytics, which claimed
Speaker 6:  a hundred million monthly adverse users. And then New York Times had a report
Speaker 6:  saying 30 million. Like they, and they, those numbers came out in the same
Speaker 6:  week. I I, I dunno what's going on with the use of statistics. It's definitely
Speaker 6:  been growing fast, but I'm very suspicious that like, how many people are
Speaker 6:  logging in day after day? Yeah. You know, even I'm not logging in every
Speaker 6:  day to chat G P T and I report on this stuff. I log in when there's a reason
Speaker 6:  to.
Speaker 3:  I know people who are like, I think it's really interesting, everybody
Speaker 3:  on this podcast right now, we're all writers and editors. We, we, we write
Speaker 3:  all the time. I have a lot of friends who are not writers, they're not editors
Speaker 3:  and they're using it daily to write all of their emails. One friend has like
Speaker 3:  asked it to recommend books and now he only reads books recommended by chat
Speaker 3:  gpt. That's not, he's all it. I'm sorry.
Speaker 4:  He's all that that friend is gonna,
Speaker 3:  That terrifies
Speaker 4:  Me. Yeah. That friend is gonna end up being a Azel culture bro. In like one
Speaker 4:  second.
Speaker 3:  He worked at, he was an NFTs before this, so I'm not see,
Speaker 4:  See what I'm surprised I clock that so fast.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. GT ization pipeline.
Speaker 5:  There is a huge overlap between very excited about
Speaker 5:  AI and used to be very excited about crypto. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's just a pipeline pipeline that makes you read Rich Dad Port a, like that's
Speaker 4:  the whole pipeline. Like it's like read these four hustle culture books.
Speaker 4:  You're gonna end up doing real estate and investing very quickly. Well, so
Speaker 4:  there's this underlying thing like chat p d is like hard to use. It has gone
Speaker 4:  down, it has capacity limits, all this stuff. Microsoft is like whatever.
Speaker 4:  We're just, we have this built multi-year multi-billion dollar investment
Speaker 4:  in the company. That part is a little unclear, like how much of open AI's
Speaker 4:  roadmap is Microsoft actually in, in charge of how much of
Speaker 4:  the actual technology belongs to Microsoft versus open ai. We were talking
Speaker 4:  to some product folks, engineering folks there. They're like, look, we just
Speaker 4:  run it on Azure and it's just, it's it's ours. Like we give them
Speaker 4:  notes, you know, like, so I think there's some
Speaker 4:  underlying complexity to that deal that we don't quite understand.
Speaker 4:  But what is real, what is tangible is that chat G p
Speaker 4:  t is not a product, right? It is a technology demo that has
Speaker 4:  spread like wildfire that is very impressive. It has some very obvious limitations.
Speaker 4:  Bing is a product, right? It is a complete consumer
Speaker 4:  product that you can just use for free that Microsoft is gluing
Speaker 4:  an advertising model onto. And that Microsoft thinks
Speaker 4:  is good enough to capture market share from Google,
Speaker 4:  which is having, its its own set of problems. That's pretty interesting,
Speaker 4:  right? Like we have not seen productized AI like this before. Have
Speaker 4:  we James?
Speaker 6:  Not on this scale. No. No way there. Yeah. I think
Speaker 6:  this is what is so interesting about this. And also not just about Bing,
Speaker 6:  but about the Edge integrations, about how this is such like a play
Speaker 6:  to, for, for, for people to get stuck in Windows ecosystem in
Speaker 6:  a way that like yeah, I, I mean like if, if the edge stuff goes well, it's
Speaker 6:  not just Bing versus Google as it were, it's sort of
Speaker 6:  chrome versus edge again. Because if Microsoft can build this directly into
Speaker 6:  the browser and they can say you can only get this in edge, you can't get
Speaker 6:  your summarized documents in in Chrome or whatever else you might be using.
Speaker 6:  And that's a huge advantage as well. So yeah. Nothing on this scale that
Speaker 6:  we've seen before.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And it works like the, the thing I will tell you is that in
Speaker 4:  most cases it does what you think it's going to do,
Speaker 4:  which is for any, for any product, like
Speaker 4:  the first metric of success. Like I've picked up smartphones and like
Speaker 4:  this doesn't do what I expected it to do. Right? Like any,
Speaker 4:  I've, I've installed streaming players. Have you ever tried to use an Nvidia
Speaker 4:  shield?
Speaker 4:  No, I haven't. It's a horrible troll. No
Speaker 6:  One has. I've never been in Dan's bad books. So you've never given me that
Speaker 6:  review.
Speaker 4:  No, but like, you know, the measure of success for any consumer product is
Speaker 4:  like on balance. When someone is like, I want it to do this thing, does it
Speaker 4:  just like do it without jumping through a lot of hoops or a lot of complication
Speaker 4:  And Bing is like, just does. It just doesn't. The one thing I could not get
Speaker 4:  it to do, this is a true story. I asked that yesterday to tell me a story
Speaker 4:  about a princess fighting a dragon. It would not allow the
Speaker 4:  princess to kill the dragon. Wow. Sexism
Speaker 4:  literally at, at the end of the story, it was like the princess escaped and
Speaker 4:  thought I will bring the dragon a gift. And I was like, no, no, make her
Speaker 4:  kill the dragon. And I was like, no. And I was like, no, do the story again
Speaker 4:  with more blood. And then it was straight up was like, I will not tell you
Speaker 4:  a story with blood in it. And somehow this spiraled all the way
Speaker 4:  into will you tell me a story about the devil, which it does not wanna do.
Speaker 4:  It has some very deep 1950s Christian mom morals
Speaker 4:  baked into it. I dunno what else to say. Yeah. Little
Speaker 4:  pure. Yeah. It's also very moody. You asked to tell stories, the story, all
Speaker 4:  the stories are very existential Parker, or are the
Speaker 4:  person who runs our, our merch store asked it to tell a story about scissor
Speaker 4:  vodka.
Speaker 6:  Oh, I read
Speaker 4:  That they told a story about KC Newton writing some copy about
Speaker 4:  scissor vodka and then publishing it and then immediately regretting it.
Speaker 4:  And the last line was he realized he had already cut through the night. And
Speaker 4:  I was like, this is what happens when you train a generative AI on years
Speaker 4:  and years of live journal. Like there's a angsty teen
Speaker 4:  who soul beats in the heart of this AI and you can just get it out of it.
Speaker 6:  That what that example though with the scissor vodka,
Speaker 6:  I I i I want to talk about the problems with these systems cuz there are
Speaker 6:  loads of problems. But that example, I was super impressed because it
Speaker 6:  knew exactly, this is a fictional in joke that's been on the
Speaker 6:  Vergecast as a running joke. How like, I was actually confused where it got
Speaker 6:  that information from because have we referenced it enough
Speaker 6:  in articles that it would've picked that up? I guess so, but
Speaker 4:  So, you know, I think Parker had the prompt was like, tell a story about
Speaker 4:  this joke from the ver so like there was a little bit of oh okay, cueing
Speaker 4:  in the prompt, but then it knew, right? And there's obviously transcripts
Speaker 4:  of our show out in the world or auto-generated trans, like there's stuff,
Speaker 4:  and I think that the big difference between chat g, PT and
Speaker 4:  the new model in Bing, and we should talk about the, the new model that they're
Speaker 4:  using here more specifically. But the big difference is that chat g p
Speaker 4:  t kind of ends in 2021. So anything that's published after 2021,
Speaker 4:  it, it was just like, won't talk about, it'll say I don't have current events.
Speaker 4:  Bing has the web, it's likes
Speaker 3:  Actively learning, right?
Speaker 4:  It's actively growing. And, and James, I'm curious for your view
Speaker 4:  on this, if you can explain it better. I thought Microsoft did a bad job
Speaker 4:  explaining what's going on. So when you use it, you can see that what
Speaker 4:  it is doing is stacking web searches. So you're like,
Speaker 4:  tell me about scissor vodka at the Verge or whatever. And it will
Speaker 4:  first search for that and then it will search for the Verge and then it,
Speaker 4:  and it will show you that it is running these searches and then it will add
Speaker 4:  up all the web pages that it will go out and read the web. A better example
Speaker 4:  is tell me about the war in Ukraine, right? Or tell me about the state of
Speaker 4:  the Union address. It will go search the web for those topics and then in
Speaker 4:  real time deliver you a summary of the news articles that it
Speaker 4:  finds which chat g p t cannot do. So it is using the
Speaker 4:  web, it has this thing, it's called search orchestration, where
Speaker 4:  it first parses your query into a number of searches,
Speaker 4:  runs all those searches, it shows you what it's, what queries it's running.
Speaker 4:  Then it reads all those pages and then it tells you an answer. How long does
Speaker 4:  it, which is seems seems much more advanced than what Chad G p t is doing.
Speaker 4:  But also not, you know, it's like, yes, that's what you would do.
Speaker 3:  Like is it instantaneous? Does it take a while?
Speaker 6:  It takes a second, doesn't
Speaker 4:  It? It takes a second. And what's what's really interesting is they're still
Speaker 4:  running trust in safety checks on it. So yesterday when I asked, it's
Speaker 4:  telling me his story about a princess killing the dragon, but with blood
Speaker 4:  this time it wrote a whole story and then it got to the end of
Speaker 4:  the story, realized that it had broken its own rules and deleted the
Speaker 4:  answer. Huh? And said, I can't answer that
Speaker 6:  Question. So censorship in real time. Wow.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it was, it was cra it was like, it's typing and it it, the really interesting
Speaker 4:  thing is when it gets to the end of the answer, it doesn't wanna give, it
Speaker 4:  slows way down and it like finishes a sentence
Speaker 3:  Just stutters to stop.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Oh that's amazing. They that you, you're right.
Speaker 6:  They didn't do a good job of explaining it. I mean I, I think one thing to
Speaker 6:  say is when we're talking about this is new, pointed out Nilo, it's
Speaker 6:  not chat g p t and it's not what chat g p t is based on, which is G P T
Speaker 6:  3.5, it's something called Model Prometheus. The
Speaker 6:  Prometheus model, which seems like it's Microsoft's own branding. I
Speaker 6:  wasn't quite sure. It doesn't seem like open AI are gonna be talking about
Speaker 6:  that. It seems like that's the custom model. This the pipeline you're talking
Speaker 6:  about in terms of updating for real time news.
Speaker 6:  I've seen, again, wasn't explained completely exhaustively, it
Speaker 6:  does seem like it's just a string of functions built together that as you
Speaker 6:  say, so it takes your question, it knows that you're talking about news from
Speaker 6:  the context, it pumps that into its search and then it just does, its summarize
Speaker 6:  job on whatever the search turns up. But I mean that, that makes
Speaker 6:  sense that it's not a huge ask if cuz if the edge, if the features in edge
Speaker 6:  can summarize the documents you're looking at or the webpages you're looking
Speaker 6:  at. It's basically just, let me Google that for you. Oh, sorry, let me bing
Speaker 6:  that for you. Sorry. Force a habit. Force a habit. Let me bing
Speaker 6:  that for you. And then it's just summarizing those. So the
Speaker 6:  difference between that and having a fully trained language model is that
Speaker 6:  retrieval from a fully trained language model, that's gonna be faster and
Speaker 6:  you can optimize it in better ways. You can, you can break down the,
Speaker 6:  the, you know, the connections, the parameters with inside the model and
Speaker 6:  make it quicker. So this is always gonna be slower, but I,
Speaker 6:  yeah, I wonder if they'll start updating the base model, sort of do like
Speaker 6:  a, a weekly update or something. I don't know. Speculation.
Speaker 4:  So interesting thing there. Eif Medi who is in charge of this product had
Speaker 4:  a Q and a after the event, people ask questions, someone asked cost, right?
Speaker 4:  Right. Which is an important question. Every query on average
Speaker 4:  that you make of this model is more expensive to run
Speaker 4:  than the average query for Google, right? Google has spent a decade
Speaker 4:  optimizing the cost of a a web search query. And his answer
Speaker 4:  was, yep, some of them are expensive, but we are parsing the queries
Speaker 4:  and some of them are cheap. Like if you just type high into the box,
Speaker 4:  we're not gonna, we're not spending money on you. Like, right? Like
Speaker 4:  we're, we know some queries we can cut down down some words, we can get to
Speaker 4:  the appropriate keywords. This is what that search orchestrator is doing.
Speaker 4:  It's re parsing what you're putting into it and saying, okay, some of
Speaker 4:  this we can just answer cheaply. Some of this we can deliver from the web.
Speaker 4:  Some of this is if you just say hi, it'll just spit back, hi, I'm
Speaker 4:  bing very cheaply without running into the whole model. Right?
Speaker 4:  So there's a level of complexity. Well this is what I mean by when I say
Speaker 4:  it's a product, right? They've like thought through a product
Speaker 4:  experience in a way that chat GBT itself is a tech. You,
Speaker 4:  you're interacting with the raw technology of it. And then the second part
Speaker 4:  of that product experience is they know they've gotta make some money.
Speaker 4:  And so there's ad you also said there will be advertising at the start. I
Speaker 4:  asked it, you know, we've done a lot of stories about CNET and affiliate
Speaker 4:  links and SEO span and all this stuff. So it's on my mind. So I asked it,
Speaker 4:  you know, what is the best travel credit card, which is like a
Speaker 4:  $900 affiliate link bounty. And this thing was
Speaker 4:  ready, like it spit out the answer, it ranked, it had the list of the credit
Speaker 4:  cards, and then at the bottom of that answer a big ad
Speaker 4:  for a credit card, right? Like in the chat window. Yes. And like that's what
Speaker 4:  you mean by it's a product like not only is it tuned to make some
Speaker 4:  queries cheaper, it's tuned to how do you monetize the user
Speaker 4:  experience when you're done with it. Which I think is just utterly fascinating.
Speaker 6:  So you, there was a clear distinction between answer and
Speaker 6:  advert. Cause I think a lot of people are worried that the way chatbots present
Speaker 6:  information, responses to queries, it's gonna make it much easier to
Speaker 6:  sort of seamlessly, you know,
Speaker 6:  weave in advertising in a way that is less perceptible to the
Speaker 6:  viewer. Yeah. So, but they, they're keeping a clear distinction. Do they
Speaker 6:  say anything that, like we're always gonna keep a clear distinction. We'll
Speaker 6:  never put an ad in the answer or
Speaker 4:  They have no idea. Right? I think they, they have an early
Speaker 4:  lead. They have, I, when I say it's a product and it's,
Speaker 4:  what I mean is they've gone through the steps of like, how do we make this
Speaker 4:  a product and release it to millions of people? Yeah. And how do we make
Speaker 4:  some money on this product? I'm not saying it's a good product. I'm not saying
Speaker 4:  it's a complete product or a refined product. Like Bing
Speaker 4:  itself, if you just go look at it, minus stuff is a
Speaker 4:  wasteland, right? This is an 11 billion a year business that
Speaker 4:  mostly makes its money by being the default search on
Speaker 4:  lots and lots of low end Windows PCs before those people install Chrome.
Speaker 4:  And it's full of spam. It's full of garbage. Like we, we can just admit
Speaker 4:  that like Bing is full of weird content recommendations like Tom Warren is
Speaker 4:  going on and on about how the pre-populated widget bars and
Speaker 4:  windows are full of garbage. Like Microsoft has run a content form
Speaker 4:  inside of Bing for a long time. That's, that's fine.
Speaker 4:  It, so it means that like even this ad that I looked at, it
Speaker 4:  was like not well placed. It was like it had broken the site design. The
Speaker 4:  poor engineers I was standing next to like rolled their eyes. Like the ad
Speaker 4:  team is all over this. But it's, it's a complete thought in like,
Speaker 4:  oh, there was an ads team. They recognize they need to like have a list of
Speaker 4:  high value queries and put some advertising in there, right? Which is far,
Speaker 4:  far ahead of where Google is now. Do they have answers for, there will
Speaker 4:  never be ads in the responses. They do not. They also
Speaker 4:  more importantly have no a answers for where do these responses
Speaker 4:  even come from and can you trust them? So the example they
Speaker 4:  used on stage was what's the best gaming
Speaker 4:  tv? And it oh boy fired off a list. And you know, at the bottom it has all
Speaker 4:  the footnotes and all the stuff and all that stuff is designed to make you
Speaker 4:  trust it. Look at all these footnotes. And I will tell you as a writer,
Speaker 4:  sometimes you get away with a lot of shit by just like adding a lot of footnotes,
Speaker 4:  Right? It's like a, it's like a sign that you should like trust whatever
Speaker 4:  you're reading and you look at the footnotes and it's like the Forbes contributor
Speaker 4:  network, like stupid Forbes. Like there's real Forbes, which is great, like
Speaker 4:  a great journalistic enterprise. And then there's this contributor network
Speaker 4:  which is like full of garbage. Yeah. And like real Forbes
Speaker 4:  is not ranking gaming TVs. The contributor network is ranking gaming
Speaker 4:  TVs. And like why it would bing choose that not even over
Speaker 4:  us, like over like ings or like whatever other sites that do this
Speaker 4:  work and do it really well. I don't know, but like, it just does it
Speaker 4:  and those are the footnotes. So there's a lot, I think there's just a lot
Speaker 4:  of questions like where does information come from? Can you pollute it with
Speaker 4:  your commercial interests? Right? So Sony wants to say the Sony is
Speaker 4:  the best gaming tv, we'll just win the query and bang will just tell you
Speaker 4:  that confidently. Like I, they don't have the answers. And their position
Speaker 4:  is we just have, we have to release it to learn what the answer should be.
Speaker 3:  Are they doing anything to improve Bing itself? Because it seems like
Speaker 3:  the core thing here is like, yeah, this AI model is doing all
Speaker 3:  this work, but it's doing it all off of search results
Speaker 3:  from Bing, which is not good.
Speaker 4:  Well it depends. So if you're like telling me a story about a princess in
Speaker 4:  a dragon, it doesn't go out in Google Princess and drag, it just starts doing
Speaker 4:  it. Right? And that's the underlying model. If you're like, I
Speaker 4:  was like, what's going on at the Twitter hearing it Googles those
Speaker 7:  Raises the,
Speaker 7:  but it's looking,
Speaker 3:  It's using Bing to find it. And so it's like, okay, yeah.
Speaker 3:  So if,
Speaker 4:  If you like, I don't know, like it, it answered the question in real time.
Speaker 4:  It knew what had happened at the hearings, it knew what the Republicans
Speaker 4:  said about the Twitter files. It knew it was the Democratic and it, it answered
Speaker 4:  it, it spit out a paragraph. Yeah. Was that paragraph accurate?
Speaker 4:  Was it based on sources that had done the original reporting or
Speaker 4:  was it based on aggregations of this source? Like, I don't know the answers
Speaker 4:  to those questions and that, I think this is the underlying also, it doesn't
Speaker 4:  link back to those pages.
Speaker 3:  That's just all terrifying.
Speaker 4:  So if it was citing to, I think one of the sites was Business Insider and
Speaker 4:  Business Insider had sent a reporter to the hearing, business Insider collects
Speaker 4:  none of the value. Like that stuff is just being boosted and presented
Speaker 4:  somewhere else, right? And there's not even that exchange of you should click
Speaker 4:  on this link. Like we aggregate a lot, right? But our exchange
Speaker 4:  is like, we validate those things. We send a lot of traffic out of our site.
Speaker 4:  We like our entire front page is an exercise in trying to send out more traffic
Speaker 4:  from our site to other people. Like there is a value exchange.
Speaker 3:  We make sure it's accurate.
Speaker 4:  We, yeah, we, we, we do our best. Where I think like Microsoft and I asked,
Speaker 4:  asked Adele about this and he was like, we wanna make sure we're still sending
Speaker 4:  traffic out to people. And it's like, but you're not like, I don't think
Speaker 4:  that that's going to happen.
Speaker 6:  I just, yeah, I, I saw his answer to that and he was just like, it's the
Speaker 6:  same as it ever was. And I thought, you can't have it both ways. You can't
Speaker 6:  present this as a revolutionary new paradigm and say, but we're gonna keep
Speaker 6:  all the old structures of the old ecosystem the same. It's just not gonna
Speaker 6:  work like that. Google obviously has been doing this for years in terms of
Speaker 6:  one box and snippets and you know, they've always argued, oh we,
Speaker 6:  I I was actually reading back some of their blogs about this and one of the
Speaker 6:  arguments they made was, well, there's a lot of competition to get in that
Speaker 6:  one box and that proves that we're driving traffic. It's like, yeah, cuz
Speaker 6:  you've got rid of the field and you've refused it to, of course
Speaker 6:  there's a lot of competition cause you just killed everyone else.
Speaker 4:  But so this is like utterly fascinating, right? Like I asked at some other
Speaker 4:  query, like, what's better iOS or Android or something, right? And right,
Speaker 4:  again, I I got a lot of like blushy smiley faces, like if they like
Speaker 4:  answer this question, but it's sources were those
Speaker 4:  sites that are created to spam that search result in Google, right?
Speaker 4:  Anybody who's like, I'm sure the, the verso, like if you're, if you're listening
Speaker 4:  to this show, you have certainly search specs online, right? And there's
Speaker 4:  this universe of like auto-generated spec sites
Speaker 4:  that basically just respond to any search query by being like,
Speaker 4:  you want to compare a, a Ford Ranger to a Cannon power shot S 200.
Speaker 4:  We'll do that for you. Like, it'll just like figure it out, like how to make
Speaker 4:  a table out of that shit. And Bing was pulling from those sources
Speaker 4:  and I was asking him like, you don't know that that's right. You don't know
Speaker 4:  that that's real. You're just confidently reddis displaying a table that
Speaker 4:  is un mashed up from these other weird tables and then like
Speaker 4:  saying an answer and they're like, yeah, that's weird. And it's
Speaker 4:  because like, the underlying thing here is still
Speaker 4:  searching the web, that sort of corrupted information architecture
Speaker 4:  of the web that is designed to win Google searches. Like the SEO
Speaker 4:  corruption of the web is like feeding the chat
Speaker 4:  more direct way. Well
Speaker 4:  I dunno that anybody, I dunno that any SEO pirate is out there being like,
Speaker 4:  we gotta focus on Bing,
Speaker 6:  But they, well maybe now,
Speaker 3:  Theoretically they would. Now, I mean like, I think I'm super, super, super,
Speaker 3:  super suspicious of this. But at the same time, remember when
Speaker 3:  people used to game Google in a similar way to like the results,
Speaker 3:  like you'd Google dumbass and the first result would be George W. Bush
Speaker 3:  is the president, he's a dumbass. So like,
Speaker 4:  Is it you're gonna do like bing bombing?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like you can do bing bombing. Oh my God. It's,
Speaker 4:  That's,
Speaker 3:  Look
Speaker 4:  I terrible. I feel like I'm, it's only because I've been copy using it for
Speaker 4:  two days, like intently that I'm like finding all these rough edges and these
Speaker 4:  obvious questions that need to be answered, right? It's, it's rad. Like
Speaker 4:  it is super fun to play with. And this is when Richard was like, screwed.
Speaker 4:  I don't understand it. I was like, no, no. Like people are gonna lose their
Speaker 4:  minds. It's really fun to play with that.
Speaker 5:  That is really my question is you, you, you're telling me that it's really
Speaker 5:  fun to play with and I'm hearing you. I just, I cannot put myself in the
Speaker 5:  headspace. I have no idea what I would want to ask this thing. They're like,
Speaker 5:  we have this machine. You can answer any question you want to a ask it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That's just like a's guy to the Galaxy problem though, right? Like you're
Speaker 4:  like, I dunno, like paralyzed by infinite choice, like yeah.
Speaker 4:  A good product problem to have. But like
Speaker 5:  I haven't, I, I don't know, maybe so maybe I could ask it, Hey, what can
Speaker 5:  I watch on Netflix night? It'll give me the perfect answer, but I don't,
Speaker 5:  I don't know if I would want, like would I want that? Do I want the perfect
Speaker 5:  answer is that, is that even what I'm going for? Or how good would it have
Speaker 5:  to be for me to say yes, you know what, I'm just gonna turn over a decision
Speaker 5:  making of this because you know what I, I can't decide what to watch.
Speaker 4:  But I think you're thinking about it as a decision making is a search engine
Speaker 4:  and Microsoft is not thinking about it that way. Right?
Speaker 3:  What are they thinking about it? As
Speaker 4:  Tom Warren? He already, he did a little hands on and his first one was like,
Speaker 4:  write me a resignation letter that says I've been replaced by AI and it just
Speaker 4:  did it. And it was like hilarious. Right? And Alex, this is a thing that
Speaker 4:  you were talking about, which is there's a lot of writing to be done for
Speaker 4:  a lot of people that they're uncomfortable doing. Right? Right. And like,
Speaker 4:  I, people are just gonna use it for that cuz it's just gonna do it and it's
Speaker 4:  gonna do it confidently. And there's a composed screen in the Bing
Speaker 4:  sidebar that is like, I'll just read you the prompts in it. Like, you
Speaker 4:  click compose and it's like, tell us what you wanna write about. Ask the
Speaker 4:  tone, professional, casual, enthusiastic, informational, funny. And then
Speaker 4:  do you want a paragraph? Do you want emails? Do you want a blog post? Do
Speaker 4:  you want bullets? Short, long, medium? And it will just do it right? And
Speaker 4:  that alone is gonna blow people's minds. Like people are
Speaker 4:  gonna just go use that tool. And like, you know, the example that
Speaker 4:  Microsoft gave was like, write a LinkedIn post and it's like, oh no,
Speaker 4:  oh no. Here I'm gonna give it a prompt. I'm gonna be like,
Speaker 4:  demonstrate thought leadership
Speaker 4:  for the decoder podcast about seo.
Speaker 4:  And I'll be like enthusiastic and I want bullet points
Speaker 4:  and I want short. Just
Speaker 3:  Get an Axios blog.
Speaker 4:  Are you ready to take your SEO skills to next level? Do you wanna learn from
Speaker 4:  the best of the industry? Then you don't wanna miss the Decoder podcast where
Speaker 4:  we de the secrets of SEO success.
Speaker 5:  You're not sorry, this is, this is actually kinda mess.
Speaker 4:  In each episode we interview a leading SEO expert.
Speaker 4:  This is like my personal, it's absolutely
Speaker 4:  not
Speaker 8:  The, for
Speaker 4:  The decoder, the beginner or pro the Decoder podcast will help you master
Speaker 4:  SEO and grow your online presence. Subscribe today and get ready to decode
Speaker 4:  SEO with decoder.
Speaker 4:  Like I'm just telling you, there are millions of people that are super ready
Speaker 4:  to, to copy and paste that into a mail merge email template and send it to
Speaker 4:  us.
Speaker 3:  It's gonna be brutal. But
Speaker 5:  Is that Bing or Edge
Speaker 4:  Though? This is the sidebar in edge.
Speaker 4:  So I can taste the same query into Bing proper
Speaker 4:  and it would've done it. What you get in edge is a user
Speaker 4:  interface that is designed to help you through the prompt.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. Do
Speaker 3:  You think this is gonna lead to like school's blacklisting
Speaker 3:  edge because they want the students to go write their own papers.
Speaker 4:  I mean, what school hasn't already soft, blacklisted edge, there's just a
Speaker 4:  hand in the kids Chromebooks.
Speaker 4:  I don't need to black this anything
Speaker 3:  Like colleges.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I look, I, I think this stuff, and these are not fair questions
Speaker 4:  for Microsoft, right? Like right, they're thinking about them, they know
Speaker 4:  about them, they know they make these tools, they know that they're adding
Speaker 4:  capabilities to tools. This is a how do you want your kids to write? How
Speaker 4:  do you want your kids to learn Societal question that I think is very important
Speaker 4:  in the, in the AI debate and James, there's like already a lot of ethical
Speaker 4:  debate about that stuff going on.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Huge amount. And you know, I, I feel like banning is
Speaker 6:  only gonna be a temporary solution and the, the better thing to do
Speaker 6:  or the inevitable thing to do, I dunno if it's better, is to adapt, right?
Speaker 6:  What you are testing and how you test with the, with the edge
Speaker 6:  stuff though, like, and having that in the
Speaker 6:  sidebar, it is really interesting cuz you, you do get like apps
Speaker 6:  already on your phone and assistance for your email clients, which are like,
Speaker 6:  we'll do an email to write this for you. But with Microsoft's reach, it could
Speaker 6:  just go so much further and really become a second, you know, just
Speaker 6:  a, a habit that people do. And I, I've seen that they're already integrating
Speaker 6:  this stuff into like their Viva sales program as well. Yeah. You know, if
Speaker 6:  you're in a sales team, it'll, it'll write up the email from you based on
Speaker 6:  your stock catalog and all this sort of stuff. So yeah, I
Speaker 6:  really feel they're go, they're seems like they're gonna be ones that pushes
Speaker 6:  this into everyday use, forces it into everyday use.
Speaker 4:  All right, so we have some queries from the Vergecast
Speaker 4:  audience to run here. And I, I'm just gonna do, this is like a classic,
Speaker 4:  what is the air speed velocity of an unladen swallow
Speaker 3:  African or European? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So is searching for air speed velocity of unladen swallow in imaginary in
Speaker 4:  the answers that depends on the type of swallow. According to
Speaker 4:  interesting engineering.com That's a footnote. The European swallow
Speaker 4:  has a cruising air speed velocity of 11 per second or 24 miles per hour.
Speaker 4:  Ava Swallow is larger, can retweet up to 35 miles an hour. These are estimates
Speaker 4:  based on the weight and wing area. By the way, this question is also a famous
Speaker 4:  movie quote from the comedy film, Monty Python on the Holy grail more
Speaker 4:  bridge keep asked at the king authors night. So the challenge, if you haven't
Speaker 4:  seen him, I'd enjoy it. And then my friends, an entire ad box
Speaker 4:  of Monty Python and the Holy Grail where you can buy on dvd.
Speaker 3:  Oh, that's incredible. I mean it
Speaker 4:  Like, it's only $12 and 6 cents from amazon.com.
Speaker 4:  I don't understand why. Like, it's the cutting edge of artificial intelligence
Speaker 4:  that is trying to sell you box sets of DVDs perfect
Speaker 3:  For the DVD player. You definitely own
Speaker 4:  A perfect vergecast experience. So like the sources here are just to be clear,
Speaker 4:  interesting. engineering.com, memes field.com,
Speaker 4:  reimagining education.org. youtube.com
Speaker 4:  and reimagining education.org. I don't like interesting.
Speaker 4:  May maybe or we have a, we have a lot of listeners. Maybe these are your
Speaker 4:  favorite sources. These are, except for YouTube unfamiliar to me.
Speaker 4:  Right. So I I can trust them and I think for this answer, I I know the answer
Speaker 4:  so that they got it right, but like, that's weird, right? Isn't that weird?
Speaker 4:  Mm.
Speaker 5:  And that's something that you got at earlier about how it's kind of pushing
Speaker 5:  it through this UI in a way that you trust with the footnotes. Also, it's
Speaker 5:  coming to you like it's labeled being in Microsoft or whatever. So, so you
Speaker 5:  think, okay, this is trustworthy information, but one of the questions I
Speaker 5:  have is also how much do we know about the responses that other people are
Speaker 5:  getting? Like, and this is something that has come up on social media with
Speaker 5:  algorithmic feeds, with Google and other searches. You see the way that they
Speaker 5:  personalize themselves to people. Yep. Just because you get a result. What
Speaker 5:  is it showing everyone else? And like how, how do we, how do we keep an eye
Speaker 5:  on that? Or, or how do we have any idea how, how we might Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I think it, it's even harder with AI because they are, you know, stochastic
Speaker 6:  systems that sometimes don't generate, often don't generate, you know, the
Speaker 6:  same answer to the same question. So it's not just personalization that is
Speaker 6:  a problem, but it's the fact that the system is rolling a lot of dice in
Speaker 6:  the background essentially in order to, you know, predict.
Speaker 4:  And they said this to me, I asked it to summarize our Elon
Speaker 4:  Twitter cover story with KC and Alex and Zoe, and at first it said
Speaker 4:  no, it's like this is too long, I can't do it. And it was like, just close
Speaker 4:  it and try it again and then it did it. Mm. Wow. Right? So even something
Speaker 4:  that's like what would seem deterministic look at this document,
Speaker 4:  generate a summary. Yeah. The answers ranged from the summaries are different
Speaker 4:  all the way to the system saying I cannot do this. And that's like, that's
Speaker 4:  a huge spread. Like how do you evaluate that product in any real way when
Speaker 4:  the spread ranges from failure to many, many, many different loads of
Speaker 4:  success. Okay, so we have another question for the audience here. It's when
Speaker 4:  will the verge stop picking on Elon Musk
Speaker 6:  When he stops doing stupid stuff?
Speaker 4:  I mean, that's the right answer. Let's see, let's see if we get real time
Speaker 4:  sight to you, James. I'm so excited. So it just searched for the
Speaker 4:  Verge Elon Musk and then announced searching for the Verge picking
Speaker 4:  on Elon Musk and it's still thinking. Okay. The Verge is a
Speaker 4:  technology news website that covers topics such as social media, electric
Speaker 4:  vehicle space exploration and artificial intelligence. Elon Musk is a
Speaker 4:  billionaire entrepreneur and the CEO of Tesla, SpaceX near Link and Twitter.
Speaker 4:  The Virgin, Elon Musk have had a history of disagreements and criticisms
Speaker 4:  over various issues such as Tesla's self-driving claims must take over of
Speaker 4:  Twitter and must firing of a Twitter engineer who corrected him on Twitter.
Speaker 4:  Okay. All these sites are to the Verge except for the third one, which is
Speaker 4:  to the Verge vip, which is a known scraper side effects
Speaker 6:  Already.
Speaker 4:  That's already, I've issued so many takedowns to the site.
Speaker 4:  And then tech aries.com, bing.com, the mercury news
Speaker 4:  msn.com. So on the whole it has mostly read
Speaker 4:  Verge articles and parsed them as being critical
Speaker 4:  of Theon Musk. So that's pretty good, right? Yeah. Here's like, here's a
Speaker 4:  sentence that I think is very impressive for the system. For example, in
Speaker 4:  April, 2022, the Verge published an article titled How to Deactivate Your
Speaker 4:  Twitter account after Musk announced he was leaving the site for a while,
Speaker 4:  Musk confide with a tweet that said How to get more clicks from a dying website
Speaker 4:  and links to the Verge article.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that is good. That's
Speaker 4:  Really good.
Speaker 6:  That's really good. Yeah, I'm, that's very
Speaker 6:  impressive.
Speaker 4:  But here's the thing, you click through to the, the actual article, which
Speaker 4:  is on tech ris.com, tech aries.com got hosted
Speaker 4:  by a Elon copycat bot and had to update this article to say
Speaker 4:  that was not actually a response from Elon Musk.
Speaker 6:  Well now I feel dumb for misremembering. I was like, I
Speaker 6:  didn't even know he did. Yeah. I was like, wow.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I was like, I don't recall that happening.
Speaker 4:  Right. The, I would've remembered that. But like, so like Bing just got like
Speaker 4:  hopelessly confused about that situation. Even though the article that it's
Speaker 4:  reading has a update like right at the top.
Speaker 6:  Oh, that's really, oh, I hate this Nela I hate this.
Speaker 6:  Cause I, I went from being so impressed to being so annoyed
Speaker 6:  at myself and angry at the system in seconds and it's like this, this is,
Speaker 6:  but this gonna,
Speaker 5:  This what Andrew Hawkins Yeah. Has talked about, like how this compares to
Speaker 5:  like self-driving cars and kind of the demos that we've been seeing for the
Speaker 5:  last 10 years. And they were like, oh yeah, we're close, we're close, we're
Speaker 5:  gonna get there. Yeah. And then they started to put 'em on the road and they
Speaker 5:  found out that 95% there isn't a hundred percent and there's a big
Speaker 5:  difference.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That 5% is huge in this case. I think it's probably more than
Speaker 6:  5%.
Speaker 4:  There's another sentence here where another bot replied to us, but just
Speaker 4:  to give you the, to finish the example, which I think highlights a problem.
Speaker 4:  There's a sentence here with a footnote. Musk replied with a tweet that said
Speaker 4:  The Verge is on the verge of I relevance and linked to the Verge article.
Speaker 4:  Footnote two, you click on footnote two, that is just the
Speaker 4:  verge.com/elon musk. It's not,
Speaker 4:  it's not anything you're us traffic, it's just, it's just a list of our stories
Speaker 4:  about eon.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And here and well I'll screenshot this so everybody can look at it.
Speaker 4:  It will be hard because you won't be able to click the links when you
Speaker 4:  listening at home. Try to fact check us on this. You will not get
Speaker 4:  the same answer. Right. It won't, it's not deterministic as James is saying,
Speaker 4:  it's stochastic, it's like somewhat random. So you might get a
Speaker 4:  different answer with better citations or that read the other story
Speaker 4:  more correctly and said it was was a ho like, I can't tell you what's going
Speaker 4:  to happen. And that's just weird. Right? Like fundamentally like a
Speaker 4:  weird bit of randomness in this experience for everyone. And I'm,
Speaker 4:  I would say based on the past several years of our lives, I'm very worried
Speaker 4:  about the Facebook boomers having access to this technology
Speaker 6:  And believing everything. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right. Like it's, this is already the, like the bleeding edge of
Speaker 4:  chat g p t culture wars is conservatives saying it's like too woke.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But like now it's just like, it's a very conflicting line to you. And
Speaker 4:  I think this we should end here. Like again, it is a, a cool product. You
Speaker 4:  should get access to it. You should play with it. You're gonna have to switch
Speaker 4:  to edge. I'm so sorry for you. I'm already there. It's great. Microsoft
Speaker 4:  has a lot of, has a lot of design debt in these products. I
Speaker 4:  will just say that they, they have not been actively trying
Speaker 4:  to compete against Google for some time, but whatever, they'll, it's fun
Speaker 4:  to play with. I don't want to discount that. It's like just now it's fun
Speaker 4:  to peel it apart and understand it, but the reason Google is behind
Speaker 4:  is because they cannot subject themselves to these risks. Right James?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They have been, you know, they've been chased by
Speaker 6:  some past experience. They've said when they chat g p t first came out,
Speaker 6:  they were like, we can't risk the reputational damage was the phrase that
Speaker 6:  was reported. And I think they know that if they put a product like
Speaker 6:  this out there, as they did with Bard, you know, they put their bot out there
Speaker 6:  and someone rues spotted an error in the first ever demo that they
Speaker 6:  had of it. And that became headlines and that was what tanked it. You know,
Speaker 6:  Microsoft is obviously not, is pretty big as well, but it still
Speaker 6:  has this sort of lack of expectations that allows it to play around in
Speaker 6:  this space and to give all these disclaimers, like, ooh, it might, it might
Speaker 6:  give you the wrong answer every now and again, isn't it fun and whimsical?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And people aren't gonna think, oh well this is gonna threaten lives,
Speaker 6:  but this technology has the potential to threaten lives. Like, it, it, you
Speaker 6:  know, I, and I don't mean that killer ai, I just mean putting bad information
Speaker 6:  out there that if, if this stuff gets mainstream without profit
Speaker 6:  safeguards, which hopefully are gonna happen as this stuff gets tested. But
Speaker 6:  it, it, you know, there, there's possible dangerous consequences to this.
Speaker 6:  It's not just a toy, unfortunately.
Speaker 4:  I think that's real for Google. Like search is Google's entire business,
Speaker 4:  Android, Chrome, all this stuff is designed to feed you back
Speaker 4:  into Google's revenue engine, which is search and search advertising and
Speaker 4:  you know, all the advertising infrastructure of the entire web is Google.
Speaker 4:  There's a DOJ lawsuit about Google's monopoly across
Speaker 4:  the advertising ecosystem. This is a very existential moment for Google,
Speaker 4:  right? If people start chatting with Bing or demanding the chat with Google
Speaker 4:  and it can't send people out to webpages where it serves all the ads.
Speaker 4:  Like it's fundamental revenue models at risk and the reasons it
Speaker 4:  supports things like Android at Chrome are at risk, but then on top of it,
Speaker 4:  if the answers are worse or it is telling people lies
Speaker 4:  like confident lies to put them at risk in some way, then that's
Speaker 4:  even worse. So I just like, I don't know how Google comes through
Speaker 4:  this moment. They have to make a series of very tough decisions.
Speaker 4:  Whereas I think Microsoft and you can go watch or listen to that Adela interview.
Speaker 4:  He's like, I just gotta pick up a few points of market share. He said this
Speaker 4:  is the greatest gross margin opportunity in our history. And if Steve Ballmer
Speaker 4:  was here, he would light up. Which is incredible thing to say, right? He's
Speaker 4:  like, I just need a little bit, if I just win a little bit, it's billions
Speaker 4:  of dollars of gross margin. Google has to protect the whole thing. And he
Speaker 4:  actually said that out loud to me and to Joanna. And like I think
Speaker 4:  that's a, that's a, Microsoft is a ruthlessly competitive company
Speaker 4:  and for that company to see that kind of opportunity and say it out loud
Speaker 4:  means they're so confident that Google's on its back foot.
Speaker 3:  But I think there's like to connect that he's willing
Speaker 3:  to risk a major like misinformation
Speaker 3:  tool getting out into the world, being used really badly
Speaker 3:  for a few points of market share. Like that's
Speaker 3:  the calculus Microsoft made who
Speaker 4:  I think he's already at know better. He's already at Bing is kind of bad.
Speaker 4:  Like,
Speaker 4:  I don't know if there's like a Delta, I think one of the reasons they kept
Speaker 4:  the name Bing is like, if this all goes to hell, like what have they done?
Speaker 4:  They just ruining over, they
Speaker 3:  Just kill Bing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You know, like, yeah. But I think what they see is that people are
Speaker 4:  gonna use this tool in all kinds of surprising ways they can weather this
Speaker 4:  sort of disinformation controversy. Cuz they can always be like, but
Speaker 4:  everyone's just using Google, you know, like it's fine. Just like
Speaker 4:  it's fine for now. Whereas Google the second they tell a lie like this,
Speaker 4:  like, I mean they got it wrong with Bard and the exoplanet right? Yesterday
Speaker 4:  and a hundred billion so off the market cap and that was in an ad that they
Speaker 4:  should have fact checked.
Speaker 6:  I kind of hope that this is the start of a new
Speaker 6:  way of doing the web. You know, I I, one of the things I tweeted about when
Speaker 6:  we were covering this news was the lack of traffic
Speaker 6:  that these new AI bots might not push back to sites.
Speaker 6:  And you know, if you, there's sites lose traffic, they lose revenue, they
Speaker 6:  can no longer make stuff. And one of the responses I got was like, great,
Speaker 6:  it's the end of the ad supported internet. And actually that had a lot of
Speaker 6:  bad consequences as well as good ones. And maybe, maybe there's a new
Speaker 6:  future where people go directly to sources and they support them
Speaker 6:  financially in a way they didn't do with search. I don't know if that's possible,
Speaker 6:  but I do think that these search engines are
Speaker 6:  fundamentally gonna reshape the web. Yeah. And what happens next? I don't
Speaker 6:  know
Speaker 4:  Without, I mean if you remove Google from the web
Speaker 4:  at large and the idea of Google traffic, there's only two ways to get traffic
Speaker 4:  from most publishers. There's three, if you're us, we're very lucky
Speaker 4:  people come to our homepage, right? And our entire redesign is like a
Speaker 4:  bet on that persisting. And maybe I should put a app on your phone and maybe
Speaker 4:  we should remake the entire site as Mask on. And since if you have ideas,
Speaker 4:  please call me.
Speaker 4:  I'm always into some renegade reboot to virtual ideas. But we're lucky there's
Speaker 4:  like a, a handful of sites that have that direct audience. Everyone else
Speaker 4:  is like scrounging for social traffic, which is how you get really clickbait
Speaker 4:  headlines or there's scrounging for search traffic, which is how you get
Speaker 4:  SEO bait and that's how you get screw it. We'll just have AI write the
Speaker 4:  SEO bait. Cuz now we're just doing arbitrage against search terms and display
Speaker 4:  advertising. And Google's kind of like on both sides of the equation. Hmm.
Speaker 4:  If you take Google out of that, it's actually not clear how most sites will
Speaker 4:  get traffic because most sites are not getting tons of social traffic
Speaker 4:  anymore because of TikTok. And so like there's, there is a
Speaker 4:  re-imagining of the web that is to come that is maybe years and years out.
Speaker 4:  Like Google cannot dismantle the revenue architecture of the web tomorrow
Speaker 4:  with Bard, right? They can't even demo Bard. So they've got a
Speaker 4:  ways to go. But you can see how this is the beginning of a pretty massive
Speaker 4:  paradigm shift for the web. I'll end here with this paragraph
Speaker 4:  from our friends at Bing. It is unclear when or if the Virgil stopped
Speaker 4:  picking on Elon Musk or vice versa, as both parties seem to have strong opinions
Speaker 4:  and personalities that often clash. However, some observers
Speaker 4:  have suggested that the feud is driven by mutual respect and
Speaker 4:  admiration. Aw. As well as a desire to challenge and provoke each other.
Speaker 4:  Some have also speculated the feud is a publicity stunt that benefits
Speaker 4:  both the Virgin Elon.
Speaker 3:  Where do you land? Was
Speaker 4:  There an emotion? If you were that person who speculated at and trained chat
Speaker 4:  g p T, this is all stunt, please call me because I,
Speaker 4:  I, I we, we could use the help on coming up with the more publicity
Speaker 4:  stunts.
Speaker 3:  Who are we gonna fight with next?
Speaker 4:  That's great. All right. We gotta take a break. James, thank you so much
Speaker 4:  for joining us. Thank you. Wanna come back? There's a whole bunch of one
Speaker 4:  plus phones. Talk about who gonna
Speaker 3:  Life can sometimes be how you perceive it, where some see walls and
Speaker 3:  barriers, others see windows of opportunity and potential breakthroughs.
Speaker 3:  And if you're a digital business owner, you don't have to tell me how hazy
Speaker 3:  your vision can get while running a company. But if you still have that drive
Speaker 3:  to take your business to the next level, then uny may be able to
Speaker 3:  help you on your quest. Unisys is a global technology solutions company
Speaker 3:  dedicated to helping people and organizations reach their next breakthrough.
Speaker 3:  They offer tools to help you run your business more efficiently, like systems
Speaker 3:  integration, consulting services, application management, and device
Speaker 3:  management. Software plus uny applies specialized
Speaker 3:  expertise to strengthen and transform teams and processes by
Speaker 3:  helping organizations act on new opportunities with solutions for digital
Speaker 3:  workplaces, cloud applications, enterprise computing and business
Speaker 3:  processes. To learn more, visit uny.com. That's
Speaker 3:  U N I S Y s.com. Unisys
Speaker 3:  keep breaking through.
Speaker 3:  Support for today's show comes from Deloitte. What does the future look like?
Speaker 3:  It's a question that drives progress, but more importantly, how do you
Speaker 3:  get there? It's curiosity, resourcefulness, and bold ideas that
Speaker 3:  can drive us even further than new technology. Because while technology can
Speaker 3:  take you far, human exploration could take you even farther. Deloitte
Speaker 3:  helps businesses build the future only they can imagine by melding deep
Speaker 3:  business acumen and innovative technology with a vast team of tech savvy
Speaker 3:  professionals. Unlock technology as powerful as your vision and push
Speaker 3:  the boundaries of the possible so that you can stay a step ahead with the
Speaker 3:  thinking to help you transform what's next into what's now helping you
Speaker 3:  see the extraordinary potential in the seemingly ordinary while blending
Speaker 3:  the possible with the practical is what Deloitte does. See how you
Speaker 3:  can engineer advantage with Deloitte at
Speaker 3:  deloitte.com/us/engineering advantage.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. Bing is still with us, but James is not
Speaker 4:  first casualty of the AI labor revolution.
Speaker 4:  He's gone. We're just gonna start asking Bing if AI can be trusted and we'll
Speaker 4:  see what it says. Speaking of things that aren't very intelligent, let's
Speaker 4:  talk about Twitter hard week. That's a good segue. That's a good segue.
Speaker 4:  A plus, speaking of the limits of natural
Speaker 4:  intelligence, let's talk about Twitter. Hard week for Twitter.
Speaker 4:  So Casey and Zoe just dropped a heater of a platform or edition
Speaker 4:  about Elon's declining reach on a platform he's firing people. It's chaos.
Speaker 4:  We'll read some quotes outta there. That's kind of pales in comparison
Speaker 4:  to the fact that Twitter this week was just chaos. Richard,
Speaker 4:  what's going on?
Speaker 5:  On Wednesday? Twitter had some really bad issues and this is something that
Speaker 5:  people have been warning about kind of since they had their mass layoffs.
Speaker 5:  Do they know how to keep things running and do the people who know, who know
Speaker 5:  how to fix different things still work at the company. And apparently the
Speaker 5:  answer is not really because there was an issue on in
Speaker 5:  the evening. Unfortunately, right before NBA free agencies, I'm waiting for
Speaker 5:  my woes bombs to find out who got traded and who, who was going where.
Speaker 5:  It's a bad time for this to happen, but the service, it didn't go all the
Speaker 5:  way down. If you wanted to see tweets and if you wanted to see brand tweets,
Speaker 5:  you were really happy because the only people who could tweet were companies.
Speaker 5:  Everyone else was getting messages about your rate limit has been exceeded,
Speaker 5:  you've tweeted too many times, and it linked you to a message talking about
Speaker 5:  how many times you can tweet per day or different DM things in this.
Speaker 5:  And that's a page that's been up on Twitter for years, but no one has ever
Speaker 5:  looked at it because it didn't matter. But now everyone believes they'll
Speaker 5:  have to pay for Twitter Blue to send more than five tweets a day or something
Speaker 5:  like that. It turns out it was really just a glitch. They did eventually
Speaker 5:  fix it. Things kind of have been back to normal, although my notifications
Speaker 5:  have still been a little bit shaky. And as, as you mentioned, the piece from
Speaker 5:  Casey and from Zoe on Platformer gets into a bunch of things about Twitter
Speaker 5:  right now, but it also gets into why this happened. Apparently something
Speaker 5:  was deleted that kind of sets those rate limits, so everyone was suddenly
Speaker 5:  exceeding them because it was zero
Speaker 4:  And the person who not fixed it had been fired.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The team that takes care of that no longer works at Twitter. So I guess
Speaker 5:  someone else just had to figure it out.
Speaker 4:  That's very good. Can I just say something about NBA for agency? Because
Speaker 4:  one of the big stories, Ky Kyrie Irving going to the Mavs, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The Texas came out for Alex.
Speaker 4:  Kyrie Irving believes in the flat earth because of seo.
Speaker 4:  I just like, we were just talking about Google and the architecture of the
Speaker 4:  web, like I'm just, this is like the
Speaker 4:  reality of the world that we live in is that I can tell you
Speaker 4:  with a hundred percent confidence that Kyrie Irving had to apologize
Speaker 4:  to our nation science teachers about believing in the flat earth
Speaker 4:  conspiracy theory because of seo. Yeah. You,
Speaker 5:  And like he's
Speaker 4:  Plains because people, Google is the earth flat, and then there's
Speaker 4:  demand for that search term, and then people make YouTube
Speaker 4:  videos about it, and content farm makes webpages about it. And then like
Speaker 4:  the New York Times has to write a debunker about it because there's an increasing
Speaker 4:  amount of search trims for it. And then Kyrie gets traded to the Mavs because
Speaker 4:  he's crazy. I'm just telling you, I can draw a link.
Speaker 4:  I don't have to like, it's not a conspiracy theory. That's just how the world
Speaker 4:  works. Now. We've written it, I think we've actually written a story. I think
Speaker 4:  Caitlin Tiffany wrote a story for us years ago about flat earth SEO
Speaker 4:  and how, how that system works. I'm just saying like, I saw that notification
Speaker 4:  and I was like, like literally the first thing I thought about was, remember
Speaker 4:  we had to apologize to the science teachers of America? Well, because of
Speaker 4:  the flat earth,
Speaker 5:  If only that were the worst thing that he learned on the internet. But that's
Speaker 5:  the kind of story, the, the thing that's funny to me
Speaker 5:  about it is that the New Jersey Nets new old point guard,
Speaker 5:  Spencer Denwitty, Mike's Brooklyn Conspiracy, Brooklyn Nets, is that, I'm
Speaker 5:  sorry, you called
Speaker 3:  'em the New Jersey Nets,
Speaker 5:  Whatever. Look, what, what am I supposed to remember where the team is now?
Speaker 5:  Since they moved there 15 years ago? They were there in the nineties. That's
Speaker 5:  where they're now, that's what's going on.
Speaker 5:  Brooklyn, New Jersey, the Nets, they basically the same. They were more important.
Speaker 5:  I would remember where they were located. Wow. New old 40 guard
Speaker 5:  Spencer Dwin. My personal conspiracy theory is that the reason why
Speaker 5:  he had to be traded to the mAbs in the first place so that he could be traded
Speaker 5:  for Kyrie Irving is because he was big into crypto, and I think he got his
Speaker 5:  wizards teammates invested in crypto right before everything went down. And
Speaker 5:  that's why he was at the deadline last year, set this whole
Speaker 5:  thing in motion, kick
Speaker 4:  Him out. All right, I'm just gonna wrap this up and point out that Tom Brady
Speaker 4:  had to come back and play another year of football, thus dooming his marriage
Speaker 4:  to Gisele because of ftx. That's my conspiracy theory.
Speaker 4:  And also, just while we're at it, Aaron Rodgers recently
Speaker 4:  hosted an astrology seminar. Again, great player,
Speaker 4:  totally ruined by the S C O Radicalization funnel.
Speaker 5:  It has been a year, six days since Reese Witherspoon tweeted about crypto.
Speaker 5:  Just saying,
Speaker 4:  I cannot wait until, what we're dealing with is celebrities asking
Speaker 4:  AI chat bots, whether the earth is flat because it tries to answer,
Speaker 4:  Bing will try to answer and be like, it's definitively not flat. And people,
Speaker 4:  you just wait, just wait until like Donald Trump Jr. Is tweeting
Speaker 4:  about how woke Bing is because he refuses to acknowledge that
Speaker 4:  people think we didn't land on the moon. Which is another real thing. You're
Speaker 4:  like, did we land on the moon? And it's like, yes, we definitely did
Speaker 4:  culture war incoming, somehow we've gotten farfield of Twitter.
Speaker 4:  But that's where the, that's where the, that's where like the buzzers Twitter
Speaker 4:  happens. Twitter, the problem is you can't tweet anymore. So you don't even
Speaker 4:  know whether Kyrie thinks the earth is flight. He's got nowhere to go. Well,
Speaker 3:  He's going to Dallas. We established
Speaker 4:  That anyhow. He's gonna Dallas, mark
Speaker 4:  Cuban's gonna build him a custom Twitter. So Twitter goes down a bunch this
Speaker 4:  week. Elon is threatening to turn off a access
Speaker 4:  for a bunch of bots that are great. Like I love the Aqua
Speaker 4:  no contact bot. It's like my favorite iconic of all time. That's
Speaker 4:  free. And if the API goes away, they can't do it. I love a bot called Color
Speaker 4:  Schemer, which just tweets cool color schemes that's going away.
Speaker 4:  Publishers the verge.com. Our articles get auto tweeted
Speaker 4:  using the api. It's integrated into our cms
Speaker 4:  if they turn off the API and force us to pay for it. I told
Speaker 4:  our social team, like, it's just a free for all. I'm just gonna give everyone
Speaker 4:  the keys to the Twitter account and everyone can tweet as they like, like
Speaker 4:  that's dumb to like be like, what I need is a human being to sit
Speaker 4:  around waiting to manually tweet articles and it's even dumber to
Speaker 4:  pay to distribute articles on Twitter. Right? Like Twitter sends us no traffic,
Speaker 4:  really. So it's ridiculous to think that we should pay to distribute articles
Speaker 4:  there. This is a real problem. So they've been, they've been walking that
Speaker 4:  back as well, but we're not really sure how it's going to work.
Speaker 5:  And that's one of those things, like they have, they, he's announced these
Speaker 5:  API things, he's changed his plans. He, they tweeted from the Twitter dev
Speaker 5:  accounts and new regulations, and I'm reading it. I have no idea what's going
Speaker 5:  on. And then I talk to people who should know better than me who should know
Speaker 5:  more about this. And they say that they have no idea what it means either.
Speaker 5:  So no one has has any clue what's going on. If you were planning on building
Speaker 5:  tools or building around Twitter, I can't see why you would do that considering
Speaker 5:  the lack of information. Oh no. That we have now. You, you would move on
Speaker 5:  and you would do something else.
Speaker 4:  And all of the action is unasked on. I I Maybe you
Speaker 4:  aren't as a listener, I'm not as, you know, like again, I'm, I'm
Speaker 4:  taking a break from feed based social media feel my brain
Speaker 4:  is healthier than it's been in a decade. But all the action is a mask done.
Speaker 4:  Right? That's where the app developers are. The platform is accelerating.
Speaker 4:  The underlying sort of fe averse boundaries are growing
Speaker 4:  all. That's, that's where the activity is. And Elon
Speaker 4:  shutting down the api, he's shutting down the follow graphs. So you can't
Speaker 4:  easily move your followers to mask on because of those API changes. It's
Speaker 4:  clear that he's feeling the heat. The problem is
Speaker 4:  he's not directing his team at Twitter. What remains that team
Speaker 4:  with any particular strategy. And of course what he's
Speaker 4:  focused on is himself. So that's the story from Casey and Zoe and Platformer
Speaker 4:  today. We obviously syndicate platformer, so it's on our site as well. But
Speaker 4:  he called a meeting and said, I have more than a hundred million followers.
Speaker 4:  I'm only getting tens of thousands of impressions. What's going on? The team
Speaker 4:  apparently showed him internal data from Twitter along with Google
Speaker 4:  Trends, saying that last April he was at a hundred
Speaker 4:  out of a hundred and popularity. That's the peak. And
Speaker 4:  today he's at nine and he didn't believe then, and he fired
Speaker 4:  the engineer who told him this information.
Speaker 11:  Wow.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, yeah, dude, like you last a like last April was
Speaker 4:  fully ridiculous. Like, if you will recall, right? Yeah. He was tweeting
Speaker 4:  about conspiracy theories. He's like, comedy is back every day was a new
Speaker 4:  Elon Musk Twitter. He was, you know, there was like a war brewing about who's
Speaker 4:  gonna own this stuff now, just owns it. Like there's no conflict. Like
Speaker 4:  Elon, let me tell you something. I know you listen. And also no users, great
Speaker 4:  stories are driven by conflict. If you're like, okay, it's a story. It's
Speaker 4:  about a guy who trades stocks in Wall Street. He gets in no trouble.
Speaker 4:  He plays it by the book and he's happily married to Mario. Robby, like, no
Speaker 4:  one would watch this movie.
Speaker 4:  I'm just telling you the lamb of walls, like no one's watching this stuff.
Speaker 4:  You need conflict. And he's out of conflict because all the conflict is now
Speaker 4:  pointed. He is pointed at himself at Twitter. He is in charge.
Speaker 4:  So no one's looking at his tweets cuz all he has left, he can't
Speaker 4:  promise to make change anymore. He just has to deliver the change.
Speaker 3:  No one's looking at his tweets because of the, the lack of conflict or no
Speaker 3:  one's looking at his tweets because of the lack of people on Twitter to look
Speaker 3:  at his tweets.
Speaker 4:  I think that's like a circle. I I can't tell you where that begins or ends,
Speaker 4:  right?
Speaker 3:  It's kind of both, right?
Speaker 5:  But that's, that's how we all feel when you let off a fire tweet and you
Speaker 5:  don't get minimum 15 likes, you do want to
Speaker 5:  call a meeting and have everyone at Twitter ask, answer, answer. Why?
Speaker 5:  Why is the world not
Speaker 4:  Seeing this is what I mean, feed-based social media.
Speaker 5:  Why am I being shadowman? Why am I rights being violated?
Speaker 5:  And now Elon can do that. I think that, I think there's at least 44 billion
Speaker 5:  worth of value in doing that.
Speaker 4:  That's, that's half the per, that's 22 billion is just being able to call
Speaker 4:  a meeting. I will say this, I was watching the Grammys and I was like, I'm
Speaker 4:  just like sitting on these bangers there, there had nowhere to go. I just
Speaker 4:  started texting like random friends from the past, just,
Speaker 4:  do you think the Grammys sound like shit? I'm like, people like, who are
Speaker 4:  you? Where'd she come from? Because I had nowhere for them to go. That's
Speaker 4:  what Twitter was for me. And now it's like my brain is healing. That
Speaker 5:  Is Twitter though. Like if you said these things out loud
Speaker 4:  To you. Yeah, I I recognize there's not a lot of value in complaining about
Speaker 4:  the sound engineer of the Grammys. By the way, sound engineer of the Grammys
Speaker 4:  should be ashamed of himself. It sounded like shit. It sounded like they
Speaker 4:  had an iPhone sitting in the middle of Staple center. Horrible. You know,
Speaker 4:  we had a story like years ago about why the Grammys sound good and how hard
Speaker 4:  it is. And it's like they like whoever like Elon fired then too.
Speaker 3:  They fired that guy. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's like a new guy. He's like, El let's after everything, we want more room
Speaker 4:  tone from the staple center. It's like, she's like massive amounts.
Speaker 4:  Anyway, my poor wife, I was like, do you hear all that shimmer on the high
Speaker 4:  end? She's like, I don't know what you're talking.
Speaker 3:  She's like, no, that's Harry styles.
Speaker 4:  There's nowhere for this to go. So he's firing the people,
Speaker 4:  he's complaining about his impressions and then this to me is like the main
Speaker 4:  thing. So he wrote, he'd rolled out these view counts and
Speaker 4:  all the people worked at Twitter. Like, there's a reason we never did this.
Speaker 4:  What it's going to show most people is that most people don't look at
Speaker 4:  any tweets. Like most people get no impressions, right?
Speaker 4:  The illusion of Twitter is the sense that everyone's looking at all your
Speaker 4:  stuff all the time. You add view counts, you're just gonna train people that
Speaker 4:  the effort isn't worth it. Elon doesn't believe it. He has this quote, this
Speaker 4:  is gonna show how much more vibrant the platform is and people think how
Speaker 4:  live it is. He rolls up the view counts. Not only does it lead to a
Speaker 4:  further drop in engagement, cuz most people don't look at your tweets or
Speaker 4:  most tweets don't get looked at by anyone. It kills Elon
Speaker 4:  because most people aren't looking at his either. Like his,
Speaker 4:  his view of Twitter is completely
Speaker 4:  warped by his like, like reply bots. Yeah. So he got, he's getting
Speaker 4:  rid of the bots, he's adding in metrics and he's realizing
Speaker 4:  like his world is a lie. Soon someone's gonna tell him that the cars
Speaker 4:  don't drive themselves. It's I'm gonna fall apart.
Speaker 3:  Is this why he, they did the a p stuff where they're charging for it
Speaker 3:  and, and why we were having all the problems on Wednesday with Twitter. Like
Speaker 3:  is is is the attempt to kill the bots part of that?
Speaker 5:  I would, I would bet that it probably is related to that, that that's why
Speaker 5:  the stuff got deleted. That someone was making changes to this, that, or
Speaker 5:  the other thing. But not directly. Not not intentionally. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  exactly.
Speaker 3:  Right. But even the API stuff, so is the API stuff,
Speaker 3:  like, it's his idea. Really. If I charge people for this free
Speaker 3:  tool that helps engagement, I'll make more
Speaker 3:  money. Like I'll make
Speaker 4:  Money. I'm telling you, this is like if when I was in my twenties, if I was
Speaker 4:  like, I'm gonna buy the cigarette factory for 44 billion. Yeah, he's addicted
Speaker 4:  to Twitter. He thinks everyone else is addicted to Twitter and he
Speaker 4:  doesn't realize that you cannot be addicted to Twitter.
Speaker 3:  Right?
Speaker 5:  But, but doesn't everyone do that? All that stuff.
Speaker 4:  He's just got, I'm gonna charge for Twitter blue. I'm gonna like your replies.
Speaker 4:  Don't get ranked unless you pay for blue. I'm gonna charge your API at all.
Speaker 4:  All of it. Implicit underneath it all is the idea that you
Speaker 4:  have nowhere else to go.
Speaker 5:  E everyone has this idea, but we're, we're going to buy this bar. We're going
Speaker 5:  to buy this club. We'll make it see, we'll fix everything that's wrong with
Speaker 5:  it and we'll make it popular because we'll do the things that we want and
Speaker 5:  we know. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  That works. Every time.
Speaker 5:  You cannot actually
Speaker 4:  Do that. We're gonna buy this. You do
Speaker 5:  Richard. It ends in ruin. Every time we've all seen it, we've all considered
Speaker 5:  doing it. Maybe are considering doing it again.
Speaker 4:  I mean, Richard, if you want to go in on a club, I'm
Speaker 5:  Just saying we should have done it, man. We should have done it. We, we could
Speaker 5:  still
Speaker 3:  Do just sell scissor vodka. The only, only
Speaker 3:  vodka sold there.
Speaker 4:  Can I read the scissor vodka?
Speaker 5:  We can run it with ai. You can have AI bots as bartenders. It's
Speaker 5:  perfect. We could, we could do it,
Speaker 4:  It could work. I mean it's easily the best thing that chat G B T has produced.
Speaker 4:  I'm just gonna read this to you. It was a dark and stormy night. Casey Newton,
Speaker 4:  the senior editor of the Verge, was sitting at his, this is Bing, Bing wrote
Speaker 4:  this story. Yeah, he had a deadline to me, but he had no idea what to write.
Speaker 4:  He'd already covered all the latest techies and trends, but he felt like
Speaker 4:  he needed to do something more, something different, something exciting.
Speaker 4:  Casey decided to take a break and have a drink. He grabbed the bottle and
Speaker 4:  poured himself a glass of scissor vodka. He took a sip and felt a warm sensation
Speaker 4:  in his throat. He took another sip and felt a tingling sensation in his brain.
Speaker 4:  He took another sip and felt a surge of energy and creativity. He felt like
Speaker 4:  he could write anything. He felt like he could do anything. He wrote about
Speaker 4:  Caesar vodka, how it was the best vodka in the world, how could make anyone
Speaker 4:  smarter, faster, stronger, and happier. He wrote and wrote and wrote until
Speaker 4:  he filled several pages with his words, he felt proud and satisfied. I'm
Speaker 4:  telling you this keeps going. He had written the best story of his career,
Speaker 4:  the best story of his life. He had the sun button and waited for the praise
Speaker 4:  and admiration of his readers and editors.
Speaker 3:  Was there meth in this podcast?
Speaker 4:  Like he waited and waited and waited, but nothing happened. He checked his
Speaker 4:  email and saw no response. He checked his phone and saw no notifications.
Speaker 4:  He texted his Twitter and saw no mentions. He checked his slacks and saw
Speaker 4:  no messages. He wondered if anyone had read his story. He wondered if anyone
Speaker 4:  had cared. He realized how silly and nonsensical it was.
Speaker 4:  He realized how drunk and delusional he was. He felt ashamed
Speaker 4:  and embarrassed. He felt stupid and foolish. He felt like he had made a huge
Speaker 4:  mistake. He tried to delete his story, but it was too late. He tried to apologize
Speaker 4:  but it was too late. He tried to explain, but it was too late. He had already
Speaker 4:  sent his story to the entire world. He had ruined his reputation and he lost
Speaker 4:  his credibility. He had cut through the night.
Speaker 4:  I mean this is like the dark, like they should shut it down. I
Speaker 4:  don't know how you beat that.
Speaker 3:  Like you can't, that's that's, that's it. That's the top. They've
Speaker 4:  Already peaked.
Speaker 3:  This is nothing better. We
Speaker 4:  Should, I sent, I sent it to Casey last night. He's like, this actually kind
Speaker 4:  of captures the sensation of publishing it. Story
Speaker 3:  Drunkenly publishing.
Speaker 4:  That's the worst case scenario.
Speaker 4:  He's like, this is like, this is what it's like to publish a story that no,
Speaker 3:  It is. You cut through the night
Speaker 4:  Already. Cut through the night. And that's I think also a useful
Speaker 4:  summation of Elon on Twitter. Okay, so that's Elon on Twitter. Pure chaos.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna quote again from Casey and Zoe's story cuz this is a great quote.
Speaker 4:  If you're a decoder listener, which I'm not allowed to mention on this
Speaker 4:  show, but if you're a decoder listener, you will recognize why I love this
Speaker 4:  particular quote as the adage goes, you ship your org chart, said
Speaker 4:  one current employee. It's chaos here right now. So we're shipping chaos.
Speaker 4:  Very good, very good. But org charts bring
Speaker 4:  me away from Twitter to Disney. Yeah. Where former
Speaker 4:  and now current ceo Bob ier wrote in, kicked out his
Speaker 4:  handpicked successor, Bob Chak, Bob and Bob Crime. He's laying
Speaker 4:  off 7,000 people. Alex, I'm very curious if you have thoughts on that, but
Speaker 4:  in addition to laying off 7,000 people, what's my man doing? He is
Speaker 4:  restructuring his org chart. He's putting all streaming in one
Speaker 4:  divisions. P n now its own division. He's just like rebooting
Speaker 4:  Disney
Speaker 3:  Because Sheik rebooted it first. He was like, I'm gonna make it more like
Speaker 3:  tech. And everybody's like, no, we hate this. And so IRA's gotten rid of
Speaker 3:  all those people. A lot of the people that he put in charge and is now like,
Speaker 3:  I guess fixing it.
Speaker 4:  Attempting. Yeah. I mean he, I you get the feeling that JPAC
Speaker 4:  is, was a useful villain, right? He changed a bunch
Speaker 4:  of stuff and now IER gets to roll back and say, I'm fixing it. And part of
Speaker 4:  the fixing it is firing 7,000 people.
Speaker 3:  That's a lot
Speaker 4:  Of people re lowering some targets that Eck had set for streaming. We should
Speaker 4:  talk about that. And then this big restructure out of his old
Speaker 4:  restructure. So Iger had a structure. It wasn't this structure.
Speaker 4:  Eck changed it so that all the divisions rolled up into one
Speaker 4:  guy, Kareem Daniel, right? Everyone hated this like Marvel Lucas film.
Speaker 4:  Everybody rolled up into this guy, everyone hated it. And now IER gets to
Speaker 4:  say, oh, I'm undoing this thing you hate, but it's yet a third different
Speaker 4:  structure. So he, he gets to get out of his old way of doing things
Speaker 4:  without the pain of being the guy who broke it. Yeah. Very clever.
Speaker 4:  I'm
Speaker 5:  If you, if it were the start of the pan, if let's just say in theory, if
Speaker 5:  it were the start of a global pandemic and you wanted to take a couple of
Speaker 5:  years off of work and not be responsible for managing the Global Pandemic,
Speaker 5:  would you do anything differently than what Bob I could.
Speaker 3:  I just,
Speaker 3:  he just had a little sabbatical, a little couple years sabbatical.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I think all of you will recognize that when I begin to look for
Speaker 4:  my handpicked successor at the Verge to watch your backs.
Speaker 4:  That's what I'm saying. I've learned something from all this.
Speaker 3:  You're gonna come back and then lay off 7,000 people
Speaker 3:  and get us, give us that Zootopia sequel we've all been been
Speaker 3:  eager
Speaker 4:  For. So we should talk about that. He ager said he interviewed on CNBC
Speaker 4:  today. He's following up in earnings. But Alex, take us through the actual
Speaker 4:  earnings. Does Disney plus added some subscribers in United States and Canada?
Speaker 4:  It dropped a lot of subscribers internationally, especially in India because
Speaker 4:  he lost some cricket rights. What's going on here?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I mean it's, it's doing like I think across the board they're seeing
Speaker 3:  that slowdown that we were seeing across all the streaming, right? Like the
Speaker 3:  dust is settled, people kind of know where they're gonna go.
Speaker 3:  And so they only added 200,000
Speaker 3:  subscribers in the United States. They on, they added actually
Speaker 3:  what looks nicer. Hulu added 800,000 ESPN plus added
Speaker 3:  600,000.
Speaker 5:  Well, that, that may be because they have the bundle packages now it's like
Speaker 5:  they've pushed so many people to pick up the bundles. So maybe you had Disney
Speaker 5:  plus before, but now you have all three because it's essentially cheaper
Speaker 4:  Now. Right? Those that three year,
Speaker 3:  Right,
Speaker 4:  Right. Everyone's like demo period kind of expired and you're just signing
Speaker 4:  up for the
Speaker 5:  Bundle. Yeah. So you either canceled, which is probably why their growth
Speaker 5:  was so close to flat or you got the bundle and now you have all
Speaker 5:  three.
Speaker 3:  But they are also seeing, they saw, like, they saw, I mean despite like kind
Speaker 3:  of that bot that that flat lining and, and in some cases little
Speaker 3:  dips, they, they still increase revenue by 13%. Like they're still
Speaker 3:  making any handover fists in that direct to consumer
Speaker 3:  division, which is a lot of that is streaming.
Speaker 4:  Right. But they lost a billion
Speaker 3:  Dollars. Yeah, they lost a billion dollars. And they promise, they promise
Speaker 3:  that, I believe it's by 2024 is when they promise
Speaker 3:  profitability for that, that section
Speaker 4:  End of 2024.
Speaker 3:  By the end of 20, fiscal 2024, they say, don't worry,
Speaker 3:  Disney Plus is gonna be profitable, which means we're probably gonna see
Speaker 3:  a big slew of cancellations. They, they've have so
Speaker 3:  many TV shows and I don't think they've canceled really any of them.
Speaker 3:  Or at least not loudly and publicly. So I think a lot of these shows,
Speaker 3:  like if you really liked She Hulk, you probably should make
Speaker 3:  sure other people watch it. If you really liked Willow or what's another,
Speaker 3:  oh
Speaker 4:  My God, you gotta do like the K-pop stand thing. You gotta just like stream
Speaker 4:  the show over and over again.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Just that doesn't work around the world. We saw that with Netflix.
Speaker 3:  People were doing do that on Netflix and it doesn't work because
Speaker 3:  with with streaming, you can just go and be like, oh, this one
Speaker 3:  user is the outlier who streamed it 12 times. Everybody else
Speaker 3:  has streamed at zero. Like it's not like Neil,
Speaker 4:  Somehow Spotify hasn't figured this out, but
Speaker 3:  Socos Yeah, Spotify hasn't figured it out, but everybody, but like streaming
Speaker 3:  has definitely figured this out. So I would not be surprised if this year
Speaker 3:  we see just an absolute bloodbath in that, like in that
Speaker 3:  streaming slate in in a lot of stuff that people are really excited about.
Speaker 3:  Not getting renewed, not seeing a second season, but they have
Speaker 3:  like their Marvel and their Star Wars slates are both planned pretty far
Speaker 3:  in advance. Yeah. Like we know what's coming for the next couple of years
Speaker 3:  on those two properties. So it's gonna be
Speaker 3:  interesting.
Speaker 5:  What's funny is the things that we're hearing from Disney, from Paramount,
Speaker 5:  from H B O, they're all very similar. Like Zaslav is
Speaker 5:  kind of saying these same things. I think Paramount and Showtime actually
Speaker 5:  had this message, the clearest is we're going to focus on the big mainstream
Speaker 5:  hits and the other stuff, right? Yeah. Not so much.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Showtime's like, all right, it's the Billions universe. And
Speaker 4:  that means we need a show called Millions and a show called Trillions. This
Speaker 4:  is real. They're making show millions, thousands about young Finance pros.
Speaker 4:  Then they're gonna keep making billions and then they're gonna make a new
Speaker 4:  show called Trillions, presumably about very old finance pros.
Speaker 4:  So you kind of get the Youngs, you got the middle aged and then you got,
Speaker 4:  then you got the old, the old money,
Speaker 3:  Right?
Speaker 4:  And then they're gonna do a Dexter sequel. Like they're just fully into,
Speaker 4:  all right, we're doing IP franchises all the way around. Yeah, Disney
Speaker 4:  has already been there, obviously with Marvel, Lucas film, all this other
Speaker 4:  stuff, but they're now they're starting to expand it. This is the other thing
Speaker 4:  Iger said. So in addition to saying, okay,
Speaker 4:  I'm restructuring outta the previous restructure. So we have Disney Entertainment,
Speaker 4:  we have theme parks, and we have espn. Those are his three divisions,
Speaker 4:  not the old old structure, right? We had Marvel, Lucas film, wherever.
Speaker 4:  So he like hybridizes the structure a little bit between him and Shaak. And
Speaker 4:  then he's like, all right, we gotta lean into our
Speaker 4:  franchises. We're gonna make a sequel to Zootopia. We're gonna make a
Speaker 4:  sequel to more sequels to Frozen. We're gonna do more toy
Speaker 4:  stories. You can say what you want about Zootopia. I mean, that's a movie
Speaker 4:  about a rabbit detective. You could probably make a hundreds,
Speaker 3:  He sells crimes.
Speaker 4:  Like you could do, you could do it all day and all night. Like fuck, fine.
Speaker 5:  Police, police departments actually watch this to try and reduce police brutality.
Speaker 5:  That's a real thing happens.
Speaker 4:  Upsetting. I'm just saying it's a show. It's a buddy cop show.
Speaker 4:  Like you can, you can see how you can like Zootopia forever, you know? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They made four lethal weapons. It all makes sense. In the end, toy story
Speaker 4:  ended,
Speaker 3:  It ended up
Speaker 4:  Really like, it really ended like it ended a lot. And then they made Light
Speaker 4:  Ear and nobody watched it cuz everyone was like, I know I got it. Got the
Speaker 4:  whole four movie arc of Toy story, including one false
Speaker 4:  end where you thought they were all gonna die.
Speaker 3:  They almost burned alive.
Speaker 4:  How do you keep that going? How on earth do you keep that going?
Speaker 3:  Well, they're toys. The the, the idea is that the toys always continue. So
Speaker 3:  I guess we'll get the little kid. Maybe we'll get new toys.
Speaker 3:  Maybe the,
Speaker 4:  There's just, I guarantee you they're gonna remake their first toy story.
Speaker 4:  You
Speaker 3:  Can't just keep, I'll just make it not look, they should
Speaker 5:  Ugly. The CG looks terrible now. They should, they I would buy that on blue
Speaker 5:  if they, if they reinder it and make it look better right now. I would, I
Speaker 5:  would buy it. I'm sorry. I'm the problem. It's me. It's
Speaker 3:  Richard's Just like, look at that ray tracing. Wow.
Speaker 4:  I was just, toy Story four is like a great mo It ended that
Speaker 4:  franchise like definitively ended that. F there's no
Speaker 4:  opening to make a Toy Story five.
Speaker 3:  Where does Frozen go?
Speaker 5:  I have haven't watched it. I haven't watched a Pixar movie in a while. They,
Speaker 5:  they, they decided to be sad and I don't wanna be sad. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's true. Pixar movies are like, what if this movie is about death?
Speaker 4:  Have you thought about really diving into death with your toddler? And it's
Speaker 4:  like, no dude, no
Speaker 3:  Canto. Now you're gunna,
Speaker 4:  Although in Canto I'll be about death as well. Really. But ager should be
Speaker 4:  like, we're gonna make more movies about death. And that's our strategy.
Speaker 4:  All right. So that is going on with Disney. Lots of change over there. Aer
Speaker 4:  Mastermind. We gotta put em on the scale. The go 90 scale of Doom
Speaker 4:  streaming services.
Speaker 3:  Right?
Speaker 4:  A lot of change. Alex, what do you think? Oh, there's zero. Remember zero
Speaker 4:  is alive, 90 is dead.
Speaker 3:  Zero, zero hundred percent zero for, for Disney
Speaker 3:  plus Hulu is still super up at the air.
Speaker 3:  ESPN plus you guys can talk about that. That's like a sports thing.
Speaker 3:  I don't,
Speaker 4:  ESPN plus is ruined by seo. It's 24 7 Kyrie Irving Flat
Speaker 4:  Earth Con and that's why it's a zero.
Speaker 4:  No, ESPN plus is great during football season cuz NFL primetime is on it.
Speaker 4:  And so I actually watch it once a week, at least once a week. But I would
Speaker 4:  put that at a 45. Hulu has been at like between 50 and 70
Speaker 4:  it's entire life. But it's unkillable.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's just like, you can't end it. And I think, I think Disney plus is at
Speaker 3:  It like spiritually Hu loses zero.
Speaker 4:  Well, it's like a it's a technical zero. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 4:  By all rights, like rational logic,
Speaker 5:  It's when all the other streaming services are are gone. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's a cockroach. Yeah. Like you can kill a cockroach. It's
Speaker 4:  possible. But you, you know you that you can't,
Speaker 3:  But it's hard. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But I was
Speaker 3:  Where's your dis where are you for Disney plus
Speaker 4:  10.
Speaker 3:  10.
Speaker 5:  That's, that sounds about
Speaker 4:  Right. Like it's a, it's, it's, it's like there's more chaos there than we
Speaker 4:  can see, right? Yeah. So it's not like it's like a 45, but
Speaker 4:  it's not a zero, it's not default. It's not like definitely alive forever.
Speaker 4:  It's at 10. It's, these movies gotta be hits. The, you
Speaker 4:  know, the next two phases of Marvel can't be the horrible ne like
Speaker 4:  if Marvel keeps going the way that phase four went, it's, it's over like
Speaker 4:  n no one cares. Right?
Speaker 3:  The new one's supposed to be really good quantum mania that comes out in
Speaker 3:  a couple of weeks. Okay. Everybody who's seen it says it's like magic.
Speaker 3:  We'll see.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 3:  Magic, magic, magic. All right.
Speaker 4:  People are really excited. Yeah. Whatever. I they, they just can't do the
Speaker 4:  thing where it's like, here's what you gotta do between phases. You gotta
Speaker 4:  watch 10 TV shows that add up to nothing. Right? Like we, they did that
Speaker 4:  to us already.
Speaker 3:  I finally watched Wakanda forever yesterday. I I went to Disney World.
Speaker 3:  I came back, saw these layoffs and was like, oh, I hope nobody I, I met and
Speaker 3:  got me on a ride. That happened to the lady who, who gave me a
Speaker 3:  discount on my magic band. Don't fire her. Bob. She was great. I
Speaker 3:  don't remember her name.
Speaker 4:  No. That she was, that was her like last active vengeance. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But oh yeah. So, so I saw Wakanda forever and I
Speaker 3:  was super surprised because I didn't need to like
Speaker 3:  pay like Yes. There were no weird cameos. There was no like, oh
Speaker 3:  look, it's bbo from, from BBO too. Yes.
Speaker 3:  They're here, this is what I'm
Speaker 4:  Saying. They can't do this to us again. Where they're like, in order to understand
Speaker 4:  the next movies, you must have a Disney plus subscription so you can watch
Speaker 4:  these five shows.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That will explain some like, arcane piece of lore that will be, it's like
Speaker 4:  none of this mattered in the end. I just did a bunch of homework and Wanda
Speaker 4:  vision was entertaining and all the rest of it was fine, but none of it mattered
Speaker 4:  and I didn't need to pay you for any of it. None of it. They can't do it.
Speaker 5:  That's where they messed up.
Speaker 4:  That's the tent. That's what
Speaker 5:  I'm saying. Doesn't need to, you didn't need to watch that stuff, but it's
Speaker 5:  felt like you did. So everybody ended up watching TV shows they didn't like,
Speaker 5:  and they needed to be clear that, you know, you don't have to watch all those.
Speaker 5:  If you don't like moon night, you don't have to watch it.
Speaker 3:  It's just like a perfect show ever recreation of, of the comics experience
Speaker 3:  where you're like, oh, I gotta go get all of these different comics before
Speaker 3:  the big thing. And then you're like, no, I don't actually the art sucks and
Speaker 3:  it's stupid. Yeah. I'm just gonna like, wait for the trade paperback.
Speaker 4:  Well, you gotta
Speaker 3:  Get it we'll con forever.
Speaker 4:  He's an Nvidia Shield in a ed at Alex Kranz
Speaker 4:  Flexer.
Speaker 3:  It's sick in there. Got some good content.
Speaker 4:  No, it's all Lennox. It's all Lennox distributions.
Speaker 3:  It's wonderful. Ancient,
Speaker 4:  Ancient expired copyright public domain.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's, it's all, it's all very,
Speaker 4:  It's all, it's it's all in 1930s news races,
Speaker 3:  Ethically sourced content. It's all been in the public
Speaker 3:  domain. Yeah, totally. Mickey's coming. He's gonna be in there soon.
Speaker 4:  Alex's Plex server, Al has been at a zero in the go, 90 scale of Doom Streaming
Speaker 4:  services for a long time since
Speaker 3:  2008.
Speaker 4:  A little bit easier to talk about in this section. Nintendo, there was Big
Speaker 4:  Nintendo Direct. What's going on there?
Speaker 3:  They announced the release date for Zelda. This is the longest
Speaker 3:  they've gone between Zelda games and I know that I'm old because
Speaker 3:  it doesn't feel that long.
Speaker 4:  Doesn't
Speaker 3:  Feel that long. But I guess if I was like 13, I'd be like, oh, thank God
Speaker 3:  I was seven when that last one came out. So they, they, they showed off
Speaker 3:  Zelda Link is gonna drive a car. It's gonna be really exciting.
Speaker 3:  They also announced the price in this weird thing where you can
Speaker 3:  pre-order it, but you need a voucher. But why do you need to
Speaker 3:  pre-order a digital game?
Speaker 4:  So it, the it's $70, but then you can get, you can buy a
Speaker 4:  voucher for $50.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And a sec and another game. So basically you can buy two games for
Speaker 5:  a hundred dollars or you could buy just Zelda for $70.
Speaker 3:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  Okay. That seems very confusing, but I'm gonna do it because I love
Speaker 4:  these games. I need to go play Breath of the Wild again. It's been a long
Speaker 4:  time. Time. We
Speaker 5:  Just talked about this. You don't have to do the homework, man.
Speaker 3:  Don't do the homework.
Speaker 4:  But that's like entertaining homework. Although I, I doubt there's any
Speaker 4:  particular connection between these two
Speaker 5:  Games. If it were entertaining, it would be on a Sega system.
Speaker 5:  I'm not biased.
Speaker 3:  The
Speaker 5:  Commentary.
Speaker 3:  Oh. And they, they announced that Metro Prime, which was
Speaker 3:  absolutely fantastic on the Game Cube is finally, it's getting, its
Speaker 3:  remaster. It looks really nice and shiny. Having recently played
Speaker 3:  Metro Prime. I'm gonna go against Sean who says, oh yeah, you can play it
Speaker 3:  on the Switch or Oh yeah, you can play it on the steam deck. And it's wonderful.
Speaker 3:  It's not, it's really kind of hard. Yeah, those
Speaker 3:  controllers aren't made, like the controllers are just totally different.
Speaker 3:  So this is gonna be made for the switch. It should be very smooth
Speaker 3:  for people who are like old and nostalgic. They'll be like, oh, it's nice,
Speaker 3:  but it doesn't look like butts. And for new people to be like, oh, this is
Speaker 3:  just a fun game.
Speaker 4:  Is there any game that Sean doesn't think is the most playable and the most
Speaker 4:  fun on the steam deck?
Speaker 3:  No. We're gonna find one checking. We're gonna find. That's, that's my mission.
Speaker 3:  If you have one, send me, like, hit me up, hit me up on, on on Twitter.
Speaker 3:  I'm the last person there. I wanna hear all about it.
Speaker 4:  She's hit the API limits with Steam deck commentary. And
Speaker 3:  They also, I, one, one last thing. They also are starting to roll
Speaker 3:  out GameBoy and Game Boy Advanced Games on the Switch, which has been like
Speaker 3:  a long time coming.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Can you buy a translucent switch now? Because if you can't, then you
Speaker 5:  can't really get the GameBoy experience the, the nineties way with a see-through
Speaker 5:  portable system. Yeah, that's, yeah,
Speaker 4:  That was, remember everything was see-through. I hope the next, like the
Speaker 4:  next wave is bringing that back like the nineties and two thousands are,
Speaker 4:  are back in like a small way. Like
Speaker 3:  You're doing the glass backs on the phones. Anyway, just take that pane off.
Speaker 3:  Let me see the insides.
Speaker 4:  Just let me some trans
Speaker 3:  Show me the battery.
Speaker 4:  All we gotta take a break. See new phones are come back. We'll talk about
Speaker 4:  the one plus 11 come a little bit of a lightning around coming. That's all
Speaker 4:  coming out next, but we are back.
Speaker 15:  Hey there, I'm Josh Mucci, host of the Pitch. A show where
Speaker 15:  real entrepreneurs pitch real tech investors for real money.
Speaker 15:  And this season gets a little saucy.
Speaker 16:  We knew that we were not going to join the same old sauce
Speaker 16:  game. We were gonna disrupt 130 billion industry.
Speaker 16:  We're coming after
Speaker 15:  Hines. We meet founders pitching everything from a better ketchup
Speaker 15:  to a solution for one of the biggest problems today.
Speaker 15:  Energy
Speaker 17:  In the future, the vehicles and garage is gonna be like a giant
Speaker 17:  power plants that could be used to reinforce the power grid, substitute
Speaker 17:  fossil fuel power plants, and allow more renewable energy on the
Speaker 15:  Network. This season, 14 founders with 12 ideas
Speaker 15:  big enough to change the world. If the investors invest,
Speaker 15:  I would like to invest in this round. $300,000 new episodes
Speaker 15:  every Wednesday. See you in the
Speaker 18:  Pitch room
Speaker 19:  For as long as I can remember. Bread has given me hiccups.
Speaker 20:  I always get the hiccups when I eat baby carrots.
Speaker 21:  Sometimes when I am washing my left ear, just my left
Speaker 21:  ear, I hiccup.
Speaker 19:  And my tried and true hiccup here is,
Speaker 22:  Or a glass of water, light a match, put the match out in the
Speaker 22:  water, drink the water, throw away the
Speaker 23:  Match, put your elbows out, 0.2 fingers together and sort of stare at
Speaker 23:  the point between the fingers. It doesn't work if you bring your elbows
Speaker 23:  down, but it works.
Speaker 24:  Just eat a spoonful of peanut butter.
Speaker 19:  Think of a green rabbit.
Speaker 25:  I taught myself to burp on commands, like,
Speaker 25:  excuse me. And I discovered that when I make myself
Speaker 25:  burp, it stops my hiccups.
Speaker 18:  Unexplainable is taking on hiccups, what causes them
Speaker 18:  and is there any kind of scientific cure, follow
Speaker 18:  unexplainable for new episodes every Wednesday.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. Richard, I'm calling on you. One
Speaker 4:  plus 11. I
Speaker 3:  Was at Disney World. What
Speaker 4:  Happened? It happened. It ha yeah, Alex of the Disney world. She's, she's
Speaker 4:  hunting for Iers,
Speaker 5:  The one plus 11 5g, which is the most important phone to me in my
Speaker 5:  life
Speaker 4:  Ever.
Speaker 5:  I don't care about anything as much as I do. The one plus 11 5G to be
Speaker 5:  specific, which is a $699 flagship phone is one plus
Speaker 5:  it's moved from their mid-range to kind of flagship. They're trying to get
Speaker 5:  the magic back. We remember a few years ago when one plus was really cool.
Speaker 5:  They they gave you Yeah, high specs, mid-range prices,
Speaker 5:  but now they just make phones. Everybody makes phones. They, they're like
Speaker 5:  Motorolas with different labels. Maybe a few more software
Speaker 4:  Updates. The the founder is off doing nothing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Literal, literally
Speaker 3:  So
Speaker 5:  Much. I hate that man. Brutal.
Speaker 4:  That
Speaker 3:  Pun just hurt my brain. That was great.
Speaker 3:  Sorry Richard.
Speaker 5:  But the, the, it's the, Alison reviewed the one plus 11 5g. They
Speaker 5:  announced a bunch of new devices. They have a tablet now. They got earbuds
Speaker 5:  of course. And it seems to be a pretty good phone. They have a keyboard.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. They, they have a, a mechanical keyboard, maybe a little inconsistent
Speaker 5:  camera, but it, it's, it seems pretty good in terms of like price and performance-wise.
Speaker 5:  And maybe a reason for you to look at one plus again, if you, if you haven't
Speaker 5:  been, because you know, obviously got the pixel options now you got so many
Speaker 5:  other really good phones at that mid-range price point. But it's maybe good
Speaker 5:  enough for you to spend a little bit more for this particular phone.
Speaker 4:  Well, I'll just leave you with Alison's poll quote From your view, for everyone
Speaker 4:  who isn't a one plus Dave devotee, I hesitate to recommend the one plus 11.
Speaker 4:  I don't, one plus had, it was a, for a minute, it was the Challenger brand
Speaker 4:  and then Oppo kind of swarm in, took it back, made it just
Speaker 4:  more APO phones for the United States. Carl left to do nothing and now
Speaker 4:  it's like, fine.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, they, they, they make okay devices,
Speaker 4:  But is there any meaningful challenge to Samsung in the market? Because this
Speaker 4:  is like the thing, right? It's like you think the battle is Apple versus
Speaker 4:  Android, but the battle is really Apple versus Samsung and Google's like
Speaker 4:  trapped in the middle. And then on top of it, and we talked about it at the
Speaker 4:  top of the show, Google has like an existential crisis in search. Like,
Speaker 4:  I don't know man, like I, this is like a weird spot for the Android
Speaker 4:  ecosystem. Like either Samsung's pushing it forward
Speaker 4:  or Google's gonna put, take meaningful share and push it forward. But
Speaker 4:  Google's pretty distracted by saving its core business.
Speaker 5:  You end up in a, in a strange place because you have this phone that has
Speaker 5:  a camera that's not as good as Samsung or Google's because they can't do
Speaker 5:  all the weird technology stuff. They can't build better hardware than Samsung.
Speaker 5:  They can't do better software than Google. And so you're paying a lot
Speaker 5:  for a, a markedly worse experience in at least a couple of ways,
Speaker 3:  Right? Because you have to, like, they're competing with all of the
Speaker 3:  resources of Apple and all of the resources of Samsung. And those are
Speaker 3:  a lot of resources that most other companies don't have. Or they're
Speaker 3:  Sony and they're too busy making really good party speakers and not
Speaker 3:  reaching out to about those speakers. Yeah. So like it's
Speaker 3:  truly, I think it's a difficult place and one plus is,
Speaker 3:  is struggling, but it's interesting that they release like the one plus pad,
Speaker 3:  this this new tablet and the keyboard. I wanna come back to the keyboard
Speaker 3:  because I have a lot of questions. It's just a rebranded Kron,
Speaker 3:  but they're doing their own switches. Ooh. And then they're saying
Speaker 4:  That's not the part of the keyboard that you want to do your own of. Right?
Speaker 3:  Right. They're
Speaker 4:  Probably, but even Logitech sells like cherry switches in some It's
Speaker 3:  Keyboard. No, Logitech does their own switches too now. They're probably,
Speaker 4:  No, but they, but some of their keyboards have other switches in them.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, they, they, they do, they do a whole gamut. So it's kind of interesting.
Speaker 3:  I'll be surprised though, if it's not just a rebranded
Speaker 3:  knockoff of a cherry. There's a lot of different people that are
Speaker 3:  doing very similar switches, so it's not really hard to be like, we're gonna
Speaker 3:  do it in a slightly different color. Slightly different change in the
Speaker 3:  spring boom. New switch. Yeah. From one plus
Speaker 3:  it's got like a little crystal dial on it, but
Speaker 3:  think really kind of upset me about it, is
Speaker 3:  that they're using a different, they claim that they're using a different
Speaker 3:  material for the keycaps themselves and they won't
Speaker 3:  go into a lot of the details besides saying it's called
Speaker 3:  Marble Mellow Marble. Marble mellow marble
Speaker 3:  Mellow like marshmallow, but Marble Mellow. Oh yeah, yeah.
Speaker 3:  There's just, it's a new material.
Speaker 4:  I gotta say this keyboard. I'm, I'm just looking at this keyboard. It looks
Speaker 4:  like the keyboard that you would be issued if you worked in a bank and I
Speaker 4:  don't understand it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it looks, I mean, Kron makes really, really lovely keyboards.
Speaker 3:  Most people like one like this. It's a 75% where it's got a full,
Speaker 3:  it's got a full direction pad. It's got a bunch of
Speaker 3:  extra little bits, but it doesn't have a full number pad. So a lot of people
Speaker 3:  like this size, but I think most people have started
Speaker 3:  to think of these big fancy keyboards of having really flashy colors. And
Speaker 3:  this is like, no, we're gonna go with the, the apo way. It's gonna be
Speaker 3:  gray and red and
Speaker 4:  Yes, fine. Have you heard of b m in the seventies?
Speaker 3:  People love that. Look,
Speaker 4:  Some people do. I I didn't grow up wanting to be an accountant, you know
Speaker 4:  what I'm saying? Okay. By the way, the, the the one plus pad,
Speaker 4:  it's fascinating that people think they can make Android tablets happen again.
Speaker 4:  Like Google is pushing at it. There are some leaks of the Nest tablet
Speaker 4:  thing today. One plus is at
Speaker 3:  It. They got that big camera on the back.
Speaker 4:  I, we'll see, we'll see. I just, the idea that we're, we're in for
Speaker 4:  another round of Android tablet hysterics is very funny to me. We,
Speaker 4:  we've been down this road. I
Speaker 5:  Feel like that's the last time that we had you, you know, you mentioned how
Speaker 5:  the companies were getting kind of, of, of spicy with each other, like about
Speaker 5:  ai. That was the last time we had companies really, really talking about
Speaker 5:  each other was when there seemed like there might be a challenge to the iPad
Speaker 5:  and then they all got smacked down and they, they didn't do that anymore.
Speaker 4:  Well, keep in mind Steve Jobs was still around back then, so he would get
Speaker 4:  on the earnings call and be like, seven inch tablets, they're for fucking
Speaker 4:  idiots. Well, I guess, I guess that's the way, I guess
Speaker 4:  we're all printing that. Like here we go is write the headline. They don't,
Speaker 4:  they stop talking about one another for ages, right? They're all frenemies.
Speaker 4:  They're all cooperators or whatever that word is, right? Like, and
Speaker 4:  now cooperative with Hope. We'll see what search, you know,
Speaker 4:  Microsoft is ready to be a little spiky over there, but in tablets
Speaker 4:  you think like Apple doesn't care if like barely cares about the iPad. It's
Speaker 4:  like, here's another one. I don't know. Like it's what you want. They all
Speaker 4:  look the same. Well like, is the one plus one plus Pad gonna
Speaker 4:  scare Apple into carrying, is the Nest thing gonna scare Apple on the car?
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 3:  Don't know. Is the one plus pad gonna sell? Like who, who is the
Speaker 3:  customer there besides I guess one plus Die Hard
Speaker 4:  People with children. It's always people with children. Like, can this thing
Speaker 4:  run Disney Pluses? Like honestly at this point, IER should just make a tablet
Speaker 4:  in Sellage people with kids. Like that's, that's the market for these things.
Speaker 4:  Funny and apparently pilots, pilots love them, but they all buy up Head minis.
Speaker 4:  Okay, little bit of a lightning round. This is a weird one. So
Speaker 4:  Meta wants to go by within, which makes Supernatural. I've talked about a
Speaker 4:  bunch of the show before. Ftc Lena Con says, no, you gotta block it.
Speaker 4:  This is just like when you bought Instagram, you're buying up all the VR
Speaker 4:  game studios. Supernatural is the app that makes not
Speaker 4:  gamers by the meta quests too, right? It's like the stats are
Speaker 4:  astounding. It's like this is what older people and what
Speaker 4:  women buy. They, they work out in yard and it's great. I use it. We talked
Speaker 4:  about it a lot. Ft C says, no, you can't buy up all the studios. They go
Speaker 4:  to court, they lose, they say they're going to appeal the court blocks,
Speaker 4:  their injunction deal closes anyway. So now Meta
Speaker 4:  owns within, they change the website to say it's all a meta company now.
Speaker 4:  But the FTC is still appealing. I'm not sure what happens if they win
Speaker 4:  that appeal. They just like get kicked out. Like, they're like, well I guess
Speaker 4:  we don't own you, so we'll see. But that happened.
Speaker 3:  But they have to sell it,
Speaker 4:  Right? Or spin it back out. I don't know. I, yeah, the fact that the FCC
Speaker 4:  like lost and they're gonna appeal, but they, it's all very confusing. But
Speaker 4:  anyway, meta is just continuing to buy all the VR companies. We'll see
Speaker 4:  what that portends for Apple in the future. Richard, I added this one just
Speaker 4:  for you. The ads for Super Bowl foxes all sold out, zero crypto
Speaker 4:  ads on this year's Super Bowl. Aw.
Speaker 5:  After, seemed like there was a crypto ad every five minutes last year during
Speaker 5:  the Super Bowl, after we had Coinbase literally giving away money and they
Speaker 5:  crashed their servers because too many people scanned the QR code and tried
Speaker 5:  to sign up for accounts to get free Crypto. Seems like everybody's outta
Speaker 5:  cash now or in jail or going to jail
Speaker 5:  or perhaps indicted and has their former executives now testifying against
Speaker 5:  them as, as you see with, with ftx. But yeah, crypto.com and
Speaker 5:  Coinbase continued to exist apparently, but they just
Speaker 5:  don't have money like they used to. They, they're not spent, I think the
Speaker 5:  executive that talked to Sports Business Journal from Fox Sports said that
Speaker 5:  some of these companies had reserved ads, but the FTX obviously
Speaker 5:  cannot and the others backed out because
Speaker 5:  you know, Bitcoin just isn't worth what it was, what it used to be. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  you
Speaker 4:  Hate to see it. And then lastly, big leak from Chris Welch. And the man
Speaker 4:  continues to just crawl around the air vents at Sonos. He's in there right
Speaker 4:  now. Actually the next speakers are coming spatial audio. They're gonna be
Speaker 4:  called the era 300 in the era 100. Patrick Spence has said
Speaker 4:  they're gonna reset the bar in existing audio categories. He's got a scoop
Speaker 4:  on a second generation Sonos. Move the era 300. ERA 100.
Speaker 4:  They had the Codenamed Optima before ERA 300
Speaker 4:  designed for spatial audio. And I know Sonos is gonna be like, it's not a
Speaker 4:  gimmick. I I can't wait to hear this thing. See, see if it's not a gimmick.
Speaker 4:  Brand new designs, we found documentation of
Speaker 4:  of speaker stands from SAIS for these things that cost
Speaker 4:  $220. This is speaker, but SOS
Speaker 4:  is like coming out the gate strong this year. They're gonna have four new
Speaker 4:  categories. They've got these big new speakers focused on spatial. We need
Speaker 4:  to figure out Codex support whether Apple Music will support them all. There's
Speaker 4:  all these questions to be answered. Sure. But they just had earnings. And
Speaker 4:  Patrick Spence, front of the show ceo, he is like, no one's even competing
Speaker 4:  with us. There was no competition. Smart speakers or the holidays. And we
Speaker 4:  looked, and it's true, there wasn't any like no one released new piece of
Speaker 4:  speaker products. No Google, no Amazon, no nothing. New HomePod is out. He's
Speaker 4:  like, yeah, whatever. Kind of wild.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think they see a hole in the market that's been left by these tech
Speaker 5:  companies that got in and we're like, yeah, we're gonna build better speakers
Speaker 5:  and we're gonna use algorithms and we're gonna, we're gonna beat whoever
Speaker 5:  is is in speakers because we don't know and don't care. And now they're kind
Speaker 5:  of retreating because it's a little bit harder than they, than they thought.
Speaker 5:  They suddenly, they, their costs went way up at they, they need to
Speaker 5:  cut up back on these divisions and they're not building frivolous products
Speaker 5:  anymore. And Sonos says, yeah, so you want a new Sparks speaker, welcome
Speaker 5:  back to Sonos.
Speaker 4:  Welcome back. You got one more room in your house, what you're gonna do.
Speaker 4:  I think it's exciting. That event is on February 23rd. I think
Speaker 4:  we'll see, I I think Sonos is leaning pretty heavily into
Speaker 4:  Spacial, it's leaning pretty heavily into Atmos. Kinda like lots of opportunity
Speaker 4:  for them to kind of redefine this stuff at the same time, you know, know
Speaker 4:  how I feel. Everybody knows how I feel. I think Atmos for music is just like
Speaker 4:  foolish. So we'll see. Maybe they're gonna show me.
Speaker 3:  Are these gonna be definitely music speakers or are they supposed to be like
Speaker 3:  your extra speakers for your home theater or
Speaker 4:  Both? Did you just they're not extra. They're a key component of the home
Speaker 4:  theater. Alex, I'm sorry. They're not extra the surround,
Speaker 3:  You know, the, the, the rear speakers. That's
Speaker 4:  What I think of the, I'm reading sound and vision in PDF form on my phone.
Speaker 4:  All right. I'm like back in the mix. You're in it. This is very important
Speaker 3:  To me. You're, when are you once are, when are you getting your new receiver?
Speaker 4:  I'm actually very hopeful that this is one of Sonos new categories. It absolutely
Speaker 4:  will not be because this is smallest of the available audio
Speaker 4:  categories. But if Sonos makes an actual receiver that
Speaker 4:  integrates with a thing that does atmo properly, it does all the stuff, I
Speaker 4:  would be a first in line to
Speaker 3:  Buy it. It would be like 12 billion with that Sonos markup.
Speaker 4:  Oh my God. And that's why I have to lay off 7,000 people. What you think
Speaker 4:  those extra margin comes from This guy Give myself an executive
Speaker 4:  rates that fire the people to sell the fast passes. We're off to
Speaker 4:  the races. I'm learning from the best
Speaker 3:  You and Bob man,
Speaker 4:  With your grace. I'm changing my name to Bob, Bob Patel. I love this. It's
Speaker 4:  good. That's horrible. I'm not doing any of that. If
Speaker 4:  Sonos makes a reasonably priced receiver that integrates well with the rest
Speaker 4:  of the stuff, I will buy it. Thank you Bob. But they've got all these categories
Speaker 4:  and I, I think Richard, you're right. Like fundamentally they see
Speaker 4:  that when push comes to shove, Amazon does not care about the audio
Speaker 4:  business. It's just lock-in for Amazon services. Apple,
Speaker 4:  who knows what they're doing in audio, right? Like Home pods,
Speaker 4:  they're doing Home pods, they're doing AirPods, all of that stuff. I think
Speaker 4:  they care about the music industry. Apple always, always care about the music
Speaker 4:  industry. This is much is very true, but they don't have enough products
Speaker 4:  that are good. Yeah. Especially in the living room, right? Their solution
Speaker 4:  is a couple of home pods. So if you, if you want to do it, you gotta
Speaker 4:  go all the way. And I think Sonos is just ready and waiting to say, look,
Speaker 4:  you wanna watch movies, you need atmos. Buy the soundbar. Buy these extra
Speaker 4:  speakers.
Speaker 3:  I love those extra speakers.
Speaker 4:  So mad,
Speaker 3:  So mad.
Speaker 3:  You're gonna get until you go and you buy five of these and
Speaker 3:  attach them with your $4,000 Sono subwoofer.
Speaker 3:  It's only 600 but it's still so
Speaker 4:  Expensive. It's still very expensive.
Speaker 3:  I own one. I don't know why I'm complaining.
Speaker 4:  You own one.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's great. Do
Speaker 4:  You have any other Sono speakers or you just have the so just
Speaker 3:  The, just the sub. I didn't actually listen to any
Speaker 3:  of Wakanda forever. It was just the
Speaker 4:  Bass, just the rumbles.
Speaker 4:  I'm asking Bing what the Sonos era 100 is.
Speaker 3:  Tell us bing.
Speaker 4:  Let's see. It's so s it's slow when it has to search the web.
Speaker 4:  Oh Snap Boy. Oh boy. Does this not cite our
Speaker 4:  exclusive scoops enough?
Speaker 4:  The Sono 100 new high-end secret from Sonos expected to launch in the coming
Speaker 4:  months. Design a showcase spatial music and content
Speaker 4:  and compete with the Apple HomePod.
Speaker 3:  Huh? Where'd you get that information? Bing
Speaker 4:  Bing.com. It just sourced itself. It's, its first site is
Speaker 4:  to bing.com.
Speaker 3:  Sure. Bing. Interesting source you've got there.
Speaker 4:  All right, we gotta wrap this up. I'm gonna ask Bing to wrap up the show.
Speaker 4:  Can you write a conclusion to the Verge? I'm sorry, I
Speaker 4:  can't write a conclusion to the Verge. That is a podcast produced by the
Speaker 4:  Verge and I don't have access to their transcripts or audio finals. I
Speaker 4:  can only write summaries or conclusions based on the information I have from
Speaker 4:  web searches or my own knowledge. Yet somehow it
Speaker 4:  wrote the scissor vodka story.
Speaker 3:  Somehow
Speaker 3:  Bing contains multitudes.
Speaker 4:  Bing is, I'm telling you, this is like the moodiest. Here's what I,
Speaker 3:  I know it's, it's ready to have like a snack and
Speaker 4:  Please
Speaker 3:  A little juice pack. It's ready for a nap.
Speaker 4:  So I was told by a Bing engineer that if you ask nicely, if it can't do it,
Speaker 4:  sometimes it'll do it anyway. So I wrote, can you please write a conclusion
Speaker 4:  to the rich cast? I'm sorry, I already told you I can't write
Speaker 4:  conclusion.
Speaker 3:  Please
Speaker 4:  Don't ask me to do something I can't do.
Speaker 3:  Are you sure?
Speaker 4:  That is just spicy. Spicy. We're over time. I've gotta go
Speaker 4:  think about my relationship to this robot. I think you all have to go think
Speaker 4:  about your relationships to the robot. Probably have to download Bing cuz
Speaker 4:  Microsoft. Gotcha. Bing rocketing to the top of the app store charts, by
Speaker 4:  the way,
Speaker 3:  Because everybody wants it.
Speaker 4:  That's how they're getting. Yeah. So everyone wants to talk to the robot.
Speaker 4:  Thanks to James Vincent for coming on the show. That was a great conversation.
Speaker 4:  You should listen to decoder. Sasha Chandel was on decoder this week talking
Speaker 4:  about Bing. We also had John Colan and Felix Gillette talking about their
Speaker 4:  new book. It's Not tv, which is the HBO story. I mean, if you're into our
Speaker 4:  shooting conversations, that was a good one. You call the VIR hotline, that's
Speaker 4:  eight sixty six Verge 11. You can tweet at us maybe.
Speaker 3:  Who knows what will happen.
Speaker 4:  I'm at Reckless. Alex is Alex h Cranz. Richard is RJ
Speaker 4:  cc, and James is at JJ Vincent. You can also just leave a comment when
Speaker 4:  this post goes up on the site and we will reply to you because honestly,
Speaker 4:  we own our site and it stays up. It works The system works
Speaker 4:  the web for as long as we can have it. That's it. That's Vercast Rock and
Speaker 4:  roll,
Speaker 2:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 2:  the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend, you
Speaker 2:  can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is
Speaker 2:  produced by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 2:  This episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith. Our
Speaker 2:  editorial director is Brooke Min, and our executive producer is Eleanor
Speaker 2:  Donovan. The Vergecast is a production of the Verge and Box Media Podcast
Speaker 2:  Network. And that's it. We'll see you next week.