# Transcript
ID: 37c144d4-4928-4c77-bf35-2b618f211b6d
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Amazon, Google, and crypto are on trial
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/9031817360811009889/-1995165788160250833/s93290-US-4277s-1696404857.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of The Sherman Antitrust Act of 1890:
01:43 - The Verge’s David Pierce chats with policy editor Adi Robertson and reporter Makena Kelly about US v. Google, and what we’ve learned so far. They also talk about the FTC’s lawsuit against Amazon, which could be the next big tech trial.
US v. Google antitrust trial: updates
Amazon reportedly used a secret algorithm to jack up prices
Satya Nadella tells a court that Bing is worse than Google — and Apple could fix it
Why the US is suing Amazon
28:46 - Later, senior correspondent Liz Lopatto joins the show to preview the trial of Sam Bankman-Fried, the former CEO of FTX.
FTX’s Sam Bankman-Fried is on trial for fraud and conspiracy
52:36 - Keep listening for this week’s Vergecast hotline question with Alex Cranz.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (7 ads detected)
Speaker 1:  Welcome
Speaker 2:  To The Vergecast at the flagship podcast of the Sherman Antitrust Act of
Speaker 2:  1890. I'm your friend David Pierce, and I am currently in the hallway outside
Speaker 2:  of Courtroom 10 at the e Barrett Prettyman United States Courthouse
Speaker 2:  in Washington DC Inside Courtroom 10 is where U S V Google,
Speaker 2:  one of the most important tech trials in the last two decades and probably
Speaker 2:  the biggest Antitrust trial since the Microsoft trial in the late nineties
Speaker 2:  is currently going on. I'm here in the building today because Satya Nadella,
Speaker 2:  the C E O of Microsoft is taking the stand to talk about search engines,
Speaker 2:  Bing ai, apple Chat, G P T, and who
Speaker 2:  knows what else. There's a lot to talk to that guy about. This trial has
Speaker 2:  been weird and complex and important and today should be more of the
Speaker 2:  same and that actually is a big part of what we're gonna talk about on the
Speaker 2:  show today. Yes, there are tons of gadgets coming out and lots of news to
Speaker 2:  cover and we're gonna get to all of that, don't you worry. But we also have
Speaker 2:  three very different lawsuits happening that could all change the way the
Speaker 2:  tech industry works. So we're gonna talk about U S V, Google And, what we've
Speaker 2:  learned so far about the future of search. We're also gonna talk about the
Speaker 2:  FTCs lawsuit against Amazon, which could be the next big tech trial. And
Speaker 2:  we're gonna talk about the trial of Sam Bankman free, the former c e O of
Speaker 2:  FTX and for a long time the golden bully of the whole crypto world. And
Speaker 2:  now he's on trial in New York. And in some ways, honestly, it feels like
Speaker 2:  the whole crypto industry is on trial with him. So there's a lot to dig into
Speaker 2:  there as well. All that is coming in just a sec, but the proceedings here
Speaker 2:  are just about to start. And if there's one thing I've learned about the
Speaker 2:  US District Court these last few weeks, it's that they are sticklers for
Speaker 2:  punctuality that, and they never seem to be able to get the screens in the
Speaker 2:  courtroom to work. But I digress, gotta run. This is The Vergecast. See you
Speaker 2:  in a sec.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. All right, I'm home. Satya na della's testimony is
Speaker 2:  over. He said some really wild stuff about why Bing can't compete
Speaker 2:  with Google and why it's kind of Apple's fault. It was a lot and I have
Speaker 2:  a lot of thoughts. So actually let's just start there. Today, like I mentioned,
Speaker 2:  we have two big Antitrust trials in progress now. One
Speaker 2:  at the very beginning of the process, which is the government's case against
Speaker 2:  Amazon and one very much in the middle. US v Google.
Speaker 2:  These two cases are very different in some ways, but I think they also have
Speaker 2:  a lot in common and the combination of them is going to tell us a
Speaker 2:  lot about the future of the tech industry. So I called up the verges, Addie
Speaker 2:  Robertson and Makena Kelly to help me dig into the differences and
Speaker 2:  similarities and where we go from here. Addie, hello. Hi
Speaker 2:  Makena. Hello. Hi. So, okay, we have
Speaker 2:  basically two big trials to talk about in like
Speaker 2:  very different versions of the process and I want to talk about the ways
Speaker 2:  in which they are the same, but let's just sort of catch up on both of them
Speaker 2:  first. And let's start with U US v Google, because I've been in the courtroom
Speaker 2:  a bunch and Addie and I have been talking about this nonstop for like two
Speaker 2:  weeks. So it is like deep in my mind. Addie, where are we in this trial
Speaker 2:  right now? Like what's, what's your sense? We've talked a bunch about kind
Speaker 2:  of the stakes of the search engine and like what it means to be a
Speaker 2:  default. We're now, what, three weeks in almost four
Speaker 2:  weeks in? Where do you feel like we are
Speaker 5:  So pragmatically in the course of this trial? We're at the part where the
Speaker 5:  justice department is getting close to having made its
Speaker 5:  argument for why Google is an unlawful monopoly, which gives us kind of a
Speaker 5:  skewed view of it that right now we are hearing all of the bad stuff
Speaker 5:  about Google and after this there's going to be some state's attorney generals
Speaker 5:  making their case for why it's ad business is also
Speaker 5:  a monopoly and then we're going to get Google's rebuttal. And I think that's
Speaker 5:  going to probably bring out some details that cast the
Speaker 5:  current case in a new light.
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. I kind of don't care about the advertising part of this is that
Speaker 2:  okay, am I allowed to just not be interested in the advertising piece of
Speaker 2:  this case? I get that it's relevant, I just cannot make myself care about
Speaker 2:  it. I
Speaker 5:  Think. Yeah, well in one sense this is all about ads because ads is how search
Speaker 5:  makes money and ads is also if you're going to treat this as
Speaker 5:  their consumers and they are harmed per maybe through raised
Speaker 5:  prices. This is where you get the prices. But it's a lot of
Speaker 5:  it is I think less juicy.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And so to your point about the, the sort of side of it that we've
Speaker 2:  seen so far, what's your sense of how much of a preview of Google's argument
Speaker 2:  we've actually gotten? Because you, you're right that Google has spent most
Speaker 2:  of its time responding to different allegations from the D O J and
Speaker 2:  John Schmidt line. Google's lead counsel is like spectacularly good at his
Speaker 2:  job and has done a very good job of like being mad at
Speaker 2:  various people for lots of reasons. But Google's defense always
Speaker 2:  seemed to be You know Google is very good and that's not
Speaker 2:  illegal and that's definitely been the case so far. Do you
Speaker 2:  think there's gonna be sort of a, a different turn once Google actually starts
Speaker 2:  to take the stand here?
Speaker 5:  It seems like what we're probably going to get is more people testifying
Speaker 5:  in more detail about how Google is good. And the
Speaker 5:  flip side of this is how being does the same things in Google's
Speaker 5:  estimation as Google, but Bing is bad and therefore does not
Speaker 5:  succeed.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Being, being bad is like we've been saying the the crux of this entire
Speaker 2:  case.
Speaker 5:  It also seems like this is maybe when Google tries to poke holes in some
Speaker 5:  of the more sort of embarrassing things that the Justice Department has brought
Speaker 5:  up. What's
Speaker 2:  Your sense of how the d o j's side of this is going? I was
Speaker 2:  in court on Monday for Satya Nadella and before they got to
Speaker 2:  Satya they spent a bunch of time on scheduling stuff and it came up a couple
Speaker 2:  of times that Google's stance on how the D O J
Speaker 2:  is doing is that the D O J is taking a long time not
Speaker 2:  moving its case forward and just sort of mucking around
Speaker 2:  without actually proving its point. Of course Google is going to say that
Speaker 2:  loudly and on the record as many times as it can. But what's your sense now
Speaker 2:  a few weeks in, does it feel like the D O J is doing a good job
Speaker 2:  of making the case it's trying to make Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Google's case is sort of just that the D O J is wasting a bunch of time throwing
Speaker 5:  Google's dirty laundry out. Right? But it's also not necessarily
Speaker 5:  clear to me that this case is not partly about Google's dirty laundry
Speaker 5:  and that judge Meta is not interested in potentially
Speaker 5:  embarrassing things that Google executives have said. But it's also, I think
Speaker 5:  it's often pretty hard to tell how judges are going to rule and
Speaker 5:  you should probably not read too much into them. And I also, I don't think
Speaker 5:  that Meta has said a lot of incredibly pointed things.
Speaker 5:  Hmm. He's asked questions but I think it's a little bit hard to tell and
Speaker 5:  there was a hot mic moment where he was talking about how
Speaker 5:  frustrating this all is with another judge because it's so complicated and
Speaker 5:  there's not like a, there's not d n a evidence.
Speaker 2:  Oh, interesting. I didn't know that.
Speaker 5:  That was not his words, that was the, the other judge I believe. But it,
Speaker 5:  it seems like he's a little bit frustrated with a lot of this case,
Speaker 5:  but it's hard for me to tell how that translates into a ruling. Do you think
Speaker 2:  That's because of the way the case is going or because of the actual sort
Speaker 2:  of stakes of the case? Like we've been talking from the beginning that it's
Speaker 2:  not even necessarily super obvious what the
Speaker 2:  boundaries of the fight are here. Everybody's kind of arguing these
Speaker 2:  nebulous things that are good or bad, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, you have to argue, okay, so if there's consumer harm,
Speaker 5:  well who are the consumers? What does harm mean? Is it enough to
Speaker 5:  say that Google just isn't as good as it could be even if it's the best thing
Speaker 5:  on the market or is that unfair? And
Speaker 5:  then there's been this ar this whole sort of meta layer to the trial
Speaker 5:  about how much can be fairly disclosed. And so
Speaker 5:  there have been a lot of arguments about how much of any of this
Speaker 5:  is vital to the DOJs argument. And I think that has been its
Speaker 5:  own source of
Speaker 6:  Frustration for a lot of people.
Speaker 2:  Very much so. That got better. Hooray. That has
Speaker 6:  Gotten better.
Speaker 2:  Makena. My first question for you, if I'm remembering this correctly,
Speaker 2:  we've been waiting for this case for what feels like the hundreds of thousands
Speaker 2:  of years. What actually made this case happen? Like how did we finally get
Speaker 2:  to the point where we have like words on paper about what the FTC is mad
Speaker 2:  about at Amazon?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so the investigation into Amazon on Antitrust grounds has
Speaker 6:  actually been going on since the Trump administration. The former FTC
Speaker 6:  chair Joe Simons kicked it off. Of course a lot happened in tech
Speaker 6:  under the Trump administration as well. Cambridge Analytica, a bunch of
Speaker 6:  other FTC stuff with that company. And so instead of pursuing the
Speaker 6:  Amazon case, Simons kind of designated the FTC
Speaker 6:  is very meager resources. They've gotten more in recent years towards
Speaker 6:  like Facebook and Meta. But of course in 2021
Speaker 6:  President Biden nominated Lena Kahn to be the chair of the
Speaker 6:  FTC. Lena Khan of course is famous for
Speaker 6:  a somewhat viral legal paper on
Speaker 6:  Amazon. The
Speaker 2:  Only one ever.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, the only one ever called the Amazon Antitrust Paradox. And
Speaker 6:  in it she kind of talks about basically how common Antitrust,
Speaker 6:  American Antitrust doctrine, the way that we've approach approached Antitrust
Speaker 6:  law for decades doesn't really apply too well to big tech
Speaker 6:  companies. So Con gets into office, she's confirmed and then she
Speaker 6:  designates You know more of the FTC resources to that case. And so it's been
Speaker 6:  You know probably about five years that the company has been under investigation
Speaker 6:  for anti-competitive behavior.
Speaker 2:  The thing that strikes me about this case, and I want you to kind of lay
Speaker 2:  out the basics of what the FTC actually thinks that Amazon is doing wrong,
Speaker 2:  but one of the things that it strikes me big picture is that, like you said,
Speaker 2:  lean Conn knows better than most that it's very hard to bring an
Speaker 2:  Antitrust case against a company like Amazon, right? We, we talk a lot about
Speaker 2:  how do you prove consumer harm. We typically, these things are like
Speaker 2:  monopoly plus raise prices equals bad is like the legal framework
Speaker 2:  for a lot of this stuff. And that's very hard to do when products get
Speaker 2:  cheaper and when in many cases they're free. Like Google search,
Speaker 2:  what it seems like they tried very, very, very hard to do in this case is
Speaker 2:  make a case about how Amazon has raised prices. And part of me
Speaker 2:  wonders if that case, which is very different from like the big sort of heady
Speaker 2:  argument about Amazon being too powerful that Lena Kahan was making a bunch
Speaker 2:  of years ago. Now we're in this place where she's like, I get the sense she
Speaker 2:  tasked a bunch of people with saying we have to make an argument about
Speaker 2:  Amazon being bad for customers because things are getting more expensive.
Speaker 2:  Is that a fair way to look at what's happening here?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I, I mean that's how the US Antitrust
Speaker 6:  enforcers have long approached You know Antitrust law is whether or not
Speaker 6:  a company, the BA behavior that it's engaging in is driving up prices,
Speaker 6:  lowering them. And I'm sure people on this podcast have
Speaker 6:  heard You know for so many years the consumer welfare standard. So
Speaker 6:  she has been losing a lot. We've talked about
Speaker 6:  the Microsoft Activision merger,
Speaker 6:  not so hot there. The FTC didn't win of course like Meta
Speaker 6:  and the within acquisition they didn't really win there. And so
Speaker 6:  with a case so monumental like this Amazon case, the
Speaker 6:  FTC really needs to show that it can take these companies on.
Speaker 6:  'cause for the first You know couple years of her tenure, it hasn't quite
Speaker 6:  been working out. And so trying to make those arguments You know about whether
Speaker 6:  Amazon is raising prices is might just be the only winning argument
Speaker 6:  that the FTC can find under current Antitrust doctrine.
Speaker 2:  Right. Yeah. So walk me through that case a little bit. Like what, what are
Speaker 2:  the sort of specific accusations that the government is making against Amazon?
Speaker 6:  Sure. So I don't want to make it seem like the F D
Speaker 6:  C isn't looking at structural parts of Amazon as well. 'cause
Speaker 6:  really the heart of the case is saying that Amazon for as long as it's
Speaker 6:  been around, has been making sizable investments in its company, creating
Speaker 6:  Amazon, Prime Prime video. It's basically a fashion
Speaker 6:  designer has logistics and fulfillment. Amazon is a behemoth
Speaker 6:  and by reinvesting all of this You know would be profit back into the company.
Speaker 6:  It's been able to grow immensely and have a lot of control
Speaker 6:  over individual sellers and then also being very
Speaker 6:  competitive against other You know big box stores like Walmart,
Speaker 6:  target and other companies like that. And so
Speaker 6:  because of that structural You know power that Amazon has
Speaker 6:  created over decades, the FTC is making the argument
Speaker 6:  that it has a lot of control over requesting. You know
Speaker 6:  that some third party sellers put their products on Amazon
Speaker 6:  at a significantly lower price than they would on other platforms. Also
Speaker 6:  requiring, basically requiring third party sellers to buy
Speaker 6:  ads on Amazon's You know search When you go into type of product
Speaker 6:  in order for that product to even be seen while Amazon is selling its own
Speaker 6:  You know Amazon Basics products, which are competitors, it has that control
Speaker 6:  over the infrastructure in order to create a better system for its own
Speaker 6:  products and services compared to those of its competitors.
Speaker 6:  Which yeah, sounds a lot like the case Addie is talking about in a little
Speaker 6:  bit.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean that's the thing, right, that we're, we're in this weird place
Speaker 2:  where just the overarching question is like, are these companies too powerful?
Speaker 2:  And it feels like the Amazon version of that cycle, at least the way
Speaker 2:  the government describes it, is kind of unusually tight and succinct
Speaker 2:  where it's like I I you you can actually explain the whole cycle of how things
Speaker 2:  get more expensive because of Amazon. I don't know whether that's true. Amazon
Speaker 2:  obviously like Vociferously denies that it is responsible for prices
Speaker 2:  going up all over the internet. But it's like the, the government sort of
Speaker 2:  lays out this case where it's like, okay, Amazon forces
Speaker 2:  sellers to use the fulfilled by Amazon things. Those
Speaker 2:  fees are super high and also Amazon prevents them from offering cheaper prices
Speaker 2:  anywhere else because it, it has these mechanisms to figure, figure out what
Speaker 2:  you're pricing around the internet and then they either like bury you in
Speaker 2:  search results or they get rid of the buy box. I've like learned so much
Speaker 2:  about how the Amazon website works through this case, which is really fascinating.
Speaker 2:  But Amazon has all these little knobs it can turn to just wreck your business
Speaker 2:  on Amazon if it feels like it. And so what you do is you
Speaker 2:  raise all your other prices elsewhere in order to not
Speaker 2:  run afoul of Amazon's increasingly expensive process. And
Speaker 2:  that is like an actual case of consumer harm. Like if that's true,
Speaker 2:  that is the most like straightforward, this is bad for
Speaker 2:  consumers anti-trust argument against a tech company. I feel like I've heard
Speaker 2:  in a long time,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, there were a lot of figures in the lawsuit that were
Speaker 6:  redacted that I would so much I would have loved to see. Yes,
Speaker 6:  like the percentage of You know how many people subscribe to Prime,
Speaker 6:  how many people over other websites order stuff
Speaker 6:  through Amazon because of Prime. I think those figures
Speaker 6:  would really, really say a lot and help us to drive that point home
Speaker 6:  if we had them, but of course we don't.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that complaint was very redacted. Like there was one thing that kept
Speaker 2:  coming up this thing called Project Nessie, which can tell is this like very
Speaker 2:  exciting internal program at Amazon that does something and
Speaker 2:  every time it's about to reveal anything there's just like twofold lines
Speaker 2:  redacted, do we know anything about Project Nessie? What, what is the story
Speaker 2:  here?
Speaker 6:  It is just as elusive as the Lochness monster
Speaker 6:  that it's named after. I have not been able to find too much
Speaker 6:  information on it and I bet You know I hope that when this case, if
Speaker 6:  this case, right, 'cause Amazon could still settle if that will happen, I'm
Speaker 6:  not entirely sure, it's very hard to predict right now, but in a couple of
Speaker 6:  years You know if this case actually goes to court. I'd be really excited
Speaker 6:  to see what else You know comes out of that complaint. Those those pieces
Speaker 6:  of data. More info on Nessie You know and all these things that we haven't
Speaker 6:  really seen but kind of vaguely know about
Speaker 6:  because of You know the text
Speaker 2:  And I'm assuming, if I remember right Addie, the first version of the Google
Speaker 2:  case was super redacted just like the Amazon case was
Speaker 2:  and then we got another version of it that was much less redacted, which
Speaker 2:  is when we learned all the actual information about the case. Am I remembering
Speaker 2:  that right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think that we've gotten, this is kind of typical in a lot of these
Speaker 5:  cases that you'll get very heavily redacted versions and then they slowly
Speaker 5:  get exposed as the trial gets closer.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So we might get Nessie information at some point here in the near future.
Speaker 2:  I just wanna know about Project Nessie, that's all I wanna know in the whole
Speaker 2:  world. I don't care about anything else. Just wanna know what Project Nessie
Speaker 2:  is. If You know, please email meDavid@thevirgin.com. That's all I wanna know.
Speaker 2:  Addie, my, my question for you is like these two cases sort
Speaker 2:  of rhyme to me in the sense that they are like they're happening at
Speaker 2:  roughly at the same time, which is either really interesting or a total coincidence.
Speaker 2:  And I'm curious if you guys see it one way or the other, but it also feels
Speaker 2:  like if you, if you sort of boil it all the way down the question of like
Speaker 2:  is it illegal to be wildly successful? Feels
Speaker 2:  like the question of both of these things And where does being wildly
Speaker 2:  successful in protecting all of that success tip into
Speaker 2:  monopolistic practices? Like do you see similarities between these
Speaker 2:  two cases, Addie, or are they more different than I'm giving them credit
Speaker 2:  for?
Speaker 5:  It's definitely not a coincidence that this kind of aggressive enforcement
Speaker 5:  is happening under the Biden administration, which has nominated people who
Speaker 5:  are very strongly pro being Antitrust
Speaker 5:  watchdogs. So on that side, like the big
Speaker 5:  tech investigations have been going on for years. This is sort of just this
Speaker 5:  finally coming to fruition. On the other hand, I actually think that
Speaker 5:  there are some levels of difference in the case, at least the allegations
Speaker 5:  that Google's case so far, the trial has been all about, look, Google is
Speaker 5:  legitimately good. There are downsides that we haven't gotten into the really
Speaker 5:  the arguments for like privacy, but Google really, it knows what you want.
Speaker 5:  It uses its data to produce a product that's actually
Speaker 5:  genuinely good. The Amazon case, at least from the
Speaker 5:  parts that we've seen, the allegations are basically Amazon's terrible.
Speaker 5:  Amazon forces prices up, it throws ads all
Speaker 5:  over everything and forces sellers to buy them, which is part of the Google
Speaker 5:  case too, but has not really come up as much yet that
Speaker 5:  there are all of these cases where their argument is, look, people
Speaker 5:  don't even necessarily wanna be signed up for Prime as a part of a separate
Speaker 5:  case. They, they're just getting signed up accidentally that
Speaker 5:  it really feels like the argument in the FTC case is that
Speaker 5:  Amazon sucks and there's no alternative. The D
Speaker 5:  O J case against Google, at least so far in court has been Google's really
Speaker 5:  good, but it's bad that no one else can be that good.
Speaker 2:  Makena. Is that your read too? Like do you think the the Amazon is bad case
Speaker 2:  is part of this? I I have gone back and forth on this because on the one
Speaker 2:  hand, yeah, some of the things they're talking about like it's super easy
Speaker 2:  to buy stuff and you get things really fast is like those are good
Speaker 2:  things and, and those are things people like, right? Like lots of people
Speaker 2:  did sign up for Prime on purpose and really fast shipping is one of the things
Speaker 2:  that people really like about Amazon. I do think it's true that the Amazon
Speaker 2:  shopping experience has been on a pretty fast decline for a pretty long time.
Speaker 2:  And I wonder if now is the moment where it's like the,
Speaker 2:  the case is Amazon used to be good and then got really big and has gotten
Speaker 2:  worse for everyone involved and there's nothing you can do about it.
Speaker 5:  I mean, to be clear, people make that case about Google too all the time
Speaker 5:  outside the court fair. Like this isn't necessarily about the reality of
Speaker 5:  the, of the actual platforms right now, but it's sort of the cases that both
Speaker 5:  sides are making.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think that's totally fair. I think when it comes to similarities
Speaker 6:  between the two, it really becomes, it really comes down to like the consumer
Speaker 6:  experience and how that feels for the consumer. So when I buy cat
Speaker 6:  food, right, I normally buy my cat food from Amazon, I have to wade
Speaker 6:  through so many listings and often it's not the same seller that I'm
Speaker 6:  buying the same cat food from. And it's really confusing. It's a different
Speaker 6:  price oftentimes it's like it like it sucks but like my
Speaker 6:  cat needs food and I know it's gonna be here in two days 'cause I have Prime,
Speaker 6:  right? So You know you weigh the cons, You know the benefits and the cons
Speaker 6:  over that. And then also You know similarly with Google, it's using
Speaker 6:  that service, using that search bar and how the company
Speaker 6:  controls that search bar. That plays a really key role in
Speaker 6:  the case.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I, I'm very curious to see, especially in the
Speaker 2:  Amazon case, it doesn't seem like in the Google case we're gonna have the
Speaker 2:  Google has gotten worse argument. It would be interesting if we did,
Speaker 2:  but I it does, it just doesn't seem like we're gonna get there. Google certainly
Speaker 2:  not, is not going to argue that Google is a worse product than it once was.
Speaker 2:  But it does seem like Amazon worked for
Speaker 2:  a long time because it was good and now it's bad and there's nothing you
Speaker 2:  can do about it. It's like that's part of how you win this. Everything is
Speaker 2:  getting worse and more expensive case. Like if you're Lena Khan, you kind
Speaker 2:  of have to make that argument.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think that's really the argument that the case
Speaker 6:  looks at the most. And I mean when you look at also like it comes down to
Speaker 6:  like what does the FTC want as well. Now Lenahan has been very
Speaker 6:  like tight-lipped about the exact remedies that they're looking for,
Speaker 6:  but in the press release it says like structural remedy,
Speaker 6:  that is a breakup, right? What gets broken off, what goes
Speaker 6:  where, who buys what? I'm not entirely sure, but it'll be interesting to
Speaker 6:  see You know how that pans out over the next You know months and years.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Addie do you have a, do you have a theory? If you were gonna break
Speaker 2:  up Amazon, how would you, if you're Lean Con and you're, you have to figure
Speaker 2:  out how to split up that company, what would you do? Well the
Speaker 5:  Really cheap answer is that you split up Amazon the, it's not always called
Speaker 5:  Amazon basics now, but the equivalent of Amazon's white label products,
Speaker 2:  Right? It's many, many, many, many in-house brands that you don't realize
Speaker 2:  are Amazon brands in many cases.
Speaker 5:  Especially because there are specific Antitrust allegations around that.
Speaker 5:  There's the argument that they use all of their consumer data to see what's
Speaker 5:  selling well and then they clone it. I don't know if that's
Speaker 5:  necessarily where the FTC thinks it would be most useful to split
Speaker 5:  up Amazon, but that's just the obvious cleavage point.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Personally for me, I think the place where it'd be
Speaker 6:  most beneficial for the case to break up Amazon would be the logistics and
Speaker 6:  fulfillment side because that really is what adds that additional
Speaker 6:  competitiveness. Like we're saying that knowing that the product is gonna
Speaker 6:  come in two days, right to you. So instead of like Amazon having You
Speaker 6:  know its own fulfillment services, having to operate with like a U P S or
Speaker 6:  a FedEx more often than not, I think would really, if not, if
Speaker 6:  that's not the only thing that gets broken up, I imagine that would be a
Speaker 6:  really intimate focus of the FTC as well.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And that would obviously be a huge, huge, huge blow to
Speaker 2:  Amazon. I think realistically you could get rid of the in-house brands and
Speaker 2:  like a bunch of people at Amazon would be like, oh shucks, and they'd all
Speaker 2:  move on. If you split off the logistics side of Amazon, you have like fundamentally
Speaker 2:  changed that company, right? Which I suppose is if you're the FTC
Speaker 2:  the goal. So I I I, it'll be interesting to see how big that swing turns
Speaker 2:  out to be. Last thing before I let you guys go, I, I have been trained over
Speaker 2:  the years that if we're gonna talk about Tech Antitrust, we have to argue
Speaker 2:  about market size because all they argue about is market size. And I've been
Speaker 2:  sitting in the courtroom at Google where everybody is arguing about what
Speaker 2:  a general search engine is and no one seems to know and it's very
Speaker 2:  complicated and there's vertical search engines and there's general search
Speaker 2:  engines and TikTok is neither of those but it's something else and everybody
Speaker 2:  just sort of spins outta control about whether Google just
Speaker 2:  competes with Bing or competes with like every other site that exists on
Speaker 2:  the internet. Amazon I feel like is about to go through exactly the same
Speaker 2:  thing, right? Amazon's case has been, we compete with every store on planet
Speaker 2:  Earth and we're actually like a pretty tiny minority of the retail market.
Speaker 2:  The FTC is gonna have to make a different and much harder case now,
Speaker 2:  right? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So in the case of Amazon, the FTC basically defines the market
Speaker 6:  as the online marketplace
Speaker 6:  industry, which is a really interesting way to define it, which I think honestly
Speaker 6:  I don't think Amazon would really even like that 'cause it wants you to think
Speaker 6:  that it competes with the big box stores with Target and
Speaker 6:  Walmart and all the Antitrust hearings and all this stuff that we paid attention
Speaker 6:  to over the last couple years. You always have the Amazon reps pointing
Speaker 6:  to You know the way that it arranges products and search to
Speaker 6:  the way that a Walmart or a Target arranges products on a
Speaker 6:  shelf. So in order to define as an online marketplace, I don't
Speaker 6:  think Amazon would be really happy with that. And I imagine they're going
Speaker 6:  to challenge that in court just looking at like the way that it's defined.
Speaker 6:  It really has to do with like online storefronts and I, I imagine that
Speaker 6:  will get kind of shaken out a bit more as time goes on. It seems kind
Speaker 5:  Of co even more complicated because stores like Walmart have gotten more
Speaker 5:  like Amazon, right? That if you go to walmart.com now you can get a bunch
Speaker 5:  of third party storefront store items.
Speaker 2:  But even that well, so this is, this is where it gets really heady for me,
Speaker 2:  right? 'cause I think like if Amazon has its way, the competition is everyone
Speaker 2:  who sells anything in any way anywhere in the world, right? I would argue
Speaker 2:  that is a reach, but also if the FTC has its way, it's like
Speaker 2:  companies that allow other companies to set up storefronts inside of
Speaker 2:  your storefront on the internet. Which is a much, much
Speaker 2:  smaller thing that Amazon and to like a lesser extent Walmart. 'cause
Speaker 2:  Walmart will sell third party stuff, but you can't really have a store on
Speaker 2:  walmart.com in the same way that you can kind of have your own store on
Speaker 2:  amazon.com. So it's like that teeny tiny thing is probably too
Speaker 2:  small because I don't know that like if you're a real person on the internet,
Speaker 2:  you're not thinking like, oh I'm gonna go to the storefront on amazon.com.
Speaker 2:  You're just like shopping for things on Amazon. The answer seems to be, I
Speaker 2:  mean it's somewhere in the middle there, but it does feel like even where
Speaker 2:  like if you go 60 40 on one side or the other, that's gonna end up being
Speaker 2:  really important in this case. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  What are the competitors, 'cause the thing that I'm thinking of is Etsy for
Speaker 6:  example, very small company in comparison like
Speaker 2:  Shopify sort of, but it's, it's a slightly different thing.
Speaker 5:  Alibaba,
Speaker 2:  Alibaba's a good one. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Instagram is setting up a bunch of like ways to buy products in like
Speaker 6:  storefronts, which I guess are essentially people's accounts now. And then
Speaker 6:  also like TikTok shop maybe. But that's like really, really new.
Speaker 6:  So You know other than like to think about like competitors,
Speaker 6:  it's mostly You know these kind of smaller companies compared
Speaker 6:  to like, I guess like meta stuff and like TikTok stuff, which is really still
Speaker 6:  very nascent and not people I'm not going to Instagram to buy things.
Speaker 5:  And also then you add the whole distribution logistics chain that you mentioned
Speaker 5:  too, that really none of these competitors
Speaker 5:  have that. That it's fairly unique. None of the
Speaker 5:  small like meta and TikTok don't have that at this point.
Speaker 2:  Right? The only company doing Amazon things is Amazon, which
Speaker 2:  is I suppose a, a strength of the argument here but also gonna
Speaker 2:  make it a challenge to figure out like who are we, who else are we arguing
Speaker 2:  about here is gonna be weird in this case.
Speaker 2:  Whereas like at least Google has one real honest to God
Speaker 2:  like apples to apples competitor, which is why the Google trial has become
Speaker 2:  so much about Bing because like why isn't Bing good is like a central question,
Speaker 2:  but in a way you can't quite ask the same question about Walmart
Speaker 2:  and, and get answers about Amazon. It's gonna be very, it's gonna be very
Speaker 2:  strange to see how we talk about this because there just isn't any company
Speaker 2:  out there remotely like Amazon anymore.
Speaker 5:  And we are also not even touching Amazon's media business. The fact that
Speaker 5:  it runs Prime, which is its own very powerful player in its market.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like Prime movies, it
Speaker 6:  Has Lord of the Rings now, right? Yeah. There's
Speaker 2:  Like, although that show sucks, so I, I suspect that will not come up on
Speaker 2:  anybody's side in this argument.
Speaker 5:  Well there's the M G M acquisition. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  All these things to bolster Prime like in a lot of ways it does seem like,
Speaker 2:  and this goes back to like is this raising prices things like is the, is
Speaker 2:  the ongoing push and existence of Prime good or bad
Speaker 2:  for consumers is a big part of the question here. And Amazon has spent a
Speaker 2:  long time being like it's cheap. We keep giving you reasons to make it better
Speaker 2:  and the FTC is gonna be like no, actually what it's doing is like building
Speaker 2:  ever higher walled gardens through which it can screw both sellers and customers.
Speaker 2:  A
Speaker 6:  Solution to a problem it created essentially.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Right, right. And has made more and more expensive to solve over time.
Speaker 2:  What, what do we have any sense of the timeline on the Amazon trial? Like
Speaker 2:  the Google thing took what, almost three years to
Speaker 2:  actually go to trial from that first complaint is, is that a roughly
Speaker 2:  good guide for the Amazon one do we think? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I think that's probably fair. Justice moves very slowly
Speaker 6:  in this country on all fronts, but I do
Speaker 6:  imagine it's gonna be quite a bit of time and well people
Speaker 6:  interested, I think we just have to continue following it before we have
Speaker 6:  like a gauge of when arguments could take place when things
Speaker 6:  start. Right now it's just, it could be anyone's guess.
Speaker 5:  We also don't really know what's going to end up going to trial. Like even
Speaker 5:  the Google case that went to trial is somewhat subtly different than the
Speaker 5:  one that was filed.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's very true. Well listen, as long as Project Nessie doesn't go
Speaker 2:  away in this process, I'll be okay.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Which is a cooler name Project Nessie or Jedi Blue.
Speaker 2:  They're both very good but Project Nessie for something that is heavily
Speaker 2:  redacted is perfect. Yeah. Like it's the Sasquatch
Speaker 2:  like they should just have secret names for everything and then just redact
Speaker 2:  them all. Like that's what I would do.
Speaker 6:  They all have crypted names.
Speaker 2:  Alright, thank you both very much for being here. We gotta take a
Speaker 2:  break and then we're gonna come back and talk about a very different trial,
Speaker 2:  about a very different industry with very different stakes. It's
Speaker 2:  crypto time y'all. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back as you're hearing this on Wednesday, it's day two
Speaker 2:  of the trial against Sam. Bankman Freed, who's better known as S P F
Speaker 2:  and is also known as the former founder and C t O of FTX,
Speaker 2:  which was for a while, one of the hottest companies in crypto. It was
Speaker 2:  huge. Now of course crypto has taken a dive and
Speaker 2:  so have s SPFs fortunes and the two things have a lot to do with
Speaker 2:  each other. Actually there are a lot of folks out there who think this trial,
Speaker 2:  which is ostensibly just about SS B f, is going to have huge
Speaker 2:  ramifications for the whole crypto universe as new information comes
Speaker 2:  out about how the industry actually works. It's a complicated
Speaker 2:  trial and an important one. The Verges Liz Lipato is covering it for us.
Speaker 2:  And I suspect right this second she's probably in a courtroom. So
Speaker 2:  we caught up a couple of days ago before things really got going. Hi Liz.
Speaker 2:  Hey
Speaker 7:  David, how's it going?
Speaker 2:  Okay, so I realized I was prepping for this and like you and I have both
Speaker 2:  been following this pretty closely for a long time. You
Speaker 2:  mercifully more closely than I you've hired tolerance for this nonsense
Speaker 2:  than I do I think. But I realized after all of like the chaos of
Speaker 2:  the last however many months it's been, I've sort of lost
Speaker 2:  track of what Sam Bankman Freed is actually on trial
Speaker 2:  for. So in a weird way, let's just start at like absolute ground
Speaker 2:  level here. I think there are a lot of layers and a lot of things to talk
Speaker 2:  about. But like what does this man actually being accused of
Speaker 2:  and on trial for?
Speaker 8:  Well conveniently David, I brought something to the
Speaker 8:  recording. Did you? And it is, it is a copy of the superseding
Speaker 8:  indictment. So this is what he's on trial for. I love it. And there are seven
Speaker 8:  counts in it. Okay. And they are wire fraud
Speaker 8:  and conspiracy to confi wire fraud mostly. Okay, so
Speaker 8:  count one is wire fraud on the customers of FTX. Count
Speaker 8:  two is conspiracy to commit wire fraud on the customers of FTX. Sure.
Speaker 8:  That's, this is pretty straightforward. And I just wanna pause here and talk
Speaker 8:  about how you prove this because this is part of what's exciting part of
Speaker 8:  it. For wire fraud, you have to show the bank transfer happened. That's boring.
Speaker 8:  But then you have to prove that people were defrauded. That
Speaker 8:  Sam Bankman freed, knew he was lying to the customers of
Speaker 8:  FTX. And so this is something where we might hear testimony from actual customers
Speaker 8:  You know who are talking about what he told them. It's where we
Speaker 8:  might talk about what he was saying in front of Congress is where we might
Speaker 8:  talk about what he You know what the Super Bowl ad said. Those kinds of things
Speaker 8:  are where this all comes into play,
Speaker 2:  Right? And this sort of base underlying thing is that he used
Speaker 2:  customer's money basically funneled it to this in his investment arm called
Speaker 2:  Alameda. Was it Alameda Capital?
Speaker 8:  Alameda Research.
Speaker 2:  Alameda Research.
Speaker 8:  But also used it to buy himself real estate and to make some investments.
Speaker 8:  It's, it's a straightforward, the accusations are straightforward, it's embezzlement,
Speaker 8:  it's very old fashioned. See this
Speaker 2:  Is why this is useful 'cause I feel like this is all, it all spins in so
Speaker 2:  many directions about like the crypto industry and tax fraud and all this
Speaker 2:  stuff. But ultimately it is just like he used money that wasn't his to do
Speaker 2:  things you're not allowed to do with money that isn't yours. It's like that's
Speaker 2:  exactly right. It's pretty simple. Okay. Alright. So that's the first two.
Speaker 2:  What else we got?
Speaker 8:  So we have count three wire fraud on lenders to Alameda research.
Speaker 8:  So this is his crypto trading arm and they had borrowed money and now the
Speaker 8:  allegation is that he defrauded the people he borrowed money from. And then
Speaker 8:  count four is conspiracy to commit wire fraud. Again, this you, you
Speaker 8:  see where this is going,
Speaker 2:  You want to do it and then you do it. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And then count five is conspiracy to commit securities fraud
Speaker 8:  on investors of FTX. So that's different. And that's the one where we might
Speaker 8:  see VC testimony. So the people who were
Speaker 8:  investing were given bad information. Sam, bickman, Fried had re reason
Speaker 8:  to know it was bad information. That's the allegation, right? So you might
Speaker 8:  see somebody step up on the stand and say, hey, this is what the documents
Speaker 8:  that I got said, here's what Sam said and here's the due diligence
Speaker 8:  we did. Here are our due diligence documents. And again, you have to prove
Speaker 8:  that he knew what he was saying is wrong 'cause like being an idiot isn't
Speaker 8:  illegal. Right? So that's count five. And then we have
Speaker 8:  count six, which is conspiracy to commit
Speaker 8:  commodity fraud on customers of F D X. I'm
Speaker 2:  Seeing a trend here. Liz.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, let's, well we're gonna get to the conspirators in a minute, right?
Speaker 8:  And then count seven is conspiracy to commit money laundering. Okay. So those,
Speaker 8:  that's what, that's what we're gonna be hearing from. And part of the reason
Speaker 8:  I wanted to go through those things specifically is that there's a bunch
Speaker 8:  of other stuff that's going on around this. There
Speaker 8:  are so many things going on. There's like an SS e c lawsuit, there's a C
Speaker 8:  F D C lawsuit, there's another trial actually that's gonna be happening.
Speaker 8:  It's scheduled for next March for a number of counts we aren't gonna be hearing
Speaker 8:  here. So I wanted to make sure we knew which counts we're dealing with, right?
Speaker 8:  'cause some of the allegations around like campaign finance stuff for
Speaker 8:  instance, while they might show up in this trial, they are not the charges
Speaker 8:  that are being brought against him here.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And you've kind of alluded to this, but one of the things I think is
Speaker 2:  important and sort of complicated to understand is what's different about
Speaker 2:  what happened at FTX versus what has happened in some of these other
Speaker 2:  crypto messes we've talked about on this show over the years. And I
Speaker 2:  think about like everything from You know the, the Luna
Speaker 2:  debacle where a bunch of people lost a lot of money to like what happened
Speaker 2:  with Axe Infinity where a bunch of people lost a lot of money. It, it seems
Speaker 2:  like there's one thing that is like crypto gone
Speaker 2:  bad and that seems to have all gone, kind of gone one direction and this
Speaker 2:  has gone a slightly different direction. Like how do you explain
Speaker 2:  the difference between what all those things are, where a lot of people lose
Speaker 2:  a lot of money And what this has become?
Speaker 8:  Oh boy. So Tara Luna was a project that
Speaker 8:  I think was badly conceived from the jump and there were a number
Speaker 8:  of people who predicted that that death spiral would happen in exactly the
Speaker 8:  way that it did. Right. And now there are You know also some allegations
Speaker 8:  that are being brought against Quan about You know, the last I
Speaker 8:  saw was that he might have been falsifying some trading. Okay. But as far
Speaker 8:  as I know, and I'm I'm saying this now, we may, we may see something else
Speaker 8:  in the future. As far as I know, DeQuan did not tip his hand into the till
Speaker 8:  and actually take money. Okay. Right. And when you talk about like
Speaker 8:  the various crypto failures of things like Three Arrows Capital
Speaker 8:  again, like they had loans that went bad and they couldn't make good on them.
Speaker 8:  Sure. There's a difference between making bad betts and actually
Speaker 8:  taking people's money. So like that's kind of what we're looking at. And
Speaker 8:  there are people within the crypto industry by the way, who are very happy
Speaker 8:  to see Sam Bankman free go down because they want,
Speaker 8:  they want the fraudsters out of the industry. They really do think that this
Speaker 8:  is something that's big and real and important. So clearing out all of the
Speaker 8:  villains, if you will, is a positive for crypto.
Speaker 8:  I think that they are a little confused about what the general public
Speaker 8:  understands about crypto because I think once you're in
Speaker 8:  it, like there's a lot of stuff that, there are a lot of subtleties and nuances.
Speaker 8:  It's kind of like an onion, right? Like there's just always more down there.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. But Sam, Bankman Freed was really, really successful at
Speaker 8:  marketing and really, really successful at promoting himself and really,
Speaker 8:  really successful at making himself synonymous with crypto in the United States.
Speaker 2:  He was the good guy. Yeah. Like not only was he not the villain, he was like
Speaker 2:  the disheveled good guy of crypto who like wasn't trying to sell you
Speaker 2:  a bunch of nonsense. He was the other one. Right.
Speaker 8:  And so that makes it a lot harder for anybody who says, Hey, we wanna be
Speaker 8:  regulated 'cause You know who else said that was Sam Bankman free. Right.
Speaker 8:  Right. So there's a like sort of a lot of a taint here I
Speaker 8:  think for people who are not directly involved in crypto. And one of the
Speaker 8:  sort of long-term goals of crypto is I think to get a lot of people involved
Speaker 8:  and I think potentially You know this kind of trial and the
Speaker 8:  associations with Sam Bankman free as a very public face of crypto
Speaker 8:  could be bad for the entire industry as far as like recruiting new
Speaker 8:  customers goes.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I was thinking about this. I re-watched the, the big short movie relatively
Speaker 2:  recently. I love it very much. But there's this character in it, Michael
Speaker 2:  Burry, who is like one of the first people to see that the housing
Speaker 2:  crisis is coming and that the way we've propped up mortgage bonds
Speaker 2:  is a disaster. And he is like the voice of reason. He's also like a
Speaker 2:  maniac. And I had this moment of reading about Sam
Speaker 2:  Bankman freed in the run up to this trial thinking he's both trying
Speaker 2:  to be like the c e o of Goldman Sachs setting up these
Speaker 2:  systems that are a disaster. And the Michael Burry saying
Speaker 2:  this is all a mess and is all going to come crashing down. He like tried
Speaker 2:  to do both of those things simultaneously and sort of play all sides
Speaker 2:  depending on who he's in a room talking to. And did it really well for a
Speaker 2:  surprisingly long period of time. He was like, this is the future also. We
Speaker 2:  need to be regulated also. It might be nothing, but it's possibly everything.
Speaker 2:  And like it worked until it didn't.
Speaker 8:  Well I have a, I have a couple thoughts about this and then there's, there's
Speaker 8:  something that I've noticed when I explain crypto to people, which is
Speaker 8:  I'll explain it to them and they'll say, oh, is that it? Is that all? And
Speaker 8:  it's like, yeah, that that's all I that is it. You know And they think it
Speaker 8:  must be much more complicated than it actually is. And there You know there
Speaker 8:  are like a bunch of, there's a bunch of complicated math in there
Speaker 8:  You know, but conceptually it's actually not that difficult to understand.
Speaker 8:  And so as soon as you explain like an N F T to people, they're like, but
Speaker 8:  I thought that, I thought this was supposed to be sophisticated. It's like,
Speaker 8:  well the math is sophisticated, the programming is sophisticated. But like
Speaker 8:  the concept pretty simple. And I think one of the things
Speaker 8:  that people like Sam Beckman Fried really benefit from is this assumption
Speaker 8:  of technical complexity. And that if you think it
Speaker 8:  sounds You know half baked, maybe it's just that you don't understand it,
Speaker 8:  maybe you're just not smart enough to understand it. And Bankman
Speaker 8:  Free's background as somebody who went to m i t
Speaker 8:  worked on Jane Street, You know math whizz makes it easy to
Speaker 8:  sell something like that. Part of what's really striking to me about all
Speaker 8:  of this is actually running the casino is a pretty
Speaker 8:  profitable business. And if he had just run FTX and like let
Speaker 8:  Alameda fail, I think he would be fine. The problem here
Speaker 8:  is that he wanted to propped up Alameda research, which was
Speaker 8:  the reason he founded FTX in the first place. Like if you go back to that,
Speaker 8:  that profile from Sequoia Capital that they like deleted 'cause it was so
Speaker 8:  embarrassing, but don't worry, it's, it's on the internet archive, you can
Speaker 8:  go read it. He talks about You know other exchanges being rickety and
Speaker 8:  Alameda having losses because the exchanges weren't good enough. And so he
Speaker 8:  wanted to build an exchange that was good enough for what he wanted to do.
Speaker 8:  And again, You know there are moments in that
Speaker 8:  profile where the, the VCs are like, well we assumed he wouldn't need money,
Speaker 8:  but here he is and it's like, that's an alarm bell for me right there. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  You know there might be a good reason to go get VC money even if you don't
Speaker 8:  need it just because it lets you expand faster for instance, lets you do
Speaker 8:  more things. But in retrospect that does seem like a striking
Speaker 8:  thing in the profile where they're like, oh, we assumed he was just minting
Speaker 8:  money hand over fist. But here he is asking us for some.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And You know, if you read the s e c complaint, they say FTX was
Speaker 8:  a fraud from the jump that the like from the very beginning You know
Speaker 8:  customer funds were being misallocate. And so I'm partially curious to know
Speaker 8:  sort of like the timeline of all of this because the way that
Speaker 8:  FTX ex was exposed was particularly chaotic. Yes. And we
Speaker 8:  found out about the misappropriated customer funds after
Speaker 8:  a different kind of chaos that is not on trial.
Speaker 2:  Explain that really quickly and then let's, again, there are many more tentacles
Speaker 2:  of this story that are gonna come out over time, but I do think that part
Speaker 2:  is important. 'cause you're right, it's not on trial, but it is like central
Speaker 2:  to what happened to FTX. So just explain that chaos real fast. Sure.
Speaker 8:  So CoinDesk gets a hold of Alameda research's balance
Speaker 8:  sheet and the balance sheet is weird. That's the easiest
Speaker 8:  way to put it. Yep. There's an awful lot of this token
Speaker 8:  F t t that's minted by FTX that's propping up the balance
Speaker 8:  sheet and backing up their loans. That's like if
Speaker 8:  Sephora were to go out and get loans based on the beauty
Speaker 8:  insider points, which they determine the value of. Okay. That's a good
Speaker 2:  Example. I like that. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And so there's, there's something like weird happening here and Sam
Speaker 8:  Bank Reed has a long running rivalry with the head of Binance
Speaker 8:  cz and CZ happens to have a lot of F T T tokens because
Speaker 8:  CZ was an early investor in FTX and Sam bought him out and gave him f
Speaker 8:  t t tokens to do it. And so CZ essentially announced he's going to dump his
Speaker 8:  tokens and at that point the market panics. And so
Speaker 8:  people, there's, there's a run. People are trying to get their money out,
Speaker 8:  they're You know dumping tokens left, right. And center
Speaker 8:  FTX is like, we're up for sale. Binance is like, oh we'll buy you. And then
Speaker 8:  Binance like after a day is like, just kidding, we're not buying this.
Speaker 8:  And then after that there's bankruptcy and it's in this period
Speaker 8:  of time post bankruptcy that these
Speaker 8:  details start to emerge that get weirder. You know
Speaker 8:  like the, the sort of like funky accounting of
Speaker 8:  valuing yourself by a token that you get to assign the value of yourself.
Speaker 8:  Like that's not great in and of itself. Yeah. But the customer funds stuff
Speaker 8:  that comes up afterwards where it's like there's this hideous balance sheet
Speaker 8:  of terrors that the, the Financial Times gets a hold of that. Like
Speaker 8:  it's still up there. Like if you wanna go look at that terrible spreadsheet,
Speaker 8:  like it gives me panic attacks, but like go look, there's You know, just
Speaker 8:  like a hole, there's an $8 billion hole
Speaker 8:  billion with a B. That's when everybody was sort of like, okay, well
Speaker 8:  where's the money? Where's the money Lebowski?
Speaker 2:  Well, and so this is where the FTX trial and this
Speaker 2:  sort of relatively specific set of allegations against Sam, Bankman Freed
Speaker 2:  becomes the trial about crypto. Right. And you, you wrote a,
Speaker 2:  a sort of run up to the trial getting at a lot of this that there is a, there
Speaker 2:  is a sense in the industry that actually what's about to happen is
Speaker 2:  a lot of evidence is going to be introduced and a lot of testimony is going
Speaker 2:  to be given not just about Sam but about the
Speaker 2:  crypto world. And this is both a a, it seems like both a prosecution
Speaker 2:  tactic and a defense tactic is to basically make the whole crypto
Speaker 2:  world look really, really, really, really bad.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, that's right. I think there is a lot of danger here Without knowing
Speaker 8:  the specifics of what's going to be said, we're gonna find out during opening
Speaker 8:  arguments what we've got is an offshore exchange that is
Speaker 8:  doing something that would be illegal in the United States. You can't run
Speaker 8:  both your own trading firm and your own exchange. Like that's an obvious
Speaker 8:  conflict of interest. Right. We
Speaker 2:  Have laws about that. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  It turns out, yeah. So it's in and it's in The Bahamas, so. Hmm.
Speaker 8:  And You know as we, we ran through the charges, I think it's worth thinking
Speaker 8:  about what kind of evidence it takes to prove each one of these charges.
Speaker 8:  Like there's the boring part where you show the wire transfer happened, like
Speaker 8:  that's gonna happen. Sure. There's like some chain of custody stuff about
Speaker 8:  like text messages also boring, but that has to go on the record. But then
Speaker 8:  it's like you have to demonstrate what was actually said by
Speaker 8:  Sam Bankman, Fried And what Sam Bankman Freed knew. And
Speaker 8:  those might be two entirely different things. And so you think about like,
Speaker 8:  okay, what kinds of text messages were there, what was going on in Slack?
Speaker 8:  What conversations were happen happening? We know that there are a couple
Speaker 8:  of his co-conspirators who pled guilty and are cooperating will most likely
Speaker 8:  testify including his ex-girlfriend Carolyn Ellison, who was one of
Speaker 8:  the CEOs of Alameda research. You know
Speaker 2:  Who was in a position to know everything about what happened here.
Speaker 8:  Exactly. And there is a recording of her contemporaneously explaining
Speaker 8:  what happened. Like you can say, you can make an argument
Speaker 8:  maybe to try to take her down. Oh, well You know she's trying to pin it
Speaker 8:  all on Sam because she wants a a, an easier sentence. But like if you have
Speaker 8:  that contemporaneous evidence of her explaining what happened,
Speaker 8:  that's a much harder thing to make. You can't make it stick if she's, she
Speaker 8:  said it before she thought she was gonna get caught. You know. So there's
Speaker 8:  a lot of stuff that is going on that I think we could potentially
Speaker 8:  hear about. But one of the things that I want everybody to sort of remember,
Speaker 8:  because there are so many moving parts in this case that it's easy to get
Speaker 8:  lost is that right before Sam Bankman Freed was
Speaker 8:  arrested in The Bahamas, he was going to testify before Congress and
Speaker 8:  we had his prepared testimony, which included a group
Speaker 8:  chat of crypto exchanges where he was being You
Speaker 8:  know, sort of scolded by cz. And
Speaker 8:  I wonder one if we're going to see more
Speaker 8:  of those exchanges, especially brought in by the defense and two,
Speaker 8:  what they will say, because You know this is the sort of thing where like
Speaker 8:  I don't think it's unusual for crypto exchanges
Speaker 8:  to have conversations with each other. I'm, I'm sure that happens all the
Speaker 8:  time. Sure. If only because You know everybody's trying to be like, okay,
Speaker 8:  so what's the s e c gonna do next? But like
Speaker 8:  I am interested in You know what kinds of evidence might be
Speaker 8:  brought forward potentially either to try to get the not guilty
Speaker 8:  verdict or to try to get Sam a lighter sentence. Because you
Speaker 8:  have to keep in mind the defense is doing about three things at once. First
Speaker 8:  and foremost, they want him not guilty. Sure. But should that fail,
Speaker 8:  they second wanna make sure that sentencing is relatively light and
Speaker 8:  third want grounds for appeals. So that means there's a bunch of evidence
Speaker 8:  that they're going to be stuffing the record with that may not necessarily
Speaker 8:  be directly relevant to the verdict itself, but might
Speaker 8:  for instance, be helpful for those other two goals.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And it seems like if you're his defense, the only two moves I can
Speaker 2:  think of are you either have to make the case that he didn't
Speaker 2:  know what was going on. Like you said, that being an idiot is not illegal.
Speaker 2:  And so they, they either have to make the, he's just sort of a
Speaker 2:  dumb figurehead case or make the
Speaker 2:  everybody in crypto as a conman. Sam's not worse than everybody else case.
Speaker 2:  Is there a, is there a third version of the defense that you've heard about?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, so one of the things that that that sort of a joke
Speaker 8:  and white collar crime is either you're too small to be responsible or you're
Speaker 8:  too big to be responsible and like, yeah,
Speaker 2:  There you go. You know, like
Speaker 8:  That you're too far down the food chain to be responsible for the crime or
Speaker 8:  you're so high up the food chain, you had no idea it happened. Right.
Speaker 2:  He's like, I'm hobnobbing with democratic hopefuls who, how could I possibly
Speaker 2:  have known what was going on. That's right.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So I expect that we're gonna get the, he was, he was too far up the
Speaker 8:  food chain to know the specifics of what happened. But I also think that
Speaker 8:  based on the reporting I've seen, there's going to be an advice of counsel
Speaker 8:  defense. He's basically going to say that his, he's gonna throw his lawyers
Speaker 8:  under the bus. He's gonna say, the lawyers told me that this was the best
Speaker 8:  way to do things, so I did it their way. I don't know how much water that's
Speaker 8:  going to hold. I am very curious about what kind of
Speaker 8:  evidence you might present in order to make that defense.
Speaker 8:  Particularly, because there seems to be a lot, just like
Speaker 8:  a mountain of evidence here in terms of like chats
Speaker 8:  and recordings and press, You know moments in the press, all of these things.
Speaker 8:  Just a, just a mountain of stuff that he said. So I am
Speaker 8:  very curious about what could possibly be brought forward in order to,
Speaker 8:  to show that he was acting at the advice of counsel, that he was doing what
Speaker 8:  his lawyers told him to do, and it wasn't his fault.
Speaker 2:  Just from a trial perspective itself. How do you think this is
Speaker 2:  gonna compare to, say, the Elizabeth Holmes trial, which you also covered
Speaker 2:  very closely. That one was just like a nonstop spectacle, right? There were
Speaker 2:  people cosplaying as Elizabeth Holmes outside of the courthouse.
Speaker 2:  Do you think this one's gonna be sort of a show in the same way?
Speaker 8:  I, I honestly have no idea. I think there are going to be a lot of people
Speaker 8:  from the crypto industry who are going to pop by to watch. I've certainly
Speaker 8:  spoken with people who've expressed an interest in doing so. Just out of
Speaker 8:  curiosity, in the same way that like You know, I, I think a lot of us are
Speaker 8:  very curious about this. Certainly. I'm curious. That's why I'm going. One
Speaker 8:  of the things that I'm interested in is You know with a lot of the sort of
Speaker 8:  like crypto bankruptcy proceedings, there are investors who show
Speaker 8:  up. And so I'm curious if we're gonna see people who are FTX customers who
Speaker 8:  are going to show up to see what happens and You know. The other thing that's
Speaker 8:  like worth keeping in mind here is we've been talking about the sort of boring
Speaker 8:  financial side of all of this, but there is this salacious human
Speaker 8:  element that I am now going to talk about because Totally. I think that's
Speaker 8:  one of the things that people are really interested in. You know questions
Speaker 8:  about recreational drug use. A lot of the people within FTX were dating each
Speaker 8:  other. I mean, Carolyn Ellison is Sam, Beckman Fried's, ex-girlfriend
Speaker 8:  You know. And like someone who is likely to testify and who has already pled
Speaker 8:  guilty is his childhood friend from Map camp. Like, oh, right. There's some
Speaker 8:  operatic stuff going on. So I think that there's like, I don't
Speaker 8:  know if we're gonna see necessarily people showing up dressed as Sam Bankman
Speaker 8:  freed or in FTX gear, although we might, who knows?
Speaker 8:  But I do think that there is a very, very high
Speaker 8:  likelihood of like real fireworks. Because if you think about like
Speaker 8:  David, you've worked at a startup too. If you think about what people are
Speaker 8:  like when they're, you're working at startups like, especially because you're
Speaker 8:  working these long hours and everybody's in their twenties and like you don't
Speaker 8:  know what you're doing. Yep. It's just, just the case. There are shenanigans
Speaker 8:  and these are shenanigans that are now going to be in the courtroom. And
Speaker 8:  so like you can imagine in an attempt to discredit a witness, you might bring
Speaker 8:  up some dumb stuff they did in the office.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Or in an effort to discredit the defendant, you might
Speaker 2:  bring up a lot of their own personal shenanigans. And I, I do, I think you're
Speaker 2:  right that there were a lot, there are a lot of shenanigans we know about
Speaker 2:  because especially like since the man went on house arrest,
Speaker 2:  he has, he had the most public house arrest of all time and just happily
Speaker 2:  told anyone who asked about all the shenanigans going on, on going on at
Speaker 2:  FTX. And yeah, I have a feeling there is a lot more to come.
Speaker 2:  How long is this trial supposed to be?
Speaker 8:  It's scheduled for about five weeks. It may run a little longer or a little
Speaker 8:  shorter, but I, I will be in New York City for all of October in the first
Speaker 8:  couple weeks in November. I'm actually turning 40 while in there. Ah,
Speaker 2:  Happy almost birthday. Very. Thank you. Tell Sam that he, you owes you, this
Speaker 2:  is how I'm
Speaker 8:  Celebrating. Yeah, it's,
Speaker 2:  It's, it's, it feels very fitting for you as actually is how to celebrate
Speaker 2:  your birthday. This feels right,
Speaker 8:  But yeah, I You know, I think that there's, there's a lot to come
Speaker 8:  and I, I really can't wait to find out what kind of evidence
Speaker 8:  I'm gonna see because You know there's a lot of stuff that as a reporter,
Speaker 8:  I just love being in other people's business. I'm a huge gossip. Like that's
Speaker 8:  just the truth of the matter. Like I was that before I was a reporter, I
Speaker 8:  grew up in a small town. Gossip was a contact sport. Like this is like a
Speaker 8:  game I love. And the government can get ahold of so much more juicy info
Speaker 8:  than I can. Like I would love to see the due diligence
Speaker 8:  that Sequoia did. Like I would love it. I never get to see that stuff.
Speaker 8:  So this is the kind of thing that I'm really hyped for.
Speaker 2:  It is a really underrated thing. I had this experience being in the, the
Speaker 2:  courtroom for U S V Google for a couple of the sort of bigger named
Speaker 2:  people, the people who a never meet with
Speaker 2:  reporters most of the time. s Bankman free is sort of unusual in that he
Speaker 2:  loved talking to reporters, but most of the time these people either never
Speaker 2:  tell the truth or never meet with reporters in general, but just
Speaker 2:  watching them sit there and they're, it's like, oh, they have to tell the
Speaker 2:  truth now and they have to say it out loud and I get to just sit here and
Speaker 2:  listen to it. It's the best It rules. Sometimes it's very boring and
Speaker 2:  procedural and it takes a long time, but eventually they have to answer the
Speaker 2:  question and it's kind of great.
Speaker 2:  Alright, well we're gonna check in a bunch over the course of this trial,
Speaker 2:  like you said, it's, it's long. I suspect if I had to guess, I would say
Speaker 2:  it's gonna kind of ebb and flow. There's gonna be a lot of really
Speaker 2:  wonky talk about how money moves around. But then we're gonna get
Speaker 2:  a lot of shenanigans and we're gonna check in on both of those things.
Speaker 8:  I'll tell you what David, because I, I don't know how many of our listeners
Speaker 8:  are aware of like the sort of the reporting that goes on, but because there's
Speaker 8:  a limited amount of people that just a limited physical number of bodies
Speaker 8:  that can fit in that courtroom, I'm usually like, for something like this,
Speaker 8:  I'm gonna be standing outside at like an unholy hour in the morning. And
Speaker 8:  so if there are shenanigans, I have some time where I'm doing
Speaker 8:  nothing standing on the streets of New York City. And so yes, I will be calling
Speaker 8:  in. You'll get to hear the cell phone report. This is
Speaker 2:  What I like to hear. All right, thanks Liz. We'll talk
Speaker 8:  Again soon. Alright. Bye David.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna get to The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  hotline. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Let's answer a question from The Vergecast hotline as we
Speaker 2:  do on this show every week. As a reminder, the hotline number is
Speaker 2:  eight six six Verge one, one call and ask us all of your
Speaker 2:  best tech questions. No question, too big, no question. Too weird. The weirder
Speaker 2:  the better. If I'm being honest with you. We've gotten some amazing questions
Speaker 2:  recently. Thank you for all of your most bonkers thoughts about all things
Speaker 2:  technology. Oh, and if you don't wanna call or can't, you can always email
Speaker 2:  us Vergecast at The Verge dot com. That works just as well.
Speaker 2:  Today's question comes from Zach.
Speaker 13:  Hi, this is Zach. I'm in Milwaukee, Wisconsin. My daughter is a
Speaker 13:  voracious reader, very proud dad. It also means she just goes through
Speaker 13:  tons of library books. Basically anytime we go to a bookstore, she's picking
Speaker 13:  up something. I kind of don't know where to go as far as
Speaker 13:  a electronic reader. This feels like a really natural holiday gift.
Speaker 13:  But do I just go for the iPad because it's got the most access to apps,
Speaker 13:  especially things like hoopla, things that work with the local library system.
Speaker 13:  I don't want to really get super locked into a an into an ecosystem. But
Speaker 13:  on the other hand, like if you go with the E Ink, it's not gonna
Speaker 13:  use for anything else. It's just gonna be for for reading. But then it doesn't
Speaker 13:  have access to those, those library apps. And, and we're kind of back to
Speaker 13:  square one spending You know 10 to $15 for every single book,
Speaker 13:  especially books you will read once I, I don't know what the correct answer
Speaker 13:  is. So light up the crayon signal and
Speaker 13:  get me the best information you've got. Thanks. Bye.
Speaker 2:  Ask and you shall receive. We lit up the crayon signal. Alex. Cranz is here.
Speaker 2:  Hi Alex.
Speaker 14:  Hi. Oh my God, this is a great question, right?
Speaker 2:  There are so many layers to this question in ways that I find so
Speaker 2:  very interesting. So let me just try and like lay the land for you here
Speaker 2:  and see if you think about this the way that I do. Okay. There's like a hardware
Speaker 2:  and a software question here. I think we can immediately rule out buying
Speaker 2:  a Kindle. Yes. Because we don't wanna be tethered to one
Speaker 2:  ecosystem, right? Fair, yeah. Good on that. Okay. So I think we're, we're
Speaker 2:  basically in one of three places now. We, we can either tell our buddies
Speaker 2:  Zach to buy an iPad. We can tell our friends Zach to buy a different
Speaker 2:  EIN ebook reader, which is, i I know you're gonna have several thoughts about
Speaker 2:  certain brands that may or may not exist in America but are possible
Speaker 2:  to find or you can buy a different Android
Speaker 2:  tablet. Those seem like the three categories. Am I missing anything?
Speaker 14:  I, I think that's exactly right. Okay. Because the Kindle, Kindle
Speaker 14:  can work with some libraries, but it only works with Libby and and
Speaker 14:  Overdrive and that's not like the only library ecosystem
Speaker 14:  out there. And it's
Speaker 2:  Also kind of wacky and complicated and yeah, they just haven't done a good
Speaker 2:  job of that for
Speaker 14:  Kids. Like it's very involved and Cobo has kind of
Speaker 14:  built itself as like, oh you can use it for your library books and all these
Speaker 14:  other kinds of reading. Like I think it's got pocket built in or it used
Speaker 14:  to, it's also not really great 'cause again, it's really limited
Speaker 14:  to overdrive and otherwise you're gonna be like teaching your daughter how
Speaker 14:  to side load stuff and that is a great skill she should have.
Speaker 14:  Like I highly encourage you doing that. I don't know if this is the time
Speaker 14:  you want to do that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 14:  So I don't wanna get into your parenting. Like
Speaker 2:  You teach your kids to side load whenever feels right to you. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  That's a very personal moment for you and your daughter. So yeah, it really
Speaker 14:  is like, okay, do you wanna go iPad and You know it's more likely to,
Speaker 14:  she can crack it and break it and, and make it more difficult to use, a
Speaker 14:  lot easier than a lot of other devices. But it is very, very flexible.
Speaker 14:  But also like you could catch your plane Roblox on it or
Speaker 14:  watching YouTube. Like there's a lot of things that can happen there. Or
Speaker 14:  you can go with something like probably the best brand and I've, I've
Speaker 14:  mentioned it a bunch of times on the show and David already knows what I'm
Speaker 14:  gonna say, which is books
Speaker 2:  B O O X we should say Yeah.
Speaker 14:  B O O X. And they're probably the best at like Android e
Speaker 14:  Ink tablets. I'm a little hesitant to say go that route just because
Speaker 14:  she is a child. And like it can be a little complicated. And so
Speaker 14:  you will probably still have to teach her the side loading situation but
Speaker 14:  also a whole bunch of other things. And like if you want your
Speaker 14:  daughter to be really, really understanding of how technology works, the
Speaker 14:  books is the best way to go. If you don't wanna also be participating
Speaker 14:  in that educational activity, the iPad or like an
Speaker 14:  Android tablets, like a traditional Android tablet feels right.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. My my heart wants books to be the answer
Speaker 2:  because in theory that combination of, it's almost
Speaker 2:  exclusively a reading device, but I also need all the other apps because
Speaker 2:  there are lots of places you read, not just in the one ebook system, right?
Speaker 2:  Like yes, what an incredibly common use case that no one
Speaker 2:  has fixed. I want books to be the answer, but I I do agree. I think for
Speaker 2:  most people the book's version of Android
Speaker 2:  is just like somewhere between one and five ticks too complicated
Speaker 2:  to really work.
Speaker 14:  I'm using like the, the most recent color one and it's got the most recent
Speaker 14:  software on it, night and day difference really in onboarding
Speaker 14:  versus, yeah, like the Google Play store is built in now. So you can
Speaker 14:  just start using the Google Play store whereas before you had, you would've
Speaker 14:  had to teach your daughter about patients and, and waiting for 24 hours
Speaker 14:  for Google to register the device. After you register it, now you can just
Speaker 14:  start using it. So the, it has improved a
Speaker 14:  lot and, and there's some pretty affordable ones there. You know, there's,
Speaker 14:  there's some, I think like the pokey three is like
Speaker 14:  $150. Maybe it's, it's a little more affordable. I definitely
Speaker 14:  would look into it and have a serious conversation with yourself on how
Speaker 14:  much you are willing to troubleshoot things. 'cause I think it's still gonna
Speaker 14:  require it, even with a software update, there's still gonna be more handholding
Speaker 14:  than with an iPad, but it's probably gonna get you closer to that experience
Speaker 14:  you're looking for. So yeah, it just depends on like how often do you wanna
Speaker 14:  have to answer tech questions for your daughter
Speaker 2:  Fair. Can I throw one wrench in here that I Oh yes. Am not
Speaker 2:  a hundred percent sure I think is a good idea, but I think might be a good
Speaker 2:  idea, which is one of Amazon's tablets. My
Speaker 2:  hesitation with all tablets, whether they run Android or iOS,
Speaker 2:  is that they have all the apps. That's true. But
Speaker 2:  buying stuff on those devices is a gigantic pain in the ass
Speaker 2:  because of the way that Google and Apple run those platforms. You can't buy
Speaker 2:  Kindle books in the Kindle app. You know where you can buy Kindle books in
Speaker 2:  the Kindle app and buy other things in other apps is on the fire tablets.
Speaker 2:  And those tablets aren't like amazing hardware. But like the, the fire
Speaker 2:  HD plus eight inch has a decent screen. It's pretty
Speaker 2:  rough and tumble. You're not really gonna break it if you beat it up. They
Speaker 2:  make a kid's version that's even more rugged and it's $70. Like,
Speaker 2:  I, I cannot explain enough how much more expensive
Speaker 2:  every other tablet is. This one is not a great tablet. But if, if
Speaker 2:  truly all you want is a reading device, this feels like it might be enough.
Speaker 14:  It might be, I think you'd have to double check on what apps will work with
Speaker 14:  it because it's still like Amazon's thing and they want you to buy their
Speaker 14:  books. Right. They don't, won't necess like they might make it difficult.
Speaker 14:  I, I don't know the state of like the Libby app on on a fire
Speaker 14:  tablet or, or the hoopla or whatever. So you
Speaker 14:  probably would need to do just a touch of research there. 'cause I haven't
Speaker 14:  used one in a little bit.
Speaker 2:  It's definitely significantly more open than the Kindle, but significantly
Speaker 2:  less open than like full Android. You're still getting Amazon's spin
Speaker 2:  on Android. That's definitely true. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  But if it's got the apps, it's probably like the most affordable
Speaker 14:  and like easiest to use of it. It just requires like
Speaker 14:  quadruple checking that the app is available for it also. It's like a hundred
Speaker 14:  bucks and easy to return. So if you get it and it doesn't work, return it.
Speaker 14:  Buy books, buy an iPad and you'll be happy.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I I will say I think we're probably aligned on this one that like if
Speaker 2:  money is no object and you're not worried about like breaking the thing,
Speaker 2:  the iPad mini is the correct answer. Right? It is like objectively the best
Speaker 2:  device of all these devices. Yeah,
Speaker 14:  I I I try to switch between my, my e-reader and my iPad mini a lot
Speaker 14:  and I'll oftentimes will find my, like my iPad mini just does more stuff
Speaker 14:  so I use it more. But I love having my, my e-reader.
Speaker 14:  I love being able to read it outside. I love it for just focus and I think
Speaker 14:  for a kid it's prob that might actually be a good thing in some cases, right?
Speaker 14:  Like they gotta focus on the reading and not just go off on a tear
Speaker 14:  being like, I wonder like when you read a chapter in a book and you're like,
Speaker 14:  oh that's interesting and you immediately go Google it on your iPad. That's
Speaker 14:  easy on your, on your e-reader. You have to wait and do it later and
Speaker 14:  that's kind of nice. 'cause then you just keep reading,
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. It's either a feature or a bug depending on how you look at
Speaker 2:  it. And I think that has a lot to do with it. So I think we're aligned on
Speaker 2:  that. I would say if you're feeling ambitious, Zach,
Speaker 2:  buy a books device. See how it feels. My sense would be it will
Speaker 2:  immediately be obvious to you if it's more and more
Speaker 2:  work than you want, right? Yeah. Like you're gonna take the thing outta the
Speaker 2:  box, turn it on and immediately just be like, Nope. Or you're gonna be like,
Speaker 2:  oh this solves all my problems. Right. That's that seems it. It will not
Speaker 2:  be unclear. I wouldn't think it, it,
Speaker 14:  Yeah, it will not be unclear. You're gonna know really, really quickly.
Speaker 14:  And generally speaking, the new, the new operating system, the new
Speaker 14:  version they've rolled out has been really, really good. They're very good
Speaker 14:  about like getting the latest version of Android on things. You just can't
Speaker 14:  use 70% of Android 'cause it's not meant for a black and white
Speaker 14:  tablet. Yeah, that's so like you can watch YouTube on it. Don't
Speaker 2:  If you Yeah, it's a specific kind of torture trying to watch
Speaker 2:  YouTube on a device like that. So my other question for you is where do
Speaker 2:  you buy your eBooks? I realized in prepping for this that I
Speaker 2:  accidentally just became sort of Amazon exclusive like a million years ago.
Speaker 2:  I loved the Kindle and had a bunch of Kindle books and now that's where all
Speaker 2:  my books are. So I have kept buying Kindle books and like, am I here to tell
Speaker 2:  you that the Caliber app exists and does a really good job of stripping d
Speaker 2:  r m from your Kindle books so that you can use them on other devices? No,
Speaker 2:  that's not what I'm here to tell you. It's true. And the app is free and
Speaker 2:  open source and it strips d r m from all your eBooks. So you can use them
Speaker 2:  on other devices, but that's not the point. My question for you is where
Speaker 2:  do you get your eBooks, if not from Amazon? I
Speaker 14:  Originally started with Nook and then I found Caliber and, and
Speaker 14:  made the switch to Amazon and took my whole Nook library with me, which
Speaker 14:  was really, really nice. And then I was at Amazon for a while and then,
Speaker 14:  then I was like, I feel weird being in this one ecosystem. So I switched
Speaker 14:  back to Nook and brought all my books back via Caliber. And so now
Speaker 14:  I'm usually like, I, I tend to go Nook, but I've got a couple
Speaker 14:  of like, there's ebooks.com, there's a couple of other ones and I'll kind
Speaker 14:  of look around. 'cause sometimes the stories, the selection is different.
Speaker 14:  And honestly, Amazon has a ton of books. It's gotten so big
Speaker 14:  with self-publishing that a lot of like self-published books, somebody will
Speaker 14:  say, oh, you gotta read this. It's really good. It's only available at Amazon,
Speaker 14:  which is super frustrating. And also sometimes I'll just buy it directly
Speaker 14:  from the, the publisher and the author gets more
Speaker 14:  money that way. So that's if you really are supporting an author, buying
Speaker 14:  it directly from their poper if available best way to buy the books.
Speaker 14:  Yeah, and
Speaker 2:  You can usually, if You know what you wanna buy, if you just Google the title
Speaker 2:  and ebook, you can pretty quickly find that publisher website usually and,
Speaker 2:  and get the book that way. That's a good trick. What I wish existed like
Speaker 2:  bookshop.org, which is this amazing website for buying physical books from
Speaker 2:  like actual bookstores that are better citizens of the publishing
Speaker 2:  world than your Amazon's. I love that website and I wish something like it
Speaker 2:  existed for eBooks. It feels like ebooks.com is like kind of that
Speaker 2:  but not quite.
Speaker 14:  Ebooks.com is kind of doing that. Libro FM
Speaker 14:  does that, but it's almost exclusively audio books. I spend like
Speaker 14:  $15 a month there and it gives me one book credit and that's nice. And I
Speaker 14:  know I'm supporting a, an author and I'm supporting my local bookstore,
Speaker 14:  like feels great. You can also find your local bookstores. A lot of 'em
Speaker 14:  actually will have partnerships with Booksellers online and be like, oh
Speaker 14:  yeah, you, you can go here and buy any ebook from us at
Speaker 14:  this. They often will have garbage websites, but if you wanna
Speaker 14:  support your local bookstore, that's the way to do it. It just unfortunately
Speaker 14:  requires more work than logging into Amazon.
Speaker 2:  The only thing I would add to your list of websites, which is, which is very
Speaker 2:  good and I just am going to go sign up for Libro FM right now, is there's
Speaker 2:  this website called BookBub, B O O K B U b.com. And
Speaker 2:  its whole thing is just spectacular deals on eBooks from
Speaker 2:  around the internet. And so it's like not a place to go if you're like,
Speaker 2:  I wanna read this specific brand new book. But if you're just like, I like
Speaker 2:  spy novels, let me know when I can get a spy novel for a dollar
Speaker 2:  99 as an ebook. They send emails and it has
Speaker 2:  become my like most quickly clicked email every week because
Speaker 2:  it's just nonstop ebook deals and it's great and I use it all the time. So
Speaker 2:  highly recommend
Speaker 14:  I'm doing that as soon as we're done with this podcast.
Speaker 2:  I think we've helped. Right this, this feels, Zach, let us know what you
Speaker 2:  end up doing. I think your instincts are good and if you, if you buy a books
Speaker 2:  and you love it, it will warm Alex's heart, so let us know. It will,
Speaker 14:  It will
Speaker 2:  Alex. Thank you. Appreciate it as always.
Speaker 14:  Always.
Speaker 1:  Alright,
Speaker 2:  That's it for the Vergecast today. Thanks to everybody who came on the show
Speaker 2:  today, and thank you as always for listening as ever. There is lots more
Speaker 2:  from everything we talked about at The Verge dot com. We're covering all
Speaker 2:  of these trials pretty closely, so we'll put some links in the show notes,
Speaker 2:  but also we're posting all over The Verge dot com as everything happens.
Speaker 2:  So keep an eye on the website also, if you have thoughts, questions, feelings,
Speaker 2:  or tips on how to improve my handwriting because I'm not allowed to have
Speaker 2:  electronics in the courtroom. You can always email us at Vergecast at The
Speaker 2:  Verge dot com or keep calling the hotline. 8 6 6 Verge one, one. we love
Speaker 2:  hearing from you. Send us all your thoughts and questions and ideas for what
Speaker 2:  we should do on the show. We do at least one hotline question every week,
Speaker 2:  so please keep 'em coming. This show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam
Speaker 2:  James. Brooke Miners is our editorial director of Audio Vergecast is Verge
Speaker 2:  production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli, Alex and I will
Speaker 2:  be back on Friday to talk about the pixel event, the sphere in Vegas,
Speaker 2:  the sad fate of the $17,000 Apple Watch and all of the rest of this
Speaker 2:  week's tech news. We'll see you then. Rock and roll.