# Transcript
ID: 9c4f3215-3067-4577-ad90-05e6bc6f7d9f
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Humane Pins and your own ChatGPT
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8040525363765735058/5250667281620810394/s93290-US-6479s-1699626140.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, Alex Cranz, and Alex Heath discuss the debut of Humane's AI Pin, OpenAI's DevDay, GPT-4 updates, and more.
Speaker 2:  Hello
Speaker 3:  And Welcome To, the Vergecast flagship podcast of Fox Media.
Speaker 3:  I'm just taking it back baby. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I love that.
Speaker 3:  That's 2024. Yeah, just open mutiny.
Speaker 3:  Bring it on Sports website. I'm your friend Neil Alex.
Speaker 3:  Cranz is here.
Speaker 4:  I'm your friend who, I just gotta say it. My brother won a Michelin Star.
Speaker 4:  It's pretty good. And I didn't even want to try to, to put that in neatly.
Speaker 4:  I just wanna brag. Yeah. So that was me bragging. And that's, that's it.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's here. It happened.
Speaker 3:  The flagship podcast is being related to Michelin Stars. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  There we go.
Speaker 3:  He's my brother too. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  He's all our
Speaker 3:  Brothers. He's everyone's family.
Speaker 4:  Everyone. Everyone earned this with
Speaker 3:  Him. If you're listening to this show, you can tell people You know a Michelin
Speaker 3:  Star.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, you can.
Speaker 3:  The star, not the person,
Speaker 4:  Just the star. Just the star.
Speaker 3:  David Pierce is in San Francisco.
Speaker 5:  We're like 85 seconds in and I'm like, this is gonna be a three and a half
Speaker 5:  hour long broadcast. It's not gonna make any sense to anyone. And this
Speaker 5:  might be the end of The Vergecast. Yeah. Like this for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 5:  Today might be the last Vergecast ever. I think it's gonna be, it's gonna
Speaker 5:  be a day.
Speaker 3:  If you're gonna go go with a bang. Alex Heath is here
Speaker 3:  from Los Angeles. Hi. I am really just a AI agent, but I'm here.
Speaker 3:  I'll say that some people in the YouTube comments
Speaker 3:  openly wondered if I was interviewing an AI Barack Obama. They're like, that
Speaker 3:  didn't happen. Aw, you got trolled by AI Barack Obama. And maybe I did
Speaker 3:  All. right? So David. You're in San Francisco. Yep. Because you were supposed
Speaker 3:  to attend the launch of the Humane AI Pin. That's correct.
Speaker 3:  Which when David says the energy of this podcast is a little,
Speaker 3:  I would say that that is the thing that we are gonna talk about. It is. It's
Speaker 3:  a lot. Yes. There's a lot to unpack with the, with the fact that David is
Speaker 3:  in San Francisco and did not go to that event.
Speaker 3:  And then earlier this week, Alex, you did attend the OpenAI s DevDay.
Speaker 6:  That's right.
Speaker 3:  Which is probably like a pivotal moment in the history of that
Speaker 3:  company because they're, they're headed towards app stores,
Speaker 3:  so there's like quite a lot of news. And then we got a lightning round.
Speaker 3:  But we should start with the fact that I'm using Samsung decks.
Speaker 5:  Well first I should say, we should actually start with an apology, which
Speaker 5:  is that I made certain promises on this show two weeks ago to hold you to
Speaker 5:  a standard of using decks on the podcast. And I did not do that.
Speaker 5:  I abdicated my responsibility in bullying you into using this
Speaker 5:  insane setup that you have going on and on YouTube, there
Speaker 5:  were several people who were very upset with us. And so I just wanna
Speaker 5:  preface whatever Neli ISS about to say as the 30 minutes
Speaker 5:  before we started recording this podcast, were spent with Neli and
Speaker 5:  Liam, our producer, attempting to make this thing that is happening
Speaker 5:  now work.
Speaker 3:  So if you're listening, if you're in your car, close your eyes, pull over,
Speaker 3:  close your eyes. I want you to just imagine my setup. Dell Monitor. Pretty
Speaker 3:  nice. Still monitor actually that we, we just stole it from a desk. Liam
Speaker 3:  just wandered the office and took the nicest one he could find is connected
Speaker 3:  to A-U-S-B-C hub, which is connected to
Speaker 3:  a dead Bluetooth keyboard that is now charging by being plugged into the
Speaker 3:  hub and a, a wired mouse. And the tracking speed of this
Speaker 3:  mouse is out of control. This computer is almost unusable because the tracking
Speaker 3:  speed of this mouse is set at Warp 20. It's out of control.
Speaker 3:  And then that's all plugged into a Galaxy fold five with AD brand skin on
Speaker 3:  it. It's our custom D brandand skin. You can go to store out The Verge dot
Speaker 3:  com. Put that plug in there and I'm, I'm in it man. I'm just running
Speaker 3:  multi windows. Yeah. My dream Alex doesn't know any of this. My dream
Speaker 3:  Alex is that I would commute with nothing. No
Speaker 3:  bag, no laptop. I would just have the fold. I would do phone stuff
Speaker 3:  on the train. I would tell David that his Humane leak was clunky
Speaker 3:  just for my, my folding tablet. Then I would get to the office and I would
Speaker 3:  use decks and this would be my computer at work.
Speaker 3:  And Alex, I just want to you to tell the people what you said
Speaker 3:  immediately upon seeing this setup.
Speaker 6:  Just that looks stupid. I, I actually don't, I don't remember exactly what
Speaker 6:  I said. That was it. Yeah. But yeah, the only
Speaker 6:  thing that could possibly be stupider is like a screenless thing
Speaker 6:  on your lapel I think that you're using but
Speaker 6:  you're not using it. So
Speaker 3:  I. Wish I had one, but we never will. Nope. That seems clear. All, right?
Speaker 3:  So I'm using Dex. We're gonna get through the show notes with Dex.
Speaker 3:  It's not unusable. I would say. Well the monitor's
Speaker 3:  gorgeous. The Dell display that we again just boosted
Speaker 3:  from the working space in this office with, without asking anyone.
Speaker 3:  That's great. And it's basically just a Chromebook that sucks.
Speaker 5:  Neli has the exact energy of the person who brings an iMac to Starbucks
Speaker 5:  and plugs it in. Like that's, that's the vibe that I'm getting from you in
Speaker 5:  the studio right now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You gotta bring this whole setup to Starbucks. That's when we'll really
Speaker 4:  appreciate it
Speaker 3:  All. right. We're gonna try to get through the rundown with this. So let's
Speaker 3:  start with Humane. There's, we're gonna take the first ad break in the show.
Speaker 3:  My laptop is 100% coming back.
Speaker 3:  I just want you all to know this also, just to remind everyone I
Speaker 3:  truly dislike using this phone because of the jelly scrolling. Nothing about
Speaker 3:  this plan was a good idea.
Speaker 4:  I like that. I don't need my laptop open because this screen is so large.
Speaker 4:  I see the whole rundown.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. This is a good case for having a big screen. Yeah. Not a
Speaker 3:  folding phone that runs text All. right. Let's start with Humane. There's
Speaker 3:  a lot of drama with Humane right now.
Speaker 3:  We do a lot of big splashy launch features.
Speaker 3:  David has written a billion of them. I have written half a billion of them.
Speaker 3:  They're fun to do. I appreciate that people do them. It's great. They're,
Speaker 3:  they're like great. This company
Speaker 3:  just from the jump has communicated about itself
Speaker 3:  in the weirdest ways possible. And then they,
Speaker 3:  I'm just gonna say it David, they invited you to California and then ghosted
Speaker 3:  you and you are not at the That's correct. They disinvited you from the
Speaker 3:  event, which is crazy. And I, we know a lot of other reporters and
Speaker 3:  reviewers who are not there either.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. This is a weird situation that I still am trying to wrap my head
Speaker 5:  around because on the one hand, like I think a majority of
Speaker 5:  people who work at Humane used to work at Apple. So there's a
Speaker 5:  real apple like aesthetic and ethos and way of
Speaker 5:  thinking about the world. And Apple is a famously secretive company that
Speaker 5:  has weird ideas about how to sort of bring people in on what it wants to
Speaker 5:  do. And that's all fine and good, right? Like Apple,
Speaker 5:  apple does things its own way and that works fine. But then also
Speaker 5:  Humane has been doing this thing where I think for eight months now, it has
Speaker 5:  been sort of slowly trickling out information about the device. And one of
Speaker 5:  the things we're gonna get into this, but one of the most fascinating things
Speaker 5:  about this launch to me was that it's functionally the same
Speaker 5:  thing that Iran Chowdry the co-founder did
Speaker 5:  on the TED stage like six months ago. Like the,
Speaker 5:  the features are the same, the device is the same. Like my guy just launched
Speaker 5:  it then and it has really not changed all that much since then, which is
Speaker 5:  really fascinating. But yeah, so there was supposed to be a
Speaker 5:  kind of launch thing ahead of the event and then that got
Speaker 5:  changed to being after the event and then a bunch of people got disinvited
Speaker 5:  from that And. what seems very clear is that Humane is not interested
Speaker 5:  in product reviewers getting
Speaker 5:  their hands on this thing at this time. Even the people, they gave these
Speaker 5:  sort of big splashy stories to like Wired had a good story. The Times
Speaker 5:  had a big giant profiley thing. The Wall Street Journal got a story ahead
Speaker 5:  of time. They weren't allowed to photograph the thing. They weren't allowed
Speaker 5:  to like talk that much about how to use it. No one is really trying this
Speaker 5:  thing. It's a strange thing that is happening right now
Speaker 5:  where it is both a launched product that they've been talking about for many
Speaker 5:  months and also seems to be not close to being finished
Speaker 5:  or ready for public consumption. It's very strange. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  A lot of the features were just, they'd be like, they're coming soon. They're
Speaker 4:  coming soon. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like recording video is coming in a software update. It's like that. That's
Speaker 5:  a pretty basic thing to get right on your camera.
Speaker 3:  So we have obviously talked a lot about Humane. David was invited
Speaker 3:  to the event, got disinvited and then last night totally separate from all
Speaker 3:  of that. And the other reviewers we know who
Speaker 3:  didn't get to cover the thing, it was all leak to us. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Which is what happens. That's, that's life. And I'll take the leak every
Speaker 3:  time. So we know a lot about this thing and Yep. There were no
Speaker 3:  surprises. I think most of the leaks we got, all of the leaks we got were
Speaker 3:  dead on accurate today. Yep. So the basics are pretty,
Speaker 3:  they're understandable. And then what's not understandable is this device
Speaker 3:  at all. So the basics are, it's a smartphone, right?
Speaker 3:  It's a Qualcomm eight core. Yep. Qualcomm processor. They didn't say which
Speaker 3:  one but whatever. It's got a camera, it has a person
Speaker 3:  speaker that creates a bubble of sound, which no one has experienced.
Speaker 3:  It has the laser projector, which we've seen it needs
Speaker 3:  wireless service. Obviously they've partnered with T-Mobile, which is really
Speaker 3:  interesting. And it's not just T-Mobile. It's like
Speaker 3:  they have their own wireless network like an MVNO.
Speaker 3:  So You know how like visible is Verizon. Yeah, they've got that. But it's
Speaker 3:  Humane. And so you get a phone number, you can get
Speaker 3:  texts, you're a green bubble. We should talk about that. You get
Speaker 3:  data and you get cloud storage and you get access to OpenAI
Speaker 3:  and Microsoft models and then their slides say had Google
Speaker 3:  and Slack and importantly title
Speaker 4:  And it's weighs about the same as the tennis ball.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Which
Speaker 4:  That, that's the part that's really I'm hanging up on because like
Speaker 4:  my mom gave me this beautiful pen earlier this year that also weighs about
Speaker 4:  the same as a tennis ball. And I'm like, oh I wanna wear this really pretty
Speaker 4:  pen. It's this big gold pen. It's cool. And I'm like, I wanna wear it. I
Speaker 4:  can't wear it with anything because fabrics like
Speaker 4:  just crumple under it And you can see it. What's wild is you can see it in
Speaker 4:  the video, you can see it in the New York Times piece too, where it's just
Speaker 4:  like the, the fabric around the Pin is just crumpling around the weight
Speaker 4:  of the Pin. And I'm like, okay, so this won't work with the T-shirt 'cause
Speaker 4:  it's gonna drag the whole side down. Like you can watch him and he's wearing
Speaker 4:  a shirt, his whole side's like one side of the collar's dragging down from
Speaker 4:  this thing. Yeah. I'm like, why would you? No. Like who wants that?
Speaker 4:  I don't want that.
Speaker 3:  Well you haven't gotten to the battery boosters yet.
Speaker 4:  Oh, sorry.
Speaker 3:  Sorry. I think it's, it's a tennis ball without the batteries.
Speaker 3:  So I would say a huge part of the Humane story
Speaker 3:  is what you might call self seriousness. There are other words you could
Speaker 3:  use, but self seriousness I think really
Speaker 3:  captures it. 'cause I think they're sincere. Yes. And I think that means
Speaker 3:  they're blinded by some of the inherent
Speaker 3:  absurdities of the product. And I'll just give you this example which has
Speaker 3:  made me giggle all day. And this is very clever. Again,
Speaker 3:  I think they're sincere. I think they came up with the solutions. It's very
Speaker 3:  clever. The thing obviously choose through battery. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  'cause it's small
Speaker 3:  and it has an always on wireless connection and it's running GPT and it's
Speaker 3:  got around the mics and it's, it has a laser projector in it.
Speaker 3:  So instead of making it big, they're doing an inductive
Speaker 3:  battery that is the clip. Yeah. So the back of the
Speaker 3:  magnetized clip contains the battery or more battery.
Speaker 3:  So, and you can swap them so that the computer part has a battery in it.
Speaker 3:  And then the back of the thing is called the battery booster and you can
Speaker 3:  hot swap them because the computer part has a battery. Yeah. This is
Speaker 3:  very clever. I don't want to take one ounce. If you were to solve this problem,
Speaker 3:  this is very clever. They're doing this cool inductive thing. Many questions.
Speaker 3:  If the fabric is really thick, does that lower the transfer power? Like all
Speaker 3:  this stuff, but whatever. It's very clever Humane, I
Speaker 3:  just watch this video. They're like, this is a perpetual power
Speaker 3:  system.
Speaker 3:  And it's like my guys, it's a battery. Like
Speaker 3:  is my anchor USBC battery pack a perpetual power
Speaker 3:  system? Yeah. And I think the answer is yes. The apple
Speaker 3:  MagSafe battery attachment is a perpetual bat. Like what are we doing?
Speaker 3:  Like the, the overtalk of the product is out of control. Well didn't David
Speaker 6:  Say that most of the people at Humane used to work at Apple? So doesn't that
Speaker 6:  explain the branding? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It kind of reminded me of a lot of times you'll, you'll get a really good
Speaker 4:  writer out there in the world like writing like a TV show and they go and
Speaker 4:  they write this really cool TV show and you're like, oh man, I wish they
Speaker 4:  ran that show. That would be so cool. Instead of just being like a writer,
Speaker 4:  I want them to run it. And then they go and they run it and no one's
Speaker 4:  there to say, Hey, that's a bad idea. And so you just get
Speaker 4:  unfiltered writer and it's, that's the sa it felt the same way.
Speaker 3:  In fact Alex, I would suggest that the exact opposite happened. Oh
Speaker 4:  You
Speaker 3:  Think, which
Speaker 4:  You mean. Okay. You think these are the bad writers?
Speaker 3:  No, I think that, I mean Iran and, and Bethany, the two leaders of the
Speaker 3:  company worked at Apple that they have a long history. They've built some
Speaker 3:  amazing things. Their names are on some very important technologies. Lemme
Speaker 3:  just read you this section from the Times profile, which I
Speaker 3:  encourage everyone to read. And again, I began
Speaker 4:  The podcast. I mean I can already see it
Speaker 3:  By saying we have written a lot of access based
Speaker 3:  launch features. I love 'em. I love doing 'em. I love reading 'em.
Speaker 3:  They're, they're some of the most fun things you can do. I have no qualms
Speaker 3:  against it, but you add the self seriousness of
Speaker 3:  Humane to the institutional self seriousness of the times.
Speaker 3:  And it's, it's a gold, like every line of this is gold. So
Speaker 3:  when like the writer, no one told them to stop. In fact the exact
Speaker 3:  opposite happened. A Buddhist monk named Brother Spirit led
Speaker 3:  them to Humane.
Speaker 3:  Mr. Chadri and Ms. Angiano had developed concepts for two AI products,
Speaker 3:  a women's health device in the Pin mm. Brother spirit
Speaker 3:  whom they had met through their acupuncturist
Speaker 3:  recommended that they share these ideas with his friend Mark
Speaker 3:  Benioff,
Speaker 3:  the founder of Salesforce, sitting beneath a palm
Speaker 3:  tree on a cliff above the ocean at Mr. Benioff's Hawaiian home.
Speaker 3:  They explained both devices. This one, Mr. Benioff said
Speaker 3:  pointing at the Pin as Dolphins breached to the surf below
Speaker 3:  is huge. It's going to be a massive company. He said
Speaker 4:  He was right about one thing. It is huge.
Speaker 3:  I just wanna know if the Dolphins thing passed the Times fact check. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Do they have three sources on the Dolphins? Incredible.
Speaker 3:  The best part about that whole thing by the way, is that Benioff owns Time
Speaker 3:  Magazine and then Time Magazine just like immediately named the AI Pin best
Speaker 3:  invention of 2023. Like before it'd ever been announced. Yeah, it's
Speaker 3:  good. Yeah. All that's great. That's what I mean by self seriousness.
Speaker 3:  Like maybe this thing's really cool. Maybe having a voice assistant that
Speaker 3:  talks to ChatGPT BT is a really good idea. Mm.
Speaker 3:  It's $700, it costs $24 a month.
Speaker 3:  I don't know about that. I, I
Speaker 5:  Think the, the like very basic thing, like if you describe it the way you
Speaker 5:  just described it, which is a, a voice assistant for talking to chat GPT,
Speaker 5:  I think that is like a real thing that a lot of people are going to have
Speaker 5:  at some point in the very near future. That makes perfect sense to me. Like
Speaker 5:  I have talked to a lot of people who think that there is a really interesting
Speaker 5:  set of hardware to be made around some of these AI things, right? We heard
Speaker 5:  about Sam Altman and Johnny, ive working on some of this stuff
Speaker 5:  together. Like how do you access these language models from an interface
Speaker 5:  is super interesting. What this feels like to
Speaker 5:  me is like, do you remember that period of Samsung where they never
Speaker 5:  said no to anything that it was like any engineer and product manager who
Speaker 5:  was like, I have an idea about how something should work and where a button
Speaker 5:  should go. They just said yes. So there were 40,000 ways to do everything
Speaker 5:  and nothing. None of it actually made any sort of coherent sense.
Speaker 5:  That's what this seems like to me is they like built a bunch of tech demos
Speaker 5:  and then were just like, yes, this is it.
Speaker 3:  Well no, it's yes to anything but a screen. Right, right. Because there's
Speaker 3:  one really easy way to interact with AI chatbots
Speaker 3:  and it's the chat GPT app on the iPhone.
Speaker 3:  You can just get it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Which is It works pretty well. Also has really good voice assistant
Speaker 5:  stuff
Speaker 4:  Now. And I was gonna say Alex, do you and I have both used the Ray bands?
Speaker 4:  Yes. From from from Meta. I, I like 'em. I was wearing 'em on the way to
Speaker 4:  work today. They were great. I infinitely prefer that to
Speaker 4:  this. What about you as a way for accessing voice,
Speaker 6:  For accessing voice? It helps to have something that can sit on your body
Speaker 6:  that isn't dependent on the clothes you wear, I would say. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And You know, speaking of Sam Altman Neli, what did Sam Altman say about
Speaker 6:  Humane in that Times piece?
Speaker 3:  The time piece is so good.
Speaker 6:  So Sam Altman is a, is a large investor in Humane
Speaker 6:  and he's and de
Speaker 5:  Seemingly every other AI thing happening right now, right? Like anybody who's
Speaker 5:  making a hardware, it's like, yep, Sam's there,
Speaker 3:  Right?
Speaker 6:  But yeah, So
Speaker 3:  I, I was talking to our friend Joanna Stern at the journal.
Speaker 3:  She also did not get to interact with the AI Pin.
Speaker 3:  But when I say like they didn't want reviewers there, people who were gonna
Speaker 3:  ask technical questions about how things work. They got reporters there.
Speaker 3:  They in very good reporters went to this So I don't mean to, yeah, it's just
Speaker 3:  a different skill set, a different mindset, whatever. No reviewers have seen
Speaker 3:  this thing. Tech reporters have seen it and they wrote that's great. And
Speaker 3:  many newsrooms have a split between news and reviews. We kind of don't. It's
Speaker 3:  where a tech publication is different, but Joanna didn't get to go and see
Speaker 3:  it. And so she and I were just talking about all of this and she pointed
Speaker 3:  out that Sam Altman, an investor in Humane, was on stage with her
Speaker 3:  at her conference last month. And he, she asked him if he was gonna
Speaker 3:  make a phone and he said, no, phones are great. There's no point in competing
Speaker 3:  with a phone. And then there's these rumors he's working with Johnny Ive,
Speaker 3:  and he said, ah, You know like Demurred. And he said, I think there's something
Speaker 3:  great to do in AI hardware, but I don't know what it is yet.
Speaker 3:  Which is like
Speaker 4:  A month ago. A month.
Speaker 3:  Do you think it's the company you invested in? Maybe. Maybe he's just taking
Speaker 3:  shots. And then today in the Times he's an investor. So the Times
Speaker 3:  talked to him, Sam, I would say waffled,
Speaker 3:  no guarantee of success. That will be up to customers to decide. Maybe it's
Speaker 3:  a bridge too far. Or maybe people are like, this is better than my phone.
Speaker 3:  And then he says to the times, plenty of technology, it looks like a Sher
Speaker 3:  bet ends up selling for 90% off at Best Buy.
Speaker 3:  Which is brutal.
Speaker 4:  Brutal. The Zune
Speaker 3:  Here, the Zune look like a sherbet.
Speaker 6:  We'll we'll talk more about this later, but I was with Sam on
Speaker 6:  Monday at OpenAI. He talked about consumer hardware. He didn't
Speaker 6:  mention Humane and this was days ahead of the
Speaker 6:  public. Everyone knew Humane was about to launch. He didn't acknowledge it,
Speaker 6:  but he got asked about this. We can talk more about this later, but yeah,
Speaker 6:  there is this very interesting pressure happening where people are
Speaker 6:  talking about how can OpenAI intersect with
Speaker 6:  a consumer device. And Sam does not seem to think Humane is
Speaker 6:  that device
Speaker 3:  Because
Speaker 4:  He's invested in this. And also like there's a a necklace too. Like an
Speaker 4:  AI powered necklace. Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  Re it's like the Rewinder Rewind. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  The rewind or something.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, the rewind pendant it's
Speaker 3:  Called. Yeah. All this is great. And. what they're all trying to run away
Speaker 3:  from is the phone. Yeah. Because the second you put a screen on it, this
Speaker 3:  you've made a little phone. And then once you've made a little phone, and
Speaker 3:  we've seen this with every other little phone, you've gotta have Instagram,
Speaker 3:  you've right. Bank apps have to be there. All the stuff that people expect
Speaker 3:  from phones just come for the package. You have to deal with
Speaker 3:  whatever Epic and Google are doing in their trial this week. Right. You
Speaker 3:  can't like, it's too hard. The mountain is too high to climb. So you
Speaker 3:  take the screen off it and you're like, and again, in the Times Fe and in
Speaker 3:  all of the marketing for the Pin, they're like, this is to solve your
Speaker 3:  relationship with your phone. And they are very clear
Speaker 3:  that you should not need a phone. Right. That you're
Speaker 3:  $700, that's the cost of a phone. $24 a month.
Speaker 3:  That's a cost of a data plan. If you've got this and your phone in your pocket,
Speaker 3:  you're doing something wrong.
Speaker 4:  They sent mixed messages there because in the New York Times piece, they
Speaker 4:  end it with saying, oh we we're still using our phones,
Speaker 4:  we just, we use 'em differently. Yeah, but we're still using them. I mean
Speaker 4:  I guess you, you were also still using a phone just differently.
Speaker 3:  So they did answer some questions in the presentation today that I've had
Speaker 3:  for a long time. How does it know your contacts, if you wanna make a call,
Speaker 3:  where do your photos go? All this stuff. When you set up, when you go to
Speaker 3:  order one, you import all your contacts and then it
Speaker 3:  arrives with your contacts preloaded. This is, this is what they want you
Speaker 3:  to do then. Then there's a website called Humane Center
Speaker 3:  where your photos are and your videos are, well your videos when video recording
Speaker 3:  is released, they haven't, what
Speaker 6:  Happens if I meet someone and I add their contact? How do I do
Speaker 6:  that? How does that then get on the Pin
Speaker 4:  Chest bump?
Speaker 3:  I don't know man. These are all, these are all questions that like phones
Speaker 3:  have solved really well and I think this is why when people ask Altman about
Speaker 3:  it, he knows that whatever AI device
Speaker 3:  arrives is gonna sit right next to your phone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And also what is a phone? This thing comes with a phone number.
Speaker 6:  It makes calls. It is a phone. What is a phone? It's a phone. It's a
Speaker 6:  Screenless phone. They made a Screenless phone. So let's stop calling it
Speaker 6:  anything else but that, that's
Speaker 4:  Fair.
Speaker 5:  I don't think the idea that you have to have this and your phone is like
Speaker 5:  a huge strike against Humane. I think we're, we're in this
Speaker 5:  phase now where I think every gadget maker is out there trying to sort
Speaker 5:  of disintermediate the phone with the recognition that like, you're gonna
Speaker 5:  keep having your phone in your pocket. What can we give you that is better
Speaker 5:  and faster? And like it's certainly true that if you want to
Speaker 5:  ask chat GPT a question, the Pin is going to be a faster way to do it
Speaker 5:  than your phone. And that's meaningful. That's real. You don't have to fish
Speaker 5:  a thing outta your pocket. You don't have to unlock a thing. You don't have
Speaker 5:  to open an app. Like that's a better system.
Speaker 3:  Right, right. Until that thing is built into your AirPods,
Speaker 6:  It already is. You can already, with shortcuts on iOS, you can already ask
Speaker 6:  chat GPT things through your AirPods.
Speaker 5:  No Alex. The minute a sentence starts with shortcuts on iOS, like I'm
Speaker 5:  out.
Speaker 3:  Sure. Like,
Speaker 6:  Oh so, so that's harder for you than buying an $800 Pin that you have to
Speaker 6:  sync on the web and pay a monthly. No
Speaker 3:  Alex, you can listen to title on it.
Speaker 4:  I forgot about title.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The persona speakers. But no, but I think the, the problem
Speaker 5:  with a thing like this, and a problem with a lot of these LLMs is
Speaker 5:  they don't do anything. They're really good like information
Speaker 5:  retrieval systems and they're useful for generating text and images. But
Speaker 5:  like I, I want to, I want to add to my contacts,
Speaker 5:  that is not a thing Chat GPT is capable of and Humane is gonna
Speaker 5:  try to be the platform for all of that in the same way that OpenAI is trying
Speaker 5:  to be the platform for that the like the real race underlying all of this
Speaker 5:  is to be the AI app store. Like that is, that is the fight here and
Speaker 5:  everybody wants to do it. And until someone wins
Speaker 5:  that battle, the list of things you can actually do by
Speaker 5:  interacting with an LLM is pretty small.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna get that because that's the OpenAI story, right?
Speaker 6:  Yes. But D David, what David is hitting on is very important here, which
Speaker 6:  is that You know you saying ChatGPT BT is a good information
Speaker 6:  retrieval system. I would argue that it's not, and the problem
Speaker 6:  with this Humane product is that it's core tech, which is
Speaker 6:  like talk to OpenAI, guess what? ChatGPT BT makes
Speaker 6:  shit up all the time. Like and they know this and
Speaker 6:  Sam talked about this with me and other reporters on Monday and he doesn't
Speaker 6:  think this problem will be solved for like three years.
Speaker 6:  So this is a at least, so this is a device you're buying where the
Speaker 6:  primary interface, information retrieval system, the people who designed
Speaker 6:  it know that it has still a huge accuracy problem. I was using
Speaker 6:  chat GPT to try to do some earnings coverage. It just made the financials
Speaker 6:  up for the company. I was so, so imagine walking around and this
Speaker 6:  is your only device on you and you ask it something and it's like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  take a left to go here and you end up like walking into oncoming
Speaker 6:  traffic. Right. So
Speaker 3:  This raises another important point, which is we still dunno how It
Speaker 3:  works. Like even in all the coverage you can read and in their demos,
Speaker 3:  we don't know like is it OpenAI underneath
Speaker 3:  it in the press release? It just says Microsoft and OpenAI models
Speaker 3:  doesn't say which ones. They said
Speaker 5:  In a couple of the stories that it's, it's chat GPT primarily So I think,
Speaker 5:  I think we can fairly safely assume it's a
Speaker 6:  ChatGPT they're they're using open AI's. API. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Right. But then the, there's the Google logo sitting right in their
Speaker 3:  press release and I don't know why. Then they claim they have their own platform
Speaker 3:  called my AI and maybe it is all just chat GBT
Speaker 4:  And it's all cloud-based, right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Which I think is also why it burns through batteries because
Speaker 4:  Yeah, well it burns through batteries and it also, that just cuts off a
Speaker 4:  huge user base. There's a ton of people who can't have ready access to the
Speaker 4:  cloud all the time. Right. Like internet is inconsistent. They weren't gonna
Speaker 4:  buy it anyway.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You think the people in rural America, or
Speaker 4:  Are you saying they were not watching the CAPI show's to see it like, oh
Speaker 4:  my
Speaker 3:  God it's it's running on the T-Mobile network. Yeah. Those people were already
Speaker 3:  left out.
Speaker 3:  It's just like even that stuff, right? It primarily the ChatGPT
Speaker 3:  B-T-A-P-I, that's what we think it is. We don't know.
Speaker 3:  No one's actually used it to figure out its limits. No one's actually used
Speaker 3:  it to figure out if when you ask it for directions, it falls back to Google
Speaker 3:  Maps or something like, or Bing Maps or whatever
Speaker 3:  acquisition. No, like Microsoft made through the Nokia deal 500 years ago
Speaker 3:  that they forgot about that still runs and somehow makes $5 million. Which
Speaker 3:  is the true story of many Microsoft acquisitions.
Speaker 3:  And because it doesn't have a screen, you, the user will never
Speaker 3:  know. Like you'll ask it a question and it can never tell you how it arrived
Speaker 3:  at the answer. Which has been a problem with voice assistance in general
Speaker 3:  for a very long time.
Speaker 6:  It could list sources, but still, like I don't, we'll talk more about this
Speaker 6:  later. I don't trust chat GPT for like information because it
Speaker 6:  hallucinates. Yeah. And so if you're thinking date like tactically this is
Speaker 6:  my new phone, this is how I'm gonna interact with the internet.
Speaker 6:  The main way that you're doing that, you cannot inherently trust
Speaker 6:  what is being said back to you. How is that a replacement for the
Speaker 6:  devices we already have? It doesn't make sense.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. There's this interesting moment in the, the demo video that they put
Speaker 5:  out, which everyone should watch. It's, it's Wild. Neli has suggestion to
Speaker 5:  me it was to watch it at two x speed, which it seems like normal speed, which
Speaker 5:  is good advice. But there's this one moment in it where he holds up I
Speaker 5:  think a book to the Pin and says, how much does this
Speaker 5:  cost online? He's, he's like demonstrating the shopping features and he's
Speaker 5:  like, how much does this cost online? And it responds, it costs $28 online.
Speaker 5:  And he says Buy it. And that's the end of the demo. And it's like, I have
Speaker 5:  a million questions between here and there. Like
Speaker 5:  there's only one price on the whole internet for this thing. Where did that
Speaker 5:  price come from? Where am I buying it from? How fast is it gonna ship? Where's
Speaker 5:  it gonna ship? Which credit card did it use? Like Amazon has gone through
Speaker 5:  this problem where if you just say to your echo speaker
Speaker 5:  by toilet paper, it turns out that actually takes you through a flow that
Speaker 5:  you don't understand and can go wrong in a thousand ways. And people don't
Speaker 5:  do it as a result. And the idea that Humane
Speaker 5:  is going for is to abstract even more of that away and to just
Speaker 5:  say, all you have to do is just describe to this thing what you wanna accomplish
Speaker 5:  in the world and it will do it for you. And I think that's a super interesting
Speaker 5:  and completely impossible. Yeah. The thesis,
Speaker 3:  The price online is $28. It's like, is it Amazon?
Speaker 3:  Do you think Amazon is the, the only store?
Speaker 6:  Is it, who knows eBay?
Speaker 3:  Like right. Who knows? Maybe
Speaker 5:  It's an artist and it's like, by doing this, am I signing up for
Speaker 5:  whoever Humane has decided to like Rev share partner with in order to be
Speaker 5:  able to do this? Should I be able to choose? And at that point, if I'm choosing,
Speaker 5:  what are we accomplishing by abstracting all of this away? There's just no
Speaker 5:  version of this that feels good in the way that you kind of want it to.
Speaker 3:  And by the way, the book is a easy example in the sort of medium
Speaker 3:  scheme of things. Because the book has a barcode and maybe it has
Speaker 3:  a barcode. Maybe he can see the title. Yeah. And right there's
Speaker 3:  structured data. Yeah. On and around the book.
Speaker 3:  There's another part of that demo where he just holds up a handful of almonds
Speaker 3:  and he says how many, how much protein is in these almonds? And it just
Speaker 3:  tells him it's 15 grams. Mm. And it's like, did it count
Speaker 3:  the almonds? And I pointed out it must be kind of almonds. And Liam
Speaker 3:  said, well technically you'd wanna weigh the almonds,
Speaker 3:  right? Because you're inside of that Chad GBT is just making up
Speaker 3:  grams per almond. Yes. Average. And then spitting out
Speaker 3:  a number amount of protein
Speaker 6:  Using a dubiously data collected source
Speaker 6:  that could be accurate or could not be accurate. Yeah. Who knows that you
Speaker 6:  would not know. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And it's like all you've made is like a very complicated lose it. And you
Speaker 3:  don't know if it's counting the almonds accurately. That's weird.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean it's, I mean it's not good. There's
Speaker 3:  No structured data about the almonds.
Speaker 6:  There are a mil, I mean there are a million holes you can poke in this thing.
Speaker 6:  And I think we're doing that appropriately. I think the direction Humane
Speaker 6:  is trying to go here is really interesting. And I want to have competing
Speaker 6:  visions for where computing is going in the world because everyone else,
Speaker 6:  meta, et cetera, apple, they think the future of computing is
Speaker 6:  more visuals in your eyes, right? Like literally
Speaker 6:  augmenting over the world. And Humane is saying no, we think actually
Speaker 6:  computing should be recessed more into the background and you should
Speaker 6:  interact through voice. And it's more of that Spike Jones her future. And
Speaker 6:  I think those different directions need to exist. People need to be building
Speaker 6:  those different directions. It just feels very early. This feels like General
Speaker 6:  Magic or Magic Leap. You know, there's a ton of examples of
Speaker 6:  companies that were just too early to the tech. And I think this is the case
Speaker 6:  here.
Speaker 3:  No, I'll make a, I'll make a big distinction between those things because
Speaker 3:  we, oh, now we're old and we know a bunch of external magic people. They
Speaker 3:  were very sincere. Tony Fidel's friend of the show, he was part of the general
Speaker 3:  magic story. He financed the documentary, a self-serving documentary.
Speaker 3:  But you will take, 'cause they all come out as heroes like in the end.
Speaker 3:  But it's, it's a fun watch. And I encourage you to go watch the General Magic
Speaker 3:  documentary. They were nerds, like huge nerds. And
Speaker 3:  they did not think they were cool and they thought they were inventing the
Speaker 3:  future fine. But at the end of the day, they were like
Speaker 3:  silly nerds.
Speaker 6:  They didn't put their Pin on like fashion models in Paris fashion. They,
Speaker 3:  They weren't, none of that stuff was happening. Right? Yeah. No, Capri show
Speaker 3:  Magic Leap. Huge Nerds obviously took
Speaker 3:  themselves so seriously. Well they
Speaker 4:  Blew Beyonce away,
Speaker 3:  Right? They had other people down there for demos. I think
Speaker 3:  David got a demo once. Didn't you go down there at some point, David? I
Speaker 5:  Got a demo. It wasn't, I didn't get the full treatment, but I did get to
Speaker 5:  try it at one point. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 3:  They said things like we're hacking the GPU of the mind, which is,
Speaker 3:  it's just an incredible phrase. They promised to reinvent
Speaker 3:  all of entertainment. Yeah. All of technology
Speaker 3:  that like this thing was, and they got so far ahead of the
Speaker 3:  technology with the hype and the seriousness that
Speaker 3:  there was no way the product could have lived up to their own ideas. General
Speaker 3:  Magic was early, but they weren't, they knew that
Speaker 3:  there was a thing that they were trying to get to that was far away
Speaker 3:  from where they were. And they were honest about it, I think.
Speaker 3:  And if that's the spectrum of companies that are too early, like sincere
Speaker 3:  nerds trying to build the future and they're aware of their limitations and
Speaker 3:  kind of silly and honest about it. And we've hyped ourselves so much
Speaker 3:  that nothing we invent can meet the standard. Like Humane is
Speaker 3:  beyond that. You think it's beyond Magic Leap? I think it's
Speaker 3:  beyond magically. Wow. Wow.
Speaker 4:  But it actually is
Speaker 3:  Because they, they're out there. They have their employees ex Apple people
Speaker 3:  in the press today saying they, they had retired from Apple
Speaker 3:  and they joined Humane because they were disgusted
Speaker 3:  with having invented the iPhone and destroyed society. And Humane
Speaker 3:  is their chance to like reset. And it's like, you guys, I don't even
Speaker 3:  know if it's counting the almonds You know. It's like imagine what
Speaker 3:  bookstore You know. It's like that's crazy. And if you are, if you are
Speaker 3:  positioning is that this will rescue us from the phone, but you've made a
Speaker 3:  phone
Speaker 3:  no nothing. There's, there's no product that can fill the hole
Speaker 3:  that they are drawing. Right? And that is the
Speaker 3:  issue I think with the, the product itself in many big ways, but
Speaker 3:  also like how they're putting it out into market. But this
Speaker 5:  Is also, this is just the world we live in now. I mean, I think about like
Speaker 5:  Carl Pay and nothing, like he's running around being like, there are no interesting
Speaker 5:  consumer electronics companies left. And it's like, well that just isn't
Speaker 5:  true. But you have to like, you have to tell this big grand
Speaker 5:  story about yourself and how you're changing the world. And it's like we
Speaker 5:  still live in the, we're making the world a better place thing, which you
Speaker 5:  would think Silicon Valley would've killed like by just
Speaker 5:  being on that TV show. But it didn't. And So I think
Speaker 5:  honestly like the, the single worst thing that Apple has done to tech culture
Speaker 5:  is convince everybody that this is the right way to talk about your products.
Speaker 5:  That everything has to be finished. Everything has to appear as if it was
Speaker 5:  inevitable and just sort of rose out of the ground. This perfect finished
Speaker 5:  product that we have solved every problem that has ever existed in the world.
Speaker 5:  And there are no companies anymore who are making things being like, we
Speaker 5:  made this. We don't know if it's any good. Do you want it? Ironically, OpenAI
Speaker 5:  is probably the closest thing to that right now. Yeah. But it's, it's just
Speaker 5:  not, it's just not how this works anymore. And the playbook
Speaker 5:  worked so well for Apple that if you're a company who raised a lot of money
Speaker 5:  and would like to make a lot of money, you just follow the Apple playbook.
Speaker 5:  And I think the thing we've learned over and over is that it doesn't work
Speaker 5:  for anybody other than Apple. I
Speaker 4:  Don't think this is fair because there are a lot of interesting consumer
Speaker 4:  tech companies that aren't doing this. They're not based in Silicon Valley.
Speaker 4:  They're not, they're not in this like weird investor
Speaker 4:  ecosystem, right? Where, where they're there there, there's almost this demand
Speaker 4:  from their investors to ship something and to change the world at the same
Speaker 4:  time. Right? Like there's plenty of weird tablets in China.
Speaker 4:  China's doing a lot of cool consumer tech gadgets and not promising to change
Speaker 4:  the world with their Steam Deck knockoffs.
Speaker 3:  It would be amazing if Apple was like, we made these gamer lights. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  they're awesome.
Speaker 4:  They're just cool. Yeah, they're never gonna do that.
Speaker 6:  But if you go back to like the launch of the original iPhone, Steve Dobbs,
Speaker 6:  he didn't say it's gonna change the world. He was like, here are three things
Speaker 6:  it can do at once. Well,
Speaker 3:  No, he did start with today Apple reinvents the phone.
Speaker 6:  But that's not, but that's
Speaker 3:  Different with his arms outstretched. I would
Speaker 6:  Argue that's different than what Humane's doing than what Magic Leap did.
Speaker 6:  Which is like, it's the hubris, right? And Apple has hubris
Speaker 6:  on You know they have tons of it and Steve Jobs was the king of hubris. But
Speaker 6:  like yeah, you go back to that original iPhone, there was like an almost
Speaker 6:  weird humility with the hubris, right? Where it was like we actually were
Speaker 6:  just focusing on what it does. And what it did was such a aha moment
Speaker 6:  where everybody in the room was like, oh my God, these three things together
Speaker 6:  in a mobile form factor. Yes. You didn't have to overexplain it. Whereas
Speaker 6:  like Humane, they, they can't explain it. Like, because it's,
Speaker 6:  it's incomprehensible. There's, it's a, it's an idea in search of a
Speaker 6:  product. Right? And and I think that was, that's the key difference here
Speaker 6:  between like the early Apple where Apple is now and Humane I think.
Speaker 6:  So
Speaker 3:  Here's a question I have for you, Alex, just thinking about the, the cycle
Speaker 3:  OpenAI is in. Yeah. Brother Spirit, the Buddhist monk introduced
Speaker 3:  them to Mark Benioff in
Speaker 3:  2018. The connection by the way, made through their acupuncturists
Speaker 3:  very, this is all very important detail. 2018. That's a
Speaker 3:  long time ago. Yeah. To, to start working on this. Pin OpenAI was
Speaker 3:  nowhere in 2018, right? The
Speaker 3:  the first glimmers of the thing were happening. They
Speaker 6:  Were a research project. Yeah. They were, they were, they were maybe 60 people
Speaker 6:  at that point. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And they were still kind of focused on not being a commercial company.
Speaker 3:  So if you're making this product in 2018 and you have this vision,
Speaker 3:  what is the technology that you're basing this on? What have they been
Speaker 3:  working on? Oh,
Speaker 4:  Oh, I, I know it. What
Speaker 3:  Happened, right? There's, there's a pivot that's that's contained in the
Speaker 3:  story of this product where they were like, you're gonna talk to chat GPT
Speaker 3:  and that's the thing that's gonna sell it. Right? Because that's what we're
Speaker 3:  talking about today. In 2018, you could not begin work on that
Speaker 3:  product. Well
Speaker 6:  Chat It didn't exist. Chat GPT. That's what I mean. It barely existed a year
Speaker 6:  ago. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  This was totally gonna be like an Android product until
Speaker 4:  OpenAI popped off. Right. Like that that had to have been what happened.
Speaker 4:  They were, they were building their own little android dumb like dumb phone.
Speaker 4:  'cause it's effectively a dumb phone. Right? And, and then OpenAI
Speaker 4:  popped off and they were like, oh, finally we have something cool to attach
Speaker 4:  this to, to ship it so we're not just like we did a phone, but it's a Pin
Speaker 4:  and not really a good phone.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I don't know. I there's just, I'm, I'm like thinking about this chronology
Speaker 3:  and it's like in 2018 when you set off to make this product,
Speaker 3:  you cannot assume that there will be an LLM explosion
Speaker 3:  in mid 2023.
Speaker 4:  No, but you could assume
Speaker 3:  That recontextualizes this whole product,
Speaker 4:  But you could assume Google was doing, Google was doing a lot at that point,
Speaker 4:  right? They were doing a lot about visual identity, like, like being able
Speaker 4:  to visually ID things with a camera. They were doing a lot about being able
Speaker 4:  to just talk and, and have those natural conversations with Google, Google
Speaker 4:  Assistant. Like all of that was happening in 2018. So I, I,
Speaker 4:  that's why I'm, I'm fully convinced that at some point we're gonna find out
Speaker 4:  that this was originally an Android product.
Speaker 5:  I mean it's an Android product now. Like the thing, the thing runs Android.
Speaker 5:  I I think you're exactly right. I think if you, if you rewind five years,
Speaker 5:  they're looking at voice assistant and Google
Speaker 5:  Lens and some of these other, like what can we do without
Speaker 5:  putting a screen and a bunch of apps on your smartphone? Which
Speaker 5:  in the abstract, like Heath has been saying is a really interesting and valuable
Speaker 5:  question. Like, this is stuff we should be talking about. Because the idea
Speaker 5:  that the like platonic ideal of how we interact with technology
Speaker 5:  is like a grid of icons on a screen is just not true. And
Speaker 5:  we, we should be exploring all these things. But I do think it's very clear
Speaker 5:  that at some point along the way they went from, we're gonna
Speaker 5:  have to cobble together a bunch of different things and probably invent a
Speaker 5:  bunch of technology ourselves to just, this is now we are an interface
Speaker 5:  company on top of chat GPT, which is functionally what this is, this
Speaker 5:  is a, this is a, it's a revolutionary input device on par
Speaker 5:  with the, with the keyboard and mouse for chat GPT.
Speaker 5:  Like that's what they're trying to build. They, they make a big song and
Speaker 5:  dance about all their stuff they can do. But this is functionally a way to
Speaker 5:  input things to chat GPT. That is what this device exists to do. It's
Speaker 4:  A real digital crown moment.
Speaker 3:  You know any minute Apple's going to do a partnership with one of these
Speaker 3:  companies 'cause they can't build it by themselves 'cause of all the privacy
Speaker 3:  reasons. And they will say, if you want to use chat GBT,
Speaker 3:  your Apple Watch can do it. And that will be the end of the AI Pin.
Speaker 6:  Oh, I will take the opposite side of that bet. Yeah. I I'll bet money that
Speaker 6:  they will not. Yeah, because because of, because of the privacy reasons
Speaker 6:  you cited, they will not do this as an external partnership. No, but we're
Speaker 3:  Watching this in the trial right now where Tim Cook and Sundar
Speaker 3:  Petya are in meetings discussing their search deal and
Speaker 3:  apple's like your services can begin where our
Speaker 3:  limitations end. So you can see they could
Speaker 3:  say, well,
Speaker 6:  Well that there's an important fact there, which is that Google is paying
Speaker 6:  Apple on the order of $20 billion a year. So yes, if someone
Speaker 6:  is paying you You know 20% of your profit margin. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  sure. You can have deep partnerships.
Speaker 3:  You don't think OpenAI and Microsoft are gonna, they're gonna throw that
Speaker 3:  money down. Like that's what I mean, the second Apple gets over it and there's
Speaker 3:  a few ways for 'em to get over it. They can invent a privacy focused LLM
Speaker 3:  very hard inside your values. You could take the money.
Speaker 3:  It's true. Or you can do shortcuts with David's favorite
Speaker 5:  Love shortcuts.
Speaker 3:  But like, all I'm saying is there's a big action button on the side of my
Speaker 3:  watch and there's a lot of different ways for that thing to trigger. Talk
Speaker 3:  to ChatGPT GPT. Yeah. Right. There's, there's many methods by
Speaker 3:  which that button can, can do the thing. And at that moment,
Speaker 3:  the value of $700 plus another $24 of
Speaker 3:  service fees a month, like begins to slide.
Speaker 4:  If I hold my phone just right, I can do the shortcuts method
Speaker 4:  with chat GPT and the Raybans.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like it. And, and they're adding, so Cranz, they're adding early next
Speaker 6:  year. Zuckerberg was talking to me about this when I interviewed him ahead
Speaker 6:  of Connect. They're gonna do a software update for the Raybans where it's
Speaker 6:  visual recognition. So in the interview he was like, you'll just look at
Speaker 6:  the camera and say, what is that camera? Where can I buy it? And he didn't
Speaker 6:  say buy it. He said, where can I buy it? And because so, so that's,
Speaker 6:  that's a much more, I think, compelling because it's on you. Right. And
Speaker 4:  Cheaper. And
Speaker 6:  Cheaper. No subscription. And
Speaker 4:  Like if you go, if you go to the beach, you don't have to worry about
Speaker 4:  right. Where you're gonna Pin it.
Speaker 6:  And it turns out And what kind of shots you're gonna get your head is on
Speaker 6:  you all the time. Who knew? And you can have stuff on your head
Speaker 6:  all the time no matter what you're wearing. It's actually a really cool human
Speaker 6:  feature. Okay. This
Speaker 3:  Brings me to the last thing I want to talk about in this sequence, which
Speaker 3:  is a graph that's in my head at all times. Oh,
Speaker 6:  Is there AY axis?
Speaker 3:  There's AY and I'm, I'm gonna label the graph for you. So pull over in your
Speaker 3:  car and I want you to imagine X in Y web axis. Okay. And I've worked this
Speaker 3:  out 'cause I was on threads last night and people really helped me figure
Speaker 3:  this out. This is the formula of
Speaker 3:  wearable product success. Mm.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I, I, I saw this on threads.
Speaker 3:  Okay, so it's X and y axis.
Speaker 3:  It doesn't matter which side, which the Y axis, let's call
Speaker 3:  it. Okay. Is amount. I have to care about this shit
Speaker 4:  All, right.
Speaker 3:  Times
Speaker 3:  face multiple.
Speaker 6:  Which is what's a what's a face?
Speaker 3:  Is it on my face? Okay. Oh, okay. Okay. And is it a VR headset? So like,
Speaker 3:  is it on my face and it's like a cool pair of sunglasses, low face, multiple
Speaker 3:  mm. Is it on my face? And it's the medic quest pro high, enormous
Speaker 3:  face. Multiple. Yeah. If it's not on your face, on your wrist, no face. Multiple.
Speaker 4:  Okay,
Speaker 3:  You
Speaker 4:  Got me. Got it. I
Speaker 3:  See it. Okay. So that's like, that's just one variable. Yeah, it's either
Speaker 3:  it's, and you gotta decide for yourself in the glasses, how much do I have
Speaker 3:  to care about it? Is, is this a tiny little computer? Do I
Speaker 3:  got a software update? Plug it into battery charge. It does it Beep
Speaker 3:  computer stuff. Yeah. And you gotta decide. Is it weird to get the photos
Speaker 3:  off it? Yeah. All in the first factor. Yeah. So
Speaker 3:  fids times, is it face? That's one axis.
Speaker 3:  Okay. And then the X axis is how useful is it? Okay.
Speaker 3:  Okay. So if X is greater than or equal to Y, so there's a
Speaker 3:  line at 45 degrees.
Speaker 6:  Oh God.
Speaker 3:  Then it's, it's good. And if it's lower, you're
Speaker 3:  duped. So like regular glasses, right? Alex, you're wearing
Speaker 3:  some glasses. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You
Speaker 3:  Gotta think about them. Never. So low number times on your
Speaker 3:  face, low number. 'cause you have cool glasses value very high.
Speaker 3:  So you're like historic success.
Speaker 6:  Oh, right. Okay. See I didn't do well at math in school, but I, I think I'm
Speaker 6:  tracking with you.
Speaker 3:  You see what I'm saying? No. Neli also de is describing a graph that has
Speaker 3:  like six or seven different s It's just one, it's just two numbers. So, I
Speaker 4:  Wouldn't, there's there's algebra involved.
Speaker 3:  Isly bullshit. Greater than or less than.
Speaker 3:  How
Speaker 6:  Useful is this? I'm gonna make a GPT for this. Where you can just,
Speaker 3:  And I'm just saying the only real variable here is face.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 3:  It's, it's really just fake. Is it on your face? And then it's gotta be super
Speaker 3:  valuable. Right? Right, right. Apple watch a lot of fiddly bits at the beginning.
Speaker 3:  Low value.
Speaker 4:  Not on your
Speaker 3:  Face. Not on your face. But it still didn't do a lot at the beginning.
Speaker 3:  You could like send flirty heartbeats to people who maybe didn't want them.
Speaker 3:  Right. And they figured it out and they brought it up above the curve. And
Speaker 3:  now it's actually kind of less fiddly too. Yeah. Success. Okay. Me, quest
Speaker 3:  pro fid likeliest product in the world, gigantic
Speaker 3:  face, multiple, no value. No
Speaker 4:  Value,
Speaker 3:  Not a success. They won't even talk about it anymore. Hmm. You see what I'm
Speaker 3:  saying? So Humane ai Pin, very fiddly,
Speaker 3:  no face. Multiple unclear value. Big question
Speaker 3:  mark. Yeah. Vision pro. Enormous
Speaker 3:  face multiple on the order of, they put another face on your face, right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Huge problem there. Very
Speaker 3:  fiddly, we think. Or perhaps not because it's kind of standalone,
Speaker 3:  unclear. Fids, unclear value
Speaker 4:  X, it's an X, the value is X. Who
Speaker 3:  Knows? I'm just telling you, this works every time.
Speaker 6:  Wow.
Speaker 3:  Someone's gonna animate this graph and it's gonna be amazing. But I promise
Speaker 3:  you, if you just work this out for any product, you get there. So the the
Speaker 3:  meta glasses, people like 'em, right? Yeah. So you do
Speaker 3:  it, they look cool. Low face, multiple, eh, fiddly.
Speaker 4:  Liam complimented mine today before he saw the, the, the
Speaker 3:  Lenses before he knew. Yeah. So medium face multiple, because people are
Speaker 3:  like, oh, you've been, you've been watching me creep. That's a problem. But
Speaker 3:  they look cool. Yeah. And then they're fun, right? Because they
Speaker 3:  have good music, they've got great call mics. You should watch that video
Speaker 3:  with Becca.
Speaker 4:  They're useful.
Speaker 3:  They're useful. Right on the line of success.
Speaker 6:  Okay. I, my challenge to any Vergecast listener right now who's playing with
Speaker 6:  Chad GT's, GPT builder, is to make a GPT based on what
Speaker 6:  Neli just said, send it to us and it's gonna be
Speaker 6:  amazing.
Speaker 3:  Fids Times face, multiple has to be less than or equal
Speaker 3:  to. How useful is it? What
Speaker 6:  Is this bot called? Eli's. Eli's Gadget Or Eli's, yeah.
Speaker 6:  Wearable
Speaker 3:  Value. It needs a
Speaker 6:  Good name. Yeah. Indicator. This is a horrible name.
Speaker 3:  The theory of wearable bullshit.
Speaker 6:  Okay, there we go. That's the episode title.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It needs a name. I, I am just telling you, I've been working this out
Speaker 3:  on the show forever and last night it finally clicked when I looked at the
Speaker 3:  Humane Pin where I was like, oh, it's not on your face. So that changes
Speaker 3:  the whole equation. But then it is all the other things that it is,
Speaker 3:  I was disgusted by my work on the iPhone, so instead I made a little laser
Speaker 3:  projector that you have to look at your hand.
Speaker 4:  There's no Instagram, can't do Instagram with lasers. Just
Speaker 3:  Doesn't work. This thing is real silly. They should've let us, they should've
Speaker 3:  let us and other reviewers actually into it and they should have been less
Speaker 3:  self serious about it, is what I'll say. I'm excited to play with one. I
Speaker 3:  think we're all excited about new gadgets all the time.
Speaker 4:  I wanna see how the speakers work. I wanna
Speaker 3:  The person speaker.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I wanna see, I want you and I both to have one and see if we can hear
Speaker 4:  each other's. That's
Speaker 3:  Gonna be the worst episode of the show.
Speaker 4:  The worst episode. I'm sorry, just
Speaker 3:  Sorry. People posting a title four feet apart.
Speaker 1:  I mean, I will say again, to go back to the meta things on that one, like
Speaker 1:  I've seen a bunch of people be like, oh, the person speaker, that's, this
Speaker 1:  is the thing that the smart glasses have been doing for a while, right? This
Speaker 1:  like personal directed audio that you can hear and other people
Speaker 1:  don't is like relatively proven technology.
Speaker 6:  The Ray bands do that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I do this and I hear so well with the Ray bands.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's the projector. I sit on the train like this. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  The projector is what I want to try. I want to, I'm going to a concert Friday.
Speaker 6:  I wish I had this so that during the concert I could just hold my hand out
Speaker 6:  and it just like matrix displays. Are
Speaker 3:  You gonna a concert that sucks. Is anyone else gonna be there?
Speaker 6:  No, I'm just, I just wanna do it to get the reaction around me. You know,
Speaker 6:  like,
Speaker 3:  It's like you're, you're Alex is in the pitch. Just like
Speaker 4:  I just assume it's very bright.
Speaker 3:  Try not. I brought my own laser show.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, there you go.
Speaker 3:  That would be actually be sick. Okay, here's the killer app for the Humane
Speaker 3:  ai Pin personal laser show.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. Imagine Coldplay. And instead of the the bracelets they give you,
Speaker 6:  it's just the Pins. They all, they
Speaker 3:  All, yeah. This is a good time to know. Synced
Speaker 4:  To your
Speaker 3:  Title account Labs had it bored ape NFT party and they bought the
Speaker 3:  wrong EV lights and they burned everyone's eyes. I love that. Maybe don't
Speaker 3:  do the laser show thing. Just an idea. All, right? We gotta take a break.
Speaker 3:  That's a true story by the way. It's heartbreaking. Check your EV lights.
Speaker 3:  We gotta take a break. We'll be right back to talk about OpenAI Day.
Speaker 3:  All right we're back. Less hardware this time, more software, but the future
Speaker 3:  of software in a very exciting way. Alex, you went to OpenAI s DevDay
Speaker 3:  this week. They announced a bunch of stuff. Take us through
Speaker 6:  It. Yeah, so this was in downtown San Francisco Monday
Speaker 6:  and this was Open AI's first big conference. And
Speaker 6:  when I was going to it like realizing that ChatGPT PT is not even
Speaker 6:  a year old at this point, like blew my mind. And then you get
Speaker 6:  there and they have about a thousand developers there and it
Speaker 6:  just had this energy of I, I'll get into the announcements, but I think it's
Speaker 6:  important to like contextualize the energy. It felt like
Speaker 6:  the early Apple events, it felt like this buzz that You know we had that
Speaker 6:  a little bit. I think You know David and Eli, you were there too for the
Speaker 6:  Vision Pro unveiling that had a an a special kind of feel
Speaker 6:  'cause You know people had high hopes for Apple finally doing a big new thing.
Speaker 6:  But like this just felt like something I haven't experienced since like early
Speaker 6:  Mac Worlds and you get in
Speaker 6:  and I mean they did a really nice keynote. It was about an hour and a
Speaker 6:  half's worth of content packed into like a tight 45 minutes with
Speaker 6:  like real live demos. Like there was a moment where they were showing off
Speaker 6:  like a Zapier integration where you could like have a bot, you make You know
Speaker 6:  text someone or send them a slack based on what you tell it. And like they're
Speaker 6:  doing it on stage live. They're building the thing in like a minute and then
Speaker 6:  like it sends the pinging to Sam and he's on the other side of the stage
Speaker 6:  and he just holds his phone up and is like, yep, got it. Like, like I,
Speaker 6:  I really don't like the direction the industry's going thanks to Apple where
Speaker 6:  it's these highly produced pre-recorded keynotes that are
Speaker 6:  really just like becoming marketing videos. I think we saw that with the
Speaker 6:  last Mac event especially.
Speaker 6:  So open a, it felt like this return to form that was like, wow, this feels
Speaker 6:  good. In terms of what they announced, it was a lot.
Speaker 6:  I mean I think like the most immediate thing that the developers were like
Speaker 6:  freaking out about and like Sam had to tell everyone to like stop clapping
Speaker 6:  'cause they kept clapping over and over was just like making GPT
Speaker 6:  cheaper to use as a developer. So it's like three times cheaper.
Speaker 6:  They've got GTP four Turbo, which apparently
Speaker 6:  people really want larger context windows, which is the ability to upload
Speaker 6:  more text tokens to these models and do more with them. So I think
Speaker 6:  the limit was around like 20 ish K max before and now it's
Speaker 6:  like 128 plus K context window.
Speaker 6:  So you could put a book in this thing and have it do all kinds of things.
Speaker 6:  People got really excited about that. And then a bunch of like kind of
Speaker 6:  more developer focused stuff, right? It's a developer conference. The biggest
Speaker 6:  thing though was this new AI platform. I mean really
Speaker 6:  what OpenAI wants to become, and I wrote about this in command
Speaker 6:  line this week, is the app store of ai. And so they've got this
Speaker 6:  new GPT platform where with no coding required,
Speaker 6:  you can build your own GPT, upload custom knowledge
Speaker 6:  and do a bunch of what is essentially like abstracting away prompt engineering,
Speaker 6:  right? And making it very like tailored to a specific use case
Speaker 6:  and do all that in like honestly a matter of minutes. I got a live demo of
Speaker 6:  one of these things being made and you can do it in under five minutes and
Speaker 6:  then just publish it to the web eventually. And
Speaker 6:  when I say eventually, I think just in like a few weeks, OpenAI is gonna
Speaker 6:  have this store, the GPT store. And that's where things get really interesting
Speaker 6:  I think because you're seeing OpenAI, not only is it becoming a a
Speaker 6:  huge developer platform, an external platform
Speaker 6:  that powers other things. They have over 2 million developers in under a
Speaker 6:  year, which is just like wild. But they've got this massive
Speaker 6:  growing consumer business. They have a hundred million weekly users of
Speaker 6:  chat GPT, which is like a a for a product that is less than a year old
Speaker 6:  is just absolutely insane. That means their monthlies are probably on the
Speaker 6:  order of half a billion. And so what they're trying to do is like
Speaker 6:  aggregate that audience and also become a consumer internet
Speaker 6:  platform and, and have people making GPTs no
Speaker 6:  coding required that they then surface to people through
Speaker 6:  chat GPT and through the store. And so the store is coming very soon but
Speaker 6:  they, they showed a preview of it and I think that's where things get really
Speaker 6:  interesting. Is that a hundred million,
Speaker 3:  Is that GPT plus the
Speaker 6:  Paid thing or just ChatGPT that chat GPT users, they didn't give a plus number.
Speaker 6:  Very important for the the custom GPT. You have to be a plus subscriber
Speaker 6:  to access and build the custom GPT. So this is all feeding
Speaker 6:  that loop of like OpenAI, I think I the information reported, they're already
Speaker 6:  on like a 1 billion a year revenue run rate with the consumer
Speaker 6:  subscription business. They really want to have more reasons to pay
Speaker 6:  for chat GPT and, and an app store and custom GPT and
Speaker 6:  again, abstracting way all that prompt engineering they think is gonna be
Speaker 6:  a, a key unlock there. So like some of the examples were like, and it's multimodal
Speaker 6:  so you can use Dolly. So it's like an interior design GPT that's like
Speaker 6:  specifically for helping you figure out how to design your home or
Speaker 6:  a cooking one or You know. Theoretically here at The Verge
Speaker 6:  we could upload all Verge content ever made into
Speaker 6:  a GPT and it could replace search on our website.
Speaker 6:  That's an idea, right? And OpenAI, which we should get into this
Speaker 6:  next OpenAI, will be compensating creators of these GPTs based on their
Speaker 6:  usage. Which I think is a very interesting distinction from other
Speaker 6:  platforms.
Speaker 4:  I think two things that kind of, I, I read your piece and it was great. The
Speaker 4:  two things that stuck out to me were one the compensation and how they're
Speaker 4:  planning to do that. 'cause that seems like a whole mess. Yeah. And also
Speaker 4:  just how quickly he seemed to gloss over
Speaker 4:  the hallucination problem. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Just like any
Speaker 6:  Enormous store,
Speaker 4:  Like you're releasing an enormous app
Speaker 3:  Store, you go into a Walmart or Target, you're like most products a lot like
Speaker 4:  An enormous lying, enormous live store basically. Yeah. A normal store.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  You go into a Walmart or a Target.
Speaker 6:  Well yes, but the, the difference with the custom GPT is
Speaker 6:  you can upload custom knowledge. So like on stage Sam made a bot and
Speaker 6:  he used to be the head of Y Combinator, the startup ex incubator.
Speaker 6:  And he was like, I have wanted to have a bot that just tells people
Speaker 6:  what I would tell startup founders the advice I would give them for like
Speaker 6:  a decade. And he just built it on stage in like three minutes and he
Speaker 6:  uploaded transcripts of every talk he's given on these topics, right? So
Speaker 6:  yes, the halluc it's still a problem. Like hallucination obviously is still
Speaker 6:  a problem and he talked about this more after the keynote and a press thing
Speaker 6:  I went to. But the fact that you can augment it with
Speaker 6:  custom knowledge makes it more domain specific and
Speaker 6:  so it's hopefully gonna alleviate a lot
Speaker 3:  Of that.
Speaker 4:  Doesn't that kind of just make it like, I think the no code part is probably
Speaker 4:  the coolest part of this. Yeah, but doesn't this just make it like no code
Speaker 4:  chat chatbots like you had on AIM 20 years ago. Like if you
Speaker 4:  can upload like for him the the same Altman one in particular.
Speaker 4:  Okay, that's really, really cool. Somebody could have done that 20 years
Speaker 4:  ago, it just would've taken them quite a bit of time and now it Right.
Speaker 3:  But you have the sort of like Eliza problem, right? Right. Where it's like
Speaker 3:  there's some canned responses, this one is like gonna talk to you, it's
Speaker 3:  gonna be, I think the fidelity of the conversation is higher. The thing that's
Speaker 3:  really interesting to me is what you're saying Alex the compensation model.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. So OpenAI is what, 20 bucks a month for plus
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Ish. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And then they're, they're probably gonna what, just share out some of that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. To the bot builders. That's the Spotify model,
Speaker 3:  which is historically right. Doesn't make anyone rich except Spotify.
Speaker 6:  Well Spotify important distinction. There's this whole thing called the
Speaker 6:  labels, right. That OpenAI doesn't have to deal with because they don't pay
Speaker 6:  for a lot of their content, which is something that Sam did not really wanna
Speaker 6:  talk about. Yeah. But yes, I actually think it's closer
Speaker 6:  to YouTube because the way they're gonna do it in initially is they're gonna
Speaker 6:  share some percentage, we don't know, we don't know if it's fixed, we
Speaker 6:  don't know if it fluctuates based on the category, but they're gonna share
Speaker 6:  a percentage of the companies. So OpenAI
Speaker 6:  Chad GPT subscription revenue with GPT creators and it's based on
Speaker 6:  usage. So this, and and Altman was very kind of high level about this on
Speaker 6:  stage. I think they're gonna share more in the next few weeks. But at this
Speaker 6:  press q and a I went to with after and I wrote about this in command line,
Speaker 6:  he elaborated and said there's going to be category specific bonuses
Speaker 6:  and that down the road they're open to actually letting you subscribe directly
Speaker 6:  to custom GPTs, letting GPT creators charge one-off fees
Speaker 6:  for them.
Speaker 6:  But it sounds like a lot of it is gonna get figured out in like the first
Speaker 6:  few months of the store they're rolling out with this initial kind of
Speaker 6:  mushy rev share thing. But it is YouTube esque. It's not Apple-esque because
Speaker 6:  there isn't going to be like a transactional piece to this. Right. Have
Speaker 4:  They asked chat GPT itself how it thinks it should handle
Speaker 4:  the Rev
Speaker 3:  Models?
Speaker 6:  I'm sure they have. I mean well
Speaker 3:  So this analogies are difficult 'cause it's weird and it's mushy.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  YouTube
Speaker 3:  Like most YouTubers are getting a cut of the ads, right? Right. There's a
Speaker 3:  sort of like infinite amount of money coming into YouTube or at least an
Speaker 3:  uncapped amount of advertising money coming into YouTube and that goes
Speaker 3:  out, right? Spotify is like you pay Spotify premium and I
Speaker 3:  know my ever increasing amount of money I pay for Spotify premium, I listen
Speaker 3:  to a song, there's some formula that goes to the label in the artist and
Speaker 3:  it's pennies and this feels more like that, right? I pay ChatGPT 20 bucks
Speaker 3:  a month, I go use a bunch of GPTs, my usage gets
Speaker 3:  divvied up into fractions and goes to those creators and
Speaker 3:  that they got it. The reason I'm, I'm harping on this is
Speaker 3:  because of what David said earlier, which is the entire game is the app store
Speaker 3:  for ai and you cannot distribute this anywhere
Speaker 3:  because the second you start doing a better revenue model, which is
Speaker 3:  just pay for the apps or pay for a subscription or have
Speaker 3:  transactions, Apple's gonna sit there and take 30% away from you.
Speaker 3:  Well, yeah. And Google is gonna take 30% away from you Apple
Speaker 6:  Already. So the Apple already is taking 30% of chat GPT plus revenue
Speaker 6:  on iOS. Right. And I, because it's a subscription
Speaker 3:  Down. Well if you sign up on the
Speaker 6:  Phone, right. If you sign up on the phone. So yeah. And this is where I kind
Speaker 6:  of like ended with Command Line this week is like I would love to know what
Speaker 6:  Apple thinks about all this because Apple, they don't like stores within
Speaker 6:  apps. You know, like you can ask Mark Zuckerberg about that one. You can
Speaker 6:  ask a lot of people about that one. Actually a lot of people have tried versions
Speaker 6:  of this. The only one that's gotten it through for reasons that are too complex
Speaker 6:  to get into is WeChat in China. But I think they're gonna run into
Speaker 6:  a massive wall there eventually, which is Apple's take rate
Speaker 6:  and their historical hatred of an app
Speaker 6:  trying to recreate any kind of a digital store experience
Speaker 3:  And potentially having their own Yeah. ai. Right?
Speaker 3:  Right. And wanting their own AI to be their primary AI in the device.
Speaker 3:  Because once the AI is looking at books and just buying 'em for you,
Speaker 3:  that's a whole nother world of transactions that Apple can take money out
Speaker 3:  of and they're gonna wanna be the primary AI there. So it's
Speaker 3:  just to bring this together, you can see why people wanna build a not
Speaker 3:  phone. Hmm. Why Sam Altman is investing in 45 different
Speaker 3:  attempts at this and might be working with Johnny. Ive at some attempt at
Speaker 3:  this, there's a massive blocker to
Speaker 3:  mobile innovation here, which is that 30% cut.
Speaker 3:  And I just don't have any sense of how anyone will actually get around it
Speaker 3:  because building the Humane AI Pin or the rewind
Speaker 3:  pent or whatever Johnny Ive comes up with on the side,
Speaker 3:  the phone is still gonna be the primary device. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Well the, the other part of it is like, this is not all that different
Speaker 5:  from what Amazon and Google were trying to do with skills for their voice
Speaker 5:  assistant. Like we've been down this road where Amazon
Speaker 5:  was like, okay, you're gonna interact with Alexa, but we're also gonna offer
Speaker 5:  you lots of ways to interact with other data and other services skills is
Speaker 5:  gonna be a huge business that got past Apple.
Speaker 5:  It was fine, it just turns out nobody wanted that because it has this he
Speaker 5:  discovery problem. The interface is actually not that good for
Speaker 5:  it in most ways because like the thing where you have to essentially say
Speaker 5:  a wake word to get to the thing and then another wake word to get to the
Speaker 5:  app that you want and then talk to it in a very specific way all to route
Speaker 5:  right back to you. Like that flow sucks and So I think what
Speaker 5:  chat GPT is gonna have to figure out is how to, like, again,
Speaker 5:  we're talking about abstracting all of this away, and by virtue of making
Speaker 5:  you choose things, you lose that abstraction in a really helpful way.
Speaker 5:  Like ChatGPT already has these plugins. Yeah. So the plugin system sucks.
Speaker 5:  Those are replacing, it's a, it's a, yeah. Perfectly useful thing, right?
Speaker 5:  But I think that is one way to go down that road
Speaker 5:  that doesn't work because it it, you can't find the stuff you have to like
Speaker 5:  turn it on every time you want to use it. It just doesn't work. And I think
Speaker 5:  figuring out how to do this thing they're trying to do in a way that doesn't
Speaker 5:  cause those exact same problems is gonna be really hard. Especially
Speaker 5:  because OpenAI is trying to have its cake and eat it too. Because
Speaker 5:  it also wants to be the interface to all of it. It does
Speaker 6:  Like,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it wants to be the underlying infrastructure and the most
Speaker 5:  powerful, important product. And right at some point doing both of those
Speaker 5:  becomes really, really, really hard to do.
Speaker 6:  This is what Altman said in the q and a I was at after his keynote.
Speaker 6:  And I thought it was really interesting because it gets at that tension,
Speaker 6:  David, that you talk about where OpenAI is building a
Speaker 6:  platform very clearly. They're continuing to add things into chat
Speaker 6:  GPT, add different modalities, different data sets. At the same
Speaker 6:  time they're saying, come build on our platform, we'll share revenue with
Speaker 6:  you, come make your own GPT, et cetera. And
Speaker 6:  he got asked about this and he said very clearly, he was like, don't build
Speaker 6:  a thin wrapper on top of OpenAI. We are planning to build the obvious features
Speaker 6:  that you would expect for a robust platform over time. And there's enormous
Speaker 6:  value to build. So that's him just being straight up like we will
Speaker 6:  probably Sherlock you. Yeah. And, and I'm, I'm gonna see,
Speaker 6:  I see a lot of parallels here to the early app store.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We're gonna build the app
Speaker 6:  And I think that's okay. Like You know the early app store had a bunch of
Speaker 6:  flashlight apps, right? Eventually that just became a feature on the phone
Speaker 6:  and that's, it was a, it's a better feature as a result. You
Speaker 3:  Can go in the app store right now and download a home interior
Speaker 3:  app that is a thin wrapper on Dolly.
Speaker 6:  Like Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like we are, we're painting our house and I wanted an app that would just
Speaker 3:  like put paint colors on the wall and like half of them are now just
Speaker 3:  dolly wrappers. Right. And they're bananas. Like,
Speaker 3:  it's like, don't do this. Like I don't recommend them. Like your house starts
Speaker 3:  to look real wild after a minute, but it's, but there's obviously a
Speaker 3:  market for that thing to occur right now. And maybe one day
Speaker 3:  OpenAI will build that exact thing 'cause it's a useful case for Dolly.
Speaker 3:  But in the meantime, like they're just watching a bunch of these companies
Speaker 3:  try and fail and that's useful to them. And in the
Speaker 3:  short term useful, the companies are making some money. I
Speaker 4:  Just keep thinking about all the scummy apps
Speaker 4:  that are gonna come to this thing, right? Like there's the obvious ones where
Speaker 4:  I, as an adult call it scummy. A lot of our younger listeners would probably
Speaker 4:  love it, is like one that'll just write your papers for you. Right? That's,
Speaker 4:  that's the thing chat GPD can already do. Somebody will probably make a really,
Speaker 4:  really good version of it using this. And a lot of people will
Speaker 4:  probably be very upset about that and demand for it to be pulled down because
Speaker 4:  it's helping a bunch of kids cheat. There's ones where like, okay, you can
Speaker 4:  have an You know input, some actress that
Speaker 4:  you really wanna talk to. And then everybody's like, oh yeah, I can go talk
Speaker 4:  to that hot actress. And it's like, ooh, no, you can already
Speaker 6:  Do that Alex. I mean there's like, yeah, you can do that replica character
Speaker 6:  ai but that's
Speaker 4:  Gonna happen now on Yeah. OpenAI Yes form, right? Like
Speaker 4:  they're, they're gonna have to deal with that. Oh,
Speaker 3:  Someone's gonna build that GPT, right? Sure. If you build a GPT of me.
Speaker 3:  So it's over.
Speaker 6:  So that is like the law
Speaker 3:  Will, the law will
Speaker 6:  Come down. So Neli like we are a group, we, there's a lot of stuff on the
Speaker 6:  internet that could like be used to inform a chatbot about us because we
Speaker 6:  write on the internet. Like that is a perfect example. Someone could just
Speaker 6:  make a Neli bot and it's everything Eli's written on The Verge. And you ask
Speaker 6:  Neli questions about copyright You know forever, right? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And then Neli bot is like, this is copyright infringement.
Speaker 6:  But you, just to be clear, well we about what's happening, I want to, we,
Speaker 6:  this is a little bit of a tangent, but like they, another thing OpenAI announced
Speaker 6:  this week is a copyright shield, which is a program where they will pay for
Speaker 6:  any legal fees incurred by their developers for copyright claims
Speaker 6:  of use of the technology. Oh. So theoretically someone builds a Eli bot,
Speaker 6:  they scrape The Verge for all Eli's stories, they put it in the bot,
Speaker 6:  Vox Media goes, Hey you stole our IP and you're making money off of this
Speaker 6:  'cause OpenAI is paying you, we're gonna sue you. And OpenAI is saying, now
Speaker 6:  we will fight all those legal Yeah. Legal things that
Speaker 6:  happen. So like what do you think about that Neli?
Speaker 5:  That's a bad answer to this problem. We should all just like, I just wanna
Speaker 5:  acknowledge that is a bad answer too. Oh yeah.
Speaker 4:  That's how OpenAI goes bankrupt real fast. Well
Speaker 5:  That's, well no there are also, there are so many interesting
Speaker 5:  ways of thinking about this content. Like Alex your paper example is a really
Speaker 5:  interesting one because like you put together all the announcements that
Speaker 5:  came out this week and what's gonna happen now is you're gonna be able to
Speaker 5:  upload your history textbook Yeah. To a GPT and you're gonna be able to write
Speaker 5:  papers from it. That is that it, it now has the a big enough context window
Speaker 5:  and it like the, they're using this thing. It's, it's like the
Speaker 5:  AI term for it is rag, which is basically like by doing this
Speaker 5:  custom knowledge, you're able to reduce it all the way down just to the stuff
Speaker 5:  that You know that it knows, which means it hallucinates less, which is actually
Speaker 5:  a really important part of this. It's gonna write you a good paper based
Speaker 5:  on your history textbook and that is just, it's all sitting there and that's
Speaker 5:  a mess in so many ways. And for OpenAI to just be like, don't worry about
Speaker 5:  it. We have lawyers is not a good answer to the problem.
Speaker 6:  So Sam was Sam's exact wording on this
Speaker 6:  issue was we don't like to do things that are illegal.
Speaker 6:  Congrats Sam. Which is like Sam
Speaker 3:  Cool, cool.
Speaker 6:  Sam, same. Sam, same. But like, I mean they clearly
Speaker 6:  think all this is under fair use and there's a lot You know you all have
Speaker 6:  talked about on the show, a lot of You know there's a lot of lawsuits right
Speaker 6:  now that it's trying, that are trying to You know they are gonna figure this
Speaker 6:  out. Whether this is fair use, this is happening while all this
Speaker 6:  is going on. It's a very, can
Speaker 3:  I color that in for you? Yeah. So the copyright office took comments about
Speaker 3:  whether it's fair use and all the big companies filed comments. Oh yeah,
Speaker 3:  that's good. And we have some of 'em on site and the one that just stuck
Speaker 3:  out was Andreesen Horowitz, big Silicon Valley firm. Their comment was, look,
Speaker 3:  companies have invested billions and billions of dollars into this technology
Speaker 3:  assuming it's fair use. So it's fair use.
Speaker 6:  No, I mean they were clear. They were like, if this is not fair use like
Speaker 6:  these investments go to zero. Basically it was like, it was like the whole,
Speaker 6:  the whole structure of all this is predicated on the idea that we can
Speaker 6:  have this for free. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I know a lot of media executives, they don't
Speaker 3:  agree with all
Speaker 5:  You.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, not, not a little bit. We had Barack Obama on decoder this week. I
Speaker 3:  asked him this question like, you're an author, do you think this is fair
Speaker 3:  use? 'cause he really wants talk about ai and he, he was like, he's a
Speaker 3:  politician, he's very good at this. He's like, leave me out of it. I've sold
Speaker 3:  enough books. Like you watch him do it. He is like, no, no, no, no, no. I
Speaker 3:  refuse to engage this question. And then he said, this is a speed
Speaker 3:  bump. The revenue will get figured out. And So I think there's a
Speaker 3:  real tension in the industry. There's an expectation from the people who
Speaker 3:  make the IP that this is Yep. A speed bump that
Speaker 3:  the money will sort itself out. The creators will get paid. And there's the
Speaker 3:  expectation from the tech industry that they're gonna get to
Speaker 3:  do a Google and just take it. And like Google's
Speaker 3:  history is built on taking it. And they were the
Speaker 3:  scrappy upstart when they did that. When Google scraped all the books
Speaker 3:  on the internet and made Google books. They got sued but they showed up with
Speaker 3:  their like big colorful logo and their propeller hats.
Speaker 3:  Literally that image of Google protected it from these lawsuits when
Speaker 3:  Viacom sued Google over YouTube for just ingesting huge
Speaker 3:  amounts of Viacom television shows onto YouTube.
Speaker 3:  YouTube is like, but it's so cool. Like everyone loves it.
Speaker 3:  You could just watch South Park for free. And Viacom was like, yeah, that's
Speaker 3:  the problem that they won and they won running away because
Speaker 3:  Viacom was perceived as evil and Google again, stupid logo
Speaker 3:  slides in the office, beanie hat. And it was really useful.
Speaker 5:  That's part of the story. The rest of the story is that
Speaker 5:  Google had a reasonable defense, which was to say we're not the
Speaker 5:  ones uploading it. And it turns out there's like a large part of tech policy
Speaker 5:  that is based on that specific idea.
Speaker 3:  No, they, they wait, I mean their other defense was, and we built you content
Speaker 3:  id, we built you a private copyright enforcement
Speaker 3:  system that is unaccountable to everyone and pisses everybody off every day.
Speaker 3:  Right. That's the actual, that's the thing that they did to get outta that
Speaker 3:  jam. Google
Speaker 5:  Got so much out of this in a lot of ways by returning value to people like
Speaker 5:  Google made the case to Viacom that more people are watching Viacom stuff
Speaker 5:  because they're finding it on YouTube. And whether that's true or not, it's
Speaker 5:  a case to make and it's, it's done the same thing with
Speaker 5:  websites, right? Like there have been all these issues for years about like
Speaker 5:  media organizations being like, how are we supposed to feel about the fact
Speaker 5:  that there is a constantly updated version of our entire website sitting
Speaker 5:  on Google servers and that's what they're crawling and serving. Not our
Speaker 5:  website And. what Google says is we send you traffic. Yeah. And there's like,
Speaker 5:  there is some set of trades that you're willing to make there. And
Speaker 5:  chat GPT so far has not returned any value to the people
Speaker 5:  whose stuff that it is taking. It's not directing traffic, they're not getting
Speaker 5:  money. It's just like a nifty thing that other people get to do. And I think
Speaker 5:  without, if it can't figure out how to make that turn back to like,
Speaker 5:  here is what it's worth for you, I think it's much bigger than a speed bump.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. No, it will bring the whole thing down. Like it is the end of the industry
Speaker 3:  if this isn't fair use. And the the thing for all of these companies
Speaker 3:  is you cannot rely on the court system to
Speaker 3:  be reliable when it comes to fair use. Right? Like it
Speaker 3:  is not a stable decision making framework. It is a coin flip.
Speaker 3:  Like every time it is a coin flip even in just like recent memory. Like
Speaker 3:  I bring up this example all the time, but I'll do it again 'cause it's useful.
Speaker 3:  The estate of Marvin Gaye was not happy.
Speaker 3:  No, it just comes up
Speaker 5:  Drink somebody owes me $10.
Speaker 3:  I'm just telling you blur. The blurred lines case is gonna go down as like
Speaker 3:  the thing that upends maybe all of technology.
Speaker 3:  It did bring us Emily Ruski, many things happened because of the song.
Speaker 3:  They, Robin Thick Andre sued Marvin Gaye's estate preemptively
Speaker 3:  'cause they thought it was so clear cut, they hadn't stolen a note, it was
Speaker 3:  just a vibe and they lost. That is a totally unpredictable result.
Speaker 3:  And then the estate of Marvin Gaye embolden goes and Sues Ed Sheeran.
Speaker 3:  Ed Sheeran shows up in court all floppy hair and says,
Speaker 3:  well just the music. And he wins. And he actually took the course.
Speaker 5:  He played guitar in court. That was the different incredible edge shear impression
Speaker 5:  by the way.
Speaker 3:  You could use some accent work, but yeah, it was, it was All, right? He's
Speaker 3:  just a floppy guy. He's just a floppy guy. But that is a straight coin
Speaker 3:  flip. If I gave you the facts of that outside of the actual characters and
Speaker 3:  said these two didn't take any of the chords or the music. They
Speaker 3:  took a vibe and this guy took the actual chords
Speaker 3:  who, who should win? Who should lose, right? And it's the exact opposite
Speaker 3:  of what you expect. And if you are OpenAI or your Google or any, any one
Speaker 3:  of these other folks, you're staring at a problem where
Speaker 3:  it is so unpredictable that you should go and make some deals
Speaker 3:  just to bring some semblance of order to this marketplace.
Speaker 3:  But to what David's point is, no one knows what that deal's worth. The
Speaker 3:  second you make one deal, everyone else is gonna want a deal. The second
Speaker 3:  you make a deal, you have communicated to the world
Speaker 3:  you think deals might be necessary and everyone shows up with their hands
Speaker 3:  out. Like this is classic like rock in a hard place situation
Speaker 3:  for all these companies. And if they end up going to court and
Speaker 3:  fighting this out, no one knows if they're gonna get to the right answer
Speaker 3:  on either side. A couple weeks ago on decoder, we had a
Speaker 3:  record label executive and she said, look, the music industry is like this.
Speaker 3:  You sue each other in the morning and you go to dinner at night and that's
Speaker 3:  how It works. And like you're just gonna have to deal with it. And they're
Speaker 3:  gonna have to get good at that too, because that's how we, that's how we
Speaker 3:  do this. And I, I don't think Sam is ready for that. They
Speaker 6:  Are not thinking about it at all. It didn't come up on like the stage. It
Speaker 6:  didn't really come up afterwards in the conversations I was hearing. They're
Speaker 6:  very focused on what is the value we can give to developers and users
Speaker 6:  and the data that is powering all of this is like something they do not want
Speaker 6:  to talk about because of what we've all been saying. But I mean, I I
Speaker 6:  do wanna just like if to take devil's advocate here, like yes, like there's
Speaker 6:  a huge copyright question here. Generally I feel like with
Speaker 6:  these new things, the Viacom YouTube example is a great example where
Speaker 6:  better product experiences tend to win in the long run,
Speaker 6:  right? So and if I'm thinking about a GPT for The Verge,
Speaker 6:  unless I'm in kind of like discovery mode where I just wanna literally
Speaker 6:  You know, surf our beautiful site and look at things and I have no idea what
Speaker 6:  I'm wanting,
Speaker 6:  I actually would love the idea of just going, what should I know
Speaker 6:  about the new iPhone? Is it good or not? And a bot just, it
Speaker 6:  surfaces our article. It tells me, it says this is, this is the score,
Speaker 6:  this is the history of our coverage. Here's a link to the video. Or just
Speaker 6:  watch the video there. Like that's a pretty good experience. There's, there's
Speaker 6:  a lot of like finding things on the internet that like that
Speaker 6:  time collapses immediately when you're using an interface like this. And
Speaker 6:  that's gonna, I think provide value. Yeah. And so if you believe that that's
Speaker 6:  valuable and I think a lot of people will, and I think we're gonna start
Speaker 6:  seeing a lot of really interesting GPTs that are doing very dubious
Speaker 6:  You know fair use things, but are showing like, hey, this interface is actually
Speaker 6:  better for just finding information. I do think that
Speaker 6:  idea may win out in the long run regardless of what happens in the short
Speaker 6:  term with the legal system.
Speaker 4:  It just feels like they're moving way too fast. They are like, yeah, between
Speaker 4:  the lying thing and the fact that they haven't figured out whether or or
Speaker 4:  not they're wholesale ripping off a whole bunch of creators.
Speaker 4:  Like what are you doing?
Speaker 6:  What do you mean ripping off all these, what do you mean
Speaker 4:  What we just talked about? Like, like the payout structure. A lot of people
Speaker 4:  Yeah, a lot of people straight up accuse them of if they're, if they're ingesting
Speaker 4:  their stuff without paying them, they're, they're, that's ripping them off.
Speaker 4:  Oh,
Speaker 6:  Here, I'll just give
Speaker 3:  You, lemme give you just another example of this outside of ChatGPT. I think
Speaker 3:  about this with TikTok all the time. I keep a list of TikTok that I think
Speaker 3:  should be media PhDs. It's great. One day I'll publish the whole list
Speaker 3:  and there's one I keep coming back to Haggerty Media, which is a great
Speaker 3:  car YouTube channel. I love it. They did a stop motion video
Speaker 3:  of an engine being disassembled cool. This, this took forever.
Speaker 3:  Like just dis making a video of an engine being disassembled such that anyone
Speaker 3:  can understand what's happening takes a long time with people to do it
Speaker 3:  in stop motion is like a ma just obviously massive investment
Speaker 3:  and So I, it instantly got cut up into 10,000 different
Speaker 3:  TikTok channels that reposted into 10,000 different clips. 'cause it's, it
Speaker 3:  looks cool as hell. And if you're running one of these TikTok channels, they're
Speaker 3:  just trying to get views so you can like send people their TikTok shop. This
Speaker 3:  is great. Should that, should any of that exist media PhD?
Speaker 3:  Okay. Here's the real thing that I think about all the time. The comments
Speaker 3:  on all of the tos that have free booted this video are,
Speaker 3:  this took so long. This must have been so hard to do.
Speaker 3:  This is so cool. I'm so glad you spent all this time doing this. And it's
Speaker 3:  like, not like everyone can see the value
Speaker 3:  and the difficulty of the work and no one
Speaker 3:  not, not a cent of that value is going back to the person that made the video.
Speaker 3:  Right. And no, like, no one's confused that this was like a
Speaker 3:  hard thing to do.
Speaker 3:  TikTok is making the most money in that. The free booting channel is making
Speaker 3:  some money in that. The users are getting a ton of value, right? 'cause they're
Speaker 3:  seeing a video they wouldn't have ever seen. And the poor person who like
Speaker 3:  had to move the bolt like a 16th of an inch and then take another
Speaker 3:  frame gets nothing. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And like I keep thinking like, I came up as a guy who when I was my short
Speaker 3:  stint as a lawyer, I defended the kids who used Kaza. And I'm sitting here
Speaker 3:  being like, am I the bad guy now? Like
Speaker 3:  what is going on here? Like that's like one step too far.
Speaker 3:  And that's just with video and everybody can understand. Everyone can see
Speaker 3:  it. If you make a GPT and you ingest all
Speaker 3:  of some YouTube creator's videos and you're like, now you can talk to Doug
Speaker 3:  DeMiro and he doesn't get a cent, like at some
Speaker 3:  point you have to say this is not like fair.
Speaker 6:  Oh, it's not even like not
Speaker 3:  Fair use or whatever. Just like
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 3:  Not, this is just like outrageous.
Speaker 6:  It's not even that the creator doesn't get a cent, it's that in that case,
Speaker 6:  YouTube doesn't get a cent. And guess who has a lot of lawyers who is comfortable
Speaker 6:  suing is Google, right? So like yeah, I think Open Eyes entering a world
Speaker 6:  of hurt here. Like I saw, again, I got a demo of the builder and you would
Speaker 6:  think that the ability to upload custom Knowledge, they would have some pretty
Speaker 6:  stringent guidelines on what you can upload and maybe
Speaker 6:  they scan it before they let you put it in the GPT to make sure it's You
Speaker 6:  know. Not something that is like very blatantly like paid copyrighted
Speaker 6:  material that is like behind a paywall or something like that. Yeah. It's
Speaker 6:  literally just a upload field. It's just an upload field. You can upload
Speaker 6:  anything. Like there, there's no nothing said about like how they're gonna
Speaker 6:  look for this stuff. So I, I don't think they're ready
Speaker 6:  for what's about to happen. Which is that like someone is going to be,
Speaker 6:  I I it's just obvious like you, like you take a paid product online,
Speaker 6:  you pay for it, you scrape it, you put it into, into a GPT and
Speaker 6:  you make money from it. And it's like in that
Speaker 6:  flow of events, like the value is just being stolen.
Speaker 6:  Right. And like, and OpenAI is saying at the same time, guess what? We're
Speaker 6:  gonna pay all your legal defenses. Yeah. It's just wild.
Speaker 3:  We should just get OpenAI sued. That's
Speaker 6:  The new challenge. They're already, they're being sued. They're being, I
Speaker 6:  mean they're, they
Speaker 3:  Look, I'm throwing out my wearable graph. The next episode is us just
Speaker 3:  us doing dubious things to get OpenAI suit. No, but wait,
Speaker 3:  they are getting sued by artists like Sarah Silver and all these people.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But this next turn where they're offering revenue to people to build
Speaker 3:  things. Yeah. And then protecting them from the claims. I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  Make a bot that adjusts all of the Game of Thrones books
Speaker 4:  and writes the final two.
Speaker 3:  I think George R. Martin at this point would just pay you for that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. Like that. That's that's, that's my loophole here.
Speaker 3:  He's gonna he should just do that. That's my loophole. George, if you're
Speaker 3:  listening and I know you are. I
Speaker 4:  Got you George.
Speaker 3:  You can, you can do it. It's, they've, they've expanded the field.
Speaker 6:  I I the
Speaker 3:  Context wing window's bigger. George,
Speaker 6:  I, I I do think this is like a huge problem, but I do wanna acknowledge like
Speaker 6:  these GPT, they're they're cool. They're gonna be cool. They're cool as hell.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. People are gonna like using them. The the dolly stuff is wild. Like
Speaker 6:  just having like something that can like generate Yeah. And like I have this
Speaker 6:  problem, I don't know about you guys with these, these chatbots, these like
Speaker 6:  all in one chatbots is like, it's just a, it's just a text bar. I don't know
Speaker 6:  what to do with it. I don't know all the things it can do. There's this context
Speaker 6:  problem with these bots that like barred and all these where they can do
Speaker 6:  so much that like, it's overwhelming frankly for me. So having like a cooking
Speaker 6:  bot that has like all the cooking information I would want to like make recipes.
Speaker 6:  I would pay separately for that because like, I actually just want that.
Speaker 6:  I don't want the all of it. Right. And So I, I do think it's a really powerful
Speaker 6:  idea and Meta's doing it, they're gonna have a bot creation platform next
Speaker 6:  year. There's already character AI replica the industry seems this
Speaker 6:  year to have realized that we are moving on from these like one bot
Speaker 6:  to rule them all concept to like millions of bots everywhere. Right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And that's a, that's a cool idea. It's just, yeah, there's all
Speaker 6:  this like copyright problem. But I think as an idea it's, it's,
Speaker 3:  It's, there's just existential risk to the center. The actually the model
Speaker 3:  thing is really interesting.
Speaker 3:  They had touch Nadella on Sage, Microsoft, they're obviously a huge open
Speaker 3:  air investor. Yeah. And part of the argument that they're making is
Speaker 3:  they're all just using one big model, but they're learning to segment it
Speaker 3:  into these use cases. Right? So the big model is getting better overall,
Speaker 3:  right. While people are doing these specialized things with it. And then
Speaker 3:  on the side, Microsoft research is trying to figure out
Speaker 3:  if you can take small models that could run locally or on these other places
Speaker 3:  and make them fully useful in like very narrow contexts.
Speaker 3:  So you see this like kind of parallel innovation pathway where like
Speaker 3:  the big model, maybe you can put guardrails around it and make these GPT
Speaker 3:  or you could have like the little model that's just good at what it does.
Speaker 3:  And there's something, and the funniest thing about the, I think the little
Speaker 3:  model training at Microsoft is doing is one of the prompts they give it is
Speaker 3:  pretend you're the big model,
Speaker 6:  Which
Speaker 3:  Is incredible. Yeah. Right. It's like, don't it, it's not
Speaker 3:  impossible. Like it's like that thing You know it's
Speaker 3:  pretty good. It's funny that we've had this whole conversation about voice
Speaker 3:  assistance and, and AI and all this stuff. And it's like we've brought up
Speaker 3:  Amazon and Google many times, which have voice
Speaker 3:  assistance. Millions of them deployed in homes today
Speaker 3:  and seem not ready for this next turn at all.
Speaker 6:  OpenAI is moving so fast. And that was just the takeaway from being there
Speaker 6:  and like talking to developers there and just, I mean, when you think about
Speaker 6:  the fact that ChatGPT PT is almost a year old and everything they've done
Speaker 6:  in a year and everything they just announced on stage and like the
Speaker 6:  demand for it. Like there was a massive chat GPT outage this week right after
Speaker 6:  they announced all this stuff. Yeah. Like their servers are melting. So they
Speaker 6:  have clearly like captured lightning in a bottle. It's their game to lose.
Speaker 6:  I really feel that it's just a matter of the legal ramifications
Speaker 6:  potentially catching up with them and the DIC of this store concept.
Speaker 6:  And like, if you're doing a usage based system, what's to keep
Speaker 6:  me from buying a bunch of bots to use my bot so that I
Speaker 6:  have the most used bot? Like how do they know that it's actually real?
Speaker 6:  I guess because it's through the subscription business. But So I guess that
Speaker 6:  is a good limiting factor on that. But there's just a lot of
Speaker 6:  like dicey like who decide, like I'm already imagining like
Speaker 6:  chat GBT is used to like influence the next election and they
Speaker 6:  decide to demonetize news, right? It's like everything old is new again.
Speaker 6:  Right? Like yeah,
Speaker 3:  Well that's like what is, what's gonna be the coco melon of chat GBT
Speaker 3:  that's on the good side, right? That's like the biggest YouTube success story
Speaker 3:  ever. Yeah. Enough so that Disney has listed it
Speaker 3:  not owning Coco Melon as like a risk. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Because
Speaker 3:  It it, and that's just a YouTube success story. And it's like on the other
Speaker 3:  side is like, what is the horrible white noise playlist on Spotify
Speaker 3:  Yeah. App, right? That is just like zero value delivered and just
Speaker 3:  sucking money out of the ecosystem until Spotify has
Speaker 3:  to shut it down. Yeah. I dunno.
Speaker 6:  Yes. And and the next turn here, really, and this is what Sam was telling
Speaker 6:  us after the keynote, is he imagines that we will all have
Speaker 6:  our own GPT, which I'm really excited about. So a GPT that is trained
Speaker 6:  on all of your stuff, like a, the rewind idea, the pendant. But like
Speaker 6:  all of your software, all of your You know notes and your
Speaker 6:  GPT engages with other GPTs on your behalf. So it's like
Speaker 6:  bots on bots all the way down talking to each other. So it's like you tell
Speaker 6:  your GPT, I want to go to see a concert and have dinner with these friends
Speaker 6:  on this date, line up my ride, my reservation, the tickets. And it all
Speaker 6:  talks to different bots to do that. Sam thinks that's inevitable.
Speaker 6:  And what really? So open AI's stated mission is to build
Speaker 6:  AGI right? Artificial general intelligence, which is this like super, it's
Speaker 6:  like godlike AI that can think better than all of us combined.
Speaker 6:  People in the AI field that I've talked to over the last year think that
Speaker 6:  this next step where it's GPTs representing us,
Speaker 6:  engaging on our behalf unsupervised is
Speaker 6:  the environment that is needed to train the models to become
Speaker 6:  a step function even more intelligent. Because you need to have
Speaker 6:  this concept called self supervised learning, where these agents
Speaker 6:  are all interacting and training on their own. That's pretty freaky, right?
Speaker 6:  That's like matrix stuff. Yeah. That's coming in like the next couple of
Speaker 6:  years. I I think the world could look a lot different. It's just we're it
Speaker 6:  it, I think that, and that was the vibe there was like, we are kind of witnessing
Speaker 6:  a very, very exciting but also like very scary
Speaker 6:  next few years
Speaker 3:  Here. Yeah. And inside of it is a
Speaker 3:  copyright lawsuit.
Speaker 6:  It's a giant ticking time bomb of life.
Speaker 3:  It's just Ed Sheeran looking mad at you All. right? We gotta take a break.
Speaker 3:  We'll come back. We got a lightning round. We gotta get outta here. We'll
Speaker 3:  be right back
Speaker 3:  We're back. There's quite a lot on this lightning round, but we gotta go
Speaker 3:  fast. Cranz, why don't you start 'cause you got, I think you have the best
Speaker 3:  one.
Speaker 4:  I do have the best one. There's a new Steam Deck.
Speaker 4:  Sean Hollister has reviewed it. He naturally loves
Speaker 4:  it. I I, I think I called him like the day after he got it
Speaker 4:  and I was like, tell me everything. And he sure did.
Speaker 4:  He like, he really likes it. The the big things that have changed with this
Speaker 4:  one is there's a new processor. They went from the seven nanometer
Speaker 4:  ath processor named after the character from Final
Speaker 4:  Fantasy seven to the six nanometer Sphero
Speaker 4:  processor. Sames.
Speaker 4:  They, they've, they've, they've switched to an OLED display. They've switched,
Speaker 4:  they, they've, the battery license supposedly increased, which led to an
Speaker 4:  incredible quote from from Sean where he said,
Speaker 4:  for example, in 2022, I was able to play the
Speaker 4:  graphically intensive control for just under two hours on my original Steam
Speaker 4:  Deck review unit at 60 frames per second. This week I
Speaker 4:  played the same game at up to 80 frames per second
Speaker 4:  for two hours and 11 minutes.
Speaker 3:  I mean more frames You know. Yeah. More frames. He saw more frames. Frames.
Speaker 4:  He, he he, he does, he does add more stuff to it. It it is a pretty
Speaker 4:  measurably different big difference in battery life. Especially on games
Speaker 4:  that don't use as much of the, the CPU and the GPU. So like those,
Speaker 4:  those lower impact games are gonna last a lot, lot longer. The high impact
Speaker 4:  games. Those of us who are making our way through Boulder's Gate
Speaker 4:  three on the thing, we're not gonna see as much success.
Speaker 4:  The big shock for me was that there are no hu effect joysticks. I
Speaker 4:  just assumed that was gonna happen because there's been so much
Speaker 4:  frustration with the drift on the current joysticks. Yeah, they didn't do
Speaker 4:  that. That's a big bummer. But they got rid of the 32 gigabyte
Speaker 4:  EEMC version, which was the one that I bought. 'cause you could
Speaker 4:  replace the drive really cheap and easy. They got rid of that one now starts
Speaker 4:  at five 50 or 5 49. I'm
Speaker 4:  resisting buying one, but Sean loves it. Oh. And the power buttons now
Speaker 4:  orange.
Speaker 3:  Hey, that's pretty good.
Speaker 4:  I love it. Yeah, I'm excited. I
Speaker 3:  Would put this out as evidence as we've been saying there's more action in
Speaker 3:  gadgets than people ever give any credit to. And the love
Speaker 3:  that our audience and in particular Sean has for the Steam Deck is like
Speaker 3:  off the charts.
Speaker 4:  It's it's an awesome device and they don't have to do a bunch of really long
Speaker 4:  infomercials for, for us to be get hyped about it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You're like, look, you can play control at 80 frames per second for
Speaker 3:  11 minutes more. Yeah. That's all you gotta say.
Speaker 5:  All you got. I just love this thing. They just, they were just like, what
Speaker 5:  are all the things we can do to make this device better? And then they just
Speaker 5:  did all those things and now here we are, like, God
Speaker 5:  forbid more companies don't just like make their things better all the time.
Speaker 5:  Like it's, it's just, it's just makes me happy. And it was the same thing
Speaker 5:  with the Switch OLED, where they're like, we got this thing pretty right
Speaker 5:  the first time, but what if we just did a couple of things better? Wouldn't
Speaker 5:  that be cool? And everybody's like, yes. But it's like most companies are
Speaker 5:  like, okay, this is called the Steam Deck two and this time
Speaker 5:  it comes in six pieces and you have to like
Speaker 5:  do back flips while you use it. It's gonna be so dope. And it, and, and Valve
Speaker 5:  instead is just like, no, we like pretty much got this right. Yeah. We just
Speaker 5:  made it better now.
Speaker 4:  It's cool. It's like, yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's, that's the way. Just make your things better.
Speaker 4:  I yeah, I'm, that's all you need to do.
Speaker 5:  I just really appreciate that. One of the headline features of this one is
Speaker 5:  that the fan is both larger and quieter, which is like
Speaker 5:  crushed guys.
Speaker 4:  No more fan
Speaker 5:  One. This is some video game stuff here. Nailed it. We did it. It
Speaker 3:  I would know that. But I've been trying to scroll this article using Samsung
Speaker 3:  decks, which is not possible.
Speaker 4:  I didn't realize you were actively scrolling. I thought you were doing I
Speaker 4:  always do the thing where I like fidget and scroll up and down. No, you're
Speaker 4:  just trying to read
Speaker 3:  It. No, I'm just trying to land on a sentence that I can read because this
Speaker 3:  mouse is so fast.
Speaker 5:  You just flying top to bottom of the, the table. I was controlled of it.
Speaker 3:  And look Android as many things as an operating system and
Speaker 3:  Samsung's one UI as many things as a skin on Android,
Speaker 3:  a combination of things that is designed to let you change mouse tracking
Speaker 3:  speed is not on the list of priorities for either of those com companies.
Speaker 3:  All, right. David, what is your lightning round?
Speaker 5:  Mine's very simple. It's just that YouTube in its relentless
Speaker 5:  quest to be TikTok is now adding a for you page to,
Speaker 5:  or a for you carousel to people's channels,
Speaker 5:  which is basically like personalized recommended videos on people's
Speaker 5:  channels that you land on a very smart be
Speaker 5:  forever interesting to me that the phrase for you has just completely taken
Speaker 5:  over the internet. Like we've just decided that that is the term for every
Speaker 5:  personalized everything for you. Just one. And
Speaker 5:  also YouTube really ought to stop trying to be TikTok. Like just, oh
Speaker 5:  my God,
Speaker 6:  Just
Speaker 3:  Stop. I think everything is inevitably gonna be TikTok. But I,
Speaker 6:  I opened my YouTube mobile app to the shorts thing and it was just, it
Speaker 6:  was a, it was little tiles of shorts filling my entire serene
Speaker 6:  when I opened my YouTube app on my phone. Like, no, no.
Speaker 4:  I still sometimes accidentally scroll it forgetting I'm not in TikTok.
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah. That's that's incredible.
Speaker 4:  That and Instagram, I'm like, oh, that's why it's kind of crummy and weird.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's it's like watching the algorithms grow up.
Speaker 3:  Like they're at different stages of being toddlers and like
Speaker 3:  TikTok is like running away with the election You know. But
Speaker 3:  like YouTube is just like, is this anything? Will this make you mad? Will
Speaker 3:  it make you sad? Horny? Yeah. You know. Instagram is like, here's a
Speaker 3:  Kardashian You know. Like back to basics. Yeah. At least in my feed, they
Speaker 3:  figured out that I like truck jumps. A lot of truck jumps on my Instagram.
Speaker 3:  Like You know. It's like getting better You know. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Because
Speaker 3:  I engage with it more. And then TikTok is just like full crazy.
Speaker 4:  I I screwed up on TikTok the other day and I thought I had broken my algorithm
Speaker 4:  'cause it just kept showing me bagpipe videos.
Speaker 3:  No, that's what I mean. TikTok is now at the point where it's in the deepest
Speaker 3:  darkest recesses of your personality. Oh yeah. Yeah. If you've been scrolling
Speaker 3:  it for years and years, it's horrible. It's, it's like beyond truck jumps,
Speaker 3:  but it's like deep fried truck memes that like, I can't explain
Speaker 3:  to anyone else. There's a video I keep seeing of like a
Speaker 3:  motorized pizza peel that just picks up a pizza. Okay. But that's, and puts
Speaker 3:  it back down. Cool. It's,
Speaker 4:  It was bagpipes.
Speaker 3:  I'm saying Alex. It's telling you more about yourself than you need to know.
Speaker 3:  I never, it's in there. It's in there.
Speaker 4:  Five year old Alex thought they were cool.
Speaker 3:  So
Speaker 4:  I left it at five. Leave me alone. That
Speaker 3:  Guys TikTok has the reset algorithm button and I think about hitting it all
Speaker 3:  the time.
Speaker 4:  Oh my God, I should hit it. Mm. I think I have to at this point time.
Speaker 3:  We should all hit it here. Here's my pitch for this whole thing. I've now
Speaker 3:  watched more. Again, we've had a lot of copyright on the show, but I've watched
Speaker 3:  more movies on TikTok recently than anything. And all of these
Speaker 3:  video streaming platforms are trying to get you to engage again. And it's
Speaker 3:  like Netflix just make make the
Speaker 3:  TikTok. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Just show me.
Speaker 3:  Just like, let me scroll through it and I'm like, oh man. Yeah. I'll start
Speaker 3:  couples retreat in the middle of it for some reason and then that'll play
Speaker 3:  on my TV and we'll be done. Yeah. And like a, I
Speaker 5:  Absolutely 100% guarantee you that's coming. Yeah. Like
Speaker 5:  there is not one shadow of a doubt in my mind that at some point in the very
Speaker 5:  near future, the Netflix mobile app will have that thing for you.
Speaker 5:  But I also think part of the reason I, I picked this one is my lightning
Speaker 5:  round thing is because it's just like, I've gotten totally obsessed with
Speaker 5:  the idea that scrolling is just like the, the behavior. And it doesn't matter
Speaker 5:  what you're scrolling, it doesn't matter what you're doing. It's just like
Speaker 5:  people wanna scroll. You just like have a moment where you're like, I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  get on my phone and just do some scrolling. It's just like a thing people
Speaker 5:  talk about and the activity is so much more important than what you're doing
Speaker 5:  it with. But it's just like, I, I now think about that all the time is it's
Speaker 5:  just like, that is a mode of engaging with technology is I'm just gonna scroll.
Speaker 5:  And I think the more that becomes the thing, especially as young people are
Speaker 5:  trained on that as like, I have five minutes, I'm gonna do some scrolling.
Speaker 5:  I just like, I hear more people say that and you're gonna see it
Speaker 5:  absolutely everywhere and it is gonna like completely change the internet
Speaker 5:  because it's like, instead of I'm gonna go like look at Reddit or whatever,
Speaker 5:  it's just like, I'm just gonna do some scrolling
Speaker 3:  And it's just the for you feed of scrolls everywhere.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's
Speaker 3:  Nuts. And it's just a bunch of algorithms starting at the very beginning
Speaker 3:  of like personalities, like angry, sad, hungry, horny
Speaker 3:  and then all the way to bagpipes. No.
Speaker 5:  Like,
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Whatever complex. I would love to see the database
Speaker 3:  field of like bagpipe emotional reactions that TikTok thinks
Speaker 3:  it's getting when it gets a bagpipe engagement. You know, like Netflix has
Speaker 3:  those like deeply over constructed movie categories. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Bagpipes are
Speaker 4:  Like, it was all because I liked a friend's video. Yeah. And for some reason
Speaker 4:  it was like, I know which part of that we need to pull out for you
Speaker 5:  Bagpipes.
Speaker 3:  I'm telling you
Speaker 5:  One of the things I love about these conversations is it's always just people
Speaker 5:  telling on themselves. Yep. About the stuff that they watch on social media.
Speaker 5:  It's so fun. You're like, aren't you also on bagpipe TikTok? And it's like,
Speaker 5:  no, no one else is on just
Speaker 4:  You. There are a lot of people on Bag
Speaker 5:  Pipe TikTok,
Speaker 3:  Including
Speaker 4:  Me now.
Speaker 3:  All. right. Here's mine. Great piece by Jen Tuey this week.
Speaker 3:  If you're a smart home nerd, this really hits you. There's a company called
Speaker 3:  Chamberlain makes all the garage door openers, like if you buy a house,
Speaker 3:  the chance that you have a lift master garage door opener made by Chamberlain.
Speaker 3:  Very, very high. They, like many
Speaker 3:  bad companies, have smart devices, so you can make the, you can make the
Speaker 3:  garage opener smart. They have a proprietary platform called MyQ, which is
Speaker 3:  long since a disaster. MyQ is monetized through partnerships
Speaker 3:  with car companies. So you've got a car with like a
Speaker 3:  wifi connection in it. You can like push the button, cloud service happens,
Speaker 3:  your garage door opens, whatever. Man. Many,
Speaker 3:  many, many people have hacked into my queue with
Speaker 3:  HomeBridge and home assistant, which are really cool things. It's
Speaker 3:  very nerdy, but you can have a little tamagotchi of raspberry pie in your
Speaker 3:  house, so you have to reset every couple months. And it, it bridges all the
Speaker 3:  things together into HomeKit. That's my home bridge. Like my ring cameras
Speaker 3:  show up in HomeKit because of Home Bridge. My queue showed up in
Speaker 3:  HomeKit for a lot of people because of Home Bridge. My queue shut off this
Speaker 3:  integration.
Speaker 4:  Not cool.
Speaker 3:  They claim that they're getting DDoS through it, which is like, you could
Speaker 3:  have a real integration with HomeKit and everyone Shut up. You wouldn't get
Speaker 3:  DDoS. So they th and this is the part that just
Speaker 3:  rankles, they explain their decision by saying,
Speaker 3:  we've made the decision to prevent unauthorized usage of the MyQ ecosystem
Speaker 3:  through third party apps. It's so that we can continue to provide the best
Speaker 3:  possible experience for our 10 million plus users. We understand this
Speaker 3:  impacts a small percentage of users, but ultimately this will improve the
Speaker 3:  performance and reliability of MyQ benefiting all of our users.
Speaker 4:  That is the cleanest garage I've ever seen. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  The picture here, so they said this is 2%
Speaker 3:  of people. So Jen just did the math. You've got 10 million users. You've,
Speaker 3:  you've broken 200,000 garage doors,
Speaker 3:  Which is just incredible. So now they're freaking out. I will
Speaker 3:  tell you, MyQ has always been a disaster. They've always been pretty user
Speaker 3:  hostile. This is not a secret, it's just what people have and no one thinks
Speaker 3:  about replacing the garage door opener. So everyone's been hacking around
Speaker 3:  it. You can buy little adapters. I have one called
Speaker 3:  Miros, I think they're refurbished. Ones are called Ress. It's a very confusing,
Speaker 3:  they're like some, anywhere between 30 and 50 bucks depending on sale.
Speaker 3:  You can just wire 'em into your garage opener, put 'em at home. Kit they
Speaker 3:  work. There's other ones. Jen has a whole list of other alternatives.
Speaker 3:  If you're the sort of person who wants to open your garage door from your
Speaker 3:  phone, and I am that sort of person. You are, there are many ways to do this,
Speaker 3:  to do not involve the MyQ platform. And our article has irritated
Speaker 3:  them so much that they're issuing corrections and they're trying
Speaker 3:  to explain their decision even more when all they need to do is just either
Speaker 3:  build the home kit integration or let the people do the hacks.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Just like say, okay, home assistance's fine.
Speaker 3:  I love it when companies are like, it's a tiny percentage of users. They're
Speaker 3:  like, you just broke 200,000 garage doors.
Speaker 4:  Only 200. Whatcha doing only 200 K
Speaker 3:  All, right? Alex, you got a lightning your hand? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's actually a thing. I've been trying, I've been test driving a rivian
Speaker 6:  R one s for the last week. Yeah. So RJ the CO is at code,
Speaker 6:  and this is not a, an ad by any means, but
Speaker 6:  I have had fun in it a lot. We took it offroading in Joshua Tree
Speaker 6:  and an electric, it was my first time in an electric
Speaker 6:  like SUV and the thinking goes zero to 60
Speaker 6:  in three, three seconds and has like 840 hor horsepower.
Speaker 6:  And it's just like driving a big ass go-kart through the desert that
Speaker 6:  Yeah, like it was just, and I like the, I mean just a lot of
Speaker 6:  the small decisions they've made in terms of the You know the OSS and
Speaker 6:  the, the interior of the car. The moment they do a mid-sized
Speaker 6:  one of these, I think it's gonna be a really compelling Tesla alternative.
Speaker 6:  But right now it's very like outdoorsy, You know, big, big hulking vehicles.
Speaker 6:  But yeah.
Speaker 3:  Had a lot of
Speaker 5:  Next up cyber truck for you.
Speaker 3:  That's the Yeah, I've
Speaker 6:  Heard, yeah, I've heard the rivian described as the, i I can't say it on
Speaker 6:  our air, but the, a version of the cyber truck that for people who
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I, IIII
Speaker 6:  All, right? Yeah. Anyway,
Speaker 3:  Okay. Can I say my cyber truck thing? So I asked for pictures of the wiper
Speaker 3:  and there've been lots of cyber trucks everywhere and people keep sending
Speaker 3:  me not closeups. They're like, here's another video of the
Speaker 3:  wiper. And it's like you're six miles away. Hmm. So. I'm gonna be more specific
Speaker 3:  and need a closeup of the middle of the wiper. Hmm. The middle,
Speaker 3:  not the, not the arm, not the part at the bottom of the windshield that turns
Speaker 3:  the middle of the wiper blade. Or even better closeups all
Speaker 3:  the way up the wiper. Like connecting to the glass. Yes. And I'll be more
Speaker 3:  specific. I have heard rumors of how the actual blade is
Speaker 3:  constructed that I would like to verify. I will not tell you what they
Speaker 3:  are. Please. 'cause I don't want to put disinformation in the world and I
Speaker 3:  know the Tesla people are crazy and I don't wanna, I don't want clips of
Speaker 3:  me saying a thing that's wrong. I'm just saying I've heard some information
Speaker 3:  that I cannot verify about the wiper blade itself. So if
Speaker 3:  you encounter one, just go look at the blade, take some
Speaker 3:  pictures, start at the bottom, click, click, click, click, click all the
Speaker 3:  way at the top, see if you notice anything.
Speaker 6:  A thing about the rivian wipers, they work and there's two of them.
Speaker 3:  I was about to say I heard a
Speaker 6:  Plural there. Yeah, there's two of them. They cover the entire windshield
Speaker 6:  and they work. The only thing I don't like is there's not the cleaner fluid
Speaker 6:  boring. Right? Like you can't, like why are we making new cars that cost
Speaker 6:  a lot of money that don't have this? Wait, it
Speaker 3:  Doesn't have windshield washer,
Speaker 6:  It doesn't have the washer fluid. I'm like, I'm driving this thing through
Speaker 6:  the desert. I
Speaker 3:  It's empty. Or it just
Speaker 6:  Doesn't have it, it doesn't exist.
Speaker 5:  No, you guys, we cannot pick the windshield wiper fight again. We can't.
Speaker 5:  We've been, we've been down this road before. Neli iss about to say, just
Speaker 5:  put water in, it'll be fine. And we're gonna get
Speaker 6:  Emails
Speaker 3:  Again saying doesn't exist. He's saying there's no tank. There's no tank.
Speaker 3:  He's saying they've obviated the entire problem.
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 3:  Bizarre. Someone asked me if I was gonna ask Obama what win should washer
Speaker 3:  fluid. He says, we have picked a lot of dumb battles on the show and this
Speaker 3:  is easily the dumbest and do not just put water in your
Speaker 3:  fluid. Anyway, Neli
Speaker 6:  Neli, the one thing I did wanna ask you about Obama was how was the secret
Speaker 6:  service?
Speaker 3:  So this was our second round with him and we are in his offices. So they
Speaker 3:  were chill. Okay. The first round. What, did
Speaker 6:  You get a pat down?
Speaker 3:  I did not. We already, we were already all cleared from Okay. Before.
Speaker 3:  So when we were at Harvard, there was like intense security in the other
Speaker 3:  protests that day. 'cause he was speaking, we're on a college campus, there
Speaker 3:  were dogs. Like the whole thing happened. We hung out with the dogs and we
Speaker 3:  found out he wasn't gonna be there. So then we, it was cool. The dogs were
Speaker 3:  cool. They're very friendly. But at his offices we had already
Speaker 3:  been pre-screened and we were on his home turf.
Speaker 3:  So there was, there was a, there was a presence. He doesn't not have a presence.
Speaker 3:  And there was some discussion about whether the blinds could be open or closed
Speaker 3:  and the, and whatever. But it was, it was very chill. 'cause we were in his
Speaker 3:  space as opposed to when you're not in his, just moving him around
Speaker 3:  is a complicated, I would imagine is what we have discovered. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Can't go to ban. Can I actually, can I tell you my one Obama
Speaker 3:  behind the scenes story and we can, we can end this episode to,
Speaker 3:  in that episode we talk a lot about free speech on the internet and regulating
Speaker 3:  free speech. And one of the things that's really hard to do is like you need
Speaker 3:  some constitutional authority to go ahead and regulate speech. So the one
Speaker 3:  that came up in the episode is the FCC has some authority over
Speaker 3:  broadcast stations. Right? So you swear
Speaker 3:  on A, B, C or CBS or NBC people can file complaints to
Speaker 3:  the FCC. The FCC can find them because you're using the public airwaves.
Speaker 3:  This is like a real thing. So like radio stations and broadcast
Speaker 3:  tv. There's some basis for the FCC to regulate the content in there.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And that is wax and weight. This doesn't exist for cable tv, which
Speaker 3:  is why HBO can exist. Why cable news is like off the rails. Why?
Speaker 3:  I can just swear it will on the internet on this show. Right. The government
Speaker 3:  has basically no authority. 'cause there's no public airwaves, So, I ask
Speaker 3:  Obama this question. It's in the episode and he's like, Hey, you've seen
Speaker 3:  some hook. So then we get up and we take a group photo 'cause he's an
Speaker 3:  excellent politician and he knows they should take a group photo. So everyone's
Speaker 3:  like happy. And I did the least journalistic thing in my life, which
Speaker 3:  I took a video of him saying hi to Max. Which again,
Speaker 3:  I'm just admitting to you disclosure, the least journalistic thing I've ever
Speaker 3:  did in my life. But my daughter has a video of a bomb saying hi to her. Which
Speaker 3:  that's awesome. You can't get that on cameo. Yeah, yeah. It's like hard.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And then he's leaving and I was like that
Speaker 3:  this like thing, like this feels like the problem to me. Like everyone
Speaker 3:  wants to do this, everyone wants to issue some speech regulation, but you
Speaker 3:  gotta get over this problem. And he looked at me and he goes, yeah, you just
Speaker 3:  need a hook. You just gotta figure it out. We'll figure it out. And he like
Speaker 3:  walked outta the room and I was like, oh, you used to be the most powerful
Speaker 3:  person in the world. Like your brain is just like, this problem should be
Speaker 3:  solved. Like figure it out. Yeah. And it was like Kate Cox,
Speaker 3:  the decoder producer and I, both our minds were just blown
Speaker 3:  because that's just like not, I don't have the ability to just like order
Speaker 3:  someone to solve a constitutional law problem. Yeah. And he was like, yeah,
Speaker 3:  just, I dunno, shut up. Just like what? Just delegate
Speaker 3:  It was and it was just like, you don't have that experience very often. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  The charisma too. Yeah. Yeah. It was a lot. Anyhow,
Speaker 3:  that's it. That's of our Chest. Please. If you see a cyber
Speaker 3:  truck just all the way up the wiper stock, I'm telling you there's something
Speaker 3:  there. I don't know what it is, but people tell me there's something there
Speaker 3:  I should look at
Speaker 6:  And make the Neli wearable index. GPT. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  The graph. The graph. We need the graph. Yeah. I'm telling you, we, we,
Speaker 3:  the Vision Pro, the whole Vision Pro review is just gonna be me doing math,
Speaker 6:  But, but I want it to be a input. I want it to be a GPT. Where you can say
Speaker 6:  is this thing, how does this fit into Eli's graph of wearable
Speaker 6:  awesomeness?
Speaker 3:  Right? fids Times face has to be less than or equal
Speaker 3:  to usefulness. That's the whole equation. You just figure that out for me.
Speaker 3:  All, right? That's it. Thanks everybody. That's rich cast. Back on
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The. Vergecast is
Speaker 1:  a production of The Verge and Box Media Podcast Network. The show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. This episode was mixed and edited by
Speaker 1:  Xandr Adams. And that's it. We'll see you next week.