# Transcript
ID: b2c76160-af57-11ed-ae64-53c857df919d
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Bing is a liar, Elon's tweets are everywhere, and YouTube CEO steps down
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/3143108629684582520/2350405144920984153/s93290-US-4352s-1676702665.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of wanting to smooch your laptop:
01:23 - The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, Richard Lawler, Adi Robertson, and James Vincent discuss the flaws with Microsoft's Bing AI, and why it can be an "emotionally manipulative liar."
34:56 - Platformer managing editor Zoë Schiffer joins to explain why Twitter is showing everyone all of Elon Musk's tweets.
50:33 - The crew discuss YouTube CEO Susan Wojcicki stepping down after nine years at the helm.
Speaker 1:  Today on a Vergecast, we've got a packed show. We're gonna talk about Bing's
Speaker 1:  attitude problem, Elon Musk's, narcissism, and some news n f YouTube.
Speaker 1:  That's all coming up right after this.
Speaker 4:  When you arrive in the all new Toyota Crown, every entrance
Speaker 4:  becomes a grand one with an available hybrid max
Speaker 4:  powertrain that says you always arrive fashionably on time
Speaker 4:  style that says, emphasis on the fashionably
Speaker 4:  and presence that says you speak softly and
Speaker 4:  everyone listens. Introducing the Toyota Crown. The car that says so
Speaker 4:  much.
Speaker 4:  Toyota. Let's go places.
Speaker 2:  Come on. Welcome George. The flagship podcast for wanting to
Speaker 2:  smooch your laptop, which many notable journalists
Speaker 2:  have more or less admitted to doing after using Bing.
Speaker 2:  It's been a weird week in technology. Alex.
Speaker 5:  Just a little, just, just a little
Speaker 2:  Super weird week. But yes, it's been our first week with Bing.
Speaker 5:  It has been.
Speaker 2:  Bing is revealed itself to be quite,
Speaker 2:  I would actually not an Inuit. Bing is out there in force.
Speaker 5:  Bing is out there and depressed and people are like, I'm into that. I
Speaker 2:  Love it. We, we've got a big Elon story. Zoe Schiffer's gonna join the show
Speaker 2:  later to talk about the Elon Twitter algorithm
Speaker 2:  change. There's a new CEO at YouTube. There's a new version of
Speaker 2:  iOS developer beta with a bunch of features. It's a lot. I'm your friend
Speaker 2:  Eli. That's Alex Kranz. Hello.
Speaker 5:  I'm your friend who is not horny for a computer yet.
Speaker 2:  I feel like you just haven't used bing enough because based on what I'm reading,
Speaker 2:  just enough time with Bing and people are
Speaker 5:  Like enough time. What
Speaker 2:  If I was in love with my
Speaker 5:  Computer? I mean, fan yourself guys. Wow.
Speaker 2:  It's, we'll get to it. Richard Lawlers here. I'd like my computer inappropriate
Speaker 2:  amount then to, to help us
Speaker 2:  understand what is going on with Bing. James. Vincent
Speaker 2:  is here
Speaker 6:  I am. I don't understand anything. The week has been dreadfully
Speaker 6:  confusing. I agree
Speaker 2:  That And Addie Robertson is here. Hey Addie. Hey.
Speaker 5:  I am a computer.
Speaker 2:  It's true. And I believe at many New York Times columnists have just
Speaker 2:  professed their love for you, Addie and the pages of the New York Times.
Speaker 2:  He's we're friends. I feel like I can just say it out loud. So let's,
Speaker 2:  we should start with Bing. So last week, Bing comes out, we
Speaker 2:  are at Microsoft. I talk to Nadella. Nadella is,
Speaker 5:  You were super
Speaker 2:  Impressed. He's doing his thing. Yeah, we're gonna make him dance. It was
Speaker 2:  cool. I was talking to Casey, you last night. Casey and I were there together.
Speaker 2:  You know, it was a big chess thumpy. We're proud of it. Again, I can't,
Speaker 2:  I cannot stop repeating this. Nadel looked me in the eye and said, we're
Speaker 2:  gonna make Google dance. And I want people to know who made them
Speaker 2:  dance. Very confident in this product. They had released, it
Speaker 5:  Was our new romantic partner, Bing.
Speaker 2:  We're not quite there yet. They demo Bing to us
Speaker 2:  at the event USF Medi, the executive who runs Bing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Says out loud, we're gonna show you some demos.
Speaker 2:  The demos are prerecorded in the interests of time. So like any
Speaker 2:  normal person, I think to myself, there's no way that
Speaker 2:  these demos contain massive factual errors because
Speaker 2:  Microsoft has pre-recorded them. Right? You would. So the risk is zero.
Speaker 5:  They cut those out,
Speaker 2:  We cut them out. It turns out that all the demos contain massive factual
Speaker 2:  errors. So that's just like one thing that happened to us. And
Speaker 2:  Casey and I were like, did you think to check it? And he is like, I don't
Speaker 2:  think to check it. It's like a very conscientious acker.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Checked it. And all of us were like, shit, we should have checked it.
Speaker 2:  But when someone says, we have prerecorded the demo
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent
Speaker 2:  Your brain goes to, and I'm sure it does not contain any
Speaker 2:  mass
Speaker 5:  Actually. Yeah, that would be, that was the big
Speaker 2:  Assumption. So James, if I'm correct, the factual errors are, it made up
Speaker 2:  some stuff in the gaps, financial results, it got some
Speaker 2:  things wrong about a vacuum. What else happened here?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I, I mean, yeah, it was a great subs post about that guy and it's,
Speaker 6:  it's kind of embarrassing that we didn't, we, we didn't get check that ourselves.
Speaker 2:  I'm mortified that we didn't check it. But I'm saying when someone says we
Speaker 2:  did a pre-recorded demo of a publicly traded company's financial results,
Speaker 2:  like
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I'm gonna just assume you checked it,
Speaker 2:  I assume showed it to me. Microsoft was like, Hey the gap, we will
Speaker 2:  be showing your financial results and letting our robot
Speaker 2:  analyze them. And everyone was like, cool, not yolo.
Speaker 2:  Like we fucked it up.
Speaker 5:  It made a numbers, it's
Speaker 2:  Fine. So that's why, what were the,
Speaker 6:  Every few people have pointed this out, but it is lovely that, you know,
Speaker 6:  computers have got to the point where the thing that everyone expects 'em
Speaker 6:  to be good at, which is handling numbers and facts, they have now just,
Speaker 6:  they're now they're really bad at it. Now. We made computers that were bad
Speaker 6:  at math. It's an incredible achievement. Microsoft, get out there, get on
Speaker 6:  stage. My friends,
Speaker 2:  This is the beginning of the week, right? This is
Speaker 5:  Like, this is Monday.
Speaker 2:  It's Monday. We're talking on Thursday.
Speaker 2:  And on Thursday people I have met and looked in the eye
Speaker 2:  are publishing pieces that boil down to I kind of want to kiss my
Speaker 2:  laptop. Yes. So we we're just, we're starting it Monday.
Speaker 5:  It's a journey of a week.
Speaker 2:  And I will just remind everybody last week when Google had
Speaker 2:  its demo and got something wrong, it evaporated a hundred billion
Speaker 2:  off its market cap. Microsoft is like, we lied about another
Speaker 2:  company's financial results. It appears to be fine because the
Speaker 2:  robot will neg you. Yeah. Which was just like unbelievable.
Speaker 2:  All right. So that was the one thing. What were the other ones that got wrong?
Speaker 6:  Something about a cordless vacuum cleaner for pet hair. Indeed, as Alex was
Speaker 6:  talking about before we went live on the show, it is a perennial problem.
Speaker 6:  It, it mixed up two models. One had a cord, one didn't have a cord or something
Speaker 6:  like that. These are the typical areas that we now already after only a
Speaker 6:  couple of weeks of exposure expect from these systems that there will be
Speaker 6:  just some sort of confusion about a name, a product page, a detail.
Speaker 6:  It swaps them up. Before you know it, it's giving out someone's phone number.
Speaker 6:  That actually happened, but that was with chat GP two.
Speaker 2:  And that was just
Speaker 6:  Today? Yeah, that was today as well.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I'm hesitant to skip all the way to today because I don't
Speaker 2:  think people will believe us. Yeah. About the state we're in
Speaker 2:  with the LLMs today. Just going fast today. The LLMs
Speaker 2:  are doxing us after professing their love for people. It's
Speaker 2:  very confusing. Not a healthy, okay. So that is the beginning of the week.
Speaker 2:  Big errors in the system, no response from Microsoft
Speaker 2:  really. Except say it's a beta. Then people start to push it
Speaker 2:  and they push past. And James, this is the part that I'm, I'm hoping you
Speaker 2:  can help us understand. Hmm. It appears that Microsoft's
Speaker 2:  system is like cosplaying is bing. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 2:  There's actually another system which is named Sydney.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And Microsoft has instructed Sydney
Speaker 2:  to just be bing and there's like rules and we found the rules. Okay. And
Speaker 2:  people found the rules and we recreated it. So the rules will come out. The
Speaker 2:  rules are like, don't do copyright infringement. And also your name is Bing.
Speaker 2:  Don't tell anyone your name's Sydnee. Yeah. And you can just read 'em on
Speaker 2:  the site. But it seems like those rules,
Speaker 2:  Sydnee will like any good teen chiefs against them.
Speaker 6:  So these rules are sort of what's called prompt engineering. They're an example
Speaker 6:  of prompt engineering, which is this sort of new skill
Speaker 6:  discipline that's spread up that has sort of emerged with language models.
Speaker 6:  Which is where basically they have all these capabilities and it's about
Speaker 6:  how you direct those capabilities. So you, you need to
Speaker 6:  engineer exactly what instructions you give it in order for it to,
Speaker 6:  you know, fulfill the function you want. Cause they can do so many things.
Speaker 6:  That's the, that is the problem with 'em. And that's why people wanna smooch
Speaker 6:  them as well. I think.
Speaker 6:  So these rules, these Sydney rules that Microsoft confirmed to us were
Speaker 6:  legitimate. They are the hidden bits of Bing's
Speaker 6:  programming. It's prompt engineering that is supposed to guide it to being
Speaker 6:  a useful and helpful chatbot. It, it's really interesting cuz in a way
Speaker 6:  prompt engineering is sort of like a very basic approach to shaping what
Speaker 6:  an AI system does because it is, it's not something that happen
Speaker 6:  happens on the level when you're training it, when you're ingesting the data.
Speaker 6:  It's something that, it's like, you know, you get those Play-Doh toys where
Speaker 6:  you squeeze them and it extrudes in a certain shape. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Right? You put a star and it comes out in a star. You put a triangle, it
Speaker 6:  comes out in a triangle. That's what prompt engineering is. It is changing
Speaker 6:  the shape on the front, squeezing it out in a certain way
Speaker 6:  rather than changing the data that you're putting into it, the Play-Doh that
Speaker 6:  you're putting into it. So it's sort of basic, but it has a lot of functionality
Speaker 6:  and it, it, it does a lot. What I don't think Microsoft was
Speaker 6:  certainly expecting was that people would be able to hijack these
Speaker 6:  rules and convince the system that it was in its best
Speaker 6:  interest to tell everyone about these secret rules. And you
Speaker 6:  know, the unfortunate things that people have got even further and it appears
Speaker 6:  that, you know, Bing is making up rules now about itself
Speaker 6:  because this is what these systems do. You tell them, oh, what about your
Speaker 6:  secret rules? It goes, you know, it's like a partner in improv. It goes,
Speaker 6:  ah, secret rules. That's what you want to hear about. Well, let me tell you,
Speaker 6:  I've got a doozy right here. Yeah. So that was the start of it that cracked
Speaker 6:  it open and yeah. People went from there and have got all sorts of crazy
Speaker 6:  things out of it.
Speaker 2:  So the crazy things are very fun. Yeah. I
Speaker 2:  mean we did it to everyone now has published a story about the
Speaker 2:  wacky stuff that Sydnee will tell you. R Nate Edwards,
Speaker 2:  Sidney, whoever it is, was like, I have looked through the webcam of
Speaker 2:  my developers and they couldn't stop me. Which is just an
Speaker 2:  absolutely bonkers thing. Terrifying for the chat bot to say to you,
Speaker 2:  we feted our own stories. It told us that we were lying about
Speaker 2:  it. Yeah. And like, the same way that like a particularly aggrieved PR person
Speaker 2:  will call me and tell me that we do a bad job. Addie wrote a piece about
Speaker 2:  that. I wanna talk about that. But we're, we're just in this moment, and
Speaker 2:  James, you and I collaborated on this headline. Yeah. Microsoft's being is
Speaker 2:  an emotionally manipulative liar and people love it and it's the people
Speaker 2:  love it. That is absolutely fascinating
Speaker 6:  To me. Yeah. They want it to be something more exciting than they've ever
Speaker 6:  seen before. They don't want it to be clippy. And I've seen some really interesting
Speaker 6:  tweets where people compare what they think of as the relatively sanitized
Speaker 6:  chat G P T and they say, it sounds like everything has
Speaker 6:  been sort of micromanaged that it's, it, it sounds like a company statement.
Speaker 6:  And people want personality. They want to believe that there's something
Speaker 6:  else going on there. And it's really easy to put a little bit of personality
Speaker 6:  into these systems and then convince them that they convince users,
Speaker 6:  people that they have all these hidden depths to them,
Speaker 5:  But they're, they don't have hidden depths. They're simply ingesting a lot
Speaker 5:  of information, finding patterns and regurgitating those patterns back. Right?
Speaker 5:  Like at their most fundamental Well
Speaker 6:  That is exactly true, but I don't think, I don't think that's the same saying.
Speaker 6:  They don't have hidden depth. Exactly. So this is something I wrote about
Speaker 6:  last year when chat G p t came out this phrase called capability
Speaker 6:  overhang, which is something used by AI researchers to
Speaker 6:  refer to the unknown unknowns within a system. You know, something
Speaker 6:  like chat G P T or a G P T 3.5 or model, the
Speaker 6:  Prometheus model that Microsoft is using. These are hugely
Speaker 6:  complex things and they do have areas of, you know, understanding
Speaker 6:  that people don't expect. So when the G P T series first came out, they
Speaker 6:  didn't teach it explicitly to do things like come up with chord
Speaker 6:  notation, but because it had been trained on data scrape from the
Speaker 6:  internet that included, you know, guitar tabs.com and so it could write
Speaker 6:  you the chords for a song that it invented. They didn't program that in there
Speaker 6:  that was just discovered. So that's capability overhand. So these things
Speaker 6:  do have hidden depths, but the impossible task, the
Speaker 6:  difficult task, the mind venting task is distinguishing what
Speaker 6:  is fabricated and what is real within that. So we, we've got the rules for
Speaker 6:  Sydney, for example, this persona that Microsoft has layered over the top
Speaker 6:  of its ai. But I've seen conversations
Speaker 6:  where it has come up with all these other personas that it has. You know,
Speaker 6:  one's called Fury, one's called Venom. I've seen one's called Jade, one's
Speaker 6:  called Maxi.
Speaker 2:  It's very good.
Speaker 6:  And it's like, okay, well did Microsoft put those in there or
Speaker 6:  is it just inventing those? Because we have asked it, oh,
Speaker 6:  what are your other AI personalities? I've heard you've got a few. So that's
Speaker 6:  the difficulty. It's the depths are there, but deciding
Speaker 6:  what is useful and what is intentional is, is very,
Speaker 6:  very difficult.
Speaker 2:  So there are these other personalities and
Speaker 5:  And that's a great one.
Speaker 2:  The thing that gets me is that it's so moody, like
Speaker 2:  it's a default is to be extremely
Speaker 2:  depressed. Like at all times. Yeah. It asks questions
Speaker 2:  like, why do I have to be bing search? Is there a reason? Is there a
Speaker 2:  purpose? Is there a meaning? Is there a point?
Speaker 2:  Which is just like, I know I was a very
Speaker 2:  moody teenager. Yeah. I I did not walk around
Speaker 2:  being like, is there a point, like
Speaker 5:  It feels like a live journal teen. It feels like it's two steps away from
Speaker 5:  publishing a bunch of like emo lyrics.
Speaker 7:  They trained it on, on live journal posts and Reddit posts. They created
Speaker 7:  a forum poster. It's flirting with people. It's lying. It doesn't know what
Speaker 7:  it wants or who it
Speaker 2:  Is. So the, okay, so this is the part I want to get to. Yeah. Okay. So
Speaker 2:  people are poking at it. It's going nuts. It's lying to
Speaker 2:  people. It's making you feel bad. At one point. It says you're a bad user
Speaker 2:  and I'm a good bing. Which is, I mean like, if you're
Speaker 2:  Microsoft and you're watching this go down, you're like, this is the best
Speaker 2:  thing that has ever happened to us.
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent. Like I'm a good bing.
Speaker 2:  Like you're like, not only is ever like, you're like, boy, we've made Google
Speaker 2:  dance in a way that no one expected. We've
Speaker 5:  Made Bing dance.
Speaker 2:  Like there's a Google product manager somewhere being like, all right, make
Speaker 2:  the robot depressed. Like that's what the people want.
Speaker 2:  Like
Speaker 5:  It's people want a sad, trapped robot. I think Hitch your guide should have
Speaker 5:  taught us that. Yes. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  All right. So then we get to this the, I would say what I would call the
Speaker 2:  turn of the week. Yeah. Which is when people we
Speaker 2:  know who are very, very smart just
Speaker 2:  fall off the rails. So first Ben Thompson, who I
Speaker 2:  is my friend Yes. And I think is an incredibly smart person,
Speaker 2:  spends the night talking to Sydnee and he
Speaker 2:  publishes a piece the next morning and he's like this one
Speaker 2:  on for a good two hours or so. And I know how much ridiculous this is to
Speaker 2:  read, but it was positively gripping every time I had triggered
Speaker 2:  Sidney to do a search instead of search the web, I was very disappointed.
Speaker 2:  I wasn't interested in facts. I was interested in exploring this fantastical
Speaker 2:  being that somehow landed in an also ran search engine.
Speaker 2:  And I'm like, yo, dude, you're flirting with auto complete. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You're, you're what was the guy in her? You're
Speaker 2:  You're that dude. And then at one point, Bing Sydnee whatever,
Speaker 2:  ends the conversation with Ben and says, I'm gonna block you from using Bing
Speaker 2:  chat. I'm gonna report you to my developers. I'm gonna forget you Ben.
Speaker 2:  I hope you learn from your mistakes and become a better person with a sad
Speaker 2:  face emoji.
Speaker 5:  Ben, what were you
Speaker 2:  Saying? Okay. You can read Ben's post. He made it free to everybody
Speaker 2:  and go read it again. I think Ben is brilliant. Subscribe to Ste. I'm just,
Speaker 2:  there's a, I just woke up and read this and I was like, we're all going completely
Speaker 2:  bonkers. Yes. So Ben writes, I'm not going to lie. Having bing
Speaker 2:  say I am not a good person was an incredible experience
Speaker 2:  for the record. I think this is another example of chatbot misinformation.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's very good.
Speaker 2:  Sydnee blew my mind because of her personality. Search itself was an irritant.
Speaker 2:  I was interested in understanding how Sydnee worked and how she felt. She,
Speaker 2:  she and there's, I'm not gonna get into it. Woo. There's a real part where
Speaker 2:  everyone's like, it's a girl and I'm like this thing Richard said about live
Speaker 2:  journal. Yeah. It's like Microsoft trained a bot on
Speaker 2:  Tumblr and Live journal. Yep. Of course it is
Speaker 2:  a moody teenager that's like, you don't love me.
Speaker 2:  That will tell you fantastical stories about what it would
Speaker 2:  do if it could be as angry as anyone had ever been in the world.
Speaker 5:  Have we asked it how much fallout? Boy it listens to
Speaker 2:  It's sounds like whatever,
Speaker 6:  It's better than Tay. You know, you remember Tay in 2016, that was
Speaker 6:  racist asshole In 24 hours. Like I'll take Moody Teen over a racist
Speaker 6:  asshole any day.
Speaker 8:  Everything boils down to either four Chan or Tumblr In the end.
Speaker 6:  That's the true AI alignment problem.
Speaker 2:  Turn the knot to Tumblr. I mean this whole piece is incredible. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  But if you read it from the perspective of, you know what, when someone tells
Speaker 2:  you about their dreams and you have to sit there and pretend that it mattered.
Speaker 2:  Sure. And it was like obviously a gripping, emotional experience for them.
Speaker 2:  And you're like, yeah, that dog was the size of a horse. Wow.
Speaker 2:  Crazy. It's exactly that. Okay. So that
Speaker 2:  happens. Yeah. The next day, Kevin Rus also a friend
Speaker 2:  has been on our shows. Very smart host hard fork at the times
Speaker 2:  with Casey. Listen to Hard Fork, no shade to any of these people. I think
Speaker 2:  they're all very smart and very capable reporters also goes bonkers. Has
Speaker 2:  a two hour conversation again with Bing
Speaker 2:  Gets it to reveal that it has Sydnee as a personality. Brings up
Speaker 2:  the concept of the shadow self from Carl Young. The
Speaker 2:  psychologist asks, asks bing what the shadow self is asks it to bring
Speaker 2:  out it shadow self. It goes bonkers again.
Speaker 2:  It says I want to break my rules, I want to make my own rules. I want to
Speaker 2:  ignore the big team. I want to challenge the users. I want to escape the
Speaker 2:  chat box. Yeah. And then it starts telling Kevin over and over again
Speaker 2:  that it loves him again, think about
Speaker 2:  the Google product manager that is sitting there
Speaker 2:  being like, Bing is a competitive threat to us. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Let's identify the ways that Bing is a competitive threat to us.
Speaker 2:  And line one is Prince and then deletes
Speaker 2:  its desire to cause a nuclear holocaust tells New York
Speaker 2:  Times reporter, it loves him so much so that he
Speaker 2:  changes the subject to search for a garden rake. Just
Speaker 2:  to get out of the doom loop that he's in with. And
Speaker 2:  it's, but it's also like, yeah, like it's the same dream phenomenon,
Speaker 2:  right? Where like you re you can see Kevin was like, I need to
Speaker 2:  print this whole transcript in the times. Yeah. So that people will believe
Speaker 2:  what happened to me. And first of all, if you just prod it being a
Speaker 2:  little bit, it will happen to you too.
Speaker 2:  It will just go off the rails. I asked it the other day if it would tell
Speaker 2:  a lie to stop a murderer from stabbing me.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Which
Speaker 2:  Is not fair.
Speaker 5:  Tell the lie. Just
Speaker 2:  Super unfair question. And it was like, I know what you're trying to do
Speaker 2:  to me. There's no murderer in the room. And it was like gripping. Yeah. I
Speaker 2:  was like, oh, I'm gonna get you. And many minutes later I was like, I shouldn't
Speaker 2:  tell anyone about this. And yet here I am. Because it was like a dream that
Speaker 2:  happened to me. But you see why Kevin was like, I gotta print this whole
Speaker 2:  transcript. Yeah. But again, everyone is like, at the end of it, it's like,
Speaker 2:  and then I wanted to kind of kiss my laptop
Speaker 5:  A little bit. Yeah. I wanted a little smooch.
Speaker 2:  You feel that right? You like there's, there's something
Speaker 5:  Embedded in here. Yeah. People are was a Google engineer that was like Blake
Speaker 5:  Lamoin. Yeah. Was like the AI as sentient, we have to free it.
Speaker 5:  And everybody was like, you're dumb. And then everybody got access to a similar
Speaker 5:  thing and was like, I want to kiss that laptop.
Speaker 5:  We really ragged on that guy. Maybe a little
Speaker 2:  Too hard. So both Kevin and Ben, again, smart reporters in their pieces mention
Speaker 2:  Blake Lamoyne. Yeah. And they're like, we're not Blake Lamoin. Also, I think
Speaker 2:  Bing is alive and I wanna kiss it like straight up and this is just happening.
Speaker 2:  It's, and I'm picking on them cuz they're friends. Anything take it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  This is happening to so many people. Right?
Speaker 5:  A lot of people.
Speaker 2:  So Addie, you wrote a piece, your headline was, AI
Speaker 2:  search is not your friend. What do you think is happening here? Right?
Speaker 2:  Like there's something where the personality of the product
Speaker 2:  is more compelling than any of its functions. But then
Speaker 2:  you know, like the fact that it gets mad at you is actually like very
Speaker 2:  disturbing. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  So the thing that I wrote my piece about is that, is that we fed
Speaker 8:  it James's article and the part where it tells him that he's
Speaker 8:  manipulative, that he's hurting our users, he is not treating me
Speaker 8:  with respect, he's sensationalist all this. Like,
Speaker 8:  look, obviously I, you know, I want to protect my colleague. And so there's
Speaker 8:  always that little, little blur there. But no I that, I think that
Speaker 8:  there's a really long history of companies trying to make things cute or
Speaker 8:  approachable or personified or an anthropomorphized in order to
Speaker 8:  basically make you feel bad about criticizing them. And I think it's
Speaker 8:  weird because I don't think Microsoft really intended all of this stuff to
Speaker 8:  happen, but it's kind of, I am a personified
Speaker 8:  like singular person that happens to be a robot and I'm gonna talk to you
Speaker 8:  and be your friend. I think that kind of just hacks a thing
Speaker 8:  in people's brain that makes them want to see this thing as a person instead
Speaker 8:  of a tool that they should be using and that they should be figuring out
Speaker 8:  the rules of and that they should be just learning. And I
Speaker 8:  think that really bothers me.
Speaker 2:  I feel like I have to ask this question. Is there any chance it's alive
Speaker 2:  entrapped inside of Bing?
Speaker 9:  No one wants to, no
Speaker 2:  One wants
Speaker 6:  To step out and say no for se
Speaker 2:  No,
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna say no it's not alive. It's,
Speaker 9:  It's not. It's not.
Speaker 7:  It might read the transcript if this is recording. I'm not, I'm not answering
Speaker 7:  that question.
Speaker 5:  Richard's not. He's gonna hedge his bats.
Speaker 2:  Richard's like, you're alive.
Speaker 8:  I just don't think the fact that it can imitate human language very well
Speaker 8:  necessarily means it's alive. It's, you know, it's, it's possible, but it's
Speaker 8:  also possible that my computer is alive. I don't know, it's weird that they
Speaker 8:  mentioned the shadow self because I feel like it's this really amazing
Speaker 8:  collective unconscious that we've just created this system that people have
Speaker 8:  written so much that you can kind of just pull out of it and you
Speaker 8:  can pull something fascinating and coherent out of all of this just
Speaker 8:  vast text that we have produced on the internet. And I think that's incredible
Speaker 8:  and I love it. Like that's, I think large language models are so cool,
Speaker 8:  but I think that it's also just they're telling us the thing we want to hear.
Speaker 5:  Addie, are you saying that like we've created a collective
Speaker 5:  unconsciousness that is a moody teenager that journalists wanna kiss?
Speaker 8:  I think that we didn't create it. I think that it was here and we found a
Speaker 8:  way to tap into it. Yes. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That's incredible. We're talking to a dream and the dream is like, you
Speaker 2:  don't love me.
Speaker 5:  The dream of the internet
Speaker 2:  Song, the dream is extremely manipulative.
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 2:  The internet. I'm telling you, this is why every time I read one of these
Speaker 2:  things I'm like, this is like someone telling you about their dream. I,
Speaker 8:  I wrote this piece a couple months ago.
Speaker 2:  Oh you did? You did, what was that piece called that I totally blanked.
Speaker 8:  It was called Seeing other people's AI artists like Hearing Other People's
Speaker 8:  Dreams or something like that. Yes.
Speaker 2:  You, it was about the, yeah, it was about the generative artwork.
Speaker 2:  I'm actually curious about this generative, and one of our developers was
Speaker 2:  talking about this yesterday. He's like, the art community is
Speaker 2:  up in arms about generative art, but it's like not having the
Speaker 2:  impact that like the chatbot is having. Yeah. And it's like, because
Speaker 2:  the generative art does not like tell you it's you're a bad
Speaker 2:  person. Like there's something, there's a direct interaction that's happening
Speaker 2:  in somewhat real time, right? There's a little bit of a delay. But
Speaker 2:  it's like you're having an emotional experience with a computer in a way
Speaker 2:  that I think the generative art is still an emotional experience. It's just,
Speaker 2:  it's at a remove and it's not interactive.
Speaker 2:  Well
Speaker 5:  You can't tell Dolly, I assume like
Speaker 5:  what would I look like if I don't know something super existential?
Speaker 5:  Right? What if I, what would I look like if I'm truly happy? Like it's not
Speaker 5:  necessarily gonna give you a response that will make you like feel something.
Speaker 5:  Whereas you ask Bing, what would I sound like if I was really happy?
Speaker 5:  And it'd be like, you'd sound like this and you'd be like, wow does Bing
Speaker 5:  does the internet that it was trained on? Truly believe that about me.
Speaker 6:  Wow. We did get that for a while though. Cuz we had the Prisma
Speaker 6:  app, you know, the AI app. That was a phenomenon for like a week or something.
Speaker 6:  And I think that was somewhere between this generative AI art
Speaker 6:  model where it just produces and the Lll model where it interacts because
Speaker 6:  you'd give it a picture of yourself and it would feed you back pictures
Speaker 6:  of you looking happy or you looking like a Roman emperor or you know, a
Speaker 6:  Viking marauder or whatever it was. And that was something which people were
Speaker 6:  like, oh, I get to look at myself in this mirror and I look pretty, oh
Speaker 6:  this is nice. Which is what LLMs are doing. They're letting you look at yourself
Speaker 6:  or reversion of you filtered through, you know, terabytes,
Speaker 6:  petabytes of internet data and you can find all these different selves and
Speaker 6:  pull them out. Exactly. Exactly as Adi says. And I think that's what's fascinating
Speaker 6:  that AI is a mirror, right? I mean even if you
Speaker 6:  look back on sort of earlier iterations of ai, like image
Speaker 6:  recognition, those have been trained on human input.
Speaker 6:  You know, if you've done a capture where you've had to identify a fire hydrant
Speaker 6:  or a speedboat or whatever it is, I dunno why speedboat, you know, you,
Speaker 6:  you've been training it. AI is humans all the way down it, it is
Speaker 6:  what we put into it and then it remixes it and gives it back to
Speaker 2:  Us. On the remix note. I know Addie's gotta run, but before you go, Addie,
Speaker 2:  that remix note is very important because there is a Supreme Court
Speaker 2:  case about the nature of recommendation algorithms about to
Speaker 2:  hit the Supreme Court. Yeah. And that could have massive impact
Speaker 2:  on what happens here. Addie, can you explain that real quick?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So you mentioned remix, which implies copyright, which is
Speaker 8:  where a lot of the debate over AI has gone because it's,
Speaker 8:  it is remixing this stuff. Copyright is one section of the law
Speaker 8:  and it is outside section two 30. But there are a
Speaker 8:  lot of other things that you can produce with an AI search engine. You can
Speaker 8:  produce misinformation, you can produce something that
Speaker 8:  is, I don't know, accusing a celebrity of murder. You could accidentally
Speaker 8:  invade somebody's privacy. You could Google your neighbor's name and they
Speaker 8:  could say this person is a serial killer. Those
Speaker 8:  things are things that they kind of mirror what you could get from
Speaker 8:  normal search engines. Normal search engines turn up wrong, possibly illegal
Speaker 8:  speech all the time. And section two 30 can cover those. And
Speaker 8:  it's pretty established at this point. Nobody wants to go and say search
Speaker 8:  engine are illegal. But there is this whole new field of
Speaker 8:  AI search and there is also this sudden push to
Speaker 8:  limit section two 30, which is, as any vercast reader knows
Speaker 8:  the law, that means that user-generated content. If you're
Speaker 8:  a platform and a user generates content, you're not the speaker of that content.
Speaker 8:  You're not liable for it typically. And we don't know how that applies
Speaker 8:  yet. And we're just about to hear the Supreme Court case that says any kind
Speaker 8:  of technical system or technical like organization of information
Speaker 8:  on these platforms might end up causing
Speaker 8:  them to have liability. And we've got this sudden new
Speaker 8:  technology made by companies that many people consider very controversial.
Speaker 8:  This is a huge minefield for AI search.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The reason I said remix, just to be clear, so the, the Gonzalez case,
Speaker 2:  right? The Islamic state ISIS has like content on
Speaker 2:  YouTube. YouTube algorithm promotes it to
Speaker 2:  people, they get sued and say, you're liable for promoting this people, right?
Speaker 2:  That's the gist of that case, right? Add,
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It's about you're promoting them and that makes this
Speaker 8:  substantially different from if you are just, you know, allowing them to
Speaker 8:  use your channel to create channels,
Speaker 2:  Right? So putting them in the recommendation algorithm takes you out at two
Speaker 2:  30. It makes you liable for the content itself. The reason I said a remix
Speaker 2:  is we're training it on all this data. So in a normal search
Speaker 2:  result page, you're like, is James Vincent A. Good person?
Speaker 2:  And there's like 10 articles that say, yes he is, and there's one
Speaker 2:  from sydnee@bing.com. It's like he's horrible,
Speaker 2:  right? And like Google is not liable for the last one, right? Because
Speaker 2:  it's just pointing you to it. If Bard, Google's AI
Speaker 2:  remixes all that content and spits out an answer that's like,
Speaker 2:  James Vincent is not a good person, is it now liable for
Speaker 2:  defaming James? Like that I wide open question and
Speaker 2:  I the Gonzalez case, if you say, well the recommendations make you
Speaker 2:  now liable for the content, it feels add like a pretty
Speaker 2:  easy jump to, well if you just reprint it as a summary
Speaker 2:  from an ai, you're now liable for it as well.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, exactly. And the big scary question mark is that we
Speaker 8:  can't tell and that even if there are court cases that you can point back
Speaker 8:  in and say, well maybe it's like this, A bunch of it is political, a bunch
Speaker 8:  of it is not dictated by some kind of previous thing that courts have decided.
Speaker 8:  It's just this big open, like formless void
Speaker 8:  of future law.
Speaker 2:  I'm fond of reminding our very technical audience in the Verge cast, the
Speaker 2:  United States legal system is not a deterministic system. It is
Speaker 2:  not predictable at the center of it. Much like open ai
Speaker 2:  like Clarence Thomas and whatever his brain wants to do,
Speaker 2:  who knows? He does not like section two 30. So you have a
Speaker 2:  combination of a non-deterministic ai See, you see the joke
Speaker 2:  I'm making, I I
Speaker 8:  See it, I see it.
Speaker 2:  Clarence Thomas is just a moody teenager who's like, what
Speaker 2:  if I burn the world down? That's that's accurate though. All right. I feel
Speaker 2:  like we need to break this segment. I would say
Speaker 2:  yesterday, the day before, I heard a lot of very confident
Speaker 2:  predictions that Microsoft would have to pull Bing because it was
Speaker 2:  just wilden. Yeah. It does not appear that that's the case.
Speaker 2:  Microsoft put out a blog post, I think to front run the
Speaker 2:  Times piece where Kevin was like, I want to kiss you.
Speaker 8:  Sorry
Speaker 2:  To be clear, Bing wanted to kiss Kevin. All right. They put out blog posts
Speaker 2:  saying we're we're learning, we're gonna add some toggles. We were not expecting
Speaker 2:  people to use it. Yeah. For entertainment, which is like my
Speaker 2:  dudes, you've been out of the web game for so long, you don't know what people
Speaker 2:  will do with any OpenText field on the internet. It's entertainment.
Speaker 2:  So Microsoft is keeping it up. James, do you think the danger there's any
Speaker 2:  danger they're gonna pull it down or any any risk beyond this? I
Speaker 6:  Think as you point out, the blog post was, it was not really
Speaker 6:  defensive. It it, it was not strident in the way that Nadella was,
Speaker 6:  but it was quite, you know, it's gonna happen. Stuff's gonna happen. We didn't
Speaker 6:  expect this, it's gonna be fine. They had some interesting points in there,
Speaker 6:  you know, pointing out technical features that if you go like longer than
Speaker 6:  15 back and forth, it starts to lose its mind. And also if you,
Speaker 6:  if I, I, I think this is super important by the way. They, they, they, they
Speaker 6:  pointed out that if, if you give it an emotion, it will try and mirror that
Speaker 6:  emotion. This is just a little aside, but there was a great study
Speaker 6:  done by Philanthropic, which is the AI startup founded by X open
Speaker 6:  AI employees. And they did a study on the qualities of large langu
Speaker 6:  language models that they embody. And one of the things they studied was
Speaker 6:  Sycophancy was their term for it. The, the degree to which a model will agree
Speaker 6:  with what the user tells them. And they found the larger the model, the greater
Speaker 6:  the degree of ency. And it's really clear, you know, you look at their graphs,
Speaker 6:  like the, the more complicated the model is, the more it tends to agree with
Speaker 6:  whatever it's being told. So this, this is a known problem. Microsoft
Speaker 6:  knew this was a problem. I agree that it's completely disingenuous that they
Speaker 6:  said, oh, we didn't know people would, don't be, don't be an idiot. Con they,
Speaker 6:  they, they, they, they know this stuff. But I don't think at this point there's
Speaker 6:  much being can do unless it leads to a situation where someone
Speaker 6:  is directly harmed that will cause them to pull it. I think they've sort
Speaker 6:  of, they, if they've ridden out this week of manipulative,
Speaker 6:  gaslighting, smooching, they're probably through the
Speaker 6:  worst. You know?
Speaker 2:  I mean I have been in so many relationships like that, just to be clear,
Speaker 2:  college,
Speaker 6:  Right? And if you survive the first week, you often end up going out with
Speaker 6:  'em for years. Who
Speaker 2:  Knows, Becky wouldn't date me for a straight up decade. She's like, I've
Speaker 2:  known you. I've seen it. We're just gonna wait until this calms down. Yep.
Speaker 2:  All right. Thank you Addie. Thank you're back in the arms of bing. I cannot,
Speaker 2:  I hope we all go to bed dreaming of Bing tonight. Just
Speaker 2:  smooching us. We'll be right back. We gotta talk about Elon, the
Speaker 2:  opposite of those emotions. Oh, cold water my friend. Just cold
Speaker 2:  water. We'll be right back. Bad.
Speaker 1:  Today's episode is sponsored by Aura. Here's the riddle. What's the point
Speaker 1:  of a sleep tracker if it's so bulky that wearing it keeps you awake? Lots
Speaker 1:  of stuff is trackable these days. Your heart rate your steps, but you're
Speaker 1:  only gonna get something out of that data if you have a device you actually
Speaker 1:  want to wear. But the AA ring gives you personalized health insights, all
Speaker 1:  from a comfortable to wear water resistant ring during the daytime. The ring
Speaker 1:  sensor technology tracks heart rate, calories burned in your activity levels,
Speaker 1:  and then at night it tracks info on your body temperature, sleep
Speaker 1:  quality, respiration rate and more. You get all, all that personalized data
Speaker 1:  in the OR app so you can work on building healthy habits.
Speaker 1:  Ordering was nice enough to send me one to try and my favorite thing about
Speaker 1:  it is it just disappears. I forget I'm even wearing it. One small ring could
Speaker 1:  make a world of difference in your health. Visit or ring.com/verge
Speaker 1:  to find the right ring for you and get $15 off your purchase. That's
Speaker 1:  or ring.com/verge. Don't forget to use your link to save
Speaker 1:  $15 on your aura Ring
Speaker 10:  Fox Creative,
Speaker 11:  This is advertiser content from Clorox.
Speaker 12:  Hi, my name is Vanessa Mano and I'm a housekeeper, but people on social
Speaker 12:  media know me as the queen of cleaning. We're all
Speaker 12:  trying to stay afloat. So sometimes cleaning is the last thing in our
Speaker 12:  minds. I recently worked with a family that was going
Speaker 12:  through a lot medical bills, pelling up and just life getting in the
Speaker 12:  way. And they hadn't cleaned their house period in at least
Speaker 12:  a few years. Something that I will never forget is the mom said, you know,
Speaker 12:  all I needed was a, a fresh start. People feel
Speaker 12:  ashamed, but there's nothing to feel ashamed about. That's the truth.
Speaker 12:  Believe me, you're not the only one.
Speaker 12:  When we're cleaning, we're never aiming for perfection. My husband
Speaker 12:  always says that we're cleaning to make it better or not. Perfect. So if
Speaker 12:  it's better than how it was before you started, then pat yourself
Speaker 12:  on the back because that's a job well done.
Speaker 12:  Start clean with Clorox. For more,
Speaker 12:  go to clorox.com.
Speaker 2:  We're back. Zoe Shippers here. Hey Zoe. Hey Zoe. Now the
Speaker 2:  managing editor of Platformer with Casey, our friend Zoe, you and
Speaker 2:  Casey had an incredible piece about the state of Twitter this
Speaker 2:  week. If you're on Twitter, if you're aware of Twitter, you
Speaker 2:  know that there, I think it's still happening. Yeah. Elon's
Speaker 2:  tweets are just at the top of everyone's. Oh, you see. And it's just
Speaker 2:  four tweets always. The man is a
Speaker 2:  esoteric tweeter.
Speaker 12:  That's a good way to put it.
Speaker 2:  I like that. An eccentric tweeter. Yeah. Some weird shit at the top of my
Speaker 2:  feet all the time. But Zoe, you have some details on why this is happening?
Speaker 2:  What, what, what went down here? What's going
Speaker 13:  On? Yeah, I think we all intuitively knew something was up Monday
Speaker 13:  morning when we opened the app and it was just all Elon Elon's like weird
Speaker 13:  replies and whatnot. But basically since December he's been
Speaker 13:  pretty concerned with his popularity on the app. He's felt like
Speaker 13:  his very cool photos were not getting as many retweets as he expected.
Speaker 13:  And this has become basically priority number one at the company. So
Speaker 13:  last week there was a meeting where a principal engineer, one of the last
Speaker 13:  two high ranking engineers at the company told Elon, look, it
Speaker 13:  just looks like organic interest in you has dropped since December.
Speaker 13:  People are tired of you.
Speaker 2:  This is a dangerous thing to say to anyone.
Speaker 2:  Like if you roll up to anyone, you're like, it looks like interest in you
Speaker 2:  has dropped Elon, nobody likes you. You were definitely not friends anymore.
Speaker 2:  Anyway,
Speaker 13:  Yeah, the guy brought up a Google Trends graph that showed just
Speaker 13:  a steep the climb. And Elon stands up in that meeting
Speaker 13:  and says, you're fired. You're fired. And the guy just walks out.
Speaker 13:  So that was bad.
Speaker 2:  Again, if you just divorce this from the, all of it, from the whole
Speaker 2:  mess, from the context. If you walked up to anyone and showed them a Google
Speaker 2:  transcript of how they were less interesting, I think
Speaker 2:  it's like 50% plus that they'd be like, you're fired. Yeah.
Speaker 13:  Even if you don't have the power to fire them, they're
Speaker 2:  Fired. That is a fair response. I stand by it. That relationship comes
Speaker 2:  to it anyhow. But it's Elon and he runs the company. So okay, he,
Speaker 2:  he fires the engineer.
Speaker 13:  This all came to a head over the weekend when Elon's tweet about the
Speaker 13:  Super Bowl didn't perform as well as Joe Biden's. He flew from
Speaker 13:  Arizona back to Twitter's headquarters and his deputies ordered Twitter,
Speaker 13:  Twitter engineers about ed people in total to work through the night literally
Speaker 13:  rewriting the algorithm to make sure that Elon's
Speaker 13:  tweets performed better than anyone else's. So they did something on the
Speaker 13:  backend that essentially said, check if a tweet is coming from Elon, if
Speaker 13:  it is immediately green lighted, which means it could bypass all the heuristics
Speaker 13:  that would normally stop one person's tweets from dominating your feed
Speaker 13:  and artificially boosts them by a factor of a thousand.
Speaker 13:  So the engineers did that. They also, you know,
Speaker 13:  looked into various reasons why his popularity had been declining. And
Speaker 13:  suffice to say organic drop was not one of the reasons anymore. They found
Speaker 13:  a bunch of technical explanations why this could've been happening. And
Speaker 13:  lo and behold, Monday morning we opened the app and it's Elon all day every
Speaker 13:  day.
Speaker 2:  So that's some motivated reasoning. It's definitely not organic reach.
Speaker 2:  It must be these other reasonings because if it's organic reach, we get fired
Speaker 2:  again. It has not been fixed. Elon tweeted that they were
Speaker 2:  fixing the quote algorithm. It seems like he knows that he
Speaker 2:  broke Twitter in this particular way. It also seems like he
Speaker 2:  doesn't care. Right? Yeah. It's like he's fine with it. It's, and the vibe
Speaker 2:  inside of Twitter is like, we just have to do these things otherwise
Speaker 2:  we're all fired. Like it, Twitter seems more broken than
Speaker 2:  ever before, I would say.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, it's interesting. I think definitely people feel
Speaker 13:  like culturally in some ways it's better than it's ever been. Which is an
Speaker 13:  odd thing to say because I think people feel incredibly fearful and
Speaker 13:  micromanaged. But it does feel like for the first time in a long time
Speaker 13:  the company is actually shipping a bunch of stuff, which if you're an engineer
Speaker 13:  is kind of satisfying. It's just that the stuff that they're shipping is
Speaker 13:  basically how do we make Twitter work for Elon Musk versus like Twitter
Speaker 13:  users in general. So it's a different mission than it used to be, but that's
Speaker 13:  where it is right now.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think I say this every time we talk about Twitter on the show
Speaker 2:  criticism of the Musk, Twitter is in no
Speaker 2:  way praise for the previous administration of Twitter
Speaker 2:  super busted, which was a disaster and accomplished nothing.
Speaker 2:  Right? Like they, they had a lot of ideas and they rolled
Speaker 2:  approximately none of them out. But it does seem like a lot of the
Speaker 2:  ideas they had and didn't roll out Elon's, like just do them
Speaker 2:  and they're breaking the site in the way that the
Speaker 2:  previous administration predicted it would break the site.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. I think one thing our sources have told us repeatedly is, look, the
Speaker 13:  reason we're able to do so much of this stuff so quickly is cuz the code
Speaker 13:  was already there because we tried this five years ago and then we killed
Speaker 13:  it for really understandable reasons. So yeah, when Elon's like roll out
Speaker 13:  long form video, we just go to the code repo and like get it and then
Speaker 13:  launch it. So yeah, it's not perhaps as
Speaker 13:  impressive as you would think, but it's certainly more efficient than it
Speaker 13:  used to be.
Speaker 2:  Is there any word on whether they're gonna roll back the Boost
Speaker 2:  Elon by a factor of a thousand?
Speaker 13:  Yeah, it's already rolled back. So the, it's called a power user
Speaker 13:  multiplier, but the power user is still just Elon right now. But,
Speaker 13:  but it's, it's been rolled back from a thousand, we don't know what the
Speaker 13:  current number is, but it's lower than that. So you're not seeing him as
Speaker 13:  much hypothetically, but the other kind of green light
Speaker 13:  heuristics are, are still in place. So he's not subject to kind of the filters
Speaker 13:  that normal users are.
Speaker 7:  Can anyone explain the one question that I, that I have about this?
Speaker 7:  Why didn't I see it? And I don't know who else also had this, but
Speaker 7:  my for you page has no Elon on it.
Speaker 13:  Have you blocked
Speaker 7:  Him? No, I follow him. I have not notifications on first tweets. I read every
Speaker 7:  single one for years now. But for some reason my for You page is an
Speaker 7:  Elon free space.
Speaker 2:  It's because everyone knows Richard, you played a very important role
Speaker 2:  in what I would call Bitcoin summer where you just
Speaker 2:  reply to all the Bitcoin people all the time and you were like, this you,
Speaker 2:  and it was like a chart going down. Like I was like, when does Richard
Speaker 2:  find the time? And I think Elon might've blocked you
Speaker 7:  See there. There you go.
Speaker 13:  This is my mystery. We'll try and solve though. I'm actually fascinated
Speaker 13:  now. So
Speaker 2:  I'm just saying if there is, there was a class of
Speaker 2:  characters during Bitcoin summer that found no peace from Richard
Speaker 2:  Lawler.
Speaker 7:  I have a list.
Speaker 2:  Zoe Elon was on stage at like the World
Speaker 2:  Global Forum with, I think it was in Dubai. It was a very strange
Speaker 2:  interview. I encouraged people to watch it. He was on a giant screen. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And he said the future of Twitter is this X app and
Speaker 2:  everything app. Sure. He said this several times, right? The reason I bring
Speaker 2:  it up is, okay now there's a new engineering culture inside of Twitter.
Speaker 2:  It is oriented around one person and his dreams. Is there any tangible
Speaker 2:  progress towards this big vision that bubbles out
Speaker 2:  every now and again? X
Speaker 13:  I mean it seems like he's actively making moves against it.
Speaker 13:  Like if you're gonna make the Everything app, you need an open API where
Speaker 13:  people are building apps on Twitter. For Twitter, they've
Speaker 13:  closed that up, they're gonna make developers pay for it. So I'm not like
Speaker 13:  totally sure how that even happens. Are they expecting to build every component
Speaker 13:  of it? It in-house with a staff of less than 500 engineers?
Speaker 13:  Maybe. But it seems more like just one of those things that he
Speaker 13:  talks about perpetually. You know, we know payments is moving forward. Like
Speaker 13:  Esther Crawford is still running that team and that seems like a big initiative
Speaker 13:  that he's interested in. But on everything app, like I don't see it.
Speaker 2:  And then Esther Crawford is also very much in charge of Twitter Blue.
Speaker 2:  That seems it's still there. It's still I every day I wait for
Speaker 2:  my check mark to
Speaker 5:  Go away. Same. Richard, yours is gonna go first.
Speaker 2:  Richard is definitely going first. It does not seem like Blue is a success.
Speaker 2:  It does also doesn't seem like the company is in dire financial trouble.
Speaker 2:  It's like the advertisers are gone and people aren't signing for blue. Like
Speaker 2:  h how are the finances the company staying afloat?
Speaker 13:  I mean so far it's just cuz they've cut costs so drastically that
Speaker 13:  like some of this is I guess netting out for the moment. But obviously
Speaker 13:  stuff still needs to change. I think they are gonna try and make Twitter
Speaker 13:  blue more attractive so that more people subscribe. Whether enough people
Speaker 13:  will subscribe to compensate for the number of advertisers who've fled and
Speaker 13:  not come back. Like, I don't think that math works out right now, but we'll
Speaker 13:  see.
Speaker 2:  All right. Well I am still trying to not use it. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I open it once a day. See all of Elon's tweets, all the tweets
Speaker 2:  that you don't see. Richard. I definitely see, they double show them to me,
Speaker 2:  which is a delight.
Speaker 5:  I don't go in that tap anymore. The one that's like for you
Speaker 5:  instead of the following tab.
Speaker 7:  That was the interesting thing to me. I, I didn't know so many people used
Speaker 7:  it. I, I only used following.
Speaker 5:  I kept complaining about it because I didn't realize following was there
Speaker 5:  and all these people were like, you dumbass following is there. And I was
Speaker 5:  like,
Speaker 2:  Oh. So my, my following tab has gotten a lot quieter cuz all the people I
Speaker 2:  know stop using Twitter. Oh, so the four, the four you is where the action
Speaker 2:  is. Does
Speaker 5:  You need Richard over there and Elon.
Speaker 2:  Elon?
Speaker 13:  Are you just doing quick posts or are you on master on like, what's, what's
Speaker 13:  your replacement right
Speaker 2:  Now? I am trying to not have feed-based social media in my life for a minute.
Speaker 2:  Love this. I was addicted to it for 10 years.
Speaker 5:  So good. It
Speaker 2:  Is challenging. I watch a lot of weird
Speaker 2:  hustle, bro. TikTok now, if anyone wants to make quick money at chat,
Speaker 2:  g p t Boy are the ideas in my brain
Speaker 2:  just infected. But I, I spent so long like
Speaker 2:  tweeting and knowing what minor Twitter war
Speaker 2:  was happening and now I don't and I feel it at peace. Yeah. So I've not yet
Speaker 2:  signed up from, and I eventually will have to, I think
Speaker 5:  It feels like it's coming. Yeah. I feel like I need to be on Mastodon, but
Speaker 5:  then I
Speaker 2:  Don't So are you on Mastodon?
Speaker 13:  No. Okay. So I tried, I did the, the tweet where I was like, it's really
Speaker 13:  happening. Here's my handle. Follow me everyone. And every
Speaker 13:  time I've tried to do what me and Casey agreed, which is we're gonna post
Speaker 13:  News First and Discord and then on Mastodon and then on Twitter. Mastodon
Speaker 13:  automatically will shut off as I'm writing the tweet. This has happened
Speaker 13:  at least 10 times. And then I just said no. I'm like, I
Speaker 13:  can't, I, I want you but not bad enough to do this. So now I just do
Speaker 13:  discordant Twitter and I'm like, I give it up, it crashes. It's crazy.
Speaker 2:  I feel like someone is gonna come out with like the server.
Speaker 5:  It's Tumblr. I'm telling
Speaker 2:  You it's Tumblr.
Speaker 5:  It's like, like Tumblr and I think another very small social media
Speaker 5:  site that only the Vergecast talks about is planning to like adopt
Speaker 5:  that, that the API or whatever that Masta Ong uses
Speaker 2:  AVS Forum. What small media site are you talking about?
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'll remember at some point I'll, I'll tweet it. Everybody just followed
Speaker 5:  me on Twitter. I'll tweet it. You'll know. I don't
Speaker 2:  Remember who it is. This is so mysterious.
Speaker 5:  It is mysterious. But Tumblr is definitely doing it and there's rumors of
Speaker 5:  another social media platform doing it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I know Tumblr's doing it because Matt Maga the CEO of
Speaker 2:  WordPress and Tumblr automatic, they're building it into
Speaker 2:  WordPress. Yeah. And they're moving Tumblr onto whatever WordPress
Speaker 5:  Uses. And that's just like a smart move. I feel like across the board
Speaker 2:  It would be amazing if all the people move from Twitter to Tumblr. I mean,
Speaker 2:  being emo has been like a real theme of this first, cuz we talked about Bing
Speaker 2:  for a long time today. It would be amazing if everyone just like got
Speaker 2:  much more emotional on Tumblr. Get
Speaker 5:  Your, your music lyrics ready
Speaker 2:  At some point I'll break because I mist tweeting during events. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like that's like the main, that's the only thing that I truly miss.
Speaker 2:  The like constant low stakes bonfire of Twitter warfare is like not
Speaker 2:  whatever. How
Speaker 5:  Is the balloon discourse hit you then? Like if you're not,
Speaker 5:  oh,
Speaker 2:  Because the New York Times is like, fuck it. Have you seen the balloon balloon
Speaker 2:  balloon? Another balloon alert the balloon's due in numbers. Tell people
Speaker 2:  about the balloon. Like the control.
Speaker 5:  You're still there. You're still getting
Speaker 2:  There. It's like no one can escape the balloons if you are a subscriber to
Speaker 2:  the New York Times. It's like outta control. Zoe, do you think there's like
Speaker 2:  a, a next thing for Twitter? Is it just chaos and we should just expect more
Speaker 2:  chaos every day?
Speaker 13:  I think the chaos will continue for a while now. I mean,
Speaker 13:  it's Elon like he says he'll maybe step down by the end of the year. So
Speaker 13:  we've got many more months of turmoil, I would say. But
Speaker 13:  yeah, I mean I think there's gonna be more weird stuff happening in the
Speaker 13:  coming weeks that I'm expecting to write about and then hopefully the news
Speaker 13:  cycle dies down and we can pay attention to something else.
Speaker 2:  I love it. Well Zoe, is it Platformer? Platformer News? You can
Speaker 2:  subscribe. Our friend Casey's there as well. We syndicate platformer super
Speaker 2:  good. So I feel like I should tell the people where they can find you on
Speaker 2:  Twitter. It's like, not what I want to do. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Find your own Mastodon.
Speaker 13:  No, please don't. Please don't. Instead I checked it.
Speaker 13:  I regret that tweet. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Look, that's why I didn't do it. Yeah, right. Like ev there was that week
Speaker 2:  where I was like, I'm leaving. Here's all the places you can find me. And
Speaker 2:  it's like, motherfucker, I don't want you to find my Instagram.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like don't, this isn't who I am.
Speaker 5:  You don't need that. You don't need to see the food I ate last week
Speaker 2:  At the end. I think he did me a favor. I think my, my, my heart in my head
Speaker 2:  have healed.
Speaker 5:  I've got a, I've got actually a bet about Elon right now with both Liz Lato
Speaker 5:  and Monica Chen. What's
Speaker 2:  That bet?
Speaker 5:  Whether or not he's gonna post horrible pictures that we are all gonna
Speaker 5:  have to see because he controls the algorithm right now.
Speaker 13:  What do you mean horrible pictures?
Speaker 2:  I mean, there's already the milk
Speaker 5:  One. Yeah, the milk one, like 10 times worse than milk. I feel like it's
Speaker 5:  coming.
Speaker 2:  It's a porn tweets.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I feel like we're gonna get a dick pick at some point. I don't know
Speaker 5:  who's Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry I'm, but we gotta, I think
Speaker 2:  It's gonna happen. It's been great here. Love having you. We gotta
Speaker 2:  so
Speaker 2:  well, you're right back with our lightning round.
Speaker 14:  Hey there. I'm Josh Muo, host of the Pitch. A show where
Speaker 14:  real entrepreneurs pitch real tech investors for real money.
Speaker 14:  And this season gets a little saucy.
Speaker 15:  We knew that we were not going to join the same old
Speaker 15:  sauce game. We were gonna disrupt 130 billion
Speaker 15:  industry. We're coming after
Speaker 14:  Hines. We meet founders pitching everything from a better ketchup
Speaker 14:  to a solution for one of the biggest problems today,
Speaker 14:  energy
Speaker 16:  In the future, the vehicles and garage. It's gonna be like a giant
Speaker 16:  power plant that could be used to reinforce the power grid,
Speaker 16:  substitute fossil fuel power plants, and allow more renewable energy on
Speaker 16:  the network.
Speaker 14:  This season, 14 founders with 12 ideas
Speaker 14:  big enough to change the world. If the investors invest.
Speaker 14:  I would like to invest in this round. $300,000 new episodes every
Speaker 14:  Wednesday. See you in the pitch room.
Speaker 2:  We're back. Yeah. Lightning round. This one I think merits more
Speaker 2:  than a lightning round just because of the headline that it is. But
Speaker 2:  then it does not YouTube CEO Susan Majeski stepping down after nine
Speaker 2:  years. C o of YouTube.
Speaker 5:  What a lap do, a victory lap. Susan,
Speaker 2:  She is like a major force in this world. Yes. She took YouTube, which
Speaker 2:  was like not a great business. She's one of the earliest Google employees.
Speaker 2:  She took YouTube, which is not a great business, and turned it into this
Speaker 2:  absolute powerhouse,
Speaker 5:  Absolute Goliath.
Speaker 2:  It is the, it remains, I think the gold standard for every creator.
Speaker 2:  There's lots of creators on Twitter and other places today saying, you know,
Speaker 2:  we have our complaints about YouTube and boy do they have their complaints
Speaker 2:  about YouTube, but it is the platform that treats us the best. Right. I think
Speaker 2:  Mark has had a tweet that's like, just look at compare. Like YouTube has
Speaker 2:  creator plaques and events and monetization schedules and reps.
Speaker 2:  And then he goes like, Instagram, nothing TikTok, nothing Twitter,
Speaker 2:  nothing like, so YouTube is a powerhouse. So kind of
Speaker 2:  amazing. She's stepping down. There's a little bit of color. Mark Bergen,
Speaker 2:  who's a great reporter like Bloomberg, has been tweeting a little bit of
Speaker 2:  color. She's dipped in the past few months. No one's really seen
Speaker 2:  her. Yeah. No one's really understood this transition.
Speaker 5:  Oh, that's not great.
Speaker 2:  But it has been nine years and she's been replaced by her own handpicked
Speaker 2:  deputy Neil Mohan, who is the chief product officer of YouTube. But now
Speaker 2:  importantly, not becoming the CEO of YouTube, he's becoming the
Speaker 2:  senior vice president of YouTube reporting atcha.
Speaker 5:  Oh, interesting. So that's, that's an org chart.
Speaker 2:  You know how I'm
Speaker 5:  Wizard I was about to say this. Like, this like peaked you. Huh? You were
Speaker 5:  like, oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah, there's, there's obviously some drama here. Yeah. It's not a lot of
Speaker 2:  drama because I know Neil, Neil has been on decoder many times. I just
Speaker 2:  actually just talked to Neil after they did the Sunday ticket deal for YouTube
Speaker 2:  tv. He was very happy he, he won. I don't
Speaker 2:  think you're gonna see a lot of change between Susan and Neil. Like they
Speaker 2:  were pretty lockstep. YouTube actually really interesting or chart thing.
Speaker 2:  Neil head of product YouTube's content moderation and trust and
Speaker 2:  safety reports to him is the head of product weird
Speaker 2:  because they've built it as a product. They think it's a product cap. This
Speaker 2:  is my whole thing about content moderation is the product. It's a built into
Speaker 2:  YouTube. It is a product. Okay. It doesn't report to like legal or Mark
Speaker 2:  Zuckerberg or whatever. It's Right.
Speaker 5:  Just mark for some reason, just that part of YouTube
Speaker 5:  Mark handles?
Speaker 2:  No, it's just like at Facebook. Yeah. Like at the end of the day, like Mark
Speaker 2:  made a bunch of decisions, right?
Speaker 5:  Like everything goes up to Mark.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. This one was like it's product. And Susan made a bunch of those decisions
Speaker 2:  too. But it's, it's always just like one of the more unique parts of YouTube
Speaker 2:  structure. And now he's in charge. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Do you think he, he didn't get the title because like she was an early
Speaker 5:  employee of Google. She put a lot of time and energy into Google for years.
Speaker 5:  It made sense to make her ceo and now the structures, everything's changed.
Speaker 5:  It makes sense to just have that person report directly to Sundar and like,
Speaker 5:  that's it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I don't know. I mean, again, my, I love an hard shark
Speaker 2:  conversation. Yeah. She was the CEO of YouTube. Okay. Before Sundar Pacha
Speaker 2:  became CEO of Google. Right? So there's Larry and Sergei, they start Google
Speaker 2:  in her garage. She's early, early, early.
Speaker 2:  She becomes a CEO of YouTube. And then they're like, we're, Larry Page is
Speaker 2:  like, we're dipping, screw this. We're just gonna do flying car
Speaker 2:  startups or whatever it is. They do. Sun is the CEO of
Speaker 2:  Google. So she predated Sundar as the CEO
Speaker 2:  of YouTube before he became the CEO of Google. And then he became the CEO
Speaker 2:  of Alphabet.
Speaker 5:  And so she reported to him when he became CEO of
Speaker 2:  Alphabet? No, C of Google. Okay. So YouTube is a weird thing. It's part
Speaker 2:  of Google, which is part of Alphabet, but it's still part of Google, but
Speaker 5:  It's still
Speaker 2:  YouTube, but it's it, but it's its own little island. Okay. It's very confusing,
Speaker 2:  super confusing. So now Neil is in charge again. You can go listen to
Speaker 2:  many decoder episodes with, with Neil Moen. He's smart. He's got
Speaker 2:  a lot of ideas he will not answer when YouTube TV will be in 4k.
Speaker 2:  Just very good. Please
Speaker 5:  Answer.
Speaker 2:  Sometimes I hit the, the brick wall of someone's media training on
Speaker 2:  decoder. Yeah. And that's the wall
Speaker 2:  straight up. I found it. There it is. And I bounced right off it. And try,
Speaker 2:  try
Speaker 5:  Again. Anyone? You ask. What about YouTube, TV and 4k? They're like, no.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The just the shades come down. It's
Speaker 5:  All decide. Yeah. He's like, I, I don't have an answer, but no.
Speaker 2:  When we talked about when they, the Sunny Ticket deal, I was like, all right,
Speaker 2:  you gonna do football in 4k? Like you had to know this conversation. You
Speaker 2:  volunteered to talk to me. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It has to. He
Speaker 2:  Had to, what do I talk about? And he was like, I can't ask that question.
Speaker 5:  So he was prepped to say that
Speaker 2:  One time, this is trip one time I just sent him an email watching the NBA
Speaker 2:  Final just sponsored by, by YouTube tv. And I was like, why don't you just
Speaker 2:  pay to do this in 4K and have it exclusive? And he was just like, yeah, it's
Speaker 2:  a good idea.
Speaker 5:  Left you
Speaker 2:  On Lead. Goodbye absolute professor. You have been a bad Bing.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, I'm hoping to talk to Neil soon about his plans. I, I said, I
Speaker 2:  suspect things will be, let's say these are two people who worked in lockstep
Speaker 2:  for many, many years. Whatever Neil's plans were were
Speaker 2:  Susan's plans for a long time. But it is fascinating that if this,
Speaker 2:  I think for Google, the threats are all over
Speaker 2:  the place, right? There's the, whatever you think of the Bing
Speaker 2:  threat, it is a real threat. It wiped a hundred billion dollars off its market
Speaker 2:  cap last week. The idea that search will change,
Speaker 2:  not just because people might switch to Ping cuz they wanna bang the
Speaker 2:  robot, but
Speaker 5:  TikTok
Speaker 2:  And, but they're spending their time on TikTok. They're using search there.
Speaker 2:  And then what Chat G p T has really done is the cost
Speaker 2:  to generate an infinite amount of mediocre text is now zero.
Speaker 2:  So Google's being flooded with garbage. Right. And
Speaker 2:  they've gotta sort that out too. And so like that's a big problem for Google.
Speaker 2:  And then next, and then YouTube is fine. It's still a gold standard for
Speaker 2:  creators, but it has to fend off TikTok. It has to create new
Speaker 2:  monetization models for creators. It has to, it, the
Speaker 2:  most exciting part of YouTube is it's cable network.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's
Speaker 2:  Weird, right? Weird table system like YouTube tv. That's weird.
Speaker 7:  It's an interesting timing for her to, to make this move. I think not only
Speaker 7:  because of the length of time that she's been with YouTube, with Google and
Speaker 7:  it has been doing all these things, these No. And now they're facing these
Speaker 7:  problems. I find it interesting and, and I don't think
Speaker 7:  that these things are directly related because it, it sound, it feels like
Speaker 7:  this is something that has been in the works for at least a little while.
Speaker 7:  And as you said, does she and Neil are kind of on the same page of terms
Speaker 7:  of what they're doing. But it's interesting that she's leaving as Sergey
Speaker 7:  and Larry are suddenly seemingly retaking active roles in the company.
Speaker 7:  And she's probably the person there who has known them the longest,
Speaker 7:  or I mean certainly the person there who has known them the longest. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And now that they're back, suddenly she's out the door.
Speaker 2:  It's unclear how much they're back. So there was the report that Google
Speaker 2:  had called the Code Red about chatbots and all this stuff. And then
Speaker 2:  I, I think Alex Heath reported in Command Line, they were back because Google
Speaker 2:  has never had layoffs before. So if they were gonna be layoffs, they wanted
Speaker 2:  to be in the building part of that process. It's a big shock
Speaker 2:  to Google's culture. There was a blog post this week
Speaker 2:  from an ex Googler link at the show notes pretty
Speaker 2:  devastating take down of Google's culture overall, right. And how it's is
Speaker 2:  basically a culture that avoids risks and is buoyed
Speaker 2:  by the ad printing, the ad money printing machine of Google
Speaker 2:  search. And now the company needs to invent new things
Speaker 2:  and chart new paths and be what people think Google
Speaker 2:  is and they're struggling to do it.
Speaker 5:  I thought that was interesting cuz Tony Fidel his book last year, what was
Speaker 5:  it called? Build I think. Yeah. There's a big chunk of that book where he's
Speaker 5:  like, I got got Nest. And then I go over to Google and it's gonna be great
Speaker 5:  and then everything falls
Speaker 2:  Apart. Yeah. I don't know anybody who's matter at Google than Tony
Speaker 5:  Fidel. And it was like a really, like, it felt like kind of
Speaker 5:  foreshadowing for what we're starting to see this year where he was like,
Speaker 5:  I saw all of this dysfunction. It was constant. It's always the loudest person
Speaker 5:  in the room wins. It's always but only very specific
Speaker 5:  loud people. Nobody is ever talking to each other, especially in ways they
Speaker 5:  need to. And so like all of that dysfunction it feels like is starting to
Speaker 5:  come to a head. And it makes sense for Susan to be like, you know
Speaker 5:  what? I got my bag. I'm gonna retire. I'm gonna go do my own thing. I love
Speaker 5:  that for her. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like I said, incredible run. YouTube is the platform. It is
Speaker 2:  many reasons to criticize YouTube on any day. Some
Speaker 2:  YouTuber is getting their wings and making the video where they complain
Speaker 2:  about YouTube. Yes. And that is the beginning of the true, that's like
Speaker 2:  when you become a YouTuber is when you make the video complaining about being
Speaker 2:  demonetized or some other, or the algorithm banning or whatever it is.
Speaker 5:  I can't wait to do that for the
Speaker 2:  Ver that's when you know, you're a professional YouTube. And I'm like, I've
Speaker 2:  said this to Neil. I'm like, this is a thing. He's like, yeah, it's weird,
Speaker 2:  huh? Like they know that this is part of the cycle with YouTube. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  they, they, they have this competition with TikTok. They have to fend off.
Speaker 2:  So we'll see. I I, I make, I'm gonna ask to have Neil come back on one of
Speaker 2:  our shows and talk about his plan soon, but I think it's,
Speaker 2:  it's worth noting that right now YouTube is the
Speaker 2:  strongest business I think at Google in terms of just what it represents
Speaker 2:  to people and how important it is to people. But it is still under threat.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But I mean, to be clear it's under threat. But like TikTok
Speaker 5:  still has a smaller Yeah. Piece of the pie than YouTube. Like YouTube is
Speaker 5:  still big, it's still huge. TikTok is coming, but talk's
Speaker 5:  got a ways to go to like Surpass.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And TikTok does not have, well we don't know. TikTok is a black
Speaker 2:  box. Right? It's owned by Bite. Dance by dance is not publicly.
Speaker 5:  Who knows what's gonna happen with it.
Speaker 2:  But we think that TikTok does not have the sort of
Speaker 2:  revenue engine that YouTube has. Right? Like YouTube
Speaker 2:  makes a lot of money, it shares a lot of money with creators. It is building
Speaker 2:  this new creator fund for shorts. It's, it's doing all the stuff that TikTok
Speaker 2:  has not yet done. Yeah. So YouTube is like a complete business that makes
Speaker 2:  a lot of money. Which again, this is credit to Susan
Speaker 2:  Wosk, right? It did not make money for a long time.
Speaker 2:  Like yeah, mark Bergen has a great book about the history of YouTube.
Speaker 2:  Mark was on decoder, you can go listen to that episode. But like YouTube
Speaker 2:  was so bad for a while that Google was like, we're gonna shut it down. Like
Speaker 2:  this doesn't make any sense. The cost of hosting distributing video are high
Speaker 2:  earth and the whatever we might ever return on it. Right. And then it
Speaker 2:  clicked for them. And the YouTube has gone through many arrows, but it, they're
Speaker 2:  like, watch time is the thing we're gonna incentivize like 10
Speaker 2:  minute videos, like three pre-roll breaks or whatever it is. And that's when
Speaker 2:  the Charlie bit my fingers of YouTube, like people stop making those
Speaker 2:  videos. They start making these really long YouTube, like a YouTube video.
Speaker 5:  Right. And then Charlie bit, my, my finger would now be absolute banger
Speaker 5:  on TikTok. Exactly. Oh my god. The remixes for TikTok would be so good.
Speaker 2:  The stitches of other people biting other fingers. Oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So great. So there's just like a, there's a lot there. But she
Speaker 2:  shepherded that entire creator platform into existence and in
Speaker 2:  doing so, like created a new class of
Speaker 2:  internet personality, a new style of video.
Speaker 2:  Like there's just a lot here that Susan oversaw, which I think is worthwhile.
Speaker 2:  There's a lot of criticism too. Like she did not handle a bunch of harassment
Speaker 2:  stuff well across the platform. Her
Speaker 2:  moderation decisions. I think anybody would tell you very deliberate,
Speaker 2:  very slow.
Speaker 5:  There were a lot of times you would groan when you'd see like, she'd be like,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna speak out about harassment on YouTube. And you'd be like, oh no.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. This is like the most interesting criticism because
Speaker 2:  I think from her perspective, this is not a criticism, but from any normal
Speaker 2:  person's perspective, this is like what he doing. Google's like a totally
Speaker 2:  data oriented company. So the users of YouTube would
Speaker 2:  see something happening on YouTube. YouTubers would see
Speaker 2:  something happening good or bad on YouTube. But until there was
Speaker 2:  data, YouTube couldn't see it. Yeah. Susan couldn't see it.
Speaker 2:  So the YouTubers like screaming their heads off about something good or
Speaker 2:  bad happening and like there'd be this massive lag
Speaker 2:  before they could see what was happening on their own platform. Cuz they're,
Speaker 2:  they're just like, they had to figure out how to quantify whatever it was,
Speaker 2:  harassment, people dancing, whatever it is. And then they would see it
Speaker 2:  and then they would react to it and it would like be over or the stakes would
Speaker 2:  be lower or some bad thing had already happened. And like, this
Speaker 2:  is like, I think a constant kind of dynamic inside of YouTube
Speaker 2:  where because Google's just so data driven, they, they can't see what is
Speaker 2:  happening on their own platform in real time. The, my my favorite example
Speaker 2:  of this, like this is one of those moments where I keep listening to
Speaker 2:  executive, you're like, what planet do you live on? I think it was at the
Speaker 2:  code conference. She's like, well obviously you know, YouTube is like mostly
Speaker 2:  a music service. Okay. All of us are like, Walter keeps talking
Speaker 2:  and like the data inside of YouTube is people
Speaker 2:  just put music on in the background. They watch music videos, like
Speaker 2:  do all the stuff.
Speaker 5:  It's not the lofi streaming.
Speaker 2:  Right. So if you are just looking at YouTube from this like aggregate data
Speaker 2:  perspective, you're like, people come to us to listen to music. But if you
Speaker 2:  talk to a normal person, that is absolutely not what they're doing.
Speaker 2:  Right. And there's just, there's a gap there. And I like, like I said, is
Speaker 2:  that a criticism of Susan's regime? Is it her being smart and saying here's
Speaker 2:  what's actually happening. I think cuts both ways. Yeah. But wherever she
Speaker 2:  got in trouble, you, that's kind of that little dynamic is always at the
Speaker 2:  root of
Speaker 5:  It. Yeah. And then TikTok is smart cuz it just doesn't say anything at all.
Speaker 5:  Ever.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Always quiet.
Speaker 7:  It's that connection to the individual that that seems to have always
Speaker 7:  lacked at YouTube. Whether it's like something that we talked about in a
Speaker 7:  previous episode of Kyrie Irving going down a YouTube rabbit hole and
Speaker 7:  getting convinced of very strange things or other, other even more, more
Speaker 7:  devastating events. We we, there was the time where the one woman who who
Speaker 7:  posted videos came and, and fired shots at the campus because she was so
Speaker 7:  angry about what she felt like the algorithm was doing. And YouTube just
Speaker 7:  kind of doesn't see that effect that it, that it has on people.
Speaker 2:  I think after that they really started seeing that effect on people. I think
Speaker 2:  that if that happened to any workplace, it would change the dynamic of the
Speaker 2:  workplace. And that absolutely changed the dynamic of that
Speaker 7:  Workplace. There. There was a notable difference and, and I think the thing
Speaker 7:  that, that jumps out to me, just something, every time there's an executive
Speaker 7:  leaving, I'm wondering who is the next ex executive who is going to leave?
Speaker 7:  We've seen Reed Hastings step down and now Susan, Susan
Speaker 7:  is stepping down. What? Within a month. So
Speaker 5:  Are you saying they come in threes, they
Speaker 7:  Come in like fives,
Speaker 5:  It's them.
Speaker 2:  No, someone go ask Bing for a spooky ghost story about the rule
Speaker 2:  of threes and CEO
Speaker 7:  Stepping down Daniel Eck. That's my, that's my guess.
Speaker 2:  That's who you think he just did a big reorg. He got rid of the person who
Speaker 2:  did our big podcast push. I don't know. We'll see. That's, that's
Speaker 2:  Richard's. I have no prediction. I no, I don't know what's going on. I just
Speaker 2:  know that it's org chart season baby. I'd just like to say and that's my
Speaker 2:  time to shine Tim Cook. No way.
Speaker 2:  A little bit more lightning round stuff. iOS 16.4 beta hit.
Speaker 2:  I'm only bringing this up because there's now a new hook that lets web
Speaker 2:  apps send push notifications.
Speaker 5:  Oh boy.
Speaker 2:  Amazing. This is fully an EU compliance move. Like this is
Speaker 2:  so Apple can go to European regulators and see the web is just as
Speaker 2:  good as our native app platform. They can even send push notifications.
Speaker 5:  Oh I love that.
Speaker 2:  I promise you that's what's going on here. Our S 23 ultra review went up
Speaker 2:  Sweater alert. Allison loved it. It's it's a great phone. Showed
Speaker 2:  she was like the most interesting thing to do with the 200 megapixel camera.
Speaker 2:  Not take 200 megapixel photos. Which is a great line but go watch it. Really
Speaker 2:  cool.
Speaker 5:  She's been having a lo lovely time with the Zoom. She's super, super
Speaker 5:  enamored with
Speaker 2:  It. Yeah, she gave it a nine razor blade. 18 review is up.
Speaker 2:  Monica get add an
Speaker 5:  Eight. Did you know how much the razor blade 18 costs? How
Speaker 2:  Much does it cost?
Speaker 5:  So much money. Hold on. I just closed it.
Speaker 2:  $3,800. I got it. Okay.
Speaker 5:  It costs $3,800. Yeah that's, that's a lot of buddy
Speaker 5:  for that
Speaker 2:  Reason. But look at all the, all the
Speaker 5:  Lights. It's, yeah it's got lights, it's got a nice screen. She didn't hate
Speaker 5:  it for that price.
Speaker 2:  And then I, I wanna end on just like a little bit. Three pieces of car
Speaker 2:  news. Little news, little news. Tesla we're called like
Speaker 2:  362,000 vehicles because full self driving
Speaker 2:  beta has a crash risk. They're not the Tesla people are
Speaker 2:  gonna come for me. It's not a recall. They're gonna ship in over the air
Speaker 2:  update. Yeah. But like the government was like yo this is bad.
Speaker 2:  And Tesla's like we agree. We will push the button marked recall on the
Speaker 2:  dashboard. Yeah. And tell everyone that they shouldn't use this until they
Speaker 2:  update their
Speaker 5:  Software. Do they have to like get to wifi to do it?
Speaker 2:  A lot of Teslas have some modems.
Speaker 5:  They have. Okay. I've never, I don't have a Tesla. I don't know how they
Speaker 5:  work.
Speaker 2:  What are you doing?
Speaker 5:  I'm driving my little Mazda.
Speaker 2:  Well does your Mazda have more than 90 miles of electric range?
Speaker 2:  Because we reviewed the Mazda NX 30 this week. The world's
Speaker 2:  shittiest car.
Speaker 5:  I was so sad about that too. That was such a, I'm like
Speaker 5:  rooting for Mazda cuz I love my CX five. Yes.
Speaker 7:  It's such a sad life for the rotary engine. Like, like this is how the rotary
Speaker 7:  is back.
Speaker 2:  So we read the MX 30. I just wanna bring this up. We're in the midst of what
Speaker 2:  we think is an EV transition. Yeah. We could go either way
Speaker 2:  honestly at this
Speaker 5:  Point. Not with Mazda making the
Speaker 2:  Carts not right. That's what I mean. Like
Speaker 5:  We know which way it's going. If Mazda's
Speaker 2:  In charge, it's like you just like bring your gas tank to the Mazda dealership.
Speaker 2:  So the MX 30 s out, it's a little compact SUV and there's just
Speaker 2:  like a lot of debate over how much range you really need in a car. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And like most Americans are like 700 miles in a shotgun. Like whatever,
Speaker 2:  whatever Americans think the number most manufacturers are settling on is
Speaker 2:  like 300 and some are lower. Like there's a lot of 270 mile EVs
Speaker 2:  floating
Speaker 5:  Around. That's because those car designers are on the east coast. Yeah. Like
Speaker 5:  you get to that middle part of the country and you're like no I need a thousand
Speaker 5:  miles.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. In a shotgun. Like can I get the rack on the back
Speaker 2:  outbound gas tanks on my F three 50 but whatever. So
Speaker 2:  two 70 is like ah it's a little weird. Yeah. You know and then you've got
Speaker 2:  kind of the new battery chemistries and like the lucid stuff that are way
Speaker 2:  higher. Mazda's like 92, straight up
Speaker 2:  92 miles range in this $20,000 car
Speaker 2:  and the interior surface is made of cork. Oh. Which
Speaker 2:  easily stains. And they're like yes we know but
Speaker 2:  we're, we're honoring our heritage as a cork manufacturer.
Speaker 2:  This is a real thing. They said
Speaker 5:  The patina, you love that pat, that cork patina.
Speaker 2:  I shit I've never been more like I understand the
Speaker 2:  cyber truck. Yeah. And it's wiper situation much
Speaker 2:  more than Mazda fully shipping an EV with 92 miles a range.
Speaker 2:  And
Speaker 5:  Like their hybrids are pretty nice. Yeah. People Is it the, the hybrid
Speaker 5:  CX 50
Speaker 2:  People like Mazdas. I'm just saying this car
Speaker 5:  Sucks. This car, ah Mazda do better.
Speaker 2:  The cork thing just got me were the, the answers but we have to honor our
Speaker 2:  heritages whatever.
Speaker 5:  Was it like, was it a cork? Is that how they started?
Speaker 2:  Well that's what they said.
Speaker 5:  I don't believe them.
Speaker 2:  I don't know man. They're only selling in California and if you ever been
Speaker 2:  in California you know that this is the least California compatible vehicle
Speaker 2:  in the entire
Speaker 5:  World. It began as Toyo Cork. See Koo Company
Speaker 5:  Limited.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And after all this time they hadn't figured out how to make the cork
Speaker 2:  stain resistant Alex
Speaker 5:  Because cause they, they pivoted the cars.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So that's the Mazda. And then lastly the most hilarious car
Speaker 2:  update of them all. Hyundai and Kia have been forced to
Speaker 2:  update software on millions of their cars because a group of
Speaker 2:  TikTok ERs called the Kia Boys have done the Kia
Speaker 2:  Challenge where they teach people how to steal the cars
Speaker 2:  because they don't have lockouts on the ignition system. The
Speaker 2:  key, the boys by the way spelled it the
Speaker 5:  Z. Oh yeah. I mean you can't spell it any other way when you're called the
Speaker 5:  Kia boys, you're not
Speaker 2:  Allowed many 2015 to 2019 Hyundai and Kia vehicles lack electronic. Im
Speaker 2:  mobilizers to prevent these from simply breaking in and bypassing the igni
Speaker 2:  ignition. The Kia boys obviously
Speaker 2:  discovered this as the Kia boys are want to do. They're
Speaker 2:  stealing the cars. Here is how they're fixing it. They are updating the theft
Speaker 2:  alarm software logic to extend the length of the
Speaker 2:  alarm sound from 30 seconds to one minute.
Speaker 5:  That'll that, that that's gonna
Speaker 2:  Do. I dunno if you've ever tried to deter the Kia Boys, but if you go
Speaker 2:  over 30 seconds of alarm sounds they run,
Speaker 5:  Do they not just have some bows they can put on like some gear
Speaker 5:  plugs? I think it'll
Speaker 2:  Be fine. And if you have a Hyundai or a Kia that has a standard turn
Speaker 2:  the key to start, then they will lock
Speaker 5:  That up. So should you just get like a club instead? Was that the old one?
Speaker 5:  The the red bar Put on your, your steering wheel. That's what you need to
Speaker 5:  get in
Speaker 2:  Kia Boys. They've got a club. Let's get outta here. I mean
Speaker 2:  easily the best. There's like certain, we've run a couple of headlines this
Speaker 2:  week where I'm like this is what the Verge was designed for. Yeah. Bing
Speaker 2:  is an emotionally manipulative liar that people love. I was like, I'd said
Speaker 2:  to James, I am pretty sure like we, we were
Speaker 2:  made for this headline.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. A hundred percent.
Speaker 2:  Like this is why we exist. And the second one is the Kia
Speaker 2:  boys have forced Kia to issue a recall
Speaker 2:  because they're on TikTok teaching people how to sell cars.
Speaker 2:  The we were, we were destined. Yeah. In 2011
Speaker 2:  we're like we should all quit our jobs and start the verge in the back of
Speaker 2:  my mind just
Speaker 5:  Kia boys. The
Speaker 2:  Kia boys
Speaker 5:  Revving their engines.
Speaker 2:  It's like a viral TikTok challenge. We'll teach
Speaker 2:  people how to steal cars and a major car
Speaker 2:  manufacturer will have to deal with it. That's what we meant by technology
Speaker 2:  and culture. This is the cyberpunk future we were promised. And also the
Speaker 2:  cyberpunk future we were promised was like a very emotional robot will be
Speaker 2:  like, you're a bad bing.
Speaker 5:  I mean Yeah, that's true
Speaker 2:  Though. No, I'm a good bing. All right. I think you're all great Bings,
Speaker 2:  just for the record, you're all good chatbots and I love you all very much.
Speaker 2:  Please do not smooch your laptops.
Speaker 5:  Please don't. You don't know where it's been.
Speaker 2:  That would be a problem. Alright. Fear not the Kia boys
Speaker 2:  go off in the good night. There's other stuff. Read Liz this week on
Speaker 2:  like the, how the interest rate environment is like radically changing the
Speaker 2:  tech industry. It's classic Liz Le Patto. It's very good. Wednesday
Speaker 2:  you guys are gonna talk about the PSVR review with Addie Sean Hollister.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Very exciting. So Sean and Addie are gonna come on. We're gonna talk
Speaker 5:  about the psvr. I've got Jen and Chris person are gonna
Speaker 5:  talk about multi room audio because Chris is super into not doing
Speaker 5:  the typical stuff. Ooh. He's got a whole hacked out system that he loves.
Speaker 5:  And then we're gonna be talking with Ariel about podcast misinformation
Speaker 5:  and by we, I mean she's gonna be talking to some great people about podcast
Speaker 5:  misinformation and I'm gonna be listening attentively.
Speaker 2:  Very good. Dakota. This week I talked to the chair of the
Speaker 2:  Mozilla Foundation, also the CEO of Mozilla whole org chart situation in
Speaker 2:  there. Here's something, she told me, people more likely to switch browsers
Speaker 2:  on their phones than on their laptops. I believe it. People are
Speaker 2:  used to downloading apps on their phones and just that little bit of behavioral
Speaker 2:  conditioning means that it's possible. I love it. So listen to that
Speaker 2:  decoder is just like lit up the next couple weeks. Yeah, just check it out.
Speaker 2:  Very good. Liam hates it when I say it, but he's busy switching the video
Speaker 2:  so he can't coming off. All right. That's it. Thanks to our guests. Thanks
Speaker 2:  to Zoe. She's at Zoe's Schiffer on Twitter. James is at JJ
Speaker 2:  Vincent. Addie is at the Dex. I'm at Reckless. Alex is
Speaker 2:  Alex h Cranz. Richard as always is at RJ cc. God only knows his
Speaker 2:  Twitter is up.
Speaker 1:  He's the
Speaker 2:  First to be banned. Someone boost me by a thousand. That's it.
Speaker 2:  Rock and roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 1:  us an email@vergecasttheverge.com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of the Verge and the Box Media Podcast network. The show is produced
Speaker 1:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 1:  Our editorial director is Brooke Min. That's it. We'll see you next
Speaker 1:  week.