# Transcript
ID: 43839080-9e63-11ed-be7a-736800e8a3eb
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Apple M2 reviews, DOJ sues Google, and this week in Elon
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4138346948009396087/5048026518405987790/s93290-US-4982s-1674838462.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of staring directly down the barrel of a camera, The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, Richard Lawler, and Monica Chin start the show with an inside look at our M2 MacBook Pro and Mac Mini reviews. After that, the crew breaks down the case the US Department of Justice has filed against Google's ad business and of course we try to make sense of the latest Elon Musk shenanigans.
Speaker 4:  Hello and welcome to the verse, the flagship podcast. I'm
Speaker 4:  staring directly down the barrel of the camera,
Speaker 4:  whether it's your real eyes or fake computer generated
Speaker 4:  eyes.
Speaker 1:  These are real eyes here. These are fake, beautiful
Speaker 4:  Real eyes. I'm your friend Eli. I have an announcement to make.
Speaker 4:  This is gonna be one of the first episodes of our show in a long
Speaker 4:  time that we post is a video podcast to
Speaker 4:  YouTube. We used to do it all the time. Yeah. We used to it live on
Speaker 4:  video, which was a mistake
Speaker 4:  then to pay back the, the karmic debt of doing
Speaker 4:  that. He's just stopped. We stopped the video. Right. And talked for years
Speaker 4:  and now we've slowly started adding it back in with everything that we've
Speaker 4:  learned. Yeah. And what we've learned is that Richard has the invidious software
Speaker 4:  on his computer that makes his eyes stare
Speaker 4:  directly at you no matter where he's looking. And it is
Speaker 4:  terrifying. I can't look away. Hello Richard.
Speaker 5:  It's fine. These are my real eyes. This is what I actually look like.
Speaker 5:  This is not AI enhanced by Nvidia. I, I am offended
Speaker 5:  by, by this, this suggestion that I would use software to enhance
Speaker 5:  the way that I look at you because I always look directly at
Speaker 4:  You. It's so creepy.
Speaker 5:  That's what people say about me all the time.
Speaker 4:  It's a lot. We're gonna,
Speaker 5:  There's anything I love, it's eye contact. That's what I'm into
Speaker 4:  When I say karmic debt, it's like we're already accruing it. Like we
Speaker 4:  paid off the balance. We're like, turn the cameras back
Speaker 1:  Off like three episodes.
Speaker 4:  I'm ringing it up. Just making, making purchases that
Speaker 4:  we're gonna have to pay off by with AI
Speaker 5:  Assist. Yeah. This isn't weird at all.
Speaker 4:  Oh my goodness. Alex Kranz is here.
Speaker 1:  I am here and I've got my own camera in the studio and
Speaker 4:  It's great if you're in your car, you're, you're doing great
Speaker 4:  cuz Richard isn't looking at you. But if you're watching this on video, here's
Speaker 4:  Richard looking at you. All right. And
Speaker 4:  Monica Chen is joining us for the first segment of the show. Hey Monica.
Speaker 1:  Hello.
Speaker 4:  I you know, we're two minutes into doing this on video
Speaker 4:  again. There's a reason I turned the cameras off. I
Speaker 1:  Think we look great. I think this is the best thing we've ever done. Well,
Speaker 4:  Look, I I'm gonna start with some like inside. The funny thing is when I
Speaker 4:  can
Speaker 1:  Just now get outta my frame. I'm looking great.
Speaker 4:  I can just get in Alex's camera.
Speaker 1:  It looks like he's intently examining
Speaker 4:  The wall. This is the worst radio that's ever been made. Here's what I will
Speaker 4:  tell everyone. Just back it up inside Media Baseball. We used to do
Speaker 4:  it on video all the time. We were arguably ahead of our time. Yes. In
Speaker 4:  2011 Live streaming a podcast.
Speaker 1:  But podcast live streaming podcast 2011.
Speaker 1:  None of those things existed though
Speaker 4:  Younger Drunker Ne Eli on camera live.
Speaker 4:  Many mistakes from me.
Speaker 1:  Some really good gifs out there of it, by the way. It's
Speaker 4:  It's incredible. Some of our finest moments. Yeah. Who is
Speaker 4:  the Samsung guy? Big Papa Joe. It's all,
Speaker 4:  it's all, we hired people off the off the call-ins for the
Speaker 4:  podcast. It's a true story. Whatever many things happen in the ver
Speaker 4:  I'm sure people remember or don't. We started the ver up
Speaker 4:  again and we're like, this is a lot of effort for videos. Yeah. That a small
Speaker 4:  group of very passionate people watch. But we wanted the podcast to be
Speaker 4:  big and so we shut off the cameras to make a better radio show. Right.
Speaker 4:  And our numbers went up because we were no longer looking
Speaker 4:  at each other and telling each other jokes about things we could see Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That no one in their cars could see. Yeah. So that we were like, okay, we're
Speaker 4:  good at making a podcast. So fast forward 2023, everyone with a
Speaker 4:  podcast is like, just turn on the cameras and put it on YouTube. That's where
Speaker 4:  all the podcast growth is. Yeah. So now we're fully back to the future. We
Speaker 4:  have potentially learned something about making a better
Speaker 4:  podcast by just having made a podcast for a long time.
Speaker 4:  And we are not Alex going to do bits to
Speaker 4:  the camera. Never.
Speaker 1:  I'm not doing that today, tomorrow, ever again. Hi
Speaker 1:  guys. How are you? We just talk to you
Speaker 1:  personally. Get outta my frame.
Speaker 4:  All right. So if you are listening to this and we
Speaker 4:  get outta line, send us a polite, e polite,
Speaker 1:  Very polite
Speaker 4:  Email. We'll we'll try to rein it in. If you're watching this for the first
Speaker 4:  time on YouTube, welcome Liam. What's the YouTube channel people can subscribe
Speaker 4:  to? Just type the vergecast into whatever text field you encounter
Speaker 4:  on the internet and it will lead you square our YouTube page.
Speaker 4:  Bing yahoo.com. No, it's the, it's YouTube the vergecast.
Speaker 4:  That's our channel. You can watch, you can watch this live. Love that. Once
Speaker 4:  again
Speaker 1:  You won't credit.
Speaker 4:  And Richard, we continue to stare directly at you the whole
Speaker 4:  time.
Speaker 1:  Just unblinking.
Speaker 4:  Can we, let's talk about this. This technology, we have a lot to talk about.
Speaker 4:  Monica's here to talk about MacBook Pro and Mac Mini with M two chip
Speaker 4:  reviews. Tesla earnings. We have a,
Speaker 4:  we have a headline here that just says Trouble in Alphabet City, which is
Speaker 4:  very good. So good. Which is just about Google. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  There's lots of problems for Google. Microsoft layoffs. Google, there's lots
Speaker 4:  to talk about. But we should talk about the fact that Nvidia released
Speaker 4:  this software for their video cards that lets you just stare at the
Speaker 4:  camera. This is not new technology, right?
Speaker 4:  It's built in a FaceTime. Monica you were saying it's built in a lot of
Speaker 6:  Laptops. We've been on the surface line for a bit.
Speaker 6:  Samsung has claimed to have a technology that does
Speaker 6:  it, which I haven't personally used it before. HP says they have
Speaker 6:  it. There are various people who have been trying it
Speaker 6:  with varying degrees of success.
Speaker 1:  But no one like Richard.
Speaker 4:  No. Well so the thing about Nvidia, right? It's because it, you can set
Speaker 4:  any video source to go through.
Speaker 6:  This is a, this one is is a, is a bigger
Speaker 6:  release.
Speaker 4:  So Right. Like you can't
Speaker 1:  Yeah cuz usually if you're doing FaceTime you have to be in the FaceTime
Speaker 1:  app
Speaker 4:  On the FaceTime
Speaker 1:  And it's not as nearly as your iPhone camera. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And then Richard, this is just like Nvidia broadcaster and you're just pumping
Speaker 4:  o bs through it. What's going on here?
Speaker 5:  Yep. It just connects it you, I open up Nvidia
Speaker 5:  broadcast, pick my camera and then in our recording software, I just tell
Speaker 5:  it to look for Nvidia broadcast and it, it gets whatever, whatever is piped
Speaker 5:  there.
Speaker 1:  Which is your cartoon ice. Yes.
Speaker 4:  I mean it's
Speaker 5:  Eyes that it is drawn and occasionally you'll see, like if it decides that
Speaker 5:  I've looked away too far, it'll go back to my real eyes and then it will
Speaker 5:  turn my eyes back to you. And for me that's the creepiest part. It's
Speaker 5:  the animated turn.
Speaker 6:  Well it would be weirder if they just like blinked out and then blinked to
Speaker 6:  be staring at us again.
Speaker 5:  It's strange because it's looking, it's like looking at like a ghost mirror
Speaker 5:  of myself because I'm looking at myself down in the middle of the screen
Speaker 5:  and it's looking directly back, which is very
Speaker 5:  strange.
Speaker 4:  That's terrifying. We've done a lot of stories about this attack recently.
Speaker 4:  James Vincent has written a lot of stories about this kinda attack. His one
Speaker 4:  today is very good. It's just about people putting movies through it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So the actors are looking directly down the barrel of the
Speaker 1:  Lens. No, don't do that. And
Speaker 4:  All of it looks like high school theater, like the most
Speaker 4:  dramatic high school monologues that you have ever experienced. It's very
Speaker 4:  good. I don't know if this is the future of all video conferencing. I know
Speaker 4:  that it's very funny and I also know that it's been on
Speaker 4:  FaceTime for a minute and no one has noticed it. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  True.
Speaker 4:  And I think it's just because in videos, letting basically anybody pump anything
Speaker 4:  through it
Speaker 6:  That you And how many people use FaceTime?
Speaker 4:  Like lots of people. But I like my mom is not like you're looking directly
Speaker 4:  at the camera, aren't you? Yeah. She's more like, where's your baby? Get
Speaker 4:  outta my face. Like you're old and dusty.
Speaker 1:  Don't like
Speaker 4:  You. I already raised you. Show
Speaker 1:  Me the child.
Speaker 4:  All right. So this is amazing Tack Richard and enjoy. It's just
Speaker 4:  so weird man. I'll
Speaker 5:  Just flip it on and off randomly during meetings and during the, during this
Speaker 5:  call it's fine. No, but I, we came into a meeting
Speaker 5:  last week and veering our video producer. He was on and I forgot that I had
Speaker 5:  turned it on the first day that it came out and we were talking for about
Speaker 5:  10 minutes and I don't know, he must have thought I was
Speaker 4:  Going
Speaker 5:  Because like I'm just talking to him and I wasn't looking at the video preview
Speaker 5:  so I didn't realize it was on until until a while in and he was like, I
Speaker 5:  wasn't, I was gonna say something but yeah.
Speaker 4:  Who doesn't have an entire meeting staring only directly into their
Speaker 4:  webcam. I do it all the time. Actually I think it's,
Speaker 1:  I was like, you're really, really good at it. Like annoyingly.
Speaker 4:  So I like mugging directly into Theam ones. Yeah, I'm doing it right now.
Speaker 4:  So I That's enough talking about this. It's so creepy. But it's out.
Speaker 4:  You should go play with it if you have it in video card. The fact that you
Speaker 4:  can pipe any source through it I think is deeply hilarious. But I would expect,
Speaker 4:  again, it's in FaceTime, it's a bunch of laptops. I would bet the next generation
Speaker 4:  of like Apple laptops has it cause they already have the technology and they're
Speaker 4:  using the same chips. Which brings me to the chips. Do you see that segue?
Speaker 1:  Oh I like that. That was good.
Speaker 4:  I did it. I loved it. It was perfect. Sweet. All right, so Monica, you
Speaker 4:  have been reviewing the new MacBook Pro sixteens with
Speaker 4:  the M two pro, the M two max.
Speaker 4:  Chris Welch reviewed the MAC Mini, which is the same chip,
Speaker 4:  the same computer in a little case without a battery and a screen.
Speaker 4:  What's going on here?
Speaker 6:  So the MacBook Pro 16 looks very similar,
Speaker 6:  identical even to the 2021 MacBook Pro 16.
Speaker 6:  But the chip inside is called the M two instead of the M one. There's the
Speaker 6:  M two max and the M two pro, which is not the M
Speaker 6:  one max and the M one Pro, it's the, you know it's the two. Yeah, it's the
Speaker 6:  second one. It's
Speaker 1:  Dose. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Dose
Speaker 4:  Is any good.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. For the workload that I do, which is you know,
Speaker 6:  lots of Google docs and lots of spreadsheets and lots of Zoom calls,
Speaker 6:  it's like not a noticeable difference. It's not, that's not anything that
Speaker 6:  it impacts. It is an upgrade in graphic
Speaker 6:  performance and an upgrade in CPU performance. And it is something
Speaker 6:  that you will notice if you are doing heavier
Speaker 6:  professional workloads. We saw decreases in export time. We
Speaker 6:  saw decreases in Xcode time. Benchmarks across the board were
Speaker 6:  higher. So it is a more powerful laptop. The battery life is a lot longer
Speaker 6:  and I think to me that's the most significant part.
Speaker 1:  Is it the same battery as last time? Like the same size battery
Speaker 4:  I think isn't Apple's like running right up against the limit?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it is the same 100 watt hour
Speaker 6:  battery. So
Speaker 1:  That is like super impressive.
Speaker 6:  Well the chip is more efficient. There are two more cores on the M
Speaker 6:  two max than there were on the M one max. They're both efficiency
Speaker 6:  cores. It, it seems like a more efficient chip. I would usually
Speaker 6:  get around 10 hours out of the M one max. I'm getting, depending
Speaker 6:  on my workload, I'll get 16 to 20. Wow,
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 6:  Crazy. A very big difference for me. That doesn't mean everyone will see
Speaker 6:  that same difference. You know, people's workloads vary, people's usage habits
Speaker 6:  vary. But I will be very surprised if any, if
Speaker 6:  anyone didn't see a couple more hours at least of battery out of this machine
Speaker 6:  than outta the older one. Which doesn't mean I don't think anyone's necessarily
Speaker 6:  trying to upgrade from the M one, that would surprise me. But like if you're
Speaker 6:  thinking of doing that, you don't need to do that. The M one PRO and and
Speaker 6:  M one max are fine, but these are four people who are still
Speaker 6:  upgrading from Intel machines. These are big increases in power and they're
Speaker 6:  more efficient.
Speaker 1:  I mean that's like six to eight hours extra battery though. Like Neela. Do
Speaker 1:  you have some FOMO about your M one?
Speaker 4:  So I'm, I'm staring at my M one Pro. Yeah. 16 inch MacBook Pro. It's
Speaker 4:  still the best laptop I've ever owned and we have
Speaker 4:  an M two PRO 16 inch MacBook Pro. You've yet to run benchmarks
Speaker 4:  on it and, but we've run the benchmarks on the, on the mini with that shit.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And it's like it's a linear increase in
Speaker 4:  performance in a linear increase in battery life. It's just like these
Speaker 4:  numbers are better. Yeah, yeah. In sort of exactly the way that you would
Speaker 4:  expect them to be. Which is kind of
Speaker 6:  Interesting. It somewhat has the vibes of like an intel, a pre AMD
Speaker 6:  being a competitor Intel upgrade. It's like they made the chips better.
Speaker 6:  They didn't feel like they had to make a giant splash with the chips.
Speaker 6:  Which is fine because the last ones that came out were a
Speaker 6:  giant splash.
Speaker 1:  So real talk kind of situations.
Speaker 4:  Right. And the rumors are the m threes will be on a three nanometer process.
Speaker 4:  Right. And that's like, that's like straight up
Speaker 1:  Just to straight up intel.
Speaker 6:  And that is the pattern that we saw from Intel pre before AMD sort of burst
Speaker 6:  on the scene as you know, making, we often had less exciting generations
Speaker 6:  followed by more exciting generations. It was
Speaker 1:  Super fun to write about those too because you'd be like, this year they're
Speaker 1:  10% faster you think. Cool. I said 10% faster.
Speaker 1:  That's all you need. Be excited. The
Speaker 6:  Number is 10 what org do you want? Yeah,
Speaker 4:  So I, I don't this computer rds, the M one
Speaker 4:  PRO 16 inch pro same battery, a hundred Kilo R battery,
Speaker 4:  which is like, it's, I think it's actually like 99 point something they like
Speaker 4:  sneak under the
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Under the plane.
Speaker 4:  But like this computer, I just like never plugged it in. I haven't plugged
Speaker 4:  in all day today.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean do we go to the only, the only way I'm getting that 16
Speaker 6:  hour figure is I do not let it go to sleep and I have it run something constantly.
Speaker 6:  If I were just using this my day-to-day life, I would not need to plug in.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, you would just
Speaker 6:  Every couple days. That's
Speaker 4:  Incredible. Now I didn't get that from the M one max when we tested the M
Speaker 4:  one max. Right. So if I was like, I'm always on the road
Speaker 4:  rendering road renderers.
Speaker 1:  Sure, yeah.
Speaker 4:  Who
Speaker 6:  Isn't just driving one hand
Speaker 4:  Over here constantly just
Speaker 6:  Mobilex code. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Maybe like, honestly maybe I'd be like, you know what, it's more power.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And more battery life and my mobile rendering
Speaker 4:  workflow will be significantly improved. The thing that really struck me
Speaker 4:  reading your review is that it runs the fan and it is like a noisier
Speaker 6:  Computer. It was much noisier I was using, I was running like Puget
Speaker 6:  bench in the office and like people were a couple ducks over and they were
Speaker 6:  coming over like what is going on over here? Like that.
Speaker 4:  That's correct. I can't remember the last time we had a noisy Mac.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So that is, and I mean that was it running on high
Speaker 6:  power mode, which like if you don't run on high power mode, you probably
Speaker 6:  will not get that much noise. You probably will get decreased performance.
Speaker 1:  But is high power mode like a thing you have to
Speaker 6:  Activate? Yeah. So if you go into the, the, the battery profiles you can
Speaker 6:  put on silent mode, you can put it on high power mode, you can put it on
Speaker 6:  automatic which decides which one to use based on what
Speaker 1:  You're doing. Which did you do for your battery
Speaker 6:  Test? The battery one.
Speaker 1:  I love that. Yeah. Okay. So like high power mode, super loud but also
Speaker 1:  like balls to the wall. Perform
Speaker 6:  Performance. Yeah. And, and there was, when I, when I ran benchmarks while
Speaker 6:  I was in the battery mode, they were, there was substantially decreased
Speaker 6:  performance. So you wanna have high power mode on if you're doing load
Speaker 4:  Mobile rendering. Yeah. You
Speaker 6:  Won't be stealthy.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. You won't be selling. Everybody's gonna hear I drive.
Speaker 1:  Everybody
Speaker 6:  Was hearing it was very like I I the the area behind the keyboard
Speaker 6:  was like very hot. Which like I've never seen from one of these MacBooks.
Speaker 1:  Well that's interesting though cuz that means like, so these, these are thermally
Speaker 1:  limited. Like that's where, where the slowdown is on this. Well
Speaker 4:  So actually I think this is like kind of a weird moment for Apple, right.
Speaker 4:  Because they have been very aggressive thermally limiting their
Speaker 4:  machines for quite a while. Yeah. Like the Intel MacBook errors
Speaker 4:  were like thermally throt, it throttling all over the place. The first generation
Speaker 4:  M one error in the old case design was
Speaker 4:  throttled all like we would've hit its limit and throttle down all the time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And the M one 13 inch MacBook Pro would be like, I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  run the fan and like last longer And it was like a pretty quiet fan.
Speaker 4:  This one seems like the first time apple's like, you know what, it's gonna
Speaker 4:  get hot and noisy and we're gonna keep that performance envelope up. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And I will just be clear like that was only, that was when it was running
Speaker 6:  Puget Bench, which does just like the wildest things. Like it's throwing
Speaker 6:  effects. It's doing all this random stuff with 4K and eight K. Like if I'm
Speaker 6:  just like doing my like regular, like if I'm watching Better Call SA or whatever,
Speaker 6:  it's not like those
Speaker 4:  Are the two extremes.
Speaker 1:  The two extremes, Monica,
Speaker 4:  Either it's gonna melt down or we're gonna watch the superior
Speaker 4:  prequel.
Speaker 1:  Exactly. Those the only two things that
Speaker 6:  You could would ever do a MacBook, I'm just coming out and saying it is,
Speaker 6:  it is a, it is not, we're not back in 13 inch
Speaker 6:  Intel MacBook Pro land where like I open one Chrome tab and it fries itself
Speaker 6:  to death. Like this is still that that's not gonna happen if you're just
Speaker 6:  like doing Chrome or whatever. That was when it was running like the most
Speaker 6:  intense thing that I ran on it.
Speaker 4:  The other thing that really struck me about the review is you pointed out
Speaker 4:  that apart from Battery life where Apple is still just like way ahead of
Speaker 4:  everybody performance-wise, Intel is making some
Speaker 4:  products that can compete
Speaker 6:  It. Yeah. So this year we just went, we just came back from ces a
Speaker 6:  MD and Intel both announced these just absolutely wild
Speaker 6:  chips. There's like, Intel has a 24 quarter chip, AMT has a 16
Speaker 6:  core chip and that's not a big little one that's like a full
Speaker 6:  16 power cores. These, I would expect
Speaker 6:  these chips to be competitive with Apple on like
Speaker 6:  CVE scores in. So we are in a very different landscape from the
Speaker 6:  landscape we were in when the one max can hour Intel was just not even
Speaker 6:  holy and canceled to its performance. Where we do not expect
Speaker 6:  Intel a MD to compete is battery life. And I don't, I don't wanna make
Speaker 6:  pronouncements before I've tested the chips, but when I was talking to Jason
Speaker 6:  Bade from a MD at c e s, he was telling me basically like, yeah, we're not
Speaker 6:  targeting an audience that cares about battery life with this chip. Like
Speaker 6:  this is, don't care about, this is really for people who don't unplug lot's.
Speaker 6:  Describe it that those weren't the exact words but that was the sentiment
Speaker 6:  I got from, you know, talking to a number of different people who are involved
Speaker 6:  in the making of that stuff.
Speaker 4:  Rash. What were you saying?
Speaker 5:  I said that that's one way to describe it and another thing that I noticed,
Speaker 5:  the gaming performance is noticeably better. We've got a lot more GPU power
Speaker 5:  here and it, it seems like if you want to use your MacBook Pro to play
Speaker 6:  Games, right? I don't do that. I don't recommend doing that. But if you wanna
Speaker 6:  do it, I just need a copy of that. But if you wanna buy a MacBook Pro and
Speaker 6:  play ton of games on it, we saw around a 20% increase in in graphic
Speaker 6:  performance and that, you know, that's a noticeably better gaming experience.
Speaker 1:  It just means like game developers have to actually develop for the Mac.
Speaker 1:  And we're seeing
Speaker 6:  Like we're seeing more of that Apple.
Speaker 1:  Apple is courting these developers, these developers are starting to seem
Speaker 1:  a little more interested. There's more you can play now than you could a
Speaker 1:  couple of years ago, but it's, this is such
Speaker 4:  A low
Speaker 1:  Bar. It's Yeah, it's bar's on the bar. The bar is on the
Speaker 1:  floor. But is this going
Speaker 6:  Up? Yeah. It's one of those things where it's like this and I, I hate to
Speaker 6:  make this comparison for all kinds of reasons, but if I hadn't made comparison,
Speaker 6:  I think it's, so it's it's competitive with the RTX 30 70.
Speaker 6:  Okay. And oh
Speaker 4:  My God, they're coming over the walls with pitchforks.
Speaker 6:  They're coming with pitchforks. I only say that to sort of put it the cat
Speaker 6:  the way you can think about it, sort the way you can classify it is like
Speaker 6:  that is the kind of, if,
Speaker 6:  if you were thinking about like what kind of power do I need? If
Speaker 6:  that is the kind of p graphic power you are looking for, this is the
Speaker 6:  computer that will give you that
Speaker 1:  Cool.
Speaker 6:  Which doesn't mean, doesn't mean buy to play games
Speaker 1:  And, and you also can't do creepy staring down the camera lens with
Speaker 1:  your Apple
Speaker 6:  Laptop. Well apparently you can do it on FaceTime
Speaker 1:  Except for on FaceTime.
Speaker 4:  No, you can do that. I don't can you hold
Speaker 6:  On Now is that only on the
Speaker 4:  Phone? Oh, I'm not running the latest version of Makos. I it might only
Speaker 4:  be on the phone. This is gonna make for both horrible video and audio. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Don't worry about it.
Speaker 4:  The other thing that caught me was basically the only other change here is
Speaker 4:  an H GM I spec change
Speaker 1:  2.1.
Speaker 4:  Two point. I mean, you mean what show is this? We, we need to talk about
Speaker 4:  the H DM I spec change for the next hour.
Speaker 1:  Surprise
Speaker 5:  Max. Don't do H D M I cec. This is something I hadn't thought about but I
Speaker 5:  just learned last week. It's such a strange emission. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Because they don't do cec so you cannot, like a Mac right now is
Speaker 1:  not a recommended product for your home theater system.
Speaker 1:  And it used to be 20 years ago when
Speaker 1:  the Mac first came out.
Speaker 4:  I'm sorry, what kind of piracy situation do you need a Mac
Speaker 4:  in your home theater for?
Speaker 1:  You know what, sometimes you just need to acquire things from the internet
Speaker 1:  and you don't wanna like then transfer them over. You just want it
Speaker 1:  fast.
Speaker 4:  Can I, can I tell a very tangential story? You, you know the story. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Alex actually is part of the story. Oh. So I'm off
Speaker 4:  Twitter. I gotta fill the time. Yeah. There's hours
Speaker 4:  to reclaim now that the Twitter's not on my phone. Yes. I look at Twitter
Speaker 4:  on the desktop every now and again. Sometimes I might send a tweet and then
Speaker 4:  500 people tweeted me like, I thought you quit Twitter. And it's like, that's
Speaker 4:  great. Anyway. Not on my phone. So I'm trying all these new things. I'm trying
Speaker 4:  not to immediately fill it with more feeds. Yeah, right. You're not trying
Speaker 4:  to quit cigarettes and immediately pick up nicotine gum. You're like, I'm
Speaker 4:  trying to, I'm trying to rewire the brain. So this last week Apple News,
Speaker 4:  cause I paid for Apple One, I got the, did you know there's a magazine Red
Speaker 4:  when I was a kid called Stereo Review. It has now turned into magazine called
Speaker 4:  Sam Division. They do not publish the Apple news format. They publish as
Speaker 4:  just PDFs. Yay. Of a print magazine, which is like super fun to
Speaker 4:  read. Getting back to the source. Yeah, it's, it's like good man. Like reading
Speaker 4:  a giant PDF magazine and iPad is like maybe Steve Jobs is
Speaker 4:  on full page print ad for
Speaker 4:  Samsung HDR 10 in this last, it's beautiful. I mean it's beautiful.
Speaker 4:  But they had letters to the editor about the Kalei Escape, which is like
Speaker 4:  a $5,000 $8,000. Yeah. Lossless
Speaker 4:  audio high bit rate streaming thing
Speaker 1:  Like the be it's the best of the best.
Speaker 4:  The highest quality digital video players.
Speaker 1:  The people who own this also have like home theater systems, like
Speaker 1:  $50,000.
Speaker 4:  They custom tag all the movies Yes. To trigger home
Speaker 4:  automation points as you're watching them. Oh my God. So when the credits
Speaker 4:  come on, you can trigger the lights to come on in
Speaker 1:  Your house. I need to own this.
Speaker 4:  I want this. So like Liam's like losing his mind. This is like Liam
Speaker 4:  Street. So like reading and like reading a letter to edit
Speaker 4:  about it and like the last line is I'm incarcerated and this is how I keep
Speaker 4:  up with news. Oh no. And it's like, well first Alex
Speaker 1:  Immediately Googles
Speaker 4:  So we can't figure out who it's, I'm just telling you, no matter where you
Speaker 4:  go, the AV nerds are like,
Speaker 1:  I need, they're there. Need to know. They need to know
Speaker 4:  Alex. People are everywhere. We're everywhere. And now I feel bad that I'm
Speaker 4:  like, who has a Mac mini in their home theater setup? Because it's the guy
Speaker 4:  in jail writing student review.
Speaker 1:  He's like, he's got like the little clear Mac mini. They've taken all that
Speaker 1:  out so you can see the inside. He's ready. He's got a six system
Speaker 4:  In there. Anyway, if anybody has a Kale escape, please, please let me know.
Speaker 4:  And I desperately want to know how you've coded your home automations to
Speaker 4:  trigger with the custom triggers, the movie files. I'm just thinking the
Speaker 4:  thing sounds amazing.
Speaker 1:  Think of like panic room and then all of the Windows shades come down
Speaker 1:  when they go into the room and you're like, oh, it's so immersive
Speaker 4:  Idx. I read the actual review in the middle of it. They're like, fast and
Speaker 4:  furious set looks great. I'm like escape. I'm like, it doesn't matter. Like
Speaker 4:  it's all the same in the end. Alright. Ht My two point, all I had to do to
Speaker 4:  start this conversation was mention hd and there we go. I told you
Speaker 4:  what show it is. So the only reason that you ha you really need 2.1 is
Speaker 4:  eight K, which you can support. Great. But
Speaker 4:  then it's really 144 hertz refresh rates. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Which is only for gaming. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Which I mean, you know, if you bump the settings way down on
Speaker 6:  two, you can maybe get there.
Speaker 4:  Wait, so you can't, you don't think you can, you you can't run 4K 1 44 on
Speaker 4:  this thing we
Speaker 6:  Got at 1920 by 1200, we got I think 1 0 3.
Speaker 6:  Okay. FPSs
Speaker 1:  Did you, what what game was it to Raider? So you didn't run something
Speaker 1:  like a, the classic civilization for Oh I, that would've gotten
Speaker 1:  1 44.
Speaker 6:  I I mean I'm, I'm sure there
Speaker 4:  Are like a mostly static game
Speaker 5:  Open up Sim city Reticulate
Speaker 6:  Trying. There are games where, where, I mean you can find a game where, where
Speaker 6:  you'll get that if you're, if you really wanna do eSports on your
Speaker 6:  MacBook Pro 16 with M one max and that two Mac imagine
Speaker 6:  of choice, bully
Speaker 1:  It. If you try to do eSports on a Mac,
Speaker 6:  I mean I would bowl you. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Like I would
Speaker 4:  Your
Speaker 6:  As like why did you spend that much under
Speaker 1:  Time? That's just
Speaker 6:  At the, at at minimum. That is just such a waste of your money.
Speaker 4:  All right. So these feel like solid incremental upgrades.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean, and I, you know, incremental upgrade is like a hot
Speaker 6:  buttoned word to use. I don't say that to mean that this is like
Speaker 6:  an inadequate upgrade or a boring upgrade or like objectionable
Speaker 6:  incremental in the sense that, you know, it's around a
Speaker 6:  20% CPU uplift and a 10 to 15 ish percent single
Speaker 6:  core
Speaker 1:  And a lot more battery. I mean like, I think we're, we're kind of discounting
Speaker 1:  the battery
Speaker 6:  And a lot more better because
Speaker 4:  I'm a lot to know what the battery life, the M two PRO
Speaker 6:  Is. I'm, I have the whole weekend blocked out. We're gonna see if I
Speaker 6:  can run it down in, I've canceled
Speaker 4:  Plans this last time. It took you the
Speaker 6:  Whole weekend. It took, it was agonizing. I, I've canceled plans. We are
Speaker 6:  gonna sit down. We are gonna run, we are gonna edit on it till it dies. But
Speaker 6:  yeah, it, it, it, I don't mean to say it's unexciting. It's, it's exciting
Speaker 6:  to see that, you know, these are increasing how quickly people
Speaker 6:  can do their work and they're increasing, you know, the number of things
Speaker 6:  they can cram into a workday. The most exciting upgrade for me
Speaker 6:  is the battery life. And that is what would make
Speaker 6:  biggest difference in, you know, the workload for someone like me. But that
Speaker 6:  also goes to show somewhat that I'm not really the target audience for this,
Speaker 6:  for this kind of
Speaker 4:  Device. You're not the stealthy mobile rendering ninja.
Speaker 6:  No, I'm not. Maybe for my eSports.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  No, no. You, but you, you are a person who might work an entire day on your
Speaker 5:  laptop. You've been in different places. You've moved from location to location.
Speaker 5:  You didn't plug it in, you went to sleep, you didn't plug it in. You wake
Speaker 5:  up, you have something you need to do and you can't.
Speaker 6:  I can keep it right by my head. Can't
Speaker 5:  Plug it in again. It'll be
Speaker 1:  Fine. Yeah. Can we do a challenge for you guys when you go to wwdc
Speaker 1:  where you just take a 16 inch MAC Pro and don't charge it the entire time
Speaker 1:  you're there?
Speaker 4:  No, because we have to get our work done. And that is, that is the environment
Speaker 4:  where we actually end up killing the batteries. Cuz we, you're in a really
Speaker 4:  RF constrained environment. So your wifi radio is like hunting a lot. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And that's actually bizarrely the thing that always ends up
Speaker 1:  Coming. Oh, interesting.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The other thing, and I mentioned this review,
Speaker 6:  I actually am almost as excited
Speaker 6:  to see what kinds of discounts we see on the M one PRO
Speaker 6:  and M one max because if those laptops go below
Speaker 6:  $2,000, I'm going to have, I, I can't say this for sure.
Speaker 6:  I would not be surprised if I have a real hard time recommending
Speaker 6:  any 15 or 16 inch laptop that's not those. Yeah. Because that is just going
Speaker 6:  to be such a like
Speaker 6:  wildly goodbye for, for for a lower price
Speaker 6:  than this. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I I'm actually, I I feel the same way about the Mac
Speaker 4:  Minis. Yeah. Right. Like if this generation of Mac Minis ever sees
Speaker 4:  a discount with the M two PRO in IT distance right now it's like sitting
Speaker 4:  at 600 bucks, 5 99. Yeah. If that thing gets dips
Speaker 4:  anywhere below five, it's like
Speaker 1:  Oh, so five 50, no, five.
Speaker 4:  No, it's, it's, it's like 4 99 99. I'm like, I'll be
Speaker 4:  like
Speaker 1:  Four 50 done. You just didn't even think.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, because it's, it's, it's the longevity of that machine given
Speaker 4:  its performance envelope. Yeah. For the things you want to do with
Speaker 4:  the MAC Mini. You're like, I'm gonna have this computer for 15 years,
Speaker 1:  But you won't be able to put in your home theater system. You will
Speaker 4:  Not be, that's how you get a kale
Speaker 4:  escape.
Speaker 1:  If
Speaker 4:  The Kale Escape people are listening, which I I'm sure they are.
Speaker 1:  Yes, a hundred percent.
Speaker 4:  The first time we've ever mentioned this product on this podcast,
Speaker 1:  They're like sitting up right now.
Speaker 4:  Send, send Alex a kale escape.
Speaker 1:  I I wanna, I wanna try one out please. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's a client server system. Yeah. So if you just buy the client,
Speaker 4:  you still can't do anything. You have to buy a separate like 64
Speaker 4:  gigabyte server,
Speaker 1:  Huge servers. And I was trying to price them out, but it's one of those
Speaker 1:  websites where you go and they, they're like, call us for a quote. I
Speaker 4:  Was like, oh, that's good. It's good.
Speaker 6:  Nevermind. Yeah. Yeah. I mean the elephant in the room when you're reviewing
Speaker 6:  something like this and you know, sort of the, the caveat you have to make
Speaker 6:  when you say anything good about it, it's like, these are really expensive.
Speaker 6:  Like they're really great. There are lots of great things about them. The
Speaker 6:  cheapest M two max unit is like over
Speaker 6:  $3,000. It is really inaccessible laptop for many,
Speaker 6:  many people. But so, so I'm sort of still, I'm still, you know, I
Speaker 6:  think it's great. I still see it as kind of a niche purchase because it is
Speaker 6:  in that high price point. The M one max and the M one Pro are
Speaker 6:  moving. It, it,
Speaker 4:  They come
Speaker 6:  More discounted. They are the much closer they are to being like very
Speaker 6:  accessible mainstream purchases or it's certainly more so than the M
Speaker 6:  two devices.
Speaker 4:  Again, I, that M one max, I I felt like didn't
Speaker 4:  quite have the ba it had the performance, but most people
Speaker 4:  don't need it. Yeah. Because it's mostly like extra GPU performance,
Speaker 4:  right? Yeah. And like what are you gonna do play games on this thing?
Speaker 1:  Yes. Alex is crusader. King is three King is
Speaker 1:  gonna play. So four,
Speaker 4:  It's the M one pro. If it comes down then like that thing is, it's
Speaker 4:  in such a sweet spot. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean my device is usually, and I, I think that based on we, we
Speaker 6:  haven't gotten to fully benchmark and break down the M two
Speaker 6:  PRO laptop yet. We do have the M two Pro Mac Mini. So we have a
Speaker 6:  sense of how that's going to perform. We'll have more updates
Speaker 6:  next week about how the laptop specifically compare. But based on what we
Speaker 6:  are seeing so far, I imagine it's going to be a similar situation where
Speaker 6:  the M two PRO is more of the everyone chip. Like that's
Speaker 6:  what you can get if you, you know, are doing this stuff occasionally, like
Speaker 6:  this stuff being like video stuff. Xcode the
Speaker 6:  rendering that NEI is doing all the time. If you are buying this
Speaker 1:  Laptop in your car,
Speaker 4:  Right. I'm rendering Bitcoins on the go left and right.
Speaker 6:  If you are are buying this primarily to do a graphically
Speaker 6:  intensive task, then it, the M two max, you'll have a better
Speaker 6:  time. It will save you, you know, if your job requires you to do all this
Speaker 6:  stuff really fast, the M two max will save you time. But the, the increase
Speaker 6:  is not such that it is super, super necessary for like the average buyer
Speaker 6:  to have it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  All right. We gotta take a break. Monica, thank you so much for joining us.
Speaker 4:  You're welcome. We'll have more after Monica's marathon M two
Speaker 4:  Pro battery testing session. We'll see. He's gonna come out
Speaker 4:  the other side like a skeleton.
Speaker 6:  I'll be just a zombie. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  We'll have more. We'll have updates on that. We gotta take a break. We'll
Speaker 4:  be right back. We gotta talk about Google. Okay. We'll be right
Speaker 4:  back.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. It's time to talk about trouble in Alphabet City.
Speaker 1:  Big trouble in Alphabet
Speaker 4:  City, which is a real neighborhood here in New York City.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, but this is, this is a different alphabet, but
Speaker 4:  You like to normal people. If you say there's trouble in Alphabet City, they'll
Speaker 4:  be like, what did a trust fund baby run over a car? Like Yes.
Speaker 4:  Did someone not get into the club? That's not what's happening here.
Speaker 4:  No, it's way less fun. Yeah. So lots of Google news this
Speaker 4:  week. They laid off 12,000 people on Friday.
Speaker 4:  First mass layoffs in Google history. Major
Speaker 4:  culture change for Google. They've never done it before. Larry
Speaker 4:  Page, Sege Brynn back at the company to talk it over with Sundar.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Obviously they're the founders and they, they, no one knows where they've
Speaker 4:  been for years. Like Sergey is just like out, like
Speaker 1:  Parked came back from the Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Larry's trying to fly a taxi
Speaker 1:  Landed
Speaker 4:  In Larry Page has like five flying car startups.
Speaker 5:  I think it's down to like three or maybe
Speaker 4:  Two nights. It's just two. All right. Okay. But they're back in the building
Speaker 4:  at Google. Cause they gotta refocus big New York Times story about Google
Speaker 4:  calling a code red over chat G P T. We can get all to that. They have
Speaker 4:  12,000 people seemingly at random. Right. I'm sure that,
Speaker 4:  you know, there are reports they had hundreds of executives making, like
Speaker 4:  all together make sure they made the right decisions. But you know, very
Speaker 4:  senior people who've been at Google for 8, 10, 12 years clipped very junior
Speaker 4:  people who actually like, you know, it's a 12,000 people. A lot of people.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So like I've seen tos from Google employees. So like I just
Speaker 4:  walked, walked out of a client meeting, whoops. Woo. You know,
Speaker 4:  and they're not done yet cuz they're all over the world. Lots of legal regulations,
Speaker 4:  lots of different countries. So that's just the top line. And Liz actually
Speaker 4:  has a great piece today about the layoffs across tech because Amazon had
Speaker 4:  layoffs. Stripe had layoffs. Microsoft's had layoffs just down the line.
Speaker 4:  And they all have the same reasoning. Spotify had layoffs. Yeah. Which
Speaker 4:  is, we thought that changes brought about by the
Speaker 4:  pandemic would would stay.
Speaker 1:  Which is everybody really sat there and was like, we thought everybody
Speaker 1:  sitting in their houses baking bread and crying about missing the
Speaker 1:  outdoors would just be the The present forever.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like we're all gonna shop online. We're gonna watch all of our videos
Speaker 4:  on YouTube and Netflix. We're gonna listen to everything on Spotify. We do
Speaker 4:  Clubhouse. Do you remember when the tech industry tried to convince us Clubhouse
Speaker 4:  was real? And like I talk for a living. Yeah. And I was like, y'all
Speaker 4:  Uhuh.
Speaker 1:  Everybody's like, we got spaces now though. We got spaces
Speaker 1:  out of it. And
Speaker 4:  Like
Speaker 5:  They thought that, they thought that we were going to be buying brand new
Speaker 5:  electronics and new laptops every six months for
Speaker 4:  The next Yeah. Logitech was like, webcams are back. I was
Speaker 4:  like,
Speaker 5:  You know, I, I'm trying to keep Logitech in business but I can only buy so
Speaker 5:  many. Like I have to put them somewhere
Speaker 4:  At some point. Stare directly down the camera. The racing wheel logic
Speaker 4:  had bad earnings. This escort. So this is the context, right? They're
Speaker 4:  all blaming it on. We thought the pandemic trends would stay where they
Speaker 4:  were.
Speaker 1:  How could we know
Speaker 4:  It? It seems a little shortsighted.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like when Liz was writing this piece, she's like, what do you think?
Speaker 4:  I was like the first sentence is they didn't think we would go back outside.
Speaker 4:  And so I like, we can talk about why the laughs are happening and all, all
Speaker 4:  this stuff. But like that's the reason that the tech companies are
Speaker 4:  giving and we talked about it on this show. I've talked about it in decoder,
Speaker 4:  like what are the first order changes of the pandemic? What
Speaker 4:  are the second order changes? Like remote work is a
Speaker 4:  lasting right. Second order change. Like a real
Speaker 4:  thing on, I go on CNBC a lot. All
Speaker 4:  cable news is like, screw it, you can be on Zoom now. They used to be like,
Speaker 4:  you have to come in. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  School
Speaker 5:  Has changed. We don't have snow days anymore. I was just talking to my sister
Speaker 5:  about my, my nephew. They had a snow day but it was not a snow day, it was
Speaker 5:  just a
Speaker 4:  Go to school. That's brutal. That should be illegal. I don't, I dunno if
Speaker 4:  there's anyone we can call about
Speaker 1:  That. Little kids unionized right now. Exactly.
Speaker 4:  The little kids union. That's great. I
Speaker 4:  mean so there, there's that stuff. But the top line of all these layoffs
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Is we thought it was permanent and that just seems so
Speaker 4:  mistaken. And I think for Google especially, it just rings
Speaker 4:  really hollow to me.
Speaker 1:  Yes. Especially when you compare it to Apple who's notably not
Speaker 1:  had layoffs and also didn't grow at nearly
Speaker 1:  the same pace as these other companies. These other companies were doing
Speaker 1:  60, 70% growth year over year for like their
Speaker 1:  staff and Apple was like 10 20%. And so
Speaker 1:  yeah. Now these companies are going, oh we need all that money back. Nevermind.
Speaker 1:  Give
Speaker 4:  It back. Right. And they're, and they're apart from meta, which Mark Zuckerberg
Speaker 4:  said the same thing. We had saw this acceleration pandemic and now we gotta
Speaker 4:  wind it back. Okay. But you know Google, they left their
Speaker 4:  AI divisions alone but they shut down their incubator which does all their
Speaker 4:  20% time projects. They're shutting down all these like weird
Speaker 4:  other bets they're doing. They're like health
Speaker 4:  science division of alphabet. Like they're trying to refocus
Speaker 4:  on the core of Google. I think a lot of people have learned from
Speaker 4:  Elon like I just get rid of like most of the company
Speaker 4:  and like yeah it'll be a little crappier but
Speaker 1:  Still
Speaker 4:  Gonna do a crash. And, and and we have yet to
Speaker 4:  see. So that's like the big context for Google, right? They just had this
Speaker 4:  like very traumatic event. Yeah. And like maybe the whole tech industry is
Speaker 4:  just copycatting each other. Liz has great quotes in her piece. Like a management
Speaker 4:  professor at Stanford is like, everyone's an idiot.
Speaker 4:  She's like, he's like, it's morons being morons. What do you want for this?
Speaker 4:  It's very good. So but that's a broader context. But then specifically
Speaker 4:  Google, right? You look at all the other companies, Amazon, it's like, oh
Speaker 4:  maybe they built too much warehouse capacity. They're landing people off
Speaker 4:  Microsoft. They're like shut down HoloLens and a bunch of weird surface stuff
Speaker 4:  that people aren't gonna buy. PC shipments are down cuz pandemic is over
Speaker 4:  and everyone already bought their new pc. Still Microsoft. They're gonna
Speaker 4:  be fine. Yeah. Google is like, oh they did all of this. They fired
Speaker 4:  12,000 people. The government is suing them. We should talk about this ad
Speaker 4:  tech lawsuit. The second big antitrust lawsuit against Google,
Speaker 4:  which it's adtech
Speaker 1:  Is, we're little biased here, but yeah, we're little
Speaker 4:  By, you know how I feel about the web. That's a big
Speaker 4:  deal. And then they are on the run from
Speaker 4:  chat gt, we talked about this a little bit last week. Yeah. Can you just
Speaker 4:  like add up this week for Google and you're like, oh this is the most
Speaker 4:  existential threats a company can face at the same time.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. This is, this is way different than like the pixel comes out and
Speaker 1:  does not great numbers. This is, this is their core
Speaker 1:  businesses under attack from many different avenues. And
Speaker 1:  like I think the chat G p t Avenue is not actually the, the
Speaker 1:  big existential threat that they feel it is. But the, the stuff going on
Speaker 1:  with the DOJ that feels really, really big and important to me. Potentially
Speaker 1:  much more so than the chat G P T. But that feels like more of a, a crisis
Speaker 1:  of like what are we as a company?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Richard Roseon
Speaker 5:  And all of these things are happening at once and it's just something that
Speaker 5:  we really have never seen for Google. Like since it came on the scene that
Speaker 5:  we, that they've had all of this a real comp competitor that maybe they
Speaker 5:  aren't ready for in a, in a space that they aren't ready for. The,
Speaker 5:  the pressures of regulators are perhaps higher than they've
Speaker 5:  ever been because everyone has a reason to take, take a hammer to big tech.
Speaker 5:  It's just a way that you can score points as a politician as you've pointed
Speaker 5:  out. Many times Eli and I, I don't know, I, I can't, I
Speaker 5:  can't remember a time since Google has existed that we've seen them on the
Speaker 5:  back foot like
Speaker 4:  This. Yeah. It's tough. And I, you know, my theory about Google is people
Speaker 4:  don't take it seriously cuz it's called Google. Like it's,
Speaker 4:  it's hard to see the company for what it is. Yeah. Because it's called
Speaker 4:  Google and it, you know it very, and for a good reason
Speaker 4:  it maintains this image of being like a goofball place for smart people to
Speaker 4:  do smart stuff. Well
Speaker 1:  I worked really hard on that whole do no evil thing, which they've gotten
Speaker 1:  rid of.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's
Speaker 5:  Gone. They had a movie about working, they made a movie about getting
Speaker 4:  Jobs. It was like Owen Wilson
Speaker 5:  With real Hollywood stars and it's an advertising company
Speaker 5:  like, and for some reason we don't think of it that
Speaker 4:  Way. Well you what's funny, like big advertising companies, they love to
Speaker 4:  think of themselves as like creative progressive shops and then at the end
Speaker 4:  of the day they're like selling you cigarettes and like fine
Speaker 4:  Google is an advertising company but they're like an ad tech company. And
Speaker 4:  so this is where what this lawsuit really gets at is most of what we
Speaker 4:  as consumers experience of Google are the products in particularly the
Speaker 4:  two search and YouTube gmail. Great. And they're good
Speaker 4:  products. People like them. They're the industry leader. It's a very hard
Speaker 4:  to compete with Google search in particular. But the other side of Google,
Speaker 4:  the business of Google is as ruthlessly competitive as any
Speaker 4:  company. Yeah. And it's run by advertising executives and salespeople
Speaker 4:  and money people. And they are not shy. And
Speaker 4:  so they are not shy about winning whatever competition they're in or
Speaker 4:  foreclosing competition or protecting their monopoly. So you see this lawsuit,
Speaker 4:  it's 194 pages long. It's fun to read in the sense that
Speaker 4:  any lawsuit that explains what ad tech is and how it works, could it be
Speaker 4:  fun to, I read it, I recommend you go read the complaint. It's just the complaint.
Speaker 4:  It's a bunch of allegations. But you know, they've obviously done a bunch
Speaker 4:  of discovery. They have have a lot of quotes from executives and what you
Speaker 4:  find is that when you load a webpage, when you load one of
Speaker 4:  our webpages or the Times webpage or any publisher, any website really that
Speaker 4:  has ads on it, there's a whole stack of technology. It's called the
Speaker 4:  Ad tech stack. And there's lots of components and at every layer
Speaker 4:  of the stack, Google owns either the one or two
Speaker 4:  product and they make it so that all those products work
Speaker 4:  better together and they charge more money that Google then skims off at
Speaker 4:  another layer of the stack and they have ruthlessly
Speaker 4:  operated this system to basically be the winner. There's no way to compete
Speaker 4:  with him. Yeah. And all this other stuff that Google has done in the past
Speaker 4:  like Google Amp, Google Discu like this, these
Speaker 4:  products that Google makes, they use them to force people back into their
Speaker 4:  advertising ecosystem. The funnel. It's, it's, it's like
Speaker 4:  a ruthless money machine. Yeah. And so if you just like to abstract it,
Speaker 4:  the way to think about it is Apple's a revenue platform that we've complained
Speaker 4:  about many times is the iPhone in the app store. Right? Right.
Speaker 4:  And at, at the end of the day, Tim Cook's goal is that every time you push
Speaker 4:  any button on your phone, he gets money. He gets money. And you can just
Speaker 4:  see that they ruthlessly optimize for that. And people can argue about
Speaker 4:  whether that's good or that's bad. You can have antitrust lawsuits or laws
Speaker 4:  in Congress or the European scream mad at you. But like that's the goal and
Speaker 4:  you can see how they get there. Yeah. You can see that, you
Speaker 4:  know, Amazon's revenue platform is its store and it's
Speaker 4:  AWS business and their goal is to get you to buy everything from Amazon and
Speaker 4:  for every app to use AWS to cloud search. Right. You can do this with
Speaker 4:  Microsoft too. You can do this to all these companies. Google's revenue platform
Speaker 4:  is the web. Yeah. And so it's hard to see
Speaker 4:  where it begins and ends because you're not,
Speaker 4:  it's so ubiquitous. It's just everywhere. It's so you forget, so
Speaker 4:  you forget that all these ads are being served to you by Google in particular
Speaker 4:  by a company Google acquired called DoubleClick and they run this product
Speaker 4:  called DFP DoubleClick for publishers what they change to Google Ads manager
Speaker 4:  every still calls dp. And that
Speaker 4:  that thing that they own, the ad server is like
Speaker 4:  hard coded to prefer Google's ad exchanges. It's hard. And that is hard
Speaker 4:  coded to prefer Google's demand side platform. These are all just like ad
Speaker 4:  tech words, whatever. It's just like everywhere you go, the whole chain is
Speaker 4:  Google. And so the government's casing against Google is you
Speaker 4:  bought up all the competitors and every layer of the stack, you used your
Speaker 4:  dominance in one layer of the stack to achieve dominance in another layer
Speaker 4:  of the stack. And now you're charging higher prices, which
Speaker 4:  every other time we talk about antitrust, we're like we gotta change this
Speaker 4:  thing from the consumer welfare theory where there's no higher prices cuz
Speaker 4:  everything's free. Right. Da da we gotta like invent this new a, this is
Speaker 4:  just like old school. Yeah. 1980s. Ronald Reagan,
Speaker 4:  Robert Bork, antitrust. It's like, oh, you bought all this shit
Speaker 4:  and now the prices went up. And so like, maybe they got like, you
Speaker 4:  know, usually every time there's a lawsuit Amazon's like, but people love
Speaker 4:  Amazon Prime. Like, you know, Apple's like the app store made
Speaker 4:  everyone happier today.
Speaker 1:  Everybody loves Netflix.
Speaker 4:  This is like a bunch of advertisers like you, you robbed us.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And like Google's Google can be like, people love web
Speaker 4:  advertising. Like they're in a tough spot with this shit.
Speaker 5:  That's a much harder case
Speaker 4:  To make. Yeah. And so like, I just see this as, it's not a novel legal theory.
Speaker 4:  It's not something like Lena Khan invention. Yeah. It's a
Speaker 4:  class. The people who want the lawsuit are the
Speaker 4:  media advertising companies. Other
Speaker 4:  e-commerce companies, like they all see it that, oh, we're losing revenue,
Speaker 4:  we're losing profit margin into Google. There's real money at
Speaker 4:  stake and this is Google's bi. Like this is the
Speaker 4:  money. Yeah. Right. If you, if you uncouple the web from
Speaker 4:  Google, I'm not sure what the web looks like.
Speaker 1:  Duck duck go.
Speaker 4:  Like if people are doing SEO spam for Duck Duck go like you
Speaker 4:  founded like the niches of niche interests.
Speaker 1:  You've got three
Speaker 4:  Customers. Here's what I do. I cosplay is a specific Victorian Lord
Speaker 4:  and I do SEO for duck.gov. Like what
Speaker 4:  are
Speaker 5:  You doing? Like, man, I'm telling you what we're gonna do. We're gonna rebuild
Speaker 5:  Ask G, it's gonna be real people. It's just, it's just gonna be a guy.
Speaker 5:  You're just gonna ask a guy, he's gonna, he's gonna tell you something. And
Speaker 5:  similar to ai, it may or may not be true, but you'll
Speaker 4:  Get a, yeah. Chat GBT is just a, a bunch of cost players
Speaker 4:  definitely
Speaker 5:  Obvious.
Speaker 4:  I mean that's, this to me is like, you just add this up, it's on the one
Speaker 4:  hand, and I, I don't think this is true at all, but people will are out
Speaker 4:  there freaking out the stock market by saying chat G P T is gonna replace
Speaker 4:  Google. Yeah. And it's like mostly what you experience at chat
Speaker 4:  G P T is the good stuff. If you actually sit around trying to use chat d,
Speaker 4:  you're like this, this thing is like not very good. Yeah. It's very impressive.
Speaker 4:  But you're seeing it filtered through millions of people only showing you
Speaker 4:  the best stuff
Speaker 1:  Resource intensive and expensive to use.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. By the way, we got it wrong in the show in classic TikTok strategy.
Speaker 4:  We published the thing we said Wrong and that is our most viewed TikTok.
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 1:  That's all for you guys. Misinformation.
Speaker 4:  We got, you clicked, didn't you? No, we got it wrong. We
Speaker 4:  were getting wrong. It's, it's on Azure. Okay. Microsoft obviously has huge
Speaker 4:  investment open eye that just made a bigger investment. It Sam Altman ceo
Speaker 4:  Okay. Says it is not very expensive to run now. Oh you to make it cheaper.
Speaker 4:  It is not as cheap as Google searches. Right. Per query.
Speaker 1:  It's still like more
Speaker 4:  Resources. It's more resource intensive than Google search. But you see Microsoft
Speaker 4:  is like, oh, we don't have to do Bing. We can just answer the questions directly
Speaker 4:  with chat. G P T. All right. Maybe that's right. Buzzfeed today
Speaker 4:  announced that it's gonna start having chat G P T, right? The quizzes.
Speaker 1:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 4:  Mia has done a lot of great reporting on our competitors. Cnet,
Speaker 4:  which I have very bittersweet feelings about this. CNET has been the thing
Speaker 4:  that we have competed against.
Speaker 1:  They're our enemy
Speaker 4:  Since we are founding. Right? Yeah. They're like, we gotta beat cnet. They're
Speaker 4:  like the Bastion and they got bought by this private equity company and now
Speaker 4:  they're like published SEO spam written by robots cuz they
Speaker 4:  are flooding Google to try to win searches and then put ads on those
Speaker 4:  pages. The ads are served by Google.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Basically they're just chasing Google.
Speaker 4:  When I say I don't know what the shape of the web is without Google, it's
Speaker 4:  you can, C'S ownership can be like everybody
Speaker 4:  automates their mortgage rate stories. What they have not accounted for is
Speaker 4:  why does CNET publish mortgage rate stories? And the answer
Speaker 4:  is cuz they want to win the Google searches. Yeah. So that when you buy a
Speaker 4:  mortgage, you've come through their affiliate link and they get a huge cut
Speaker 4:  of that. Do you know when you sign up for a credit card on like the points
Speaker 4:  Sky is great when you sign up for a credit card, it's all lot of company.
Speaker 4:  It's like almost $900 to sign up in an affiliate rank by the way we are gonna
Speaker 4:  start recommending credit cards, the british.com
Speaker 1:  And mortgages sign up with us.
Speaker 4:  You just look at that system. Yeah. And you're like, on the one hand,
Speaker 4:  people think whether or not it's true that it will be disrupted by
Speaker 4:  AI chatbot technology and Microsoft is making that investment and Google
Speaker 4:  cannot replace, like regulators around the world will destroy Google.
Speaker 4:  If Google stops sending traffic to people, scrapes their data into a language
Speaker 4:  model and then starts answering the questions directly. Yeah. I just, I just
Speaker 4:  don't think that's gonna go well for them.
Speaker 1:  Well I think everybody would just also probably frantically start delisting
Speaker 1:  at being all in on duck dot. Go.
Speaker 4:  That's Alex is the new CEO of Duck dot Go everyone,
Speaker 1:  Please invest directly to me. Vindo.
Speaker 4:  And then on the flip side, the AI is being used to flood the search results
Speaker 4:  with garbage. Right? So like, Google's in like a war of
Speaker 4:  attrition against SEO spammers who now have an even cheaper way
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Of filling out their content forms. And then the government's
Speaker 4:  like, also your money is evil. And we want to, and oh, I forgot to say this,
Speaker 4:  the government is asking to break up Google's adtech division. They wanna
Speaker 4:  spin off DoubleClick for publishers in atx, which is their exchange.
Speaker 4:  So like, just imagine being like sunk,
Speaker 4:  right? You're like, on the one hand, I've gotta kill the cash cow and
Speaker 4:  replace it with the technology. We developed our own LLMs Lambda
Speaker 4:  and others. Yeah. Which are superior to Chet, but we haven't released because
Speaker 4:  we have ethical concerns about it. Whoops. But our competitor Microsoft
Speaker 4:  has no such qualms. They're just gonna do it. Meanwhile,
Speaker 4:  our cash cow search is being
Speaker 4:  turned into a worse product by the same chat G P t
Speaker 4:  wielding SEO spammers. Oh. And the government wants to break
Speaker 4:  us up.
Speaker 1:  It's, and it's all kind of of Google's own making too, right?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like Google became so dominant. Everybody is chasing to
Speaker 1:  be on Google, seeking the fastest, easiest way to get a tiny
Speaker 1:  piece of the pie that Google has made itself. Yeah. So like
Speaker 1:  it's kind of its own fault.
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 1:  His success is like what's brought it here, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean this is a very smart company. I think Sun's a great ceo.
Speaker 4:  I I think he's ruthless when he needs to be and he's kind of needs to be,
Speaker 4:  he's very thoughtful. It's whatever. Like
Speaker 1:  He knows how to make money.
Speaker 4:  We've interviewed him many times. Yeah. He's a very thoughtful and considered
Speaker 4:  man. I just am like, his choice is effectively
Speaker 4:  alright, it's everyone on the web, it's
Speaker 4:  governments around the world. It's the Department of Justice. Who am I
Speaker 4:  gonna piss off? Right? Because like whatever move he
Speaker 4:  makes is going to piss off like two of those entities.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I just think that is such a difficult place to be. So they're,
Speaker 4:  like I said, we, there's reporting out that Google is called a code red about
Speaker 4:  chat. G p D, they do have all this AI technology. They have
Speaker 4:  incepted, this meme that Google invented the tea in chat. She p t it
Speaker 4:  stands for transform. It's true. They've demoed it many times. Go back and
Speaker 4:  watch any Google io. Like there's a weird middle segment
Speaker 4:  where sun's like, now I will talk to a fire hydrant as though it's a kitty.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, I know what's going on. But like they, they can do it
Speaker 1:  When they had everybody calling, you could just like ask for it to call and
Speaker 1:  make a reservation
Speaker 4:  For you. I don't think that's, is that
Speaker 1:  Not the same
Speaker 4:  Model? Okay. That's, that's a different conversation. They even demoing the,
Speaker 4:  the transformer large language models and like, I think the
Speaker 4:  last demo was either this past year or the year before, he like asked Pluto
Speaker 4:  if it was a planet. That's right. And Pluto was like kind of sad, you
Speaker 4:  know, I was like, well, here by myself, I don't really know what's going
Speaker 4:  on. But what they are demoing is effectively the same technology as chat
Speaker 4:  G p T. So they have it, they are not releasing it because it's,
Speaker 4:  they've thought until now it is unethical to let people
Speaker 4:  talk to a robot that will confidently lie to them.
Speaker 1:  Yes. And it, it is unethical.
Speaker 1:  Microsoft.
Speaker 4:  Microsoft is like, whatever man. Like we lost at mobile. We lost on the web,
Speaker 4:  we lost it search. We
Speaker 1:  Do. We're we're gonna do
Speaker 4:  Some check, check out his lion robot. We
Speaker 1:  With Bing.
Speaker 5:  But that's, that's the issue that they're running in into now. So they're
Speaker 5:  trying to launch all these AI products. They've got there search issues that
Speaker 5:  you've laid out. But something that, that you've talked about a lot when
Speaker 5:  we talked about these antitrust and these these massive tech companies is
Speaker 5:  that every single thing that they launch isn't big enough to really have
Speaker 5:  any impact on their core product and all the money that it makes. So they
Speaker 5:  can have all these, these new AI things. They can, you know, Sundar, he he
Speaker 5:  can, he can do all
Speaker 4:  Of these. They say they're gonna launch 20 new AI products. None
Speaker 5:  Of them mattered. None of them will replace what he has. Yeah. New York Times,
Speaker 5:  New York Times described all of these products that they are, are going to
Speaker 5:  try to make, they're doing all the AI things that you've heard of that everyone
Speaker 5:  else is doing. Maybe some that we haven't heard of. We're gonna see 'em all
Speaker 5:  at io. But none of them are bigger than advertising. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And and that's the thing that's under direct threat. And it's under the threat
Speaker 4:  threat again in two different No, it's under direct threat in three different
Speaker 4:  ways. Right? Yeah. The demand side of it, we talked to this last week,
Speaker 4:  the demand side of it is people might search TikTok or
Speaker 4:  ask Chat G B T or something else instead. Yeah. Or just search Reddit.
Speaker 4:  The people do that all the time. The supply side of it
Speaker 4:  is futurism, which is also doing a great job reporting on the c ai
Speaker 4:  controversy. They great headline last week. That's like the SEO
Speaker 4:  spammers are thrilled a Google's non-response to CS AI issues. Like,
Speaker 4:  and they're like in the dark web forums and the ISTs spammers are like, light
Speaker 4:  it up boys. Like cuz that is a pure volume game for them,
Speaker 4:  right? You flood the internet with garbage content. You hope that people,
Speaker 4:  you hope it ranks anywhere. You hope you collect some traffic, you show
Speaker 4:  some garbage ads and you take your pennies and you just
Speaker 4:  stack pennies until you've made dollars. And if you
Speaker 4:  can make webpages for nothing with an AI product Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Whew.
Speaker 4:  You can stack those pennies pretty fast. Right. And Google just like needs
Speaker 4:  to have an answer to this. And I don't think that they've arrived at one
Speaker 4:  where they're like, we will preserve the quality of Google search without
Speaker 4:  irritating everyone or compete with chat gbt without irritating everyone.
Speaker 4:  And in the middle of it, to Richard's point, the government's like, you know,
Speaker 4:  the machine that makes money that you're trying to fix, what if we took
Speaker 4:  two-thirds of it away and spun it off into different companies? And I just
Speaker 4:  like, I'm just like looking at this week for Google, I'm like, this is one
Speaker 4:  of the most pivotal weeks for one of like, we talk about the, you know, this
Speaker 4:  set of fan companies like every week we're never like, man, Netflix is having
Speaker 4:  an existential week. We're never, you know, like yeah. We're never like,
Speaker 4:  oh, apple could be five companies tomorrow. Like this is like one of the
Speaker 4:  most consequential existential weeks for Google that I
Speaker 4:  can think of for a big tech company. You a like a long
Speaker 4:  time. We're potentially five years down the line we're looking at this week
Speaker 4:  as like, oh, that was the beginning of a total re-architecting of
Speaker 4:  the web.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I do wonder, I I, you know, I've been knocking on the chat
Speaker 1:  g p t plan to like compete with a, I wonder how much of that plan though
Speaker 1:  is also to figure out how to combat it and, and the
Speaker 1:  spam it creates on Google. Cuz like, if you go and you create a new
Speaker 1:  competitor for it and figure out all the inner workings, you theoretically
Speaker 1:  could like figure out how to highlight it and spot it.
Speaker 4:  I think Casey and platform are spotlighted some of this where he is like
Speaker 4:  Google does have AI detection systems. It
Speaker 4:  can, because it knows the training data sets, it knows what it looks like
Speaker 4:  on the other side. And there's this concept of like radioactive data
Speaker 4:  where you seed the models with some stuff where you know what
Speaker 4:  outputs it will generate and you can detect it even better. We'll see, I,
Speaker 4:  I think we're in the middle of an arm's race for
Speaker 1:  Google. I love it.
Speaker 4:  12,000. It's the first time the company's ever had layoffs of the
Speaker 1:  Scale. Nevermind. I don't love it.
Speaker 4:  I think it's gonna be weird. All right. We gotta take a break. When come
Speaker 4:  back. We talk about Tesla learnings a little lightning round. Some Microsoft
Speaker 4:  in there where we
Speaker 4:  at.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. I don't know why I thought we could get through Tesla
Speaker 4:  and a lightning round in the last segment
Speaker 1:  Here. I believe in us, we're gonna go really fast. We're just gonna accelerate
Speaker 1:  it. Listen to us at three x
Speaker 4:  So we're gonna talk fast and to listen to us at three x,
Speaker 1:  Do a line of coke first. Don't do a line of Coke.
Speaker 1:  This is not an endorsement of cocaine.
Speaker 1:  Sorry.
Speaker 5:  I heard specifically I was
Speaker 5:  told by an executive
Speaker 5:  at this company that I had a a job to
Speaker 5:  do and what else can I do?
Speaker 4:  What's the job doing cocaine.
Speaker 1:  Which exec?
Speaker 5:  All right, it's fun. Was that, was that not, was that not, was that not in
Speaker 5:  your public contract? Because
Speaker 4:  Our start, our startup days are very
Speaker 5:  Negotiated.
Speaker 4:  There was a time,
Speaker 1:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Again, that this was the time when we were doing the video
Speaker 4:  vergecast the last time, like I said,
Speaker 4:  karmic debt. We are just immediately running up the bill again. Just
Speaker 4:  you turn the cameras on, Alex is like, here's what you should do. Kids
Speaker 1:  Go on.
Speaker 4:  All right. We do have to get through this. Please just don't tell
Speaker 4:  your parents about that.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, don't do that. It's
Speaker 4:  Bad. Just don't let him know any of that happened. All right. Lots
Speaker 4:  of Tesla, Tesla earnings. Elon's on trial for
Speaker 4:  the four 20, for
Speaker 1:  The four 20 tweet. Finally back.
Speaker 4:  He's very upset about being on trial. Yeah. He's attacked
Speaker 4:  the, the plaintiff's, he's attacked the plaintiff's lawyer several times.
Speaker 4:  Oof. The, it's a class action. It's a group
Speaker 4:  of investors who feel that they lost money because Elon
Speaker 4:  tweeted taking Tesla private at four 20 as share funding secured,
Speaker 1:  Which was a thing that the s e C was also like. No.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The judge has instructed the jury in this case
Speaker 4:  to proceed knowing the tweet was a
Speaker 4:  lie. So like Elon's on his back foot and so he is in
Speaker 4:  the courtroom. He is taken the stand. We've been covering it, but he's
Speaker 4:  basically said to the plaintiff's lawyer like, you don't represent my actual
Speaker 4:  investors. Yeah, you're just, you're just like a vulture. Which is very funny.
Speaker 4:  The judge got mad at him. He said that
Speaker 4:  he knows that he's popular because he has so many Twitter
Speaker 4:  followers. Oh, buddy, that's tough. That's a tough one. Who
Speaker 4:  just, I would say he's complained of back pain. Yeah. So just a very
Speaker 4:  rough week.
Speaker 1:  He did say the four 20 tweet was not about anything
Speaker 1:  in particular as well.
Speaker 4:  Oh, he said it was not, he said it wasn't a weed joke. He said it was a real
Speaker 4:  number that was a 20% premium over the share price.
Speaker 4:  Sure. For which again, he was castigated by the judge because the judge was
Speaker 4:  like, but the treat was a lie. It's a lot. So he's been on the stand. There's
Speaker 4:  a lot of coverage there. Obviously that trial is mostly mechanical about
Speaker 4:  injury to these shareholders. But Elon's on witness stand,
Speaker 4:  we're not gonna not
Speaker 1:  Cover it. We're gonna, we're gonna watch it.
Speaker 4:  So that's happening At the same time. Tesla had earnings. Richard earnings
Speaker 4:  did pretty well.
Speaker 5:  They actually made more money in 2022 than they ever did before. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  So it, it's amazing the way that we talk about the chaos, the way
Speaker 5:  that his focus on Twitter may have taken away from Tesla or, or any number
Speaker 5:  of other things. Tesla is still making money. They are still making more
Speaker 5:  cars than they, than they did before. They are relying less on those
Speaker 5:  credits that they sell to other companies for revenue. They are acting like
Speaker 5:  an actual car company. Amazing building vehicles that people buy.
Speaker 5:  They showed off the semifinal, the cyber truck will arrive.
Speaker 4:  So, so they, they pushed 2024. They pushed the cyber truck. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They said, you know, the factory construction's underway. This is on the
Speaker 4:  earnings call. No update on the windshield wiper
Speaker 4:  situation. Zero. I swear to God they're still working on the cyber trucks
Speaker 1:  Wipe. That's what told to get back.
Speaker 4:  It's three wipers in a circle. I will accept no other
Speaker 4:  answer.
Speaker 1:  Just gonna get super high. They
Speaker 4:  Have, they have not solved this problem. Yeah. I guarantee you they have
Speaker 4:  not solved this problem. It's, it's the, it's amazing. But cyber
Speaker 4:  truck's still vaporware, but they lowered the price of the three and the
Speaker 4:  y sales skyrocketed.
Speaker 5:  They say they have a new platform coming that they're going to show at their
Speaker 5:  investor day. So they're, they're
Speaker 4:  Stuff, yeah. So Tesla's moving, obviously he got some questions, questions
Speaker 4:  about Twitter. He again said that he
Speaker 4:  didn't think Twitter was a distraction. Woo. That it's a good marketing channel
Speaker 4:  for Tesla. Look at my followers. Yeah. I don't know
Speaker 4:  man. At the same time, Twitter has run
Speaker 4:  just face first into what I might
Speaker 4:  be so bold is to call a predictable welcome to hell
Speaker 4:  situation in which the government of India,
Speaker 4:  the, the MOI administration in India is very upset about a
Speaker 4:  BBC documentary that looks at riots instead of Gora
Speaker 4:  Hindu versus Muslim riots. They're very, very bad and basically places
Speaker 4:  a lot of the blame for these riots with the current prime minister of Indian
Speaker 4:  Miranda Modi. This is like not a surprise to anyone that
Speaker 4:  like he was an inciting factor in these riots or that he,
Speaker 4:  he allowed it to happen. Like he's a handy nationalist. That's what this
Speaker 4:  party has done for this happened in 2014. Yeah. This has been the accusation
Speaker 4:  all along. BBC just made a documentary about it. If you weren't interested
Speaker 4:  in such thing, you should have watched the ary Government of India has
Speaker 4:  strict censorship laws like super strict censorship laws.
Speaker 4:  They require social media companies to have national
Speaker 4:  offices staffed by locals so that they can threaten to arrest
Speaker 4:  those locals if you do not comply with their censorship laws.
Speaker 1:  Well, I don't wanna work.
Speaker 4:  You do not want, yeah. This is like, and this is like one of those things
Speaker 4:  where you can claim to be a free speech warrior. You are going to end
Speaker 4:  up asking yourself if you would like to do business in India,
Speaker 4:  one of the largest countries in the world. And if you do want to
Speaker 4:  do business in India, you have to staff an office full of potential
Speaker 4:  hostages for the Indian government to take if you do not comply with their
Speaker 4:  censorship demands. Ooh, real problem. Yeah. So India sees this
Speaker 4:  documentary again, produced by the bbc, have many opinions about the bbc,
Speaker 4:  but you know, they at least attempt to be journalistically rigorous. It says
Speaker 4:  a thing that people have been saying for a long time. They hate it. Right.
Speaker 4:  This attacks the government of India. This is not respectful of whatever
Speaker 4:  the justification, take it down. YouTube,
Speaker 4:  Twitter, internet archive, remove your links to
Speaker 4:  this thing. So YouTube caves, which is
Speaker 4:  unsurprising, right? For YouTube. They have the office there,
Speaker 4:  they do it. This is their stance, right? This like tight rope balancing
Speaker 4:  act that all the big platforms have done. Where do we comply? Where do we
Speaker 4:  stand up for users? All right, we're taking this one out. We're not serving
Speaker 4:  in an India, you can get it here, but in India you don't get see it. By the
Speaker 4:  way, Indian YouTube flooded with Indians talking about the video that was
Speaker 4:  removed. Did this work? Who knows
Speaker 1:  VPNs exist.
Speaker 4:  Strat Effect was this a, does this, does censorship work on the internet?
Speaker 4:  Who knows? Yeah. That's what, that's what YouTube does. And on balance, right?
Speaker 4:  YouTube is like, they have a lot of lawyers, you have a lot of Google policy
Speaker 4:  people were like actively arguing set. Twitter just takes down and it's like,
Speaker 4:  does Twitter have a policy team anymore? Do they know that the government
Speaker 4:  ideas removing links to a BBC documentary, do they know that their
Speaker 4:  owner is like Elon Musk who's like, I believe in free speech. I'm a,
Speaker 4:  I'm a free speech absolutist. I don't know. People ask Elon
Speaker 4:  about it. He's like, I can't keep on top of everything all the time.
Speaker 1:  No,
Speaker 4:  I mean, I mean this is it, right? If like you are against government censorship.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  These are the fights that you are going to have.
Speaker 1:  Like this is a core fight for someone who says they are very much against
Speaker 1:  government censorship.
Speaker 4:  So Eddie Peace, you should read it. Her point is, Elon has always said,
Speaker 4:  I don't think companies should censor. If the people want things censored,
Speaker 4:  they should pass a law. So that is just open support
Speaker 4:  of government censorship. Yep. I don't think the people of India have voted
Speaker 4:  on a law remove this documentary, but that's where we're at is this
Speaker 4:  extremely fine tight rope walk
Speaker 4:  of what it actually means to support free speech against the actual threat
Speaker 4:  to free speech, which is government censorship. Yeah. And I, I
Speaker 4:  think Elon, I think he's like back on the Tesla SpaceX trip. He's over the
Speaker 4:  Twitter adventure and it's just gonna get worse. Richard, do you wanna
Speaker 4:  say something?
Speaker 5:  Well, I just wanted to know, you know, if, if you support free speech, if
Speaker 5:  anyone does support free speech, why didn't they spend 44 billion on a social
Speaker 5:  network that no one wanted about? That's, that's just what a real
Speaker 5:  free speech supporter would've done. Like Elon Musk who
Speaker 5:  does support free speech for people who have 44 billion and
Speaker 5:  don't piss off the government's in countries that they wanted to visit. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I mean, again, I think that I should be made king of Twitter, Elon Phil
Speaker 4:  listening. I'll do it. It'll be, it'll be expensive.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's the title that I demand. I like it. King of Twitter. It'll be
Speaker 4:  spendy. Yeah. Giant
Speaker 1:  Cheap. Oh no, they're not public. I was gonna be like, do you go to earnings
Speaker 1:  calls? But you wouldn't have to because you're the king of Twitter.
Speaker 4:  There's one earnings call you have to go to and it will be extremely
Speaker 4:  annoying audience of
Speaker 4:  one. We'll see, I'm just saying like Tesla's back
Speaker 4:  on track, they need new cars. They're facing an
Speaker 4:  onslaught of competition this year. Most of those cars are still vaporware.
Speaker 4:  Like can you get an F-150 Lightning? No, you cannot. No. Can you get a Rivian?
Speaker 4:  No, you cannot. Can
Speaker 1:  You get a cyber truck?
Speaker 4:  Fair enough. No. Can you get a Cadillac lyric? No you cannot.
Speaker 4:  Like the competition is coming as a, as a drum that has
Speaker 4:  been beaten but the cars are not shipping. Yeah. Once
Speaker 4:  they start shipping, once the ad dollars flow through Google's
Speaker 4:  ecosystem, I think Tesla is gonna have to
Speaker 4:  like figure out what to do. But what they know they can do right now is
Speaker 4:  there's got a lower prices. Yeah. People are just gonna show up. And
Speaker 4:  I think I'm excited for actual competition in the EV market. I think that'll
Speaker 4:  be good. But the moment Elon has to turn his attention back
Speaker 4:  to governments around the world want to censor Twitter and
Speaker 4:  it's like, what do you thinks a powder keg
Speaker 1:  Wants? Because he doesn't wanna really turn there. He's already said if you
Speaker 1:  make a law and, and we we're just gonna abide by that law. So if the government
Speaker 1:  comes to us and says take it down, we're gonna take it down.
Speaker 4:  Except, but if the United States government does that, he gets real mad because
Speaker 1:  The First Amendment, he
Speaker 4:  Doesn't care about that.
Speaker 1:  I know, that's what I'm saying is like he's got that so he doesn't wanna
Speaker 1:  take anything down in America. Right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I dunno. But he wants to make it the safest place in the world for
Speaker 4:  advertisers. Like he, it's,
Speaker 1:  It's, yeah, he,
Speaker 4:  When I say this is a welcome to hell problem, this is like
Speaker 1:  None of it makes sense.
Speaker 4:  The other social networks, you know that Financial Times set up a massives.
Speaker 4:  Everyone wants us to set up a massive incense. By the way, thank you to the
Speaker 4:  one VER has listener who just went off and did it. Yes. And like
Speaker 4:  beat our own teams to study up a NASA instance with activity pub
Speaker 4:  with Hatch, which has quick posts in it. Like very good.
Speaker 4:  Congratulations. Potentially an IP issue. But for
Speaker 4:  now I've just, I'm overlooking it. It's great. I love it. Thank you so
Speaker 4:  much.
Speaker 1:  Really excited for you to talk about that in the court case in six months.
Speaker 1:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  If, if this is opposing counsel's attorney, I didn't
Speaker 4:  mean it. I'm not Neil a Patel. This is a deep fake, you can tell because
Speaker 4:  I'm looking directly into the camera.
Speaker 4:  Hmm. I'm not me
Speaker 4:  right now. A deep fake is saying this in Spanish. Who knows what's
Speaker 4:  happening. The financial time set up a mask on server. Do you
Speaker 4:  see this? Yeah. They took it down. They're like, this is too
Speaker 1:  Hard. No, it's too much.
Speaker 4:  They're like the escalating legal server costs are too much.
Speaker 4:  We don't want to do this anymore.
Speaker 1:  You said server costs, you have to be like, oh I can now see everyone's dms.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like we don't, we don't want this in our lives. Very good. Microsoft
Speaker 4:  outside earnings. What's going on Microsoft?
Speaker 1:  Not, not good. Good news. Pretty bad news at
Speaker 1:  Microsoft. And
Speaker 4:  Can I use it Intel too?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I think there is a theme here, which is that everybody bought their
Speaker 1:  laptops and computers in 2020 and 2021 and they didn't buy any in
Speaker 1:  2022, especially at the end of the year.
Speaker 1:  So Microsoft's earnings were really down across all hardware. So that means
Speaker 1:  Windows, the OEMs, they're not selling enough to the OEMs cuz the
Speaker 1:  OEMs aren't selling enough laptops. They're not selling
Speaker 1:  surfaces cuz nobody wants to buy them. They're not selling
Speaker 1:  boxes. Which was kind of an interesting one. Their, their cloud's
Speaker 1:  holding strong. Azure is, is doing great. That's where they're putting a
Speaker 1:  lot of their investments. And I think we saw also with their layoffs, their
Speaker 1:  layoffs really particularly hit hard. A lot of those hardware divisions,
Speaker 1:  a lot of those places that are based in you owning the device
Speaker 1:  and using all of it. So if you like
Speaker 1:  that,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Microsoft's turning away from
Speaker 1:  You. They don't care about you. I mean they probably still care about you.
Speaker 1:  They still have the business. They're not gonna get
Speaker 4:  Rid of this. They're gonna put edge icons in your desktop to try to get you
Speaker 4:  into some Microsoft services.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But it was, it was not good times for Microsoft. And we saw
Speaker 1:  the same thing with Intel. Intel. Again, they're stuffed down. Chips are
Speaker 1:  down because nobody is buying the laptops to put the chips in. So none of
Speaker 1:  the laptop bakers are buying the chips. And the GPU business is real
Speaker 1:  down. To be fair, there's only like one GPU
Speaker 1:  too. There's not that many Gs at Intel. So this is not a
Speaker 1:  shock. Intel is also anticipating a 40% drop
Speaker 1:  year over year. Next quarter. Not good. Not
Speaker 1:  good. So Intel is in trouble. They knew they were in trouble. They, they
Speaker 1:  they've been anticipating this unlike a lot of the other companies. They
Speaker 1:  still miss a lot of their forecasts, right? Yeah. They, they didn't hit any
Speaker 1:  of, of their marks, but they also were like, it's not gonna be good. And
Speaker 1:  it wasn't good And they're like, it's gonna be even worse and it's gonna
Speaker 1:  be even worse. And I think they're really looking towards when they get these
Speaker 1:  fabs up in what, 2024 I think is when the first one's supposed to come online
Speaker 1:  in Ohio. Yeah. So they're like them in the in in Tesla. They're
Speaker 1:  like, just, just wait. So worry about 2027.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna back the cyber truck right up to our new fab. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 4:  Roll out some three nanometer chips. Send directly to amd.
Speaker 4:  We'll see, I mean, again, the, the theme of these sec layouts and you really
Speaker 4:  should read Liz's piece. All of them are like, we just thought the pandemic
Speaker 4:  would last forever. Yeah. We just thought people would buy a new laptop every
Speaker 4:  year. And it's like when why did you think that? It's like, it's like the
Speaker 4:  best example I can give is like the whole TV industry thought 3D TV would
Speaker 4:  work and last forever. Yes. And it's like guys,
Speaker 1:  James Cameron still thinks that by the
Speaker 1:  way,
Speaker 4:  Some, the lightning round stuff. It was the big Taylor Swift Ticketmaster
Speaker 4:  hearing.
Speaker 1:  T Swift was not there.
Speaker 4:  I but you. They all, she was there.
Speaker 1:  She was there Spirit
Speaker 4:  That every center quoted.
Speaker 5:  She was there in every senator's comments where their interns or whoever
Speaker 5:  had written in Taylor Swift lyrics.
Speaker 4:  It's good. We've got a big decoder episode about Ticketmaster Monopoly
Speaker 4:  coming. It's another text stack.
Speaker 1:  We we're gonna allow you to, to plug decoder just this once because
Speaker 1:  just
Speaker 4:  This one. I'm just saying it's coming. I'm excited about it. We were waiting
Speaker 4:  for this hearing cause we want, and I was like, now all I got is a bunch
Speaker 4:  of like old senators saying Taylor Swift, like what did I get outta this?
Speaker 4:  That's gonna be good. Golden eye remaster coming to Nintendo. Switch
Speaker 4:  an Xbox.
Speaker 1:  We're gonna, the big fight for Golden Eye is gonna be who gets to play odd
Speaker 1:  job when we all play together.
Speaker 4:  Should we do a Vergecast?
Speaker 1:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  With an ice stream?
Speaker 1:  I'm real bad at it. It's gonna be
Speaker 4:  Great. Whenever, whenever David comes back from his break, he had a baby.
Speaker 4:  He's, he's on break. You should take care of the baby.
Speaker 1:  No, we're just giving him time all but David can't have all this
Speaker 1:  time to practice.
Speaker 4:  He's got a baby. He's not practicing.
Speaker 1:  He's practicing with like one hand. He's holding that baby. He's got him
Speaker 1:  in the little pom. It's great.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Okay. I mean, you know, there's, there's four of us, of us. Yeah. We're
Speaker 4:  by the way, it has local split screen multiplayer, which is like what I really
Speaker 4:  want. Perfect. It's gonna be great. Very excited about that. TikTok has
Speaker 4:  confirmed now after reporting in Forbes that I can just
Speaker 4:  make videos go viral whenever it won.
Speaker 1:  Shock. I'm just shocked by this news.
Speaker 4:  Back in the Facebook video era, we would joke that Mark Zuckerberg just had
Speaker 4:  a knob and you just like, turn it up. TikTok s Yeah we bought, we have that
Speaker 4:  knob and you can pay us to turn it whenever you want.
Speaker 5:  Just press the button. Just press the button.
Speaker 4:  I feel like the TikTok balloon is gonna pop that story in Forbes.
Speaker 1:  That's why the one video that really pops for us is
Speaker 1:  they're like, oh, ver got it wrong.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Crank it.
Speaker 5:  I feel certain that TikTok is not actually an AI feed. It's just
Speaker 5:  That's that's the one that's It's just some dude
Speaker 1:  That's all
Speaker 5:  It's, there's like 25
Speaker 4:  Players. You could
Speaker 5:  Be on one. There's just some Dude Casey case III is back
Speaker 5:  there dropping videos in the playlists and that's all it is. And we're gonna
Speaker 5:  find out that all this time there was no
Speaker 4:  Ai. I'm very excited for that. Go read that story. It's actually really interesting
Speaker 4:  cause TikTok is so embedded in the music industry. There's just a lot of
Speaker 4:  pay to play to break a song on TikTok right now, which is fascinating. And
Speaker 4:  then we gotta, we gotta end here Alex. It's a downer.
Speaker 1:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  But it's the Verge. We have sand with Peacock,
Speaker 4:  Comcast head earnings. Comcast as you
Speaker 4:  know, N B C U division. Minority investor in V Media, the versus parent
Speaker 4:  company. There's your disclosure. That was good. What's going on with
Speaker 1:  Peacock? So peacock. It's, it's
Speaker 1:  not doing great. I truly believe that poker face is gonna
Speaker 1:  save it. Yeah. If you watch the show with Natasha Leon, I
Speaker 4:  Almost, it's not out yet.
Speaker 1:  It just came
Speaker 4:  Out. It's out today.
Speaker 1:  It's out today. Some of us got to watch a little bit of it early. Oh I see.
Speaker 1:  I swear I didn't watch. Some of us are in the right
Speaker 4:  Eastern good screeners. This is what I just learned.
Speaker 1:  It was great. Highly, highly recommend it. But yeah, they, they,
Speaker 1:  Comcast overall NBCUniversal overall did face big losses.
Speaker 1:  Peacock just recently surpassed a really big number for them.
Speaker 1:  Guess how many subscribers? Six 20 million.
Speaker 4:  Hey, that's pretty good.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's is it? What is it a 10th
Speaker 1:  of what Netflix
Speaker 4:  Is doing? I was just saying it's more subscribers than I have.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  Subscribe to my CK everyone. I don't, I don't have
Speaker 4:  one of those. I didn't even have a Twitter anymore. What am I doing?
Speaker 1:  Yeah, so, so it's, it's taking losses and it's a loss
Speaker 1:  on the Comcast balance sheet. I think we've always said in the go 90 scale
Speaker 1:  where the zero means they're alive and the 90 means they're,
Speaker 1:  they're boot doomed. This is now like a 70 to 80.
Speaker 4:  Wow. You're gonna always 70 80.
Speaker 1:  I I think so. I think Peacock probably has the best chance of being
Speaker 1:  the first big broadcast streamer that goes actually this is not
Speaker 1:  for us. And they sell. I don't know what they're gonna do though because
Speaker 5:  Alright, are you sure they'll do that? Or that they'll try and buy some other
Speaker 5:  streamer that is
Speaker 1:  Also cool. They're not gonna buy Paramount. Cuz Paramount has been like in
Speaker 1:  this, we're doing it by ourselves thing before anybody else did.
Speaker 4:  And and they have the Yellowstone verse.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, they got the, they got the 23. Oh my God.
Speaker 1:  1923 is so good. You
Speaker 4:  Know what, every single year of American history people in Montana have shot
Speaker 1:  Each other with Tommy
Speaker 1:  Gun.
Speaker 4:  That show, we have been watching that show It's Yellowstone. Yellowstone
Speaker 4:  proper.
Speaker 1:  The, yeah,
Speaker 4:  Okay. The conceit. I dunno, this is crazy talking about Ro chest. It's just,
Speaker 4:  if you think about that show is having the lawyer's
Speaker 4:  son, the business daughter and then the Call of Duty son.
Speaker 4:  It just like locks into place. You're like, all right, we need to have a
Speaker 4:  Call of Duty cut seat in the middle of this episode. And it's just always
Speaker 4:  happens.
Speaker 1:  It's so like the most compelling thing. Is it good tv?
Speaker 1:  I
Speaker 4:  Don't know. Yeah. I mean we've been watching. It's very
Speaker 1:  Entertaining.
Speaker 4:  But yeah, there's like, oh the cut scene is here
Speaker 1:  Despite my Yeah, look at it. They're on horses.
Speaker 4:  They introduce characters just for the Call of Duty son to murder
Speaker 4:  them. It's like very, you're like, oh, that motherfucker's gonna die. But
Speaker 1:  He's sad about it. He's sad about it. He feels, he feels, feels grief.
Speaker 4:  No, I think actually by season four he is like, this is what I do.
Speaker 1:  I just kill.
Speaker 4:  Anyway, but that's Peacock had, that's what Peacock had going for. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Peacock. Peacock And the first four Seasons,
Speaker 1:  It's got the first four
Speaker 4:  Seasons and now it's Paramount Plus.
Speaker 1:  Paramount Plus has all of the adjacent shows. So it's got the, the fancy
Speaker 1:  one with Harrison Ford. It's got the Sylvester Stallone one where
Speaker 1:  he goes to Oklahoma to start a
Speaker 1:  mob. It's him and like Martin
Speaker 1:  Starr just out there mobing
Speaker 4:  Up. That's I'll take it. I love it. It's great. I wanna watch 'em all. See
Speaker 4:  that's, that's why Peacock won Pie Paramount
Speaker 1:  Plus. Yeah. They, they, they can't afford it.
Speaker 4:  They're all in on the Taylor verse.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So, so Peacock is not doing great. It has not had any hits.
Speaker 1:  It's still hoping poker face, like it's put a lot of, of time and energy
Speaker 1:  into making poker face a thing. This is the new show with Natasha Leon. It
Speaker 1:  comes from Ryan Johnson who did Knives Out and the Star Wars movies and stuff
Speaker 1:  like that. So they're
Speaker 4:  Really Ryan Johnson a Verge fan. Yeah. Yeah. In fact The Verge
Speaker 4:  makes a cameo and knives. That too.
Speaker 1:  That's true. It did. Yeah. I screamed, I was with my mom and I was like,
Speaker 1:  see I have a job.
Speaker 4:  I looked at my 17 year old niece nephew and said, that's cool. Right? And
Speaker 4:  they're like, it was cool.
Speaker 1:  My mom did. She was like, it's fine.
Speaker 1:  Cigarette. So yeah, peacock not
Speaker 1:  doing great. I, I'll be surprised if it lasts. And, and and I think
Speaker 1:  the big concern though, if something happens to the Peacock, what happens
Speaker 1:  to shows like Poker Face, which is a legitimately great show. It's super,
Speaker 1:  super entertaining. But 20 million people max are
Speaker 1:  gonna be watching it cuz that's how many people have
Speaker 4:  Subscribed. Well, we're trying to get more people.
Speaker 1:  We'll see. Yeah. So we'll see. We'll see. Right.
Speaker 4:  But you're putting at 70 to
Speaker 1:  80 on the I'm at 70 to 80.
Speaker 4:  Wow. All right. Big call from Alex Kranz.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Sorry guys. Peacock
Speaker 4:  70 to 80 on the go. 90 scale of June streaming services. Let us know what
Speaker 4:  you think of Peacock and it's rating on the Go 90 Scale. You can tweet it
Speaker 4:  out. She's Alex h Cranz.
Speaker 1:  Wow. Thanks.
Speaker 4:  Tweet At Richard, he's at RJ ccc. Monica is at
Speaker 4:  mc squared. 96. I'm at Reckless. I do
Speaker 4:  check it like once a day and just like all the tweets. Yeah. So if you wanna
Speaker 4:  get a light, you can still tweet at me. It'll just be delayed from what's
Speaker 4:  happening. I'm trying to be off a feeds-based media for a little bit.
Speaker 4:  It's nice. Do you feel like I'm rewiring my brain? I have read a lot of magazines
Speaker 4:  on pdf. God bless. Do you have that? New editor-in-Chief of Sound
Speaker 4:  Vision is an Xav s Forum poster. That's great. Like that's where we are in
Speaker 4:  like the media cycle. Perfect. We're like the hardcore forum posters. So
Speaker 4:  now the editors in chief of like the legendary stereo.
Speaker 1:  How how many, how many staff came from the Verge came from the Verge worms.
Speaker 4:  A surprising amount
Speaker 1:  Actually. Yeah, it's a good
Speaker 4:  Path. I mean I came from the in gadget comments.
Speaker 1:  I love
Speaker 4:  This pretty good. Don't look up those comments. I presumably anyone has
Speaker 4:  deleted them all. You're
Speaker 1:  Good. Please don't,
Speaker 4:  It's all gonna be fine. Wednesday show what's going on the Wednesday
Speaker 1:  Show. So on the Wednesday show I'm talking to Sean Hollister about the steam
Speaker 1:  deck.
Speaker 4:  Shawn wants to talk about.
Speaker 1:  We almost got Liam to, we almost bullied him into buying one. It was great.
Speaker 1:  I'm also talking with Catherine Chin DeCosta about faking your own death
Speaker 1:  online. Surprisingly common just recently happened with a, a romance novelist.
Speaker 1:  Created a whole bunch of yeah. Conversations. And then,
Speaker 1:  I don't know if I can talk about this last one yet, but we're gonna have
Speaker 1:  a, a really special one coming up next week as well. So you gotta stay tuned
Speaker 1:  and tell then to hear it cuz it's gonna be really good and exciting. But
Speaker 1:  I can't talk about it right now. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 4:  All right. You can call The Verge has Hotline. Eight sixty six Verge
Speaker 4:  11. Here's what I'll tell you about listener and how viewer
Speaker 4:  feedback Last week on the show, I was like, special audio sucks. Usually
Speaker 4:  I say anything is bad. A flurry of responses.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  One, one person tweeted and I was like, I don't know. It might be
Speaker 4:  good. That's how I know, that's how I know it sucks.
Speaker 1:  It's,
Speaker 4:  But
Speaker 1:  If you are that one person, 8 66 Verge 11,
Speaker 4:  I'm asking for the call.
Speaker 1:  Call him.
Speaker 4:  Call.
Speaker 1:  Just call me on. That's his number.
Speaker 4:  All right. That's the Verge has, thank you for listening in your car. If
Speaker 4:  you're watching this for the first time in years, we're so sorry. We just
Speaker 1:  We're not, hi,
Speaker 4:  We're not. Go home and do your cocaine. That's it. That's the verge cast,
Speaker 4:  rock and
Speaker 4:  roll.
Speaker 7:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 7:  the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend, you
Speaker 7:  can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is produced
Speaker 7:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. This
Speaker 7:  episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith. Our
Speaker 7:  editorial director is Brooke Min and our executive producer is Eleanor
Speaker 7:  Donovan. The Verge Cast is a production of the Verge and Box Media
Speaker 7:  podcast network. And that's it. We'll see you next
Speaker 7:  week.