# Transcript
ID: 338eb20b-c6b0-4b39-8dab-5c497bf3747f
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The better, smarter future of messaging
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-1205434968983134514/-2000422927465606528/s93290-US-3305s-1697451350.mp3
Description: In episode two of our connectivity mini series, The Verge's David Pierce chats with Eric Migicovsky co-founder of Beeper. Beeper is a universal messaging app trying to take all your messages from all your apps and put them in one place. Is this the future of chat?
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (4 ads detected)
Speaker 3:  Welcome. To. The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of interoperable messaging
Speaker 3:  protocols. I'm your friend David Pierce, and this is the second episode in
Speaker 3:  our miniseries all about connectivity. Last week we talked to tele c
Speaker 3:  e o, Ilia Posen about how we interact with our TVs, the biggest
Speaker 3:  screens in our house, and how we connect to the content that we care about.
Speaker 3:  This week we're gonna talk about people. I think the best way I can explain
Speaker 3:  the conversation we're about to have is to tell you a story about my wife.
Speaker 3:  This happened just the other day. I swear this is true. It was the most perfect
Speaker 3:  timing. So I'm in the living room, sitting on the couch watching tv, and
Speaker 3:  my wife Anna comes in and is like, I hate so much when somebody
Speaker 3:  makes you download a whole new app. Just to group chat. Turns out she
Speaker 3:  joined this mom's group and the person organizing everything made her download
Speaker 3:  GroupMe, which you might remember as the messaging app Microsoft bought a
Speaker 3:  bunch of years ago and then like forgot about, she had never heard of GroupMe,
Speaker 3:  didn't want to use GroupMe, and now she had to have it on her phone just
Speaker 3:  for this one group chat. She was standing there like, why can't
Speaker 3:  messaging apps just work together? So I can talk to everyone in one place.
Speaker 3:  And, what I said to her is, listen to The Vergecast, because that right
Speaker 3:  there is what today's episode is all about. How did we get to the point
Speaker 3:  where talking to my friends requires a half dozen apps and I have to check
Speaker 3:  10 inboxes every day and I have to have this mental map of
Speaker 3:  who I talk to in WhatsApp and who I talk to in iMessage and who I talk to
Speaker 3:  in Instagram dms and on and on and on. It's awful.
Speaker 3:  And before you messaged me saying, David, this is because America is dumb.
Speaker 3:  Everyone else in the world is just on WhatsApp. Two things, one I
Speaker 3:  know and I'm deeply jealous. And two, I don't think
Speaker 3:  that's actually a good answer either. We shouldn't all be on one
Speaker 3:  platform. There are lots of these platforms and systems out there. Shouldn't
Speaker 3:  they all work together like the web or like email? I kind of think it
Speaker 3:  should, and the person I'm talking with today absolutely thinks it should.
Speaker 4:  My full name is Eric. Migicovsky
Speaker 3:  Eric is the co-founder and c e o of Beeper, a new-ish universal
Speaker 3:  messaging app. Beeper's big idea is to take all your messages from
Speaker 3:  all of your apps, Twitter, LinkedIn, iMessage, slack, a bunch of
Speaker 3:  other places, and put them all in one place. I've been a Beeper user for
Speaker 3:  a couple of years now and the app is definitely still new and definitely
Speaker 3:  kind of hacky, but this also feels like the way things
Speaker 3:  obviously should work. One place for all your communications
Speaker 3:  that just makes sense. So why doesn't it work like that and can we get
Speaker 3:  this sprawling, messy chat ecosystem back to a place that
Speaker 3:  makes sense? That's kind of my big question going into this.
Speaker 3:  The first thing you need to know about Eric is that before he started Beeper,
Speaker 3:  he was the founder of Pebble, one of the early smartwatch companies and one
Speaker 3:  of the more interesting and beloved hardware startups, I think ever So I
Speaker 3:  figured You know you're making a smart watch, you're thinking about chat
Speaker 3:  and notifications, so suddenly messaging gets stuck in your brain. That's
Speaker 3:  where I assumed this story started, but Eric said no, it actually goes
Speaker 3:  back much, much farther than that.
Speaker 4:  I think that because of my era, like when I started to use
Speaker 4:  chat and when I started to use the internet, I associated a lot of my
Speaker 4:  experiences of You know being online, finding
Speaker 4:  groups of friends, hanging out with my friends. Like we just, we hung out
Speaker 4:  on M S N after school, you'd You know Fire up the modem
Speaker 4:  or D S L or whatever you had and you'd hang out and you'd do homework and
Speaker 4:  you'd wait for, well, actually it probably even goes back to I C Q
Speaker 4:  that that uhoh, remember that sound? Uhoh?
Speaker 3:  Of course it
Speaker 4:  Was addictive because it, it was a reminder that there was someone who was
Speaker 4:  You know pinging you and wanted to chat. Got to the point where my dad could
Speaker 4:  actually emulate the Uhoh sound and cause me to drop whatever
Speaker 4:  I was doing in the house and just like run, run back to my computer because
Speaker 4:  I needed to get there before he or anyone else in the family did. Because
Speaker 4:  You know shared computers.
Speaker 3:  Yep. That was back in the days of the computer room.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And so my experience with chat is kind of
Speaker 4:  foundational to computing. Like every device that I pick up,
Speaker 4:  I use it to chat with friends and I have, I think like
Speaker 4:  I've benchmarked myself against other folks and, and I can kind of see how
Speaker 4:  my chat patterns. Like I, I spend a lot of the day chatting. I have, I, I
Speaker 4:  grew up in Canada, I've lived in Europe, I've lived in Asia, I now live in
Speaker 4:  California. I have collected friends and family members
Speaker 4:  on every single chat app in existence. And for
Speaker 4:  some crazy reason, each place around the world kind of
Speaker 4:  has a different chat app as their primary means of communication. So I've
Speaker 4:  collected friends, You know two or three people on every single app.
Speaker 4:  And yeah, this is obviously all leading towards starting Beeper, but in the
Speaker 4:  last You know, 10 years, there really hasn't been
Speaker 4:  a single app that you can use to chat with all of your friends.
Speaker 4:  We were forced to download five to 10 different apps.
Speaker 4:  Even if you just wanted to, to message like one person and every computer
Speaker 4:  you'd have, you'd have to install all these, all these apps and it just
Speaker 4:  got to be more annoying. Like it felt like communication, like we live in
Speaker 4:  the future. You know, I just tried out chat G B T for the image
Speaker 4:  recognition one. It's, it's crazy. It's wild. Yeah. Like we literally are
Speaker 4:  living in the future, but for some reason the experience of
Speaker 4:  chatting is still stuck in like 15 years ago.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Why do you think that is? Actually, I've, I've spent some time looking
Speaker 3:  into this and I, I've heard a lot of people blame a lot of things. Like
Speaker 3:  we had that era of Adio and Trillian and this idea of
Speaker 3:  messaging that worked kind of like email, right? Where you could have an
Speaker 3:  account on a bunch of different platforms, but all these platforms more or
Speaker 3:  less could talk to each other. It wasn't always perfect, but it kind of
Speaker 3:  worked and you could at least have an app that had all the platforms in one
Speaker 3:  place, even if they weren't talking to each other, you could at least have
Speaker 3:  them all in one place. And then that broke. And I've talked to people who
Speaker 3:  blame Facebook, I've talked to people who blame Google. I've talked to people
Speaker 3:  who say, well, it was just never gonna work that way forever. What's your
Speaker 3:  sense of what led us down kind of that wrong
Speaker 3:  siloed path we've been on for the last decade?
Speaker 4:  I think there's a couple things at play here. One is the shift to
Speaker 4:  mobile. 2007, the iPhone came out and that changed everything.
Speaker 4:  Everything that had existed on the internet before was based
Speaker 4:  on long running socket connections to a central server
Speaker 4:  or You know, a P two P style Torrent You know
Speaker 4:  distributed mesh network. But both of those models
Speaker 4:  required kind of cheap access to the internet
Speaker 3:  In a way that they were perfectly suited to the like always on computer room,
Speaker 3:  right? Like that was yes, that it was exactly right for that device that
Speaker 3:  just sits there in the background kind of on all the time. I had never thought
Speaker 3:  of it like that.
Speaker 4:  I R C doesn't actually have, like when you log into an I R
Speaker 4:  C server, you don't get any history. You have to have your I R C
Speaker 4:  client running 24 7 in order to be able to see what was
Speaker 4:  happening in the scroll back. So that's just like an indicator of how
Speaker 4:  little the world was set up for, or the, the kind of internet as a whole
Speaker 4:  was set up for this big shift to mobile. And so with the shift to mobile,
Speaker 4:  all the existing chat apps died. They weren't ready for it. And new apps
Speaker 4:  sprung up to fill the void. WhatsApp, iMessage,
Speaker 4:  telegram, Snapchat, they were all built mobile
Speaker 4:  first. They had many new features like end-to-end encryption
Speaker 4:  because you had this device that was, you You know you have your phone and
Speaker 4:  it's always with you and, and you only have one phone at a time. These new
Speaker 4:  apps or these new systems could afford to have a closer connection to
Speaker 4:  your personal identity, which allows for things like You know, You know you
Speaker 4:  have a pretty good idea of who you're gonna message when you message their
Speaker 4:  phone number end an encryption. You know didn't exist before there was You
Speaker 4:  know a little bit of Jabber end an encryption, but no one really implemented
Speaker 4:  that. So it was a big new innovation that came along with the switch to mobile
Speaker 4:  and everyone got a phone that allowed so many more
Speaker 4:  people to start chatting. And so while we remembered the, the golden age
Speaker 4:  of Chat being You know, logging into Adio on our Dell
Speaker 4:  desktop or whatever, most people's first experience with chat is
Speaker 4:  SS m s, WhatsApp, iMessage, discord, You know
Speaker 4:  Snapchat. Yeah, Instagram, You know all those apps and and
Speaker 4:  networks were not built with Federation or decentralization in
Speaker 4:  mind. They were built as, they should have been just individual
Speaker 4:  apps that served a great purpose, that delivered an excellent experience
Speaker 4:  to people and they just didn't really care about the past. And
Speaker 4:  that was fine. I don't think that anyone should be blamed for that. Like
Speaker 4:  we want to have new products, we want to have the evolution of You know technology.
Speaker 4:  We don't want things to be stuck stagnant. Sure.
Speaker 3:  But at the same time, Google didn't wall off Gmail from the rest
Speaker 3:  of the email universe just because it switched to how
Speaker 3:  mobile works. And I get, I think what what you're describing is a much bigger
Speaker 3:  technical change, which makes sense and and there's a moment where it's like,
Speaker 3:  okay, we have to rebuild this anyway. We're gonna rebuild it differently.
Speaker 3:  But part of me still wonders if, if there wasn't room back then
Speaker 3:  to do it better and a bunch of companies who had business reasons not to,
Speaker 3:  just didn't.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I mean I would actually take Google aside and say that
Speaker 4:  everyone else is net neutral if You know they're not maliciously trying
Speaker 4:  to make life worse for people, but Google actually goes an extra
Speaker 4:  step to say, I want to, even though it's harder to make something with an
Speaker 4:  A P I or even though it's harder to make something that's federated and decentralized,
Speaker 4:  I think Google goes a step in that direction to say, look, let's at least
Speaker 4:  try. And I think that just goes to the core of You know Google's
Speaker 4:  hacker You know sensibilities. Yeah. But no one else seems to have that.
Speaker 4:  So that's, but if you look at the major players like Facebook and
Speaker 4:  Apple and even s m s to a certain degree, no,
Speaker 4:  there's no ability for other apps to interact with those or
Speaker 4:  those systems easily.
Speaker 3:  I mean for so many years Facebook's own apps didn't interact with each other.
Speaker 3:  Like it was just, it was not even a thing anybody thought about for so, so,
Speaker 3:  so long. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Now that you, now that we're talking about it, like technically Facebook
Speaker 4:  Messenger did actually support Jabber back in the day. And so you could message
Speaker 4:  someone on Google talk from Facebook Messenger and I think like
Speaker 4:  there probably was some moment where
Speaker 4:  you'll have to research the history, but I think either Google shut down
Speaker 4:  their Jabber Bridge or Facebook shut down the Jabber Bridge and then
Speaker 4:  everyone kind of sharped down at the same point.
Speaker 3:  Because that was also the time when everybody realized how valuable
Speaker 3:  these networks are And what you can do if you have people in your space.
Speaker 3:  And it feels like, like the other thing that happened in that time was everybody
Speaker 3:  in every industry said, we have to build universes inside of our apps.
Speaker 3:  Right? Like, that's what Netflix did. It's, it's not that different a behavior
Speaker 3:  in a lot of ways.
Speaker 4:  But what's interesting about that is I think that's the prevailing wisdom.
Speaker 4:  That's what we all assume. But if you look at the actual businesses
Speaker 4:  that have been built on top of chat or adjacent to chat,
Speaker 4:  chat does not make any of these big companies money, right? They're not even,
Speaker 4:  it's close to making the money. Take WhatsApp for example. WhatsApp
Speaker 4:  was acquired in 2013 ish and it was the
Speaker 4:  biggest acquisition ever. And there was You know noise about
Speaker 4:  who's gonna get WhatsApp? Is it gonna be Google or Facebook? And Facebook
Speaker 4:  paid this outrageous sum because they didn't want it to go to Google and
Speaker 4:  enrich Google's Google Plus or whatever they were doing at the time.
Speaker 4:  And you'd, you'd imagine like, I think it was probably hundreds of millions
Speaker 4:  if not a billion users already when they acquired them. And
Speaker 4:  you'd be like, great, okay. Like how are we gonna make money off this?
Speaker 4:  And we are 10 years later and I don't think WhatsApp
Speaker 4:  is making significant money for Facebook at all.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I don't, I I I think that's true. And I think one of the things a lot
Speaker 3:  of these services have discovered over the last few years is there's no money
Speaker 3:  in messaging. And if you try to stick
Speaker 3:  money making things into messaging, people will revolt. Like I think
Speaker 3:  back to Google Aloe where they were like, we're gonna bring in
Speaker 3:  an AI assistant that's gonna help you buy tickets when we understand that
Speaker 3:  you're talking about tickets, isn't that useful? And everybody went, no,
Speaker 3:  that's horrible. Just let me talk to my friends.
Speaker 4:  What I find is remarkable about this as someone who's building a chat app
Speaker 4:  where You know our plan is to actually just charge charge people money chat
Speaker 4:  is so fundamental to what we do. We do it dozens if not
Speaker 4:  hundreds of times per day. You know if you look at your screen time across
Speaker 4:  all your devices, it probably doesn't, maybe it adds up to like an hour or
Speaker 4:  two, but it, the, the number of interactions that you spend in chat across
Speaker 4:  all the different chat platforms that you have is mind-boggling. You know
Speaker 4:  that is the way that we as humans communicate. Like it's no longer
Speaker 4:  phone calls, it's no longer email. The future is chat. Like
Speaker 4:  that is how we communicate and as
Speaker 4:  a product, it has been kind of left by the wayside because
Speaker 4:  of this unclear definition around the business model. So what I
Speaker 4:  mean by that is iMessage started in 2011, I think
Speaker 4:  WhatsApp just a few years before that. If you look at roughly how these apps
Speaker 4:  work, You know there's an inbox and there's a conversation view, a
Speaker 4:  chat view. They haven't changed in the last 10, 15 years. Yep. It's
Speaker 4:  the same view, it's the same functionality. There's been a few other message
Speaker 4:  types. You can now send emo emoji reactions. You know we're literally
Speaker 4:  just added to WhatsApp a year, a year, like a year ago. They're
Speaker 3:  Great, by the way. I don't mean to denigrate emoji reactions. It's like I'm,
Speaker 3:  I'm, no, it's a big fan of emoji reactions.
Speaker 4:  It's good. But it's like, I think that just to illustrate how slowly
Speaker 4:  these things are moving and You know part of that symptom of getting
Speaker 4:  to scale, like once you have 3 billion users, it's harder to steer sort of
Speaker 4:  the steer the ship in different directions. But what I think is missing
Speaker 4:  is an opportunity for other people to build on top of these
Speaker 4:  communication protocols and expand what
Speaker 4:  we can do with chat You know in an instant
Speaker 4:  messaging. Just look at email You know as a counter example.
Speaker 4:  When you have an open standard for communication or for
Speaker 4:  for email or you have Gmail, which goes outta their way again to, to
Speaker 4:  allow other kind of people to build on top of it, whether it's plugins or
Speaker 4:  alternative clients or just the a p i, you get
Speaker 4:  an evolution, a very clear timeline over the last 15 years
Speaker 4:  of new productivity software, of new
Speaker 4:  casual, fun, You know entertainment. You get kind of
Speaker 4:  this work operating system that people now use through Google
Speaker 4:  Workspace and, and all the apps that you can associate with your You know
Speaker 4:  Google account. That Cambrian explosion of tools
Speaker 4:  built on top of Gmail is just completely and utterly missing
Speaker 4:  from chat because of the fact that there is no a p i for
Speaker 4:  iMessage or WhatsApp or even S m Ss to a certain degree. You know
Speaker 4:  actually, I guess SMS and Twilio is a, is a, is a kind of good counter example
Speaker 4:  of what happens when there is at least one kind of side door that you
Speaker 4:  could get into and build on top of. But in the case of iMessage and and WhatsApp,
Speaker 4:  like there's basically nothing you can't build on top of those systems.
Speaker 3:  All, right? We gotta take a break and then we'll be back with more from Eric
Speaker 3:  Welcome back like Eric was just talking about. Part of the challenge with
Speaker 3:  messaging has been that there's just no way to build on top of
Speaker 3:  these systems. They're often not great products, honestly, and there's
Speaker 3:  not much you can do to help them. You're just stuck with the app that they
Speaker 3:  give you. But at the same time, they're so entrenched in our lives and
Speaker 3:  so often set in their ways just like people are that I think most
Speaker 3:  developers would look at this market and just decide not to even
Speaker 3:  try. I mean the network effects of messaging are massive. The switching
Speaker 3:  costs are super high. There's really not much reason to think you can make
Speaker 3:  a dent at all in the messaging world at this point. Many have tried and frankly
Speaker 3:  many have failed. But then here comes Eric and Beeper trying to do it anyway.
Speaker 3:  So, I just asked him, what made you look at this space and think you
Speaker 3:  could hack it?
Speaker 4:  Our long-term vision is to build the best damn chat app on earth.
Speaker 4:  It's as simple as that. We think chat is, like I said before, something that
Speaker 4:  we do dozens if not hundreds of times per day. And it deserves attention.
Speaker 4:  It deserves to have a set of people building an experience that
Speaker 4:  continues to get better, that that really pushes the boundary on what's possible
Speaker 4:  with chat. And I don't feel like there's anyone carrying the torch
Speaker 4:  today. If you look at the top companies in chat, none of them are
Speaker 4:  incentivized to build a better experience. Their only incentive is to
Speaker 4:  keep you locked into their platform so that they make money through some
Speaker 4:  ulterior motive.
Speaker 3:  That's how Apple sells iPhones. The blue bubble thing is just as real as
Speaker 3:  it gets.
Speaker 4:  So our simple thing is we wanna build a great chat app
Speaker 4:  and we will charge people money to use it. Not everyone, there's
Speaker 4:  gonna be a a free option to use Beeper, but we think that there's a
Speaker 4:  You know there's 3 billion people in the world who use chat on a daily basis.
Speaker 4:  Some percentage of them we could argue about the exact number. We'll be interested
Speaker 4:  in paying for a better experience. Those are the people that we're intending
Speaker 4:  to capture and You know build an increasingly better chat
Speaker 4:  experience.
Speaker 3:  Was that the kind of original insight that like we can do
Speaker 3:  something powerful just by putting all of these things in one place?
Speaker 4:  The original insight, it started to solve a personal problem. Okay. Like
Speaker 4:  I have two friends on Google Talk or Google Chat or whatever it's called
Speaker 4:  today. I have three friends on WeChat. I have two friends on
Speaker 4:  Telegram and I just got sick and tired of there being 10 different
Speaker 4:  apps on my phone that kind of did exactly the same thing, albeit with a slightly
Speaker 4:  different contact list. I just wanted a single app, a
Speaker 4:  single search box that I could type in anyone's name and instantly start
Speaker 4:  chatting with them. I didn't want to have to remember like I basically
Speaker 4:  had this lookup table in my mind that matched each person,
Speaker 4:  each friend, each, each family member and which Neli, which app they used.
Speaker 4:  Computers are much better than us at doing that. They can memorize, they're
Speaker 4:  really good at lookup tables. So all I wanted to do was build
Speaker 4:  something that would allow me to just type in someone's name and start chatting
Speaker 4:  with them and not have that cognitive overhead of like, wait, where? Where
Speaker 4:  were we chatting? Was it like LinkedIn chat or was it like the little
Speaker 4:  sidebar chat in a Google Docs? Like I just wanted one single place that I
Speaker 4:  could use to chat with everyone.
Speaker 3:  I had a friend for many years who would, every time I would message him,
Speaker 3:  he would message me back on a different platform. I
Speaker 4:  Like that. That's chaotic. Good.
Speaker 3:  Honestly, it was great. He, it was the funniest thing and so every one of
Speaker 3:  our conversations just made absolutely no sense because it was one out of
Speaker 3:  every like 12 messages of our conversation. But it really was, you could
Speaker 3:  go an alarmingly long time without ever repeating chat apps. It
Speaker 3:  was kind of incredible. Still
Speaker 4:  Happens. Like You know you start something on Instagram because you're responding
Speaker 4:  to their story and then you see a funny tweet and you send them a TWI Twitter
Speaker 4:  dmm. Yeah. And then someone asks for an intro in LinkedIn, like it
Speaker 4:  adds up. I like to think of it as currently
Speaker 4:  this tax on top of every sort of communication,
Speaker 4:  it's not a big tax. It's You know a couple percent of
Speaker 4:  overhead to think about how am I gonna communicate with this person. But
Speaker 4:  think of how many times you communicate and if we can eliminate that tax,
Speaker 4:  Beeper has the potential to actually make the entire world
Speaker 4:  output of communication You know a couple percent
Speaker 4:  better. Yeah. And that's a pretty big opportunity.
Speaker 3:  Were you even aware that it was technically possible to do that at the
Speaker 3:  beginning? I mean you just described that shift when we went to mobile where
Speaker 3:  we went from having relatively intelligible protocols and
Speaker 3:  platforms to a bunch of totally siloed different systems.
Speaker 3:  Were you even sure that the thing you wanted could exist in the world we
Speaker 3:  live in now?
Speaker 4:  No. Okay. And I think that's kind of a good thing.
Speaker 4:  You know, I, I started a company before called Pebble. We built smartwatches.
Speaker 4:  I was 23. I knew nothing about building hardware and it was a good thing
Speaker 4:  because if I did I probably wouldn't have done it. And I think some of
Speaker 4:  the best companies are started because the founders are too naive to really
Speaker 4:  understand how crazy the journey that they're about to embark on is.
Speaker 4:  I think about that with Beeper as well. Like we spent the last two and a
Speaker 4:  half years understanding how each of these different protocols work, creating
Speaker 4:  what we call a bridge between Beeper and 15
Speaker 4:  different chat networks and perfecting them and making them work reliably.
Speaker 4:  That was very hard. That was incredibly hard. It still is hard but
Speaker 4:  It works and there's no going back. There's no way that I could switch
Speaker 4:  from using Beeper and being able to just seamlessly chat
Speaker 4:  with anyone to going back to having to remember like which
Speaker 4:  which app I'm on each person is on.
Speaker 3:  I would think that along the way, especially at the beginning of this process,
Speaker 3:  you you would think to really do what we want to do, not only do we
Speaker 3:  have to connect all of these systems, we have to build a new one that's right
Speaker 3:  and better. And that Bieber becomes sort
Speaker 3:  of the gateway drug into this better thing, right? It's like come talk to
Speaker 3:  your Twitter DMM friends in Beeper. But we all know Twitter
Speaker 3:  dms is a bad product for messaging. It always has been. And
Speaker 3:  ultimately we're going to train you to use this better system that is our
Speaker 3:  system and that's how it's gonna work. Is that the
Speaker 3:  idea? Was that the idea to bring people, 'cause you talk about the A
Speaker 3:  P I and all this stuff you wanna do, you would need to build the whole thing
Speaker 3:  yourself at some point to do that, right?
Speaker 4:  So you raise a good point and it's the same one that You know
Speaker 4:  the X K C D guy wrote Sure You know 10, 15 years ago,
Speaker 4:  right? There's a classic X K C D for everything and this included
Speaker 4:  and it is You know a couple panels and I You know, hey there's 10 standards.
Speaker 4:  Let's make a new app that incorporates all these 10 standards. Oh and
Speaker 4:  now we have 11 standards. And so we didn't want be
Speaker 4:  part of the problem, we didn't want to go and create yet another messaging
Speaker 4:  standard. And so we looked at what was out there and the best open source
Speaker 4:  protocol that kind of checks all the boxes is one called Matrix.
Speaker 4:  Matrix is a protocol similar to, you can kind
Speaker 4:  of think of it as a spiritual successor to Jabber or X M P
Speaker 4:  P using no-code from X M P P. It's just a brand new implementation.
Speaker 4:  It's not perfect You know, no Open standard is, but we decided to adopt it
Speaker 4:  because it represents the best way for us to be
Speaker 4:  part of a broader network without creating yet another closed
Speaker 4:  siloed standard and contributing back to the problem. So we chose to use
Speaker 4:  an open standard called Matrix. It is federated, which means
Speaker 4:  that if you run your own server or if You know your, your account is on a
Speaker 4:  different matrix server, you can still talk to someone who's on Beeper. It's
Speaker 4:  very similar to email in that regard. Like you have an account on Beeper,
Speaker 4:  you have an account on Gmail, you can still send messages to people who have
Speaker 4:  different email servers. But Beeper is a private company.
Speaker 4:  It's a not open source application and we're designed to be You know just
Speaker 4:  an excellent experience on top of this open source standard. And similar
Speaker 4:  to Gmail, you probably don't understand the intricacies of IMAP or POP
Speaker 4:  or whatever. You know
Speaker 3:  And God help you if you do at this point.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You don't have to, you just You know. You could just chat with your
Speaker 4:  friends
Speaker 3:  From a product perspective. You come into this and on the one hand,
Speaker 3:  messaging is this incredibly entrenched thing that we've been doing roughly
Speaker 3:  the same way for a very long time. You know you mentioned you have the, the
Speaker 3:  list on the left side and the conversation on the right that goes back not
Speaker 3:  just to how we message but like decades of email, right? Like everybody's
Speaker 3:  inbox is the same thing and has been forever. Yeah. All the way back to the
Speaker 3:  beginning of the internet. That is what conversation has looked like. I
Speaker 3:  think you could make a very compelling case that that is not the only or
Speaker 3:  best answer, but it is the answer right now. And So I, I,
Speaker 3:  I'm curious even at the very beginning of deciding how do we want this thing
Speaker 3:  to work And, what do we want it to look like? You have to
Speaker 3:  decide between reinventing the wheel in potentially
Speaker 3:  very cool but really kind of jarring ways for people or doing
Speaker 3:  the deeply boring old same thing that everybody
Speaker 3:  does that is fundamentally how people expect to message all the time. How
Speaker 3:  do you make that decision?
Speaker 4:  So there's a couple competing veins here. One is that we have muscle
Speaker 4:  memory for chat whether we like it or not, we've been using the same
Speaker 4:  software for the last 10, 15 years and that muscle memory is very
Speaker 4:  strong. Like you have a physical like picking up and unlocking your phone
Speaker 4:  is a physical twitch that we all, that we all have.
Speaker 3:  Totally. It's like the example of in, in the most recent iOS when they moved
Speaker 3:  the hangup button from the middle to the right, everybody freaked out 'cause
Speaker 3:  it's, you just You know where the buttons are.
Speaker 4:  We found that with Beeper, even though there are improvements that we're
Speaker 4:  making to the chat experience, people still have that
Speaker 4:  need to have something familiar. Let me put a pin in that for a sec to, to
Speaker 4:  kind of describe what our intention is for the last 10 years.
Speaker 4:  The app that you use to chat on a particular chat
Speaker 4:  network is a one-to-one mapping to that network. Like you can only use the
Speaker 4:  WhatsApp app to chat on WhatsApp. You can only use the iMessage app to chat
Speaker 4:  on iMessage. There has never been a delinking between the
Speaker 4:  network and the, the software that's used to chat on that. Now I don't want
Speaker 4:  to give the crypto people too much credit, but one of the ideas in
Speaker 4:  the, in the crypto world is this idea of separating the protocol
Speaker 4:  from the application. And I think that's what we're doing with
Speaker 4:  Beeper. We are for the first time separating the
Speaker 4:  UI that you use to interact with a particular chat network from
Speaker 4:  that chat networks first party software, which gives us the ability
Speaker 4:  to experiment in a way that these first party You know
Speaker 4:  chat apps basically can't do because they have 3 billion users and
Speaker 4:  you can't experiment too much with You know an app that that has that large
Speaker 4:  an install base.
Speaker 3:  Give me an example of something you could have done that might have been
Speaker 3:  better but you couldn't do because it's just not how It works.
Speaker 4:  A very small example is over the summer we had an intern build a widget
Speaker 4:  framework for Beeper that lets you install widgets
Speaker 4:  on the side panel of your chat. Similar to how Gmail has You know
Speaker 4:  plugins and You know you could download a Chrome extension, never been
Speaker 4:  possible, like no amount of money could have given you a widget on the side
Speaker 4:  of your iMessage chat, right? And we did it, he did it in
Speaker 4:  You know a couple weeks because we had already separated the protocol from
Speaker 4:  the application and some of the fun widgets that we made were
Speaker 4:  like a summarization widget that used chat G B T or Anthropic to
Speaker 4:  summarize what the You know. You log in the morning to Slack and you see
Speaker 4:  a bunch of unread messages and you're just like, what, what happened? What
Speaker 4:  did I miss? And here it's just a button in the side panel that you just press
Speaker 4:  it and it just tells you what you missed. That took like two days to build.
Speaker 4:  And it's only possible because we've separated that the the protocol from
Speaker 4:  the the application layer. So that's the same example, like we're still
Speaker 4:  early. I think we've worked really hard to get
Speaker 4:  the foundation to work to make sure that Bieber is reliable, to make sure
Speaker 4:  that it sends in receive messages remarkably hard, took longer than expected,
Speaker 4:  but we dedicated all of our effort just to doing that and it's still
Speaker 4:  taking quite a bit of our effort. So over time we'll begin to
Speaker 4:  use the fact that we have this kind of separation. But
Speaker 4:  honestly like some of the basics hadn't been done in messaging. Like
Speaker 4:  for example, Gmail over the last 10 years has evolved to have
Speaker 4:  archive states and tabs and all of these tools that
Speaker 4:  let you kind of manage the overflowing amount of email that you
Speaker 4:  get that overflow is shifting to chat. You know we are
Speaker 4:  getting not just spam and and junk messages, but we're just getting more
Speaker 4:  and more of our daily communication flowing through these
Speaker 4:  tools that haven't changed. And so a lot of what we did at Bieber was just
Speaker 4:  add kind of basic inbox management stuff that email has had forever
Speaker 4:  that make it a bit easier for you to deal with You know your inbox.
Speaker 4:  And we've added things like being able to archive messages. You can move
Speaker 4:  chats from your main inbox to other folders, you can mark
Speaker 4:  things as low priority. And those have been just incredibly helpful
Speaker 4:  for people that are using chat as their primary means of
Speaker 4:  communication.
Speaker 3:  Okay, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna get into where Beeper
Speaker 3:  goes from here.
Speaker 3:  All. right, we're back. Let's get back to talking about Bieber, which I really
Speaker 3:  do continue to think is one of the most interesting messaging apps on the
Speaker 3:  planet. And that's in part because its strategy is to like invade
Speaker 3:  the messaging app ecosystem as it already exists. I've
Speaker 3:  been using paper for a long time, like I said earlier, and I've kind of watched
Speaker 3:  the company lose connections to services and get them back and support new
Speaker 3:  stuff and drop support and re-add support. And in general, I just can't
Speaker 3:  imagine that the messaging apps, which like we've been talking about, don't
Speaker 3:  have APIs or developer platforms and really want you to stay in their walled
Speaker 3:  gardens are psyched that Beeper exists at all. So, I
Speaker 3:  just asked Eric, is this app a series of elaborate hacks
Speaker 3:  designed to get around messaging apps that would rather you not do all these
Speaker 3:  things? How much do these companies know or care what you're doing to their
Speaker 3:  systems?
Speaker 4:  You know at the end of the day, these are your chats, these are your
Speaker 4:  friends, these are your connections, this is your life. Like our
Speaker 4:  life is illustrated by the messages that we send to, to our
Speaker 4:  friends and family and and our colleagues. You know a lot of the, the, the
Speaker 4:  kind of AI one-offs that you've seen are people like training an AI
Speaker 4:  on their chat messages. That's because You know your messages. Are you
Speaker 4:  like, they are an embodiment of, of kind of your, your relationships and
Speaker 4:  your connections. And I think what we're doing is saying like you
Speaker 4:  should be in control of your own messages. And it's remarkable how we
Speaker 4:  take that for granted on other things like email or calls or Google
Speaker 4:  Docs or whatever. Like all of all of the other forms of You know
Speaker 4:  communication are your own, they're they're owned by you. But chat, we
Speaker 4:  kind of have accepted this, this world where like there's these
Speaker 4:  silos and those chats are stuck in the silo and we're gonna be okay with
Speaker 4:  it. I think what we're doing is saying like, no, actually
Speaker 4:  you should be in control of who you're chatting with and you should have
Speaker 4:  access to your message history and you should be able to decide You know
Speaker 4:  which, which client you use to send messages on each of these different networks.
Speaker 4:  And that's all we're doing. Like you can kind of think of it as a browser.
Speaker 4:  You know when you open up instagram.com in
Speaker 4:  Chrome or in Arc or in Brave, you're
Speaker 4:  still just You know sending and receiving messages on Instagram. That's basically
Speaker 4:  how Bieber works.
Speaker 3:  Okay. I believe you that you believe that I am less
Speaker 3:  convinced that Apple thinks all of my iMessages belong
Speaker 3:  to me and our mind to do with as I please. I think you're right. I'm just
Speaker 3:  not sure that's a super popular opinion in the messaging world.
Speaker 4:  I think honestly like kind of doesn't matter what Apple thinks, there's 3 billion
Speaker 4:  people who use chat in the world. There's a lot more of us than than them
Speaker 4:  at this point. And it matters what you think is right
Speaker 4:  And so it is to a certain degree up to us as
Speaker 4:  users of chat protocols and chat networks
Speaker 4:  to say, this is what I expect. This is my minimum bar. Part
Speaker 4:  of the reason why these companies can get away with it is it's practically
Speaker 4:  impossible to change. There is no free market right now in
Speaker 4:  messaging. Yeah, that's true. If you have You know an Android phone, you
Speaker 4:  can't send a message to someone on iMessage. If you are on WhatsApp, you
Speaker 4:  can't send a message to someone who is on Telegram. And these companies
Speaker 4:  exploit that kind of social dynamic to make it
Speaker 4:  harder for you to actually harder for companies like Beeper or or
Speaker 4:  other chat providers to actually compete on in terms of features or
Speaker 4:  capabilities. The lock-in effect is, is real. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And so what what we're doing is like giving people a choice
Speaker 4:  for the first time, giving You know Americans, giving Europeans, giving people
Speaker 4:  around the world a chance to actually choose which software they think
Speaker 4:  offers them a better experience without having to worry about the lock-in
Speaker 4:  effect. And if you look at the kind of wins
Speaker 4:  of change in Europe with the Digital Markets Act
Speaker 4:  or in the US with the American Innovation and Choice Online Act,
Speaker 4:  there are a few movements that are taking shape to say
Speaker 4:  actually You know for the good of us, for the good of You know the
Speaker 4:  world, we need to be able to have the freedom to choose. And
Speaker 4:  that's You know slowly happening. And I think it's gonna be harder for these
Speaker 4:  large companies to to, to come out with anti You know free
Speaker 4:  market anti-competitive products like the current suite of chat apps
Speaker 4:  in future.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I I was gonna ask this question later, but since you brought it up
Speaker 3:  I'll just ask it now. The thing about the regulatory stuff, especially this
Speaker 3:  idea in the EU that chat apps essentially have to interoperate
Speaker 3:  that is, that is the road we are headed down.
Speaker 4:  It's the law
Speaker 3:  I've wondered for a long time whether that essentially
Speaker 3:  obviates Beeper over time because these apps you already use are gonna be
Speaker 3:  forced to integrate with one another. Or if it gives you an actually level
Speaker 3:  playing field to be on because instead of having your own it's fantastic.
Speaker 3:  It's fantastic. You're psyched about this, it's
Speaker 4:  Fantastic. Okay. Oh absolutely. Oh yeah. The world needs to have the ability
Speaker 4:  to communicate.
Speaker 3:  But no, I, I'm, I agree with that. Give me the like ruthless capitalist case
Speaker 3:  for why this is good for be
Speaker 4:  In terms of building a better chat experience. Are you gonna bet on the product
Speaker 4:  management team at Apple who builds iMessage and
Speaker 4:  makes small changes to the UI every year that don't really have
Speaker 4:  too much impact on how you use it? Or are you gonna bet on a company whose
Speaker 4:  entire life is chat and and our entire goal is
Speaker 4:  to build the best chat experience? Some of my favorite chat apps today are
Speaker 4:  Telegram and Discord. You know, besides Beeper, I think You know the Telegram
Speaker 4:  has a 30 person team. Theoretically, I think You know building
Speaker 4:  what's arguably a much better chat experience than any of these You know
Speaker 4:  larger, more well used apps. And so given the freedom
Speaker 4:  to message and and interoperate, yeah, You know beeper's gonna take off
Speaker 4:  because we offer a better experience than the other ones. And people
Speaker 4:  can't switch because You know they're currently locked in.
Speaker 3:  One other thing I have, I dunno, struggled is the wrong word, but I've, I've
Speaker 3:  thought about this a lot is I've been a Beeper user over the years. One thing
Speaker 3:  I keep doing all the time is turning on and off
Speaker 3:  LinkedIn and, and there's this thing that happens, it's made me realize like,
Speaker 3:  yes, all these apps are chat, but they have very different norms and they
Speaker 3:  have very different systems and I have really different rules in different
Speaker 3:  places for who's allowed to contact me and when, like if
Speaker 3:  I got as many messages on WhatsApp every day as I do on Slack,
Speaker 3:  my phone would explode. Which is not like a brag. People talk too much on
Speaker 3:  Slack, right? But is it doable do you think, to have all of
Speaker 3:  those systems and all of those norms and all of those unwritten rules about
Speaker 3:  how we talk to each other and about what, like to some extent you're doing
Speaker 3:  this like context collapse of all of these different places
Speaker 3:  into one thing in a way that's really useful but also really mind
Speaker 3:  bending for me. And sometimes like I go from one chat window when I'm talking
Speaker 3:  with my friends to another identical looking chat window where I'm talking
Speaker 3:  to like the random person who just added me on LinkedIn and that's
Speaker 3:  really useful but also kind of mind bending in a way. Is it
Speaker 3:  possible to do all that?
Speaker 4:  What I've discovered through chatting with You know users of Beeper
Speaker 4:  and people who who chat a lot is that we all have this
Speaker 4:  internal heuristic that we've developed that helps us
Speaker 4:  assign a priority to messages that we receive.
Speaker 4:  LinkedIn sounds like it might not be a giant priority for you. Not super
Speaker 4:  high, no Slack, probably You know medium, maybe iMessage is your
Speaker 4:  top, like if you get a ping on iMessage, you're much more likely to to
Speaker 4:  read it. You hold, you hold this heuristic and you
Speaker 4:  use that daily to, to kind of prioritize incoming messages. You are
Speaker 4:  unique. No one else prioritizes messages in the exact same way
Speaker 4:  that you do. They should, I'm right. There's 15 different networks and everyone
Speaker 4:  is unique. Everyone is a butterfly. And what's interesting is that we all
Speaker 4:  think everyone else has the exact same heuristic.
Speaker 4:  And so this, this manifests itself in some complicated ways. When you
Speaker 4:  send someone a message on iMessage and they're in Europe, you think that
Speaker 4:  you're now trying to be like the most important. Like you think that because
Speaker 4:  you assign a higher weight to iMessage. If you send someone to iMessage,
Speaker 4:  this means like, hey, you should You know respond to this because You know
Speaker 4:  this is an important message. But that's not necessarily their heuristic.
Speaker 4:  Take salespeople for example. I'm not a salesperson thankfully, but they
Speaker 4:  love LinkedIn. Salespeople love LinkedIn, recruiters love LinkedIn. And
Speaker 4:  so if they get a ping on LinkedIn, wow, like this might be like move
Speaker 4:  over rest of the day. Like this is the most important thing that came across
Speaker 4:  my desk. Think of demographics differences. Think of the difference between
Speaker 4:  Snapchat and Instagram. Think of the like subtle differences between friend
Speaker 4:  groups that are gamers on Discord versus You know open
Speaker 4:  source hackers on I R C. Everyone has a
Speaker 4:  slightly different way of balancing that priority. And this
Speaker 4:  is one of the biggest challenges that we face at Beeper. We
Speaker 4:  pull in that messages from all of your different networks and
Speaker 4:  that's great for all the reasons that I outlined around You. know, having
Speaker 4:  one search box, having one single app to install on each of your devices,
Speaker 4:  it does sacrifice right now some of the metadata that's
Speaker 4:  associated with the, it's like the game behind the game, right?
Speaker 4:  When you get a pinging on Instagram or you might not even have notifications
Speaker 4:  set up for Instagram, right? You might not assign any weight to Instagram.
Speaker 4:  We miss that and that's something that we are looking at how we can actually
Speaker 4:  reintegrate that into, into our system. So it's, it's on the, it's on the
Speaker 4:  to-do list. It's something that we're working on. But I would hazard a guess
Speaker 4:  to say that those network-based heuristics
Speaker 4:  that you've developed are only an approximation of the
Speaker 4:  actual priority. They're good rules of thumb,
Speaker 4:  but not a hundred percent. Like for example, LinkedIn,
Speaker 4:  I get a lot of spam on LinkedIn, but it's one of the only open
Speaker 4:  inboxes that I have on the internet. Like I, I have my Twitter dms open,
Speaker 4:  but for most people, LinkedIn is the only way that friends from high school
Speaker 4:  could contact them because your LinkedIn probably shows up at the top of
Speaker 4:  You, know the Google search for your, for your name. And
Speaker 4:  occasionally I get really heartfelt and interesting
Speaker 4:  messages sent to me, me via LinkedIn because that's the only way that people
Speaker 4:  who don't have my phone number or email address can contact. And I think
Speaker 4:  about that a lot that the best system for relative
Speaker 4:  priority ranking is one based on the person that's
Speaker 4:  trying to contact you. The type of message You know and the
Speaker 4:  meta kind of relationship that you have with that person. And all of that
Speaker 4:  data is in Beeper. And so one of the things that we're working
Speaker 4:  on is how we can use that metadata. How frequently do you talk
Speaker 4:  to this person? Have you talked to them in the past but you haven't talked
Speaker 4:  to them in years? Have they sent their 30th message to you today? Like
Speaker 4:  how quickly do you respond to them? Do you respond to them on multiple platforms?
Speaker 4:  Is this a person that you talk to on Instagram, iMessage,
Speaker 4:  and Slack? Is this a work contact? Do they talk to you mostly during
Speaker 4:  work hours? Are you part of groups with them? There's so much metadata that
Speaker 4:  can be used to assign or or help like gauge priority.
Speaker 4:  And I'm really excited that we are the first platform ever
Speaker 4:  that has clear visibility into all of these different signals.
Speaker 4:  And one of our big initiatives is figuring out how we can integrate these
Speaker 4:  signals in a simple enough way to help you make
Speaker 4:  better prioritization decisions so that you don't have to use a hard and
Speaker 4:  fast rule. A clunky rule like LinkedIn is not useful to me. It
Speaker 4:  might work most of the time, but I wanna figure out a way that we can actually
Speaker 4:  get that nugget of gold. That one old friend that sent you a LinkedIn
Speaker 4:  message that you would not have actually read for years if you don't, if
Speaker 4:  you don't go to your LinkedIn inbox like I used to and bubble that up.
Speaker 4:  And at the same time, You know the heuristic that you've set up, which is
Speaker 4:  iMessage is king, right? That is You know the, the main network.
Speaker 4:  It's not as good as of a high signal to noise ratio as you think it is. No,
Speaker 4:  there's two factor off codes. There's DoorDash, there's Uber receipts, there's
Speaker 4:  spam, there's s m s, there's all this crap. Yeah, there's groups that people
Speaker 4:  add you to that you don't really want to see at the top of your inbox, but
Speaker 4:  you don't really wanna leave. Yeah. So, I, again, this all goes back to the
Speaker 4:  idea that like we want to make the best chat app on earth
Speaker 4:  and part of that means highlighting the people that matter, highlighting
Speaker 4:  the relationships, the conversations that that matter and and
Speaker 4:  bubbling those to the top.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And that totally tracks for me and also brings up, I think one of these
Speaker 3:  sort of great tensions of building an app like paper. I can't prove this,
Speaker 3:  but one of the theories that I have that I think is right based on
Speaker 3:  talking to people for a long time about this is that one of the reasons it's
Speaker 3:  very hard to do things in chat apps is that it reminds people
Speaker 3:  that you're reading their messages when Google's assistant shows up and
Speaker 3:  is like, oh, would you like to buy movie tickets? Yeah. Part of that is annoying.
Speaker 3:  Part of it is a reminder that there is a Google system that is aware of what
Speaker 3:  I'm saying to my friend and that feels bad. And So I think these, these
Speaker 3:  companies go way outta their way to say, no, no, no, no, we're not looking,
Speaker 3:  we don't care. We don't tell ads against it. Like, no, no, no, we're not,
Speaker 3:  we're not even gonna touch it. Your chats or your chats.
Speaker 4:  But do you believe that, I mean no, but all of your Instagram messages are
Speaker 4:  on their servers and and you're getting increasingly more targeted messages
Speaker 4:  in your stories. Like
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah. To be clear, I don't, I don't think that's actually true in many
Speaker 3:  cases. I actually think, ironically, there was this thing recently with Elon
Speaker 3:  Musk and X, they said, we're going to use your posts, including your dms
Speaker 3:  to train ai. And a bunch of people freaked out. And our overarching
Speaker 3:  conversation pretty quickly got to like, well, yeah, of course that's what
Speaker 3:  everybody's doing. Like how do you not think that's what's happening on all
Speaker 3:  of these services? That's a separate problem. I, I agree. That's a problem.
Speaker 3:  I think it's a problem worth solving. But I think the challenge is to say,
Speaker 3:  we're going to give you lots of things on top of your chats. We're gonna
Speaker 3:  do all kinds of cool things based on who we know you care about, what you're
Speaker 3:  talking about, the summarization stuff you're talking about without making
Speaker 3:  it feel like we're intruding on your private life, which is what my chats
Speaker 3:  are. And again, I, I believe there are lots of good reasons to not
Speaker 3:  talk in all the places that we talk, but we do. And I think any
Speaker 3:  reminder of that is always gonna feel bad to people. Yeah. How
Speaker 3:  do you get people to make that trade or at least kind of agree to
Speaker 3:  go along that ride with you over time?
Speaker 4:  I don't think it's a trade. I think that most of the things that we're doing
Speaker 4:  are bog simple things that should have been done 10 years ago.
Speaker 4:  Like archiving. Okay. Right. You know that's just a simple button in Beeper
Speaker 4:  that says, I don't want to see this chat in my inbox anymore. Sure. Simple
Speaker 4:  as that.
Speaker 3:  But the thing where you're describing like, I wanna be able to bubble up
Speaker 3:  the most important thing on your LinkedIn to the top, like objectively good
Speaker 3:  useful feature requires knowing things about me.
Speaker 4:  It does, but the beauty of Beeper is that we're giving you access to your
Speaker 4:  own messages locally on your device. Beeper is
Speaker 4:  fully encrypted. We don't have a copy of your messages on our servers. We
Speaker 4:  couldn't read your messages on our servers if, if we wanted to. Like your
Speaker 4:  history is, is encrypted with a key that only You know.
Speaker 3:  Did you set it up that way on purpose? Like was it obvious to you? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That that was the way to do it? Okay.
Speaker 4:  Absolutely. A hundred percent. And what's cool is that everyone has a phone.
Speaker 4:  These phones have tons of storage. We can store a copy
Speaker 4:  of your entire communication history on your
Speaker 4:  phone. It takes a couple gigs. That's our plan. Store a copy of your
Speaker 4:  messages locally on your device. We don't even upload your contact list.
Speaker 4:  You know your contact. Like we're the only chat app in the world that doesn't
Speaker 4:  upload your contact list. That's true. Right? Like we use the contact list
Speaker 4:  locally to be able to match like this person's phone number is associated
Speaker 4:  with this person's name. So eventually you'll be able to say, this person
Speaker 4:  on LinkedIn is the same as this person over here in iMessage. And those
Speaker 4:  links will strengthen kind of the relationship in, in beeper's
Speaker 4:  eyes. And again, this is like, we're not planning to do
Speaker 4:  rocket science here of like creating
Speaker 4:  complicated AI models, You know, trained, it's like basic
Speaker 4:  stuff. Like is this name the same on iMessage as
Speaker 4:  in LinkedIn? When was the last time I talked to them on
Speaker 4:  Instagram? Like how many stories have I liked of theirs? It's
Speaker 4:  all local, it's all just in your message history. And it
Speaker 4:  doesn't need to be uploaded anywhere. It could be all done inside the Beeper
Speaker 4:  app.
Speaker 3:  Are phone numbers the like universal username at this
Speaker 3:  point?
Speaker 4:  Mostly ish, but not exact. Not not entirely. Are
Speaker 3:  We good with phone numbers as as the universal username?
Speaker 4:  No. I, I think it's, it's it's pragmatic. It's the best option that we have.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But Beeper is not built on top of a phone number. It's built on top
Speaker 4:  of more like an email address handle. But
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's, it's, it is interesting 'cause it does seem like, I'm just trying
Speaker 3:  to think of what is the one piece of information that all of these services
Speaker 3:  know about me? And it's probably my phone number.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Unfortunately for some networks like Instagram and Facebook, that's
Speaker 4:  not actually exposed. So Facebook and Instagram though, for damn sure they
Speaker 4:  know everything about you. Oh yes. But that's not even exposed to you as
Speaker 4:  a user. You can't, you have to upload your entire contact list in order to
Speaker 4:  see which of your friends are on Instagram. There's no way to say like, is
Speaker 4:  this phone number also on Instagram?
Speaker 3:  How broad do you think this goes? I think if I were to look at people right
Speaker 3:  now, I would say you're in a place of sort of what I would call relatively
Speaker 3:  synchronous chat. If I, I don't know if you have a better term for it than
Speaker 3:  I do, but it's like, it's relatively fast moving. It's not,
Speaker 4:  I call it consumer chat versus something like enterprise or
Speaker 4:  kind of community-based chat. It's like dms, small group chats.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's our core kind of bread and butter right
Speaker 3:  Now. That makes sense. But I also think a, a lot of the stuff we've been
Speaker 3:  talking about in chat also exists in places like,
Speaker 3:  I don't know, video chat, You know, speaking of things with a million different
Speaker 3:  standards Yeah. That all compete with each other. You could talk yourself
Speaker 3:  into being an email client in a way that's useful without trying super hard.
Speaker 3:  Like how far out from consumer chat do you think
Speaker 3:  Beeper goes over time or It's useful to think about
Speaker 4:  What I love about chat And. what gets me so excited about working on,
Speaker 4:  on building this product is it's an ever present. Well, we can
Speaker 4:  always come back to it because it's such an innate human tendency.
Speaker 4:  We want to communicate, we are social beings and so
Speaker 4:  whenever we need things to work on, we just go back to the well and we say,
Speaker 4:  how could we make this aspect of communication better?
Speaker 4:  I think we're definitely focused on chat. There's so many problems with
Speaker 4:  chat that we have not You know even scratched the surface in terms of improvements
Speaker 4:  and things that we can do. But if you extend this out 5, 10, 20 years,
Speaker 4:  there is no other company You know besides us that is entirely
Speaker 4:  focused on building an amazing communication experience. And
Speaker 4:  that is our entire goal. Like we will continue to build things that
Speaker 4:  we think make it easier for people to communicate, make it more
Speaker 4:  seamless, make it lower friction. And then You know after we
Speaker 4:  get kind of a handle on what we have today, what are different modalities
Speaker 4:  that we could use for communication? You know hardware dies hard
Speaker 4:  with a hardware person like me. If you look at every computing
Speaker 4:  platform, the killer app has always been chat. If not
Speaker 4:  You know communication to a certain degree and You know playing the clock
Speaker 4:  forward a little bit. We are You know, I am
Speaker 4:  floored by the fact that I have seven Google homes in my house
Speaker 4:  and I can't send a damn text message from them. Or
Speaker 4:  I can't send a message to my wife who has an Android phone and like
Speaker 4:  You know seamlessly start voice chatting with her. Like I
Speaker 4:  maybe if she had duo we might be able to, it's, it's just like there's no
Speaker 4:  way for us to do kind of simple communication. There's, there's all
Speaker 4:  these different apps and there's all these different devices, but there's
Speaker 4:  no one way to communicate. And I think that one of the things that,
Speaker 4:  again, going back to this idea that we have of separating the protocol from
Speaker 4:  the application, from the experience, we have this
Speaker 4:  unique ability to say we can communicate to anyone
Speaker 4:  on any chat network. Could we build an app for AirPods You
Speaker 4:  know that lets you just, you're, you're driving and instead of having to
Speaker 4:  mediate things through CarPlay or through Android Auto or something like
Speaker 4:  that. Like what if we could just override that and become your
Speaker 4:  earpiece that You know connects you to other people through deeper.
Speaker 4:  Same thing with around the home. But that's kind of boring and You know,
Speaker 4:  you could already predict that. Like I'm excited to think like in five years
Speaker 4:  what will we be doing? You know what, what new devices will we have
Speaker 4:  and how will we communicate on them? Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I think that's really interesting. And it also sounds like the road we're
Speaker 3:  headed down, which I think is the right one, but it's gonna be a really tricky
Speaker 3:  one to pull off is to separate the person from the app, right?
Speaker 3:  Like you're talking about the lookup table. It seems like the end result
Speaker 3:  is just that if I want to call you, I just call you and I actually don't
Speaker 3:  have to think about how it's calling you. It can call you on any number of
Speaker 3:  platforms and ultimately I don't have to care. Is that where we go?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We're like, I mean the end result here is telepathy.
Speaker 4:  Like how can I send a message to you as a person rather than you
Speaker 4:  as an inbox in You know Facebook or iMessage or
Speaker 4:  whatever.
Speaker 3:  And you can do that without building yet another standard on top of all the
Speaker 3:  other standards.
Speaker 4:  I mean I hope so. And I think that You know once this gains
Speaker 4:  steam or gains momentum, I think that other people will realize
Speaker 4:  that as well and hopefully join in the fun because the real, the real
Speaker 4:  ticket here is building a better experience rather than a network that just
Speaker 4:  locks you in.
Speaker 3:  How is it going convincing people to pay for this? This is the kind of thing
Speaker 3:  people have never paid for except for like email sickos
Speaker 3:  who pay 30 bucks a month for superhuman. But this is not, consumer chat is
Speaker 3:  not a thing people are used to paying money for. And I grant that you're
Speaker 3:  offering You know different kinds of features and power user stuff that people
Speaker 3:  are willing to pay for, but ultimately long run. Can a
Speaker 3:  paid chat thing work?
Speaker 4:  I would say that people do pay for communication. We pay for tools that
Speaker 4:  help us communicate. We pay $80 a month for our phone
Speaker 4:  plans. Sure. We pay for any number of video chat
Speaker 4:  pieces of software You know that we use, it's a smaller budget
Speaker 4:  than it was in the nineties where we all had long distance plans as well.
Speaker 4:  Right. But there is a chunk of money that people will put towards
Speaker 4:  improving their communication. That's what we're going after, but we're also
Speaker 4:  looking to grow the pie.
Speaker 3:  Fair enough. All, right? Well we're gonna have to come back and do this again
Speaker 3:  because this Yeah, like you said, this stuff is not done changing. It's gonna
Speaker 3:  keep getting weird in, in fun ways, but thank you for doing this. I really
Speaker 3:  appreciate this. This is really fun. No,
Speaker 4:  Anytime It was good to chat.
Speaker 3:  All, right? That's it for The Vergecast today. Thanks so much to Eric for
Speaker 3:  being on and thank you as always for listening. This show is produced by
Speaker 3:  Andrew Moreno and Liam James The. Vergecast is a Verge production and part
Speaker 3:  of the Vox Media podcast network. We will be back with episodes on Wednesday
Speaker 3:  and Friday. There's lots of news to cover this week, more
Speaker 3:  gadgets to talk about, believe it or not. And we're gonna have the long awaited
Speaker 3:  Meta Vergecast episode coming really soon. And we'll be back next Monday
Speaker 3:  with the third in our four episode series all about connectivity. We'll see
Speaker 3:  you then. Rock and roll.