# Transcript
ID: bd3f6db3-cbb6-4d42-92e5-f05f7606b99c
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: 2023's biggest tech stories
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5309188288739657442/-2587221109521861623/s93290-US-6203s-1703253652.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Richard Lawler discuss Apple pulling the Watch Series 9 and Ultra 2 from its website, the potential Warner Bros. Discovery and Paramount merger, and what the biggest stories were on The Verge Dot Com.
Speaker 4:  Hello and Welcome. To Vergecast. The flagship podcast of 2023.
Speaker 4:  The whole year. When you think of 2023, you should think of the
Speaker 4:  Vergecast and you should tell your friends to think of it that way. I know
Speaker 4:  the people have been doing year in review packages. We've done them as well.
Speaker 4:  All of them are wrong because the only thing that happened in 2023 was
Speaker 4:  The Vergecast. Is that right Dave?
Speaker 5:  That's true. That is absolutely correct. The Vergecast wrapped is a thing
Speaker 5:  that doesn't exist but Will in 2024. I promise
Speaker 4:  I don't, I don't wanna know. I'm your friend. Neli. That's David. Alex Kranz
Speaker 4:  is on vacation. Well deserved vacation already.
Speaker 4:  Our holiday wishes to her, but Richard Lawler is here to fill in. Hey Richard.
Speaker 4:  Hey. Good to be back. All, right. So this is our year-End Review
Speaker 4:  show. Unfortunately, the tech industry has decided to
Speaker 4:  chaotically fire out news at the end of the year. So here's what we're gonna
Speaker 4:  do. We're gonna do what David has titled A Year End Apple
Speaker 4:  Chaos, lightning Round. Then we're gonna have an actual
Speaker 4:  news focus lightning round, and then we're gonna go through our biggest
Speaker 4:  stories of the year, which I'll, we'll when we get to it we'll explain
Speaker 4:  how we decided what they were. It's, it's surprising, but that's how we're
Speaker 4:  structuring the show. I think it'll be good. The
Speaker 5:  News is a lot like I just wanna say before we like, could everybody just
Speaker 5:  stop please. Like the last time we had a holiday, Sam. Malman
Speaker 5:  got fired. Like it's about to be Christmas. Can we just not like from
Speaker 5:  from now on, can we just, not for like two weeks
Speaker 5:  please everybody. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Just shut it down. Tur. This is, this is the problem with working from home
Speaker 4:  All, right? Let me just put it up there. Like a cranky old man. You're at
Speaker 4:  home now All, right? Stop working, stop doing things. No more calls.
Speaker 4:  Shut the laptop.
Speaker 5:  Go to the fun screen, not the work screen. It's time
Speaker 4:  All, right on that note. And then Twitter goes down in the middle of the
Speaker 4:  night. Yeah. Richard, I've never seen Richard actually like turn it all the
Speaker 4:  way off. I've known Richard for a very long time. All the way off is not
Speaker 4:  a setting that I, I think exists with Richard. Lawler, no All. right?
Speaker 4:  Let's start with the year end Apple chaos. There's a lot of year end apple
Speaker 4:  chaos. I think the biggest, most material bit
Speaker 4:  of Yearend Apple chaos news is whatever is going on with the Apple
Speaker 4:  Watch at the ITC.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  David, can you quickly run us through this?
Speaker 5:  Sure. So the basic thing that is happening is
Speaker 5:  Apple lost a long running fight against a company called
Speaker 5:  Massimo, which makes medical devices about a sensor
Speaker 5:  for blood oxidization in the Apple Watch.
Speaker 5:  There's a lot of history there that we can talk about, much of which I think
Speaker 5:  is very interesting. But what it amounts to is that Apple lost
Speaker 5:  and the ITC, the International Trade Commission put in a,
Speaker 5:  an import ban, which would mean that Apple could not import and then
Speaker 5:  sell Apple watches. All recent Apple watches since the Apple Watch series
Speaker 5:  six except for the SE would be covered. So basically no new
Speaker 5:  Apple watches for Apple into the United States. Apple had
Speaker 5:  60 days since that ruling in October to either like come
Speaker 5:  to a deal with Massimo to get this done and sign a licensing agreement
Speaker 5:  or convince President Biden to veto the order that
Speaker 5:  expires December 25th, which is Christmas. And then on December 26th
Speaker 5:  the import ban takes effect. At this point, anything could still happen,
Speaker 5:  but pretty much everybody seems to think that by a mile the
Speaker 5:  most likely outcome is that come December 26th, apple is no longer going
Speaker 5:  to be allowed to sell most of its Apple Watch models in the United States.
Speaker 4:  So there's a few things to unpack here, which I think are interesting. One
Speaker 4:  is the long history between Apple and Massimo, which we can talk about. The
Speaker 4:  second, which people have directly asked me about is patent nerdery.
Speaker 4:  So I'll just, yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's why we had to do this here. Welcome To, The Vergecast, the flagship
Speaker 5:  podcast of Patent Nerd.
Speaker 4:  This is, this is what I'm here for. So let me just, I'll just do this part
Speaker 4:  very quickly. 'cause it, it's not actually that complicated this time. You
Speaker 4:  can feel however you want about the patent system, but in this case you have
Speaker 4:  it small US company that developed some technology, got some patents on
Speaker 4:  it. Then there's the wonky backstory with
Speaker 4:  Apple, which we can get into. But you know, a small US company made some
Speaker 4:  products, got some patents. The thing that has become the trend
Speaker 4:  in patent lawsuits, especially between tech companies over the last
Speaker 4:  decade is you file two patent lawsuits when you're mad.
Speaker 4:  One is a regular old patent infringement case in federal court. The other
Speaker 4:  is a patent infringement case at the International Trade Commission, which
Speaker 4:  is an executive agency that regulates what comes into the country.
Speaker 4:  And the reason you do that, the reason it's popular is 'cause we don't make
Speaker 4:  a lot of things in America. That's just the truth. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So if you are Apple suing Samsung or Samsung suing Apple back in the
Speaker 4:  day, you are running this fast track parallel patent
Speaker 4:  infringement litigation at the ITC to ban your
Speaker 4:  competitors' phones from entering the United States. 'cause that's gonna
Speaker 4:  create a lot of leverage for you in a settlement or a negotiation or whatever.
Speaker 4:  So that is the trend. Every time you see a patent infringement lawsuit, especially
Speaker 4:  when one of the companies involved, or both the companies involved have a
Speaker 4:  big offshore manufacturing presence and they need to import goods in the
Speaker 4:  United States, the ITC gets involved. Sonos and Google ITC involved,
Speaker 4:  famously Apple and Samsung ITC was involved
Speaker 4:  and Samsung actually won at the ITC against Apple was gonna prevent
Speaker 4:  iPhones from being imported. And the
Speaker 4:  Obama administration stepped in and said, no, we're gonna
Speaker 4:  veto this one. And in that case, you see there's like a nationalistic impulsive
Speaker 4:  play. You have an American company, you have a Korean company. The White
Speaker 4:  House is like, we're gonna let the American company win. In this case, something
Speaker 4:  that's very different is you have a small American company and you have a
Speaker 4:  giant American multinational. It does not seem like the Biden
Speaker 4:  administration wants to pick sides here. It's like not an easy
Speaker 4:  win. Like no one's waving a flag when you let Apple crush
Speaker 4:  the small company. It just doesn't, doesn't seem like it's gonna happen.
Speaker 4:  So that's the, just the shape of it, right? The ICC is this place
Speaker 4:  where a lot of parallel patent litigation happens. 'cause it's
Speaker 4:  faster and because you can quickly get to a very damaging
Speaker 4:  result, which is banning imports, which creates a lot of leverage. And now
Speaker 4:  Masimo has that leverage.
Speaker 5:  The ITC is not a legal system, right? It's not like writing laws
Speaker 5:  and judges at the end of it. It's just like a, it's just like a bunch of
Speaker 5:  people who make a decision that has this gigantic effect you're talking about.
Speaker 5:  but it's not like
Speaker 4:  It's a court, it's an administrative court. It's a, it's a different kind
Speaker 4:  of court. You can get all the way down some real law school stuff.
Speaker 4:  It's not a court in the judicial branch, it's an administrative court and
Speaker 4:  it, they work a little bit differently, but it's a court like it ha it does
Speaker 4:  that thing. So that, that's the, that's what's happened here,
Speaker 4:  right? There's been this patent litigation, I'm
Speaker 4:  sure the sort of federal court patent litigation will continue to wind its
Speaker 4:  way through the court system. But Massima one at the ITC said
Speaker 4:  basically the policy of the United States is we don't allow people to import
Speaker 4:  goods that are infringing the patents of companies that operate in the United States.
Speaker 4:  Okay? Like you under like broadly patent system aside, you understand why
Speaker 4:  that's the policy. You wanna punish people for violating patents, especially
Speaker 4:  people who might be manufacturing their goods offshore or not paying all
Speaker 4:  that. Like you see where that's coming from. Okay. Apple has to
Speaker 4:  contend with that and it's what's amazing to me about this, and David, I
Speaker 4:  think this is where the backstory is really interesting. They haven't just
Speaker 4:  paid the money to mass enough. They haven't just bought the company or paid
Speaker 4:  the licensing fee. They've been waging war against a small company
Speaker 4:  for like a
Speaker 5:  Decade. Yeah. This goes back back to 2013 and the, the very short
Speaker 5:  version of the backstory is when Apple decided it wanted to start
Speaker 5:  doing the blood oxygen stuff in the Apple watch, it contacted
Speaker 5:  Massimo as as a possible partner. And both sides agreed that
Speaker 5:  that is a thing that happened that the two companies talked to each other.
Speaker 5:  And then from there Massimo's argument is essentially Apple
Speaker 5:  hired, I think it was their chief medical officer. Yeah. And a bunch of our
Speaker 5:  employees and a bunch of our engineers and essentially just ripped off our
Speaker 5:  technology whole hog and put it into the Apple Watch
Speaker 5:  Apple's version is we met with Massimo, decided
Speaker 5:  that it wasn't gonna be what we wanted it to be. They weren't close
Speaker 5:  enough to a consumer device. So we went a different direction and then
Speaker 5:  hired Massimo's chief medical Officer and a lot of engineers
Speaker 5:  and staff and built very similar versions of its technology. So the, the
Speaker 5:  sides are like far apart in a certain way, but not that far
Speaker 5:  apart in a certain way. and it seems like what has happened at this point,
Speaker 5:  I was watching a bunch of interviews with Joe Keani who's Masimo CEO and
Speaker 5:  he is like bought in on this idea that Apple is not an
Speaker 5:  innovative company and needs to be shown to the world to be the
Speaker 5:  non-innovative company that it really is. And Apple's also having this fight
Speaker 5:  with a Live Corps about some of the EKG stuff that was going on. And he
Speaker 5:  is out here being like, I have spent $60 million over a decade on this litigation
Speaker 5:  and I'm going to win to prove to the world that Apple is not the company
Speaker 5:  that it claims to be. Apple meanwhile is the largest and most resourced
Speaker 5:  company on planet Earth. And the general
Speaker 5:  consensus of the reason that no one at Apple's side has come
Speaker 5:  to the table here is that Apple doesn't want to give people incentive to
Speaker 5:  sue them. Yeah. And if, if you can sue your way into getting
Speaker 5:  bought by Apple or getting paid off by Apple, people will do it.
Speaker 5:  And I think those, if if you take those two things, there's just no
Speaker 5:  space in between them. Just none.
Speaker 4:  There's a little bit of space. Is there, there's a little bit of space.
Speaker 5:  What
Speaker 4:  Is that space? It's not a ton of space. And I, I've covered
Speaker 4:  Apple patent litigation for a long time in many ways. Apple v Samsung
Speaker 4:  is the new story that helped The Verge become The Verge. Like it was,
Speaker 4:  it was a thing that drove a lot of our early traffic and interest. So I've
Speaker 4:  spent a lot of time covering Apple patent stuff and talking to
Speaker 4:  Apple folks. They are religious that they don't steal anything, that
Speaker 4:  everyone else is a bad actor and that everyone wants money. Right. And that
Speaker 4:  Apple's gonna come and I get it. I really get it. And you can see how this
Speaker 4:  gets expressed in all kinds of ways. Apple hates
Speaker 4:  Qualcomm, they hate this company. Yeah. And it's because
Speaker 4:  Qualcomm runs a bunch of patent licensing schemes. They own all the patents
Speaker 4:  to 5G. Apple doesn't want to pay 'em. Right. They sued each other. The
Speaker 4:  lawsuits were really snippy. Apple went out and bought Intel's modem
Speaker 4:  division so they could get away from Qualcomm. That is an incredible bet.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Apple's apple has like whole billion dollar
Speaker 5:  divisions of its company that are just set up as petty counters to
Speaker 4:  Other companies failing divisions. Yeah. Like if you'll remember, Intel
Speaker 4:  failed to build a 5G modem and Apple bought the failed
Speaker 4:  modem division from Intel on the theory that they would just
Speaker 4:  manage those people better. That's crazy. You only
Speaker 4:  do that if you're like blinded by petty rage.
Speaker 4:  It's someone else believing that they had invented something that you needed.
Speaker 4:  And so that's Qualcomm. And I think people look at their attitude towards
Speaker 4:  Samsung or Qualcomm and they're like, these are giants fighting. What are
Speaker 4:  they doing? You get down to the smaller companies who feel aggrieved and
Speaker 4:  Apple runs the same playbook. And I think it comes out looking very differently.
Speaker 4:  Right. We met with this small company, we saw their technology, we went and
Speaker 4:  instead of having to pay the premium to buy the company, we just paid a premium
Speaker 4:  for all the people. Right. I think in one of the stories, Joe Keani says
Speaker 4:  the chief medical officer, like they tripled his payday or something. So
Speaker 4:  they just spent a bunch of money on people. They they took the company away
Speaker 4:  from him and they took his technology and he's been fighting his patent lawsuit.
Speaker 4:  And Apple's belief is that it can just win in court over and over and over
Speaker 4:  again. Right. And
Speaker 5:  This is a story that startups tell about big companies all the
Speaker 4:  Time, every day, every company. Yeah. Yeah. I look at this and I look at
Speaker 4:  Apple getting all the way to this moment
Speaker 4:  where they have preemptively announced they're not gonna sell the Apple Watch.
Speaker 4:  The ban isn't in effect, it's just the week before Christmas. They should
Speaker 4:  be selling every Apple Watch they can. The way Apple announced it, super
Speaker 4:  weird, super weird. If your apple
Speaker 4:  and your it's Christmas and the Apple Watch is one of your,
Speaker 4:  is like the ultimate Apple Christmas gift, right? You need to sell as many
Speaker 4:  watches as you can. This is extremely material information that your
Speaker 4:  Q4 results will be impacted by not having the ability to
Speaker 4:  sell the Apple Watch. That is, that should be a press release.
Speaker 4:  That should be an eight k filed with the SEC. Like you should
Speaker 4:  be informing investors in the biggest, most official way you can. And Apple
Speaker 4:  didn't do that. They gave a background quote to nine to five Mac, which is
Speaker 4:  great. I I love nine to five Mac my, all of my criticism here is
Speaker 4:  for Apple. Yeah. That is an insane way to announce this
Speaker 4:  news. And my belief is they announced it that way. 'cause they didn't want
Speaker 4:  to seem important. They wanted to raise the pressure on the Biden administration.
Speaker 4:  They wanted this veto and they're, I don't think they're gonna get it. And
Speaker 4:  they're gonna have to contend with the Apple watch not being on sale unless
Speaker 4:  they buy this company pay a settlement whose premium is rising every
Speaker 4:  single day. Every day the Apple Watch isn't on sale is the day that
Speaker 4:  Massimo is like winning. Right? Like the, the price
Speaker 4:  increases for from Massimo's side every day the Apple Watch is on sale. And
Speaker 4:  what's even crazier about this, Joe from Massimo keeps saying this
Speaker 4:  in every interview. He keeps saying it takes two to tango, which is just
Speaker 4:  an amazing thing to say. He's like, I'm willing, like I will accept the money
Speaker 4:  they have to show up and offer it to me. Right. And they, they won't.
Speaker 4:  And I, I think Apple's just backed itself into a weird kind of corner here
Speaker 4:  where they should have just bought this company 10 years ago and, And we
Speaker 4:  would've ne no one would've ever heard about any of this.
Speaker 6:  And I, I think your explanation of it being religion is the only one that
Speaker 6:  makes sense here. Because when you think about it, how could Apple have possibly
Speaker 6:  have let it get this far? It just, it just, it boggles my mind to think
Speaker 6:  that they didn't take care of this before, that they didn't deal with this.
Speaker 6:  Whether you're worried about being sued by other companies or who else might
Speaker 6:  follow a precedent, anything like that. They're getting sued all the time.
Speaker 6:  That is already happening there. There's just, there's no reason to do this
Speaker 6:  logically. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It,
Speaker 5:  It, it does seem like there is a certain version of
Speaker 5:  this set of events that it never gets to this. Right. Like,
Speaker 5:  the part of the reason this is so shocking is that we went through all these
Speaker 5:  steps and, and Richard, one of the things I'm curious about is how much
Speaker 5:  you've been sort of aware of this story over the last 12 months because it's
Speaker 5:  been lingering for a long time. Like they've been fighting about this for
Speaker 5:  a decade. And yet I personally was fully out
Speaker 5:  of the blue shocked by the news that this was happening because every time
Speaker 5:  you turn around and it's like, oh, a company's suing Apple, apple will eventually
Speaker 5:  write them a check and we'll never hear about it again. This is what happens
Speaker 5:  over and over. The fact that anybody talked about it at all is surprising.
Speaker 5:  And then every step gets a little more surprising, but eventually it's like
Speaker 5:  they're either gonna write the check or settle in some other way and we'll
Speaker 5:  all move on with our lives. So to me it's like, it it's the fact
Speaker 5:  that it, the fact that it came out of nowhere, even
Speaker 5:  that it absolutely did not come out of nowhere is what's so telling to me
Speaker 5:  that it's like of this is so, such an unusual outcome of an incredibly
Speaker 5:  common thing that I think if I'm Apple, I bet nobody at Apple thought it
Speaker 5:  would get this far up, up to an potentially including the day of the ban.
Speaker 5:  I bet most people at Apple are like, it it will will win, it'll be fine.
Speaker 6:  And I think you're exactly right. That's pretty much how I was thinking about
Speaker 6:  it. I was aware of it just like I was aware of a number of other lawsuits
Speaker 6:  that are winding their way through the system involving Apple. You have all
Speaker 6:  the class action lawsuits. You have all the patent lawsuits, you have everyone
Speaker 6:  ever saying that they invented the action button before you got it on your
Speaker 6:  iPhone 15 Pro. Yeah. Yeah. but it never, it never
Speaker 6:  turns into anything or very rarely turns into anything. And then this one
Speaker 6:  just dropped one day. It was like, oh, by the way, if you want an Apple watch,
Speaker 6:  you should get it soon.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. My favorite conspiracy theory about all of this, by the way, is that,
Speaker 5:  is everybody saying like, oh, this is actually gonna be awesome for Apple's
Speaker 5:  Q4 because everybody's gonna rush out to buy an Apple watch before
Speaker 5:  it leaves shelves.
Speaker 4:  What a vote of no confidence in Apple's business development or legal teams.
Speaker 4:  And you're like, this will improve sales because everyone will rush out.
Speaker 4:  You're like, because Apple's lawyers will continue to lose this fight. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Tim Cook won't just write the check Like, don don't know man.
Speaker 4:  The, it's a weird story. Every part of it is weird. It was weird 10 years
Speaker 4:  ago. It's weird because Apple's religion is weird. People
Speaker 4:  sue Apple every day. Right. You're not by settling the one case where
Speaker 4:  there's merit or will the will get this far regardless of opinion
Speaker 4:  on merit. It's not like you're gonna encourage other people to show up. They're
Speaker 4:  already there. You're already the richest company in the world. Like you're
Speaker 4:  the fattest target There is. Yeah. So I. It, it just, it's a,
Speaker 4:  it's a weird dynamic to think more people will wanna
Speaker 4:  sue you. Like there's no one left. They're already suing you.
Speaker 4:  Like if you wake up one day and you're like, you know what, I'm gonna be
Speaker 4:  a patent troll today. The first thing on your mind is how do you sue Apple?
Speaker 4:  And that is fi it's like whatever. It's part of the system. But there, there
Speaker 4:  comes a point where you had 60 days to negotiate
Speaker 4:  the settlement before the thing wouldn't go on sale. And you banked it on
Speaker 4:  Biden showing up and having an opinion on whether the Apple watch should
Speaker 4:  be on sale. don don't like, have you, you been paying attention to this dude?
Speaker 4:  Like, doesn't seem likely.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's weird.
Speaker 4:  Like, like Biden's out there giving interviews on whether President Trump
Speaker 4:  did an insurrection. There are like two, like even if you think he's
Speaker 4:  checked in, whether the Apple Watch on sale is
Speaker 4:  on his list of things to be paying attention to far down any list that
Speaker 4:  anyone would make the things that President of United States should be paying
Speaker 4:  attention to at this moment in time. So I. The the whole thing is
Speaker 4:  weird. Yeah. Last minute Apple chaos. Anyway, it's Christmas. Go buy an Apple
Speaker 4:  watch before.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I, Becky's doesn't listen to the show I bought. She got a new
Speaker 4:  one for Christmas. And I will tell you this, one of the the funniest things
Speaker 4:  I, she only got her 'cause she has a six, she has a series five or series
Speaker 4:  six. It's dying. Like the battery's dying. It's several years old. I bought
Speaker 4:  her the new one, I bought her a nine and I was like, oh this is just not
Speaker 4:  different.
Speaker 5:  No, they are remarkably the same. To the point where I had to take mine off
Speaker 5:  and look at it today to remember which one that I had like this. This is
Speaker 5:  just where we are
Speaker 4:  And what's actually funny, Victoria's song has pointed this out over and
Speaker 4:  over again. Our coverage, the blood oxygen sensor and Apple Watch is not
Speaker 4:  that useful.
Speaker 5:  No,
Speaker 4:  It just doesn't do a lot. So what, what do we do? But if
Speaker 6:  You have an old one, you should keep it around just in case it's useful for
Speaker 6:  iMessage later.
Speaker 4:  All. right. Let's get to that. Let's talk about Beeper. Eventually you're
Speaker 4:  gonna have to jailbreak iPhone. No, eventually you're gonna have to
Speaker 4:  jailbreak an Apple watch and wear it around your neck to use Beeper. That's
Speaker 4:  that's where we're going. David, what's going on here?
Speaker 5:  This makes me so sad. So we've been covering the, the
Speaker 5:  Beeper versus iMessage thing for the last few weeks. And I think
Speaker 5:  at this point I feel pretty good about pronouncing it over.
Speaker 5:  So people said at the beginning of this week that they had yet another fix
Speaker 5:  for the iMessage blue bubble on Android thing that they've been
Speaker 5:  working on and announced the fix. and it is
Speaker 5:  so ridiculous as to be more or less sort of unusable for most people.
Speaker 5:  Basically the way that it's working is, is by connecting to a
Speaker 5:  device. It can register, it can register your
Speaker 5:  phone number as an iMessage number if and only if you have an iPhone
Speaker 5:  or a Mac, which I would point out is exactly how it already worked.
Speaker 5:  And so we've just kind of come all the way back around to where we were and
Speaker 5:  their solution is literally like, it, it's gotten to the point where they'll
Speaker 5:  say, they're saying ask a friend who has an iPhone
Speaker 5:  to give you the registration code so that we can get into their system
Speaker 5:  because that's the unique number that we need. They won't have access to
Speaker 5:  your iMessages, but every once in a while they're gonna get a new code to
Speaker 5:  keep the registration going. And they're gonna have to give you that too.
Speaker 5:  Or you can have an old iPhone, which I'm sure tons of Android users have
Speaker 5:  around, or, and this is the best one. You can rent an iPhone
Speaker 5:  from Beeper, which is a thing that they're considering doing. Like this just,
Speaker 5:  it just doesn't work. Right. Like Beeper lost. And, and you can feel about
Speaker 5:  that however you'd like to feel about that Beeper lost. And I think it's
Speaker 5:  very clear now that what beeper's pushing towards is being like
Speaker 5:  a martyr for a greater cause of fighting against Apple. And
Speaker 5:  Eric Makovsky, the, the CEO was on, I
Speaker 5:  forget one of the morning shows talking about this. I think it was CBS this
Speaker 5:  morning talking about this a a bunch of Congress people wrote
Speaker 5:  a letter about, you know, the antitrust implications of iMessage.
Speaker 5:  And so there's this like, political fight starting that don don't think is
Speaker 5:  actually gonna go anywhere. 'cause don don't think the merits of this particular
Speaker 5:  case are particularly strong. But one of the
Speaker 5:  first times I talked to Eric about this, I asked him like, is there a version
Speaker 5:  of this story where you become a martyr for a greater cause and are you okay
Speaker 5:  with that being the end? And he was like, that's not what's gonna happen.
Speaker 5:  And I was write that is what happened. I'm sorry
Speaker 4:  I read that letter. You know, I want to
Speaker 4:  have a high opinion over our government. You know, like as, as a citizen
Speaker 4:  of America, I I I truly want to believe that we can
Speaker 4:  get back to having an effective government. I read that letter and I was
Speaker 4:  like, have you any of you ever used a computer?
Speaker 4:  Do you, do you have them? Are are you, you ever
Speaker 4:  turn one on you ever, you ever see how like they're using
Speaker 4:  Apple's computers without permission? Right? That's what's going on here.
Speaker 4:  It's not, this is pretty straightforward and you can believe
Speaker 4:  that Apple should make iMessage more interoperable. I believe that you
Speaker 4:  can believe that green bubbles and blue bubbles are causing an epidemic of
Speaker 4:  weird bullying in America schools. I believe that you can believe
Speaker 4:  that Apple has a moral obligation to allow for
Speaker 4:  encrypted messaging between iPhone users and Android users without,
Speaker 4:  you know, saying something like, go use WhatsApp and set like you, you can
Speaker 4:  believe all these things ages ago before Dieter went to work for
Speaker 4:  Google, while he still worked here, he wrote a story for us called The Moral
Speaker 4:  Case for bringing iMessage to Android. Right. You can believe all of those
Speaker 4:  things. That's a great piece. You should read it again. It it
Speaker 5:  Holds up really well. I read it while writing about Beeper and it is everything
Speaker 5:  he says is still true. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It, you can believe all these things you do not have to believe that requires
Speaker 4:  Apple to let people hack their systems like it
Speaker 4:  or find a these workarounds. Like there, there's just
Speaker 4:  something in there that I, the moral argument for letting Beeper work in
Speaker 4:  the way that Beeper works is just weird. Right? It's
Speaker 4:  like it's a little too uncomfortable beyond, we
Speaker 4:  should put some pressure on Apple to make the system more interoperable.
Speaker 4:  But if that's what you're pegging it on is they found a 16-year-old kid found
Speaker 4:  a hack. Like you're just in, you're just in dicey territory from
Speaker 4:  the jump. And by the way, I really do believe Apple should make iMessage
Speaker 4:  interoperable. I think everything should be interoperable, but it just, this
Speaker 4:  one is like it's Apple resolved it without a lawsuit.
Speaker 4:  That's, that's actually probably the most notable thing here. They just cat
Speaker 4:  and mouse Beeper out of the game without ever sending the mean letter,
Speaker 4:  which based on what we were just talking about, it's like very admirable
Speaker 4:  for Apple. Yeah. They, they did not use, I
Speaker 4:  assumed that we would get a computer fraud and abuse Act
Speaker 4:  letter, but they just shut it down. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Richard, what do you make of this? I feel like I, I I've talked to myself
Speaker 5:  in circles now for like three weeks about, I think
Speaker 5:  Beeper is right about everything except whether it is and should
Speaker 5:  be allowed to do what it's doing. And ultimately that's the only thing that
Speaker 5:  matters to me. But I, I'm super curious what you think having followed all
Speaker 5:  of this that
Speaker 6:  Is the stickiest part about this, is that what Beeper is actually doing,
Speaker 6:  they're pretending to be iPhones or Macs. They've figured out a way to do
Speaker 6:  that and Apple figured out a way to undo that.
Speaker 6:  And I don't think either party is wrong. It's, it's great that they've tried
Speaker 6:  to do it and Apple is certainly within their right to say, Hey, this device
Speaker 6:  that is on our messaging system is not actually an iPhone or Mac
Speaker 6:  that has been activated. It shouldn't be allowed to do that. And the kind
Speaker 6:  of the solution that they've come to where you are actually using
Speaker 6:  an iPhone or Mac is probably one that I guess Apple
Speaker 6:  doesn't really have a way around and that they, they could use. But it's
Speaker 6:  so ridiculous. This is not what any anyone wants. This is not a service that
Speaker 6:  people want to pay for as, as they were suggesting it. And
Speaker 6:  ultimately I think everyone's unsatisfied being an Android user never having
Speaker 6:  had an iPhone. The most surprising part of this whole news is when I opened
Speaker 6:  up my iPad and found out that I have nine iMessage messages in
Speaker 6:  storage somehow. And I don't know how that happened.
Speaker 6:  So that, that is a mystery that still has not been solved. And if anyone
Speaker 6:  at Beeper or Apple, no
Speaker 4:  Richard I don would like to I don, I don't know how to say this to you, but
Speaker 4:  I've been using your iPad to spoof iMessage for some time now.
Speaker 6:  I should have known, I should have known that. That explains
Speaker 6:  a lot of weird messages. I've kidding.
Speaker 4:  And it, you know, the funniest thing about this is Apple, you know, they
Speaker 4:  caved to Europe. They're gonna do RCS, they've talked about doing
Speaker 4:  encrypted RCS, they've talked about other extensions of rrc s
Speaker 4:  to make rich messages with video and photos better.
Speaker 4:  We're very close to getting what you want out of Apple here.
Speaker 4:  Right, right. Like to what End
Speaker 4:  does actually making iMessage itself
Speaker 4:  like forcibly interoperate with just one app
Speaker 4:  accomplish very much.
Speaker 5:  Again, I think it would be great. I like Beeper as a user experience a
Speaker 5:  lot. I I was able, I piped in like 10 different
Speaker 5:  inboxes into Beeper and it is like a saner way to message It's great.
Speaker 5:  No one is obligated to support that. Right. And I that's fine.
Speaker 5:  And and I think you're right. Like if you boil Eric and Bieber's like moral
Speaker 5:  argument all the way down, what they say is SMS is bad
Speaker 5:  technology and Apple is doing its users a disservice by relying on it. I
Speaker 5:  think that is absolutely true and I think RCS is the correct
Speaker 5:  solution to that problem. Not Beeper, which is the problem, right? Like
Speaker 5:  even the case Beeper wants to make doesn't end in and the right
Speaker 5:  solution is Beeper it ends in and the right solution is this better technology
Speaker 5:  that we've invented that works for everyone. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  No, the right solution is to take it back to when we had that one app that
Speaker 6:  had me, MSN Messenger and aol Instant Messenger and IRC Trillium
Speaker 6:  What what we have iic. Yes. Trillium. Yeah. That's, that is the solutions.
Speaker 6:  Those are the base. That is where we need to
Speaker 5:  Go. Trillium, ADIO, pigeon
Speaker 4:  Pigeon,
Speaker 5:  What a world.
Speaker 6:  None of them could spell any words correctly. That's the thing they all had.
Speaker 6:  I know
Speaker 5:  It's shouldn't have been Ice
Speaker 4:  All. right? So our condolences to Beeper, hopefully one day
Speaker 4:  there's Blue Bubbles for everyone. Till that time you can buy an iPhone and
Speaker 4:  use Beeper on your Android phone. We got there. You won
Speaker 4:  Again, Tim Cook, you crafted Devil other little bit of Apple News,
Speaker 4:  lots of smoke but no fire yet on a Vision Pro launch
Speaker 4:  in February, potentially late January. This makes sense.
Speaker 4:  Just if you think about the next few weeks here, it's gonna be CES very soon
Speaker 4:  a terrifying reality. Apple loves to disrupt
Speaker 4:  CES So saying we're gonna have an event in late January,
Speaker 4:  early February during the second week of January when CSS is going,
Speaker 4:  pretty good timing for Apple. Yeah. And then they, they have said early
Speaker 4:  24 for the Vision Pro since the very beginning. So we'll see.
Speaker 4:  I, you know, I I think does this thing have a killer? Have they have, has
Speaker 4:  Apple figured out what the Vision Pro is for yet? I don Dunno,
Speaker 5:  The answer seems to be spatial video. Right? Like I feel like this has the,
Speaker 5:  been the most interesting thing about the last month or so is we've seen
Speaker 5:  this trickle of stories come out from people who have tried
Speaker 5:  shooting spatial video and on the iPhone and then seeing it Yeah. On the
Speaker 5:  Vision Pro. And that just, at least from
Speaker 5:  Apple's perspective, seems to be overwhelmingly the first
Speaker 5:  thing Apple would like to tell you about the Vision Pro. I
Speaker 5:  am very skeptical. I mean, some of the headlines you see are absurd. People
Speaker 5:  are like, I was moved to tears by seeing Yeah. My photos in the vision. It's
Speaker 5:  like, I bet I probably not, that's probably just like the screen resolution
Speaker 5:  being off and it hurt your eyes. Like that's,
Speaker 4:  You're likes you haven't had emotional experiences with technology before.
Speaker 4:  That's impossible.
Speaker 5:  I don don't know. I I'm not convinced that that
Speaker 5:  is the killer app. Not you
Speaker 4:  Are just, you just never had a feeling in your life. Man, I cried when I
Speaker 4:  watched the movie Best of the Best with Julia Robert's brother. Like, I'm
Speaker 4:  confident this thing is gonna bring me to tears. Like the first time I try
Speaker 4:  it on, I've started shooting, I will say because you know, there has been
Speaker 4:  these very controlled apple's been weird with the press.
Speaker 4:  I'm just gonna say this, right? They, they did the, the Apple Watch thing
Speaker 4:  and this weird background statement to one app. Like that's weird. It's just
Speaker 4:  weird on its face. We're gonna talk about the CarPlay announcement.
Speaker 4:  CarPlay also wasn't a press release. They gave that to GQ and
Speaker 4:  cool. Like what are, what are we doing? And then this weird
Speaker 4:  thing where like some people get to do this facial video demo and some people
Speaker 4:  like whatever, even
Speaker 5:  The Beeper stuff to like call a win for us weird. Which it also was
Speaker 5:  the Beeper stuff, which Apple never in a million years would've talked about.
Speaker 5:  We spent weeks trying to get them to talk. They gave me one quote and have
Speaker 5:  never answered another question about it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  What? Yeah, that's true. Like we're in the ecosystem. Yeah. So sometimes,
Speaker 4:  you know, the light of the sun shines upon us. Yeah. It's weird. I'm just
Speaker 4:  pointing out in general it's been, it's been a weird yeah, a weird
Speaker 4:  sequence of statements and not statements and, and whatever. But
Speaker 4:  the, the Vision Pro one is to me
Speaker 4:  is like classic Apple where they just
Speaker 4:  want people to be talking about other people's experiences, which are good,
Speaker 4:  which is fine. You know, it's like again, people, companies are gonna, apple
Speaker 4:  has run the most successful playbook in this in world's history. Keep doing
Speaker 4:  it. But the idea that
Speaker 4:  you're gonna put on this headset and have an immediate set of emotional experiences
Speaker 4:  is what Apple definitely wants you to think about it right now. Yes. Not
Speaker 4:  it's
Speaker 6:  What you should think about it. Having an emotional experience through a
Speaker 6:  screen is the best thing possible. Yes. I mean what, think about it. What
Speaker 6:  would you rather do? Use your real eyes to look at your children in three
Speaker 6:  dimensions or look at them inside an Apple headset on a screen
Speaker 6:  in three dimensions.
Speaker 4:  Well, if they're not around, I
Speaker 6:  Think there's an obvious answer here.
Speaker 4:  I thi look as a, as
Speaker 6:  A parent. Well they actually, they are around, they're, they're tapping you
Speaker 6:  on the shoulder right now as you're wearing the headset looking at them.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying as a parent on the five-year-old, there are definitely moments
Speaker 4:  where I'm like, I wish I could just rewind the clock on whatever you're doing
Speaker 4:  right now and experience you a couple weeks ago.
Speaker 6:  And you can with an Apple Vision Pro, it is only $3,500.
Speaker 6:  How, how have you not bought one already?
Speaker 4:  It's beautiful. I started shooting, like I've started shooting some social
Speaker 4:  videos, just So I have them. Right? I'm like, I'm very curious about this.
Speaker 4:  My, my broader point is not positive or or negative.
Speaker 4:  It's just, you can see when I say what is the killer app
Speaker 4:  for this, it is not something that is useful. It is something that is emotional.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like that's what we're being steered towards. You're gonna have a series
Speaker 4:  of emotional experiences with this technology, which is probably the right
Speaker 4:  thing. Richard sarcasm aside probably the right thing.
Speaker 4:  Right? Here's the thing that's gonna help you relieve some memories. Here's
Speaker 4:  the thing that's gonna blow your mind. Here's the thing that's gonna be memorable
Speaker 4:  that you're gonna wanna talk about. That you're gonna be excited for buying
Speaker 4:  the more affordable version when it comes out. Not, here's a thing that
Speaker 4:  helps you get better at work. So you tell your boss to expense a
Speaker 4:  3,500 headset, which is where Meta was going with the Quest
Speaker 4:  Pro, right? and it just, no one could get there. Like no one was like,
Speaker 4:  this has made me more productive.
Speaker 5:  It's kind of what Apple learned from the watch, right? Like Apple
Speaker 5:  framed the watch as very much a successor to the phone
Speaker 5:  and that didn't work. But then Apple found out a thing the watch was good
Speaker 5:  at that the phone was not, which was all the health and wellness and fitness
Speaker 5:  stuff and just leaned really hard into that. And so all of a sudden it's
Speaker 5:  like, okay, you need this device because it does things your other devices
Speaker 5:  can't do. And I think the problem all the headsets have
Speaker 5:  had so far is they don't really have any of that, right? They, they yell
Speaker 5:  about like it's more immersive and they, they talk about like the games you
Speaker 5:  can play, but fundamentally it's like stuff you can do on other screens.
Speaker 5:  Just different and potentially cooler.
Speaker 5:  And that Pitch doesn't actually work all that well. At least not at the scale.
Speaker 5:  You need to work if you're Apple, but with something like you're talking
Speaker 5:  about like 360 videos, feel like you're living inside
Speaker 5:  of your memories. Like there it is. That's a thing real or not. Like that
Speaker 5:  is, that is a thing I can't do on my phone. Whereas like I have
Speaker 5:  more screens. It's not, and
Speaker 6:  In a world where most of the people don't have actual access to these devices,
Speaker 6:  it's a story that you can tell over and over and over again and they'll be
Speaker 6:  interested in until you can get the price down and the manufacturing up and
Speaker 6:  actually sell them in affordable headset. Yeah. Two and a half years from
Speaker 6:  now,
Speaker 4:  I'm just gonna remind everyone that many, many years ago
Speaker 4:  before disinformation and fake news was a threat to
Speaker 4:  democracy, we ran a fake Super Bowl ad.
Speaker 4:  We put out a press release saying we were gonna run a Super Bowl ad. This
Speaker 4:  got picked up far and wide. We, we did it to punk the haters. I want to be
Speaker 4:  very clear, there was like three reporters that specifically I wanted
Speaker 4:  to tweak and we got 'em all. We also unfortunately got the New York Times,
Speaker 4:  which to this day has a story in their set that says like The
Speaker 4:  Verge planned Super Bowl ad No Box. Which is technically true. It was true.
Speaker 4:  We bought a Super Bowl ad, we bought airtime in Helena, Montana for
Speaker 4:  like $700
Speaker 4:  and we ran a, a very local Super Bowl ad. We sent a reporter to the Buffalo
Speaker 4:  Wild Wings to in Helen Montana to watch our Superbowl ad
Speaker 4:  and see what people reacted. And I, I don't need to
Speaker 4:  tell you that the patrons of the Buffalo Wild Wings in Helena, Montana
Speaker 4:  during the Super Bowl were not moved by our Super Bowl ad
Speaker 4:  Our traffic did not go up on that day.
Speaker 4:  But in that ad there is a shot of former Verge editor Ross
Speaker 4:  Miller shedding a tear inside a VR headset. Oh yeah. And that is the
Speaker 4:  thing that most people seized upon is being utterly
Speaker 4:  ludicrous inside. Like, the joke inside of our joke
Speaker 4:  was that The Verge thought people would cry in VR and like
Speaker 4:  now here we are, it's 2024 and Apple's like here's what you're gonna do.
Speaker 4:  You're gonna weep like a little baby in our headset. And it's like All right?
Speaker 4:  We weren't so wrong.
Speaker 4:  I'm excited. Like I said, I've already started shooting some videos of, of
Speaker 4:  Max in the, in in spatial video. Just 'cause I don't wanna look at
Speaker 4:  someone else's kids. That's not gonna make me cry. I'm not gonna
Speaker 4:  look at David's kid. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Whatever he sucks.
Speaker 4:  We should actually that's, that's okay. This is gonna be part of the review.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna send each other videos of our children. Ooh, love and see I love
Speaker 4:  that. If one of other's children can make us cry, okay, that's cool.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna cry like a baby no matter what happens. I love kids All. right.
Speaker 4:  Last one. Richard. I feel like you gotta you gotta take us to the
Speaker 4:  CarPlay situation 'cause it is ridiculous.
Speaker 6:  Last year in 2022, if you can remember at its developer conference,
Speaker 6:  apple said that we were gonna get a new Next gen CarPlay would take over
Speaker 6:  every screen in your car and they were going to announce vehicle news by
Speaker 6:  the end of 2023. It is. We've got a few days left in 2023
Speaker 6:  and they finally said it's coming in some Porsche in
Speaker 6:  Aston Martin next year maybe. And we've got two mock up
Speaker 6:  displays Yeah. Of the kind of CarPlay equipped supercars.
Speaker 6:  And what you see is the CarPlay screen across, even, even
Speaker 6:  in the, the dashboard right in front of the driver with the, the speedometer,
Speaker 6:  the tachometer, whatever you want, it's in the center or maybe it's on the
Speaker 6:  left. It's styled with their logos, with their colors and with their, I think
Speaker 6:  Porsche's hound tos hounds tos pattern that they usually have on their seats
Speaker 6:  is now in the screen. I'm not sure if it's any better than
Speaker 6:  what you already have in your car or something you actually aspire to. But
Speaker 6:  the idea is that if you are a Porsche owner and you're using
Speaker 6:  CarPlay, you'll get a special CarPlay experience that someone doesn't get
Speaker 6:  in, you know, their their mirror Honda or or a, or a Toyota or something
Speaker 6:  like that. So, so you don't have to deal with that anymore. I'm,
Speaker 6:  I'm not sure really where we're going with this. I I just buttons are still
Speaker 6:  better. We, we had dials and needles and that was fine to show
Speaker 6:  out your speed in your tachometer.
Speaker 4:  So a couple things. One, a totally reasonable headline on the
Speaker 4:  story could have been Apple announces Photoshops. Yes. Because
Speaker 4:  these things are not real. They're, I believe they're real. They they are.
Speaker 4:  What? These pictures are not real. So the, the
Speaker 4:  Aston Martin one in particular is the interior of an Aston Martin DB 12.
Speaker 4:  and it is just a bad Photoshop job. Like the,
Speaker 4:  the CarPlay display has not been skewed correctly onto the screen of
Speaker 4:  the Aston Martin DB 12. And I know this because it broke my
Speaker 4:  brain and I put it on threads and people started noticing that the
Speaker 4:  lines aren't parallel. Oh geez. Like it's just, it's just
Speaker 4:  weird. So that's one thing the Porsche is a little more
Speaker 4:  confusing. I'm not a hundred percent. I assumed it was a can. It doesn't
Speaker 4:  look like Cayenne. If, even if you just look at that. So what
Speaker 4:  you have in the Aston Martin is they took over the infotainment with
Speaker 4:  just regular old CarPlay unclear
Speaker 4:  why they had to Photoshop this badly. That's just CarPlay
Speaker 4:  on that center screen.
Speaker 6:  It's not what they showed last, it's not what they showed in 2022.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I'm just saying like that's just, it's just CarPlay on the center screen
Speaker 4:  and the CarPlay has a handful of climate
Speaker 4:  controls baked into it. What's particularly funny about that is there are
Speaker 4:  hard buttons in the DB 12 for climate, like right below them. So
Speaker 4:  we've accomplished a lot, but you've got a little bit of climate control
Speaker 4:  and CarPlay that's a big, and then you've obviously got the speedometer and
Speaker 4:  the, but CarPlay today can access the
Speaker 4:  center screens of certain cars like pole stars. So we just very little
Speaker 4:  has been accomplished in the Aston Martin screenshot,
Speaker 4:  the poor screenshot.
Speaker 4:  Again, it appears to just be Photoshop. You look at it and you're like,
Speaker 4:  why would you want this? Like why
Speaker 4:  first of all, the Porsche is going 205 kilometers an hour,
Speaker 4:  which is 127 miles per hour sick.
Speaker 4:  Why? On a phone call
Speaker 4:  With a calendar open on the passenger display.
Speaker 4:  So it's like this is the most dangerous office environment in world history.
Speaker 4:  Like don't do this. I think did you misunderstand Porsche customers?
Speaker 4:  Like that's it. And then all of this screen real estate
Speaker 4:  is again to, to my eye just like not
Speaker 4:  being used for anything. Right. So you've got a gauge cluster,
Speaker 4:  you've got a speedometer, you've got a row of icons. So you've got
Speaker 4:  a launcher, you have a giant map
Speaker 4:  instruction that says stay on this road. You have call controls
Speaker 4:  and then over on the right, that massive passenger display,
Speaker 4:  you've got two calendar entries,
Speaker 4:  a media controller, which w why is that all the way over there?
Speaker 4:  And then more map information and then the weather.
Speaker 5:  Perfect. I didn't see the problem in here.
Speaker 4:  It's like they're rallying. What is all this obviously like is this, are
Speaker 4:  people crying out for the lowest information density
Speaker 4:  possible in the driving while you're going 130 miles an hour?
Speaker 5:  I I, I'm so torn on this because on the one hand
Speaker 5:  I think it continues to be true that CarPlay is better
Speaker 5:  than everybody else's software in cars. Yes. So,
Speaker 5:  so to some extent,
Speaker 4:  And by the way and you know, I don't think it's good. Oh but I will agree
Speaker 4:  with you. You it's, yeah, I didn't say it was good. Say for Tesla and potentially
Speaker 4:  rivian
Speaker 5:  Sure, fine. Maybe
Speaker 5:  it's, it's better than Porsche would build on its own is a thing I believe
Speaker 5:  very strongly that said,
Speaker 5:  why do we want any of this? Like the my favorite thing that happened here
Speaker 5:  was this came out like right at the same time that VW did an interview where
Speaker 5:  it was like, we're bringing buttons back to our cars because everybody wants
Speaker 5:  buttons and we tried to do other things and we moved everything around
Speaker 5:  and people said, stop it. Give us buttons. Yeah. So they were bringing back
Speaker 5:  buttons. That's like a thing that happened. And so I'm like, okay, if this
Speaker 5:  is where cars are headed, I kind of don't think it's the worst idea
Speaker 5:  to give all of it to companies that actually know how to
Speaker 5:  build software. I'm not sure the right answer is Apple, but it's like if,
Speaker 5:  if, if all of my car is going to be is a bunch of screens, I would rather
Speaker 5:  have Apple program those screens than whoever makes
Speaker 5:  my car. Just as I would rather have a car company make my car than Apple.
Speaker 5:  But I What if we just didn't do any of this? Like what if we
Speaker 5:  just rewound this idea back like six generations ago
Speaker 5:  and just made cars the better way.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And we, we did our best to, to put software
Speaker 4:  in them that made sense or
Speaker 5:  Just less software. Like I, I'm I'm almost on
Speaker 5:  the neli team of like the amount of software I need in my car is a
Speaker 5:  mount for my phone.
Speaker 5:  Maybe that's it.
Speaker 6:  Like, like when we were at the part where it was just Bluetooth controlling
Speaker 6:  the app on your phone that's playing the podcast and you could just press
Speaker 6:  the same play button and pause button to pause it or whatever. We were pretty
Speaker 6:  good there. Like that's that's what you want. Mostly
Speaker 4:  I am utterly
Speaker 6:  And your phone on a mountain with Google Map. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Befuddled. So again, I think the Aston Martin screenshot is a DB 12.
Speaker 4:  I'm almost a hundred percent sure
Speaker 6:  Of that. It has to be. It was only car announced.
Speaker 4:  Well no they didn't announce any cars. This is an important part of this
Speaker 4:  announcement. They didn't announce any actual cars, they didn't announce
Speaker 4:  any actual features. They announced two screenshots
Speaker 4:  which are Photoshops. Yep. And two quotes from people who work at Aston
Speaker 4:  Mar Martin and Porsche So I couldn't tell you
Speaker 6:  When these Well they, they told Car and Driver that it should be in the,
Speaker 6:  the system that's coming next year in the DB 12 in the Volante. Oh,
Speaker 4:  Okay. So Aston Martin or Car and Driver has
Speaker 6:  And Porsche said something they'll like have more information when they reveal
Speaker 6:  the, the mocking or however you say that the all electric car that
Speaker 4:  They approach. Okay, so this is the interior of the Macon that
Speaker 6:  That's what, that's what you can assume I think
Speaker 4:  Because it's not the current interior of the current Macon. Yes. So
Speaker 4:  a new electric Macon will have this. Okay, fine. That makes sense to me.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying why like Apple could have just been late.
Speaker 4:  Right? They promised it by the end of this year they would have some announcements
Speaker 4:  we had heard, I've heard over and over and over again from all kinds of car
Speaker 4:  companies except for Porsche, Eston, Martin. Which foolishly I did not think
Speaker 4:  to consider that no one's gonna do this because everyone thinks the future
Speaker 4:  of their cars is recurring revenue in the cars. You can go listen to
Speaker 4:  the CEO Volvo on decoder just recently talk about how he's doing it
Speaker 4:  differently. But he still wants to do recurring revenue just for like car
Speaker 4:  insurance. Like everyone thinks that controlling this interface is a big
Speaker 4:  deal. Yeah. And letting Apple undifferentiated their cars is a big deal.
Speaker 4:  So you can see this middle step is Apple is still gonna run all the software
Speaker 4:  but Porsche gets to skin it or Aston. Martin gets to skin it a
Speaker 4:  little bit.
Speaker 4:  Okay. But they're not actually cars. Like why not wait until you have an
Speaker 4:  actual car? What was the rush? Yeah. To get it out before the end of the
Speaker 4:  year. Like no one thought it was coming.
Speaker 6:  They could've done like a line on the page where they talk about the next
Speaker 6:  gen CarPlay that says oh and it's coming in of Porsche in
Speaker 6:  Aston Martin next year. Right.
Speaker 4:  But we instead we have to announce some, some screenshots.
Speaker 5:  Do you think Apple I don know man like some lawyer at Apple came like running
Speaker 5:  into Tim Cook's office and was like, the watch is getting banned And Tim
Speaker 5:  was just like, release the Photoshops
Speaker 5:  just has them ready. He's like, whenever we need to drown out bad
Speaker 5:  news, we'll just show people weird CarPlay stuff.
Speaker 4:  I'm excited, I'm excited for us to have giant screens full
Speaker 4:  of redundant information surrounding us in cars. You know what's great about
Speaker 4:  driving at night is having bright LED lit screens at you
Speaker 4:  just in the middle of nowhere. Yeah. All right? That's the end of the apple
Speaker 4:  chaos. We gotta, we gotta wrap this up. We're gonna come back. We're doing
Speaker 4:  a very fast lighting round then we're gonna do a year in review. It's gonna
Speaker 4:  be great. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  right? We're back. We have to do a very fast lightning round
Speaker 4:  fast. The note is for me, I'm the one who makes the struggle. All, right?
Speaker 4:  David, kick us off
Speaker 5:  For this lightning round. I have six things.
Speaker 5:  No mine's very short. It's that Bird, the Once
Speaker 5:  Flying Scooter company
Speaker 5:  is cooked and at to steal from. Jess
Speaker 5:  Weathered on our team. Bird filed for chapter 11 bankruptcy.
Speaker 5:  The company has been like all but dead for a pretty long time and
Speaker 5:  just seems to have completely given up. This company was worth, I wanna
Speaker 5:  say like two or $3 billion just a few years ago. I
Speaker 5:  confess I was all in on this like micro mobility future. I
Speaker 5:  still kind of think it could work that like what we need is better public
Speaker 5:  transit. But what we also need is cool ways to get around cities that
Speaker 5:  aren't cars. And like I'm, I think the e-bike revolution is really interesting.
Speaker 5:  I think scooters really interesting. All this stuff. Bird like
Speaker 5:  really started this trend in a really big way. It just sort of dropped
Speaker 5:  scooters in every city in the world. Made a ton of money. Raised a
Speaker 5:  ton of money, really did the Uber Playbook. It was run by Travis Vander Zaden,
Speaker 5:  who was a former Uber executive. Took over in a huge way. Flew
Speaker 5:  too close to the sun. And
Speaker 5:  RIP Bird. That's
Speaker 4:  That. I was just in downtown LA by the way. I went to the Emmy Awards 'cause
Speaker 4:  our Netflix show was nominated for an Emmy. Yeah, that's like a real
Speaker 5:  Thing. Disclosure. We make a Netflix show.
Speaker 4:  We, well, we we're gonna talk about Warner Bros show. It's coming anyway.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. Disclosure, our Netflix show was nominated for an Emmy and I went
Speaker 4:  to Emmy awards, which was crazy. And I sat behind
Speaker 4:  the production team for the Kelly Clarkson show it.
Speaker 4:  They loved to party, they were just whooping it up. And
Speaker 4:  statues for days over at the Kelly Clarkson Show, sadly we did not win. We
Speaker 4:  lost a show about Italy on PBS, which, you know, when you're in the
Speaker 4:  educational informational program category, the daytime mes, you
Speaker 4:  kind of think you're gonna lose to the show about Italian food. Yeah. So
Speaker 4:  it was still fun to go. It's still fun. Hang with their team. But anyway,
Speaker 4:  So I was at the Emmys downtown la The streets are full of scooters.
Speaker 4:  And what struck me was everyone, if you'll remember Bird and Lime,
Speaker 4:  they started with just like consumer scooters. They were like ordering
Speaker 4:  from like Ollie Express. Yeah. At massive costs. And they were breaking and
Speaker 4:  people like throwing in the river and they were like, we're gonna engineer
Speaker 4:  the scooter seat better once they've taken off. And they've done that. And
Speaker 4:  the Bird scooters in particular now look like some Mad Max
Speaker 4:  shit. Oh yeah. Like raw, raw aluminum. Like
Speaker 4:  totally armored. Like they're, it's like an imposing thing
Speaker 4:  and it's like, oh these are the least cute scooters now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They weigh like a thousand pounds too. Yeah. And this is the problem.
Speaker 5:  All those things became totally commoditized and everybody was like either,
Speaker 5:  you know, we're gonna win and then we're gonna be able to raise prices like
Speaker 5:  Uber did, or we're gonna figure out how to make the unit economics work so
Speaker 5:  that they stick around all this stuff. And then some combination of
Speaker 5:  everybody grew too fast and there was a global pandemic and nobody went outside
Speaker 5:  for a year. Yeah. Just crushed everybody. And like kudos to
Speaker 5:  Lime and a couple of others that have kind of managed to stick it out and
Speaker 5:  continue to, to keep on keeping on. But this was,
Speaker 5:  this was always coming for Bird. It was either going to, it really was,
Speaker 5:  it was either going to just completely decimate everybody and take
Speaker 5:  over the world, or it was going to run through all of its money really fast
Speaker 5:  and die. And that seems to be what happened.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So it, it was less Uber and more WeWork.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 4:  All SoftBank vision fund investments. I, yeah. All. right. Speaking of
Speaker 4:  things that are doomed Richard, I believe you have a lightning round item
Speaker 4:  for us. Yes.
Speaker 6:  The news broke through multiple outlets in the,
Speaker 6:  in the last day or so that Warner, Bros, Discovery and Paramount executives
Speaker 6:  are in discussions for a Max merger. That was an Alex K's headline of course.
Speaker 4:  Oh my God.
Speaker 6:  Because we might get Paramount plus Max Max
Speaker 6:  Plus or something like that. I hated so much if these companies are allowed
Speaker 6:  to combine, because we have two failing giant
Speaker 6:  entertainment companies that can't really support themselves under their
Speaker 6:  own weight. The only solution that their executives can think of
Speaker 6:  is to combine them. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Which,
Speaker 6:  I don't know what else you could do, but they're probably going to try and
Speaker 6:  find out if this, if this is the solution, you
Speaker 4:  Could try to make good movies.
Speaker 4:  One option that is, does not seem to be in vogue,
Speaker 4:  but it's just a, it's just a thing you could do. You could make a compelling
Speaker 4:  television show for your service that you've rebranded as Max.
Speaker 5:  You could stop trying to be Netflix. Yeah. That could be fun.
Speaker 5:  Like, I mean, this is the thing, right? And, and we've been talking about
Speaker 5:  this for years now, that it was always
Speaker 5:  going to be so expensive and so complicated to compete
Speaker 5:  that there were always only going to be a few winners. And I think at this
Speaker 5:  point, Netflix is one of those winners. Like
Speaker 5:  I, I think I don, I don't see how Netflix falls apart at any point in the
Speaker 5:  near future. Disney's one of those winners, but it is in kind of a weird
Speaker 5:  place. And there's probably not room for many more like Apple TV and Prime
Speaker 5:  Video get to live on because their companies have so much money that those
Speaker 5:  things are like not material. So
Speaker 4:  This is the real problem though. But all these executives will tell you is
Speaker 4:  that their competing against cost centers for tech companies,
Speaker 4:  right. That have massive profits. So Apple TV Plus is just a cost
Speaker 5:  Center. Yeah. It's like lunch for employees and Apple TV plus, and
Speaker 4:  Again, you know, my theory with Apple TV plus in particular is they make
Speaker 4:  it so that when they talk about services revenue, they don't have to talk
Speaker 4:  about Candy Crush Whales because all their service rep service's revenue
Speaker 4:  is the 30% cut of internet purchases on games. That is Apple Services
Speaker 4:  revenue. Amazon does Prime and they spend a ton
Speaker 4:  of money and you know, what you might describe as a
Speaker 4:  produced Thursday night football game. It's not the best produced, but it's
Speaker 4:  produced Thursday night football game because stuff keeps prime subscribers
Speaker 4:  around it. It it is their retention, they know it, but it's still a
Speaker 4:  cost center, right? Like the lifetime value. They, and it's Amazon, they,
Speaker 4:  they run the math, they like the lifetime value of Prime subscriber stays
Speaker 4:  on year after year is very high. And we can take some of that margin out
Speaker 4:  and produces TV show because that will inspire more people to stay for longer.
Speaker 5:  I mean, they did a Black Friday football game. Like, I don't know if you
Speaker 5:  need a clearer indication of where the money here is for Amazon,
Speaker 4:  Right? If you're Warner Brothers, you don't have some other thing that's
Speaker 4:  making all the money. You just have to like go make the thing. And
Speaker 4:  I would just remind the audience that Warner Brothers
Speaker 4:  is the most cursed company in world history
Speaker 4:  when it comes to mergers. Like,
Speaker 5:  God, that might be true.
Speaker 4:  The times I, you know, don don't, I'm not this sort of person like runs around
Speaker 4:  like New York Times. But the Times had a very funny piece on this, or at
Speaker 4:  least I thought it was funny 'cause they had the, you know, the very sort
Speaker 4:  of normal times business writing of like, there's ample business logic
Speaker 4:  for the deal. And then they like listed all the reasons you might wanna merge.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, you know, every time any company merges a Warner Bros,
Speaker 4:  it ends in disaster. Like, like the a
Speaker 4:  OL Time Warner merger is the most failed merger in history.
Speaker 4:  The at and t time Warner merger is a close second. Like
Speaker 4:  the only thing that merger accomplished was a massive layoffs. A shitload
Speaker 4:  of debt and a gray scale. Four three Snyder. Cut.
Speaker 4:  That's it. That's what you got out of that merger. It's big three. Nothing
Speaker 4:  else. Like, what are we doing y'all? Oh, the Warner
Speaker 6:  Bros Discovery Marjo hasn't failed yet.
Speaker 5:  I don't know. I think how How's your,
Speaker 5:  how's your bat girl going? No, I think, I mean the, the problem is the Warner
Speaker 5:  brothers Discovery thing was never gonna work. It has so much debt, so
Speaker 4:  Much debt
Speaker 5:  And so many holes to dig out of that. It's like
Speaker 5:  since the minute this company existed, people have been asking who are they
Speaker 5:  gonna merge with, which was just, it was just never gonna
Speaker 5:  work. And the answer I think, I mean people have seen this coming for a long
Speaker 5:  time, right? Like these are two companies that were never going to compete
Speaker 5:  with the handful of giants that are out there, but combined
Speaker 5:  maybe
Speaker 4:  Combined but combined to do what?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, exactly
Speaker 4:  Right. Like honestly combined to do what? To have more content. It's
Speaker 4:  not more content that people, no one's running around being like, don don't
Speaker 4:  have enough content. Right? Right. And don don't even like that word. Like,
Speaker 4:  it just implies like being shoveled gurg into your mouth. Just like take
Speaker 4:  the content. Like just do it. It's another Tom Cruise movie. You will have
Speaker 4:  it. There's more reality television.
Speaker 4:  I think what people are, what what you are looking to Hollywood to do
Speaker 4:  is make really good stuff that is a little bit more scarce.
Speaker 4:  Like if you want stuff with YouTube production values, boy is there a
Speaker 4:  YouTube for you? You know, if you want stuff at Hollywood production values,
Speaker 4:  there's actually not, not a lot. and it, it just seems like there's a
Speaker 4:  race to the bottom here because of all of the debt that in particular Warner
Speaker 4:  has had to take on through its sequence of disastrous
Speaker 4:  mergers. Like I don't, don don't know. Like these companies are not gonna
Speaker 4:  make a great app with a great user experience that makes you feel good about
Speaker 4:  using it. That's full of really great stuff that inspires you to pick it
Speaker 4:  over TikTok and like that's what they're really competing against is
Speaker 4:  TikTok on your phone.
Speaker 6:  And I think that's the biggest problem for them is that when you look at
Speaker 6:  the supposed winners in this space, Netflix, are they, are they
Speaker 6:  winning because they're probably going to have to raise their prices again.
Speaker 6:  They do every six months or so. So anyway, they're throwing on games. They're
Speaker 6:  trying to find some other way to get you to pay more for a slightly bigger
Speaker 6:  bundle until they actually do recreate cable Disney. What is
Speaker 6:  Disney anymore? Is it going to have ES, espn, is it going to be something
Speaker 6:  else? We don't even know. So I'm not even sure what the model for victory
Speaker 6:  is for them. They, they just, they're chasing kind of nothing.
Speaker 4:  It's mergers and golden parachutes. Let's be very honest. By the way, I have
Speaker 4:  not done the full disclosure. Comcast is a minority investor.
Speaker 4:  No Comcast by the way. I haven't done the full disclosure. Comcast NBC
Speaker 4:  Universal Division is a minority investor in Fox Media, The, Verge parent
Speaker 4:  company. I promise you not a lot of love from Comcast
Speaker 4:  flowing in our direction.
Speaker 4:  By the way, one of the, the other line was like this would in the Times cease,
Speaker 4:  one of the other lines in the Times cease was this will give them leverage
Speaker 4:  in the, is they negotiate cable rates with Comcast and Charter and it's like
Speaker 4:  the dying stars like Yeah. The thing that people are quitting in
Speaker 4:  droves. Good luck. And the
Speaker 5:  Companies who are now negotiating by saying, we don't need TV anymore because
Speaker 5:  the only place we make money is through internet service. Yeah, perfect.
Speaker 4:  It'll go great
Speaker 6:  By the way they just like leaked the last four social security digits of
Speaker 6:  everyone who has internet service. Maybe so. Perfect.
Speaker 4:  Anyway, so Comcast investor in our company,
Speaker 4:  we, we made a Netflix show. It's nominated front of Emmy. It's called The
Speaker 4:  Future I You should go watch it. We, our company makes other TV shows,
Speaker 4:  you know, the usual, I have a Disney account, I just went to Disney World.
Speaker 4:  I does that count. I think the magic band is like neoliberal fantasy. Okay,
Speaker 4:  that's good. Okay, last one. This is mine.
Speaker 4:  I think this, I think this is actually a fascinating too front. So Peloton,
Speaker 4:  you know, they're a new CEO they went through, they also went through a big
Speaker 4:  pandemic over hire. They bought pre-core, they bought factories
Speaker 4:  and then they went through a pandemic crash when people realized they could
Speaker 4:  go back to the gym. So they, they were like reorganizing their business.
Speaker 4:  So I have two Peloton ones. They're kind of the same one I think in, in interesting
Speaker 4:  ways. The first, if you have Peloton hardware in your house and you have
Speaker 4:  the subscription, which is the plus tier of the subscription, you now don't
Speaker 4:  need the hardware. So you can now walk up to any treadmill that supports
Speaker 4:  a Bluetooth protocol called FTMS and use the Peloton app
Speaker 4:  with that treadmill, which is like pretty interesting and
Speaker 5:  It'll like keep track of the same data about how you're running and all that
Speaker 5:  stuff.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You get your incline speed, pace and distance in the app, which, you
Speaker 4:  know, track it with the rest of the Peloton stuff. This is fascinating to
Speaker 4:  me. Like just, they're just DB bundling their thing. Yeah, you obviously
Speaker 4:  need the more expensive subscription, which very much implies that you have
Speaker 4:  the hardware, but they are db bundling it and then, you know,
Speaker 4:  there's a weird little Bluetooth standard for people to argue about and figure
Speaker 4:  out what supports what. 'cause it hasn't really been important yet. And now
Speaker 4:  Peloton is gonna make this weird little Bluetooth standard important next
Speaker 4:  to that, their oldest bikes are
Speaker 4:  20 15, 20 16. They're getting very old. And so they are
Speaker 4:  gonna, they are no longer supporting the Android versions that
Speaker 4:  run on those bikes tablets. So they will give you a $500
Speaker 4:  credit to buy a new bike, which is very expensive.
Speaker 4:  Also, those bikes are always on sale, so it's nothing or this is really interesting.
Speaker 4:  They will just sell you a new tablet for those bikes. Oh, the tablet is
Speaker 4:  ridiculously expensive.
Speaker 5:  So it's like the, it's like a dumb bike with a smart TV and you just replace
Speaker 5:  the smart tv.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, like there's, there's just a thing happening in Peloton world where
Speaker 4:  they're realizing that the sort of computer part of it
Speaker 4:  like can be fully disaggregated from the bike part of it or
Speaker 4:  the treadmill part of it. And so in, in the one sense they're actual hardware,
Speaker 4:  they're just upgrading the hardware and there are some arguments in our comments
Speaker 4:  and elsewhere about whether the price that upgrade is too high. It's, it's
Speaker 4:  normally $375, but if your bike is expiring they'll give you a
Speaker 4:  $50 credit. So it's $325. That's a lot To buy a new tablet. That's a lot
Speaker 4:  for like a what is not the world's greatest Android tablet, you know, on
Speaker 5:  Top of the very expensive thing that you already bought and have paying for
Speaker 5:  for a long time you already purchase. Yeah, that's a lot. Yep.
Speaker 4:  This is a lot. but it is interesting, right? You can just put a new computer
Speaker 4:  on it and then on the, on the other side of it, you can
Speaker 4:  just get a treadmill that supports this Bluetooth protocol, buy the more
Speaker 4:  expensive subscription and use your own tablet. So you kinda
Speaker 4:  just see like the, the, the nature of this company's relationship to hardware,
Speaker 4:  software subscriptions is changing a little bit in a way that you can, you
Speaker 4:  can get to a place where you're paying too much money for a Peloton subscription
Speaker 4:  and you have neither their treadmill nor their tablet
Speaker 4:  and their app is just talking to your treadmill on your iPad and that's like,
Speaker 4:  oh, now it's a totally different company. It
Speaker 6:  It just, it just feels like what Peloton always should have been. Yep. Kind
Speaker 6:  of an add-on that. They didn't need to be the new exercise bike company,
Speaker 6:  but I assume that they registered probably correctly that if they tried to
Speaker 6:  launch with something like this, either the technology wasn't ready at the
Speaker 6:  time, which I can believe to an extent or if they did deliver
Speaker 6:  it and it did work that one of the big, big bike companies would just make
Speaker 6:  their own version and they would get frozen out. But we had to go through
Speaker 6:  this whole 10 years of waste.
Speaker 4:  It's interesting to put it in the context of the streaming conversation.
Speaker 4:  Like Pelotons real differentiation, is it, it's instructors, right? They've
Speaker 4:  like, yep. They put on a show. The, the shows have communities around them.
Speaker 4:  The instructors have people, the hardware's good. We, Becky has a Peloton
Speaker 4:  treadmill, I have a Peloton bike, they're really good. We use them a lot.
Speaker 4:  I can see how having them integrated is a superior experience to,
Speaker 4:  if I was like cobbling together an iPad with something else and like needing
Speaker 4:  a Bluetooth protocol to work. Yeah. I
Speaker 5:  Mean anyone who's ever like tried to pair their phone to the treadmill at
Speaker 5:  the gym like that, that experience can suck real bad. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But what's fascinating about this is Richard, your point is they could have
Speaker 4:  just made it all about the content and maybe that would've been better, but
Speaker 4:  I think you need something to sell. Like Apple Fitness Plus is all about
Speaker 4:  the content and I don't think it's nearly as successful as Peloton and I,
Speaker 4:  you know, like Apple's, like you just bring your own bike and no one does
Speaker 4:  it. Like no one caress. No. So there's something in there that I think is
Speaker 4:  just Nexus streaming conversation, Peloton sort of DB bundling
Speaker 4:  itself in this way, way is like fascinating. And then there's a wonky Bluetooth
Speaker 4:  standard which is suddenly gonna become more important. That's correct. And
Speaker 4:  you know, I can't stay away from the
Speaker 5:  Dream holiday spectacular 2024 Peloton Bluetooth.
Speaker 5:  No. The thing I think is interesting about this is like Richard, I think
Speaker 5:  that arc you described is like exactly what Peloton should have
Speaker 5:  done and potentially was always going to do. Like no one
Speaker 5:  at Peloton I'm sure was like, we can sell $1,800 bikes to
Speaker 5:  every single person on Earth. They're like, we're gonna sell these bikes
Speaker 5:  to as like the luxury item and that's where we start and then we become a
Speaker 5:  content business to the rest of people. And that
Speaker 5:  all would've worked just fine, except they absolutely lost their mind in
Speaker 5:  the middle of the pandemic. Yep. When everybody bought a Peloton. And so
Speaker 5:  suddenly they were like, oh, maybe the market is bigger than we thought.
Speaker 5:  And what it actually was was just that they did the 10 years of business
Speaker 5:  they were ever going to do in like three months and
Speaker 5:  suddenly they were, instead of there being 10 times as many people who might
Speaker 5:  buy a Peloton, which is what they decided was the case, it was actually just
Speaker 5:  that everyone who was ever going to buy a Peloton had already bought a Peloton.
Speaker 5:  So if they had shifted right then and been like, okay, we've hit the group,
Speaker 5:  now we're gonna be a content business. Peloton might be in a really different
Speaker 5:  place. Yeah. But instead, like you said, Eli bought factories and bought
Speaker 5:  companies and was like, we're going all in on weird hardware.
Speaker 4:  And what what's particularly interesting about that is along the way the
Speaker 4:  CEO of Peloton got pushed out for making those decisions and they brought
Speaker 4:  in the new guy Barry McCarthy, ex Netflix, who is now
Speaker 4:  running a Netflix playbook. Oh yeah. By dis-aggregating the service and the
Speaker 4:  content from the hardware.
Speaker 4:  So I said, it was just we, we were talking about streaming. I was like, oh
Speaker 4:  this Peloton, there's something right there that's the same thing. The
Speaker 6:  Difference between them in streaming is that Peloton also released a treadmill
Speaker 6:  that killed a child.
Speaker 4:  That's true. Which
Speaker 6:  Is probably,
Speaker 4:  Hey that one they're, they're about to release it. It's true that it was
Speaker 4:  oddly dangerous. Yeah. Like too dangerous and it went away.
Speaker 4:  And now on their website you can pre-order the new one, which is the same
Speaker 4:  don don't know. It's very confusing. All. right on that very dark
Speaker 4:  note. Thank you Richard. We're gonna take a break. We're come back. We're
Speaker 4:  gonna do what I think will be very fun. Your interview, we'll wrap back.
Speaker 12:  safely.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. So David had an idea
Speaker 4:  to just go through all of our top stories for
Speaker 4:  the year, but then this idea got complicated by the idea of how you would
Speaker 4:  make such a list. David, what have
Speaker 5:  You done? Yeah, So. I. When I raised that I wanted to do some kind of end
Speaker 5:  of the year thing. I was like, how do we sort of pick out
Speaker 5:  the biggest stories of the year? Do we all come with our ideas for the biggest
Speaker 5:  stories? Do we come up with a list and try to rank them? And you were just
Speaker 5:  like, what if we just like took the top posts on The Verge dot com and
Speaker 5:  went through them all and decided like were those actually the top stories
Speaker 5:  of the year? And I was like, cool. Sounds fun.
Speaker 5:  Horrible idea. We're gonna do it. but it was a horrible idea.
Speaker 5:  So we went through and basically two ways that we measure traffic
Speaker 5:  on The Verge dot com are through Google Analytics and through a tool called
Speaker 5:  Parsley. They, it turns out have very different ideas
Speaker 5:  about how much traffic a page is getting So. What I ultimately did was
Speaker 5:  look at both of them and then I sort of triangulated a
Speaker 5:  list of the most popular VERGE stories of 2023. But
Speaker 5:  in order to do that you have to get rid of all the stories that are just
Speaker 5:  like obviously successful because people search for those things all the
Speaker 5:  time. Right. Like a piece of fun inside baseball is that the single most
Speaker 5:  popular VERGE URL after our homepage in 2023
Speaker 5:  was our roundup of the best wireless earbuds. Sure.
Speaker 5:  And there's tons of those, right? We do buying guides, they're really good,
Speaker 5:  they're really helpful. Lots of people find them. Lots of people I stuff
Speaker 5:  it's great. Then we have things like explainers. we have an NFT
Speaker 5:  explainer from like two years ago I think. Yep.
Speaker 5:  That is still lingering as one of our most popular stories.
Speaker 4:  The best part about that explainer by the way is it's, is it's Mitchell Clark
Speaker 4:  I believe wrote it and it is basically a reason why no one should buy an
Speaker 4:  NFT. It's
Speaker 5:  Also the reason Mitchell Clark left the Virgin and like moved to the woods.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  He's like, I need to walk around the west coast for a long time and he is
Speaker 4:  been doing ever since. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And then, yeah and then we, there were like some random things that we just
Speaker 5:  left off because they're popular for reasons that are not newsworthiness.
Speaker 5:  Like a sort of one-off story that James Vincent on our team wrote about
Speaker 5:  deep fake nudes that for reasons don don't need to explain but are very
Speaker 5:  obvious, was very popular on the internet all year.
Speaker 5:  So point is, I whittled all this down into I think an imperfect but like
Speaker 5:  directionally useful list of the
Speaker 5:  most popular stories on The Verge dot com in 2023
Speaker 5:  minus
Speaker 4:  The list of best laptops minus
Speaker 5:  The list of best laptops. Yeah. And which
Speaker 4:  Is a great list.
Speaker 5:  Oh, tons of good stuff. I, I highly recommend Googling all those things
Speaker 5:  and clicking on The Verge links many times so that they keep being popular
Speaker 5:  in 2024 and So. what I wanna do with each of these is just go through
Speaker 5:  and basically I wanna decide for each of these, does this
Speaker 5:  belong on like biggest stories of 2023 list? Because a lot of these, they
Speaker 5:  have their moments, people get very excited, like there's a huge sort of
Speaker 5:  spike in interest in traffic and then they die out. Others live much longer.
Speaker 5:  So I wanna go through and see like, does this merit
Speaker 5:  a list of the best biggest stories of 2023?
Speaker 5:  And the first one, and again I'm going in a pure list of
Speaker 5:  popularity. This has no, no judgment. The first one
Speaker 5:  is a big feature we wrote about Inside Elon Musk's, extremely
Speaker 5:  hardcore Twitter. And there were a few others on this list, including the
Speaker 5:  one where Elon Musk predicted that X will replace banks. He gave
Speaker 5:  employees a year to replace banks. Yeah. And then there was the whole
Speaker 5:  Zuckerberg Elon Musk cage match challenge. So I've just boiled all of this
Speaker 5:  down to Musk Twitter X shenanigans. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  The one thing I'll point out, just having looked at the list
Speaker 4:  You don, I don't often think about our URL slugs and the Zuckerberg versus
Speaker 4:  Musk slug had the word world star in it, which is just the funniest thing.
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 5:  Fantastic.
Speaker 4:  It was like Musk Zuckerberg cage match
Speaker 4:  worldstar and it just did numbers. And now I, now I've learned an important
Speaker 4:  lesson about putting word worldstar in all of our headphones. There you go.
Speaker 4:  All of our headlines.
Speaker 4:  I see why this is the, this is the biggest story of the year
Speaker 5:  It deserves to be here. Right?
Speaker 4:  Right. I mean it it, we've talked about this now at length. We've done a
Speaker 4:  huge package on it. Like this thing
Speaker 4:  catalyzed a reordering of the internet and, and maybe you think
Speaker 4:  I'm going too far. I really think that that's true. And the only thing that
Speaker 4:  I'm missing when I say that is also the whole AI Google search dilemma
Speaker 4:  is like right next to that. But this thing just catalyzed
Speaker 4:  a rethinking of the social internet in big ways. It threads is the number
Speaker 4:  one app on the app store. Macedon is growing interest in activity,
Speaker 4:  pub is growing threads, is gonna do activity. Like all of that
Speaker 4:  massively catalyzed by Elon's purchase
Speaker 4:  of Twitter. Then next to that, you know that story extremely hardcore.
Speaker 4:  You know, I'm just like a Verge level. We co-produced that story with
Speaker 4:  New York Magazine. It was on the cover of New York Magazine. We made
Speaker 4:  that story with Casey and Zoe, a Platformer and Alex Heath on our team.
Speaker 4:  So it was just like, just from me personally, like
Speaker 4:  a lot of people had to work together in a way that people in media don't
Speaker 4:  often work together to make something really great. That story's really great
Speaker 4:  and it is the story of a culture change inside of a company
Speaker 4:  and what it was like in those early days. Tons and tons and tons of great
Speaker 4:  reporting. And that immediately led to not like just
Speaker 4:  reflection, obviously interest, but a bunch of other companies being like,
Speaker 4:  what if we were a little bit more hardcore? And you just immediately saw
Speaker 4:  that Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's right.
Speaker 4:  Pinging pong around sort of tech culture.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. There was that brief moment where everybody was taking a page out of
Speaker 5:  Musk's book and being like, that was like how a lot of people excused bringing
Speaker 5:  people back to the office. They were like, it's time to Yep. It's time to
Speaker 5:  get serious. Like stop being so nice to your employees.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We're gonna lay off a bunch of you. It was like a real thing that happened.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Sort of in the wake of Elon. Yeah. Like what if we had 50% less people
Speaker 4:  and then a bunch of companies realized like, oh that wouldn't work. And Elon
Speaker 4:  was like, what if we did it again?
Speaker 5:  Well, we're gonna get to the layoffs in a minute here. Yeah. But Richard,
Speaker 5:  you sit in the news all day. This is, this is the biggest story of the year.
Speaker 5:  Right.
Speaker 6:  I was at a holiday party for my wife's job the other day and I,
Speaker 6:  I was telling them kind of what it's like to work in this job. And
Speaker 6:  this year really for the last few years, a lot of it has been, oh, Elon just
Speaker 6:  did a thing over and over and over
Speaker 6:  again. If you are tired of reading the news, I am tired of
Speaker 6:  thinking about writing it and talking about it. The number of
Speaker 6:  stories that we did not write is much longer than the story number of stories
Speaker 6:  that we published or that we considered. and it's one of those things where
Speaker 6:  Neil, I think you're, you're extremely right about all the things that it
Speaker 6:  covered, but it was even more than that. It was security, it was policy,
Speaker 6:  it was international. Even the layoffs, how they happen in different countries
Speaker 6:  across different continents and were affected by different laws. We had the
Speaker 6:  lawsuit, we had the whistleblower who came back and said that Twitter was
Speaker 6:  wildly insecure before and talked about the things that the previous administration
Speaker 6:  was doing.
Speaker 6:  We, we had the, the woman who was sleeping in her cubicle Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Who then got fired and later
Speaker 6:  Got fired. It was a, it was a momentary star. We, we had, there were
Speaker 6:  just so many things that happened. I, I can't remember all of them. Or even
Speaker 6:  one 10th I think. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think that's right. I think which is impressive actually. 'cause
Speaker 5:  that means Elon Musk is the story of the year, two years in a row because
Speaker 5:  all of the chaos of the acquisition was very much that thing in 2022.
Speaker 5:  So here's hoping we don't make it a threepeat. On that note, let's move on
Speaker 5:  next on the list. I I, I would not have put this second, but I'm not
Speaker 5:  surprised it's actually here is the Vision Pro are are just in
Speaker 5:  initial announcement post was number two
Speaker 5:  and Neli, you're hands on getting to
Speaker 5:  try it face
Speaker 4:  On
Speaker 5:  Your face on was also on this list too.
Speaker 5:  Not surprising to me that this is the gadget of the year. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's the newest, most impressive thing.
Speaker 4:  It has the biggest ideas. It had the flashiest launch. It's, it's Apple.
Speaker 4:  You know, Apple's always gonna be on that list. I'll, I'll just do a
Speaker 4:  spoiler way down on this list, but still in the top whatever, 50
Speaker 4:  D iPhone, 15 pro. Like it's just, it's just there. Yep. I get it. And also
Speaker 4:  people are just really curious, you know, it's like a new hardware category
Speaker 4:  from Apple, what are they gonna do better than everyone else?
Speaker 4:  I think that some of that interest will carry through the
Speaker 4:  actual launch. But you know what surprised me is that the HandsOn did
Speaker 4:  as well because it was, as I was writing it, I was like, there's no way to
Speaker 4:  convey what's actually happening. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 4:  You just, you're, I'm dancing with architecture like I'm, I'm doing the thing
Speaker 4:  here where like I can't take a picture of it. I can't show it to you. I can
Speaker 4:  just write about it around, around it, you
Speaker 5:  Know? Yeah. I was sitting one table over from you
Speaker 5:  at Apple Park in their visitor center while you were writing this story and
Speaker 5:  you came out and you were just like, I think I just have to write about all
Speaker 5:  the things that happened in a row and I think that's all I can do. And I
Speaker 5:  was like, yeah, I think that's all you can do. That's what you did. Turned
Speaker 5:  out people liked it worked out great.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  All right. Number three on the list was, I believe this was Liz
Speaker 5:  Lipato on the last day of the Sam Bankman free trial. Her headline was Sam
Speaker 5:  Bankman Fried gambled on a trial and his parents lost. But I think to some
Speaker 5:  extent, A, this is a terrific piece, but B was
Speaker 5:  the, the summary of the S-B-F-F-T-X
Speaker 5:  trial, which Richard like definitely belongs on this list.
Speaker 5:  Right. Biggest stories of the year. Surely
Speaker 6:  O over the last year we saw this kind of coming at the end of 2022 as
Speaker 6:  FTX collapsed, Sam, Bankman Fried went on a massive media tour and then he
Speaker 6:  was arrested. Right.
Speaker 5:  Like you do
Speaker 6:  A very strange sequence of events
Speaker 6:  arrested and extradited from The Bahamas. And then we had the trial and it
Speaker 6:  all kind of wrapped up within a year. And I think the verdict came in a year
Speaker 6:  to the day after CoinDesk had published this kind of expose of what turned
Speaker 6:  out to be just one of their balance sheets showing some really
Speaker 6:  serious problems within FTX. But Liz,
Speaker 6:  I thought that in particular this piece dug into the personal side of it
Speaker 6:  of who Sam Bankman Fried was and what it meant for him to
Speaker 6:  view the world in the way that he did and how that resulted in both the
Speaker 6:  growth of FTX, the way that the investors and the people who backed it were
Speaker 6:  kind of drawn into it and they saw an opportunity in, in this person
Speaker 6:  and in this company. And then what happened after it all
Speaker 6:  fell apart and after he was on trial and why, why someone
Speaker 6:  would go to trial on this, why they would risk all of this. When we all saw
Speaker 6:  it, when we all read it and we were like, yeah, he's going to be found guilty.
Speaker 6:  Right. And he was, yeah, but how, how we got there.
Speaker 4:  I always think that the tagline for The Verge is how technology
Speaker 4:  makes us feel. You know, it's just like it doesn't work in ad meetings. Like
Speaker 4:  that's where you need tagline, what we're excited about the future, whatever.
Speaker 4:  But this one to me is like a perfect encapsulation of that. Like
Speaker 4:  we're not a financial publication, we're not really a business publication.
Speaker 4:  Sometimes I think we're like a secret business publication. We're, we cover
Speaker 4:  tech really closely, but we cover like this very human part of it. We
Speaker 4:  spend a lot of time on that thing. And to me, Liz just
Speaker 4:  found that line in this trial. Her, her coverage of this trial through and
Speaker 4:  through was amazing. Yeah. But this one, it just made
Speaker 4:  it sad. Like yes, he scanned a lot of people out of a lot of money. Yes.
Speaker 4:  All this stuff. And there's just a sadness to it. And if you even read the
Speaker 4:  comments or like to people posting on threads about it or whatever, people
Speaker 4:  caught that sadness and it really resonated with him. Like, if you're just
Speaker 4:  a parent and your kid has this big belief and he is on the rocket ride, like
Speaker 4:  you're, you're just not motivated to be like, well my kid's a shit.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And there's just something in there. It is. It's worth reading and
Speaker 4:  just like really sitting with, 'cause Liz caught it like Exactly. And she
Speaker 4:  was in the courtroom every day and she was just watching this happen to these
Speaker 4:  people. And there's something in there that I think is just really powerful.
Speaker 4:  It's like, it's very literary. It's like what I want The Verge to be at.
Speaker 4:  Its, its best even that it was a trial about cryptocurrency scams. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I will say it, this is a totally unfair thing to say whatever, six
Speaker 5:  and a half weeks after the trial, but there has been less
Speaker 5:  ongoing fallout from the FTX trial than I expected. I'm sure there's a lot
Speaker 5:  of stuff brewing, but when the trial ended it felt like a lot of people kind
Speaker 5:  of, you know, white wiped their hands of it and moved on at their lives.
Speaker 5:  It was like, oh, oh no
Speaker 4:  Here. Here's one thing I know Richard remembers the
Speaker 4:  people who use, I
Speaker 6:  Remember everyone who ever tried to sell an NFT and I will follow them
Speaker 6:  forever. It'll never
Speaker 4:  Drop receipts. Lawler over here has not forgotten a goddamn thing.
Speaker 5:  What I
Speaker 6:  Was gonna say is there, there actually has been some fallout. We've seen
Speaker 6:  several other executives go down. That's true. We've seen Binance started
Speaker 6:  the entire run against FTX. They have had a guilty plea to criminal charges.
Speaker 6:  Their CEO is in America and cannot leave because he is a flight risk
Speaker 6:  there. There are still things going on. I think we're gonna, we're gonna
Speaker 6:  see these echoes just con kind of continue throughout crypto and throughout
Speaker 6:  the financial industry. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  All, right. Next one. This is just to, you know, take you further
Speaker 5:  inside the parsley Google analytics thing on Google Analytics.
Speaker 5:  This was I think in like the top three most popular stories of the year.
Speaker 5:  and it was nowhere on parsley, So, I, don't know what to make of that. So
Speaker 5:  I, just put it in here. This is Gen Two's story about Amazon opening
Speaker 5:  up its Sidewalk network to give any gadget free low speed data. I
Speaker 5:  remember being very surprised at how well this story was doing at the time.
Speaker 5:  It's a good story. But like I was shocked that that many people care about
Speaker 5:  Sidewalk as a thing.
Speaker 4:  I'm convinced that the words free data are the
Speaker 4:  thing
Speaker 5:  That's interesting.
Speaker 4:  Right? Any gadget free data, you get it. It's fair.
Speaker 4:  I immediately understood people are out there in the streets with their chums
Speaker 4:  when like, how do I connect to these Sidewalk networks?
Speaker 6:  There was also a sort of weird discussion that popped up around this where
Speaker 6:  people were like, oh, your echo is suddenly going to give away your internet
Speaker 6:  capacity to whoever wants to you. Oh, that's, so you need to change the thing.
Speaker 4:  That's true. And your ring cameras, a bunch of stuff has Sidewalk enabled
Speaker 4:  and the idea is that you can build stuff like Amazon has trackers like
Speaker 4:  tile and air tag, competitive track airing stuff. They have pet tags and
Speaker 4:  so you need to build this like big mesh network and you
Speaker 4:  would participate in it. don, don't think any of this has really come to
Speaker 4:  pass, right?
Speaker 5:  No.
Speaker 4:  Like there's not a lot of Sidewalk stuff out there yet.
Speaker 5:  This is the first story on the list that I'm like, this doesn't really belong
Speaker 5:  on the biggest stories of 2023 list, which is no slate to gin.
Speaker 5:  It's a great story. But yeah, I think Sidewalk is a longer term
Speaker 5:  super interesting thing. This idea of like these local mesh networks is really
Speaker 5:  fascinating but is not like in people's lives
Speaker 5:  and brands.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Amazon has a page that's like Amazon Sidewalk
Speaker 4:  gadgets on amazon.com and it's a long list of like
Speaker 4:  FAQ questions and what you can use and the only products you can buy are
Speaker 4:  bridges.
Speaker 5:  Oh,
Speaker 4:  Perfect. Like you can buy echo devices and ring cameras and there's not one
Speaker 4:  thing that you can do with it.
Speaker 5:  Connect all your stuff, do nothing.
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 6:  Will say this, the coverage map is looking a lot more filled in if you click
Speaker 6:  to their page compared to the version that we have in here. So it's still
Speaker 6:  going, but they've also had an executive change for Amazon So. I don't know
Speaker 6:  what the priority will be for this going forward. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's true. Panos pane now runs devices and services at
Speaker 4:  Amazon.
Speaker 5:  We'll see Panos free data for everybody. Let's do this. Okay, next up.
Speaker 5:  Sony's portable PlayStation Portal launches on November 15th for 1 99.
Speaker 5:  99. This is the single most surprising thing to me on the list.
Speaker 5:  Mostly because No way the Portal is stupid.
Speaker 4:  Well they, nobody knows that. I know that's true. One, look, you, you've
Speaker 4:  done that. See you. No way. You do this for long enough. You get jaded, you
Speaker 4:  get, you know, you gotta, you gotta sand that off. You gotta look at this
Speaker 4:  with beginner's eyes, David. You're right. People are like, there's a new
Speaker 4:  PlayStation. I'm super hype about it. And the from August it looks crazy.
Speaker 5:  Life was so simple in August.
Speaker 4:  Right? They're like, it looks crazy. It's got these weird handle
Speaker 4:  controllers. Like it could also be a battering. It's only
Speaker 4:  $199. I haven't been told about the ridiculous limitations of
Speaker 4:  this device yet. I understand why people clicked on this story. Yeah. 200
Speaker 4:  PlayStation. Yeah. On the go,
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 4:  Can tell you. And then you're like confidently and it also only works in
Speaker 4:  your house.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. How to buy the Portal not on the popular list. I'll tell you that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. I know. You're right. This was exciting at the moment and it
Speaker 5:  felt interesting. Cloud gaming was a thing people talked about all year.
Speaker 5:  It was like there was a lot going on. I can see it, but boyed that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Look, I'm, I'm, I I don't, I'm not gonna be like the, the entire media's
Speaker 4:  editor in chief. The, the difference between The Verge and it, everything
Speaker 4:  else is we're excited about technology often
Speaker 4:  because I've watched this cycle a million times. Right. People are gonna
Speaker 4:  be excited about the PlayStation Portal and like, I, I know,
Speaker 4:  I know, right? But I'm not gonna, we have this, we're not gonna like
Speaker 4:  harsh your vibe right at the beginning. Everyone else is like, this is stupid.
Speaker 4:  Technology's stupid. We're not gonna do that. We're here for you. We're gonna
Speaker 4:  talk about USBC for a full
Speaker 5:  Hour
Speaker 6:  And if you wanna carry around an LCD screen to play pss fives games on,
Speaker 6:  we're here for you. Yeah. I support, I, I personally support your choices,
Speaker 5:  But technically we're not here for you because you have to be in your house
Speaker 5:  and, and we have to be in our house. We can't actually be here for you.
Speaker 5:  Really. Sorry
Speaker 6:  For you.
Speaker 4:  I would say from far away the next one on your list is exactly the same story.
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 5:  Was just about to say, speaking of cool promises that vastly under-delivered
Speaker 5:  Google announces the Pixel fold.
Speaker 5:  WW
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That didn't go great.
Speaker 5:  I wanted to love the Pixel fold. I have a Pixel fold sitting right here and
Speaker 5:  I still look at it and I'm like, why aren't you better?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean I would say all of the hardware we saw,
Speaker 4:  the Pixel tablet was also a kind of a disaster that
Speaker 5:  Year. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 4:  Last year, I should say this past year, the the, the Pixel
Speaker 4:  folded. I think what people were hoping, and I'm,
Speaker 4:  this is just, this is a vibes based analysis, but I think what people
Speaker 4:  were hoping was that Google would've gotten it right in a way that Samsung
Speaker 4:  has not gotten it right or would be cleaner in a way that
Speaker 4:  a Samsung device is just a cacophony of capitalism.
Speaker 4:  And maybe, you know, Google's not right, but it also just like not more useful
Speaker 4:  than a regular Pixel phone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's And it's expensive. Yeah. Where we landed was like, this thing
Speaker 5:  is $1,800 and it doesn't make a particularly good case for itself.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The thing that always amazes me is like, it's just heavy.
Speaker 5:  It's just a big chunky brick of a thing.
Speaker 5:  And I still have high hopes for the fold too. I'm not gonna lie to you.
Speaker 4:  And it doesn't even run decks. Yeah. Am I right? Look, if you could take
Speaker 4:  a go, if you could take a Pixel fold and turn it into a proper Chromebook,
Speaker 4:  let's talk. You know who I'm talking to. Let's talk,
Speaker 5:  Which brings me into my next story. I love Dex by Dan Siefert. No, I'm just
Speaker 5:  kidding.
Speaker 6:  The other problem with the Pixel fold is that it's both massively expensive
Speaker 6:  and several months, just a few months later, they brought out a better phone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That wasn't foldable and it was cheaper. So
Speaker 6:  you don't have the new hardware and the new AI capabilities in the new Pixel.
Speaker 6:  It's just folds. And so, so you've, you've paid all this money and you don't
Speaker 6:  have the best phone. It's just the wrong, the wrong mix of things. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I really, I think the The Verge audience wants to love the
Speaker 5:  Pixel maybe more than it wants to love any other
Speaker 5:  individual device. Yeah. And like there's a lot to like about the Pixel,
Speaker 5:  but the Pixel continues to be
Speaker 5:  more loved than it deserves among our audience I think. And
Speaker 5:  by among our staff in a lot of ways. I love the Pixel
Speaker 5:  despite the fact that like Samsung objectively makes better Cut
Speaker 4:  This moment in time. Can't wait to get to the one Samsung guy on
Speaker 5:  This list.
Speaker 4:  I won't give it away now, but there's only one Samsung on
Speaker 5:  This list. All, right? Yeah. We can keep moving. So the next one is VW beats
Speaker 5:  Tesla to the punch and unveils an affordable electric vehicle. This
Speaker 5:  was from March when VW
Speaker 5:  announced the the ID to all
Speaker 5:  one of the worst names of all time. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's not great.
Speaker 5:  Like when you look at a name and you think, oh that has to be a typo. I should
Speaker 5:  fix that. You did it bad ID Capital I,
Speaker 5:  capital d.space number two. Lowercase.
Speaker 5:  A LL dot what? That's nothing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's not great. Nothing about this is crazy,
Speaker 5:  Crazy. This does not belong on the list. Great headline. Exciting times.
Speaker 5:  Great headline does not belong on the list. Great
Speaker 4:  Headline.
Speaker 6:  Also Vaporware car.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. VW make buttons. Yeah, that's good. But make cars.
Speaker 4:  I just realized there's no cyber truck wiper coverage on this list and I
Speaker 4:  don don't know what we're doing here guys. I gotta, we gotta go.
Speaker 5:  I should have mentioned I took all cyber truck, cyber truck wiper coverage
Speaker 5:  off because it just would've dominated the whole list. And who has the time?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Next one. A pretty recent piece of news. Sam Altman fired as CEO of
Speaker 5:  OpenAI. This one I like very much because this is
Speaker 5:  both extremely deserving as one of the biggest stories of 2023 and
Speaker 5:  extremely not deserving at the same time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. A story in which almost nothing happened at the end. Right.
Speaker 5:  But it was captivating in a way that I think no other single
Speaker 5:  news event in our world of 2023 was,
Speaker 5:  I can't think of another moment like that. This year
Speaker 4:  I maintain a list of tiktoks that should be PhD theses in media studies.
Speaker 4:  Sure. One day I'm gonna publish the entire list. And a lot of them were
Speaker 4:  tiktoks just like reading our stories about OpenAI drama and then
Speaker 4:  imposing like their own TikTok drama
Speaker 4:  narratives on them. Which was, it was just like I could, the thing
Speaker 4:  that interests me about that is like, it was a story that could be everything
Speaker 4:  to everyone. Like no matter what you thought or how you felt,
Speaker 4:  you could take this like guy got fired. Employees like guy,
Speaker 4:  guy comes back and you could just, it's like the hero's
Speaker 4:  journey man. It's like you just put any, any story you want onto that foundation.
Speaker 4:  Totally. And they did what hap you know what happened in there is actually
Speaker 4:  really meaningful, right? Like Microsoft is involved, they were taken aback.
Speaker 4:  There's a lot of reporting now that comes out that's like maybe Sam was lying
Speaker 4:  to the board, but the board couldn't point to any specific instances.
Speaker 4:  There's gonna be an investigation, but you're right in the moment
Speaker 4:  it was captivating. It was also Thanksgiving. Like literally nothing else
Speaker 4:  was going on. I think it's on those, I think this is one of those
Speaker 4:  moments when like governance of ai like
Speaker 4:  jumped all the way to the top of people's minds for a minute. That at least
Speaker 4:  means the next time we have to talk about it, everyone is
Speaker 4:  initiated into the vocabulary. Which is good.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We like have a shared reality of AI chaos now, which is useful.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The thing that struck me about this one is it's the, it's the lens
Speaker 6:  sanity story of the list.
Speaker 4:  It's both
Speaker 6:  The one that came completely out of nowhere. I think one of the things that,
Speaker 6:  that hits me when we have big stories is that when I think, oh man, we should
Speaker 6:  have seen that coming. We should have been more prepared or had something
Speaker 6:  ready. Did not see this one coming at all. Could not have seen it coming.
Speaker 6:  No, no. It just dropped in the middle of the day and suddenly we're reading
Speaker 6:  it all together and we're like, wait, he's fired. Yeah. Did that
Speaker 6:  just happen? It also as you mentioned happened when nothing else was happening.
Speaker 6:  So yeah,
Speaker 4:  Also for me personally working on this story with Alex e while at
Speaker 4:  Disney World, truly one of the most surreal, surreal
Speaker 4:  moments of the year and potentially
Speaker 5:  If they were ever gonna make a sports documentary about you and Eli, it would
Speaker 5:  be that that weekend
Speaker 4:  Can, I'm just gonna, I'm gonna, I'm gonna, there are two things happen to
Speaker 4:  me at the Outer Rim bar at the Cont Disney's Contemporary
Speaker 4:  Resort one,
Speaker 4:  I talked to Alex about the story a whole bunch, which is just weird, right?
Speaker 4:  My family's there, it's Disney World, like Mickey's singing or whatever Mickey's
Speaker 4:  doing in the restaurant. And I'm like talking about opening eye. The second
Speaker 4:  is I went to the bar after that conversation, I sat down and I was informed
Speaker 4:  that there are regulars of the Outer Rim bar at Disney's Contemporary
Speaker 4:  Resort. And a bunch of regulars were there to watch football and many of
Speaker 4:  the regulars travel for hours to come to this bar.
Speaker 4:  And I'm like looking around. I mean it's not,
Speaker 4:  it's just like, you know, it's like, it's one of those hotels where the,
Speaker 4:  the middle is like wide open and you can, you could see into
Speaker 4:  the brunch spot where like Mickey was singing and I was like, y'all come
Speaker 4:  here and like we love it here. And I was like, I need to get outta Florida.
Speaker 4:  Like I need to go away.
Speaker 5:  If you stay longer than six days, you never leave.
Speaker 4:  It's like don don't. And there are other cities.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, there are other televisions people.
Speaker 4:  But like, keep in mind this is what was happening to me while we were doing
Speaker 4:  the OpenAI reporting. I'm, I'm like a dead certain, some of
Speaker 4:  that bled into the OpenAI reporting, like
Speaker 5:  Emotionally the whole thing got more chaotic over time, which feels right
Speaker 5:  for, for your situation. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I was like, we all have to get out Florida metaphorically and literally
Speaker 5:  Next up on the list is FDC versus Microsoft. This is the story
Speaker 5:  stream that Tom Warren mostly did during the FTC versus
Speaker 5:  Microsoft trial. And a fun fact
Speaker 4:  The Activision trial,
Speaker 5:  What is that?
Speaker 4:  This is the Activision deal.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, the Activision trial. The fun fact about this one is that
Speaker 5:  this is the only story on this list for which Google was not
Speaker 5:  the top referrer. Basically any story that's going to like have a long
Speaker 5:  life on the internet ends up getting a lot of traffic from Google. 'cause
Speaker 5:  that's just how people find things. Google discover. Google News. Like Google
Speaker 5:  is sort of the long tail of internet traffic. This is the only
Speaker 5:  one on our most popular list where the number one traffic refer
Speaker 5:  was The Verge dot com, which meant that people typed in The Verge dot com
Speaker 5:  to go find Tom's news about an Activision trial. And I
Speaker 5:  think that kicks ass
Speaker 4:  Also. I think if the year wasn't ending now
Speaker 4:  Sean's coverage of Google versus Epic. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I think that's right.
Speaker 4:  Have a similar traffic curve, but it just ha it just happened towards the
Speaker 4:  end of the year. The Microsoft case was earlier in the year also, you know,
Speaker 4:  Activision is a little, this was a little sexier deal I think
Speaker 4:  in the court case was more was revealed. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I think what one thing that I have taken away from all the trial coverage
Speaker 4:  this year, and it's like a lot of it, it's a little overwhelming even for
Speaker 4:  me and I love it, is boy, there's just a lot of backroom
Speaker 4:  shenanigans at all these companies. We think these companies are sort of
Speaker 4:  like operating in the marketplace and they are not like, they are
Speaker 4:  constantly thinking of like every possible way they can turn every single
Speaker 4:  deal into an advantage. And that's, you know,
Speaker 4:  this one, they obviously took over Activision. The FCC has appealed. We'll
Speaker 4:  see how that goes. But you know, I think Microsoft's people's perception
Speaker 4:  of Microsoft changed after you like read a bunch of their internal emails
Speaker 4:  about how this will happen.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, this was a really interesting one. I feel like this was the kind of
Speaker 5:  thing that just kept being interesting day after day after day after day.
Speaker 5:  Like so many of these trials have sort of ebbs and flows,
Speaker 5:  but FTC versus Microsoft was very compressed. It happened very quickly and
Speaker 5:  a ton of stuff happened. And we also learned that like Microsoft thinks it
Speaker 5:  would be cool to buy a Nintendo and it became a whole fight about Call of
Speaker 5:  Duty. It was just like all of the like biggest sexiest names in
Speaker 5:  gaming and entertainment, just yelling at each other. It was great.
Speaker 5:  Next up on the list, Buckle up because El Nino is almost here and it's going
Speaker 5:  to get hot. And maybe the best headline we published this year, NELI has
Speaker 5:  a theory about Buckle up headlines. Andy. Oh, it's not your theory.
Speaker 4:  No, it's not my theory. It's Andy Hawkins, our transportation editor. Every
Speaker 4:  time we run a Buckle up headline and does numbers, he just says people love
Speaker 4:  buckling up. Which is totally true. Like if you put
Speaker 4:  Buckle up in a headline, people are like, I love to Buckle up. I need to
Speaker 4:  know what's gonna happen. Our climate coverage does surprisingly well. I
Speaker 4:  think we have, we have a young audience. People love it. People like being
Speaker 4:  able to share the stories, like their skeptical friends and family. Generally
Speaker 4:  there's a sense that like this is, this coverage is talking to an audience
Speaker 4:  of itself, but Justine, our climate reporter, and Andy who's her editor,
Speaker 4:  they do a really good job of making mistakes real. And I was ha I'm happy.
Speaker 4:  The stories like,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah, I agree. Justine does a really good job of covering climate stuff
Speaker 5:  like for regular people just living their lives day to day, which
Speaker 5:  is cool.
Speaker 5:  Okay, next up we have the iPhone 15 Pro and Prom max launch.
Speaker 5:  I'm actually surprised this was this low. Why? Just, it's the iPhone like
Speaker 5:  don don't know. The. Verge is like founded on the iPhone being a big deal.
Speaker 4:  It's an iPhone.
Speaker 4:  That's true. Not the iPhones, smartphones. Our early days
Speaker 4:  were like, will this Motorola phone and it won't. No.
Speaker 4:  They put
Speaker 6:  USBC on it and, and that's, that's most of
Speaker 6:  what we have to say.
Speaker 4:  I wonder if we made this list over a long enough period of time for every
Speaker 4:  year we could track the sort of dominance of the iPhone by how
Speaker 4:  high or low it is in the list. 'cause my sense is that it's trending
Speaker 4:  down.
Speaker 5:  Oh, that's interesting, right?
Speaker 4:  That like the new I, the newest iPhone is no longer the most important techniques
Speaker 4:  of the year has not, and that has been the case for a while now. There was
Speaker 4:  a case, there was a time when it was the most important techniques of the
Speaker 4:  year, the year after
Speaker 5:  Year. Yeah, I think that's right. It's still big. Like I think to some extent
Speaker 5:  it's interesting that it's the only SQL device
Speaker 5:  on the list. Everything else is like sort of brand new in some meaningful
Speaker 5:  way. This is the 15th iPhone, like the Galaxy S
Speaker 5:  23 did not make the list. You know what I mean? The Pixel eight didn't make
Speaker 5:  the list. No. So it's, it's definitely in a league of its own in that way.
Speaker 5:  But I do think it's true that I bet it it has sort of fallen down
Speaker 5:  the scale on Google Analytics over the last whatever, 12 years
Speaker 5:  of The Verge existence.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The flip side of that is that people are still really interested in
Speaker 4:  the iPhone, which, yes, again, if you kind of look in the broader press or
Speaker 4:  the conventional wisdom or in the culture, there's a sense that people are
Speaker 4:  over it. And then we look at our list and it's like, oh, this is still very
Speaker 4:  high in this list. Like, yeah, being up on the verges traffic lift
Speaker 4:  represents a lot of traffic.
Speaker 5:  The the numbers on all of these are enormous, I should just say. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Okay, next one. We have a couple more to do and then we'll get outta here.
Speaker 5:  This is Microsoft's new disc list. Xbox series X design with a lift
Speaker 5:  to weight controller. Richard. This was another FTC versus Microsoft thing.
Speaker 5:  Wasn't that there was like that run where we got accidentally a bunch of
Speaker 5:  cool leaks, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. A document was posted, I think from Microsoft that
Speaker 6:  accidentally didn't redact a bunch of things in it and that revealed
Speaker 6:  some of their future plans. And this is what we saw, the, the
Speaker 6:  cylindrical Xbox series X successor that maybe we'll see someday, maybe
Speaker 6:  we won't, their plans for future controller. What they want for the series
Speaker 6:  S, what they want for Game Pass, all of these things. And this is, this is
Speaker 6:  the second time that we've seen these kinds of plans from Microsoft. There
Speaker 6:  was a Florida leads leak years ago. Oh yeah. And you know,
Speaker 6:  people just love these. I I I don't think there was anything that
Speaker 6:  absurd about the, you know, kind of revealed in these, these documents. But
Speaker 6:  just seeing a console that they haven't launched yet and Who knows maybe
Speaker 6:  they never will
Speaker 6:  was, was ridiculous.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And Phil Spencer had to put out a statement. He was like, no,
Speaker 4:  this is a thing. We try everything. He was just like, he was very sad about
Speaker 4:  it. The thing looks cool. I will say it looks great.
Speaker 5:  It does. And the thing I, I continue to be very excited about the idea of
Speaker 5:  a console that is actually just inside of a controller and you just connect
Speaker 5:  the controller to a screen and you can play that way. Like that's the future.
Speaker 5:  Give me that. Sadia was right about everything.
Speaker 6:  And one of the things that we learned here is that Microsoft is looking at
Speaker 6:  it that way too. They found, they, I think their phrase was that the controller
Speaker 6:  is the hero and they, they're like, oh, you know, you can plug your Xbox
Speaker 6:  controller into whatever and play Xbox game.
Speaker 5:  Make it happen. Microsoft. Yeah. All. right? Last one.
Speaker 4:  P And Sony was like, the PSS five is weirder than ever.
Speaker 5:  Do you like Spider-Man, here's some.
Speaker 4:  This can only be, you can never put this on its side. Don't even try.
Speaker 6:  Weirdly no one had issues with us reporting on this one. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  'cause it was in the trial. I mean that's just like whatever. It's like
Speaker 5:  All. right? We're gonna, we have one more on the list, but first I'd like
Speaker 5:  to read you a handful of honorable mentions. Okay. We had stories about
Speaker 5:  layoffs that were huge this year. We had a story about the Steam
Speaker 5:  Deck that Sean wrote that was very good. Ironically, he wrote it
Speaker 5:  before the new Steam Deck came out. but it was a big year for the Steam Deck
Speaker 4:  Sean, the Steam Deck in The Verge dot com.
Speaker 5:  It's just beautiful. Like
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It just all comes together. It's just, it belongs together. Just don't
Speaker 4:  leave. Don't touch it. Leave it alone. I
Speaker 5:  Agree. Josh Zos piece, Inside the AI Factory about
Speaker 5:  like the real human labor behind AI was hugely popular. Really, really good
Speaker 5:  story. Yep. It's been in a bunch of like best things of 2023 lists I've seen
Speaker 5:  recently. Go read that if you haven't. Chris Person's thing about modding,
Speaker 5:  his SodaStream was really high on the list, which kind of
Speaker 4:  Made me heart happy.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And then Man of Chicago Lewis's very recent story about SEO
Speaker 5:  experts, which pissed off the whole SEO community. Thank you all for reading
Speaker 5:  our story. Loved that. But the last one on the list of
Speaker 5:  the biggest stories of 2023 and one that I think absolutely
Speaker 5:  deserves to be here. Samsung caught faking zoom. photos
Speaker 5:  of the Moon.
Speaker 4:  What is a photo?
Speaker 4:  I'm doing it. It's happening. I
Speaker 5:  Mean, this is it. This is the,
Speaker 4:  What is a photo? This is, this is proof
Speaker 5:  Forever that we get to talk about this as much as we want.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Here's what I'm gonna say. And I look, this is only half a joke,
Speaker 4:  All, right? I love Liam, our producer. But any good podcast needs
Speaker 4:  tension. You need to be fighting against someone who won't let you do what
Speaker 4:  you wanna do. And Liam is the one who says, I can't talk about what is a
Speaker 4:  photo for an hour and a half every week.
Speaker 4:  That's it. We're sticking it to the man. Every click on a, what is a photo
Speaker 4:  article? It's
Speaker 5:  A vote against Liam.
Speaker 4:  No, don't, Liam is wonderful. No, no, no. I'm just, I'm just joking around.
Speaker 4:  But you need, you need the tension. Big content's trying to hold me down.
Speaker 5:  I actually love this story because it is a, what is a photo story, which
Speaker 5:  was genuinely like an ongoing news story all year. It's, it's an AI story.
Speaker 5:  It's a like transparency in what we understand on the internet story. It's
Speaker 5:  a like, what are your gadgets supposed to do for you story? It's like, it
Speaker 5:  kind of has everything all in one fake photo of the Moon.
Speaker 4:  And also the best thing about it is it requires you to understand
Speaker 4:  that every photo of the Moon is the same photo of the Moon,
Speaker 5:  Right? Which is genuinely kind of mind bending.
Speaker 4:  Like the thing about it that is the most interesting to me is like the stakes
Speaker 4:  are zero because you can never take a different photo of the
Speaker 4:  Moon. So like it you,
Speaker 4:  I could fake a photo of the Moon today by just copying in a picture of the
Speaker 4:  Moon and it's, I haven't lied to you because the Moon, it
Speaker 4:  definitely looked like that at that time.
Speaker 4:  I love it. Ah, let's just talk about it for another hour.
Speaker 5:  No, we have to go. That's my list.
Speaker 6:  This had been dug into in 2021. It was, it was a story
Speaker 6:  that came back around and we'll probably come
Speaker 5:  This happen before
Speaker 4:  This. What?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There was a feature from 2021 where Input Magazine
Speaker 6:  talked about the fake detailed Moon photos and they, they kind of explained
Speaker 6:  it then, but they didn't explain it enough and that was why we, we had to
Speaker 6:  do this all over again.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Then. But I will say like a lot of people
Speaker 4:  try to give Samsung an out, you know, be like, it's not really faking. It's
Speaker 4:  like, no, you don't understand. Samsung is taking the longest possible route
Speaker 4:  to putting a clip Art Moon in your photos. You don't need all this
Speaker 4:  ai. Just, just be like, it's the Moon, right? Here's a
Speaker 4:  selection of photos of the Moon that you can have because they're all the
Speaker 4:  same photo. Your stupid eyes and dumb camera
Speaker 4:  aren't required for this. Just print out this photo. I
Speaker 5:  Really love that as a product that it's like every time you take a crappy
Speaker 5:  picture of something, your phone is just like, it's just like looks on the
Speaker 5:  internet and it's like, here's a better photo that of what you just Would
Speaker 5:  you like this one instead?
Speaker 4:  We're so close to it.
Speaker 6:  Fireworks concerts. Just do it. Just
Speaker 4:  The Eiffel Tower. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like somebody already did this, you're good.
Speaker 4:  But the thing is, the different, the difference with the Moon is that
Speaker 4:  no one in the world can take a different photo
Speaker 4:  of the Moon, like the Eiffel Tower, like the Eiffel Tower's always changing.
Speaker 4:  There's like dust in the air, there's people around, there's French people,
Speaker 4:  wizen Bay with Beres and cigarettes. The moon's just there,
Speaker 4:  man. It's been the same.
Speaker 4:  Just give people a photo of the Moon. I love it.
Speaker 5:  Every time you take a picture of the Moon, your printer starts and a picture
Speaker 5:  of the Moon comes out.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's amazing. All, right? That's it. That's my list.
Speaker 5:  Biggest stories of 2023. It's a good year.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it was a pretty good year on The Verge dot com. Yeah, we had a good
Speaker 4:  one. Thanks to everybody for listening to our show, which has been going
Speaker 4:  on now since 2011, and then before that even longer.
Speaker 4:  We've had a lot of notes recently about how many people have been listening
Speaker 4:  this to a whole time. Tell your children I initiating new options.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna be great. No, we had a great year. SAB was great. The
Speaker 4:  Verge persists. We've got a huge year coming both in terms of what we
Speaker 4:  want to cover, what we wanna do, the features on the site we wanna release.
Speaker 4:  I really do think that there's like a new internet coming and I want The
Speaker 4:  Verge to be right at the forefront of it. So I'm really excited about next
Speaker 4:  year. I'm happy to work with these guys. I miss Alex. I had to crans. If
Speaker 4:  you see her gallivanting around the skies of America on Santa Sleigh
Speaker 4:  and that's it. Happy. Have a happy holiday. That's Vergecast
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The Vergecast is
Speaker 1:  a production of The, Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. The show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. This episode was mixed and edited by
Speaker 1:  Xandr Adams, and that's it. We'll see you next week.