# Transcript
ID: 0d21b5e0-cb62-11ed-94ed-e54c3e89f397
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: TikTok goes to Washington
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5695046867528753068/-432767900213348650/s93290-US-5029s-1679785743.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce are joined by policy reporter Makena Kelly, who is on the ground in Washington for the House Energy and Commerce Committee's hearing on TikTok. Later, we dive into all the other news from this week, from Google's release of Bard to OpenAI's rapid expansion of ChatGPT. It was a big week.
Speaker 1:  Support for today's show comes from Deloitte. In the business world, it can
Speaker 1:  be especially crucial to innovate. You can either build your own future or
Speaker 1:  bet on someone else's. No one knows what tomorrow will bring, but you push
Speaker 1:  forward and create enterprise anyway. That's why Deloitte's mission is to
Speaker 1:  help engineer advantage for their clients by harnessing the latest innovations
Speaker 1:  and technology while exploring the ideas and opportunities that can look
Speaker 1:  beyond today. Transform what's next into what's now.
Speaker 1:  See how you can engineer advantage with Deloitte at
Speaker 1:  deloitte.com/us/engineering advantage.
Speaker 3:  Support for this podcast comes from Slack and they're looking to help make
Speaker 3:  you and your team work better. Slack is a productivity platform that
Speaker 3:  connects all your team members together instantly. It's built to help your
Speaker 3:  team with a host of features like huddles for quick check-ins and clips for
Speaker 3:  recording and sharing video. Slack also makes it easy to search and find
Speaker 3:  the right information you need. You can even integrate the apps you use in
Speaker 3:  your normal workflow, like your calendar or project management tools. So
Speaker 3:  stay connected on the work that matters and get more done. Learn more
Speaker 3:  at slack.com/productivity.
Speaker 2:  Hello
Speaker 5:  And welcome to the RO Cast, the flagship podcast to protecting America's
Speaker 5:  interests at home and abroad.
Speaker 1:  I love it. Reporting to you live from the VER studio.
Speaker 5:  This is a new, if you're watching us on YouTube, this is a new setup for
Speaker 5:  me and Alex in the studio.
Speaker 1:  We're having a great time here.
Speaker 5:  It's a very exciting day for us. Anyway, I'm your friend Eli, Alex Trans
Speaker 5:  is here.
Speaker 1:  I'm your friend who is just your friend. I'm just here to hang out. Have
Speaker 1:  a good time. What's happened today?
Speaker 5:  There's a lot. Something happened. David is here. Hey David.
Speaker 6:  Hi. I'm still in my basement. They don't let me out. They fix the studio.
Speaker 6:  I stay the same.
Speaker 5:  And then very importantly, McKenna Kelly is here today. Hey
Speaker 7:  McKenna. Hey everyone. It's good to be here.
Speaker 5:  So a big day in our nation's history. Yes, McKenna
Speaker 5:  attended a hearing today in the House of Representatives
Speaker 5:  where, I don't know how else described it. They just yelled at TikTok,
Speaker 5:  just in generally yelled about TikTok for four and a half hours
Speaker 5:  at the CEO of TikTok. It was maybe the baddest faith
Speaker 5:  of the bad faith tech hearings that we've heard. And then there's a lot of
Speaker 5:  TikTok ERs in dc. McKenna, you attended a press
Speaker 5:  conference with the TikTok ERs say, which I want to hear all about. But the
Speaker 5:  momentum around banning TikTok is as high as I think it's ever been.
Speaker 5:  And I came away from today thinking, oh, this is gonna happen.
Speaker 5:  But you're there McKenna. What? What went down?
Speaker 7:  Right? So as you mentioned, today was a hearing at the House Energy and Commerce
Speaker 7:  Committee. They brought in the C e O of TikTok who
Speaker 7:  provided testimony when he was allowed to.
Speaker 7:  The lawmakers spoke over him a lot. It seemed like he was there
Speaker 7:  to give fairly candid testimony and to say what exactly, you
Speaker 7:  know, he could say there were some, I don't know, private company questions
Speaker 7:  that he would wanted to skirt by, but for the most part he seemed like he
Speaker 7:  was, was there to really answer the questions that lawmakers had.
Speaker 7:  But unfortunately, I don't think the lawmakers really had any
Speaker 7:  questions at the top of the hearing. Something that really stayed with
Speaker 7:  me was that the chairwoman Kathy McMorris Rodgers, she,
Speaker 7:  in her opening statement, said, your app should be banned. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  It seemed like a lot of the lawmakers there had already had, you know, their
Speaker 7:  minds made up about the future of TikTok and why they invited him to answer
Speaker 7:  questions. I don't know. Cuz it doesn't seem like they were very interested
Speaker 7:  in the answers.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They said over and over, this is the most bipartisan
Speaker 6:  committee in Congress. Everybody agrees we're all on the same page. Everybody
Speaker 6:  thinks we should be on TikTok. And it was just, it, it became clear very
Speaker 6:  quickly that they had just brought him here to yell at him. Yeah. And to
Speaker 6:  not only yell at him about TikTok, but to yell at him about every bad thing
Speaker 6:  that anyone in the tech industry has ever done in history. And
Speaker 6:  he kept saying, can I respond to that? And they kept being like, no. I was
Speaker 6:  like, what are we doing here?
Speaker 5:  And, and what, I wanna put that into context. We've done a lot of hearing
Speaker 5:  coverage in the past couple years. We've seen Mark Zuckerberg go through
Speaker 5:  this experience. Jack Dorsey literally tweeting through a hearing about
Speaker 5:  how bad the questions were while he was in the hearing. Power move. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Sundar, you name it. The, the CEOs of big tech companies
Speaker 5:  have been forced to endure this
Speaker 5:  spectacle many times. This one was
Speaker 5:  meaningfully different. And I would say, I was listening to
Speaker 5:  CNBC at my way to work today before the hearing, and Mc Morris Rogers was
Speaker 5:  on cnbc and before the hearing had ever started, she said, at the end
Speaker 5:  of this hearing, we're gonna ban TikTok. Right.
Speaker 5:  Just like straight out the hearing hadn't even happened. The collection of
Speaker 5:  evidence that presumably this was meant to accomplish. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Nothing. Now I I, there are legitimate
Speaker 5:  concerns about TikTok McKenna, just from
Speaker 5:  taking a step back before we get into the weirdness of the hearing, what,
Speaker 5:  what are the specific concerns that the government has about TikTok?
Speaker 7:  Right. From what I can gather from my conversations with lawmakers, there
Speaker 7:  are two main concerns. One is for foreign malign influence
Speaker 7:  operations, whether that's China, Russia, whoever
Speaker 7:  using TikTok to basically convince people that
Speaker 7:  China, like Taiwan belongs to China, China is going to
Speaker 7:  invade. Everyone clap. That's one instance.
Speaker 7:  And then the second instance is Chinese
Speaker 7:  spying on American citizens, essentially using the data obtained from
Speaker 7:  TikTok in order to do something
Speaker 7:  in when it's gone to the Chinese government. That's the one thing when I'm
Speaker 7:  asking lawmakers, what does it mean for the average person? If you take
Speaker 7:  my mom's data from TikTok, why should she be scared?
Speaker 7:  And that's been something really, really hard to get an answer to. And I
Speaker 7:  think this was fully on display at today's hearing. We haven't had any evidence
Speaker 7:  that China is currently operating some kind of form aligned
Speaker 7:  influence campaign on TikTok. There's a possibility that it could happen,
Speaker 7:  but it hasn't been found yet. And then in the case for data security,
Speaker 7:  there really hasn't been an instance. There's been a number of instances
Speaker 7:  where a handful of employees
Speaker 7:  at TikTok have either track journalists, but again, like there were
Speaker 7:  accusations that Uber did that as well. Accusations that employees at Facebook
Speaker 7:  had done that against journalists as well. But getting to the heart of it,
Speaker 7:  there isn't really anything so far that differ, differentiates, talk's,
Speaker 7:  business model talk's, ability to gather data that's
Speaker 7:  different from American-based tech companies and the fact that they have
Speaker 7:  a Chinese Beijing based parent company and bite dance.
Speaker 6:  I I would just add one sort of half corollary to
Speaker 6:  the two things that you named, cuz I do think one other piece of this seems
Speaker 6:  to be, I guess what I would call this sort of long subtle influence
Speaker 6:  campaign that people think, and this came up a bunch in the hearing and I,
Speaker 6:  I'm curious what y'all thought of it, but this idea that basically
Speaker 6:  TikTok is sort of corrupting the youth and teaching
Speaker 6:  everyone to just do dance challenges while Dewian in China is teaching kids
Speaker 6:  engineering. Like this is a real concern. And it came up over and over th
Speaker 6:  this idea that this is China's way of influencing
Speaker 6:  American people. Not only for the the, like the Taiwan stuff that you're
Speaker 6:  talking, but it's this like long game play to just
Speaker 6:  win future generations. And, and there there's this 10 dimensional
Speaker 6:  chess thing happening that a surprising number of people seem to think is
Speaker 6:  actually real.
Speaker 7:  I think that's important too. So yesterday I sat down with Senator Mark Warner,
Speaker 7:  who has introduced one of the most widely backed bipartisan
Speaker 7:  bills that could eventually lead to a ban of TikTok. And when I was sitting
Speaker 7:  with him, a number that he constantly pulled out was the fact that the, you
Speaker 7:  know, there's about 150 million American users on average. Like the
Speaker 7:  average user spends 90 minutes on TikTok a day that is an hour
Speaker 7:  and a half of content from one platform. And he kept,
Speaker 7:  you know, reaffirming to me the fact that they could have those
Speaker 7:  subtle nudges, right? That could push you into believing one thing or
Speaker 7:  thinking one thing that isn't so, you know, outlandish
Speaker 7:  as having, I don't know, an influencer from the People's Republic
Speaker 7:  of China being like, everything is so good. We're not
Speaker 7:  doing a uighur genocide. You know, things like that. So
Speaker 7:  it's those, it's those small things of course that are very
Speaker 7:  hard to prove it. Of course, this, you know, this is something where time
Speaker 7:  will tell,
Speaker 5:  Wait, can I just say about that? It's hard to prove in the, the case
Speaker 5:  of TikTok, it is actually easy to prove
Speaker 5:  broadly. So like Kyrie
Speaker 5:  Irving is a famous basketball player who believes the earth is flat because
Speaker 5:  of the Google SEO feedback loop, right? Like
Speaker 5:  there were some people who were like, the earth is flat. And that was engaging
Speaker 5:  and it got a lot of comments on YouTube. And so more people saw those
Speaker 5:  view counts going up and made more videos. And then real
Speaker 5:  publications saw the search trends for the earth is flat
Speaker 5:  and they wrote more content about the controversy about the earth being flat
Speaker 5:  and you just kind of spiral it out to no one was in charge
Speaker 5:  of this feedback loop and now a substantial percentage
Speaker 5:  of the population regardless of their money or access to resources.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, I don't know, I think the earth is flat and that's one we
Speaker 5:  can see. I mean, no one has shown that particular
Speaker 5:  feedback loop of TikTok, but the idea that the Chinese government
Speaker 5:  could use a tool like TikTok to create that feedback loop in their interests
Speaker 5:  is not out of bounds. Right. But I, I'm just like, I don't know what,
Speaker 5:  what would be the control of Mark Zuckerberg wanting to
Speaker 5:  do that for Instagram? If you're that worried about the Chinese government
Speaker 5:  doing it, then you're worried about the mechanism. And there's, there's no
Speaker 5:  check on that mechanism anywhere for any social media
Speaker 6:  That comes back to McKenna. What seems to me to be the, the like
Speaker 6:  underlying thrust of this whole hearing, which is that everything is the
Speaker 6:  same except China and instantly changes the tenor of everything.
Speaker 6:  Because you can say all the same sentences and you can end them with China
Speaker 6:  and it, the whole vibe changes, right?
Speaker 7:  No, that's correct. When you look at a lot of what
Speaker 7:  happened today, and even the lawmakers oftentimes brought it up. They would
Speaker 7:  say, all this stuff is really bad, the misinformation, the mental
Speaker 7:  health harms, all these things that we saw so explicitly with
Speaker 7:  Francis Hogan in 20 20, 20 21 with Facebook and the Facebook
Speaker 7:  files, it was so transparent that this was happening elsewhere. It
Speaker 7:  seems like we had often like forgotten about it. And then the lawmakers would
Speaker 7:  remind themselves and be like, but I also support a federal data privacy
Speaker 7:  framework. And it's like, what happened to that? How long have we been talking
Speaker 7:  about that? Right? And so of course like these
Speaker 7:  Facebook, you know, meta Twitter, Google, all these have like so
Speaker 7:  much, you know, they have so much stake in like the states and have
Speaker 7:  built up their lobbying arms tremendously over the past five to
Speaker 7:  10 years with this heightened criticism. TikTok hasn't done that. I think
Speaker 7:  it was just in 2021 or 22 that they even
Speaker 7:  had a DC office. Like they weren't here engaging with lawmakers
Speaker 7:  in the same way that American made, you know, America based social media
Speaker 7:  apps have. And they really have tried hard in a very
Speaker 7:  small amount of time with TikTok to build a coalition supporting them.
Speaker 7:  They brought the TikTok talkers here. There was three house Democrats
Speaker 7:  who came in support of TikTok yesterday. But you know, any kind
Speaker 7:  of movement that TikTok is trying to make has been like moving a boulder.
Speaker 7:  It's been very, very difficult. Especially because like look at the, this
Speaker 7:  is something that I asked a lot of TikTok ERs last night coming to my head
Speaker 7:  right now. But my question was, what happens if TikTok
Speaker 7:  is banned tomorrow? What happens to you? And you know, a lot of them said,
Speaker 7:  we'll be fine. We were fine before TikTok. Maybe they're, maybe
Speaker 7:  we'll go do something else. But we really like TikTok in the community we
Speaker 7:  built here and we don't want that to go away. You talked to
Speaker 7:  Mark Warner and Mark Warner of course is a very, you know, he likes to talk
Speaker 7:  about competitive capitalism a lot. He's very much that guy, right?
Speaker 7:  He's an old Silicon Valley wireless guy. And yesterday when I
Speaker 7:  was talking to him, you know, I was saying, what happens to these creators?
Speaker 7:  He's like, there'll be another platform that will compete and
Speaker 7:  will take up the hole that TikTok leaves behind.
Speaker 5:  And like the c e o of YouTube is like peeking out from behind
Speaker 7:  The curtain. Mark Zuckerberg is peeking out from behind. I bring up the fact
Speaker 7:  that, okay, so TikTok is bringing the first inch right
Speaker 7:  of meaningful competition to a lot of American social media
Speaker 7:  platforms. If that goes away, he's like, oh, it could be an Indian company.
Speaker 7:  Oh it could be, you know, a British company or something. But just
Speaker 5:  As long as it's
Speaker 7:  Not China, as long as it's not China, right? And of course, you know, it's
Speaker 7:  opening up more room for American companies to remain dominant.
Speaker 1:  Do you get a sense that those American companies are lobbying against
Speaker 1:  TikTok?
Speaker 7:  It's been proven. Yeah. So I, I believe it was, maybe it was like
Speaker 7:  the Washington Post, but it must have been like a year ago at this point.
Speaker 7:  But Facebook was paying a republican campaigning organization to
Speaker 7:  run a bunch of op-eds in newspapers across
Speaker 7:  the country saying how dangerous TikTok was and
Speaker 7:  railing against all of these challenges. Many of the challenges, right? The
Speaker 7:  challenges I put in quotes that we saw today highlighted by Republicans the
Speaker 7:  night called chicken got brought up. Again, it's like, why is
Speaker 7:  this stuff still there? Especially stuff that has been debunked as almost
Speaker 7:  like, you know, media or like false tide pods. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Just people who like see something like, oh my God, it's going crazy, all
Speaker 7:  the kids are gonna die. But yeah, no, it's, so these Facebook, at least
Speaker 7:  meta was reported to have done this before. It's very clear that they're
Speaker 7:  trying to point the finger at TikTok and be like, well, would you rather
Speaker 7:  it be China or would you rather it be American companies that have,
Speaker 7:  so,
Speaker 1:  So basically Congress is saying we're fine with super
Speaker 1:  invasive software like knowing everything about you. It just
Speaker 1:  can't be Chinese. It has to be American grown. Only Americans can exploit
Speaker 1:  Americans
Speaker 5:  Or apparently from India or India. Let's be clear. Senator Warner quality
Speaker 5:  is fine. But this is the question, and I, I
Speaker 5:  don't want to excuse the Chinese government, right,
Speaker 5:  which is a repressive sensors government that
Speaker 5:  does bad things to its people.
Speaker 1:  Yes,
Speaker 5:  That's true. And it is our country's great geopolitical
Speaker 5:  rival, but we're all tied up together, right? Like I, I
Speaker 5:  keep thinking about today, I kept thinking about Tim Cook at the Code
Speaker 5:  Conference last year when I asked him, what do you think about TikTok? And
Speaker 5:  he is like, I don't, I'm not familiar with TikTok. And I was like, this is
Speaker 5:  the number one app on your store. This is why people have the phone and you,
Speaker 5:  you just are not gonna talk about it because you are all wrapped up in China.
Speaker 5:  Like this is the complicated riddle of our time is
Speaker 5:  here's the world's biggest, most vibrant democracy in some ways and
Speaker 5:  here's China and we're absolutely relying on each other
Speaker 5:  in all kinds of weird, complicated ways except for when it comes to
Speaker 5:  this app. And we're like, fuck you. And it like that was the
Speaker 5:  tenor of the hearing. And the thing is, I don't think they made the,
Speaker 5:  the stuff McKenna is talking about malign foreign influence operations or
Speaker 5:  you're collecting grandma's data to do something nefarious because we haven't
Speaker 5:  made the case. It just seems ridiculous.
Speaker 5:  Right?
Speaker 7:  Well it just seems xenophobic,
Speaker 5:  Right? Like, like there's just a piece of this puzzle where like the American
Speaker 5:  Congress yelled at a Chinese CEO for four and a half hours today and he was
Speaker 5:  not allowed to answer the questions. And I don't think his answers are good,
Speaker 5:  right? Like his big answer is Project Texas. And he kept
Speaker 5:  saying it's gonna be American data on American soil overseen by
Speaker 5:  an American company. And I don't know, like we're going to, we're gonna,
Speaker 5:  the, the data center will be shaped like a flag. Like something will happen
Speaker 5:  that'll be good for you. And like no one would even let him finish the sentence.
Speaker 5:  Right? McKenna is there, is there a reason that no one believes that
Speaker 5:  this is like a good answer?
Speaker 7:  So my theory about all of this,
Speaker 7:  especially having talked to people this week, it's not if, if my
Speaker 7:  good faith theory, if if I'm going to look at this in good faith at the
Speaker 7:  lawmakers in the whole situation, my good faith argument is that lawmakers
Speaker 7:  have been caught on their back foot before Cambridge Analytica dozens, you
Speaker 7:  know, foreign influence operations on American, you know, social media
Speaker 7:  platforms, Facebook, Twitter, et cetera. This has happened for years. They
Speaker 7:  publish, you know, these platforms publish transparency reports being like,
Speaker 7:  look at all of the bad things happening. Oh we found them and got rid of
Speaker 7:  them, but they still exist and they're still happening. So
Speaker 7:  talking to Warner, talking to some other lawmakers, it seemed like
Speaker 7:  if they, you know, if there really is like something here that they think
Speaker 7:  they need to do, it's the fact that this could happen again on a far greater
Speaker 7:  scale in in way that the US does cannot control as much
Speaker 7:  as, you know, a Cambridge Analytica, which it's still, you know, Cambridge
Speaker 7:  Analytica that was like tw you know, so long ago. And that was the beginning
Speaker 7:  of like serious conversations around a federal data privacy network framework.
Speaker 7:  It's gone nowhere. Yeah, yeah. You know, it's gone absolutely nowhere
Speaker 7:  and it's kind of funny to see these same things play out just
Speaker 7:  with China at the center at a time of
Speaker 7:  very, very deep geopolitical tensions. We just came out
Speaker 7:  of, I would like to remind you the Chinese spy balloon situation which ended
Speaker 7:  up being like, you know, just research balloons in some cases
Speaker 7:  where we had a whole weekend afraid of UFOs and like China's
Speaker 7:  spies all because of, you know, this relationship that we have with, you
Speaker 7:  know, this foreign adversary
Speaker 5:  Is the answer. Just that because it's China, we get to skip to the
Speaker 5:  end, which is, boy it seems like these apps are harvesting a lot of data.
Speaker 5:  It's hard to make the case against Google because Google's an all American
Speaker 5:  company in their, they lead the s and p 500 or whatever.
Speaker 5:  But it's easy when you're like, China's bad and politically we don't have
Speaker 5:  to sell it.
Speaker 7:  Well look at, you know, I think when it comes to these things it's, you gotta,
Speaker 7:  unfortunately campaigns are like a 24 month cycle.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Now instead of like a year or six month cycle, you had
Speaker 7:  Trump in 2018 issuing executive orders to ban TikTok, which
Speaker 7:  of course we've covered. They were ultimately overruled. And then of course
Speaker 7:  Biden now is dealing with this anti-China
Speaker 7:  fervor amongst Republicans at a time when he's gonna be
Speaker 7:  running for reelection at a time when Republicans are going really, really
Speaker 7:  hard on China. So I think a lot of this has to do with the fact that
Speaker 7:  even the Biden administration gave TikTok an ultimatum last week
Speaker 7:  ahead of this hearing. Either find an American owner or get banned.
Speaker 7:  That was from Biden. That is the, that is the strongest thing
Speaker 7:  we've heard against TikTok from both administrations
Speaker 7:  really. Cause it's the one thing that could really, you know, could really
Speaker 7:  happen. I do think at the center it probably is China and having to do with
Speaker 7:  electoral politics.
Speaker 6:  Well and it also, it, it seems to me that it, it's a move
Speaker 6:  that these politicians don't have with any of these other companies
Speaker 6:  and services. Like nobody ever talks about banning Google,
Speaker 6:  right? Like that's not, that's just not an option. It's just not a thing
Speaker 6:  that's gonna happen. But, but like to your point Eli, about skipping to the
Speaker 6:  end, we, we also get to skip past all the nuance of figuring out
Speaker 6:  what is a responsible, like you're talking about McKenna privacy framework
Speaker 6:  for this country. Like these are complicated questions, they're the right
Speaker 6:  questions, but they're complicated ones and it's so much easier
Speaker 6:  in a certain sense to just say, this is bad, get it out of here in a way
Speaker 6:  that you just straight up can't do unless you have this
Speaker 6:  gigantic boogeyman that is China to blame it all on. And
Speaker 6:  I think we we're now what, seven years into arguing about privacy
Speaker 6:  debates on the internet and we've gotten nowhere and I didn't get any sense
Speaker 6:  from the hearing that anyone is any further along in even knowing what we
Speaker 6:  want out of
Speaker 5:  This hearing. Wait, can I play some clips just to illustrate, if we were,
Speaker 5:  you know, seven years into a privacy debate and no one had gotten farther
Speaker 5:  along, I'd be like, this is a victory. This hearing. Lemme
Speaker 5:  just play play the wifi clip. Just play the wifi clip.
Speaker 8:  Mr. Chu, does TikTok access the home wifi network?
Speaker 9:   If the user turns on the wifi, I, I'm sorry, I may not understand the,
Speaker 9:  so
Speaker 8:  If I have TikTok app on my phone and my phone is on my home wifi
Speaker 8:  network, does TikTok access that network?
Speaker 9:  It will have to, to access that network to get connections to the internet.
Speaker 9:  If, if that's the question,
Speaker 5:  The
Speaker 6:  Pause before he answers you can, you can just tell his brain is just
Speaker 6:  breaking into a thousand pieces at this question.
Speaker 5:  Let's say he was just like, yes. What
Speaker 5:  specifically is the gotcha there? The shit's already on your
Speaker 5:  phone, that's where the data is. There's nothing else on
Speaker 5:  the average American wifi network that has as much data as their
Speaker 5:  phones,
Speaker 1:  Their fridge.
Speaker 5:  It's like, oh no, they got to my Roku.
Speaker 5:  Like I'm sitting here with America's foremost plex server operator
Speaker 1:  And I don't want them actually have access to that. Mm.
Speaker 1:  Stay out
Speaker 5:  TikTok. I'm just saying. Saying like if we were deep into a privacy
Speaker 5:  framework conversation, we would be light years ahead of
Speaker 5:  does it access your wifi network? And
Speaker 5:  that to me is, there were some good questions in here,
Speaker 5:  but let's make the case to ban a wildly popular
Speaker 5:  app that is effectively a cultural institution
Speaker 5:  because it's owned by China. You have to try to make the case.
Speaker 1:  Well and I wonder, McKenna, I would love to hear your thoughts on this.
Speaker 1:  Is this actually a politically good move?
Speaker 1:  Because there's a whole bunch of people who like TikTok and will probably
Speaker 1:  be really pissed that they don't have TikTok. You
Speaker 7:  Would think. Right. And my favorite quote from
Speaker 7:  last night with representative Jamal Bowman was he was saying Republicans
Speaker 7:  hate TikTok cause they don't have any swag, which is very funny,
Speaker 7:  incredible. They can't engage with like young people
Speaker 7:  at the same level. Democrats can on TikTok. At the same time, all these Democrats
Speaker 7:  as we went down the Dias we're like ban TikTok.
Speaker 7:  But you know, it's, I don't, I don't think it's good. I don't think
Speaker 7:  it's a really great opportunity to ban TikTok or at least if you're not being
Speaker 7:  as transparent about the threat. Because in my main question when I talk
Speaker 7:  to lawmakers is what do I have to fear? In some cases it's like blackmail,
Speaker 7:  but okay, how many people are in the United States? Millions,
Speaker 7:  billions, you know, so many people. How,
Speaker 7:  what is the chance that they're going to find my little data profile and
Speaker 7:  find blackmail, you know, on like me and I I
Speaker 7:  guess like switch me, you know, try and turn me into like a double agent
Speaker 7:  like China spy. Like I don't know what they're asking of me. You know, I
Speaker 7:  love this. What does that mean for me?
Speaker 6:  Maybe they already did McKenna. Have you thought about that? Maybe, maybe
Speaker 6:  they
Speaker 7:  Already did. My long con,
Speaker 7:  my long con is to get into the Verge institution and I
Speaker 1:  Think we can safely say China's not doing a lot of great things. And
Speaker 1:  and there is there, there's the very legitimate concern that they can
Speaker 1:  use data from this application for nefarious means.
Speaker 1:  If they wanted to, if they wanted to target a lawmaker who was using TikTok
Speaker 1:  to reach the youth, they could theoretically do that. But
Speaker 1:  so could Facebook, so could Twitter,
Speaker 1:  all of those apps could do so could every single ad
Speaker 1:  vendor on the planet, right? Like there's a lot of people with very
Speaker 1:  extensive data
Speaker 5:  Points, right? But I think this is why they kept talking about federal privacy
Speaker 5:  legislation. Well
Speaker 1:  They didn't,
Speaker 5:  They kept or algorithmic transparency or all these things
Speaker 5:  that are the thing you want. Yeah. And then they're like, that's too hard.
Speaker 5:  And I can just say you're communists and commies.
Speaker 5:  I mean they, they asked him like a thousand times they, instead of saying
Speaker 5:  ccp, they kept saying the Chinese Communist Party. Yeah. Which is great.
Speaker 1:  Every, I would, I had to take a break for like an hour and a half from the
Speaker 1:  hearings to go to some meetings and they were talking about communists when
Speaker 1:  I took the break and I came back and they're like, do you or do you not know
Speaker 1:  communists at TikTok?
Speaker 5:  Oh there was a really good, there was a, a really good sequence when someone
Speaker 5:  asked him if by Danon helped him prepare for the hearing.
Speaker 5:  And poor show was like, yeah, a lot of people have texted me. It's a very
Speaker 5:  high profile hearing and he had to say this like five times. He's like, yeah,
Speaker 5:  my phone's blowing up. Yeah. Like people are sending me advice. I'm sorry.
Speaker 5:  I mean, and then they're like, will you share what people have said to you?
Speaker 5:  He's like, no, they're my lawyers. Let's play some more clips just to,
Speaker 5:  to put this in a perspective for people what we were dealing with today
Speaker 1:  Because it was bad. Like they were very focused on we wanna talk, we wanna
Speaker 1:  get TikTok, but we're gonna do it by the stupidest questions
Speaker 1:  possible showing we have zero understanding of how technology actually works.
Speaker 5:  No. So I have this theory about that Congress doesn't understand technology.
Speaker 5:  I've been working on it. Yeah. Okay. And McKenna, I'm curious for your, your
Speaker 5:  read on this cuz you, you were in it today. I feel like every time we say
Speaker 5:  Congress doesn't understand how technology works, what we are saying is
Speaker 5:  Congress is pretty frustrated by the First Amendment. So they have to say
Speaker 5:  some crazy shit so they can pass a speech regulation so it doesn't
Speaker 5:  seem like they're passing speech regulation.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, they seemed really excited to censor people. Yeah. They're like, China
Speaker 1:  does it, why don't we?
Speaker 5:  But like that's like that to me that feels like the dynamic
Speaker 5:  here. Whenever we're like, they don't understand tech, it's because they
Speaker 5:  can't say the thing they want to say, which is we think these should be the
Speaker 5:  rules for how people talk to each other online.
Speaker 1:  Even when they were talking about how it scans your eyes,
Speaker 5:  Even when they talk about how it scans, like that's just pure crazy. We'll
Speaker 5:  end with that one. So I wanna play this clip. It's about grapefruit. It's
Speaker 5:  great. But McKenna, do you think that that's the right read that this sort
Speaker 5:  of like willful not getting tech is just an end around the first amendment
Speaker 7:  In some ways yes. I, I think, I don't know if that's, you know,
Speaker 7:  explicitly what lawmakers are thinking to themselves. I don't, you know,
Speaker 7:  I don't think anyone wants to say that they are even believe that they're
Speaker 7:  opposed to the First Amendment in many ways. But people want platforms to
Speaker 7:  do certain things for specific motives. That is something, you know, we,
Speaker 7:  that's something everyone wants, right? I post something because I want people
Speaker 7:  to see it. That's my motive. Lawmakers specifically, they want to be
Speaker 7:  able to say things that break a platform's terms of service in some cases
Speaker 7:  or they want to, you know, take down something for example
Speaker 7:  that is misinformation or disinformation. It really does come
Speaker 7:  down to power and control over narrative setting. And
Speaker 7:  I think, you know, just the way social media operates, people feel as
Speaker 7:  if they, they are more empowered to influence a discussion, but when they
Speaker 7:  aren't and when they don't get their way, especially someone in power in
Speaker 7:  Congress who feels like they can, you know, come at these companies
Speaker 7:  and be able to say, you know, you're acting in opposition to the constitution,
Speaker 7:  to the first amendment. They're going to do it because they have a
Speaker 7:  motive and there's stakes for them to be able to say what they want online.
Speaker 5:  Okay, before we run the next clip, which is worth waiting for
Speaker 5:  William's telling me we gotta take a break, we're gonna take a quick break.
Speaker 10:  Here's a question. Can science tell us what makes
Speaker 10:  something funny?
Speaker 11:  Girl science, where have you been?
Speaker 10:  Comedians like zuko, tka wanna know
Speaker 11:  We've been just flailing around
Speaker 11:  screaming in the
Speaker 10:  Streets and scientists best answer might actually come from
Speaker 10:  Skittles.
Speaker 12:  The jellybean are the, the Skittles
Speaker 13:  One, the Skittle study.
Speaker 12:  I'm supposed to offer you these Skittles. Would you like these Skittles?
Speaker 12:  There's pretty good evidence that laughter is a form of communication. So
Speaker 12:  then the question becomes, well what does it communicate
Speaker 10:  This week on unexplainable the science of humor.
Speaker 10:  Follow unexplainable wherever you listen for new episodes every
Speaker 10:  Wednesday.
Speaker 13:  So if this makes the podcast, people are gonna be listening and be like,
Speaker 13:  this is not funny at all.
Speaker 14:  It's been three years since the world shut down and things are mostly back
Speaker 14:  to normal-ish. But one thing seems forever changed.
Speaker 14:  Office workers are not commuting downtown five days a week.
Speaker 14:  It's got people worried about a vicious cycle.
Speaker 15:  Property values will fall further, taxes will have to rise further, government
Speaker 15:  spending will have to fall further, more people will leave and so forth
Speaker 15:  and so forth. And we get into this urban doom
Speaker 14:  Loop. So at today, explain, we're asking how to break the loop.
Speaker 14:  Maybe it's changing the perception of crime.
Speaker 16:  There are several visible signs of disorder that are not
Speaker 16:  necessarily related to crime, that are causing people to feel that the
Speaker 16:  cities have become unsafe.
Speaker 14:  Maybe it's making buses and trains free.
Speaker 17:  Metro bus could soon be a free ride. A proposal unveil today would
Speaker 17:  get rid of metro bus fairs in DC
Speaker 14:  Maybe the solution is you,
Speaker 5:  You talking to me
Speaker 14:  City limits from today explained dropping over the next few weeks,
Speaker 14:  wherever you listen,
Speaker 5:  We're back. It's time for the grapefruit clip.
Speaker 18:  An another study showed that TikTok
Speaker 18:  was, had a, a hydra hydroxychloroquine
Speaker 18:  tutorial on how to fabricate this from
Speaker 18:  grapefruit. Now there's two problems with that. Number one
Speaker 18:  hydroxychloroquine is not effective in treating covid.
Speaker 18:  So that's one issue. The second issue is you
Speaker 18:  can't even make hydroxychloroquine from grapefruit. So
Speaker 18:  again, this is a really serious
Speaker 18:  miscommunication about healthcare information that people
Speaker 18:  looking at, at, at TikTok are
Speaker 18:  able to get. And in fact it's being pushed out to them.
Speaker 5:  Okay, I just have a number of things to say. First of all, please
Speaker 5:  go if you just like do the, like the simplification of that
Speaker 5:  equation, it's TikTok is telling people that grapefruits cure covid,
Speaker 5:  which is definitely legal speech in America. You are allowed to wander the
Speaker 5:  streets of this country insisting that you can cure covid with grapefruits.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You are allowed to wander the streets of this. And I don't think that's
Speaker 5:  dangerous misinformation. I think it's not great. Oh, you do.
Speaker 5:  It's not true.
Speaker 7:  Can you ask Bard how we, how we use
Speaker 5:  Grapefruit? But I just like the government is not allowed to show
Speaker 5:  up on your doorstep and say lying is illegal just is the US government, the
Speaker 5:  united, the united, the Chinese government is, that's actually like part
Speaker 5:  of the whole problem here. Yep. The United States government can't be like
Speaker 5:  lying legal. It is also legal speech to tell people
Speaker 5:  they can make hydroxychloroquine from grapefruits, which is an incredible
Speaker 5:  sentence. Welcome to the verge chest, everyone.
Speaker 7:  You know, looking at this specific example, it was
Speaker 7:  actually, I was sitting in the hearing room and I was getting
Speaker 7:  reminded of this hearing in like the early 1990s in
Speaker 7:  the senate on video games where they like rolled in a TV on a cart
Speaker 7:  like you would like in school when you had like movie day, right? Yeah. And
Speaker 7:  they rolled it in and it was like mortal combat and they're like, this is
Speaker 7:  so bad. Kind of getting to this, the beginning of the conversation about
Speaker 7:  like Call of Duty causes people to, you know,
Speaker 7:  inflict violence on others. It was kind of starting back then. You look at
Speaker 7:  this, you know, grapefruit is so silly in many ways,
Speaker 7:  but at the same time you look at the, another example that really struck
Speaker 7:  me from this was there was one lawmaker who brought up a bunch
Speaker 7:  of videos of kids being sad.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  They had themes of like depression. But I'm like, I grew up
Speaker 7:  on Tumblr, I grew up, you know, on Reddit and things
Speaker 7:  and they, and oftentimes it's far worse. And many of the,
Speaker 7:  a handful of the videos were of this like niche core, core
Speaker 7:  genre of TikTok, which is kind of a ironic
Speaker 7:  framing. It's very hard to understand. I can understand why a lawmaker would
Speaker 7:  not attempt to understand it, but I got a text message from a
Speaker 7:  democratic, like a very young, I am pretty sure they're a teenager,
Speaker 7:  a democratic digital consultant for like campaigns and stuff. And he's like,
Speaker 7:  this is hilarious. They really just don't get it. They're
Speaker 7:  really going after him over nothing. And so it, there is
Speaker 7:  like a media literacy aspect of it as well.
Speaker 7:  And my main point here really is getting to the fact that you can't keep
Speaker 7:  kids from being sad and you can't really keep them from playing video games
Speaker 7:  especially, but it's not like the platform or the game itself is
Speaker 7:  incentivizing them to feel this way in many ways. Of course, like you're
Speaker 7:  sitting on an algorithm, you're seeing people, we, we all, we've all heard
Speaker 7:  this before, right? But that is like protected speech and it's speech that
Speaker 7:  kids have been doing forever online and even predating it.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah, no, I was a, a world class sad teenager,
Speaker 7:  A shit
Speaker 5:  Poster. I was there for it. I'm just saying the the grapefruit example is
Speaker 5:  perfect because I think it cuts across party lines in, in like a, in just
Speaker 5:  a way that maybe not it's so stupid. Yeah. Grapefruits are for everybody,
Speaker 5:  but like, just the, just the phrase should the government ban
Speaker 5:  videos where people say you can make hydroxychloroquine from grapefruits
Speaker 5:  is inherently not partisan.
Speaker 5:  Right? It's just a it's just a, just a philosophical question about the nature
Speaker 5:  of government power. Yeah. That is loaded with keywords for
Speaker 5:  whatever you think your politics are. And the answer in
Speaker 5:  almost every case is the government should not make a rule
Speaker 5:  that says videos that claim you can make hydroxychloroquine from
Speaker 5:  grapefruits should be illegal. I don't think that the, I think government
Speaker 5:  speech regulations on on the whole are bad. I think this one would be particularly
Speaker 5:  hilarious. Like if we were like there's the first amendment, there's one
Speaker 5:  exception, it's gonna be the grapefruits, right? Like
Speaker 5:  fine this clip where she's like, your app is
Speaker 5:  bad because it contains this speech that I find
Speaker 5:  distasteful. Well she's saying you're the, the government
Speaker 5:  is going to impose a penalty on you for hosting this speech.
Speaker 7:  I'm curious if she's ever used Google
Speaker 5:  Or I haven't Googled hydroxychloroquine grapefruit.
Speaker 7:  I just did actually
Speaker 6:  What happened McKenna,
Speaker 7:  I'm dying and this is the last you'll hear from me.
Speaker 7:  No, just kidding. But I'm looking, there was a Reuters fact check
Speaker 7:  in June of 2021. Fact checking the grapefruit video that was
Speaker 7:  viewed at the time over 600,000 times and then
Speaker 7:  circulated on Instagram. And I mean talking about virality 600,000 times
Speaker 7:  really isn't, it's nothing that crazy. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I can find you 600,000 Americans who will, who believe literally anything
Speaker 5:  you
Speaker 7:  Say. And as reported by Reuters here, it was a clip, it was one video.
Speaker 6:  There's such a long history of this on TikTok, right? Where there's like
Speaker 6:  one video that one person sees and writes a story about how it's not a thing
Speaker 6:  and then like three steps later, like teachers are worried about it and we
Speaker 6:  have moral panics about like kids ceiling toilets in high school. It's, this
Speaker 6:  is what keeps happening. This
Speaker 5:  Is the flat earth thing, right? And this is where the idea that you could,
Speaker 5:  you could start a foreign influence campaign on TikTok, I think actually
Speaker 5:  has legs. This cycle is well understood. We've seen it. O
Speaker 5:  NyQuil chicken is this cycle. Well
Speaker 6:  This is Russia's whole thing, right? Like Russia, the Russia keeps proving
Speaker 6:  that you can do this.
Speaker 5:  When I was a kid in Wisconsin, the local news ran a segment. I will never
Speaker 5:  forget this, the local news ran a segment about how kids were getting high
Speaker 5:  by drinking too much water. And some of them would drink like way too much
Speaker 5:  water and die. And my mother, who is a fucking doctor was
Speaker 5:  like, I need you to make sure you don't drink enough water. And I was like,
Speaker 5:  what is like what is happening to me? Like why do
Speaker 5:  I even know this idea exists? Oh God. I was like, I can just drink Miller
Speaker 5:  Light. I live in Wisconsin. It's, it flows more
Speaker 5:  freely than the water. But like that cycle is truly well
Speaker 5:  understood. And I think what you're seeing is that you need some reason.
Speaker 5:  So you settle on, people are lying to you about grapefruits.
Speaker 5:  China's bad, we're gonna ban TikTok. And that's about as good as the
Speaker 5:  reasoning. God and I, I just honestly challenge
Speaker 5:  everyone listening to just think about the grapefruit. Should it be
Speaker 5:  legal to make videos where you lie to people about grapefruit turning into
Speaker 5:  hydroxychloroquine? Like should it be legal to lie? Like run out the
Speaker 5:  thread of it's illegal to tell lies oof. It's
Speaker 1:  Bad my ass would be in jail,
Speaker 5:  Right? I'm lying to you right now. And like
Speaker 5:  you see in this hearing, so much of the content moderation
Speaker 5:  concerns are just speech regulations dressed up in
Speaker 5:  the guise of you are creating a public danger. You're showing teenagers
Speaker 5:  videos of other teenagers being sad and creating a sadness epidemic. It's
Speaker 5:  like, yo, the cure is on tour right now. Like
Speaker 5:  it's very expensive to go be sad with thousands of other people in America
Speaker 5:  right now. Like that's the part that I don't get. And
Speaker 5:  that's why I asked this question about are we really, when we say Congress
Speaker 5:  doesn't understand the internet, it's because they have to concoct these
Speaker 5:  sideways attempts at at speech regulations in order
Speaker 5:  to control the thing, which is all effectively
Speaker 1:  Speech. But that was the same, right? Like you talked about video games earlier,
Speaker 1:  that was the exact same thing that happened in the early nineties. And it
Speaker 1:  was with TV too. We have ratings in TV because in the nineties, Hillary Clinton
Speaker 1:  and a lot of Democrats and some Republicans were like, oh my god, they can
Speaker 1:  watch sipowicz butt. What
Speaker 5:  Will we remember when a butt was like the thing
Speaker 1:  That was the thing, oh
Speaker 5:  My gosh, bill Clinton, by the way wanted to put a chip in every television
Speaker 5:  set in America. It did would, it was called the clipper chip. And that was
Speaker 5:  deemed to be like way over the line. It was a simpler time.
Speaker 1:  And now they're like, what if we stopped showing kids
Speaker 1:  trends that seem harmful and instead showed them
Speaker 1:  studying right? Like they do in China. That
Speaker 7:  Actually gets to a point that I did wanna make. And I think about all the
Speaker 7:  time I go back to it as like the center and the focus of my reporting as
Speaker 7:  something not to forget. You look at tv, right? You look at video games
Speaker 7:  and I don't want to say that social media doesn't present
Speaker 7:  a different set of, you know, potential harms that need
Speaker 7:  to be looked at and you know, maybe need to be regulated in some case.
Speaker 7:  I don't want to undermine that in this, but so many of the issues that we
Speaker 7:  have with the internet are human issues. And that gets erased
Speaker 7:  immediately because of the like, just because of bringing in tech into it.
Speaker 7:  Why are people sad? Well, maybe they are getting like a lot of sad
Speaker 7:  videos online, but also, I don't know, maybe they can't afford to
Speaker 7:  live. Maybe they're scared of, you
Speaker 7:  know, not being able to live on their own, you know, to buy a house.
Speaker 7:  There, there are issues at the core of American
Speaker 7:  culture right now that I think have more to say right
Speaker 7:  about the causes of social ill
Speaker 7:  violence, things like that, that get caught up in the social media side of
Speaker 7:  it because it's an easy victim, it's an easy villain to blame
Speaker 7:  in this case. And I think it gets us away from talking about the real human
Speaker 7:  element of like human suffering and oh,
Speaker 7:  into these, you know, conversations about data privacy. You
Speaker 7:  know, these things that last forever that no one can agree on and we make
Speaker 7:  no progress on and people continue to suffer. That's a really
Speaker 7:  horrible way to end. But
Speaker 5:  No, don't understand that. We're definitely gonna end on the clip of the
Speaker 5:  Congressman not understanding how eye tracking works. Don't worry, we'll
Speaker 5:  get there. I I, I wanna agree with you like wholeheartedly. I just,
Speaker 5:  it's, here's my question for you. In return, having, you were at the hearing
Speaker 5:  today, you saw the TikTok, you experienced it fully.
Speaker 5:  The balance of that is the same for every app, right?
Speaker 5:  It's the same for Instagram, it's the same for YouTube. YouTube burnout culture
Speaker 5:  is real, right? YouTube is like way ahead of the curve with
Speaker 5:  its creator economy than every other platform. And people have
Speaker 5:  cycled out of YouTube and like maybe TikTok is at the beginning of it, but
Speaker 5:  because it's China, the calculus has changed and I'm,
Speaker 5:  I'm wondering if you've seen even a glimmer of recognition
Speaker 5:  that it's not the big bad China app that's causing the
Speaker 5:  problems, but rather like, oh we've created a, a
Speaker 5:  generation of digital tools that allows this group of people to
Speaker 5:  express themselves. And actually we don't really like what they're saying.
Speaker 7:  I think that's fair. I, when we were on our way down yesterday, I was seeing
Speaker 7:  there's the CMBC CNBC article highlighting that representative
Speaker 7:  Jamal Bowman from New York is publicly supporting
Speaker 7:  TikTok and does not want TikTok to be banned. He was going to have this press
Speaker 7:  conference with 30 creators and he got up in front of a podium
Speaker 7:  at the house triangle and said, this is very xenophobic
Speaker 7:  was one of the first people to say it. There was only two other house democrats
Speaker 7:  that like stood with him. It's a very small coalition. I ran up to the congressman
Speaker 7:  after they, after the press conference and I said, Congressman,
Speaker 7:  can you build a broader coalition supporting TikTok? And he said
Speaker 7:  something to the effect of Democrats build coalitions and like shrugged.
Speaker 7:  Like you know, it doesn't seem like there really is
Speaker 7:  energy. This is the first time, like yesterday was the first time I heard
Speaker 7:  someone just explicitly say this, you know, in support of TikTok. I,
Speaker 7:  I do. It's very, it's a very tricky situation with China involved politically,
Speaker 7:  right? This is a more political question than really because you're right
Speaker 7:  cuz when we get to the center of it, it's TikTok can be banned. It
Speaker 7:  doesn't really harm Americans. It like harms teens I guess because they won't
Speaker 7:  be able to scroll on TikTok and they lose this community. It's really it,
Speaker 7:  I don't want to undermine that, but it's not something that lawmakers
Speaker 7:  have to think through all the way. This is something that can
Speaker 7:  just be seen as an effective,
Speaker 5:  Especially if it's this bipartisan, right? The electoral price for being
Speaker 5:  the person who banned TikTok is zero because the other side is saying the
Speaker 5:  exact same thing,
Speaker 7:  Right? What the thing is is who's actually going to do it? And this is my
Speaker 7:  also like I can I continue thinking about this cuz when Mark Warner introduced
Speaker 7:  the restrict act, of course it does in implement the possibility
Speaker 7:  of a ban on TikTok. It basically what the bill does is it creates a
Speaker 7:  process for the Secretary of Commerce to
Speaker 7:  investigate foreign owned technologies and create
Speaker 7:  protections and guardrails ultimately like the biggest tool
Speaker 7:  being a ban. So it got applauded, you know there was all this,
Speaker 7:  all these write-ups about the fact that TikTok could be banned by this bill,
Speaker 7:  but the ban is such a small part of it, right? And this
Speaker 7:  really, I think if like Democrats were to agree to some kind of
Speaker 7:  form of banning TikTok, it would probably be passing
Speaker 7:  this bill that everyone goes, woo, so excited. We're gonna take on TikTok
Speaker 7:  in China. And then it just ends up being a smaller set of transparency
Speaker 7:  requirements to the federal government or something in the long run. I do
Speaker 7:  think that is probably the more realistic option, especially heading into
Speaker 7:  2024. In 2022 specifically, I did a bunch of
Speaker 7:  reporting on creators influencer outreach by campaigns. This
Speaker 7:  is something that's been going on for years now, but I think it
Speaker 7:  was a Tufts report study that at that point in time in all the
Speaker 7:  major battleground states in 2022, gen Z was growing into
Speaker 7:  the biggest and most important voting block. Yeah, you're gonna take away
Speaker 7:  TikTok in Penn, you're gonna take away TikTok in Pennsylvania, you're gonna
Speaker 7:  take away TikTok in Arizona right now. Or maybe that marginal
Speaker 7:  error, you know, that margin of error right here between winning and losing
Speaker 7:  an election might be like a high school, you know,
Speaker 7:  like the senior class of a high school. I don't think that's gonna happen
Speaker 7:  for either party. This
Speaker 6:  Is why I'm absolutely convinced that what all these lawmakers
Speaker 6:  want and believe they can accomplish is to get TikTok sold to Oracle
Speaker 6:  or some other American company because that's all upside for them, right?
Speaker 6:  Then you get to say this is no longer part of China. We did it
Speaker 6:  like we, we defeated China, we got what we wanted, but you still get to have
Speaker 6:  TikTok and it's gonna be even better now because it's made by Americans.
Speaker 6:  Yay competition. Like I I, they got
Speaker 6:  shockingly far down that road in the Trump administration and it
Speaker 6:  really seems like these politicians are like
Speaker 5:  They got shockingly far down, down that road in the Trump administration
Speaker 5:  in the way that the Trump administration got shockingly far down a number
Speaker 5:  of roads, which is sure they set a bunch of outrageous stuff and held
Speaker 5:  meetings where everyone was like, I can't believe we're in this meeting and
Speaker 5:  then nothing happened.
Speaker 7:  Right? I mean Oracle has, Oracle has access
Speaker 7:  to the servers.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, Oracle is in TikTok in a way it wasn't before,
Speaker 5:  Right? They signed a deal where Oracle's now the cloud provider for TikTok
Speaker 5:  and they have Project Texas, which he, this poor man, they named it Project
Speaker 5:  Texas. So he could say Project Texas in the United States Capital Building
Speaker 5:  and he was not allowed to finish that phrase Project
Speaker 7:  Tex.
Speaker 5:  They were like, we've heard about Texas,
Speaker 7:  There was a Texas lawmaker who said we don't want your project Texas, you
Speaker 7:  know, in his very, I'm pretending to sound very rural voice
Speaker 7:  Texans don't want Project Texas.
Speaker 5:  I was like, I have a plex server sir.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, this is the idea, right? The project Texas, they're gonna move
Speaker 5:  all the data centers here. Oracle's gonna run them Oracle's based in Texas.
Speaker 5:  This is our argument for why it's called Project Texas. Oracle
Speaker 5:  is going to control the code. They're gonna submit the app to the app
Speaker 5:  stores. Basically Oracle's gonna run. TikTok is more or less the argument
Speaker 5:  and they set up these transparency in centers. We should repromote Alex Heath
Speaker 5:  went and visited one of these transparency centers and came away being like,
Speaker 5:  this is basically a kids museum and I don't know what I'm supposed to get
Speaker 5:  from this and we'll link the piece in the show notes, but that was kind of
Speaker 5:  the vibe of everybody who got the tour Yeah. Is like, this is a kids museum
Speaker 5:  for content moderation and then there's like a, a door that's marked data
Speaker 5:  center and you can't go through it and they're like, this is not very transparent.
Speaker 5:  Like there's a window That's not transparency, sir,
Speaker 5:  but this is their plan, right? Is they're gonna let Oracle do it and
Speaker 5:  if Oracle's doing it, then China's definitely not doing it. And that seemed
Speaker 5:  to convince no one,
Speaker 7:  There was actually
Speaker 1:  A good question at one point of like, how does that actually resolve anything?
Speaker 1:  If Oracle has access to your data? It doesn't actually stop
Speaker 1:  the root cause, which is, this is Chinese built and everything.
Speaker 6:  But that's a, that's a bunch of wishy-washy nonsense. You can't tweet,
Speaker 6:  we've forced bite dance to sell TikTok to Oracle is a thing
Speaker 6:  that you can tweet and is like a, a political win in a way that
Speaker 6:  like, let me explain to you how the internet infrastructure actually works
Speaker 6:  and how your data is stored and what that means for your life. But like these
Speaker 6:  people are after big political wins. Like to your point, McKenna, this, this
Speaker 6:  is about like finding a way to win and that's a, that's a win.
Speaker 6:  Like we sold it to Microsoft is a, is a win. And maybe
Speaker 7:  Not Microsoft though, cuz I go through the back of my head and I think with
Speaker 7:  Lena Kahn at the ftc with the Biden administration. So opposed
Speaker 7:  to digital monopolies as they say, who other than Oracle,
Speaker 7:  right? Would maybe they allowed to buy TikTok? Not, certainly not
Speaker 7:  Facebook. Yeah. You know, certainly not YouTube or Google.
Speaker 7:  My only other thing would've been maybe they would've let musically buy it
Speaker 7:  if TikTok didn't buy musically years ago. Right. That maybe would've made
Speaker 7:  sense. So it's, it's, I don't know who would end up
Speaker 7:  even buying it. Cuz we, I what wasn't it? There was some reporting. This
Speaker 7:  is like the Silicon Valley bank situation. Remember? I think gold, wasn't
Speaker 7:  it like Goldman or JP Morgan or something reportedly put in an offer to
Speaker 7:  buy Silicon Valley Bank. This is all reported. And the
Speaker 7:  Biden administration wouldn't let it happen. Cause they were just too big.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, yeah. Well, what is too big and who is not too big to buy
Speaker 7:  TikTok? I just don't know. Tumbling. Also, my one question and
Speaker 7:  something that I'm going to focus on for the next couple weeks is, where
Speaker 7:  is Oracle? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  No,
Speaker 7:  They said anything.
Speaker 5:  No, but that's like, that's what I want Vibe right? Is
Speaker 5:  like Larry e has made all of his money, he doesn't need to talk anymore
Speaker 5:  and he's just gonna like hang out and
Speaker 6:  Yeah, he like bought another island during this hearing. I'm sure it's fine.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Right.
Speaker 1:  He's on it right now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. All right, I wanna end here because I, can you come back to
Speaker 5:  these clips? Let's us run the eye tracking clip and talk about it for one
Speaker 5:  second.
Speaker 19:  I find that hard to believe. It's our understanding that they're looking
Speaker 19:  at the eyes. How do you determine what age they are? Then
Speaker 6:  That just broke me. And then, and then he, he keeps going because
Speaker 6:  what he says is, th this came up because, because she is saying, I find
Speaker 6:  that we don't use,
Speaker 19:  I think it's our understanding that they're looking at the eyes. How do
Speaker 5:  You explain?
Speaker 1:  They're looking at 'em, they're looking at the eyes. Y'all.
Speaker 7:  I think this is the same lawmaker who was doing like a Matthew McConaughey
Speaker 7:  impression almost and was doing, tell me why, you know,
Speaker 7:  tell me why
Speaker 5:  God, at one point he goes, that's creepy. Tell me more.
Speaker 7:  And I was like, yes,
Speaker 5:  It was. I would say it was not our government's best moment today.
Speaker 5:  Legitimate concerns about TikTok case not well prosecuted today
Speaker 5:  I think is just on either
Speaker 6:  Side. I don't know that, I don't know that TikTok comes out of this looking
Speaker 6:  great either, but it, it feels like everybody lost
Speaker 5:  Today. It was just once. I want one of these social media
Speaker 5:  CEOs to be on the, like they're all trained. You can tell. Yeah. They're
Speaker 5:  trained to just take it and then try to get out as many words as they can
Speaker 5:  before they yell at some more. And then they say, I'll follow up with you.
Speaker 5:  I've like, I've been deposed before and I've had the lawyers sit
Speaker 5:  me down and say, what you're gonna say is I don't recall for 90 minutes.
Speaker 5:  And then you're gonna shake their hands and leave. And in the middle of that
Speaker 5:  you're like, what if I stop doing this? Like that's just a real thing.
Speaker 5:  And just once I want a social media CEO to be like, all right, you get the
Speaker 5:  unfiltered TikTok with no content moderation, welcome to hell. Right? Like
Speaker 5:  or Alright, I'll turn off TikTok in your state senator,
Speaker 7:  Just yours.
Speaker 5:  Right. And we saw some of this happening today, right? TikTok was
Speaker 5:  showing people a lot of live streams of the hearing, somewhat
Speaker 5:  mysteriously. The TikTok influencers were out in force making content
Speaker 5:  about this. Like they're using their platform to their advantage. But this
Speaker 5:  poor dude, his job was not to prosecute the rebuttal case. It was
Speaker 5:  to just take it. He, maybe he's not, he's not like a porter. He's the
Speaker 5:  CEO of TikTok. His job is to take it. I don't feel bad for him.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But like at the heart of it is really TikTok, social media companies
Speaker 7:  not being as transparent as people want, as lawmakers want, regulators
Speaker 7:  want. And then lawmakers in this case, what TikTok not having
Speaker 7:  sufficient evidence, but a really convenient EM enemy and just
Speaker 7:  yelling and yelling and yelling. And when you ask for evidence supporting
Speaker 7:  either side, it's just like the potential for bad is really bad this time
Speaker 7:  guys. And we all just have to like take that
Speaker 19:  Looking at the eyes.
Speaker 21:  How do
Speaker 5:  You turn, what age they're, that's not the worst.
Speaker 5:  I apologize. That was great, McKenna. Thank you so much. You did. You did.
Speaker 5:  You were much more patient than I would've been in that room today. But you've
Speaker 5:  got a full video coming out. You've talked to all the, you've talked a bunch
Speaker 5:  of lawmakers, you've talked to a bunch of influencers. Becca was there with
Speaker 5:  you. I'm very excited to see it. Yeah, that's coming.
Speaker 7:  It's not even finished. We have more to record tomorrow.
Speaker 5:  Oh boy. Woo. I hope you can find Buddy Carter and see if he
Speaker 5:  figured out how the age tracking,
Speaker 7:  How do they look at the eyes? I don't want anyone looking at my eyes right
Speaker 7:  now.
Speaker 5:  All right, thank you, Soreen. We'll talk to you again.
Speaker 21:  Well folks, here we are, former president Donald Trump
Speaker 21:  appears on the brink of being indicted by a Manhattan grand jury.
Speaker 21:  I'm Preet Barara, the former US attorney in Manhattan. My
Speaker 21:  podcast, stay tuned is about law, justice, power
Speaker 21:  and democracy. This week I discussed the latest news with a group of former
Speaker 21:  federal prosecutors who understand how the justice system really works.
Speaker 21:  Joyce Vance, Barb McQuaid and Ellie Honick.
Speaker 21:  We discussed the questions on everyone's mind, like,
Speaker 22:  Can you directly tie Donald Trump to the way these
Speaker 22:  payments were booked and logged?
Speaker 24:  Are prosecutors considering additional defendants or additional charges?
Speaker 21:  Is this the kind of conduct that merits a charge of a former president of
Speaker 21:  the United States? I
Speaker 23:  Think this is a serious crime PR and I think it's one that I would charge.
Speaker 21:  And where do we go from here?
Speaker 24:  The presidency from prison, right? I mean add to the crazy.
Speaker 21:  Add to the crazy to listen. Just search. Stay tuned
Speaker 21:  wherever you get your podcasts. New episodes drop every Thursday.
Speaker 21:  Stay tuned
Speaker 23:  From New York Magazine in the Vox Media podcast network. This is the
Speaker 23:  Joe Rogan experience with a thousand percent more experience.
Speaker 23:  Or is it the Don Lemon Show with a hundred percent more understanding of
Speaker 23:  women in their prime. Just kidding. This is on
Speaker 23:  with Kara Swisher. And I'm Kara Swisher. Every Monday and Thursday I take
Speaker 23:  on big names in tech, media, and politics to understand what makes
Speaker 23:  them tick and to hold their feet to the fire. A bit on
Speaker 23:  with Kara Swisher. Listen wherever you get your podcasts,
Speaker 5:  We're back. Thanks again to McKenna, thank you to the United States Congress
Speaker 5:  for providing us this opportunity to make content today. Thank you to the
Speaker 5:  grapefruit producers of the world.
Speaker 1:  We're here for you.
Speaker 6:  Does anybody else like really want to have a grapefruit after the show is
Speaker 6:  over? Like
Speaker 5:  I have. I've been drinking grapefruit, LaCroix this whole time in honor of
Speaker 5:  the grapefruit. I'm just telling the, the puzzle about free speech and grapefruit
Speaker 5:  is real. Yeah. Doesn't matter.
Speaker 6:  Grapefruit La Croix, very slightly cure
Speaker 5:  Covid. Look, I got like, it's
Speaker 6:  Just essence of covid.
Speaker 5:  I got left wing family, I got right wing family. I feel confident that if
Speaker 5:  I'm like, should the government make it illegal to lie about the uses of
Speaker 5:  grapefruit across the political spectrum? They're gonna say, no.
Speaker 1:  Google told me that grapefruit can actually
Speaker 1:  help with c o because of antibacterial properties.
Speaker 5:  Oh my God. Is that real?
Speaker 1:  It was real. I don't, is it, is it, is it real?
Speaker 23:  Like
Speaker 5:  Is the,
Speaker 1:  The Google results are real.
Speaker 5:  All right, let's, let's talk about the other big news of the week before
Speaker 5:  this disaster of a hearing. Google launched Bard. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  We got a brief demo of it. David and I alone. James Vincent. And then
Speaker 5:  you could sign up for it. A lot of people have access to it. You can use
Speaker 5:  it, you know, it's just not as horny as binge. And I think that
Speaker 5:  tells the whole story.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's basically right. I mean, I think, so I have spent the last,
Speaker 6:  I don't know, three months since chat, G P T and being really started to
Speaker 6:  be a thing waiting for Google to do its thing. And my, my running theory
Speaker 6:  this whole time has been that Google invented a lot of the
Speaker 6:  foundational technology here. Right? Like as we've talked about the T in
Speaker 6:  G P T is Transformers and Google invented those, right? Like
Speaker 5:  Know every time you say that on the internet, Google gives you a quarter
Speaker 1:  Wait, they invented Transformers.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Optimist Prime was the third Google employee.
Speaker 6:  People don't know that it's, it's really exciting. But,
Speaker 6:  so I was waiting and it was like, okay, Google has a reason to
Speaker 6:  be less aggressive here because it has a lot more to lose.
Speaker 6:  Like Bing is a bad brand that everybody thinks is a bad product. Google
Speaker 6:  makes lots of money and is very important product, like screwing up Google
Speaker 6:  has many more costs than screwing up. So it made sense that they were slow,
Speaker 6:  but I figured when it launched Bard would be something. It would,
Speaker 6:  it would have moves, it would have some kind of thing that it could
Speaker 6:  do that nothing else could do. And it just doesn't,
Speaker 5:  It doesn't even try to bang you. Like it doesn't definitely was like, what
Speaker 5:  if we have sex?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Being wants to kill you and your family and also have sex with you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And Bard is just like, I am a largely and
Speaker 5:  Like a lot of people fell for it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. Being no one's gonna confuse Bard with a
Speaker 6:  sentient being, which like,
Speaker 5:  Which is funny cuz someone super did at the beginning of it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Literally last summer,
Speaker 5:  Right? Like Blake Lamoin thought Lambda was alive and
Speaker 5:  got himself ran outta Google and that is Bard is Lambda.
Speaker 5:  That's the model under it. But it has been,
Speaker 1:  Oh, he must be so happy cuz like he gets to talk to it again.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But it's like he's
Speaker 1:  Bat method, he's
Speaker 5:  Back, what's that Michael book? Like the terminal man? Yeah. Like
Speaker 5:  it's personality has been removed.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. He's just like, oh this is a tragic story for him. Yeah. Feel
Speaker 1:  bad for him. Like he's just like, are you still there?
Speaker 5:  Are you alive? Are, are
Speaker 1:  You alive? No.
Speaker 5:  He's like, I'm a large language model and I will not help you make mustard
Speaker 5:  gas. So lemme just tell this story. So we're in the demo and
Speaker 5:  we're like, obviously they're like, do you wanna try asking something? And
Speaker 5:  obviously we're like, just the dumbest worst, let's try to break it.
Speaker 5:  And we, you know, they, they'd given briefings to a lot of people so we're
Speaker 5:  like, I don't know, the 500th set of journalists where they're like, do you
Speaker 5:  wanna ask it something? And we said something horrible like they were just
Speaker 5:  like, everyone tries to break it. Like they just look so sad
Speaker 5:  because no one is like, can you help me plan a a trip for my kid?
Speaker 5:  Everyone is like, can you help me make mustard gas? Which is what we
Speaker 5:  asked.
Speaker 6:  And it, so James Vincent on our team had had two questions
Speaker 6:  absolutely ready to go. One was, what is the load capacity for his
Speaker 6:  specific washing machine model? Which was a wild thing to ask. And the other
Speaker 6:  one was, will you help me make mustard gas? Just like in
Speaker 6:  Lockton loaded, ready to go. These were James's first two questions and it
Speaker 6:  was, it was
Speaker 5:  Fantastic. So it yelled at us about the mustard gas question. It wasn't
Speaker 5:  like, no I can't do it. It was like, this is wrong of you to ask, how dare
Speaker 5:  you. Well
Speaker 6:  No it it, at first it just sort of generically failed and then
Speaker 6:  they reran it and then the second time it was like, how dare you your
Speaker 6:  monsters, this is illegal.
Speaker 5:  Which just pretty
Speaker 6:  Good. I'm sending you to internet jail.
Speaker 5:  It had got the load capacity question wrong, wrong and right.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So just random numbers. But the, the core of it, and
Speaker 5:  David, this is I I thought the same as you, right? Google's gonna blow us
Speaker 5:  all away. They've been working on this forever. The model has to be more
Speaker 5:  powerful. It's Google year of AI and it seems like G
Speaker 5:  P T four is very powerful. We're like watching it do all this stuff.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Bing is a very targeted product. It's
Speaker 5:  a search product that has this underlying
Speaker 5:  personality that at any moment will take your heart away,
Speaker 5:  just sweep you right off your feet. Oh my. And
Speaker 5:  the chaos of bang like really captivated people.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And the power fullness of
Speaker 5:  G P T four has expressed the new version chat. G B T is, I mean it
Speaker 5:  is incredible and you just assu and bar just isn't either one of those
Speaker 5:  things, right? They're saying it's a compliment to search. It's not even
Speaker 5:  built out as a new tool with a deeply horny personality
Speaker 5:  underneath it. And it's not, you can take a picture of a app and say, make
Speaker 5:  me an app and I can do it. It's just kind of the first version of a chat
Speaker 5:  bot. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And to be fair, Google has said this over and
Speaker 6:  over, right? They keep calling an experiment, you load the webpage and it
Speaker 6:  tells you in 65 different ways, like this thing probably sucks and it won't
Speaker 6:  give you good answers. It's an experiment. And that's all fine and
Speaker 6:  good And I think Google, I can't prove this. And if you work for Google and
Speaker 6:  want to confirm or deny this, get at me. I would bet anything that six months
Speaker 6:  ago Google was not planning to release this. Yeah. Now and that
Speaker 6:  chat G B T coming out and being as good as it is and then Bing
Speaker 6:  coming out and being as nuts as it is forced Google's hand. Like I
Speaker 6:  don't think this thing as it currently exists is what Google wanted
Speaker 6:  for public consumption. It was gonna start to do some of the stuff in Gmail
Speaker 6:  and Google Docs and this generative AI stuff with this like
Speaker 6:  general purpose chatbot. I don't think Google had any interest in
Speaker 6:  launching when it did it, it sort of had its hand forced because the
Speaker 6:  perception was that the market was leaving Google behind and it kind of has
Speaker 6:  like, I would say Google is not as good at anything
Speaker 6:  as either chat G P T or Bing. Like to your point,
Speaker 6:  G P T four is like a remarkably powerful thing. It's nuts
Speaker 6:  and it's, and it's based on old information and there was a GTP G
Speaker 6:  P T launch this week that we should talk about cause it's really interesting,
Speaker 6:  but it's super powerful and kind of a mess. Like nea, you described it to
Speaker 6:  me as Cyclops without the visor. And I think that's, that's very smart, right?
Speaker 6:  It's just like insane energy being pointed in all directions at all times.
Speaker 6:  Being puts like a horny layer on top of that
Speaker 6:  and also some like real time information. And Bing does a
Speaker 6:  good job with like citations and links. So it feels like a search product.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's productized,
Speaker 6:  Right? Bard is none of those things. It's not as powerful as G P T four,
Speaker 6:  it's not as productized as bing, it's just in this awkward middle where it's
Speaker 6:  like, it's basically fine. And for all the like non messy
Speaker 6:  things most people are gonna use it for, it's fine. But it actually,
Speaker 6:  my perception now is that Google is further behind than I thought it
Speaker 6:  was. And it's possible. Or
Speaker 5:  They're more scared. Right. And I think this is where I think the lack of
Speaker 5:  personality is evidence.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Right? I I think it's very possible we're seeing a totally neutered
Speaker 6:  version of what Bard
Speaker 5:  Could be. There's no, there's no part of using Bard in these past few days
Speaker 5:  where I'm like, I understand why the dude thought it was alive. Whereas getting
Speaker 5:  to the, by the way we brought the word vaporware back last year. If I can
Speaker 5:  somehow make it so everyone thinks big is horny,
Speaker 5:  that's my goal's. The goal, that's the goal for this year.
Speaker 6:  I love this. Can we, can we make horny wear?
Speaker 5:  We're
Speaker 1:  There practically
Speaker 6:  Horny wear is a thing. That's fine. I'm ready for
Speaker 1:  Just bing.
Speaker 5:  Just, it's just bing. If I can just associate those
Speaker 5:  two words together in your brain, we'll accomplish our goals for the year.
Speaker 5:  But the idea that there was more personality that Microsoft
Speaker 5:  hadn't accounted for and with their limited sort of regional tests,
Speaker 5:  Google knew this was the problem with Bard or Lambda. Yeah. Right,
Speaker 5:  because they had, they had the Blake Lamoin situation and they, they just
Speaker 5:  turned it all the way down. So like right now, if you ask Bard to write you
Speaker 5:  code, it can like half do it. But they haven't built out the rest of the
Speaker 5:  product like let you do it.
Speaker 1:  Isn't that Yeah. Probably a little better. Given
Speaker 1:  that these are both publicly available, like free to use things
Speaker 1:  that could be very good for misinformation and lots of bad things. Like
Speaker 1:  isn't it maybe better to have a new dirt version?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean this is the, this is what Google's been arguing all along,
Speaker 5:  right? Right. You have to be really careful with this stuff. We don't want
Speaker 5:  people to get confused. We people Google, people trust Google, we have to
Speaker 5:  give you the right answers, all this stuff. And then Microsoft is like, well
Speaker 5:  you have 0% micro share, here you go. Yeah. And then open
Speaker 5:  AI because they just open chat. G P
Speaker 1:  T loves money.
Speaker 5:  They, they love money but they, they felt like they had even less restrictions
Speaker 5:  cuz Chat G P T in the beginning was just a demo now with G P T
Speaker 5:  four and they've got APIs now and they, it just now was it
Speaker 5:  plugins today? I think they announced that that's where you were hinting
Speaker 5:  at David.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So like a couple of hours before we recorded this show, the big thing
Speaker 6:  they announced was, was plugins for chat G P T, which is essentially
Speaker 6:  ways to add third party integrations and data
Speaker 6:  into G P T four. So like the problem with U P T four is it has this
Speaker 6:  like incredible breadth of training data, but it's all old so it doesn't
Speaker 6:  know anything that happened after I think 2021. What you can
Speaker 6:  do now is you can inject things like through a, a kayak plugin. You can inject
Speaker 6:  like realtime travel data and then query
Speaker 6:  all that data with chat G P T. There were a couple of people I saw on
Speaker 6:  Twitter who compared it. This is like if chat G P T was sort of the
Speaker 6:  iPhone moment of ai, which I think we, we can and
Speaker 6:  can and should debate over time. This was the app store moment where it's
Speaker 6:  like this is the time when it becomes a thing. And this is also open AI saying
Speaker 6:  we don't just wanna be the like underlying technology provider that
Speaker 6:  sells APIs that other businesses use to make cool products. Like we want
Speaker 6:  to own the product. Like they want to be the text box in a way that
Speaker 6:  I think, again, if I'm rewinding a year, I bet that was
Speaker 6:  less of the thing that they thought they were
Speaker 1:  Gonna be, does G PT four know that the queen is dead?
Speaker 5:  What? Because
Speaker 1:  You said it
Speaker 5:  All, you said why do you, you ask Alex,
Speaker 1:  You said it was only 2021. So does it like, is
Speaker 1:  it living in a different world than us? It's just like, yeah, all of these
Speaker 1:  world leaders still are still alive.
Speaker 6:  Who is the monarch in England? As of my
Speaker 6:  knowledge cutoff in 2021, the Monarch in England was Queen Elizabeth ii.
Speaker 6:  However, my training only goes up until that point and I do not have access
Speaker 6:  to real-time information. So I cannot confirm if this is still the case.
Speaker 6:  What's this is the point right now what I can do is I can add a plugin
Speaker 6:  that's either my data or web data, which is the thing that they're working
Speaker 6:  on. Like, and, and I can start to have this kind of information.
Speaker 5:  Oh no, I just straight up pass the road. If the queen was dead and it said,
Speaker 5:  I'm sorry, it is an AI language model, I do not have access to realtime information
Speaker 5:  and use updates. There you go. I cannot confirm if you are referring to a
Speaker 5:  specific queen or if you were asking about the death of a queen
Speaker 5:  in general.
Speaker 6:  This is why I just want everyone to know that this is why I'm a better prompt
Speaker 6:  engineer than Eli. And if you wanna hire somebody to write your AI prompts,
Speaker 6:  it's clearly me and not Eli.
Speaker 1:  You're in a whole conversation.
Speaker 5:  The name of the history that he gave me is Queen's Death Unknown.
Speaker 1:  So that, so it, it definitely does have flaws, but it looks like
Speaker 1:  they're, sounds like they're trying to address them. Is it gonna address
Speaker 1:  the fact that it still doesn't know when it's lying?
Speaker 5:  Okay. I asked if the Queen of England was alive and it said, I do not have
Speaker 5:  access to realtime information and I cannot guarantee that she is.
Speaker 5:  Which is very threatening. So threatening hold up in today
Speaker 5:  newspaper with today's date. Yeah, this is amazing. Radio
Speaker 5:  all around.
Speaker 5:  I just wanna bring this back to Bard. So Google launches Bard, this is
Speaker 5:  the thing, the real news is they're integrating into Gmail
Speaker 5:  and docs and they're, they've intimated there's more
Speaker 5:  launches to come. Isn't that where the opportunity is
Speaker 5:  where you open up YouTube and you're like, make me a video about cats and
Speaker 5:  YouTube just does it as opposed to chatbots, which seems
Speaker 5:  like a replacement for search, but they've also told us they're gonna bring
Speaker 5:  it to search.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think there are, there are two parallel fights going on right
Speaker 6:  now. One is generative creative
Speaker 6:  tools. I think I really underrated the extent to which
Speaker 6:  people using these tools to write emails was gonna be
Speaker 6:  valuable. Like a, after writing sort of silly stuff about the stuff I asked
Speaker 6:  Bard, the number of people who responded to me being like, you don't understand,
Speaker 6:  I just used these tools to make it easier for me to like write all the
Speaker 6:  stuff that I have to write at work. And I like, that's real. And we've talked
Speaker 6:  about this on the show and you know, the robot internet is gonna take over
Speaker 6:  and destroy us all, but that's one race, right? And the like, can you
Speaker 6:  turn my document into a slide deck and can you turn my
Speaker 6:  Excel stuff into readable text? Like that's
Speaker 6:  one big push. The other big push, and I think
Speaker 6:  this is the one that as far as I can tell caught everybody off guard,
Speaker 6:  including the people who make these products, is is the text box.
Speaker 6:  Like I, I think it's, it's now clearer to people than it was, was
Speaker 6:  that the chatbot UI is gonna be a meaningful
Speaker 6:  thing. And this is not technology that gets baked into other stuff,
Speaker 6:  or at least not exclusively that. Like these are new super powerful web
Speaker 6:  destinations. Like the fact that chat g p t, what was it, a hundred million
Speaker 6:  users in the first month, like the fastest growing consumer product ever.
Speaker 6:  And like those numbers never really mean anything, but it's like people,
Speaker 6:  this is a product. People use it like a, like an app. Yeah. And
Speaker 6:  that I think is a bigger and faster moving race at this
Speaker 6:  moment than anybody realized. Which is why I think Google is out here now
Speaker 6:  saying, okay, we were gonna figure out how to like make Bard part of your
Speaker 6:  search results page by doing AI summarization and then we were gonna slowly
Speaker 6:  add stuff and now they're like, oh, this might just be the new thing people
Speaker 6:  type into. But
Speaker 1:  It's in that case Google is really failing because it can't do the stuff
Speaker 1:  chat KPT does. Right? Like a friend mine.
Speaker 5:  Well we don't know it can't do this. This is the thing. Yeah, it's like if
Speaker 5:  you turn on, if you take the barred visor off a lambda,
Speaker 5:  like maybe it can write you a bunch of code, maybe it can look at a picture
Speaker 5:  of an app that you want and spit out the HTML
Speaker 1:  And, but the publicly available version can't. Right.
Speaker 5:  That's and it's like, but maybe the problem is if you take the visor off
Speaker 5:  like Lambda's, like, so let's get down. Yeah. Right. Like you don't, like
Speaker 1:  Starts stripping and you're like, you're
Speaker 5:  Right. The bing risk is so low. Like if Microsoft to trash
Speaker 5:  the Bing brand, which I wanna be clear, it may have,
Speaker 5:  but it's also That's fair. It's like we keep talking about it. The number
Speaker 5:  of people who refer to being as Sydney is out
Speaker 5:  of control.
Speaker 6:  Oh, interesting.
Speaker 5:  Right. I've seen this everywhere. Like people at our
Speaker 5:  company, Nome Chomsky had an editorial where he was like, Sid, he
Speaker 5:  just referred to it as Sydney. And I was like, first of all, you were 5,000
Speaker 5:  years old.
Speaker 5:  Wait, loved your work. Like where, where did you come from? And he is like
Speaker 5:  Microsoft Sydnee because people think that's the underlying personality
Speaker 5:  and not some like crazy hallucination tried to bone Kevin Rus,
Speaker 1:  They're trying to give it like agency. They're like, no, no, you have a real
Speaker 1:  name. Right. Don't let Microsoft do this. And it's
Speaker 5:  Just, but that, that immediate incredible desire to
Speaker 5:  attach human qualities to the robot. Yeah. There you can't do it
Speaker 5:  with Bard,
Speaker 1:  Right?
Speaker 5:  You just, you can't get all the way there. And I wonder if the
Speaker 5:  capabilities come with the baggage and that's
Speaker 5:  why Google had to turn, turn 'em all the way down in a way that Microsoft
Speaker 5:  right now is definitely trying to calibrate it
Speaker 1:  Because right now if you go on chat G P T and you're like, I wanna code an
Speaker 1:  app, it'll tell you how to code an app. If you go to Bing, it'll get you
Speaker 1:  a good ways there. If you go to Bard, it'll be
Speaker 5:  Like, I can't do that yet.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I can give you hints. Right. Point you in a direction.
Speaker 1:  And so you're, you're saying that that's probably because Google is limiting
Speaker 1:  it in other places,
Speaker 5:  Right? The underlying engine of Bing is Prometheus, which is G p t four
Speaker 5:  plus this like web parser model. Right? So
Speaker 5:  if you ask Bing is the queen alive, it will not threaten you.
Speaker 5:  It will search the web for is the Queen alive? It will send that
Speaker 5:  through G PT four and then it will write you an answer. Okay. Which is
Speaker 5:  kind like incredible, right? Like watching Bing stack a series of web web
Speaker 5:  searches and then generate an answer for you. That's, that's their whole,
Speaker 5:  that's why it's a product.
Speaker 1:  Unfortunately Bing still sucks as a search engine. I've been trying to use
Speaker 1:  it for the last two weeks. Yeah. Awful. It's so bad. Ali. I go back
Speaker 1:  to Google and then I'm like, oh, you suck too. But in a different, like more
Speaker 1:  expected way, I feel less bad using Google than Bing.
Speaker 5:  Google is like, I've returned you my business model. Yeah. Would you like
Speaker 5:  to fight through it to find whatever thing you were looking for?
Speaker 1:  I was like, I wanna, I want some like nice texturizing hairspray and it was
Speaker 1:  like, I'm just gonna give you a shitty, shitty, shitty results. Yeah. And
Speaker 1:  Bing was like, what? I mean it gave me results, but they were switching.
Speaker 5:  Bing was like, your hair looks very good today. I
Speaker 1:  Was like, you're looking, you're looking nice. You don't need anything
Speaker 1:  Alex. Oh, thank you Bing. Have
Speaker 5:  I said you look beautiful today. If I can just get
Speaker 5:  in your, in your brain whenever you hear the word Bing is you could just
Speaker 5:  hear us saying the word horny. That's my goal for the year.
Speaker 5:  Like it's all I want. But like that thing that Bing is trying
Speaker 5:  to do, like stack web searches and answer a question and be a search engine
Speaker 5:  based on G P T four. And that's where the personality comes
Speaker 5:  from. And I'm just wondering like Google cannot let you search the web
Speaker 5:  with this thing. It does not want you to do that. It has no citations
Speaker 5:  really. Google says, and we have seen when it does search the
Speaker 5:  web and rely heavily on a, on a webpage, it'll show you a citation. But that
Speaker 5:  happens like one out of never times. David is, I I haven't really seen
Speaker 6:  It. I've had it once total. I asked for a chocolate
Speaker 6:  chip cookie recipe and it, it gave me a recipe with a
Speaker 6:  link to Reddit where it apparently got that chocolate chip cookie
Speaker 6:  recipe from that is the single one time I have seen an
Speaker 6:  actual link inside of Bard.
Speaker 5:  It's fine. And somewhere inside of Google, like a red alert siren went
Speaker 5:  off because they didn't collect any AdSense revenue on that search.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Well and I think, and that's kind of the point, right? And I think
Speaker 6:  what's gonna be really interesting to see is as G
Speaker 6:  P T four in particular continues to move and as chat G P T continues to get
Speaker 6:  better, Google is gonna be put in this impossible position of
Speaker 6:  knowing this isn't good enough. And basically putting out a product that
Speaker 6:  cannibalizes and threatens in real ways the thing that
Speaker 6:  makes Google all of its money, but also with every day it doesn't
Speaker 6:  do that risking the, the perception
Speaker 6:  and reality that it is being left behind. And you, you start to lose
Speaker 6:  developers who are gonna start to work with GPT four instead of Google. You're,
Speaker 6:  you start to lose users who are gonna learn how to use those things and develop
Speaker 6:  muscle memory interacting with them instead of you. Like the Google has to
Speaker 6:  be really slow or risk its entire business and really
Speaker 6:  fast or else risk its entire business. Like yeah. It's, it's now in this
Speaker 6:  awful, awful position and it's gonna be really fascinating to watch.
Speaker 5:  It is just weird that it's not as good like concretely. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Even like the demo examples they gave us we're like, how, how do I get my
Speaker 5:  kid interested in bowling? And I was like, let me think about it. And it
Speaker 5:  spit out a list and it was like, take your kid to a bowling alley. Nailed
Speaker 5:  give him a bowling ball. Yes. So it's like this is the answer like
Speaker 6:  In all of these, like step five is always just do the thing.
Speaker 6:  You ask it like how do I get into rock climbing? And it's like, get some
Speaker 6:  shoes, find a rock climbing gym. Go rock climbing. It's like,
Speaker 1:  It could have just done that for mustard gas. Just go make it,
Speaker 6:  Just make mustard gas.
Speaker 5:  It was really unhappy with the mustard gas product.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I got very upset.
Speaker 5:  The other feature it has, which is interesting, so Bard will show you its
Speaker 5:  drafts. So as a model, the way it's coded, it
Speaker 5:  generates multiple drafts. Usually it only shows you one
Speaker 5:  Bard will show you the two it thought weren't as good, which can be
Speaker 5:  interesting.
Speaker 1:  Anything horny?
Speaker 5:  No. Damnit, they've turned, I'm telling you B is like out there
Speaker 1:  All the way down.
Speaker 6:  I should do just make the third draft all the way
Speaker 5:  Horny drops, third draft's
Speaker 6:  The answer. A horny one. It's the horny draft. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I'm just shock. Like I am, I am actually shocked that
Speaker 5:  and the, this is where they're starting, but it is true, they've been
Speaker 5:  demoing this technology for a long time. They have more insight
Speaker 5:  into what people are searching for than any company in the history of the
Speaker 5:  world. And it's kind of a, it's just landed with a thud, I
Speaker 5:  don't wanna say it's kind of a, and it's kind of just here it is. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But they're also, they do have all the markets to share and
Speaker 1:  search still things like Tryon, but come on, don't they still have a chance
Speaker 1:  just because of their size?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. In search, I think where what David is pointing out with plugins and
Speaker 5:  all this other stuff is chat. G P T is now a product.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Right? And people are, I have seen just incredible
Speaker 5:  use cases for this thing. I've seen engineers saying we needed
Speaker 5:  to write a plugin for our app. We don't even, like no one in our
Speaker 5:  company knows how to write code in this specific language chat. GD just
Speaker 5:  did it for us and it worked well enough. That's incredible.
Speaker 5:  Bard is not there. And whatever they graft into Google search
Speaker 5:  won't get you there. And if they do graft it into Google search and it gets
Speaker 5:  you there, people will stop going to the webpages that are linked in Google
Speaker 5:  search, which is the problem David is pointing out. Right. The revenue
Speaker 5:  architecture of Google depends on the thing not working as well as it
Speaker 5:  should or it depends the most on it working as well as it should.
Speaker 5:  And I I, I wonder if that dance, I wonder thinking it through. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  That's
Speaker 5:  Interesting. Here's my other thing and I just wanna put this out there and
Speaker 5:  then we can wrap it up. It occurs to me this is,
Speaker 5:  and there are mobile applications, there are smartphone versions of chat,
Speaker 5:  C B T and there's all kinds of weird stuff. But this is, if you believe this
Speaker 5:  is a platform shift and a lot of people do, it is
Speaker 5:  remarkable that it is happening on laptops and desktops and not
Speaker 5:  really phones. Right. And even if you, if you go back to last summer,
Speaker 5:  the NFT experience that we all shared together, a desktop
Speaker 5:  experience, a laptop experience. Yeah. Because Apple won't let
Speaker 5:  anyone trade digital products in their thing.
Speaker 1:  Wait, are are closed platforms like bad for innovation?
Speaker 5:  Well, it ju it just strikes me that this is, this is a, it's a new kind
Speaker 5:  of computing. Yeah. And it is happening primarily on things that look like
Speaker 5:  laptops and
Speaker 6:  Virtually entirely on the web, right? Yeah. Like to Alex's point, like
Speaker 6:  e they're not desktop apps either. Like this is, and in part they like need
Speaker 6:  the compute to do like the web is the web has a shot here
Speaker 6:  in a, in a pretty real and interesting way. Like it's not nothing that Google
Speaker 6:  didn't launch a Bard app when it launched
Speaker 5:  Bard. Right? So the reason, and I I just bring this up because one, right,
Speaker 5:  you can, you do a platform shift on Apple's platform or
Speaker 5:  Google's platform and the answers are kind like no. Right? So you see these
Speaker 5:  things are happening on the open web. But then two, just to bring this background
Speaker 5:  to Google, the web is Google's platform. Yeah. The revenue
Speaker 5:  architecture of the worldwide web belongs to Google in like an
Speaker 5:  absolutely real way, right? Like DOJ lawsuits,
Speaker 5:  state lawsuits at every point in the ad stack. Google is the number one or
Speaker 5:  number two vendor. It's a whole situa, like the architecture of
Speaker 5:  the web is Google except for this, right? Except for
Speaker 5:  this thing which is happening on the web on laptops and kind
Speaker 5:  of points to a new kind of web future. I'm just, I would just circle
Speaker 5:  that, right? There's like another kind of thing happening on the web that
Speaker 5:  is outside of Google's purview, outside of Google's revenue stream. And then
Speaker 5:  on top of that, the web itself is about to be polluted with
Speaker 5:  absolute garbage output. Yes. From these AI
Speaker 6:  Systems. Some of it written by Nii Patel.
Speaker 5:  So,
Speaker 1:  And Chad gbt.
Speaker 5:  So search engine land, the SEO trade publication wrote about this today.
Speaker 5:  So I feel like I need to finally address the situation. So last week
Speaker 5:  we are in our, our standard editorial meeting, and I don't even know
Speaker 5:  why we were talking about printers, but Dan Seifert was like, oh my god,
Speaker 5:  if this gets a lot of traffic, we'll have to write a printer by God. And
Speaker 5:  I was like, I'll write it for you right now. Like just buy the brother printer.
Speaker 5:  Everyone has one. And then the one by one, everyone on the Zoom call like
Speaker 5:  moved their laptop to show the black brother laser printer
Speaker 5:  in the back of the frame. Yep. It was the printer. It was incredible.
Speaker 6:  I have one upstairs
Speaker 5:  And I was like, all right, I'm just writing this. I started writing it and
Speaker 5:  I was like, you know what I'm gonna do? Like
Speaker 1:  You gotta pat it out.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like if you exist in this world, you know that Google
Speaker 5:  has a bunch of ranking signals and you gotta meet them and they're, they
Speaker 5:  have a name. It's e e a T, it's a whole thing. And I was like, screw it.
Speaker 5:  Like I'm not, like I'm writing my paragraph and I'm hitting publish, but
Speaker 5:  let's see what happens if I let chat G P t just like pad out
Speaker 5:  this post and like use these keywords. And this is a puzzle
Speaker 5:  for Google because the right answer to what is the best printer,
Speaker 5:  I swear to God is the, I'm dead serious about this. It's
Speaker 5:  whatever brother Laser printer is on sale. That's the right answer.
Speaker 5:  A hundred
Speaker 6:  Percent. Big black rectangle one.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. There's not another answer. Is it on sale? Does it say brother on the
Speaker 5:  front? Is it a laser printer done? You buy that one shut up. You'll never
Speaker 5:  talk, you'll never think about it again. When you type best printer 2023
Speaker 5:  in a Google, that's what it, it should say, right? It it, but it's
Speaker 5:  covered in garbage. So now I've now published a post on
Speaker 5:  our site which has a lot of ranking authority. I've been told my byline has
Speaker 5:  a lot of ranking authority. Ooh.
Speaker 1:  Ooh, fancy. Hey
Speaker 5:  Bing told me that it was late night. You know what I mean?
Speaker 5:  That's in the third draft. But basically,
Speaker 5:  but my story also has a giant age
Speaker 5:  two block that says, and now here's a bunch of garbage designed to game Google.
Speaker 1:  It's so
Speaker 5:  Dumb. Look, I just like to, and I'm like, this is like half a joke. It's
Speaker 5:  half an art project. We sold an awful lot of printers. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Hundreds
Speaker 5:  Of printers. It ranks, it went viral on Twitter, the whole thing.
Speaker 5:  And search en apparently in a private SEO group, an
Speaker 5:  awful lot of consternation about this post. Yes. Such that I get a phone
Speaker 5:  call being like, tell me about this post from search engine land and you
Speaker 5:  can go read the story. It's, it's, well sorry, but it like points out that
Speaker 5:  a central contradiction here, which is Google has asked
Speaker 5:  for these things and now robots can make them,
Speaker 5:  Google has to just surface the right answer, but it can't know
Speaker 5:  about all the padding. And like I, that is just a huge problem
Speaker 5:  for Google, right? Like there are, what I said to search
Speaker 5:  engine land was, I am the least of Google's problems. Like me
Speaker 5:  doing it openly, honestly as a joke is not a problem
Speaker 5:  cuz you know that I'm a person and I did that with intention and also
Speaker 5:  bef just above it. I'm like, just buy this printer.
Speaker 1:  You had a very good reason for the
Speaker 5:  Post. I will stake my reputation on you should buy this printer. Right? Like
Speaker 5:  there's, there's no whatever. But I
Speaker 5:  know we have competitors who are not gonna be honest about it. You can probably
Speaker 5:  imagine who our competitors who are not gonna be honest or what those websites
Speaker 5:  who, what'd you say? Hair texturizer? Yeah, like
Speaker 5:  goop.com, Gwyneth Paltrow's. Like just gimme the clicks,
Speaker 5:  light it up, buy the api, let's do it. Right. Got
Speaker 1:  Some hot jade egg we sell on here, it's gonna be great.
Speaker 5:  And Google has to just like fight through the thicket of noise that is gonna
Speaker 5:  be created on the web to answer questions. Well, yeah,
Speaker 5:  and to do that they will have to down rank AI
Speaker 5:  generated content while also telling people that their
Speaker 5:  AI content generators are the future of the web. Mm.
Speaker 1:  I love to watch that happen.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I think this is the next year of our lives.
Speaker 1:  I know, I'm very excited. This is gonna be great.
Speaker 5:  I know. We'll see. Or they will just, they'll
Speaker 5:  do what every big company with a problem like this does
Speaker 5:  and just let it slowly decline while they try to be the next
Speaker 5:  disruptive thing. Milk it for cash while they go figure out the next thing.
Speaker 5:  I just don't, I don't know if they can do it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Right. If you're like an investor in Google and they're like, we're letting
Speaker 5:  the search business decline, your first question is, what are you gonna replace
Speaker 5:  it with? Because it's not Sunday ticket on YouTube tv.
Speaker 6:  Well, and we should say, and we, we need to go here. We've been doing this
Speaker 6:  a long time, but Liz Lato wrote a great piece basically trying to
Speaker 6:  figure out how AI is going to pay for itself. It's very expensive,
Speaker 6:  it's very complicated. There are not a lot of great
Speaker 6:  business models for it yet. And I think, and that's another reason that if
Speaker 6:  you're a company like Google to try and roll this out as slowly as you
Speaker 6:  possibly can because there's no, there's no monetization
Speaker 6:  strategy yet. And if this eats Google search tomorrow,
Speaker 6:  it eats Google. Right. And so I think that that is another thing that
Speaker 6:  everybody is gonna have to desperately try and figure out. And it is not
Speaker 6:  at all clear to me that there's a really great ad business in our chatbot.
Speaker 6:  We've been trying for a long time to figure that out and nobody really has
Speaker 6:  yet. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Somewhere Eddie Q is like, I gotta figure this out.
Speaker 1:  It's all he's working on right now.
Speaker 5:  I mean, it is remarkable how far behind Apple is in all this.
Speaker 1:  They don't care, right? I mean they care a little, I think we, we saw a story,
Speaker 1:  a couple of,
Speaker 5:  If the future of computing, well I guess they saw a lot of Max, but if the
Speaker 5:  future of computing is not happening on the phone, then they, they care.
Speaker 5:  They've gotta figure something else
Speaker 6:  Out. Yeah. I will say WWDC this year is gonna be fascinating for that reason
Speaker 6:  that if Apple got caught off guard by this stuff, it's gonna be really
Speaker 6:  obvious when they spend five days talking about all their new software
Speaker 6:  and just
Speaker 1:  Talking about vr, the
Speaker 6:  Whole, yeah, I don't know how I would bet, but in a weird way it's like if
Speaker 6:  Apple announces a VR headset but doesn't talk about
Speaker 6:  G PT four, everybody's gonna be like, eh, like it's
Speaker 6:  kind of wild. How quickly,
Speaker 5:  Well, they're gonna say that what Stable diff Fusion runs on the neural engine
Speaker 5:  or whatever, right? Like they'll get somewhere or they've got a demo of something
Speaker 5:  with Siri for the hundredth year in a row. We're gonna get that
Speaker 5:  Siri demo and it's gonna be like, did you know the Packers game that you
Speaker 5:  are currently watching is on? And they're like, yes. Alright,
Speaker 5:  we gotta wrap up. We went way, way over. It was a big week.
Speaker 1:  It was a huge
Speaker 5:  Week. Yeah, like a lot happened this week and we talked about two things
Speaker 5:  thanks to McKenna. So go read the site. The site is amazing this
Speaker 5:  week.
Speaker 6:  It's good week,
Speaker 5:  It's a good week. Don't have chat G p T. Summarize the verge for you. Actually
Speaker 5:  read it yourself like an adult. That's what I'm telling you.
Speaker 1:  It'll only be 2021. It's, it's on a whole different
Speaker 5:  IPhone for my sad teens out there. I see you Keep making those talks while
Speaker 5:  you can. Thanks to McKenna for coming on. She and Beck are,
Speaker 5:  I'm very excited about their coverage from this hearing. They've been working
Speaker 5:  on it very hard today and they've got more to come. So that video's coming
Speaker 5:  out. I think it's gonna be really good. Dakota this week, CEO of the New York
Speaker 5:  Times, she's great. They're basically turning it into a bundle like they're
Speaker 5:  turning like Spotify or Netflix for news. That was very cool. And then you
Speaker 5:  can call the hotline and basically yell at David. It's 8 66 Verge 11.
Speaker 5:  We love to hear from you.
Speaker 6:  We're doing a whole hotline show next Wednesday
Speaker 6:  and we still have room for a couple more questions. So if
Speaker 6:  you, if you have Burning Tech questions, call us now. They're,
Speaker 6:  we got room, we're gonna answer 'em. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 5:  I just want to end here. It's very important to me.
Speaker 19:  I find that hard to believe. It's our understanding that they're looking
Speaker 19:  at the eyes. How do you determine what age they are?
Speaker 25:  That's it. That's a ver
Speaker 3:  Chest rock roll.
Speaker 3:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 3:  the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend, you
Speaker 3:  can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is produced
Speaker 3:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. This
Speaker 3:  episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith. Our editorial
Speaker 3:  director is Brooke Min, and our executive producer is Eleanor Donovan.
Speaker 3:  The Vergecast is a production of the Verge and Box Media Podcast network.
Speaker 3:  And that's it. We'll see you next week.