# Transcript
ID: 4b14d778-73a9-4899-947f-937f3a81427f
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The smart glasses era is (kind of) here
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8124861094301394363/4230116848077449639/s93290-US-5039s-1697621810.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of glassholes:
The Verge’s David Pierce chats with Victoria Song about her experience using the new Ray-Ban smart glasses from Meta.
Ray-Ban Meta Smart Glasses hands-on: in pursuit of content
The Verge’s Sean Hollister and iFixit’s Kyle Wiens join the show to discuss the latest legislation in the right to repair and what’s next for the future of fixing your own gadgets.
Right-to-repair is now the law in California
The Verge’s Nathan Edwards answers this week’s Vergecast Hotline question.
The iPhone 15 and 15 Pro launch with ‘future Qi2 wireless charging.’ Here’s why.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of glassholes.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend David Pierce and I am currently in my, I don't know, we
Speaker 2:  call it the utility room, but it's the room with like my washer and the furnace
Speaker 2:  and also it's like where we keep all of our extra paper towels, whatever
Speaker 2:  we call that room. That's where I am. I just finished my latest
Speaker 2:  home improvement project, which was to replace a bunch of
Speaker 2:  doorknobs over the course of the last two years since we bought a house.
Speaker 2:  I've gone from like I can put together Ikea furniture and feel
Speaker 2:  unnecessarily proud of myself for a week level handy to
Speaker 2:  I can watch a bunch of YouTube videos about that and probably figure out
Speaker 2:  how to take it apart and out of the wall and put it back together and back
Speaker 2:  in the wall again. Feels like big progress. I'm not really sure it's actually
Speaker 2:  all that big progress. But anyway, I just replaced a bunch of doorknobs,
Speaker 2:  which I truly cannot recommend enough as a project to give you
Speaker 2:  more pleasure than it was work like. Now every time I hold onto
Speaker 2:  that doorknob I'm like, I did this even though it was like unscrewing four
Speaker 2:  screws and screwing four screws back in again. And by the way, if you have
Speaker 2:  more ideas for home improvement projects that are very little work
Speaker 2:  and make you feel very proud of yourself for a long time, please send them
Speaker 2:  my way. I'd love to hear all about them. Anyway, we have an awesome show
Speaker 2:  coming up for you today. We're gonna talk about the right to repair fight
Speaker 2:  that has happened in California. There's a new law there that I actually
Speaker 2:  think it's a big deal for the whole way that we buy and repair and
Speaker 2:  use our electronics. We're also gonna talk about the new smart glasses
Speaker 2:  from Meta and Ray Ban. I think these are fascinating. You've heard me talk
Speaker 2:  about why I think smart glasses are interesting really for the last few weeks
Speaker 2:  since Amazon launched the new echo frames and Meta has these new smart glasses.
Speaker 2:  This is just a device category I find totally fascinating.
Speaker 2:  Vs. Song has been reviewing them for us. We're gonna talk to her and get
Speaker 2:  the whole rundown. And of course we're gonna get to The Vergecast Hotline.
Speaker 2:  We have a fun one today, which is a question I have also had. All that is
Speaker 2:  coming up in just a second. But first I just realized all of the batteries
Speaker 2:  to my drill are now dead because I don't use this thing enough and should
Speaker 2:  probably charge it more often. So I'm gonna go plug a bunch of stuff in and
Speaker 2:  then we're gonna get to it. This is The Vergecast. See you in a sec.
Speaker 3:  It's not just sci-fi anymore. Virtual reality for work is here.
Speaker 3:  Mixed reality for work is here and companies everywhere are using them
Speaker 3:  both to transform how they operate. Architects are able to walk
Speaker 3:  through buildings and mixed reality before they're even built. Coworkers
Speaker 3:  from opposite ends of the earth are working shoulder to shoulder in VR spaces
Speaker 3:  and all sorts of workers from pilots to underwater welders are getting trained
Speaker 3:  in a virtual environment that's safer and more cost effective.
Speaker 3:  That's metaphor work, giving you VR and tech to work smarter,
Speaker 3:  closer, safer together. Learn more at for work
Speaker 3:  dot Meta dot com.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Let's talk about glasses first because like I said, I am
Speaker 2:  totally fascinated by this whole category. Are smart glasses the
Speaker 2:  future? Are they nothing? I don't know, but I do know this.
Speaker 2:  Nobody is pushing the idea of smart glasses harder than Meta right now.
Speaker 2:  I really think that Meta believes that smart glasses something that looks
Speaker 2:  like a pair of glasses but is just absolutely loaded with technology
Speaker 2:  is the future in a very real way. It's new smart glasses, which it made
Speaker 2:  in partnership with RayBan just went on sale. They start at 299 bucks.
Speaker 2:  They look pretty nice. They are very much not that tech filled
Speaker 2:  future of everything, but Meta says they're vastly better than the last model.
Speaker 2:  The stories for everything from taking phone calls to taking video. The
Speaker 2:  Verges Victoria song has the smart glasses and she's been wearing them all
Speaker 2:  over New York for the last few days. So I called her up to see what life
Speaker 2:  is like as a smart glasses wearer in 2023 v Welcome
Speaker 2:  back. Hello. The listeners should know that what happened when we got
Speaker 2:  on this call to do this was you showed up wearing the smart glasses
Speaker 2:  and immediately took them off, which on the one hand is like you're, you're
Speaker 2:  sitting inside of your house wearing sunglasses, which is bad news, but also
Speaker 2:  like says something about the state of smart glasses that you could only
Speaker 2:  handle being on camera with them on for about eight seconds before it all
Speaker 2:  fell apart.
Speaker 4:  Well a lot of this was because You know it's sunglasses and
Speaker 4:  I'm indoors and my computer screen is not so blinding that
Speaker 4:  I need that and my vision is not good at all. So this is
Speaker 4:  like I'm gonna blame Meta for sending me the sunglasses version instead
Speaker 4:  of the one with clear lenses or transition lenses. That's fair. But it
Speaker 4:  kind of, it does kind of get to the issue of this whole
Speaker 4:  smart glasses, smart sunglasses divide. I
Speaker 4:  just had these on So. I could take a tiny little clip 'cause we're gonna
Speaker 4:  do a social video like day in the life and this is part of my day in the
Speaker 4:  life. So that, that was it. That's all.
Speaker 2:  I love that for you. So let's start with big feelings about smart glasses.
Speaker 2:  So you've had these things for several days now. You've been like running
Speaker 2:  around using them in your real life, trying to like immerse yourself in smart
Speaker 2:  glasses life as much as you can in order to do this review really well.
Speaker 2:  What have you found about like how the world and the idea of smart
Speaker 2:  glasses interact?
Speaker 4:  I feel like we're in a weird middle because You know I've been using smart
Speaker 4:  glasses for years. I've used several iterations of these audio
Speaker 4:  smart glasses before and some of the ones that You know were
Speaker 4:  more full featured, like having a secondary display in your eyes
Speaker 4:  and usually it's just You know they're
Speaker 4:  fine up until you find the friction in your daily life where
Speaker 4:  you're just like, okay, it's just too much work to use these versus
Speaker 4:  my phone versus my normal paragraph of glasses.
Speaker 4:  So I will say that with these that friction,
Speaker 4:  it takes longer to get there. There are reasons why you would wanna put it
Speaker 4:  on your face. Whereas in the past I've always been like, no,
Speaker 4:  why? Why would I reach for the smart one unless I have a very
Speaker 4:  specific instance. But I've used a bunch in my career and
Speaker 4:  I have to say that these are the ones that have thus far kind of
Speaker 4:  fit into my life the best though. There are a lot of a lot
Speaker 4:  of caveats to that. Like a lot of like asterisk, asterisk, asterisk,
Speaker 4:  asterisk. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And Liz, I wanna get to those in a minute. But like the thing that jumps
Speaker 2:  out to me the most, and I got a brief demo of this before the launch
Speaker 2:  where we just kind of got to like try them on on like the roof of a building
Speaker 2:  in New York and play with them for a few minutes. And the thing that jumped
Speaker 2:  out to me the most was just that they look like sunglasses, which is such
Speaker 2:  a stupid obvious thing to say. But like we've been talking about these devices
Speaker 2:  for a long time and like you said, you've, we've tried the Bose ones and
Speaker 2:  Amazon has the echo frames, which it's also sort of pushing in the looks
Speaker 2:  more like glasses realm, but like Meta's working with
Speaker 2:  RayBan here and I'm even looking at the ones sitting on your head right now
Speaker 2:  and like if I didn't look for a long time, which no one is going to,
Speaker 2:  people don't like really spend a lot of time staring at other people's glasses,
Speaker 2:  they just look like glasses. And that strikes me as like very, very
Speaker 2:  important. They're like easily the most stylish smart glasses
Speaker 2:  I've seen. Has that been your experience so far?
Speaker 4:  They're pretty on par I think with like the Bose soprano, which is like the,
Speaker 4:  the nicer looking version. Okay. Of the Bose tempo, the non
Speaker 4:  Deron version,
Speaker 2:  It's a technical term. The non giron version, the
Speaker 4:  The non giron version. Do I look like a giron? Like that's one of the, the
Speaker 4:  main criteria I grade these.
Speaker 2:  It's a good technology test actually for like all wearables like the the
Speaker 2:  Gioni factor like one to 10. I feel like that's a good one.
Speaker 4:  So these are very not Gioni like, but what I will say is most
Speaker 4:  consumer smart glasses, they go for the very boxy Warby
Speaker 4:  Parker Wayfair vibe because that's like, I think
Speaker 4:  that's what they've kind of identified as the most universally
Speaker 4:  flattering, although it's still not flattering for everyone. The most
Speaker 4:  universally flattering form factor that they can go with. And
Speaker 4:  it was a very smart choice for Meta to team up with RayBan
Speaker 4:  or Esther Luxottica, their parent company because You know
Speaker 4:  Raybans, everyone finds them to be like even if you don't like them,
Speaker 4:  they're kind of iconic in terms of fashion. So yeah, these are
Speaker 4:  probably in the top two of best looking
Speaker 4:  audio slash camera sunglasses I've ever
Speaker 4:  worn Low bar since we're all kind of going for the same
Speaker 4:  vibe. But what I will say is you have so many more style options with
Speaker 4:  this than you do with others. So that I think is a huge
Speaker 4:  underrated plus with these glasses because You know
Speaker 4:  we don't talk about it enough in terms of wearables 'cause we're geeky people.
Speaker 4:  We love to talk about the specs and everything like that, but how they look
Speaker 4:  and the design is such an integral and crucial part
Speaker 4:  of smart glasses more so than any other piece of wearable technology because
Speaker 4:  it's on your face. Yeah. And we're a vain creature.
Speaker 4:  We are a vain peoples. Like if I put something on my face, it
Speaker 4:  better look good. I don't wanna look like a duvass. Like I,
Speaker 4:  this is the money maker, right? This is how people see us, this is how people
Speaker 4:  perceive us. No one's gonna wear these things if they're like,
Speaker 4:  I look like the kid from a Christmas story. Or like You know the, the
Speaker 4:  kid who shoots his eye out with the BB gun, right? No one wants to look like
Speaker 4:  that. No one wants to look like a really dorky person. You wanna
Speaker 4:  look good, you wanna look Kingsman Exy in a,
Speaker 4:  in a nice little suit wearing his dapper little smart glasses. That's what
Speaker 4:  you want.
Speaker 2:  Dude, I have spent so many years now telling people that like,
Speaker 2:  forget ready Player one, forget Minority Report, forget her.
Speaker 2:  Kingsman is the future of technology that we should all hope for.
Speaker 2:  Like just look at that movie and that's, that's what I want. I wanna
Speaker 2:  look like that. I want green avatars of people sitting around a table while
Speaker 2:  we have a meeting. Like give me Kingsman or give me nothing I could
Speaker 2:  not agree with you more.
Speaker 4:  There are parts of like actually where I was testing these where I was like,
Speaker 4:  oh shit, I'm exy from the second
Speaker 4:  movie because there is the, oh crap, I got these
Speaker 4:  smart glasses playing music. Okay, I have to take them off now because I
Speaker 4:  touched them accidentally. But Kingsman, he
Speaker 4:  in the second movie, he's at like a dinner and he's just taking pictures
Speaker 4:  and recording things and I really felt like that this time around because
Speaker 4:  that's what I was doing on my commute one day and I felt like such
Speaker 4:  a spy, like an incog. I was like, oh my god, I'm taking pictures. And people
Speaker 4:  don't know, right? It's, it's totally like freaky. And they
Speaker 4:  have these little LEDs that are on the outside that are
Speaker 4:  supposed to signal when you're taking a video and when you're taking a photo
Speaker 4:  And, what I found is that It works indoors. Especially
Speaker 4:  if you are an ethical person and you're like, Hey I have this device and
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna do these things with it, but when I'm outside, boom. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  As to whether you can see it easily and
Speaker 2:  It requires like looking at you while you do it. Which
Speaker 2:  most of the time, again, no one is I I'm glad you brought that up and I
Speaker 2:  like I start with that because like not only do I think the way that it looks
Speaker 2:  is important to the way It works, I think it's the whole thing, right? And
Speaker 2:  I think we've, we've talked about it like, oh you have to have cool technology
Speaker 2:  and they have to look cool. No, no, no. If it doesn't look cool, none of
Speaker 2:  the rest of it matters, right? Like I think that's what we learned from Google
Speaker 2:  Glass. That's what we're learning with the VR headsets. Like if you don't
Speaker 2:  have something that is at least inoffensive that no one is going to
Speaker 2:  look at you when you walk by on the street, like that's the baseline. The
Speaker 2:  better part of it is you get to the like You know I, I feel like
Speaker 2:  where Apple got with like the wired headsets back in the day where they could
Speaker 2:  just do a silhouette and you saw nothing but the white wire and you knew
Speaker 2:  exactly what it was and you've like made something iconic. That's what you
Speaker 2:  want with all of this. But none of it matters. If it doesn't look cool, no
Speaker 2:  one's gonna wear these things, especially on their face if you can't make
Speaker 2:  them fashionable and stylish and make people actually want to wear them
Speaker 2:  even features aside. And the good news is I think belatedly, everyone
Speaker 2:  now knows that because of the way that Google Glass went. So I'm, I'm
Speaker 2:  optimistic about the road all of these are on, but you brought up the camera
Speaker 2:  and I think the two reason these things exist is
Speaker 2:  one for the sort of audio stuff which I think is interesting. Making calls,
Speaker 2:  playing music, that kind of thing. And the camera and Meta obviously made
Speaker 2:  a big deal about the camera. It's where they put in a lot of the engineering
Speaker 2:  work you can do the live streaming, all that stuff. We have not had good
Speaker 2:  luck with face cameras in the past being like good
Speaker 2:  cameras that you actually take videos and photos you want to do things
Speaker 2:  with. How did these turn out? How, how did, how do you feel?
Speaker 4:  Surprisingly good really to the point where you're angry
Speaker 4:  because the original Ray band stories looked like potato
Speaker 4:  vision, anything you took a picture on it kind of looked like
Speaker 4:  a potato, right? Yeah. Like there's just nothing you could do about it. It's
Speaker 4:  fuzzy. It looks like circa 2010 level phone
Speaker 4:  camera. This I think you could get away with saying, oh an
Speaker 4:  iPhone took this photo. Like it's that good.
Speaker 4:  There's caveats again. Like there's a little fisheye
Speaker 4:  distortion going on with everything you take and you really
Speaker 4:  can't think about it until you've worn it. But
Speaker 4:  there's a real p o v factor to all the photos
Speaker 4:  and videos that you take with this. So if you're on a phone, you can see
Speaker 4:  what you're filming. You know when you're off kilter, You know,
Speaker 4:  like to kind of just micro adjust while you're doing things. Yeah. There,
Speaker 4:  that's not necessarily what you're gonna be thinking about when you have
Speaker 4:  glasses 'cause you're not seeing the footage as it's being taken in real
Speaker 4:  time. So there's a lot of photos that I took where I'm
Speaker 4:  like, oh I'm doing the puppy dog tilt where my head is like tilt tilted
Speaker 4:  to a side 'cause I'm looking at something and that was actually a behavior
Speaker 4:  I didn't know I did until I was like re-looking at my footage. I was
Speaker 4:  like, oh I, I tilt my head a lot when I'm looking at things or when I'm
Speaker 4:  trying to suss things out. The other stuff is like I have
Speaker 4:  curtain bangs, which are You know if you don't know fashion curtain
Speaker 4:  bangs are face length framing bangs. I have a lot of ruined
Speaker 4:  photos of my cats because there's just hair like
Speaker 4:  obscuring part of their cute face. So now I have to do this thing where it's
Speaker 4:  like when I put these glasses, the new is to swoosh back my
Speaker 4:  bangs so that they don't ruin any footage. And that's not something
Speaker 4:  I ever thought about before. Or when I'm walking and taking
Speaker 4:  video and I'm talking with someone, like it was very funny watching
Speaker 4:  this footage back because you can just see me look straight every so
Speaker 4:  often while my partner was talking sometimes at like the most crucial
Speaker 4:  interesting parts. Because what I'm doing is trying not to fall flat on my
Speaker 4:  face. I'm trying to see where I'm going. I'm not trying to walk into a tree
Speaker 4:  like Looney tune style. So there's just kind of a real
Speaker 4:  found footage quality to the videos that I've taken thus far.
Speaker 4:  And it's a muscle memory that you have to learn, you have to retrain
Speaker 4:  yourself entirely to film in this context. But
Speaker 4:  it's still like in terms of video quality and photo quality,
Speaker 4:  you could share it very easily and no one would know that
Speaker 4:  it was taken on a potato camera. It's shareable, it's share ready,
Speaker 4:  which is pretty freaky when you think about it.
Speaker 2:  Well yeah, it's, it's interesting to think about taking photos kind of at
Speaker 2:  your eye level, which is essentially where the cameras are, right? They're
Speaker 2:  kind of like just above and outside your eyes, right as you're wearing the
Speaker 2:  glasses, that seems like it would be very natural. It takes a picture of
Speaker 2:  what you're looking at, but you never really think about all the work your
Speaker 2:  brain is doing when you're looking at something that the camera can't then
Speaker 2:  do to do things like solve for head tilt. Like your brain
Speaker 2:  doesn't think the world goes askew every time you tilt
Speaker 2:  your head to look at something, but your camera's sure going to and the thing
Speaker 2:  where you can't look down because it's gonna screw up your shot. Like
Speaker 2:  in a way it seems like we sort of all understand the like
Speaker 2:  language of how to take a phone photo now. And it seems like doing it
Speaker 2:  without any of that guidance or help or sort of dynamic feedback
Speaker 2:  would be much harder. Like if you found yourself taking pictures you thought
Speaker 2:  were gonna be good at the moment that turned out to be bad just because of
Speaker 2:  the like mechanics of how you shot it. Like if you had stood there and taken
Speaker 2:  a picture with an equivalently good phone camera, would it have turned out
Speaker 2:  better than what you got out of your glasses?
Speaker 4:  Absolutely. So many. I would actually say like the majority of my first day
Speaker 4:  or two of just taking photos, a lot of them ended up being like,
Speaker 4:  no good. 'cause I would look at like what came out and be like, oh the quality
Speaker 4:  is really impressive. Especially I was impressed by the low light but like,
Speaker 4:  oh the, the quality is impressive but I can't use this because it looks like
Speaker 4:  one, I really love a Dutch angle, which I don't, which 'cause my
Speaker 4:  head is tilting. But also there's things like movement. I guess
Speaker 4:  the big sell is that when you're on the go and you see something like, oh
Speaker 4:  your cat is doing something really cute and you just wanna like get it real
Speaker 4:  quick, well you actually have to be quite still. You have to stand still
Speaker 4:  and you have to like click it and you can't move while you do it otherwise
Speaker 4:  you're just gonna get, or unless this is what you want, a very blurred
Speaker 4:  motion shot, right? So a lot of the shots that I took on my first
Speaker 4:  walk, I couldn't actually see what I was taking a photo of Well because
Speaker 4:  I was like, oh that's a beautiful shot of the Queensboro bridge and it's
Speaker 4:  blurry, right? Or that's a car that I think my partner would
Speaker 4:  love to know what it is. It's yellow and sporty and I don't know what cars
Speaker 4:  are so, oh well I can't see the logo now because it's a little
Speaker 4:  blurry. Like there was a lot of that going on. So once you're
Speaker 4:  aware of it, you can just kind of adjust and be like, oh, if I'm gonna take
Speaker 4:  a picture, I need to stand still. Click wait for the sound
Speaker 4:  and then move on. So it's a little bit of learning how to
Speaker 4:  work with the device in that respect. But the
Speaker 4:  difference is, is that if you do do that, the result of what you're gonna
Speaker 4:  get is a lot better than what we've seen so far in this
Speaker 4:  category. So it's sort of like a, it's sort of a noticeable
Speaker 4:  step in terms of progression forward. So I was, I was quite
Speaker 4:  like shocked and at the same time like, oh this is how I'm gonna have to
Speaker 4:  adjust to use this properly. Yeah
Speaker 2:  That that kind of makes it make sense why all of Meta's marketing material
Speaker 2:  for this is like put on the glasses, start a video and then sit down and
Speaker 2:  play drums or look down while you use your hands to make something. Like
Speaker 2:  there's a very sort of specific moment for it. Like I'm sitting
Speaker 2:  on the couch and my kid over there does something interesting like that's,
Speaker 2:  that's a moment for it. Whereas I think a lot of the sort of run and gun
Speaker 2:  stuff phones are really good for these might not be, despite the fact that
Speaker 2:  it seems like they would be because they're on your face. It's just a really
Speaker 2:  interesting like tone shift in what these things are actually for
Speaker 2:  versus what it seems like they ought to be for because they're on your face.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, like I will say that you can get some footage that you could
Speaker 4:  never get with your phone. Like You know anyone who's taken a
Speaker 4:  picture of a kid or an animal before knows that they know what a
Speaker 4:  phone is, right? They change their behavior as soon as the phone comes out.
Speaker 4:  This you can like just click a little button and I've got
Speaker 4:  some really cute footage of my kitten just yawning and making
Speaker 4:  biscuits that he would've not done if I had my phone
Speaker 4:  out because he'd be like, oh, phone time for a snack, chomp chomp on the
Speaker 4:  phone camera. But he's not gonna do that because I have my glasses on. Like
Speaker 4:  those are instances where you're like, oh man, this is so cool.
Speaker 4:  And for me, just like this is very, very specific to smartwatch reviewers.
Speaker 4:  Only the next time the video team asked me to take a social video
Speaker 4:  of myself putting on a watch. Hallelujah. Because
Speaker 4:  do You know how hard it is to hold a phone and prop
Speaker 4:  that up and then put on a watch? It's, it's, it's a two
Speaker 4:  handed job, right? So anytime you wanna take like hands free
Speaker 4:  phone footage, it's not every instance, but depending on
Speaker 4:  who you are, there may be a ton of instances where that's really cool.
Speaker 4:  Like maybe you're a musician and you wanna like film yourself playing
Speaker 4:  piano. Like wow, you can do that now instead of having to wear a GoPro on
Speaker 4:  your face that that's what it is. Like instances where you would be like,
Speaker 4:  man, if only I could stick a phone on my head or a GoPro in my head. This
Speaker 4:  does a really good job of replacing that I think.
Speaker 2:  No, I think that that's really interesting. I, I remember, I think it was
Speaker 2:  Anthony Bourdain a bunch of years ago, talked about how much it
Speaker 2:  changed the kind of show he was able to make when he started using iPhones
Speaker 2:  instead of big giant TV cameras. Just like the vibe in
Speaker 2:  the room is different when you have these phones that people are used to
Speaker 2:  being filmed on and kind of understand what they are as opposed to like big
Speaker 2:  ass shoulder mounted cameras. And I feel like there's a world in which
Speaker 2:  the smart glasses kind of go the same way where it's like it just, you're
Speaker 2:  able to feel more intimate and literally get places
Speaker 2:  and shots you couldn't with any other device because there is now nothing
Speaker 2:  between you and the subject.
Speaker 4:  It's very social oriented. It's not like, oh I'm gonna do
Speaker 4:  a YouTube video movie shot on these glasses. It's
Speaker 4:  very like for your social media, there's like things
Speaker 4:  built within the the Meta view app that make it easy to share to
Speaker 4:  Instagram or like WhatsApp, You know all of Meta's
Speaker 4:  services. But it's just very easy to make that transition
Speaker 4:  and like, I don't livestream but I have like tried out the
Speaker 4:  livestream kind of connectivity. It's freaky how fast
Speaker 4:  it, it just recognizes that I've got a pair of these
Speaker 4:  paired, like I just pull up Instagram reels and
Speaker 4:  it can see that it's there and
Speaker 2:  You just like double tap to switch between cameras, right? That's pretty
Speaker 2:  cool.
Speaker 4:  You just, and like I saw that and I was like wow, there's just a type of
Speaker 4:  content creator that's gonna love doing that.
Speaker 4:  That's not me. But also You know it's kind of
Speaker 4:  weird to kind of test that because you're going live in a live stream
Speaker 4:  and then people are just gonna have questions. So that's not a thing I've
Speaker 4:  been able to really explore yet. But just having it there,
Speaker 4:  being able to recognize it without me having to go through a really
Speaker 4:  long setup process that was like, ooh,
Speaker 4:  that's interesting. Where you come up against a wall of
Speaker 4:  like, okay, that's not how people are going to use this is who, who
Speaker 4:  really is using Instagram reels for this type of
Speaker 4:  content. It's TikTok talkers are the ones who are gonna
Speaker 4:  want this type of like livestream capability built within the glasses
Speaker 4:  and it's kind of limited to reels. So that feels
Speaker 4:  like arbitrary ecosystem guarding when you consider, like
Speaker 4:  if you didn't do that, if you worked with TikTok to make it
Speaker 4:  a compatible thing, this would like sell like hotcakes immediately.
Speaker 4:  So
Speaker 2:  I mean, I'm not one tiny bit surprised that Meta is
Speaker 2:  doing that, but it also makes me hope that somebody else comes out and says
Speaker 2:  like we are the content agnostic one. Right? And it's like we, you can,
Speaker 2:  if you could share as easily to like shorts and TikTok and
Speaker 2:  reels and go live on Twitch and YouTube and TikTok and wherever else,
Speaker 2:  that becomes a pretty cool creator tool in a way that there really
Speaker 2:  isn't anything other than phones right now that do that. And I think
Speaker 2:  that could be very cool. But I, I frankly I would've been shocked if Meta
Speaker 2:  had opened this stuff up more than it has. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, absolutely. Like it makes sense. Like people gonna put their
Speaker 4:  ecosystems first always. It's just one of those things where you're like,
Speaker 4:  yeah, but that's not the reality of how content creators work.
Speaker 4:  So that's just one of those things where it's like maybe down the line
Speaker 4:  we'll see that happen. Maybe Beta wants to be the one who
Speaker 4:  makes that particular hardware for everyone to use. So
Speaker 4:  You know, I get it
Speaker 2:  If I know anything it's that someone in the EU is already writing smart
Speaker 2:  glasses interoperability rules. So it's, it's it's gonna happen.
Speaker 2:  What about the, the like headphone replacement piece of this? I think
Speaker 2:  one of the reasons I'm the most excited about these is for audio and
Speaker 2:  calls and microphone stuff. How do these do
Speaker 4:  So I think you sound great when you wear them and you take videos like
Speaker 4:  there is a new microphone in the nose and I thought that was
Speaker 4:  kind of silly at first, but you do really sound a lot more present and
Speaker 4:  clear.
Speaker 2:  It's a really smart place to put a microphone. Actually I had not thought
Speaker 2:  about it until they explained it but like that is such a close place
Speaker 2:  to your mouth and it's such a like they can just plain it straight downwards.
Speaker 2:  Like it's very clever. I was, I had high hopes for it. So, I'm glad It works.
Speaker 4:  I sound so clear in all the videos I took, even if there was wind out, wind
Speaker 4:  outside. That's great. And you, you sound more like the narrator when you
Speaker 4:  do it that way. Hmm. Just because it does record in stereo. So when you put
Speaker 4:  it on and you listen to the videos that you took, you do sound like the
Speaker 4:  main character of your video. Oh
Speaker 5:  Everyone's gonna know I'm recording because I'm gonna be like swooping my
Speaker 5:  bangs to the side is read for audio as what I'm assuming it does and it does
Speaker 5:  it in stereo. Oh wait, when you listen to it you can
Speaker 6:  Like how is the tous silks
Speaker 6:  like still recording? I'm sorry.
Speaker 4:  Like you can tell that you are the narrator and that you are talking and
Speaker 4:  that if you were talking to someone else, they're over there, right? Like
Speaker 4:  you can tell that which I thought was like a very subtle touch.
Speaker 4:  But You know I wore it on the very loud New York subway
Speaker 4:  and on a tram and in various forms of public transit,
Speaker 4:  they're quite loud on these forms of public transit
Speaker 4:  depending on what train line you take. And like on the four five,
Speaker 4:  I could listen and I could drown everybody out. But if you live in New York,
Speaker 4:  You know the four five is a fancy train. It's well maintained. I
Speaker 4:  also took the N R W and it was, it was a
Speaker 4:  lot harder to like listen to my music in that with everything just screeching
Speaker 4:  and being loud. So it, it really depends on the area you're
Speaker 4:  in. Didn didn't have anyone yelling at me like turn
Speaker 4:  down your audio leakage. So on the, on that respect, no one yelled at me.
Speaker 4:  So it can be really hard to hear other people though when you crank
Speaker 4:  it up really loud. But as far as that goes, it's very similar
Speaker 4:  to other smart glasses with audio components. I do think it has
Speaker 4:  good sound quality. Is it the best sound quality for listening to the
Speaker 4:  base heavy tracks of xo? Not really In ear
Speaker 4:  is always gonna be better than that, but it's good enough for my runs. Is
Speaker 4:  it good enough for a race? No, I wouldn't take it in a race. 'cause in the
Speaker 4:  race they blare their own music and that makes for a bad time
Speaker 4:  if you're very music dependent like I am. So that's just kind of how It works
Speaker 4:  there.
Speaker 2:  So hit me with some of the caveats. What sucks about these things? Like are
Speaker 2:  were there specific things that drove you nuts about the way that they work?
Speaker 4:  Battery life, You know battery life. Is it it is what they say it is.
Speaker 4:  It's just You know I have bad eyes. I need
Speaker 4:  a vision like help all the time. I need either glasses or my
Speaker 4:  contacts in terms of these You know if
Speaker 4:  they run out of battery while I'm going about my full day trying to use these
Speaker 4:  as my main driver. That's annoying to charge my main seeking
Speaker 4:  device. You can't really use this as your sole pair of
Speaker 4:  glasses. You are going to need a backup pair because this charges
Speaker 4:  within a case. So you can't even like plug yourself into a wire
Speaker 4:  while you're working and have that work. Now you have to plug it into the,
Speaker 4:  to the eyeglass case. So you, you can't just use this as your sole
Speaker 4:  pair of glasses and if you get it as sunglasses
Speaker 4:  you really have to think about what situations you're going to be using this
Speaker 4:  in. If you wanna be indoors, it's really not gonna work for you. And then
Speaker 4:  if like me, you have really, really terrible vision.
Speaker 4:  There's a limit as to what prescription glass RayBan says they
Speaker 4:  support. It's negative six to plus four. I fall outside of that.
Speaker 4:  That really sucks for me. It means I have to keep wearing contacts with these
Speaker 4:  and that makes life kind of difficult to manage because You know the
Speaker 4:  thing I think we don't really talk about with smart glasses is that glasses
Speaker 4:  are in medical device. People need them to see and you
Speaker 4:  need to see at all times. So when you add
Speaker 4:  a charging battery component to that, you're saying that this
Speaker 4:  can't be your, your main glasses all the time. You need a backup.
Speaker 4:  And that's very expensive in the United States, not in Korea,
Speaker 4:  which is why my family all goes to Korea for glasses. But you're asking
Speaker 4:  people to spend like 400 to 700 just
Speaker 4:  to have two pairs of these at any given point in time. Which You know I
Speaker 4:  don't, I don't love that. I think that's a major barrier.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. This is why transition lenses are the future. I know we were on a few
Speaker 2:  episodes ago and Neli, I talked a lot of crap about transition lenses and
Speaker 2:  the number of people who have told us that actually transition lenses are
Speaker 2:  good. I support you, you are my people and I'm sure my dad was one of
Speaker 2:  them.
Speaker 4:  They are absolutely necessary for smart glasses. I don't think the sunglasses,
Speaker 4:  if you wanna wear them in your daily life, sunglasses are not an option.
Speaker 4:  But if you wanna go outside and not have your eyeballs burn off, if
Speaker 4:  because You know eye health is important and UV rays are damaging,
Speaker 4:  then you can't really have the clear glasses all the time. So you really
Speaker 4:  do need transitions if you want these glasses to be on you at
Speaker 4:  all times and to have a camera at all times.
Speaker 2:  So it seems like we're not all the way there. We haven't sort of fully solved
Speaker 2:  these problems. There's a lot of interesting like software stuff left to
Speaker 2:  do, especially I think in the camera. But it does sound like Meta has
Speaker 2:  probably made the most convincing case yet that like there's something
Speaker 2:  here that the camera can be good, the audio stuff
Speaker 2:  can work. They're working on a bunch of AR stuff that I think is gonna get
Speaker 2:  more interesting over time. But it's like Meta wants the gadget of the future
Speaker 2:  to look a lot like the thing that you're wearing on your head right now,
Speaker 2:  right? Like it's a huge amount of technological work to get there. But I
Speaker 2:  think I'm at least You know 1% more convinced
Speaker 2:  than I was before these that that's plausible.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So what I'm gonna say is I have tested a lot of smart glasses in the
Speaker 4:  past and I've been made fun of consistently and
Speaker 4:  constantly while I wear them. This is the first time where
Speaker 4:  You know I've had people go like, oh hell no, this is a privacy nightmare.
Speaker 4:  Get away from me. But I've had way more people go like, oh my god, that's
Speaker 4:  so cool. I'm buying them. Where do I pre-order? And
Speaker 4:  that I think is huge 'cause I'll be, I'll be real.
Speaker 4:  My husband is the biggest V humble. He keeps
Speaker 4:  me humble. Yeah, because he's always like, that looks stupid. That's dumb.
Speaker 4:  Why would anyone have that?
Speaker 2:  Why do you wear five watches at a time? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I have to argue my thesis. But this is the first like pair of smart
Speaker 4:  glasses that I've ever worn that they've gone, holy crap, I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  order my own pair. They're like, they are waiting to order these and
Speaker 4:  so they can have their prescription and they're like super excited about
Speaker 4:  it. That's so weird to me. One Alex Crans had
Speaker 4:  a field day at the office stealing them from me taking the world's
Speaker 4:  blurt photos just running
Speaker 2:  Around. They're so bad.
Speaker 4:  They're so bad. But she ran around the office with these like a child going,
Speaker 4:  oh my god, I'm gonna buy a pair. These are so cool. And it was
Speaker 4:  just like, oh my god, I've never seen someone that excited
Speaker 4:  about a pair of smart glasses I've ever tested in my life. That's
Speaker 4:  something to me. You know Alex
Speaker 2:  Kranz taking bad pictures is the first sign of any, any good gadget category.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, the oh my god, just so many nostril shots of her on my
Speaker 4:  phone.
Speaker 2:  All, right. V thank you. I want to talk about these more 'cause the, the
Speaker 2:  echo frames are coming out. There's more to do. I think this is like the
Speaker 2:  next phase of these I think is gonna be really interesting. So we're gonna
Speaker 2:  have to, we're gonna have to keep in touch on, on all the smart glasses stuff.
Speaker 4:  Absolutely. We gotta make the Eggsy spy dream a reality. Please,
Speaker 2:  From from your mouth to God's ears. All, right? We gotta take a break, but
Speaker 2:  then we're gonna come back and we're gonna talk about right to repair V.
Speaker 2:  Thank you. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  It's not just sci-fi anymore. Virtual reality for work is here.
Speaker 3:  Mixed reality for work is here and companies everywhere are using them both
Speaker 3:  to transform how they operate. Architects are able to walk through
Speaker 3:  buildings and mixed reality before they're even built. Coworkers from
Speaker 3:  opposite ends of the earth are working shoulder to shoulder in VR spaces
Speaker 3:  and all sorts of workers from pilots to underwater welders are getting trained
Speaker 3:  in a virtual environment that's safer and more cost effective.
Speaker 3:  That's metaphor work, giving you VR and Mr Tech to work
Speaker 3:  smarter, closer, safer together. Learn
Speaker 3:  more at for work dot Meta dot com
Speaker 2:  All. right. We're back before we get to our next segment. Actually one more
Speaker 2:  quick thing on smart glasses. One thing that's not on the Meta
Speaker 2:  Smartt glasses, at least not yet, is augmented reality.
Speaker 2:  When Meta launched these glasses a few weeks ago, mark Zuckerberg said that
Speaker 2:  in a software update next year, the glasses will turn multimodal. That's
Speaker 2:  the word he used. Here's the way he described how it'll work.
Speaker 7:  So the glasses are gonna be able to understand what you're looking at when
Speaker 7:  you ask them questions. So if you wanna know what the building is that you're
Speaker 7:  standing in front of, or if you want to translate a sign that's
Speaker 7:  in front of you to know what it's saying, or if you need help fixing this
Speaker 7:  sad leaky faucet, you can basically just talk to Meta AI and look
Speaker 7:  at it and it'll walk you through it step by step how to do it. So You know
Speaker 7:  I, I think that smart glasses are gonna be an important platform for the
Speaker 7:  future. You know not only because they're the natural way to put
Speaker 7:  holograms in the world. So we can put digital objects You know in our physical
Speaker 7:  space, but also because if you think about it, smart glasses are the ideal
Speaker 7:  form factor for you to let an AI assistant see what you're seeing
Speaker 7:  and hear what you're hearing.
Speaker 2:  The smart glasses obviously don't have a screen, so they'll use your phone
Speaker 2:  as the display for all that stuff. It's basically a companion to your glasses.
Speaker 2:  I actually think that's super clever and a smart way to do AR glasses before
Speaker 2:  it's possible to put all the hardware and software we're gonna need into
Speaker 2:  a decent looking pair of glasses. But the race to watch out for is between
Speaker 2:  that approach and the one taken by a company like X Reil, which used to be
Speaker 2:  called N Reel, you might have heard of it back then, but is now called Xra.
Speaker 2:  For reasons I don't totally understand, doesn't really matter. I've been
Speaker 2:  toying around with X reel's, latest glasses. They're called the air and they're
Speaker 2:  essentially the opposite of the Metas Smartt glasses. They're not smart at
Speaker 2:  all, but they do have a display right now. They're basically a projector
Speaker 2:  on your face. You can plug them into your phone or your game console and
Speaker 2:  see your video on a big virtual screen in front of your eyes. You can
Speaker 2:  plug them into your computer and use them for virtual desktops. They don't
Speaker 2:  do much of anything by themselves. They're just a screen you can put on your
Speaker 2:  face. They're not the most stylish classes. They have displays underneath
Speaker 2:  each lens. So they're big and bulky, but they work pretty well actually.
Speaker 2:  And I've really enjoyed using them for watching shows that I would otherwise
Speaker 2:  stare at on the tiny screen on my phone or even playing games.
Speaker 2:  I plugged mine into my switch and I've been using it that way. It's very
Speaker 2:  cool. So that's really the battle I think. Can someone like X
Speaker 2:  reel add the smarts and the looks faster than Meta can figure out how
Speaker 2:  to get a display into these glasses? I don't know who I'd
Speaker 2:  bet on there. I think probably Meta, but we'll see. And in the
Speaker 2:  meantime, which of those approaches is actually useful to the most
Speaker 2:  people? Is it meta's AI and camera thing or
Speaker 2:  is it having a display on your face? I don't know, but I am absolutely
Speaker 2:  convinced that Meta in particular is ready to see this all the way
Speaker 2:  through. Alex Heath on our team has done some really good reporting on the
Speaker 2:  roadmap. The roadmap is long. Meta is in this for the long haul.
Speaker 2:  It's gonna be super interesting to watch, especially over the next couple
Speaker 2:  of years as everybody tries to figure out what anybody actually wants from
Speaker 2:  these classes. Anyway, sorry. Brief diversion. Let's get
Speaker 2:  to the next segment. Last week, California Governor Gavin Newsom signed into
Speaker 2:  law a bill called the Right to Repair Act, which is pretty much what it sounds
Speaker 2:  like. It makes it official that gadgets should be repairable, but it does
Speaker 2:  so in some important specific ways under the law for any electronic
Speaker 2:  made and sold after July 1st, 2021 and costing more than
Speaker 2:  $50. The manufacturer of that device has to make tools, parts,
Speaker 2:  software and documentation available for people who want to repair those
Speaker 2:  devices. Some of these devices you'll be able to repair yourself, others
Speaker 2:  you'll take to a repair shop. And those repair shops, this is important,
Speaker 2:  will be far more equipped and enabled to actually help you than before.
Speaker 2:  This law is a huge win for the right to repair movement, which has been steadily
Speaker 2:  fighting for laws like this all over the US and around the world. So to
Speaker 2:  help figure out what it means And, what it means for how we buy
Speaker 2:  and use and fix our electronics, I grab two people who know very well.
Speaker 2:  The, Verge of Sean, Hollister and iFixit, C E o, Kyle, Wiens,
Speaker 2:  Sean Hollister. Hello.
Speaker 8:  Hi. That's me.
Speaker 2:  Kyle Wiens, Welcome. back to The Vergecast.
Speaker 9:  Hey, thanks for having me back.
Speaker 2:  So there's a lot of right to repair stuff to talk about, but first
Speaker 2:  let's just kind of catch up on where we are. And it seems like this bill
Speaker 2:  that was just signed into California law is like if you, if you were to pick
Speaker 2:  a moment that you won at right to repair, it feels like this would not be
Speaker 2:  a bad one to choose. Is that, is that fair to say? This
Speaker 9:  Is far and away the most broad sweeping bill that we've had. And, and
Speaker 9:  the, the retroactivity is helpful. The, the broad
Speaker 9:  applicability to a variety of products. California had an
Speaker 9:  existing law that we modified, I don't know most people know this, but California
Speaker 9:  has this law called the Beverly Song Warranty Act. That's the best consumer
Speaker 9:  protection law in the world. Really?
Speaker 8:  The Lemon law, right? Yeah.
Speaker 9:  It's, it's the lemon law and it says that you have to be able to get your
Speaker 9:  product service for seven years, which is longer than even Europe and other
Speaker 9:  places. So the right to repair law kind of modifies and improves that lemon
Speaker 9:  law. When
Speaker 8:  We, when we think about the lemon law, most people think of this as like
Speaker 8:  the thing that protects you from buying a shitty used car though, right?
Speaker 8:  People don't know that it has anything to do with their other electronics.
Speaker 9:  Right? But so like in California, apple will repair products for seven years.
Speaker 9:  They don't do that anywhere else in the world. So if you have a six year
Speaker 9:  old MacBook and you walk into an Apple store in New York City, they won't
Speaker 9:  work on it. But if you go into the Apple Store in LA, they will.
Speaker 2:  That's wild. I I genuinely did not know that Apple
Speaker 9:  Has, they have what they call vintage and obsolete and it's in five and seven
Speaker 9:  years and at five years they cut the world off except California and then
Speaker 9:  at seven years they cut California off. Wow. And I think that goes back to
Speaker 9:  just the broader question, like how long should things last? When we talk
Speaker 9:  about right to repair You know you're buying a new thing or The Verge is
Speaker 9:  recommending a product. Well cool, I'm gonna buy it. How long am I gonna
Speaker 9:  use those new AirPods for?
Speaker 2:  Well that's actually the thing I was gonna ask 'cause you were involved in
Speaker 2:  this bill from the beginning as far as I understand, right? Like you, you,
Speaker 2:  you were an active participant in crafting this legislation. That's one of
Speaker 2:  the things you have to figure out, right? What is a reasonable amount of
Speaker 2:  time to expect a gadget to work?
Speaker 9:  Absolutely.
Speaker 2:  Seven years seems to be the magic number. Why seven years? Well,
Speaker 9:  Seven years is the default that we'd like to do. Now I should mention California's
Speaker 9:  law, the, the right to repair law is 2021 devices and forward,
Speaker 9:  but that 2021 is kinda a one time date. So the right to repair law over time
Speaker 9:  will get better and better. The kind of compromise we negotiated with
Speaker 9:  Apple was 2021, which is I fund 12 and forward.
Speaker 2:  So why seven years though? Is that like why not, why not 10 or five? Like
Speaker 2:  what, what was it about seven years.
Speaker 9:  Seven years was in the, in the Lemon law historically. So that's kind of,
Speaker 9:  and it, it You know, tailored toward You know electronics type products.
Speaker 9:  I don't think seven years is long enough. I think that's a good place to
Speaker 9:  start. But like I have a 2012 MacBook Pro that still works just fine.
Speaker 9:  So we're going in 11 years on that one. I think we should be talking
Speaker 9:  15 plus years, but you gotta start somewhere.
Speaker 8:  So the existing California law was, it requires the
Speaker 8:  manufacturers to keep the parts around. It requires them to maybe repair
Speaker 8:  them for you if you go get to the repair. You still had to pay them for that
Speaker 8:  repair though. And they didn't necessarily, like Apple didn't necessarily
Speaker 8:  have any obligation to send parts to you to that
Speaker 8:  you could repair it yourself. Right? Right.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. That's, that's the big difference. The big change that we're, we're
Speaker 9:  doing with these right to repair bills is it says manufacturers have to make
Speaker 9:  the same parts tools and information available to consumers
Speaker 9:  and independent repair shops that they have in the Apple store.
Speaker 2:  So walk me through that though, because there's a, there's a letter of that
Speaker 2:  law and there's a spirit of that law and I feel like the spirit of that law
Speaker 2:  is pretty straightforward, right? There are a bunch of tools, there are ways
Speaker 2:  to make these things more fixable. I should have the same access that somebody
Speaker 2:  at Apple does. The letter of that law says that Apple can do to Sean what
Speaker 2:  it did do to Sean, which is ship him like 9,000 pounds
Speaker 2:  worth of equipment in a bunch of pelican cases and say, here you go
Speaker 2:  jackass. You figure it out. And that's like, that's better than nothing.
Speaker 2:  There are tools that exist that you can get access to that you can fix stuff,
Speaker 2:  but there's so much gray between the tools
Speaker 2:  exist and you can have them to like, it is easy and doable for a
Speaker 2:  regular human to fix things. Do we just have to be comfortable in that gray
Speaker 2:  space for a while here
Speaker 9:  Well step back and say, what are we trying to achieve? We're trying to have
Speaker 9:  a robust repair marketplace where products get fixed where they last a long
Speaker 9:  time, where you have local repair shops in their neighborhoods that can fix
Speaker 9:  everything that all the gadgets in our lives where You know, maybe we
Speaker 9:  used to have TV repair shops in our neighborhoods. We don't anymore. Maybe
Speaker 9:  those could come back. So it's what we're trying to get at. And then with
Speaker 9:  legislation, you try to approximate You know pointed fixes to try to
Speaker 9:  nudge the world back in that direction. And then the companies can
Speaker 9:  decide if they wanna wholeheartedly embrace that and really work with you
Speaker 9:  to try to address the systemic causes that have resulted in the
Speaker 9:  kind of the repair system breaking down. Or they can engage
Speaker 9:  in You know this sort of compliance with a
Speaker 9:  maximal amount of resistance, which is has been Apple's approach so far.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Rates of repair shenanigans. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  I I call it malicious compliance. Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 8:  Do you think like California has just put every manufacturer on
Speaker 8:  notice for, for all kinds of electronics, not just like laptops and tablets
Speaker 8:  and phones, but like anything over a certain value, right?
Speaker 9:  Anything over 50 bucks. Are
Speaker 8:  You expecting in general an explosion in parts availability for
Speaker 8:  these things? Or do you think there's gonna be explosion in people attempting
Speaker 8:  to sue companies for not making those parts available?
Speaker 9:  That's a good question. I would say You know, we're, we're helping some companies,
Speaker 9:  but I'm kind of shocked at the silence that we're seeing from the middle
Speaker 9:  market from most companies. I mean obviously you've got You know Samsung
Speaker 9:  and Apple and Logitech and some of these companies out in front that,
Speaker 9:  that they're paying attention. But the vast majority, I mean, right, I mean
Speaker 9:  there's, there's thousands of these companies and I haven't, I've only seen
Speaker 9:  a handful of parts program announcements, So, I think, I think companies
Speaker 9:  are behind the eight ball and, and need to get on it. You got told January
Speaker 9:  one,
Speaker 2:  How much of this are you trying to do? Like there's a version of this where
Speaker 2:  you could be sitting here thinking like, I just want a gigantic business
Speaker 2:  opportunity for iFixit. I'm going to corner the market on
Speaker 2:  human usable repair tools. And now that these things are available in more
Speaker 2:  places, like I'm gonna be a billionaire, my sense would be this is probably
Speaker 2:  too big for iFixit to try and monopolize, but like,
Speaker 2:  are you sitting at this, looking at this as a huge business opportunity for
Speaker 2:  you?
Speaker 9:  Well, the debate when we were working at Rachel Perry was like, are we gonna
Speaker 9:  pass laws that put iFixit outta business? Because the idea is the companies
Speaker 9:  need to provide parts, tools, and information on, on their site. Like that's
Speaker 9:  what iFixit does. That's how we've always, right. We we built an alternative
Speaker 9:  ecosystem for Apple products. You can go and get all that from I Fixit now
Speaker 9:  in addition to the i Fixit service manual. You can get Apple and you can
Speaker 9:  get a, a service manual for The, iPhone, So I. Think that's pretty
Speaker 2:  Cool. And just So I understand Apple partnering with I Fixit to sell
Speaker 2:  stuff is not good enough under this law. Is that like Apple has to
Speaker 2:  offer it itself? Is that right? It
Speaker 9:  Would be. It would be. I mean that's how, that's how Samsung and others are
Speaker 9:  complying. I mean they, they have to provide a link to where to go to get
Speaker 9:  it. So if you, if you provide it on iFixit, that would meet the need. Some
Speaker 9:  companies like Samsung is purely going through us. Others like Microsoft
Speaker 9:  is selling parts directly, which is great. I think that's fantastic. That's
Speaker 9:  what we've been asking for all along. So it's really cool to see it starting
Speaker 9:  to happen.
Speaker 8:  Have you gotten an influx of, of people asking you about this? I mean, you've
Speaker 8:  already got Google and Samsung and Valve like very
Speaker 8:  publicly. We've written about it. Other publications have written this is
Speaker 8:  where do you go to get your parts for these devices? Are
Speaker 8:  other manufacturers contacting you and saying Yes, do that for me too?
Speaker 9:  We have some companies that we're working with absolutely. And, and we're
Speaker 9:  we're ready to go to, to help more. But like I said, I I'm surprised we're
Speaker 9:  not hearing from more You know, like pick a random company like, like Bose,
Speaker 9:  right? They, they make a lot of products. They're over ear headphones. They're
Speaker 9:  sold in the every airport. And these batteries were out there after a couple
Speaker 9:  years and bozo no strategy. We're not talking to them. They don't have parts
Speaker 9:  available for the, their quiet comfort headphones. I don't, I mean, they
Speaker 9:  have to do something and, and I would say that's the default for almost all
Speaker 9:  companies. So it's, it's more the exception than the rule that they're talking
Speaker 9:  to us and working with us.
Speaker 2:  I'm curious what you've heard from the companies you've been negotiating
Speaker 2:  with us on this front. 'cause I think about even a company like Apple's probably
Speaker 2:  an easy one to think about, right? Because I think making a MacBook more
Speaker 2:  repairable, pretty straightforward, like not easy, but doable. Like
Speaker 2:  we've, we know what a repairable laptop looks like, one where you can open
Speaker 2:  it up and put in a new battery, right? Like we know what that looks like.
Speaker 2:  Phone less so, but still sort of doable. But like you mentioned
Speaker 2:  AirPods and I'm trying to imagine if I'm Apple, how I
Speaker 2:  literally, how I make that tiny little integrated thing with all the stuff
Speaker 2:  in it in a way that complies with these laws. What have you heard
Speaker 2:  from the folks who are trying to do these, especially like You know,
Speaker 2:  smaller wearable things. Like are folks throwing at you saying we can't do
Speaker 2:  the thing that you're asking us to do?
Speaker 9:  No, it's totally doable. I've, I've talked with, I mean So I for the, the
Speaker 9:  Air Pods. I would point to the Samsung Galaxy Buds, which I think The Verge
Speaker 9:  scored. I basically identically did the AirPods and said the sound quality's
Speaker 9:  just as good. So the the galaxy buds you can pop open and swap out the battery
Speaker 9:  easy and and they're like 25 bucks for a set of new batteries. Form 'em.
Speaker 9:  It's great. We sell 'em, you can get them elsewhere. You just pop 'em open,
Speaker 9:  there's a gasket and that's how they all should be. So no, I don't, I don't
Speaker 9:  really accept that you can't make these things fixable. It's just a matter
Speaker 9:  of effort. When we got the Apple Watch, we, we partnered with
Speaker 9:  a watchmaker, a local watchmaker, and we took it apart with him and, and
Speaker 9:  he was just aghast. He's like, are you kidding me? This is the most shittily
Speaker 9:  designed product I've ever seen. And, and the, the
Speaker 9:  architecture hasn't changed. He's like, let's, let's take apart a Rolex and
Speaker 9:  let's look at how you really do this and, and you can seal these things.
Speaker 9:  You can have gaskets and, and the form factor is, is similar, the sizes are
Speaker 9:  similar. These are very small components, but they can be repairable. So
Speaker 9:  there are shortcuts that we take in mass manufacturing these things. But
Speaker 9:  there are paths. So when we, we do a lot of consulting with manufacturers
Speaker 9:  where we, we You know, give them feedback and we also kind of teach them
Speaker 9:  design for repairability practices. And our point is
Speaker 9:  consistently like we can innovate our way into the future here. We can come
Speaker 9:  up with new innovative technologies that make repairing products at,
Speaker 9:  at scale, at the cost that we need to hit possible.
Speaker 8:  How concerned are you with easily repairable versus
Speaker 8:  You know repairable with a lot of knowledge and the parts
Speaker 8:  available because I just watched an amazing, amazing tear down
Speaker 8:  by I fixit of the Meta Quest three and I watched that tear
Speaker 8:  down and I said, wow, that is a tremendous number of screws, 50 screws to
Speaker 8:  get to the battery. All these layers of circuit boards, ribbon cables,
Speaker 8:  all this stuff. I looked at that video and I was of two minds about it. One,
Speaker 8:  oh my god, there's so many layers. Do there really need to be that many layers,
Speaker 8:  that many screws. But the other side of my mind was every one of those steps
Speaker 8:  seems easy. It's just a lot of them. I could do that
Speaker 8:  myself at home. No problem. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  As long as there's documentation you can do it. We just published our repair
Speaker 9:  manual for the new Pixel fold. It's in depth, it's, it's like
Speaker 9:  126 steps to get to the battery. So I'm not gonna
Speaker 9:  recommend that be the first electronics repair you ever try. It's kind of
Speaker 9:  bordering on the edge of possible. I I I think it is possible we're selling
Speaker 9:  a repair kit for it, but I don't expect very many people to take us up on
Speaker 9:  it. You get that with kind of new technologies where
Speaker 9:  there's a lot of complexity. We've been taking, we've taken apart pretty
Speaker 9:  much every VR headset since the Oculus just 'cause I'm fascinated by the
Speaker 9:  category. Clearly it's some element of the future and, and the mechanical
Speaker 9:  design is really interesting and the sensors, and over time
Speaker 9:  you end up with consolidation, you simplify things down. I mean the, the
Speaker 9:  Apple watch You know system on, on chip is they took all the discreet
Speaker 9:  ics and they just bundle 'em together into one silicon package and there
Speaker 9:  is no more visible complexity for a fixer anymore. So you'll get there with
Speaker 9:  the optics on these, on these VE headsets over time.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think one interesting example of that tension that you're
Speaker 2:  describing Sean is, is I think like you, you look at the new surface
Speaker 2:  stuff from Microsoft versus like the framework 13. Right. And the,
Speaker 2:  the framework stuff, Sean, which I'm, I'm curious to hear your thoughts on
Speaker 2:  because you've spent a lot of time with these things is, I mean it is designed
Speaker 2:  for a regular person to take it apart and put it together, right? Like that
Speaker 2:  is the point. You should be able to unscrew a thing, pull a thing out, put
Speaker 2:  it back in, screw it back in and you're done. Like that is, that is a sort
Speaker 2:  of end state of right to repair that I think is really interesting. The surface
Speaker 2:  stuff is designed sort of deliberately to be harder to do
Speaker 2:  than that. They're trying to find a middle ground between, like you can still
Speaker 2:  get at it, but it's not going to be as simple, which gives us certain
Speaker 2:  affordances that we can have in design and materials and all that stuff.
Speaker 2:  Is it good that we have both of those approaches? Should we all aspire for
Speaker 2:  every gadget to be like the framework where I can just yank a thing out and
Speaker 2:  put another thing back in? Like where do you feel like we should land here?
Speaker 8:  From my perspective, what the companies tend to argue is they tend to
Speaker 8:  argue we get better component density when we don't make
Speaker 8:  things upgradable, modular repairable. And I do think
Speaker 8:  there's, there's, there's definitely a, a gap between something that's simply
Speaker 8:  repairable versus consumer upgradable, like a framework product where
Speaker 8:  everything is its own little module and you can put them in, there's been
Speaker 8:  many, many, many laptops that have had modular parts
Speaker 8:  technically in them, but making them end user, I pull a piece out,
Speaker 8:  I stick another piece in exactly where that went within You know two minutes
Speaker 8:  flat and I have a new G P U. That's definitely something new and different
Speaker 8:  and, and, and framework should be applauded for that. But to your question,
Speaker 8:  to your question like that density is less with
Speaker 8:  a framework than it's with a surface. They cram a little bit more into a
Speaker 8:  tighter space in the surface. And I don't think that
Speaker 8:  is enough justification from my perspective. I want the device that
Speaker 8:  is upgradable year after year and modular and eminently repairable.
Speaker 8:  But I can see why they come at it from that perspective and I can see why
Speaker 8:  they might be angry that the laws say, well do we have to redesign
Speaker 8:  our products and think how we're doing our products differently in order
Speaker 8:  to meet the goals of this law? I'd love to hear what Kyle has to
Speaker 8:  say about that.
Speaker 9:  Well I would note the retro repair laws in the US don't address design at
Speaker 9:  all. So the companies can continue to design products however they, they
Speaker 9:  are, it just says if you have a repair network for your products, you have
Speaker 9:  to make that competitive. So it's really angling on that competition. You
Speaker 9:  can't have a repair monopoly on your product is what the ca California and
Speaker 9:  these other laws are are tackling in Europe. They're more interested in
Speaker 9:  in mandating device design and banning lightning ports,
Speaker 9:  which You know we could argue about that. But they did it. It was effective.
Speaker 9:  Yep, it worked. Here we are, I've got U S B C port on my iPhone.
Speaker 9:  That's cool. And they're gonna do the same thing with removable batteries
Speaker 9:  on smartphones. They're gonna mandate removable batteries. Again, if you're
Speaker 9:  gonna pick a place to draw a line, I think consumables are a pretty good
Speaker 9:  place to draw a line. They're not saying you can upgrade the ram in in your
Speaker 9:  smartphone, they're just saying the smartphone can't stop working when the
Speaker 9:  You know the most fragile chemically wearing component inside it
Speaker 9:  fails. Which seems like a good, good initial line to draw.
Speaker 2:  Was it intentional to not think about design? 'cause I was, I was thinking
Speaker 2:  about Sean as you were talking. The difference between this and the U S B
Speaker 2:  C thing where they are like that is a proactive decision. They're like this
Speaker 2:  is what your thing is going to do. And the EU is pushing on a lot of that.
Speaker 2:  Right? Even some of the stuff they're doing with messaging apps like mandating
Speaker 2:  that they be interoperable like they are telling people what their products
Speaker 2:  will do and how they will work. And so far in the US the right
Speaker 2:  to repair stuff has not done that. Like it just seems like it's, it's
Speaker 2:  truly poking a bear if you start to tell these companies what they have to
Speaker 2:  do. And it's, it's a minor miracle the EU got as far as it did.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, well absolutely. I mean it's interesting that we got so much fight
Speaker 9:  against the right to bear laws as they are. 'cause they're really pretty
Speaker 9:  darn minor. I mean, you saw what Apple had to do to comply. Like it's not,
Speaker 9:  it's not a big tweak, it's just a subtle tweak. Now they, they've fought
Speaker 9:  against us for over 10 years just on a subtle tweak. So we,
Speaker 9:  we decided to focus on, on what was achievable. We talk about
Speaker 9:  in politics, we talk about the Overton window, which is the window of, of
Speaker 9:  what pol politicians can like plausibly do. Politician can't go
Speaker 9:  out and You know do something totally crazy. The society would never put
Speaker 9:  up with
Speaker 2:  Debatable.
Speaker 9:  We elect them and then they do the things that are kind of within the scope
Speaker 9:  of what is reasonable, right? So we picked something that was within the
Speaker 9:  scope of, of something that was pretty reasonable. It was really important
Speaker 9:  to us to have bipartisan legislation. It passed almost
Speaker 9:  unanimously in California and You know overwhelmingly in in
Speaker 9:  New York and Minnesota and other places. So we, we've been focused on, on
Speaker 9:  bipartisan legislation that that can be consensus based, which means that
Speaker 9:  there'll be laws that will stand the test of time. They won't be easy to
Speaker 9:  overturn. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I remember you and I talked a bunch of years ago about kind of the, you you
Speaker 2:  were in the like we haven't yet won one, but we're about to win one
Speaker 2:  phase of the right to repair fight that there had been a bunch of, almost
Speaker 2:  a bunch of near misses and you're like, it is only a matter of time until
Speaker 2:  we tip over this line and and your thought was we really just need
Speaker 2:  one or two. We don't have to get all 50 states and the federal government
Speaker 2:  to pass a right to repair bill. We need a couple of significant ones to make
Speaker 2:  it so hard for companies to make a million different
Speaker 2:  versions of their gadgets that they're all just gonna play ball. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  it's gonna work
Speaker 9:  Absolutely. With the California law, we're, we're up to 20% of the US
Speaker 9:  population has passed the right to repair line. I've
Speaker 8:  Heard for many years. You know as California goes, so goes the nation. But
Speaker 8:  then on on the other side of this call, you're telling me that an Apple
Speaker 8:  laptop is handled differently for repairs in California as it is in
Speaker 8:  New York.
Speaker 9:  Well be because that that is a business practice and that the, they
Speaker 9:  were able to kind of drive, drive a wedge there. I'm hopeful that You
Speaker 9:  know when, when it comes to things like you have to make the repair manual
Speaker 9:  online to sell your product in California, whether are they gonna like G
Speaker 9:  O I P locate people and only make the repair manuals available in
Speaker 9:  California? No, they're doing it nationwide. And and I think you'll, you'll
Speaker 9:  continue to see that
Speaker 2:  And I would assume part of it is like honestly I would not put it out of
Speaker 2:  the realm of possibility that Apple would geo IP fence the
Speaker 2:  accent. Like I really wouldn't. But the good news of it is that
Speaker 2:  stuff now exists in the world for regular like you, you
Speaker 2:  don't have to hack Apple's servers to get that stuff. It just, once it's
Speaker 2:  out there, it's gonna be out there. Right? And as soon as the version of
Speaker 2:  that manual and the existence of those parts is seen by some portion of
Speaker 2:  the broader internet, it becomes too big to hide in a way that I think works
Speaker 2:  for the movement that you're talking about, right?
Speaker 9:  Yeah. I mean getting this information out there, having Samsung say this
Speaker 9:  is how you open the phone. I mean it also by the way, helps guide regulators
Speaker 9:  because when when I go to them and say, Hey, it's hard to open the
Speaker 9:  iPad, they're like, okay, sure Kyle. But then when, when we've got Apple
Speaker 9:  service manuals say, which they haven't posted for the iPad yet by the way.
Speaker 9:  But that to show like, hey, the battery is glued in and this is the process
Speaker 9:  and it's this crazy hard, that makes it much easier for regulators, for
Speaker 9:  academics. One of the big challenges I think in regulation and, and
Speaker 9:  honestly product reviews across electronics is, is who's out there taking
Speaker 9:  these things apart? Like when's the last time you guys took something apart
Speaker 9:  while you were reviewing it? And that's not a criticism, it's just it doesn't
Speaker 9:  happen very often. Yeah, it's expensive. You have to get a lot of products.
Speaker 9:  I mean we spent over $10,000 on iPhone fifteens on launch day just
Speaker 9:  to get enough of them so we could pull 'em apart and give you guys some kind
Speaker 9:  of analysis of like, hey, if you swap the screens, the selfie camera stops
Speaker 9:  working. No one would've known that if we hadn't tested it. I'm,
Speaker 8:  I'm gonna plug here and say I totally did take apart the steam deck and the
Speaker 8:  rug ally for my reviews with those products, but yes, doesn't happen all
Speaker 8:  the time.
Speaker 9:  No, and we super appreciate it and Sean you go more in depth than just about
Speaker 9:  anybody else in the Technosphere, which is really appreciated. We need to
Speaker 9:  see more of that.
Speaker 2:  Sean, can you talk about the steam deck actually because I think in the realm
Speaker 2:  of this sort of next phase of more repairable gadgets, I think Valve with
Speaker 2:  the steam deck is kind of out ahead of a lot of other companies in the way
Speaker 2:  that it's thinking about how this stuff should work. Is that true?
Speaker 8:  Absolutely. I flew to Valves headquarters two years ago in
Speaker 8:  August and I asked them, Hey,
Speaker 8:  are the parts for this going to be replaceable? And like the very first hands
Speaker 8:  on that P had with this thing, this battery in here, it's a small
Speaker 8:  battery. You only get like your two hours of battery life. Maybe
Speaker 8:  this is gonna wear out, it's gonna go lower and lower battery. You're gonna
Speaker 8:  let, let me replace that. Right? And they were like, we have a plan
Speaker 8:  to let you repair this device. We will send you more details when they're
Speaker 8:  ready. Which we
Speaker 2:  Have learned to be dubious of over the years.
Speaker 8:  Yes. The Rug alley, we we're still waiting to find out how you repair that
Speaker 8:  one and then it turned out that you were their partner iFixit was their partner
Speaker 8:  for the Steam deck parts and you could buy I think literally
Speaker 8:  every part of this.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. And it takes a long time to set these programs up. So while, while
Speaker 9:  they were, they were showing you off, like we were hammering out the details
Speaker 9:  of logistics of how we get parts out there. But it's been really important.
Speaker 9:  It's been really successful. It's like it really shows that repair takes
Speaker 9:  an ecosystem. It takes a product that can be repaired, which maybe
Speaker 9:  is the challenge with some of the foldables right now is they're a little
Speaker 9:  hard to fix. But then it also takes the parts and tools and the information
Speaker 9:  you have to have that whole ecosystem come together. Otherwise people You
Speaker 9:  know when it breaks, they sort of do the math in their head and they and
Speaker 9:  they decide to buy a new one.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Kyle, can you explain a little more about how partnership like that
Speaker 2:  comes together? 'cause I suspect whether it's with you or with other repair
Speaker 2:  manufacturers around the country, like a lot of people who make electronics
Speaker 2:  are going to be out there trying to figure out how to strike partnerships
Speaker 2:  like this. So when Valve comes to you and they're like, we wanna work with
Speaker 2:  you on some steam deck stuff, what happens?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, so there's, there's a spectrum that the simplest thing is is they come
Speaker 9:  to us and say, Hey, we wanna fix the thing. We say Cool, set us up with your
Speaker 9:  supply chain. Introduce us to your suppliers. We'll buy from them. We'll
Speaker 9:  write the repair manuals, we'll build the store for you. We just kind of
Speaker 9:  take care of everything, okay? Which is what we've been doing historically,
Speaker 9:  You know, like we we're the largest resource for how to fix Apple products.
Speaker 9:  We have been for 20 years. We don't work with Apple all, but aside from
Speaker 9:  that You know we build the supply chain and we come up with the tools and
Speaker 9:  we build repair kits. So you get a screen and it comes with the tools you
Speaker 9:  need to do that repair. And that's kind of our happy spot is just let us
Speaker 9:  do everything. But some companies already have the information or like we
Speaker 9:  work with teenage engineering, they've got some really cool audio products
Speaker 9:  and they actually, they wanted to write the repair procedures. So they write
Speaker 9:  the repair guides, they put them on iFixit and then they send us the parts
Speaker 9:  and we're just, at that point, we're just an e-commerce company for them.
Speaker 9:  And that's, that's perfectly fine too. So we're pretty flexible. We work
Speaker 9:  with companies however they want. We'll kind of fill in whatever gaps they
Speaker 9:  need, but we're, we're perfectly capable of of doing everything from soup
Speaker 9:  to nuts.
Speaker 8:  How do you properly size the repair supply chain
Speaker 8:  pipeline for, for users who wanna buy parts through iFixit? I mean I
Speaker 8:  know that you haven't always been able to keep all the parts in stock
Speaker 8:  Yeah. That I would possibly want for a steam deck or, or a Pixel or I
Speaker 8:  think last time I checked you had like two iPhone mini screens in stock.
Speaker 8:  If I wanted to replace one of those, like how do you figure that out?
Speaker 9:  It's hard and, and we don't know how many of the
Speaker 9:  gizmos are going to sell, how many are going to break. It's really challenging,
Speaker 9:  right? And so you do the best that you can and then you adapt it over time
Speaker 9:  and the tighter knit the supply chain is the better. Also You know
Speaker 9:  planning out so All, right? We're gonna stop production of this device and
Speaker 9:  we're going to You know make the next version of it. But we have to at that
Speaker 9:  point do what's called a last time buy. You have to buy all the parts that
Speaker 9:  you're gonna need for the next five or 10 years for the device as you're
Speaker 9:  just kinda guessing at that point. So we do the best we can and when we
Speaker 9:  get it wrong, our community lets us know. That's
Speaker 2:  Fair. Yeah. Sean was was lamenting that the steam deck stuff has
Speaker 2:  be, has been sort of intermittently hard to get. Yeah, over time
Speaker 9:  We, I mean we have tools so you sign up on the email list and we'll mail
Speaker 9:  you the moment that that the part comes back in. But yeah, that doesn't,
Speaker 9:  that doesn't help when your thing is broken and I don't have the part.
Speaker 2:  So what's your sense of kind of what happens most
Speaker 2:  immediately here? It feels like long run we might start to
Speaker 2:  see a change in the way gadgets are made and work. Like your
Speaker 2:  AirPods might come from a fundamentally different manufacturing process,
Speaker 2:  but that's gonna take a while because this stuff always takes a while, right?
Speaker 2:  Maybe more immediately like the re rise of the
Speaker 2:  local repair shop, which seems to be very clearly kind of a goal of this.
Speaker 2:  Like what do you look for as sort of the first metric of success that like
Speaker 2:  this is working, this law is having its intended effect here? Well
Speaker 9:  The first and the most easiest thing is to get companies to publish all their
Speaker 9:  service information. So that should happen. New York law goes into effect
Speaker 9:  January one. So at that point, January two you should be looking at companies
Speaker 9:  and if they're not posting their service information, they're outta compliance,
Speaker 9:  right? And that having that just that basic level of insight into how are
Speaker 9:  these things put together then starts to help. Then we hope to layer on on
Speaker 9:  parts availability and then of the pricing and You know kind of consumer
Speaker 9:  awareness follows. Like right now people don't fix televisions. You have
Speaker 9:  a TV that breaks, just get a new one. There's no reason like it's, these
Speaker 9:  things are not glued together like AirPods, they're pretty easy to fix. If
Speaker 9:  you have a power supply go out in a tv, it's crazy to buy a new one. But
Speaker 9:  we have to kind of retrain society that way. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Sean is gonna be like deep in manual deep dive heaven
Speaker 2:  for like the first six months of 2024. It's gonna be, he's like a hundred
Speaker 2:  million pages of of documentation in in Sean's house. It's gonna be amazing.
Speaker 8:  I have to ask you about parts pairings, You know we can't back when I was
Speaker 8:  could report on Apple, I have an ethical conflict now, so don't report on
Speaker 8:  Apple, but back when I did, I received those two suitcases full of
Speaker 8:  Pelican suitcases full of Apple repair tools and I stuck that battery
Speaker 8:  in my iPhone and then it told me that my battery was not genuine. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Until I went through this procedure to make it genuine. And I know that
Speaker 8:  companies like I fix that they're worried that these manufacturers
Speaker 8:  may decide to require that some part be paired with some other part, either
Speaker 8:  digitally requiring some kind of special authentication that might be difficult
Speaker 8:  to get or physically where they will only sell you a module
Speaker 8:  that has all these different things on it. Can you really repair a TV if
Speaker 8:  they say you need to buy the TV main board which has all the
Speaker 8:  components on it for the entire TV and you're basically buying a whole new
Speaker 8:  tv, do we want them to You know have buy an entire
Speaker 8:  compute board for a phone or can you buy the individual
Speaker 8:  pieces?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, so the question here is one around control. Can a manufacturer dictate
Speaker 9:  where and when devices are repaired? And so if you have a chip
Speaker 9:  in the part and a chip in the, in the main board, so let's take the display
Speaker 9:  on the, on The iPhone for example. There's a chip in the, in the display
Speaker 9:  with a serial number at the factory, they marry or they pair
Speaker 9:  the serial number in your display, the serial number on your phone. We took
Speaker 9:  two brand new iPhone, 15 pro max units. We swap the screens between them
Speaker 9:  and you lose a bunch of functionality, you lose true tone, you lose the
Speaker 9:  front facing camera, which seems like an important feature of a phone.
Speaker 9:  You lose a lot of these features and you also You know start to get a lot,
Speaker 9:  a lot of warnings. It's pretty easy to build those kind of locks in.
Speaker 9:  So that's why we're kind of raising the red flag and saying this is a moment
Speaker 9:  in technology where we need to pause, we need to evaluate what road do we
Speaker 9:  wanna go down, do we wanna go down the road where parts are not interchangeable?
Speaker 9:  Right? I mean for for the entire history of the electronics industry so far,
Speaker 9:  you have two PCs, you stop the hard drives between them, you can do that
Speaker 9:  Now we're saying, well you can't even swap screens between two phones. The
Speaker 9:  entire electronics recycling ecosystem. They don't make money off the
Speaker 9:  commodity. They don't make money off the gold and the silver in these things,
Speaker 9:  they make money because 20% of the devices that they get can be fixed and
Speaker 9:  resold and that subsidizes the rest of the recycling. So when you
Speaker 9:  insert this poison pill where you say, well no actually you have two broken
Speaker 9:  phones, you can't combine them and make one that works, that's really gonna
Speaker 9:  sabotage the economics of the electronics recycling and
Speaker 9:  refurbishment industry. So we need to do something about that. None of the
Speaker 9:  right to repair laws that have passed so far address this. The California
Speaker 9:  law had some language in it that would've done that and in, in a compromise
Speaker 9:  to get Apple to support the legislation that was removed. So
Speaker 9:  stay tuned for next year I think. I think I think we're gonna need to do
Speaker 9:  this. We we cannot stop with right. Repair legislation. We need to keep going
Speaker 9:  and, and that's the conversation we're having with all the states about next
Speaker 9:  year's laws.
Speaker 2:  What does keep going look like? I think it, it's very easy to see rights
Speaker 2:  to repair as kind of a binary thing. Either you're allowed to do it or you're
Speaker 2:  not, but what you're presenting is a much sort of longer series of steps.
Speaker 2:  Like what is the step after this?
Speaker 9:  Yeah. So we need to get to a point where repair is practiced
Speaker 9:  regularly on the ground where the TV is not only is fixable,
Speaker 9:  you can get parts, but the people are and the repair sharps start to come
Speaker 9:  back. And so we, we can't really stop working on this. We, we have
Speaker 9:  momentum behind this, but we can't stop until we actually see the, the solutions
Speaker 9:  start having an effect on the material world. Someone very wise once told
Speaker 9:  me the earth doesn't care about anything that we say it only ha
Speaker 9:  caress about when you actually take a shovel and you You know stick it in
Speaker 9:  the ground and you start doing things. So we need to get right to repair
Speaker 9:  from this discussion, this intellectual discussion to like practically something
Speaker 9:  that impacts how long things last. Are there key
Speaker 8:  States that support parts pairing and other important missing
Speaker 8:  elements from the current right to repair laws where you think you've got
Speaker 8:  the momentum to make it happen there?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, so ranger repair bills were introduced in 30 states this year. So I'm
Speaker 9:  anticipating and like Minnesota is still considering it, the hope would be
Speaker 9:  to make substantial progress in many of those. That it's not just just core
Speaker 9:  electronics. We need to solve this for e-bikes, we need to solve this for,
Speaker 9:  for appliances, for power equipment. There's a broad spectrum
Speaker 9:  of other products that that need to be covered. So, I would, I would expect,
Speaker 9:  I mean like Washington is a state where the bill got really close.
Speaker 9:  Microsoft actually endorsed Washington. It's right to repair Bill and then
Speaker 9:  Apple killed it. So I think you're gonna see states where they got really
Speaker 9:  close and Oregon, they were just short one vote. I think there's many states
Speaker 9:  that going to, you're gonna see move quickly at the beginning of next year.
Speaker 9:  The the legislative season. By the way You know, you think about in the tech
Speaker 9:  world we have c e s right after c e s that's when all the legislators get
Speaker 9:  to work and there's like a two, three month kind of frenzy of activity where
Speaker 9:  between February, March, April you're gonna see a lot of action.
Speaker 9:  So
Speaker 2:  You're, you're like, like California celebratory period was very
Speaker 2:  short, very
Speaker 9:  Short. I I mean I can tell you all the, the coalition is very busy,
Speaker 9:  very engaged. There's a, there's an active coalition in each state and you
Speaker 9:  can go if you want check out your state, you can go to oregon.repair.org
Speaker 9:  and get involved. There's wonderful, I mean this really is a grassroots movement
Speaker 9:  where like I couldn't even tell you where it's gonna happen next. Like what's
Speaker 9:  gonna happen in Pennsylvania. I dunno there's a great community there that
Speaker 9:  might might push it forward
Speaker 2:  At the risk of basically asking you to jinx yourself. Does this
Speaker 2:  feel unstoppable at this point? Like have we, have we tipped into
Speaker 2:  this is gonna win, it's just a matter of time.
Speaker 9:  We're we're making very good price. I mean we've moved beyond the, the sky
Speaker 9:  will fall of this passes stage. There was so long, I mean Apple was wandering
Speaker 9:  around Sacramento telling legislators, hey, if people can open their iPhone,
Speaker 9:  they'll puncture the battery and set it on fire. And they told legislators
Speaker 9:  in Nebraska that if, if they passed rates to repair would turn Nebraska into
Speaker 9:  a mecca for hackers. And and I think those sort of like sky wolf fall kind
Speaker 9:  of claims have have clearly been proven wrong.
Speaker 2:  It's the same fight we're having about the app store. If you're allowed to
Speaker 2:  do anything, yeah, you will give all of your money to a stranger and also
Speaker 2:  burn your house down. Right? That's, these are the rules, which
Speaker 9:  By the way, the app store has banned apps that report battery status.
Speaker 9:  So Apple's the only, the the only one that can tell you how many cycles are
Speaker 9:  on your battery.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. So okay, so we're past that phase. Are there, are there other
Speaker 2:  sort of obvious roadblocks you're seeing that you still have to get past?
Speaker 9:  So parts pairing is a large one and then I think you
Speaker 9:  have to look at implementation timeframe. You know going back to 2021, is
Speaker 9:  that far enough back some challenges around internet access? Should
Speaker 9:  you be able to fix things if you don't have access to the internet? You know,
Speaker 9:  if you look at who uses iFixit, we are per capita much
Speaker 9:  more heavily used in rural areas than in, than in urban areas,
Speaker 9:  right? They're farther from access to to retail locations. I You know
Speaker 9:  the farther north in Canada you go the more people rely on on iFixit
Speaker 9:  and So I think making sure that that repair is robust and repeatable
Speaker 9:  and, and that these software diagnostic tools are available to everyone is
Speaker 9:  really important. It, it impacts far more products than you would think.
Speaker 9:  Like you think about like an outboard engine on a boat. Traditionally you've
Speaker 9:  been able to fix that without software. Now it's all software controlled
Speaker 9:  and you talk to fishermen and they're like, yeah, I can't fix my engine anymore
Speaker 9:  five years ago I could but I can't fix the one now 'cause I don't have the
Speaker 9:  software. And and that's increasingly the case across everything of the software
Speaker 9:  and the technology. It's making these products better in some ways, but they're
Speaker 9:  not following up with access to the the diagnostic tooling that we need.
Speaker 8:  Have, have you seen any of this? I mean when we're talking about phones,
Speaker 8:  I mean it's, it's very hard in the United States. There's, there's Apple
Speaker 8:  and there's Samsung is are predominant predominantly the market share of
Speaker 8:  old phones. Most people buy from them. But when it comes to like outboard
Speaker 8:  motor for your boat, do you see any kind of pushback in that realm
Speaker 8:  where consumers, the people buying those things say
Speaker 8:  we're going to buy lower tech products instead of higher tech
Speaker 8:  products so that we have the ability to repair them on their own. Are there
Speaker 8:  manufacturers, You know who are intentionally
Speaker 8:  developing more repairable lower tech devices for those those
Speaker 8:  realms?
Speaker 9:  You can see this in the farm equipment industry. If, if you take a tractor
Speaker 9:  from 1995, it's, its value is continuing to go up. It's not
Speaker 9:  going down. The, the kind of pre-computer age of farm equipment
Speaker 9:  is in is in high demand and, and you can, you can see the economics playing
Speaker 9:  out very clearly now I think it's interesting that you haven't
Speaker 9:  seen manufacturers take advantage of it. So, I haven't seen a manufacturer
Speaker 9:  like Kubota go out there and say, well we're gonna make a lower tech tractor
Speaker 9:  that's easier to work on and beat John Deere at their own game. It seems
Speaker 9:  like everyone is still in the cult of technology, the cult of the new, which
Speaker 9:  is, which is really frustrating because if one of them would break out, I
Speaker 9:  mean you see the success that framework is having, I think there's, there's
Speaker 9:  a real opportunity for, for some of these companies to really differentiate
Speaker 9:  themselves from the the Goliaths.
Speaker 2:  I think that's right and it also people root for framework in a really interesting
Speaker 2:  way. Like there is this sense that companies like framework are on this
Speaker 2:  morally right side of history and I hear people in tech
Speaker 2:  who would never buy a framework laptop and don't even care about laptops
Speaker 2:  who are like, boy I hope that company succeeds because it's like the, they,
Speaker 2:  their sense is everything is better if we prove that that can work.
Speaker 9:  It's proposing a different trajectory than what seemed was inevitable.
Speaker 2:  What is, what is the single part of a gadget that you are like
Speaker 2:  most excited for everybody to make repairable? Like what do you, if if everybody
Speaker 2:  just opens up one thing, is it screens? Is it batteries?
Speaker 9:  It's it's batteries. A hundred percent. It's batteries across everything.
Speaker 9:  Batteries are consumable. Having a a a battery glued into a device is like
Speaker 9:  buying a car with tires that are welded on it's insanity.
Speaker 9:  Go to Home Depot and they're like, hey get the new smoke detector with
Speaker 9:  a 10 year battery that you never have to change. You just throw the smoke
Speaker 9:  detector away after 10 years. The smoke detector has a radioactive isotope
Speaker 9:  at the center of this thing. We don't want to be throwing these away, right?
Speaker 9:  Like why in the world would we want everything in the world to have this,
Speaker 9:  this chemical pouch inside it that wears out after three years?
Speaker 9:  It's absolute insanity. We have to move away from glued in
Speaker 9:  integrated batteries and everything until, I mean if, if we get to a point
Speaker 9:  where we have some magical new battery technology that lasts for 50 years,
Speaker 9:  okay cool, we can glue batteries in at that point but we're, we're not there
Speaker 9:  yet. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I like thinking batteries as a consumable and otherwise very long lasting
Speaker 2:  thing is actually I think a really useful frame for how we talk about technology.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 9:  Let's take your refrigerator that was gonna last for 30 years and make it
Speaker 9:  last for two and see how happy you are. That's, that's the world.
Speaker 9:  It just drives me insane and I've been watching the trend and by the way
Speaker 9:  there are underpinning reasons like there are UL standards that have to change.
Speaker 9:  It's not completely the manufacturer's fault. Where in kind of the system
Speaker 9:  that has accidentally been designed that really pushes us in the direction
Speaker 9:  of proprietary battery packs. Even if you do make an interchangeable battery,
Speaker 9:  like what standard is there for interchangeable lithium pouch
Speaker 9:  cells right there isn't one there? What, what size if I'm like I'm a good
Speaker 9:  cell phone manufacturer, I'm gonna use the standard battery size, what is
Speaker 9:  that? And that's a problem that needs to be addressed at an industry level
Speaker 9:  to then enable manufacturers to innovate around interchangeable interoperable
Speaker 9:  batteries.
Speaker 2:  I like it. All, right? We should let you go Sean Kyle thank you both so much
Speaker 2:  and Kyle You know congratulations on your gigantic victory and your impending
Speaker 2:  billionaire status as the c e O of I fixing.
Speaker 9:  This is a win I think for all consumers, everyone who's beening for this
Speaker 9:  for so long. I mean we owe so much to Reddit and all of the
Speaker 9:  enthusiastic folks who've written and called their their representatives
Speaker 9:  over the years, let's not take off the gas now we're we, we got 'em on the
Speaker 9:  ropes. But we need to keep pushing this until we really
Speaker 9:  solidify and build a solid foundation that the next wave of technology is
Speaker 9:  built on. Love
Speaker 2:  It. Awesome. Thank you both. Appreciate you doing this. Thanks
Speaker 2:  All. right, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna get to The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast. Hotline
Speaker 10:  Support for this episode comes from Canva who just launched Magic Studio,
Speaker 10:  a set of AI powered tools that supports every part of your workflow. With
Speaker 10:  Magic Studio, you can create custom designs from just a text prompt,
Speaker 10:  generate sparkling copy in your brand's voice for any design or document,
Speaker 10:  edit images or create new ones, generate beautiful content,
Speaker 10:  fast track your first draft, automate tasks and design like an expert,
Speaker 10:  all the power of AI all in one place. Explore magic
Speaker 10:  studio at Canva dot com slash magic
Speaker 2:  Welcome back, let's do a question from The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  Hotline as you do every week for this one. Nathan Edwards is here. Hi Nathan.
Speaker 2:  Hello Welcome To. The Vergecast first time. This is very exciting. Thank
Speaker 2:  you
Speaker 11:  Long longtime listener. First time participant.
Speaker 2:  As a reminder before we get into it, the Hotline number is eight six six
Speaker 2:  Verge one one call and ask us all your questions. You can also email Vergecast
Speaker 2:  at The Verge dot com if you'd rather not call. We've gotten really good questions
Speaker 2:  the last several weeks so thank you to everyone who's been calling and emailing.
Speaker 2:  This one. We got a bunch of like charging questions this week. I
Speaker 2:  guess it's like new gadget time so everybody has lots of charging questions
Speaker 2:  but this one was my favorite And the reason we have brought you in Nathan
Speaker 2:  is because this is right up your alley, let's just play the question first.
Speaker 2:  It comes from Kyle.
Speaker 12:  Hi this is Kyle from Nova Scotia, Canada. I was wondering if there have
Speaker 12:  been any updates on the Q two wireless charging standard,
Speaker 12:  the MagSafe sort of looking magnet thing from a while back. You guys
Speaker 12:  wrote about how the new iPhone is kind of supporting it but it didn't appear
Speaker 12:  on the Pixel eight. So that's it for major flagships for now.
Speaker 12:  When we see an Android with Q two, I want my hacky magnet
Speaker 12:  accessories and car chargers. I've been listening for ajs. Love the show.
Speaker 12:  Thanks.
Speaker 2:  Okay, I love this question because it is so confused and so
Speaker 2:  vague about what Chee two is and when it's coming, which is the exact
Speaker 2:  correct response as far as I can tell to what is going on with chee two.
Speaker 2:  So Nathan, just start quickly at the very beginning, catch me up what
Speaker 2:  is Q two and why do we care?
Speaker 11:  Okay, so Q two is the sequel to Qi, which is the wireless charging
Speaker 11:  standard that is in pretty much every phone. Almost everything that charges
Speaker 11:  wirelessly right now except for smart watches is Qi regular
Speaker 11:  chi, no magnets including The, iPhone. The. iPhone also has MagSafe which
Speaker 11:  has a ring of magnets to make sure that the charger and the charging
Speaker 11:  coil aligns with the receiver coil because wireless charging is very finicky
Speaker 11:  if you're off by a couple millimeters, that takes more power. It's less
Speaker 11:  efficient is you're not gonna get a good lock. The
Speaker 2:  Thing the iPhone's always really good at is like you get sort of close and
Speaker 2:  then it just like sort of snaps into position. That's MagSafe. Everything
Speaker 2:  else is Qi. Yes.
Speaker 11:  Okay. MagSafe phones will work with Qi and in fact there's a lot of
Speaker 11:  magnetic Qi accessories that are not MagSafe certified but they've got
Speaker 11:  the Qi charger and they've got the Ring of magnets and they'll stick to
Speaker 11:  the back of mag a MagSafe phone and charge it just fine. Okay, that's Q
Speaker 11:  one. Doesn't include the magnets. Q two is basically generic MagSafe, it's
Speaker 11:  over the counter MagSafe. Okay. Basically it is wireless
Speaker 11:  charger with a ring of magnets around it. Apple contributed a bunch to the
Speaker 11:  new standard. It's run by the Wireless Power Consortium, which
Speaker 11:  is the same group that administers the cheese standard and basically
Speaker 11:  it's got a ring of magnets so it should be incompatible with
Speaker 11:  MagSafe to some degree in the sense that Apple doesn't have to do anything
Speaker 11:  as far as I know, they don't have to do anything to make QE two work hardware
Speaker 11:  wise 'cause the magnets, although they're not exactly the same configuration,
Speaker 11:  apparently they'll work just fine. Okay. So it's something that's already
Speaker 11:  on Apple. It's not officially on the new iPhones because
Speaker 11:  it's not certified yet. This
Speaker 2:  Is weird, right? So like I remember when the, when The iPhone 15 came out
Speaker 2:  a few weeks ago, Q two came up, it was
Speaker 11:  Like yes briefly.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Sort of mentioned in passing and we tried to figure out like is this
Speaker 2:  the first official QE two phone? And the answer is like kind
Speaker 2:  of,
Speaker 11:  It probably will be the first official QE two phone. Okay. So it
Speaker 11:  said the specs said future QE two support and I reached out to the
Speaker 11:  wireless power consortium and I said Hey, what's up with Q two?
Speaker 11:  Like is the standard complete, is it certified? Do we have devices ready
Speaker 11:  to go? 'cause we've had Q two chargers already have been announced. Okay.
Speaker 11:  And they told me at the time, which was like mid-September when the iPhones
Speaker 11:  launched, they said they hadn't certified any Q two devices yet because
Speaker 11:  they were waiting for the test equipment. I see. To be able to certify them,
Speaker 11:  they need to be able to test them and so forth. That stuff wasn't set up
Speaker 11:  yet and I pinged him again earlier this week and he
Speaker 11:  basically told me hold tight.
Speaker 2:  Okay,
Speaker 11:  So I am expecting that there will be QE two chargers and probably
Speaker 11:  QE two enabled on the iPhones this month, next month maybe.
Speaker 11:  Okay. As for the actual question, which is when will there be Android phones
Speaker 11:  with Q two? I don't know. Nobody knows.
Speaker 2:  The assumption would be that next year would be the answer to that, right?
Speaker 2:  There's no good reason not to have it everywhere. Right. This is the new
Speaker 2:  standard. Everyone who's been supporting Q for a while it feels like, is
Speaker 2:  there an obvious reason we wouldn't see a flood of Android phones start to
Speaker 2:  support this over the next year? Or So?
Speaker 11:  I would say development pipelines. Okay. Like I don't know, T two was officially
Speaker 11:  announced, mentioned at the beginning of 2023. If people
Speaker 11:  have had time to put the magnets into the design and manufacturing
Speaker 11:  and stuff, I would say probably spring is the earliest we'd see something.
Speaker 11:  And it also like I, I agree there's no reason not to put it in there because
Speaker 11:  there's a bunch of magnetic chargers out there already.
Speaker 11:  The generic magnetic key chargers you have now that will charge an
Speaker 11:  Android phone actually faster than they'll charge an iPhone. What? Yes,
Speaker 11:  they will. This is why
Speaker 2:  We get questions about charging because charging doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 11:  It it doesn't, it's silly. So if you have an official MagSafe
Speaker 11:  certified charger that's got a little chip in it that tells The
Speaker 11:  iPhone that it's real and The, iPhone will charge at 15 watts.
Speaker 11:  Anything else has just a regular cheat charger and iPhone, iPhone will charge
Speaker 11:  at 7.5 watts and that's an Apple thing because if you take an
Speaker 11:  Android phone and just sort of hold it to the charger or use
Speaker 11:  one of the third party cases that gives you a little ring of magnets in
Speaker 11:  the right spot it it can get 10 or 15, whatever it normally supports with
Speaker 11:  wireless charging, it can support through that. So you'll get companies
Speaker 11:  that'll be like, hey this is a 15 watt MagSafe charger, it's a 15 watt charger
Speaker 11:  and it's MagSafe compatible. But it will certainly not unless it's certified
Speaker 11:  by Apple. It actually won't do that on an iPhone. It's like 15 watts and,
Speaker 11:  and or
Speaker 2:  Right, but not simultaneously.
Speaker 11:  No. But Q two here we come circling back around Q two,
Speaker 11:  the big advantage of Q two is it will offer magnetic wireless charging at
Speaker 11:  15 watts on any phone that supports it without having to
Speaker 11:  pay extra money for the Apple certification. Okay. Including
Speaker 11:  allegedly iPhones.
Speaker 2:  And the reason this is very exciting it seems to me is that if Q two is what
Speaker 2:  it is promised, it solves both of the biggest
Speaker 2:  problems of wireless charging all at once, which is the
Speaker 2:  like finicky, I put it down, a millimeter off and so it didn't charge problem,
Speaker 2:  which is the single most annoying thing about wireless charging and the fact
Speaker 2:  that wireless charging is much slower. So if I'm getting reliable connection
Speaker 2:  to the charger and 15 watts suddenly I
Speaker 2:  personally can go from like mostly not telling people to buy wireless chargers
Speaker 2:  for their phones because they're kind of more annoying than they're worth
Speaker 2:  in a lot of cases to this actually becomes like a
Speaker 2:  tenable system, right?
Speaker 11:  Yes. I will say that 15 watts is still slower than wired charging in most
Speaker 11:  cases and both MagSafe and any other wireless charger,
Speaker 11:  there's You know it'll, it'll charge at the max rate when the phone is really
Speaker 11:  low and it'll drop it down as the phone gets closer to
Speaker 11:  a full charge to save the battery a little bit. I don't know what's going
Speaker 11:  on with The, iPhone 14 pro because it, my battery level is
Speaker 11:  at 88% health after one year. Oof.
Speaker 2:  That's not great.
Speaker 11:  But in general, I don't know what's going on there. But in general they
Speaker 11:  will only charge, they'll only hit the peak wireless charging at like if
Speaker 11:  they're like under 30% or under 50% it'll taper off.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. Okay. So yeah, I think my guess would be, and this is purely
Speaker 2:  conjecture based on nothing that like maybe next summer is
Speaker 2:  about the time we'll start to see real Qi devices. 'cause the, the things
Speaker 2:  somebody told me a while ago, CHI is held fairly true. Yeah, sorry, Qi. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  The things somebody told me that has held pretty true is the pipeline
Speaker 2:  from any announcement to devices is 18 months. So it's
Speaker 2:  like from new standard exists to, it starts to be lots of places
Speaker 2:  including like from reputable companies whose products you will
Speaker 2:  actually buy that won't catch fire and come from Amazon with sketchy names
Speaker 2:  is 18 months. And it's not always that it's sometimes a little longer, sometimes
Speaker 2:  a little shorter, but that's a pretty good like rule of thumb, which would
Speaker 2:  mean if, if Q two was this January, like summer 2024
Speaker 2:  is when we might start to see a real run of like
Speaker 2:  devices from big name manufacturers with some of this stuff. And the hope
Speaker 2:  would be that they've been working for this longer than we know and it could
Speaker 2:  be sooner. But I, I'm not necessarily holding my breath on that stuff.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I would say that probably summer is the soonest I would be curious
Speaker 11:  to know who is gonna make the first move. 'cause if, depending on which
Speaker 11:  manufacturer it is, do you want to be the company that basically put MagSafe
Speaker 11:  in your phones? Like admitting Apple was right about something. That's
Speaker 2:  A really good point.
Speaker 11:  On the other hand, now that it's generic and it's not MagSafe, maybe
Speaker 11:  they're all gonna do it. You're like, yes, this was a great idea, we told
Speaker 11:  you you should have given it to us or something. Yeah, true. I don't know,
Speaker 11:  is it gonna be Samsung, is it gonna be nothing? Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It's an interesting question. I think my guess would be if I'm Samsung ever
Speaker 2:  since the note seven, any anything to do with batteries
Speaker 2:  and charging and craziness, I'm gonna be just a little, little slow on,
Speaker 2:  just gonna take my sweet time on all things batteries and charging. So like
Speaker 2:  maybe, yeah, maybe it's nothing. Maybe it's Google, maybe Apple just
Speaker 2:  in January is like it's Q two now. Don't worry about it. And that's where
Speaker 2:  we are. But yeah, I think, I think it's coming but it's gonna keep being
Speaker 2:  confusing for a while unfortunately.
Speaker 11:  I mean, and the first phones are gonna be Apple are gonna be the iPhones
Speaker 11:  that are already here because they don't have to do anything hardware wise.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. All. right. Well Kyle, I hope that helps Nathan. Thank you.
Speaker 2:  Appreciate it.
Speaker 11:  Glad to be here.
Speaker 2:  All, right? That's it for The Vergecast today and thanks to everybody on
Speaker 2:  the show and thank you for listening. There's a lot more as always from everything
Speaker 2:  we talked about at The Verge dot com, these full review of the smart glasses
Speaker 2:  is coming later this week. We have a bunch of really good right to repair
Speaker 2:  coverage and we'll put some links to all that in the show notes. But also
Speaker 2:  read The Verge dot com. There's tons of news. Netflix is doing weird stuff,
Speaker 2:  YouTube is doing weird stuff. It's just wild times in the tech news world
Speaker 2:  this fall. If you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or gadgets you wanna
Speaker 2:  fix or home improvement ideas for me, you can always email us at Vergecast
Speaker 2:  at The Verge dot com or keep calling the Hotline 8 6 6 Verge one
Speaker 2:  one. We've gotten so many fun ones the last few weeks, I really appreciate
Speaker 2:  it. I think we're gonna have to do a full Hotline episode pretty soon, so
Speaker 2:  keep all your questions coming. This show is produced by Andrew Moreno and
Speaker 2:  Liam James The. Vergecast is Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast
Speaker 2:  network. Eli, Alex and I will be back on Friday to talk about the new Apple
Speaker 2:  pencil, Google's homepage redesign tests, Netflix's gaming
Speaker 2:  plans, and all the rest of this week's news. We'll see you then. Rock and
Speaker 2:  roll.
Speaker 3:  It's not just sci-fi anymore. Virtual reality for work is here.
Speaker 3:  Mixed reality for work is here and companies everywhere are using
Speaker 3:  them both to transform how they operate. Architects are able to
Speaker 3:  walk through buildings and mixed reality before they're even built.
Speaker 3:  Coworkers from opposite ends of the earth are working shoulder to shoulder
Speaker 3:  in VR spaces and all sorts of workers, from pilots to underwater
Speaker 3:  welders are getting trained in a virtual environment that's safer and
Speaker 3:  more cost effective. That's metaphor work, giving you
Speaker 3:  VR and tech to work smarter, closer, safer
Speaker 3:  together. Learn more at for work dot Meta dot com.