# Transcript
ID: ebdb0b61-dd18-49c3-865b-debfdbbff869
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The Cybertruck lives, and so does OpenAI
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-167697093418164831/1256546866988706350/s93290-US-5077s-1701438838.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss the Tesla Cybertruck event, the latest with OpenAI leadership, and what Elon Musk and Bob Iger said at Dealbook Summit 2023.
Getting close — but not too close — to the Tesla Cybertruck
Tesla Cybertruck delivery event: Elon Musk hands over the first trucks to customers
Elon Musk tells advertisers: ‘Go fuck yourself’
Sam Altman is back, so what’s next for OpenAI and ChatGPT?
Interview: Sam Altman on being fired and rehired by OpenAI
ChatGPT is winning the future — but what future is that?
Ikea debuts a trio of affordable smart home sensors
DealBook Summit 2023: Elon Musk, Bob Iger, and more
How to find your 2023 Spotify Wrapped
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (7 ads detected)
Speaker 5:  Hello and Welcome To Vergecast, America's number one source of Cybertruck
Speaker 5:  wiper news. And it's all thanks to readers like you.
Speaker 6:  That's actually true. Now I think like, I think that was, we spoke into existence
Speaker 6:  that we are the world's number one source of Cybertruck news.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. People believe us. The thing is, we still dunno the answer to
Speaker 5:  this question.
Speaker 7:  Not at
Speaker 5:  All. We'll get into it though. I'm your friend Neli. David Pierce is here.
Speaker 6:  Hello?
Speaker 5:  Alex. Cranz is here.
Speaker 7:  I'm your friend who wishes they'd used a crossbow, like checked it with a
Speaker 7:  crossbow. I wanna see how does it with Stan Crossbo fire. Yeah. The
Speaker 7:  Cybertruck.
Speaker 5:  Well, we know the answer now.
Speaker 7:  Do not cross bows. Just all
Speaker 5:  The Oh, oh, I see. Just Yeah. We know a regular bone arrow.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I want like cross bows. Catapults,
Speaker 6:  Alex. one of the reasons that I know that like I like you and we're friends
Speaker 6:  is that no part of me would be surprised if that was a reveal that you're
Speaker 6:  like sick with a cross crossbo. Yeah. Like nothing. I wouldn't
Speaker 6:  blink
Speaker 3:  If you
Speaker 6:  Just like pulled a crossbow out from underneath the table and were like,
Speaker 6:  just like this.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. That's, that's what I do on my, my off time. Yeah. Is practice
Speaker 7:  with my crossbow
Speaker 5:  Axe throwing crossbows. I
Speaker 7:  Am actually really good with it. Axe throwing like the axe throwing knife,
Speaker 7:  throwing terrible axe throwing. It's like I got it
Speaker 5:  All. right. Well, let's explain why we're talking about this.
Speaker 5:  There's quite a lot of news this week, but we are coming to you
Speaker 5:  directly after the Tesla Cybertruck launch event,
Speaker 5:  which was very odd. That itself followed
Speaker 5:  Elon Musk at the Dealbook conference yesterday, which was even
Speaker 5:  weirder. So we are literally live reacting
Speaker 5:  to you post Cybertruck reveal in which we learned nothing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I want to be very clear, it was a 25 minute
Speaker 5:  event. It started 25 minutes late after
Speaker 5:  playing an enormous amount of just ominous
Speaker 5:  ambient music That was strange. Elon comes out,
Speaker 5:  they, they go through the Cybertruck specs. Here's how much it can pull.
Speaker 5:  It can pull more than a Ford F-150 Lightning and a Rivian and an F three
Speaker 5:  50 diesel. Great. Cool. They threw a baseball at it
Speaker 7:  Poorly
Speaker 5:  The first time friends missed.
Speaker 7:  Yes. And then the second time he was just like,
Speaker 5:  He was, it was very weak. Yeah. But the windows didn't shatter this time.
Speaker 5:  They were happy about it.
Speaker 7:  Well, yeah. If you're throwing it that like he threw it like, I throw a ball.
Speaker 7:  I'm terrible at throwing a ball. And he was just like,
Speaker 6:  I sincerely believe that if you threw a baseball at that speed at
Speaker 6:  my car's window, it would not break.
Speaker 5:  That's kind of what I said. I was like, I've seen Honda Civics with Stan
Speaker 5:  more impact than this.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And it was just so funny 'cause it was clearly that moment was
Speaker 6:  it sort of set up to be like a big applause moment. 'cause it was
Speaker 6:  I think feasted four years ago. Yeah. Which is nuts that this was four years
Speaker 6:  ago. The first time this happened, Franz got up there and threw a ball at
Speaker 6:  a supposedly baseball proof window, which is a
Speaker 5:  Thing be clear. He threw a metal ball at a supposedly bulletproof window.
Speaker 6:  Oh, okay. That's a good distinction. Yeah. And it, it
Speaker 6:  shattered
Speaker 5:  And then he did it again and the other window shattered. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Incredible moment in product history.
Speaker 6:  Oh, it was fantastic. It was one of the great like live demos or a disaster
Speaker 6:  moments. I really enjoyed it. But he sets this up as this
Speaker 6:  sort of redemptive moment four years later and like kudos to them for,
Speaker 6:  you know, laughing about this, but then didn't rerun the test.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. He had him lobb a baseball at the window and he
Speaker 6:  missed the first time he hit like the underneath of the window and then
Speaker 6:  Yeah, like Alex was saying, sort of gently lobbed it. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  You can really tell this man did not want to do this thing.
Speaker 6:  No. And it was this, the funniest part was they got to the end and he didn't
Speaker 6:  get any of the like applause breaks or laughs or anything he was hoping for.
Speaker 6:  And he was just like, it's good is my point. It was
Speaker 6:  like All. right.
Speaker 7:  And the bulb bounced on the ground at one point. Very, very like higher than
Speaker 7:  I would expect a baseball to bounce. So I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm now a ball
Speaker 5:  Truthfully. Well, there are now 10 owners of a Cybertruck. We have been told
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  At
Speaker 5:  Least 10. They were not allowed to drive their own Cybertruck away. So the
Speaker 5:  event happens, we, and we can talk about all the specs and, and whatever.
Speaker 5:  And we've got some pricing now for the Cybertruck, which is interesting.
Speaker 5:  But the event ends with Elon one by one
Speaker 5:  shaking a person's hand and putting them in a Cybertruck in the
Speaker 5:  passenger seat and having them driven away.
Speaker 6:  Did you guys recognize anybody? I saw Alexis Hanian was the one person I
Speaker 6:  recognized the, the Reddit co-founder and husband of Serena Williams.
Speaker 6:  I'm sure there were other people in this world that I should have known.
Speaker 6:  Did you guys see any faces you recognize other than
Speaker 5:  No. I, I didn't, I didn't catch Alexis. He took a Cybertruck.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Alexis with like big m like wolverine, mutton chops
Speaker 6:  got into a Cybertruck. It was, it was a cool
Speaker 7:  Look. Do you think they were real or do you think he was like in disguise
Speaker 6:  Sneaky Alexis getting his Cybertruck?
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  What, what I caught was that after the second one, Elon was
Speaker 5:  visibly annoyed that he had to keep shaking people's hands.
Speaker 6:  People wanted hugs.
Speaker 5:  And he said on the camera, well it's a delivery event because I think he
Speaker 5:  knew that people were watching a live stream of just 10 people
Speaker 5:  getting their hand shook and driven away. And he said it like three more
Speaker 5:  times. He's like, well this is what's gonna keep happening. And then he tried
Speaker 5:  to end it early after nine I think. He was like, well, we're
Speaker 5:  done. And someone was like, there's one more. And he had to shake one more
Speaker 5:  hand and these people were getting rushed off stage. I think only one family
Speaker 5:  got like the picture. Yeah, whatever. It doesn't matter. It's,
Speaker 5:  it was an odd event. But
Speaker 6:  Wait, did you notice that nobody could figure out how to get into the car?
Speaker 6:  Yes, this was my favorite part of
Speaker 7:  The whole thing. That was
Speaker 6:  Great. He kept having to tell people. I think almost every single person
Speaker 6:  who got into the car had trouble figuring out how to open the passenger
Speaker 6:  side door to get in. And at first he, he was saying
Speaker 6:  things like, oh, you just press the, and then they would sort of figure it
Speaker 6:  out and then by the end he just sort of reflexively was going, just press
Speaker 6:  the button on the top as they're walking over to the thing and they would
Speaker 6:  press it and get in. And it's just, this just makes me so happy. Like the
Speaker 6:  Tesla has lots of interesting ideas about cars and just
Speaker 6:  exclusively bad ideas about how to get into them. And it
Speaker 6:  just makes me happy that the Cybertruck continues that pace.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. but it was great. It
Speaker 5:  Was great. And hopefully we'll see these actually around, what we did
Speaker 5:  not learn was whether the wiper blade is one blade or two in a line.
Speaker 7:  Shameful.
Speaker 5:  I haven't received so many photos now and I
Speaker 5:  think I've been clear about my theory. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  You've assigned someone to go even I,
Speaker 5:  We sent someone to the Tesla showroom. Mandy Hawkins went with our
Speaker 5:  photographer Amelia kras. I told Andy that I would pay his bail if he got
Speaker 5:  arrested for lifting the wiper up and he chickened out fine.
Speaker 5:  But I've now people have just like reinterpreted what they think I mean by,
Speaker 5:  is it two wipers? One person wrote me an email that said, I I prefer the
Speaker 5:  two wiper design on a regular card. I was like, that's not,
Speaker 7:  Most people do.
Speaker 5:  So does the free market like I don Dunno what, what to tell you.
Speaker 6:  Wait, but le let's, let's just take this back Neli. What is, what
Speaker 6:  is your current belief about the Cybertruck wiper? Because like you said,
Speaker 6:  we've gotten, I would say like the 10 best pictures
Speaker 6:  we've ever gotten of the Cybertruck wiper in the last eight days.
Speaker 6:  Most of them thanks to Verge Cat's listeners. So thank you to everyone who
Speaker 6:  sent those in. What is your current belief about the
Speaker 6:  Cybertruck
Speaker 5:  Wiper? I think it might be one wiper, I think it might be one extremely weird
Speaker 5:  custom wiper blade. I'd not, I don't know for sure.
Speaker 5:  I, I've now seen reporting of other people who have seen the, the truck
Speaker 5:  and they in YouTube videos like Tesla fans confidently saying it's two
Speaker 5:  wipers in a line. And I've asked, do you know, or do you,
Speaker 5:  do you know and got no
Speaker 7:  Response.
Speaker 5:  So I, I don't know. But now that someone owns, I'm sure Alexis has like an
Speaker 5:  NDA about this truck, but I'm definitely gonna write him a note and be
Speaker 5:  like, can you pick up wiper? Because
Speaker 5:  I no one knows. No one knows. And it is the, well someone knows the most
Speaker 5:  enduring mystery about this truck. Like, did Tesla make a very
Speaker 5:  fast triangle? They did. Is it so fast
Speaker 5:  that it can out accelerate a Porsche nine 11 while towing
Speaker 5:  a Porsche nine 11? Yes. That's very cool.
Speaker 5:  Is it bulletproof? Who knows sort of
Speaker 7:  The bottom is
Speaker 5:  The bot. We saw someone firing a, a Tommy gun into the side of it
Speaker 5:  during this event. So if you're a 1920s mobster, like you're, you're good
Speaker 5:  to go. Can it withstand Joe Rogan firing a metal tipped armor
Speaker 5:  piercing arrow at the side? Sure. Can we know that answer? How
Speaker 5:  do the wipers work remains a deep
Speaker 5:  and defining mystery about this vehicle. We've seen photos like
Speaker 5:  overhead, photos of extremely muddy and dirty Teslas just a
Speaker 7:  Huge,
Speaker 5:  And it's, there's just a huge dirty spot. I've seen videos
Speaker 5:  of extremely muddy Teslas parked at hotels where it
Speaker 5:  is obvious the passenger could not see very well and they've reached their
Speaker 5:  hand over the side and wiped off the mud manually.
Speaker 5:  There was an argument in our comments over whether or not the Ford
Speaker 5:  F-150 actually wipes proportionally less of the
Speaker 5:  windshield than the Cybertruck. And I had to be like, look,
Speaker 5:  here's one thing I know for sure. Maybe the Cybertruck
Speaker 5:  proportionally mathematically covers more of the windshield than the
Speaker 5:  F-150. No passenger in my F-150
Speaker 5:  has ever reached over the side and wiped off some more of the
Speaker 5:  windshield.
Speaker 5:  It it, it is just such a bonkers design problem that
Speaker 5:  they've created for themselves and now it's here. So eventually the mystery
Speaker 5:  will expire. Right. Eventually this will all be over and we'll know it's
Speaker 5:  one wiper or two. I just think it's amazing
Speaker 5:  that for weeks now we've
Speaker 5:  propelled a number of tech and car enthusiasts
Speaker 5:  into not knowing because no one knows.
Speaker 7:  I'm really excited.
Speaker 5:  One thing we do know, we do know some pricing. So the base model,
Speaker 5:  which is available in 2025. Oh oof.
Speaker 5:  I'm just gonna point out we, we we're at the launch event
Speaker 7:  In 2023. In
Speaker 5:  2023. Yeah. The base model in 2025
Speaker 5:  is $60,990, $61,000. That's
Speaker 5:  significantly more than we thought. Right? It was supposed to be 49. So it's
Speaker 5:  crept up about $10,000, $11,000.
Speaker 7:  But inflation has like,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, thanks Biden.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, thanks Biden.
Speaker 5:  That's, you know, you know he did it just so he could say inflation Biden
Speaker 5:  made inflation happen. We'll get to that. That's gonna have a 250
Speaker 5:  mile range. 6.5 seconds, zero to 60.
Speaker 5:  The all-wheel drive model, which should deliver next year. It says delivery
Speaker 5:  in 2024. By the way, big difference between available in 2025
Speaker 5:  and delivery in 2024. I would tell you
Speaker 5:  based on what we know of the model three and the cheap model three,
Speaker 5:  just sort of never arriving,
Speaker 7:  Go for the delivery in 2024. Model
Speaker 5:  This, this base model railroad drive. Don't,
Speaker 7:  Don't buy it. Just
Speaker 5:  Buy any other, just be like whatever. I'll buy another truck. And if that
Speaker 5:  thing ever comes out,
Speaker 7:  You, you go, you just keep leasing trucks until the Cybertruck
Speaker 7:  actually comes out and you can buy it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  This one is here to, to anchor the price for it's I Yeah.
Speaker 7:  One of your three year periods, it'll finally be available.
Speaker 5:  There was a meeting at Tesla where they were deciding what copy to put on
Speaker 5:  the website and they put delivery in 2024 for the all-wheel drive
Speaker 5:  and for the cyber beast. And then someone was like, what do we say about
Speaker 5:  the base model? And they all looked at each other and brainstormed
Speaker 5:  words possible in 2025.
Speaker 5:  Apparently in 2025. And they went with available seemingly
Speaker 7:  In
Speaker 5:  2020. We don't. So then the, then the all wheel drive, which I think is the
Speaker 5:  true base model, that's $80,000, 79, 990,
Speaker 5:  delivered in 20 24, 340 miles range. 4.1
Speaker 5:  seconds, zero to 60. You'll note they don't list the top speed on the
Speaker 5:  illusory base model. But this one has 112 mile an hour top speed,
Speaker 5:  600 horsepower, 7,400 pound feet of
Speaker 5:  torque and 11,000 pounds of towing capacity. Just big silly truck numbers.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And then the cyber beast.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, the beast. That was my brother's high school
Speaker 7:  nickname. He got it as a tattoo. He no longer has that tattoo. Wow.
Speaker 7:  We, we call him the
Speaker 5:  Beast. Well now we're gonna call him the cyber beast.
Speaker 7:  I'm
Speaker 5:  Not doing that. This is a hundred thousand dollars 99. Nine 90.
Speaker 5:  Slightly lower range. Three 20 miles much faster. 2.6 seconds.
Speaker 5:  130 mile hour top speed. 845 horsepower,
Speaker 5:  10 beast pound, feet of fork. I'm guessing
Speaker 5:  it's hard to know. I'm guessing that this is the triple motor
Speaker 5:  one. Okay. I'm guessing. I I don't know. There there are no specs. It doesn't
Speaker 5:  quite tell you what. Oh,
Speaker 7:  Do you think it's got one of those like mufflers? The speaker, the, the speakers
Speaker 7:  and the mufflers? Well,
Speaker 5:  Teslas make sounds, you know, they, they can do it. You can make like the
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  But the beast has like a special edition one.
Speaker 5:  It's growling at
Speaker 7:  You. Yeah. The whole time.
Speaker 5:  If I know anything about Tesla, they will make it make growling sounds when
Speaker 5:  it runs. So this is all of the new information that we have is
Speaker 5:  this much specs and this much pricing. And then
Speaker 5:  Elon being like it's good at truck stuff, which they really insisted upon.
Speaker 5:  Right, right. It's good at work stuff. It's good at towing.
Speaker 5:  At one point he was like, as you all know, a tractor
Speaker 5:  pole is the most important metric for a truck.
Speaker 7:  Is it?
Speaker 5:  That's exactly. I was like, is it, is that, is it? And they
Speaker 5:  demonstrated that a Tesla can pull a sled loaded down with weight
Speaker 5:  much farther than other trucks.
Speaker 7:  How is the braking? Like that's what I care about at a tractor pull.
Speaker 7:  I don't do those, but if I'm pulling a trailer, I do care about like
Speaker 5:  If you're pulling a tra an actual trailer.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. You want good brakes. Yeah. You want it to like not have it slam
Speaker 7:  into you and stuff.
Speaker 5:  Well if I know anything about Teslas, we're gonna, we're all gonna learn
Speaker 5:  something about the Cybertruck brakes.
Speaker 5:  Regular Teslas, because they use regenerative braking so much to recapture
Speaker 5:  energy. They often have weird brake issues. That's
Speaker 5:  just a thing.
Speaker 6:  I have two questions about this Cybertruck being for truck stuff thing
Speaker 6:  that I've been thinking about since they started talking about this. And
Speaker 6:  the first is like, why frame it that way?
Speaker 6:  If you're Tesla on the one hand there are a lot of people who do not
Speaker 6:  do truck stuff with their trucks who buy trucks anyway.
Speaker 6:  On the other hand, competing for the truck stuff
Speaker 6:  market is probably more complicated than just being like, look, we built
Speaker 6:  this cool new thing with a big truck bed.
Speaker 6:  It's something completely different. It will do like light truck stuff, but
Speaker 6:  not full truck stuff. But fundamentally, like he kept saying over and over
Speaker 6:  their, their tagline is the future should look like the future. Which is
Speaker 6:  very funny and doesn't mean anything. But he, and he said
Speaker 6:  something to the effect of like, this is gonna change the look of the road.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like why not call this a different thing as opposed to talking to a
Speaker 6:  bunch of people who probably don't want a car that looks like this, don't
Speaker 6:  want an electric car right now and just aren't
Speaker 6:  really the Tesla target market at all. I just don't, I don't get
Speaker 6:  that part of this. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  It's kinda like an El Camino. Like that's, that's like where it's existing
Speaker 7:  in the the truck ecosystem. Right. Is that too
Speaker 7:  mean?
Speaker 5:  It, that's too mean. Okay. I mean's a That's fair. It's a truck. It's as
Speaker 5:  big as an F-150. It an El Camino. It's a very different,
Speaker 5:  I think they should bring back the El Camino if you're listening to this,
Speaker 5:  an ev El Camino I think would be welcome on America's roads. Talk about changing
Speaker 5:  the look of the roads. This I think is different. I think if you already
Speaker 5:  make the best selling car in the country, the model y
Speaker 5:  to move the needle, you've gotta make something else that's really popular.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And the Ford F-150 is the most popular vehicle in
Speaker 5:  America for the last 400 years. Like the first job that
Speaker 5:  chat GBT is gonna take is the writing, the
Speaker 5:  press release that says the Ford F-150 is once again America's bestselling
Speaker 5:  vehicle. Like I've gotten that press release every year that I've
Speaker 5:  been alive. And that's, that's great for Ford. but it is
Speaker 5:  the biggest car market in the country. It's the
Speaker 5:  most ferocious. It is where the prices have steadily gone up. If you wanna
Speaker 5:  sell a hundred thousand dollars car, you're selling a truck. That's fair.
Speaker 5:  That's just the way it's going. You're selling a giant SUV or a pickup truck.
Speaker 7:  Most of the people buying those trucks, like just regular
Speaker 7:  consumers, are they actually buying it to be a truck or are they buying it
Speaker 7:  to be a truck?
Speaker 5:  You are the one from Texas Alex. You tell me.
Speaker 7:  Like I tend to feel it's the other, i I know a lot of people who buy trucks
Speaker 7:  because they need them to haul. My friend called me the day and was like,
Speaker 7:  I'm hauling a mire,
Speaker 5:  I'm hauling a bear.
Speaker 7:  Mayor. Mayor. But Siri thought it was mayor and I was like,
Speaker 7:  is Eric Adams in your car? What's happening?
Speaker 5:  You need an F three 50 to haul Eric Adams. Yeah. He
Speaker 5:  comes with a lot of baggage.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, like I feel like the majority of people I see who just
Speaker 7:  want a truck, want a truck just 'cause it's like, it's cool. It's fun. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  It's, it's neat to drive and sometimes you're like, well I gotta move a bunch
Speaker 7:  of crap and now I can,
Speaker 5:  I mean I I own a pickup truck for these reasons. That's
Speaker 7:  Why my mom has one. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  The most most people need to do is like, they have a pile of dirt in their
Speaker 6:  backyard that they would like to not be in their backyard anymore. And that's
Speaker 6:  like the most truck stuff I think a lot of truck owners get into. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. No, when we in the pandemic, we moved to the country and I had to take
Speaker 5:  my own trash to the dump once a week. And I convinced myself that owning
Speaker 5:  a pickup truck was the only solution to this problem. I mean, and now don
Speaker 5:  don't, now I don't live in the, in the country
Speaker 5:  then I still own a pickup truck and I haven't figured out
Speaker 5:  why, but I know that we're not getting rid of it.
Speaker 7:  Do you need to do some sod work or something in No, we
Speaker 5:  Don't have, we, no. We live in a very urban area.
Speaker 5:  This
Speaker 7:  Furniture refinishing fully
Speaker 5:  Incompatible with the area I live in now and yet, and yet we still
Speaker 5:  have it. That said, look, a lot of people like pickup trucks and you can
Speaker 5:  have a lot of feelings about that. Are they appropriate cars for most places?
Speaker 5:  No.
Speaker 7:  Depends. Right.
Speaker 5:  Do cars need to be this big? At one point in this Cybertruck event, Elon
Speaker 5:  said if you get into a fight with another car, you will win. And he showed
Speaker 5:  a car crashing into a tough truck.
Speaker 7:  Isn't that
Speaker 5:  Bad? And our transportation reporter, Andy Hawkins, who has been on a tear
Speaker 5:  pointing out that cars are too big, they're too dangerous, they're dangerous
Speaker 5:  to other pedestrians, especially when they start going this fast. They're
Speaker 5:  incredibly dangerous to other cars. That's not a good thing.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Like we used to have a Thunderbird 66 Thunderbird when I was a kid
Speaker 7:  and stuff and it was really cool. And if you got in an accident you were
Speaker 7:  totally fine. And now, but like the knowledge was if you got in an accident
Speaker 7:  with a modern car, you would annihilate it and that's actually horrible.
Speaker 7:  And then you'd also get batted around inside the car. Yeah. And just pinging
Speaker 7:  pong. And I'm like, there was not a lot of safety discussion at
Speaker 7:  this event. And that was a little concerning for me, given that they have
Speaker 7:  a giant stainless steel box they're putting on the road. Yeah. Like
Speaker 7:  what, what, what are crumple zones like on this thing? Because everybody
Speaker 7:  else is like crumple zones. They should do that. And this guy's like, you
Speaker 7:  know what, small arms fire
Speaker 6:  In a Cybertruck, you crumble everything
Speaker 5:  They did, they did show some crash testing. We will see. Who knows, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's a million Who knows questions. But but
Speaker 5:  back to David's point, which is why market this thing
Speaker 5:  as a truck? People love them. I it's because it's the last market,
Speaker 5:  the last big section in the market to go get. I think they
Speaker 5:  could have picked one or two others. Right. Luxury SUVs
Speaker 5:  that are not the Model X, which is a little long in the tooth.
Speaker 5:  That's a big market that's growing. Who knows if you can build an
Speaker 5:  ev in that form factor. But this, I think they wanted to build this 'cause
Speaker 5:  it is the statement piece. It is the big bold design.
Speaker 5:  They're not counting on it winning, which I think they've now set on some
Speaker 5:  earnings calls. Like the model Y is the volume Tesla, it's gonna
Speaker 5:  keep doing what it's doing even as pri they, they're slashing prices left
Speaker 5:  and right. This is the one that's gonna be the the halo car.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There's a way to look at this that it's like the successor to the
Speaker 6:  Roadster in a pretty real way. That, that this is like
Speaker 6:  the car hardly anybody has but reliably turns
Speaker 6:  heads when you see it on the street. And in that sense, I sort of buy it,
Speaker 6:  but I, I just keep going back, back to this idea of like, if you are a person
Speaker 6:  who like uses the hell out of your truck, what
Speaker 6:  on earth would compel you to buy a Cybertruck at this moment in time? I just
Speaker 6:  don't know that there are good answers.
Speaker 5:  This is where we have to talk about Elon and Dealbook.
Speaker 6:  We,
Speaker 5:  We should not dwell on
Speaker 6:  Yeah, okay. No, we should,
Speaker 5:  You're right. And know David like does not wanna talk about this.
Speaker 6:  I don't, I super don't. But we should.
Speaker 5:  But you can't actually right now, divorce Tesla the car company
Speaker 5:  from Elon Musk the man, which is a real problem.
Speaker 5:  So in some academic argument about market share and
Speaker 5:  products, you're like, why would you make this product? Why would you market
Speaker 5:  it this way? And you can like come to an answer. And part of the answer right
Speaker 5:  now is why would you buy a car from Elon Musk? Like there's some enormous
Speaker 5:  segment of the population that is just over his antics,
Speaker 5:  over his weird racist and anti-Semitic tweets just over
Speaker 5:  him. Right. And what we saw.
Speaker 6:  But to be fair, there's also a chunk of people on the opposite, the exact
Speaker 6:  opposite end of that spectrum, right. Who will, who will follow him to the
Speaker 6:  ends of the earth and buy anything he tells them to buy?
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like he could have a podcast selling them supplements and they would buy
Speaker 6:  the supplements. I think that group is substantially smaller than it was
Speaker 6:  24 months ago.
Speaker 5:  I also don't think they have a hundred thousand dollars to spend on the Cybertruck
Speaker 5:  that I just wanna be very clear, right. Because the, the people you
Speaker 5:  need to spend the money are often very educated.
Speaker 5:  And this is like a real problem for Elon. Like he lives in a
Speaker 5:  Twitter bubble and he thinks the Twitter bubble is real
Speaker 5:  and he thinks the thing that gets him engagement on Twitter will get him
Speaker 5:  engagement in real life. And then he goes to conferences. Like we
Speaker 5:  saw him this week, the Dealbook conference with Andrew Ross Sorkin. And he
Speaker 5:  delivers what he, what are like bangers on Twitter?
Speaker 5:  It, it's dead silence.
Speaker 7:  It was just like Twitter come to life. And then
Speaker 7:  the the silence afterwards was so aw. Like every time he'd do a punchline
Speaker 7:  and he'd ape to the camera and be like, eh, and it's just like crickets.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Our, our transportation reporter Omar pointed out that he would often
Speaker 5:  deliver the punchlines twice. And the second time he got the pity laugh,
Speaker 5:  which is a, if you go watch it again, it's a, it's a very brutal, real dynamic.
Speaker 5:  I mean that that joke, that Twitter, that thing that Twitter
Speaker 5:  isn't real life. His, his appearance at Dealbook
Speaker 5:  was just, oh, Twitter's not real life like fully encapsulated
Speaker 5:  in that event. And so we should talk about what he said. There's a few things
Speaker 5:  that are just worth pulling apart. The first and most important
Speaker 5:  is that advertisers are leaving Twitter. After yet
Speaker 5:  more of Musk's antics and weird anti-Semitism and
Speaker 5:  Media Matters had a report about ads showing
Speaker 5:  up next to bad content. The advertisers started leaving because that's what
Speaker 5:  advertisers do. Whenever there are brand safety concerns on any platforms.
Speaker 5:  I would just offer you the example of something called
Speaker 5:  the Apocalypse on YouTube, which was exactly this thing.
Speaker 5:  And Susan Waki, who was the CEO of YouTube at the time, did not
Speaker 5:  tell a bunch of advertisers to go fuck themselves. They like actively tried
Speaker 5:  to fix it. Elon's response was to look at the DealBook
Speaker 5:  audience and say, if you think you can blackmail me with money
Speaker 5:  Go fuck yourself. And he was like, Bob, if you're here meaning Bob, Iger
Speaker 5:  Go, fuck yourself. I, I don't know. Like again,
Speaker 5:  that's, it's not, I don't sell the ads for us. It's not my side of the house.
Speaker 5:  I'm fairly confident at the people who sold our ads announced at a
Speaker 5:  conference, their clients could go fuck themselves. Like I
Speaker 5:  don't think the advertisers are coming back. And then he follows up with
Speaker 5:  this advertising boycott will kill the company and the world will
Speaker 5:  know it. We will document it. And I think Andrew followed
Speaker 5:  up by asking, isn't that a bad thing? And he is like, earth will
Speaker 5:  know. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  He, he was earth, he really thinks that everyone is gonna come out and
Speaker 7:  save X. He was very, he that was one thing he was very clear on. He
Speaker 7:  constantly corrected Andrew on calling it X versus Twitter.
Speaker 7:  And he really thinks that like the uproar will save X And it's like, no,
Speaker 7:  but the uproar caused this to happen. Yeah. Everybody's leaving
Speaker 7:  because there was an uproar. 'cause everybody's mad at you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean we, we have talked about in the show, there was a time when
Speaker 5:  Twitter was a particular kind of monopoly and no matter what
Speaker 5:  the company did and that I will issue our disclaimer again, criticism
Speaker 5:  of Elon Musk as CEO of Twitter is no way praise for the previous
Speaker 5:  administration of Twitter who did a horrible job running this company.
Speaker 5:  But they had a kind of monopoly where no matter how
Speaker 5:  badly they screwed up, everyone kept coming back to Twitter.
Speaker 5:  And I'm pretty sure Elon thought that he was buying that monopoly. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Because if I was addicted to cigarettes, I'm not saying I ever was and I
Speaker 5:  bought a cigarette company, I'd be like, this rules, everyone's addicted
Speaker 5:  to my product just as much as I am. And then everyone was like, now you
Speaker 5:  are an asshole. And we vape now. And that is more or less what has happened
Speaker 5:  to Elon Musk.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. And I think, I mean, it it's wild how
Speaker 6:  even a year ago that seemed like a
Speaker 6:  reasonable bet, right? I think there was a time when it looked like
Speaker 6:  for all of the chaos and for all of the bad stuff, everybody was just
Speaker 6:  gonna kind of hold their nose and keep using Twitter because to some extent
Speaker 6:  there was nowhere to go. And to a potentially larger extent, the
Speaker 6:  chaos and the fun are so close to each other on Twitter that
Speaker 6:  you, you can ramp up one and kind of
Speaker 6:  accidentally ramp up the, like the, the mess is the point. And
Speaker 6:  I think I, like 12 months ago, I'm sure on this show
Speaker 6:  we were having this same debate. And to me at this point, I think it feels
Speaker 6:  like a foregone conclusion that at some point or another, X is gonna go
Speaker 6:  away in a pretty real way. I don't know if the company's gonna die just 'cause
Speaker 6:  he has so much money he could float the thing forever if he felt like it.
Speaker 6:  But also to he's got
Speaker 5:  Investors he has to pay off. Like there's a lot going on there.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But I also get the increasing sense that he is
Speaker 6:  trying to set it up in such a way that if X goes away,
Speaker 6:  goes outta business, declares bankruptcy, whatever it turns out to be,
Speaker 6:  he wants to be a martyr and he, he wants to have, that
Speaker 6:  will be his like full proof positive that the world
Speaker 6:  is against him and has gone woken. Everything is a disaster. And now he kind
Speaker 6:  of wins coming and going. Right. It's either like a business victory or a
Speaker 6:  moral victory or it's kind of a moral victory on either side. No matter what
Speaker 6:  happens. He's trying to set up this thing that I find very strange.
Speaker 7:  I mean, it's, it's not that strange 'cause it's a, it's a pretty common playbook
Speaker 7:  now. Like that this was the exact same playbook Trump has and, and
Speaker 7:  continues to have. And I, I think it's just a really, it's, it's difficult
Speaker 7:  to counter. And I think that's why it's a really like useful and
Speaker 7:  deeply irritating.
Speaker 5:  Let me make the distinction for you a comparison and a distinction. Okay.
Speaker 5:  You're right. It's the same playbook. Yeah. I the very different dudes, the
Speaker 5:  election was lost. Everyone is corrupt. It was stolen from me. The bad forces
Speaker 5:  came and took this away from me. That's voting with your votes. Yep.
Speaker 5:  Very few people get to make that argument when it's voting with your dollars.
Speaker 5:  That's true. And so Elon is not making the argument that these woke
Speaker 5:  corporations are no longer buying advertising to, to spite him. And
Speaker 5:  it is very hard to tell anyone, particularly
Speaker 5:  Americans, that they have an obligation to spend money.
Speaker 5:  It is just not a thing you can do in this country culturally. Just not a
Speaker 5:  thing you can do to say you have to spend money advertising dollars on
Speaker 5:  this platform because it's important that this thing exists. And
Speaker 5:  most people are like, what? You can't tell me how to spend my money. Well
Speaker 7:  That was like the immediate reaction on social media. On, on and in our own
Speaker 7:  like comments and stuff. Everybody's just like, no, it's
Speaker 7:  my money.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. No, it's, it's very like, we talk a lot about free speech on the
Speaker 5:  show and like when it's anything but money, like everyone immediately
Speaker 5:  sees the gray areas. There's like nuance when it's like you have to spend
Speaker 5:  money. People are like, no, I don't. No, no sir. No, thank you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Go fuck yourself. And it's like you just,
Speaker 5:  you just watching him run into this, right? Yeah. Like he had this argument
Speaker 5:  about Tesla's at, at the double conference as well, where he was like, I
Speaker 5:  think Andrew asked him, are you worried that your tweets and your antics
Speaker 5:  are gonna hurt the company? He said, no, we make the best car. If you want
Speaker 5:  the best car, you have to buy a Tesla. Which is debatable, but it
Speaker 5:  is a market driven argument. Right? Right.
Speaker 5:  We're we're putting our product in the market and if people are gonna look
Speaker 5:  at an evaluation and maybe they'll evaluate me, but really they're gonna
Speaker 5:  want the best car and they're gonna pick my car, we make the bestselling
Speaker 5:  car. Okay. You're competing in the market. You, you've, you're weighing all
Speaker 5:  the variables with Twitter. It's like, if you don't advertise here,
Speaker 5:  you're destroying America. And it's like, that's just not, that's not
Speaker 5:  how that works. That's just a weird argument man. And to say like,
Speaker 5:  my product is objectively worse or my product is not what the market
Speaker 5:  demands for me or what the market says it wants and not buying it anyway
Speaker 5:  is the problem. I don't know man. Like, it's just odd and
Speaker 5:  like what's gonna happen right next to it is threads is gonna light up advertising.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna go into a holiday season where TikTok and Amazon and Google
Speaker 5:  and Meta are all in Q4. They all have salespeople with
Speaker 5:  real relationships. They all have content moderation teams. And they're gonna
Speaker 5:  say, every dollar you were spending on Twitter, you should spend that dollar
Speaker 5:  here and we'll treat you nicely. We wont tell
Speaker 6:  You to fuck off.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And like, we'll, we'll send you some swag. Whatever salespeople do
Speaker 5:  I don know I don know this works.
Speaker 6:  It's swag. I just spend money. It's just t-shirts from company to company
Speaker 5:  Floating around. Yeah. And poor Linda Yao, like her job is to run
Speaker 5:  this playbook and she can't because her boss has just told all these
Speaker 5:  people to, to f off I that will kill the company.
Speaker 5:  And this attempt to run the martyr playbook, it
Speaker 5:  will fail because you just cannot be a martyr because people
Speaker 5:  didn't buy your shit. You, you can't be a like a
Speaker 5:  musician and be like, people didn't buy my album. The world is corrupt. Like
Speaker 5:  no, I mean a lot
Speaker 6:  Of musicians, I totally disagree with that. Well
Speaker 5:  Sure. but it never hits. It never hits, but it's
Speaker 6:  Never works. Literally. I like, this is gonna sound like I'm joking, but
Speaker 6:  I'm not. It's because no one else is trying hard enough. Like the thing
Speaker 6:  Elon Musk is doing is, is making it his life's mission
Speaker 6:  to tell everyone how X is the last
Speaker 6:  bastion of free speech. Anything against X is against free
Speaker 6:  speech. Like Lindy Yao's tweet said, like, what was it? X
Speaker 6:  is standing at a unique and amazing intersection of free speech and Main
Speaker 6:  Street. Which like what on earth does that mean? Yeah. But there no
Speaker 5:  Idea what that means, by
Speaker 6:  The way. It's pure nonsense. But we're now in this position where like he,
Speaker 6:  I I,
Speaker 5:  By the way, can I just point out speech notably free on Main Street,
Speaker 5:  you can find the main street in your town and stand on that corner and
Speaker 5:  do whatever you want.
Speaker 5:  Like that's the whole point. That's the whole idea. Yeah. Like you can
Speaker 5:  yell, cops arrest me and the cops would be like, no,
Speaker 7:  Depends on how many clothes you're wearing.
Speaker 5:  That's true. I'll be like, one nipple's fine,
Speaker 6:  But he's gonna be able to do this whole thing and get to the end of this
Speaker 6:  process and say, by by killing X you have killed free speech
Speaker 6:  in America. And there it's a ridiculous argument. But he has said
Speaker 6:  it so many times that at this point some people are going to believe him
Speaker 6:  and sure. It's just gonna be ridiculous. Like, like
Speaker 6:  Donald Trump says it about truth social that it is and, and nobody believes
Speaker 6:  him. Like part of it is, is Elon took this thing that was so much
Speaker 6:  bigger and destroyed it so much faster than, in a funny way, it's gonna make
Speaker 6:  his argument more credible as he does this. Like
Speaker 6:  he, he's gonna be able to track those two things against each other in a
Speaker 6:  way that is absolutely unrelated to the truth of the world,
Speaker 6:  but it's, it's gonna work for him. For some people. You, you,
Speaker 7:  You've also got Twitter brain saying that like I I I think like maybe,
Speaker 7:  maybe spicy people on Twitter, like his fans on Twitter
Speaker 7:  will probably believe that. I don't think anybody else out in the the general
Speaker 7:  world is gonna be like, man, can you believe what happened? He was right.
Speaker 7:  There's something to it. Yeah. Like some stuff he says,
Speaker 7:  sure
Speaker 6:  Don don't think you can make the Donald Trump comparison you made a few minutes
Speaker 6:  ago and then make that argument.
Speaker 7:  I mean, they're both, look, they're both, they both have very passionate
Speaker 7:  groups of followers and those, those passionate followers are gonna follow
Speaker 7:  them regardless of what they say. And, and they're both really, really good
Speaker 7:  at that. And then they use that, that that very vocal small group of followers
Speaker 7:  as as as as cudgels, right? Like to as and as barriers
Speaker 7:  to to all other discourse and all other like actual
Speaker 7:  reality. That's what he's really good at. That's, that's what Trump's really
Speaker 7:  good at. And it's interesting to watch it first play out in politics and
Speaker 7:  now in in tech. Yeah. It's a kind of a bummer, but
Speaker 7:  it's also interesting.
Speaker 5:  It is definitely a bummer. I think the world might be better off that Twitter
Speaker 5:  is on the decline as we go into an election year. Mm. Just putting that out
Speaker 5:  there. Yeah. I'm not saying that the ends justify the means. Yeah. I think
Speaker 5:  the means have been very destructive. Lots of people have lost their jobs.
Speaker 5:  Like all of it's been bad racism and antisemitism
Speaker 5:  skyrocketing on platform. The, i, in no way am I saying that the
Speaker 5:  means have been appropriate or effective. I just think this argument
Speaker 5:  that he represents free speech while he's suing media matters for
Speaker 5:  criticizing him. Like this is the stuff that just begins to fall on deaf
Speaker 5:  ears. Yeah. Like over and over and over again. And I, I think
Speaker 5:  that when we talk about Tesla, like he has to sell
Speaker 5:  more cars and his antics with Twitter are
Speaker 5:  actively making people not want to give him money. Whether that's
Speaker 5:  advertisers, whether it's car customers, whatever it is. The last monopoly
Speaker 5:  he has is actually SpaceX. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And it's a
Speaker 5:  Really good one. It's a really good one. Like there's no, the United Launch
Speaker 5:  Alliance is nowhere close to shipping a Ford F-150 lightning like
Speaker 5:  the, you know, where there's like any other choice. There's no pole star
Speaker 5:  in the rocket business. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I don Dunno. Bezos is out here kind of doing stuff. Blue Origin is like
Speaker 5:  Lingering. Bezos can't put a payload into space. He can put like four
Speaker 5:  rich people into space.
Speaker 7:  But like Subspace, it's not even literal payload full space.
Speaker 5:  He is like my girlfriend's in the sky. Like that's what he can do.
Speaker 5:  Like, like maybe he will get there. It's a long way away before
Speaker 5:  SpaceX has real competition. Yeah. And that's like, you can think about that
Speaker 5:  any way you want, but Tesla has real competition and Twitter has real competition
Speaker 5:  and in both cases he's reacting very differently. And I just think
Speaker 5:  as we go into an election year, as things get more heated
Speaker 5:  on social media, his decisions about what he amplifies, what he moderates
Speaker 5:  all this stuff, and whether or not the platform is a
Speaker 5:  safe place for advertisers. 'cause advertisers want brand safety.
Speaker 5:  I think you're right. I think there's, there's not a world in which a year
Speaker 5:  from now we are talking about a Twitter, the company
Speaker 5:  that exists in the form that even this diminished company exists right now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. One more thing I'll say All,
Speaker 6:  Right? We've officially talked too much about this so do this quickly.
Speaker 5:  It's just copy, it's just copyright law. I promise you. It's just, it's just
Speaker 5:  me talking about copy law. So, so can ask about ai. Oh
Speaker 5:  go watch this clip. Addie quick posted tech chart writeup of this clip. It
Speaker 5:  is amazing. So's like ai, it's a lot of training data. You have a lot of
Speaker 5:  training data like these copyright lawsuits might just end it all. And Musk
Speaker 5:  looks at Andrew and says, by the time these lawsuits come to a conclusion,
Speaker 5:  we'll have a digital God. And you should ask him
Speaker 5:  like, like I know Andrew, you know, like he's a
Speaker 5:  pretty rational guy and he's just like, what,
Speaker 5:  what, what are you talking about? He's like, by the time
Speaker 5:  these lawsuits get sorted out, we'll have a digital God and it won't matter.
Speaker 5:  And that was the end. Like there's nothing more you can do with that
Speaker 5:  statement. Like he's like, AI will have become a God.
Speaker 5:  And so copyright lawsuits, who cares? And it's like, dude, those
Speaker 5:  lawsuits are gonna take like two or three years
Speaker 7:  Digital God's right around the corner. He's ascending as we speak. It's
Speaker 6:  Okay. Neli digital God
Speaker 6:  base model Cybertruck,
Speaker 5:  Which comes first?
Speaker 5:  That's tough. That's tough. I gotta go digital. God on this one.
Speaker 5:  I mean honestly,
Speaker 7:  I I would agree.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I, and I think if you're working at one of these generative AI companies,
Speaker 5:  you're hoping it's digital God too. Because these copyright lawsuits are
Speaker 5:  an existential threat. And the Cybertruck, you know, it's just a truck.
Speaker 7:  Get 'em ascending, get going.
Speaker 5:  Everyone at opening eyes is like furiously ordering a base model. Cybertruck
Speaker 5:  right now. All right? We David's right. We've talked enough about Elon. We
Speaker 5:  gotta take a break. We'll right back talk about some other drama. We'll right
Speaker 5:  back
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back. It feels like we should update everybody on what's
Speaker 5:  going on with OpenAI this week. Yeah, it feels like there was a run of instantly
Speaker 5:  obsolete emergency podcasts last week. Including
Speaker 5:  our own, including our own. It's a great podcast. It wass 24 hours. It
Speaker 5:  was obsolete. We
Speaker 1:  Did our best everybody. I enjoyed
Speaker 5:  Listening to it. Yeah, it was fun people, people liked it instantly
Speaker 5:  obsolete. So here's what we know and we can kind
Speaker 5:  of unpack what we think it means because there's some stuff we don't know.
Speaker 5:  What we know is that Sam Altman is officially back as CEO. He
Speaker 5:  is not on the board of directors. Ilya, the
Speaker 5:  chief scientist, does not appear to be working at OpenAI again, is not
Speaker 5:  on the new board of directors.
Speaker 5:  Craig Bachman, the president, is back as president. The new board of directors
Speaker 5:  has begun. Brett Taylor, the former CEO of Salesforce on the
Speaker 5:  board, former treasury secretary, Larry Summers
Speaker 7:  Has interesting ideas about women.
Speaker 5:  Yes. He thinks they're bad at math.
Speaker 7:  I mean, I have said I'm bad at math on this very podcast. That's that's true.
Speaker 7:  I'm sorry to all other women. There are many very women who are excellent
Speaker 7:  at math. I'm okay.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But Larry, Larry. So there's just some weird ideas. But he's apparently
Speaker 5:  been in the mix as an adult. And then Adam D'Angelo, who was on the old board,
Speaker 5:  one of the guys who voted to remove Sam and Greg
Speaker 5:  in the first place. Yeah. And apparently Adam,
Speaker 5:  they've like Adam and Sam have like hung out. Cool. So the new
Speaker 5:  board of directors, its job is to make the actual board of directors and
Speaker 5:  fill out this board and then Microsoft is taking an observer seat
Speaker 5:  and Microsoft will not tell us who is taking that seat. We have asked and
Speaker 5:  they said we're not, we're not gonna tell you. Do
Speaker 7:  You think it could just be some like guy at mic or girl at Microsoft?
Speaker 5:  I think the only rational answer is Kevin Scott, the head of AI at
Speaker 5:  Microsoft. But for some reason Microsoft, I don't, I don't know this. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I'm just saying if I had to look at Microsoft,
Speaker 7:  Maybe they're all on vacation. They haven't decided yet.
Speaker 5:  It's not Phil Spencer.
Speaker 6:  Is it possible Microsoft doesn't know? I mean it, I I just keep going back
Speaker 6:  to, so where we left our emergency podcast was
Speaker 6:  we thought that Sam and Greg were
Speaker 6:  Microsoft employees who were going to start a new thing at Microsoft. And
Speaker 6:  that was the thing that became most instantly obsolete. Yep. Because suddenly
Speaker 6:  it became very clear that actually they were probably going back to OpenAI
Speaker 6:  and it was never really official. But then Satya Nadella does
Speaker 6:  a round of media interviews in which I don't wanna say it didn't sound like
Speaker 6:  he knew what was going on, but it kind of sounded like he didn't know what
Speaker 6:  was going on. It was, it, it got to the point where it was moving
Speaker 6:  so fast that it seemed like even he, the person
Speaker 6:  who was by all accounts kind of brokering this whole thing
Speaker 6:  was caught off guard by some of the turns of it.
Speaker 5:  Yes. I can call her in some there. Okay. I, I think there was a, a
Speaker 5:  notion that Nadela was trying to make it happen.
Speaker 5:  I think that ultimately he was involved in some
Speaker 5:  conversations. But we, we now know that Airbnb, CEO, Brian
Speaker 5:  Chesky, who's a friend of Sam Emmett, she who's the former CEO of Twitch
Speaker 5:  who became the interim CEO of OpenAI
Speaker 6:  For five minutes
Speaker 5:  And Larry Summers and some other folks, they were the ones actually sort
Speaker 5:  of like mediating this conversation. And Nadella was just like around
Speaker 5:  'cause he wanted to protect Microsoft's interest. Okay. The other thing I
Speaker 5:  know is that that round of media tours is our fault
Speaker 5:  straight up. Oh, interesting. That's, that's our fault. It's because
Speaker 5:  Alex and I reported that Sam and Greg
Speaker 5:  were trying to go back to OpenAI after Microsoft had made its big announcement.
Speaker 5:  So Microsoft had made its big announcement they're all gonna come work at,
Speaker 5:  at Microsoft. We're gonna start a new AI thing, the stock goes up,
Speaker 5:  then we report, ah, maybe this won't happen. And now there's like instability.
Speaker 5:  We got jittery investors and of course Nadela goes on CNBC and
Speaker 5:  Bloomberg to say it's all good. Like doesn't matter
Speaker 5:  which way's happening, Microsoft is moving forward with Sam Altman, which
Speaker 5:  was very much his message. And he kept saying, and I thought this was
Speaker 5:  just the funniest thing, he kept saying, irrespective of configuration,
Speaker 5:  which just sounds like he was announcing plug and play device drivers.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It doesn't matter irrespective of how your dip switches are set. Like
Speaker 5:  we will find this USB device, we will find time
Speaker 5:  Albin like he's not wrong. It doesn't matter what order you put the cards
Speaker 5:  in with PCI express for, you know, it's like irrespective
Speaker 5:  con configuration. He just kept saying it. It was amazing.
Speaker 5:  So I. I think that was that, right? Like we had, because of
Speaker 5:  our reporting, we had made it clear like this isn't a done deal
Speaker 5:  And So I think he was compelled to go out and
Speaker 5:  say, yeah, I actually dunno what's going on. Like it's gonna land one
Speaker 5:  way or the other. But our investment in OpenAI is safe because either we
Speaker 5:  will take all of these employees at very high rates, which is
Speaker 5:  a massive investment for Microsoft to make, to protect this investment. Or
Speaker 5:  we'll find a way to keep working with OpenAI. And they asked him, I think
Speaker 5:  it was Emily Chang and Bloomberg asked him, who will be the CEO of OpenAI
Speaker 5:  tomorrow? And he looked exhausted and he said
Speaker 5:  that's for the board to decide.
Speaker 5:  Don don't know man. Oh he also did, he also did on
Speaker 5:  with Kara Swisher. Yeah. And it was, it was, you know, I interviewed a lot
Speaker 5:  of CEOs. Sometimes CEOs just have a thing they're gonna say and he
Speaker 5:  said the thing in all three places. Yeah. But I know that what was happening
Speaker 5:  there was the market thought that this thing
Speaker 5:  was a done deal and it became quickly apparent that it
Speaker 5:  was actually not a done deal and actively trying to go the other way. Which
Speaker 5:  it did. So I that, which it did. Yeah. In the end. Which in the end it did.
Speaker 5:  And Microsoft seems very happy and Sam notably like tweeted
Speaker 5:  my thanks to Satya for his support, So I. I think everybody wanted
Speaker 5:  this to happen. And I think at one point
Speaker 5:  Nadella said to to Kara or Emily, like, surprises are bad.
Speaker 5:  Like we don't wanna be surprised like this Anyway. Yeah, we'll fix the governance
Speaker 5:  of the company. So you've got the board observer seat, which again, I don't
Speaker 5:  know who it will be. Yeah. but it just feels like
Speaker 5:  you want that to be Kevin Scott, your head of AI or maybe Brad Smith or
Speaker 5:  their chief legal officer. Like that's who you want in that spot. Just some
Speaker 5:  pm But I don't think you can, I I personally do not think you could put
Speaker 5:  Scha there. Yeah. I think you need to a little bit of distance from the company
Speaker 5:  to Yeah. To claim that you're not running the company. So if you put your
Speaker 5:  famous high profile CEO on this board, now you've just got another,
Speaker 5:  another part of Microsoft, which I think Microsoft wants to keep a little
Speaker 5:  bit of that distance. That's what we know so far. Then there's this
Speaker 5:  weirdness where Alex Heath got a quick interview with Sam
Speaker 5:  Altman and Mira Mirati, the former CTO who was the
Speaker 5:  first interim CEO who is now the CTO again. You did it God at
Speaker 5:  that time. Yes. Nailed it. Just so you know, that was like the third take
Speaker 5:  of that.
Speaker 5:  And you know, Alex is like, what should I ask? I was like only one question,
Speaker 5:  like why'd you get fired? And Alex asked this question five times in a row
Speaker 5:  and there's no answer to this question
Speaker 7:  That's continues to kind of baffle me. I could understand why the
Speaker 7:  board wasn't saying anything, but like, why isn't he
Speaker 5:  I, don Dunno. We do know that the board has been talking like, I think
Speaker 5:  Helen Toner, who's a member of the board, has been talking to folks saying
Speaker 5:  like, we feel confident in our decision, all this stuff.
Speaker 5:  It is abundantly clear that these ideas that it was about
Speaker 5:  safety or that there was a new model that could destroy the world
Speaker 5:  or do basic math. It's one or the other. It's do basic math or destroy the
Speaker 5:  world.
Speaker 7:  Same thing.
Speaker 5:  But like the notion that that spooked the board and they had to get rid of
Speaker 5:  Sam so they could put in their own person that none of that appears to be
Speaker 5:  true. Right. Like no one on either side is saying this was the reason. It
Speaker 5:  is, it really comes down to interpersonal conflicts
Speaker 5:  between a group of four people and Sam Altman. Yeah. And I think the board
Speaker 5:  basically thinks like they couldn't control him and then whenever
Speaker 5:  they tried he would do something to get out of it. Yeah. And there will be
Speaker 5:  an investigation. We are told, I think the results of that
Speaker 5:  investigation should likely be made public, given the dollar amounts and
Speaker 5:  investors and you know, employees involved.
Speaker 7:  Oh, we're gonna find out. Anyway.
Speaker 5:  I even, I even for open AI's employees, you need to make that investigation.
Speaker 5:  Like why did this happen to us? Right. Yeah. I think there's skittishness
Speaker 5:  on both sides there. And we'll see, and that's another job of this new board
Speaker 5:  run by Brett Taylor is to run that investigation.
Speaker 7:  I think my question is if it was something like we're upset
Speaker 7:  that he's, he's moving too fast, he he's being too commercial and which
Speaker 7:  seemed from the, from the beginning to be one of the issues there. Particularly
Speaker 7:  like his, his conflict with Helen Toner was particularly about that and how
Speaker 7:  she'd written a paper about that. If, if that's the case and they come
Speaker 7:  back and they say, oh, we, we found that was the reason why. What,
Speaker 7:  what do they do? Because they now have a board that is very much for
Speaker 7:  commercialization. They now have their biggest investor in an observer's
Speaker 7:  seat on that board. And the guy who was doing all of that, that they had
Speaker 7:  conflict with is now still CEO of the company. Right. Like,
Speaker 7:  what happens then?
Speaker 5:  Well, they're gone. They, they wiped their hands of this, by
Speaker 5:  the way that Helen Toner paper is worth reading. We'll link to it in the
Speaker 5:  show notes or something. The, you know, the part that everyone is up that
Speaker 5:  apparently Sam was up in arms about is she just points out that the industry
Speaker 5:  had been very cautious until the success of chat GPT
Speaker 5:  and then everyone started moving really fast, which, and they had abandoned
Speaker 5:  the caution in favor of whatever commercial outcomes they could see,
Speaker 5:  which
Speaker 7:  Is exactly what
Speaker 5:  Happened, which is exactly what happened. And it, it's actually really hard
Speaker 5:  to read a criticism of OpenAI into it. She's just like,
Speaker 5:  compare and contrast. Like we had, you know, the very famously philanthropic
Speaker 5:  split from OpenAI over safety concerns and they're like, they waited
Speaker 5:  but everyone else rushed. Yeah. After we had our success. That's
Speaker 5:  true.
Speaker 6:  Right. Well, and what's what's funny about that is it, there's a version
Speaker 6:  of that story that I think is true that says OpenAI didn't do
Speaker 6:  that on purpose, right? Like I think Yeah. What what
Speaker 6:  Microsoft did with binging was just ruthlessly
Speaker 6:  capitalistic, right? They just said like, yeah, I gotta figure out how to
Speaker 6:  make money off of this. And that's, that's what they did. But like today,
Speaker 6:  Thursday, as we're recording, this is the one year anniversary of the chat
Speaker 6:  GPT launch. And like the, the thing we
Speaker 6:  know beyond a shadow of a doubt at this point is that no one at
Speaker 6:  OpenAI or Microsoft or anywhere launched chat GPT thinking
Speaker 6:  it was gonna take over the world. There was this like long term plan that
Speaker 6:  everybody was on. And it's funny if you rewind back to
Speaker 6:  pre-chat GPT and sort of asked a bunch of people at these companies what
Speaker 6:  they thought the future of AI was gonna look like. They all would've been
Speaker 6:  more or less right, just wrong about the timeline. And then
Speaker 6:  chat GPT happened and everybody went, oh crap, this stuff that we've been
Speaker 6:  working on in the background towards this interesting long future
Speaker 6:  we have to do today. And that's, that's what Google did. It was like the,
Speaker 6:  what was it? The code red within Google that that Yeah. Sergey and Larry
Speaker 6:  put up. Microsoft starts running, everybody just starts running. And it
Speaker 6:  did it, it lit this fire in the tech industry that took it down a bunch
Speaker 6:  of how do we make money off of AI questions
Speaker 6:  from people who had previously been saying, we have to do this
Speaker 6:  carefully. We have to be thoughtful about this, we have to be smart about
Speaker 6:  this. but it all happened like by accident. It's the
Speaker 6:  weirdest sort of twist of fate that it wasn't like somebody launched the
Speaker 6:  revolutionary product knowing it was the revolutionary product and like turned
Speaker 6:  everything on its head. It's just like somebody just like farted out a blog
Speaker 6:  post and then the world changed. Like it's nuts.
Speaker 5:  Well yeah, that's the ChatGPT side of it, which is,
Speaker 5:  you should read David's piece. It's the fastest growing consumer product
Speaker 5:  we should reckon with it. But you know, satin Anella did
Speaker 5:  look me in the eye and say, I want Google to know I made them dance. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  yeah. Oh yeah. Like he was, he was headed that way regardless, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But I don't think he would've gotten there in February of 2023. Right?
Speaker 5:  I, don Dunno. He did make the giant investment, right? Like, yeah, this,
Speaker 5:  it's hard, it's hard to know. But like
Speaker 5:  Microsoft do was doing co-pilots already. They had started doing this stuff
Speaker 5:  in a very small way. Yeah. And I think the part of it where
Speaker 5:  the stack overflows of the world were just
Speaker 5:  overrun with, oh, this is better if I just ask an AI to do it. And that's
Speaker 5:  a real thing that's going on. Yeah. Maybe that would've happened anyway,
Speaker 5:  but the sort of like, I'll have it right in my resume for me.
Speaker 5:  Like just sort of like, whatever's gonna go on with the LLMs and
Speaker 7:  You shouldn't, by the way, have it write your resume.
Speaker 5:  Well, no. It'll hallucinate some grant on. Exactly. That's
Speaker 7:  If it's gonna be FactCheck, you shouldn't, if it's not, do it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Make me look good.
Speaker 5:  And that's actually the, the p the part of your piece, David, that I think
Speaker 5:  is the most resonant for me, which is now we have these tools and everyone
Speaker 5:  thinks they're gonna change everything. I am personally still stuck at
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But they're not very good yet. Like they're good at some things.
Speaker 5:  Programming a computer, everyone constantly telling me they're great
Speaker 5:  at this in a way that is revolutionary. And that's because it's programming
Speaker 5:  computers effectively just delivering instructions. Right. Make me a set
Speaker 5:  of instructions such that some input in the computer generates some output.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's a deterministic task. You can like set an AI to
Speaker 5:  it. Many people have done it before. The internet is full of this knowledge.
Speaker 5:  You can get there, write me a new idea. Something like
Speaker 5:  inherently creative. I still think they fall down all the time. These
Speaker 5:  non-deterministic tasks, they fall down all the time. Yeah. And, and I continue
Speaker 5:  to point out they're all these companies are one copyright decision away
Speaker 5:  from just non existing. Yeah. And that's re and like no
Speaker 5:  one, it's just like, well, let's just not look at that time bomb.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That seems Nah. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I, I love it as a, as a person who loves to do that sort of thing, just be
Speaker 7:  like, oh, I'm not gonna worry about that for now. Just put my blinders on
Speaker 7:  and go straight ahead.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That car's on fire.
Speaker 7:  It's fine. Don't worry about it.
Speaker 6:  There was a great, Corey au the, the author and EFF activist who's
Speaker 6:  been on this show a few times, wrote a really good thing this week that I'll,
Speaker 6:  I'll try and make sure we link to in the show notes, basically saying he
Speaker 6:  quoted this guy named Lee Vinzel who talks about this concept of crita hype,
Speaker 6:  which is basically taking the sort of
Speaker 6:  truths that the most optimistic people who are usually the people
Speaker 6:  making products, believing that they're going to be right
Speaker 6:  and then covering it with hell scapes is the way he describes it. So it's
Speaker 6:  like to talk about this world in which AI takes over everything and
Speaker 6:  ruins everything, assumes that AI is going to
Speaker 6:  get as good as some of these people say that it is, which they have
Speaker 6:  a massive vested interest in doing. And so like, it's the digital
Speaker 6:  God thing, right? Like Yeah. Just to talk about whether we think a digital
Speaker 6:  God is a good idea or a bad idea is, is to assume that
Speaker 6:  it's gonna happen. Yeah. And we're, we're, there is just no
Speaker 6:  evidence in the AI that exists now that we are headed toward that place
Speaker 6:  anytime soon. And this is like what OpenAI talks about with the artificial
Speaker 6:  general intelligence and a GI and this idea that like, we're on the brink
Speaker 6:  of something that is like you're talking about Eli creative and thoughtful
Speaker 6:  and human and better than us at everything. And there's just no reason
Speaker 6:  to believe right now in the world in that we live in
Speaker 6:  that that's actually coming. And it's like Corey's piece was very smart and
Speaker 6:  I've been thinking about it all week because it's like we, we have to criticize
Speaker 6:  the thing that exists, not the thing that the people who make the thing exist
Speaker 6:  promise us is coming someday soon. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Well, and I think what's really interesting about that is, is
Speaker 7:  it ignores the stuff that it, that the harms and stuff like the actual concern
Speaker 7:  you should have right now about it, which totally is the stuff we talk about
Speaker 7:  all the time. How it's it's destroying the internet like that's happening
Speaker 7:  right now. Yeah. This second, somebody is writing garb, having
Speaker 7:  it write garbage and putting, publishing it on a website and, and that gets
Speaker 7:  totally ignored to talk
Speaker 5:  About. This week Sports Illustrated got caught. Yeah. Publishing AI
Speaker 5:  generated SEO affiliate Garbage. And they took it down and they
Speaker 5:  blamed a company and like we didn't know they were using ai and then somebody
Speaker 5:  looked up the company on LinkedIn and like literally companies described
Speaker 5:  as using AI and ML to do SEO affiliate. That's like don don't know man.
Speaker 5:  I I think Aon commerce, the AI ML commerce
Speaker 5:  company was probably gonna use AI and ML to make your commerce
Speaker 5:  articles.
Speaker 7:  They actually asked AI what companies should we hire for this?
Speaker 5:  Like it was the most circular excuse in the world, but that's
Speaker 5:  happening. Like story media institutions are chasing
Speaker 5:  just the bottom of the barrel SEO content. Yeah. In a way that will
Speaker 5:  pollute Google and Well, and the internet lots of sort of just like
Speaker 5:  mid-level creatives are gonna lose their jobs over this stuff at the place
Speaker 5:  it is now. David, your point about we can't criticize what's to come is like
Speaker 5:  our oldest rule in reviewing products is
Speaker 5:  you review what comes in the box. Yep. And when the company promises you
Speaker 5:  a software update, we'll fix it. You just, we always say All, right? Let
Speaker 5:  us know when it comes out. Yeah. We're not gonna review this promise against
Speaker 5:  the promises. Sorry. So harsh. Sorry.
Speaker 5:  We
Speaker 7:  Sorry.
Speaker 5:  They just put out a next product. Yeah, that's a great example actually.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We are, we are like, we will not review a product against the promise
Speaker 5:  of a software update and hope bill's like here's a new camera,
Speaker 5:  no software updates for you.
Speaker 7:  Aw,
Speaker 5:  It's brutal. Yeah. Yeah. And so here we are with the LLMs and some
Speaker 5:  of them are good and some of they're bad and like they all have different
Speaker 5:  capabilities, but GBT four right now is not a, a threat
Speaker 5:  to the world.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  I agree with that. Just a threat to bloggers.
Speaker 5:  It's just, yeah. It's just a threat to the people who make affiliate commerce
Speaker 5:  links
Speaker 6:  And our ability to do functional Google searches.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Well I think we're gonna see it like in YouTube and we're seeing those
Speaker 7:  other mediums too, right? Like just the ability to make, to generate
Speaker 7:  mass amounts of garbage into a world that is largely driven by
Speaker 7:  algorithms that are predisposed to that garbage because they're algorithms
Speaker 7:  and they think like computers just the way this garbage being generated does,
Speaker 7:  like it's just this weird gross snake eating its tail
Speaker 7:  and we all have to sit in it. I
Speaker 5:  Need to, I'm, I'm assigning myself a story. So, I have this idea that
Speaker 5:  you can make a list of all of Google's platforms
Speaker 5:  and then you can make a list of all of Google's tools and you can just draw
Speaker 5:  a line from one to the other and be like, here's the problem.
Speaker 5:  You know, like you can draw a line from the Pixel camera using
Speaker 5:  AI to do photos Yeah. To YouTube. It's has a rule.
Speaker 5:  It's like you need to disclose the AI in the pho in the video.
Speaker 5:  And you're like, well, have you guys talked? And they're like, no,
Speaker 5:  that should
Speaker 6:  Be the headline. This is a column that you just described, NELI called, have
Speaker 6:  these guys talked.
Speaker 5:  And it's just literally drawing a line between any Google platform and any
Speaker 5:  Google tool. Like Google Docs now let's you do AI generated thing and
Speaker 5:  like you go talk to the, the search team and he'd be like, do you know about
Speaker 5:  this? And they're like, huh. It's just like a big circle. And like
Speaker 5:  every part of Google has this problem, which I think is utterly
Speaker 5:  fascinating. But that, and that's just one company that's,
Speaker 5:  that runs both platforms. Another one, just this last week,
Speaker 5:  the Bard team extended Bard such that you can just give
Speaker 5:  it a YouTube video and it'll summarize it for you. You know, like if if it's
Speaker 5:  a recipe, it'll just like pull out the recipe. Does the creator get a a YouTube
Speaker 5:  view when that happens? Does
Speaker 7:  YouTube know about that?
Speaker 5:  Does this, does YouTube know? That's weird, right? Like the, the YouTube
Speaker 5:  is an economy, like it is the
Speaker 5:  gold standard in creator platforms where people can make a living and bard's
Speaker 5:  like, what if we just pull everything off of it and summarize the videos
Speaker 5:  for people. Little
Speaker 7:  12 year olds watching, like reading Mr Beast videos in Bard.
Speaker 7:  Now he
Speaker 5:  Needs to start feeding Mr. Beast videos to Bard. And Bard would be like,
Speaker 5:  this is not a good use of your time.
Speaker 6:  Google summarize. It
Speaker 5:  Shuts down.
Speaker 6:  No. Eli, you just described a decoder series and, and
Speaker 6:  you know how much I love talking. Have you guys talked, have you guys talked?
Speaker 6:  You just bring two people in and you just say, have you guys talked? And
Speaker 6:  then you just leave
Speaker 6:  and, and it's like, it's like a big brother style. We would just record them
Speaker 6:  with security cameras for an hour and that's decoder.
Speaker 5:  That's perfect. It's just us making different parts of Google
Speaker 5:  talk to each other.
Speaker 6:  You could run that show for a decade.
Speaker 5:  This is one of my favorite stories about early Verge,
Speaker 5:  just like us learning how to do reporting, how everything
Speaker 5:  worked. And remember early Verge is like early in lifecycle all
Speaker 5:  these companies too. Yeah. So there was just one time
Speaker 5:  where basically we told Google that they had scheduled
Speaker 5:  two events on the same day because
Speaker 7:  They didn't
Speaker 5:  Know because they hadn't talked. And like, and we didn't, we were
Speaker 5:  babies. So we were like, did you, do you have the same,
Speaker 5:  is that okay? Is that how we normally? And they're like, no, we have to talk
Speaker 5:  to each other. I'm like, are we in trouble?
Speaker 5:  But no, they were just, Google was so big and sprawling that the two teams
Speaker 5:  hadn't talked and they had both scheduled events in the same day. Oh
Speaker 5:  boy. And and it was us. We had told him. Yeah, it was very good.
Speaker 5:  Have you talked the extension of Decoder coming soon to a podcast player?
Speaker 5:  All right? We should take a break. We're gonna come back. We'll do a lightning
Speaker 5:  Run.
Speaker 5:  All, right? We're back with the Cybertruck Lightning round sponsored by no
Speaker 5:  one. This could be you. I'm looking directly
Speaker 5:  at you advertisers by not sponsoring the lightning round. You are
Speaker 5:  blackmailing
Speaker 7:  Stop it.
Speaker 5:  And I, you know, the Woke Mind virus is overtaken America and
Speaker 5:  that's why the Lightning Round does not have a sponsor and that's the first
Speaker 5:  cast
Speaker 5:  possibly forever.
Speaker 5:  There you go. All, right? Alex what you got?
Speaker 7:  Okay. So. I. I'm gonna continue our theme of talking a little bit of boardroom,
Speaker 7:  boardroom drama. That's,
Speaker 5:  That's David's favorite. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  David, get excited. Okay. But this one is fun because it's Disney
Speaker 7:  and Yeah. And what actually happens here could really affect Disney
Speaker 7:  because, so there's an activist investor, his name is Nelson Peltz, and
Speaker 7:  he's really good friends with Ike Perlmutter. And Ike Perlmutter used to
Speaker 7:  run Marvel back in the day and he got fired earlier this year. Another
Speaker 5:  Guy with ideas and he,
Speaker 7:  Boy does he have a lot of ideas. He was like, you know what, we don't need
Speaker 7:  women not a fan of them. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 7:  You know, he, he didn't want a Black Widow movie, he didn't want a captive
Speaker 7:  Marvel movie, a Black Panther movie. He didn't think any of It works. He's
Speaker 7:  like, you know what you need, you need a bunch of scrapping young white guys
Speaker 7:  out there doing stuff.
Speaker 5:  I feel like we're learning something else about Ike promo.
Speaker 7:  We are. Yeah. Interesting. But they're, they're very good friends. Ike was
Speaker 7:  fired earlier this year from Disney by Bob Iger. They are, they are not friends.
Speaker 7:  Nelson Peltz is an activist investor trying to get two board seats on
Speaker 7:  the Disney board because he is mad at everything. And the Disney board is
Speaker 7:  like, you just wanna bring Ike back and all the voting shares you're using
Speaker 7:  like 78% of the voting shares you're using are Ike's voting shares.
Speaker 7:  It's good. No, so, so there's a little fight there. And, and, and right now
Speaker 7:  there is ammunition, there's a lot of garbage. Bob Iger was
Speaker 7:  also at that Dealbook conference and he talked about it and he was like,
Speaker 7:  yeah, captain Marvel didn't work because we didn't have enough, like essentially
Speaker 7:  adults in the room. We didn't have enough executives watching over this.
Speaker 7:  We've been making bad films. And in the case of the Marvels, it was really
Speaker 7:  interesting to hear him say that, given that there were a lot of reasons
Speaker 7:  that movies struggled. Yeah. Box offices down across the board this
Speaker 7:  year there was a strike. It was a film. There
Speaker 5:  Was Yeah. They couldn't promote the movie.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. They just straight up couldn't promote the movie. And, and part of
Speaker 7:  it was like, yeah, it had a mess. It was had, it was a messy production.
Speaker 7:  They did have to go back and do a whole bunch of reshoots. And the third,
Speaker 7:  the back third of the film is like not as good as the first two parts.
Speaker 7:  That's brutal. That like, it is true. But also they've been releasing a
Speaker 7:  ton of garbage for the last few years. The the fatigue is, is set in. And
Speaker 7:  so for them to be like, oh, that one just didn't work because we didn't try
Speaker 7:  hard enough was really interesting for him to say. And so now he's like,
Speaker 7:  don't worry, we're gonna try harder. And that's not what you need to
Speaker 7:  be saying when you've got activists, investors breathing down your neck,
Speaker 7:  particularly activist investors who think it's a mistake that
Speaker 7:  you've made all these films starring, you
Speaker 5:  Know, and and Peltz was in the mix, right? With Chap Ppac. So you got, you
Speaker 5:  got your dual and Bobs Yeah, a lot of Bobs. So you get Bob Iger, he hands
Speaker 5:  it out to Chap Pack, the pandemic hits. He doesn't like how Chap Ppac is
Speaker 5:  running anything and he, he brings himself back,
Speaker 7:  Brings himself back.
Speaker 5:  But in there, in somewhere in there, right. Nelson
Speaker 5:  Peltz shows up and like causes trouble for Disney along the way.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. He's, because he's been friends with Ike for this whole time. So he's
Speaker 7:  been really supportive of Ike and, and supportive of like kind of Ike's way
Speaker 7:  of doing things. And, and so he's, he's really wanted a
Speaker 7:  seat on that board. He's wanted to maintain a seat on that board and, and
Speaker 7:  he and Iger don't like each other. And and we saw that at the Dealbook conference.
Speaker 7:  Andrew was at kept asking him, tell me about Pels, what's going on with him?
Speaker 7:  And he's like, ah, don't worry about it. Yeah, it's fine. Really blowing
Speaker 7:  him off there. So it's gonna be really interesting to see how, how they
Speaker 7:  go about this. And I think it is very concerning when you have the largest
Speaker 7:  media company in the world and you've got these guys who are,
Speaker 7:  have a really strong reputation for not liking half of the
Speaker 7:  population of the world wanting to go back and wanting a seat at the table
Speaker 7:  to dictate kind of how that company operates and including the kind of
Speaker 7:  films they make for me as a, as a woman, not, not my favorite thing
Speaker 7:  to see, but it's happening. Yeah. So we'll see how it lands.
Speaker 5:  It it is also true. I, I mean I agree with you, but it is also true. Disney
Speaker 5:  is not doing great. That's
Speaker 7:  True too. Yeah. Disney is not doing great and and there's a lot of reasons
Speaker 7:  for that. Iger likes to put everything on jpeg and I think that's stupid
Speaker 7:  of him.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That clock has run out. He's been back
Speaker 7:  Long enough, right? Yeah. He's been back way too long for that. I think there
Speaker 7:  is a lot of problems with that company and, and, and there's a lot of different
Speaker 7:  reasons for that. I saw a really great story the other day about how Disney
Speaker 7:  Plus was kind of like antithetical to the way that Disney has always done
Speaker 7:  business because Disney's business has always been circular. Every single
Speaker 7:  thing builds gets you to go buy something else that Disney makes.
Speaker 7:  And when you put suddenly everything in one spot, why,
Speaker 7:  why are you going anywhere else? It's a great deal for us, the consumer.
Speaker 7:  It's a terrible deal for Disney and Disney's gotta figure out a way out
Speaker 7:  of that. And, and their idea is, okay, well we're gonna put more into our
Speaker 7:  parks. We're gonna, we're gonna make them bigger, we're gonna make them more
Speaker 7:  fun, make them more accessible. They changed a whole lot of the rules there
Speaker 7:  to like kind of get all those park goers happy again. 'cause that was one
Speaker 7:  of the things jpeg really screwed up was he pissed off all of those. He
Speaker 5:  Raised all the prices.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, he raised the prices. He, he changed like how you could get into the
Speaker 7:  park and stuff like that. So like Iris's got a lot
Speaker 7:  of work to do and I don't think he's moving fast enough.
Speaker 5:  Interesting.
Speaker 7:  I I think he, he he's gotta move a lot faster and he's also gotta start like
Speaker 7:  letting off the reins and more importantly, like trusting
Speaker 7:  your directors, trusting your writers, trusting the creatives you
Speaker 7:  hire to do their job. The, the fact that he was like, oh yeah, we just didn't
Speaker 7:  have enough executives watching over the Marvels is a wild statement to make
Speaker 7:  because one of the big reasons that Marvel has been struggling is that there's
Speaker 7:  one guy at the top, Kevin Vay and he stretched too thin and he was like kind
Speaker 7:  of, he had a Midas touch, he could fix anything and he can't fix
Speaker 7:  everything. Like delegate my man. So there, there needs to be a lot more
Speaker 7:  delegation over there.
Speaker 5:  Can I tell you a story about Dakota really quickly? Yeah. I had IBM's head
Speaker 5:  of quantum computing on Dakota this week. I don Dunno know when that upset,
Speaker 5:  but it's coming out in the very end. I was like, what do you think of those
Speaker 5:  Antman movies? And it was just like, ugh.
Speaker 5:  Just, just letting you know. Brutal. So I. She get Jerry Chow
Speaker 5:  watching this. I'll say as a person who was just a Disney world, yeah.
Speaker 5:  They have not lowered the prices. My friend. I bought a $35 bubble wand
Speaker 5:  and boy did we not get $35 in value on that thing.
Speaker 5:  Not even a little bit. No. Also Disney World. Very entertaining because
Speaker 5:  you know, people from all walks of life are there. Yeah. And there's a monorail,
Speaker 5:  which is like public transit and washing big people in maga hats like
Speaker 5:  happily ride the train is like very entertaining. And you're like, wait,
Speaker 5:  this train doesn't work nearly as well as it should.
Speaker 5:  It's like really doesn't. It's really that great. It's, I would describe
Speaker 5:  it my, my sister and I, my sister's like a Disney adult and she can like
Speaker 5:  work the app and she knows the vocabulary to get
Speaker 7:  Your lines. You're in here, all your lines in lightning
Speaker 5:  Lanes. It was incredible. No adult should ever say
Speaker 5:  to another adult, have you checked your My Genie? Plus that should
Speaker 5:  not happen.
Speaker 7:  But it does when you go to Disney.
Speaker 5:  But it, you're like, oh this is, this is the most like incredible
Speaker 5:  technocratic neoliberal bureaucracy in the world. Right? Like, if you can
Speaker 5:  work the system, the world is your oyster. There's a sheen of
Speaker 5:  light corruption that makes, makes everything a little exciting. Yeah. You're
Speaker 5:  like, is Bradley Cooper here? Like does he have to stand in mind?
Speaker 7:  Did you get the, did you get the little band?
Speaker 5:  Oh we had the band. The band flew off my wrist during Guardians of the Galaxy
Speaker 5:  and I caught it. That is by the way, one of the best rollercoasters I've
Speaker 5:  been on my entire life. Incredible. And then I somehow I lost the band during
Speaker 5:  Pirates of the Caribbean, which is a slow boat ride.
Speaker 5:  No idea. Not idea. Not the one
Speaker 7:  Where you're doing like a spiral.
Speaker 5:  No, no idea how I lost it on that one. And I caught
Speaker 5:  it during Guardians. Very cool. Loved every minute of it, but Max was happy.
Speaker 6:  Did they make you a guardian? If you catch it in midair, they're just like,
Speaker 6:  Chris Pratt comes out and he's like, you did it.
Speaker 7:  No. That's how the ride starts. Is your guardian basically?
Speaker 5:  No. Kind of, no. Yeah. I mean there's, it's like it's a ride. There's a story.
Speaker 5:  The thing is, the story comes to its conclusion during the rollercoaster
Speaker 5:  while everyone is screaming and they're blasting eighties music at you. Perfect.
Speaker 5:  So I have no idea what hap I wrote it twice and I'm like, what happens?
Speaker 7:  The first time I wrote it I was maybe really enjoying it was,
Speaker 7:  it was a, it was, you know, it was kind of an April 20th kind of day for
Speaker 7:  me.
Speaker 5:  Would you say you were in the Magic Kingdom?
Speaker 7:  I was in the Magic Kingdom and I didn't enjoy it very much 'cause I spent
Speaker 7:  the entire time being like, what if my glasses fly off? Well
Speaker 7:  I just spent like this and the video of me was just holding my glasses.
Speaker 5:  Just be more careful on Yeah.
Speaker 7:  On Tired being second time I just didn't wear it.
Speaker 5:  It was good. And the Tron Rider was good. It was fun. But you're just like
Speaker 5:  in this place where're like, oh this is what, this is what you want. The
Speaker 5:  taxes are very high, the services are available, but it somewhat
Speaker 5:  mediocre
Speaker 7:  And sometimes they just carry a man
Speaker 5:  Up and if you can work this app, you can get health insurance. Yes. Like
Speaker 5:  Disney World,
Speaker 7:  Really good health insurance.
Speaker 5:  I would not, I was not the most fun at Disney World. Like everyone's
Speaker 5:  like, yes, we understand that you have ideas about politics,
Speaker 5:  But it was very fun. We had a good time. And the enterprise wifi network
Speaker 5:  is WLAN dash T wdc, which it
Speaker 5:  has been apparently for over a decade. What?
Speaker 5:  And it's on, it's like this at every Disney property. And Disney employees
Speaker 5:  were posting on threads at me that it is so cumbersome that they installed
Speaker 5:  network devices in their house so they can get on the corporate network instead
Speaker 5:  of using the VPN all Very good. I like to think that Disney World has so
Speaker 5:  many devices on the wifi, they can never change the network name. Like
Speaker 5:  they have to walk around the entire park like hitting the reset button.
Speaker 5:  All very good. All, right? David, what's your lighting around? That was mine.
Speaker 5:  I'll just do that one.
Speaker 6:  I just,
Speaker 7:  Eli went to Disney World. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  At very, very, I just like, I'm now imagining Eli with like his 16 inch
Speaker 6:  MacBook Pro just like sitting in line for a rollercoaster,
Speaker 5:  Waiting for OpenAI News to break a real thing that I thought was gonna happen.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Have you ever been on the phone with a source being like, is this gonna get
Speaker 5:  Wrapped up tonight because I have to go to Disney World in the morning.
Speaker 6:  It's a cool line, honestly. Yeah. I support it. Mine is just
Speaker 6:  to, as I occasionally do, implore
Speaker 6:  every website and app and person on earth
Speaker 6:  to do your version of Spotify Wrapped. So Spotify Wrapped came out this week.
Speaker 6:  This is the week of like everybody gets their year in review stuff.
Speaker 6:  YouTube music did it. Apple Music did it. Has Reddit's come out yet? Reddit
Speaker 6:  does one every year. I haven't seen mine. I don't know if it came out's yet.
Speaker 6:  Think it's Spotify is his out PocketCasts, my podcast app did one.
Speaker 6:  All kinds of stuff coming out. This is my favorite genre of thing on the
Speaker 6:  internet. I saw somebody who just posted one that was like a screenshot of
Speaker 6:  their Chrome history just showing all the webpage they go to the most. I
Speaker 6:  was like, my browser should have this. I want my email to show me like who
Speaker 6:  I email the most. Should
Speaker 7:  Your browser have
Speaker 6:  This? I it does like it or not. Like it has that information. It might as
Speaker 6:  well show it to me in a funny way. I just think everything that exists,
Speaker 6:  like Mike, I want like Google Calendar Wrapped at the end of every
Speaker 6:  year just to tell me
Speaker 5:  Like, that's so brutal.
Speaker 7:  That's depressing. don don't want that.
Speaker 6:  Like David, who have you talked shit about in Slack most this year?
Speaker 5:  Oh, slack should do that. That would actually be great. This is what
Speaker 7:  I'm saying, slack didn't Slack used to, I feel like there used to be a way
Speaker 7:  where you could just see like who talks the most.
Speaker 5:  No, it it this, this was like a weird enterprise privacy
Speaker 5:  nightmare debate where like your Slack administrator could see who the, the
Speaker 5:  biggest user of Slack was in your organization. Oh yeah. And people were
Speaker 5:  like, this is a privacy violation. And I was like, no, you work at a company
Speaker 5:  bro.
Speaker 7:  You don't have privacy in the company stuff.
Speaker 5:  No, no, no, no. Like not on the work laptop.
Speaker 5:  No, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Shut it down
Speaker 5:  All. right. My last, my real lightning round item, which is
Speaker 5:  not about my
Speaker 7:  World is Lightning Lane
Speaker 5:  Technocratic Neoliberal nightmare of Disney World.
Speaker 5:  No, it's the Epic versus Google trial. So the Epic versus
Speaker 5:  Google antitrust trials ongoing. That again is about Fortnite and
Speaker 5:  billing on app stores. This is the sequel to the Apple
Speaker 5:  one. We, we mentioned this during the, while we were covering the Apple one,
Speaker 5:  I think we've mentioned this show since then. Apple case was very straightforward.
Speaker 5:  Apple doesn't allow other app stores, they require you to use their billing
Speaker 5:  system. This whole thing. There's no emails
Speaker 5:  except Apple executives being like, this is stupid go away. And so
Speaker 5:  like Epic had to concoct this entire case about Apple and its
Speaker 5:  monopoly and Lock-in. And you can believe it or not, Google is an
Speaker 5:  ecosystem provider. They have lots and lots of deals. They have lots and
Speaker 5:  lots of relationships. They have hardware vendors. They have hardware vendors
Speaker 5:  trying to differentiate their products. There is a ton of evidence about
Speaker 5:  how Google makes deals in this case and how people try to make deals
Speaker 5:  with Google. And it is not pretty. And I think that's like the thing that
Speaker 5:  we have learned throughout this entire case and throughout the DOJ case with
Speaker 5:  Google is Google does a lot of deal making. So the one that
Speaker 5:  came out this week that is I think really, really revealing is
Speaker 5:  Activision tried to start its own mobile game app store
Speaker 5:  on Android. So Activision proposed with Epic
Speaker 5:  and with the company that makes Clash of Clan super solid, they would start
Speaker 5:  their own app store on Android, it would be Steam for Android. And they called
Speaker 5:  this project Boston and they were running it with one track and they had
Speaker 5:  another track with Google that was just give us a hundred million dollars
Speaker 5:  and we won't do this. And Google just paid them the money
Speaker 5:  because they don't want competition for their app store and Android. And
Speaker 5:  they're, you know, you can, we'll link our story, there's all these emails
Speaker 5:  about it and whether they're really gonna do it and whether Google is really
Speaker 5:  afraid of it, but Google paid them the money to foreclose
Speaker 5:  the competition. And that there's just a lot of that in this case
Speaker 5:  because there are so many companies in the Android ecosystem that
Speaker 5:  are trying to get leverage over one another. And Google's sitting in the
Speaker 5:  middle of it. And you can put that right next to, hey,
Speaker 5:  you know, apple Maps is pretty good lately, right? Like Apple
Speaker 5:  had to build a competitor to Google Maps for all kinds of reasons and they
Speaker 5:  made a really good one. And there's a lot of conversation lately about how
Speaker 5:  it is superior to Google Maps. And I think if you live in the right places,
Speaker 5:  particularly for driving directions for turn by turn vastly superior to
Speaker 5:  Google Maps. I
Speaker 6:  Agree. It's really good now.
Speaker 5:  Okay, well if Apple wants to make a competitor a Google product, they can
Speaker 5:  definitely do it. Yeah. And they definitely have the install base to do it
Speaker 5:  and Google does not want that to happen to search and pays Apple the money.
Speaker 5:  And you can put that right next to Blizzard said, we might start an app store
Speaker 5:  and Google said, eh, we don't want you to do that. Pay them the money. And
Speaker 5:  we're just, I I I don't want to tell you like, I think most people
Speaker 5:  think that the world they live in is not done by
Speaker 5:  handshakes and backroom deals. Or maybe they do now Maybe it, gen Z
Speaker 5:  is wiser to the waist of
Speaker 7:  The, they all watch, they all watch Hamilton's. So they all, they all know
Speaker 7:  the
Speaker 5:  Is it Hamilton or Suits?
Speaker 7:  Both. It's,
Speaker 5:  It's, if you wanna know how the world works,
Speaker 6:  Two of the two shows,
Speaker 7:  Those are the two shows core to the your internet. No, I think, I
Speaker 5:  Think there has been,
Speaker 5:  at least on the internet, the idea that the internet is, is democratizing
Speaker 5:  that the distribution is free and open and equal.
Speaker 5:  And then you get to these app stores and you get to these mobile platforms
Speaker 5:  and that has instantly broken down. Yeah. So read that
Speaker 5:  on the site. It is, it's great. Really, really illuminating coverage about
Speaker 5:  how all the stuff works. And then when, when the trial's over, we will
Speaker 5:  have Sean on and he can synthesize what he's learned. but it is like
Speaker 5:  gleeful coverage from the courtroom from Sean. It is very,
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah, this one a great time. The USV Google was so locked
Speaker 6:  down and so redacted and so carefully
Speaker 6:  in everything that anyone revealed about anything. This one is the opposite.
Speaker 6:  They're just like, everybody is just throwing signed contracts like into
Speaker 6:  the wind every morning in the courtroom. Like you really get the sense the
Speaker 6:  discovery process here has been a, a joyful one for a lot of people. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I'm really just bummed. I haven't come up with an idea that Google will pay
Speaker 7:  me not to do.
Speaker 6:  Honestly, it really feels like if you just go like park your car
Speaker 6:  in Google's parking lot and just start going, maybe I'll open an app store.
Speaker 6:  Someone will just like fire a money cannon into your car. Yeah. Up until
Speaker 6:  you drive. Let's head out. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You know what's, what's interesting about that point David is, you
Speaker 5:  know, USV, Google, the United States government doing an
Speaker 5:  antitrust case, they need to be buttoned up. They were in a very buttoned
Speaker 5:  up courtroom. The United States government right now does not have a great
Speaker 5:  history of pursuing these cases or a lot of pressure on them. They're making
Speaker 5:  a very complicated argument about search lockin Epic is just like
Speaker 5:  f go fuck yourselves. Yeah. Like straight up like that is
Speaker 5:  Tim Sweeney's attitude towards about this is a moral mission for him as well
Speaker 5:  as an economic one. And then you have the ecosystem
Speaker 5:  that is never happy with these players and
Speaker 5:  a constant looking for every little ounce of leverage. And you can, you're
Speaker 5:  right, the tenor of this case is very different. Yeah. Because Epic has
Speaker 5:  already gone, they have nothing to
Speaker 6:  Lose. Right. You get the definite sense that even if they lose, they're prepared
Speaker 6:  to lose having landed a bunch of punches against
Speaker 6:  Google. And that is, that is pretty clearly the
Speaker 6:  tactic here. And so far I think it's working like don don't know if they'll
Speaker 6:  win the case, but boy have they made Google look bad over and over and over
Speaker 6:  here.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. What's interesting to me, just as a person who looks at how our website
Speaker 5:  is doing is when they're up against Apple, like every
Speaker 5:  one of our stories was a hit. And here we're with, with Google,
Speaker 5:  like with the evidence that the store, like there's shenanigans
Speaker 5:  afoot and we, we have to sell the stories a little bit harder. And
Speaker 5:  I, I think that just speaks to honestly how many people have iPhones versus
Speaker 5:  how many people care about how Android works. But I will remind you that
Speaker 5:  Android is the most used operating system on the planet. And how Google manages
Speaker 5:  it affects basically how computing is done. Yep. And so like
Speaker 5:  all these little shenanigans have like massive downstream effects across
Speaker 5:  the entire Android ecosystem because if Google stops making money in this
Speaker 5:  way, their case for making Android, the open source
Speaker 5:  operating system goes a little sideways. So
Speaker 5:  I'm like I said, you should read Sean's cover. It is very fun. I enjoy catching
Speaker 5:  up on it every day. This is why we invented story streams with like the quick,
Speaker 5:  like it's all happening. And then we, we will have Sean at the
Speaker 5:  conclusion on trial, which should be soon. I think we'll have Sean on set
Speaker 5:  to to talk about it. Yeah. All right? We have gone long. I gotta go throw
Speaker 5:  rocks at a triangle,
Speaker 6:  But not too hard.
Speaker 5:  NE's about to get arrested. I'm watching the social video team make comparison
Speaker 5:  videos of the metal ball versus the baseball. It's a very good Go on
Speaker 5:  TikTok and look at that. Thank you to everybody who's been posting about
Speaker 5:  your Spotify Wrapped with The Vergecast and with Decoder. We love it.
Speaker 5:  We've also got a lot, a lot of emails from people sh telling us about Spotify
Speaker 5:  Wrapped, which is great. We love it. Our hotline episode next week.
Speaker 5:  David's buying advice.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, we're doing a whole, we got a bunch of questions kind of organically
Speaker 6:  from people who are like, I'm trying to figure out what to buy or I'm trying
Speaker 6:  to buy this thing or this thing. So we're gonna do a whole bunch of those.
Speaker 6:  We're just gonna grab a bunch of folks and sit around and try to help people
Speaker 6:  buy stuff for the holidays. So if you have holiday questions, email us
Speaker 6:  Vergecast at virgin.com, which you can do about all of your feelings in general,
Speaker 6:  but also buying questions or call the hotline. Eight, six, six version
Speaker 6:  one, one. Send them all in. We're gonna answer a whole bunch of 'em on next
Speaker 6:  Wednesday show.
Speaker 10:  Love it. All, right? That's it. That's Vergecast McElroy.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The Vergecast is
Speaker 1:  a production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. The show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. This episode was mixed and edited by
Speaker 1:  Xandr Adams. And that's it. We'll see you next week.