# Transcript
ID: 261ec529-8a63-40e6-b115-bdd29d948d95
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Everything you’ve always wondered about The Vergecast
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6931258428677461879/5013698335768521312/s93290-US-4054s-1698231352.mp3
Description: The Verge's David Pierce, Nilay Patel, and Alex Cranz dedicate the show to talk about their feelings. The crew answer a bunch of questions from listeners about The Vergecast, The Verge website, and the future of it all.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of The Vergecast. I'm
Speaker 2:  your friend David Pierce, and I am currently in, I believe it's called Murphy
Speaker 2:  Tyson Airport in Knoxville, Tennessee. We just had a long weekend of
Speaker 2:  family time and Dolly Parton related shenanigans, and at one point I drank
Speaker 2:  blueberry Blackberry wine, which I have a lot of thoughts about. But now
Speaker 2:  we're headed home and that means it's about to be flight number two for our
Speaker 2:  10 month old. Flight number one actually went pretty well, which I assume
Speaker 2:  means this one is going to be a total disaster. So to anyone who's listening
Speaker 2:  who may have been on this flight with us, just know that I'm very sorry.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, we have an awesome show coming up. We've asked over the last few
Speaker 2:  weeks people to send us questions about The Verge and The Vergecast, and
Speaker 2:  you've sent in some awesome ones. Thanks to everybody who called the hotline
Speaker 2:  and everybody who sent us emails, we got questions about how we run The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast, how we think about the stuff that we cover, what gear we use,
Speaker 2:  what Neli is like as a boss. Spoiler alert, the worst, but we'll get to
Speaker 2:  that. It's a super fun show. It's a weirdly odd thing
Speaker 2:  to spend all this time talking about yourself. It was kind of a fun exercise
Speaker 2:  for the three of us to do, along with Liam and Angel, our producers. So again,
Speaker 2:  thanks to everybody who's sent in questions. This is super fun. All of that
Speaker 2:  is coming up in just a sec, but first I gotta go get on this plane. Wish
Speaker 2:  me luck and maybe even more so wish luck to everyone sitting within six rows
Speaker 2:  of us. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Support for The Vergecast comes from Quest three, the new mixed reality headset
Speaker 3:  from Meta. The new Meta Quest three lets you expand your worlds in ways you
Speaker 3:  never thought possible. It's their most powerful quest. Yet Meta sent me
Speaker 3:  one to try and I was so amazed by how easy it was to set up
Speaker 3:  with the Quest three. You can live in the action. You can feel what it's
Speaker 3:  like to step into the shoes of an assassin and Assassin's Creed nexus.
Speaker 3:  Play a part in your favorite show, like Stranger Things, or even turn your
Speaker 3:  couch into court side seats for your favorite NBA team. It's easy to dive
Speaker 3:  into whatever you're into, fitness, social apps, or a fully immersive gaming
Speaker 3:  experience. For over 500 titles, check out the Meta Quest three now
Speaker 3:  available for 4 99. Learn more@meta.com. See child
Speaker 3:  safety guidance online accounts for 10 years or older. Certain apps, games
Speaker 3:  and experiences may be suitable for a more mature audience.
Speaker 3:  How you show up on social is important and your name is perhaps the most
Speaker 3:  important of all. So don't take username unavailable for an answer.
Speaker 3:  Take control with a dot. Social web address.social is a
Speaker 3:  domain extension that does something really special. It gives you one consistent
Speaker 3:  name you can use across emerging social networks like Blue Sky
Speaker 3:  Macon and more. Learn more at name.com/social
Speaker 3:  and use the code Verge 25 to get 25% off your first year
Speaker 3:  of your.social web address. That's name.com/social
Speaker 3:  because you should be you no matter where you go.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back All, right? I made it. Home Flight went pretty well, thanks
Speaker 2:  to some well-timed PB and J sandwiches. I picked up a cold along the
Speaker 2:  way, but we're here. I'm in the studio. Neli and Alex are here
Speaker 2:  with me. Let's get into it. Neli Patel. Hello. Hello,
Speaker 2:  Alex Cranz. Hello. Hi. This is the day we
Speaker 2:  talk about the first cast, which we never normally do. We're not obsessed
Speaker 2:  with ourselves or our own podcast at all. But today people
Speaker 2:  ask us questions about the show, about The Verge. We got an
Speaker 2:  alarming number of questions asking if Neli is a good boss, which we're gonna
Speaker 2:  come around to. I don't know what people think or what to make of that,
Speaker 2:  but we got that question a number of times. So we're gonna come to that.
Speaker 2:  But basically, just so you guys know, I have set this up in such a way that
Speaker 2:  we got a bunch of questions about The Vergecast, which we're gonna answer.
Speaker 2:  Then we're gonna take a break. Then we got a bunch of questions about The
Speaker 2:  Verge, which we're gonna answer. And then we got a bunch of questions about
Speaker 2:  just like our feelings about the future. So I figured that's a good thing
Speaker 2:  to end on. That's good. So we'll end with that. So let's just dive right
Speaker 2:  in. You guys ready? Let's do this. Yeah. All, right? The first one we have,
Speaker 2:  this one's from Alex
Speaker 4:  Neil as a good boss.
Speaker 5:  Hi, this is Alex from Falls Church Virginia. I wanna say I
Speaker 5:  love Vergecast, I love decoder. I've learned a lot from you all
Speaker 5:  and laughed along with you all. And. what I wanna know is, David
Speaker 5:  Pierce has said a few times or there have been jokes about how much David
Speaker 5:  Pierce hates decoder. And I wanted to know
Speaker 5:  is, does David Pierce actually hate decoder? Is this a running joke?
Speaker 5:  Did I miss something in an early podcast about this? So I? I just
Speaker 5:  am curious about the history about how and why David
Speaker 5:  Pierce hates decoder. Thanks very much. I look forward to
Speaker 5:  hearing your response.
Speaker 4:  I wanna know the answer to this question too.
Speaker 2:  The beauty of this is, this will be quick because yes, I absolutely hate
Speaker 2:  decoder. No, I love decoder and I actually, a thing we have talked about
Speaker 2:  a bunch recently is how to sort of bring our
Speaker 2:  podcasts closer together and do more stuff together like Neli.
Speaker 2:  I'm curious from your perspective, I don't hate decoder, but I think one
Speaker 2:  of the funny challenges of decoder and The Vergecast is that you are on both
Speaker 2:  of them. Yeah. And I know for a fact that you spend a lot of time
Speaker 2:  trying to figure out what goes where on our many, many two
Speaker 2:  podcasts, So, I think the ongoing question for me is like, how
Speaker 2:  do these two shows differ from each other? Especially given the fact that
Speaker 2:  one of the hosts is the same person. So
Speaker 4:  The the the top line is a decoder is a business show and
Speaker 4:  The Vergecast is a product show, a tech product show that is not
Speaker 4:  actually a good guideline. Everything is the same thing on our show.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like I on decoder, I ask people what the products they make. I think
Speaker 4:  that's the most important and interesting and illuminating way to get
Speaker 4:  to the heart of like what a executive does. Like
Speaker 4:  if you're an executive and show decoder, you can't talk about your products.
Speaker 4:  Like I I know a lot about you as an executive. Yes. On the flip side, and
Speaker 4:  I think this is actually more important, it's funny that David jokes about
Speaker 4:  how much he hates decoder. We have only recently talked about bringing those
Speaker 4:  shows together. And I actually recently said to David that I had been
Speaker 4:  waiting for someone else to have that idea
Speaker 4:  because if I did it then I'm just munging everything together. Sure. And
Speaker 4:  when David came back and we were expanding The Vergecast, I I wanted to make
Speaker 4:  sure The Vergecast had a lot of space to grow into the next version of
Speaker 4:  itself, especially with David hosting the second episode. I think that's
Speaker 4:  done. I don't know, David, you you tell me, but it was your idea the other
Speaker 4:  day when you, when you said that to me, So I think that process is done.
Speaker 4:  And I do think we should, we can start talking about the interviews on decoder
Speaker 4:  more running this, clips more like using that the same way that we use
Speaker 4:  the other journalism on the site to enhance this show. 'cause it's, it's,
Speaker 4:  it's right there. I I don't think there's any particular reason that they
Speaker 4:  need to be so far apart, except you tell me. I think the character I play
Speaker 4:  on decoder is a little different than the character. I, I am on the Vergecast,
Speaker 4:  which is much more like myself, You know on decoder. It's, it's, it's a game.
Speaker 4:  It's a game that executives can try to win, which is, are you good at your
Speaker 4:  job?
Speaker 2:  I do like every time I start a decoder episode and I hear you doing the intro,
Speaker 2:  I'm like, oh, it's business Neli.
Speaker 4:  Like it's, it's,
Speaker 2:  It's like grownup Neli is the one who runs decoder and Bonkers Neli is
Speaker 2:  the one we get on The Vergecast. It's great. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Decoder Neli wears a tie.
Speaker 2:  Exactly.
Speaker 4:  But yeah, I, I, I think, I just think we've hit a pretty natural point in
Speaker 4:  the evolution of both of these shows where there's no reason to keep 'em
Speaker 4:  apart. I think it's very funny to have fake beef and we'll keep doing that
Speaker 4:  forever.
Speaker 2:  I do hate decoder, just to be very clear.
Speaker 6:  Decoder is the worst.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So that's, yeah, that's a good one. I think in general, like as we
Speaker 2:  grow our podcast universe, the big question for me is like how do you do
Speaker 2:  all that in a way that is cool but also like rewards people for listening
Speaker 2:  to everything? 'cause the thing that I hate, and there are podcasts out there
Speaker 2:  that I will not name that do this, is like they have shows that are essentially
Speaker 2:  just like compilations of other shows. Yeah. And so you're like, the more
Speaker 2:  I engage with you, the less it feels like it's worth my time
Speaker 2:  And. what I really don't wanna do is that where it's like if you've listened
Speaker 2:  to decoder and then you listen to The Vergecast, it's just like decoder again
Speaker 2:  or vice versa. Yep. I think that's very bad. But if we can find ways to put
Speaker 2:  those things together that like make sense and are good,
Speaker 2:  I'm all
Speaker 4:  For it. Also, the point is to like grow, right? Like not in a rapacious
Speaker 4:  capitalistic way, but it's like find new audiences and like be service to
Speaker 4:  them. And if we're all, if we just make more Vergecast or
Speaker 4:  it's all decoder, we're actually not gonna grow. Like the things need to
Speaker 4:  be different so they can go attract different groups of people. And that
Speaker 4:  that's always just sort of on my mind. Like, are we just making more of the
Speaker 4:  same thing or are we actually making different products for different customers?
Speaker 4:  That's like the most decoder thing I've ever said. I'm gonna quit now.
Speaker 2:  Neil. I just put the tie on as he was saying. All. right. Let's get to the
Speaker 2:  next one. This is an email from James, which I'm using as kind of a proxy
Speaker 2:  for a bunch of emails. We got all on roughly the same subject.
Speaker 2:  James says, over time there have been a number of comments about Neli using
Speaker 2:  an SLR for his webcam, but I don't think he's ever given the details of that
Speaker 2:  setup and how he runs it. I'd love to know more of those details as I'm thinking
Speaker 2:  about how I might set up a better remote setup at home than just me sitting
Speaker 2:  in front of my computer. And the question we've gotten from a bunch of people
Speaker 2:  is just how, what gear do you use when you sit down to record
Speaker 2:  the podcast? They've asked this question about all three of us Neli. I think
Speaker 2:  you talk about it the most. And also you have that weird camera that hangs
Speaker 2:  down in front of your computer. So you've gotten it the most. So why don't
Speaker 2:  you start just like you're in the studio right now, but when you're at home,
Speaker 2:  you also just moved. So you're rethinking this. What is, what is the Neli
Speaker 2:  Patel home studio setup like right now? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  First I want to point out that David and Alex have gone through
Speaker 4:  just an incredible array of camera setups. Oh yeah. Yeah. Just the
Speaker 4:  most over complicated overthinking
Speaker 4:  software dependent. That's
Speaker 2:  Accurate.
Speaker 4:  Like at one point Alex Trans is like, You know what? I'm gonna hinge my career
Speaker 4:  on Sony software. That's a real choice that she attempted to make. I'm still
Speaker 6:  Here though.
Speaker 4:  It's true. We've survived. I'm just saying in the background of me
Speaker 4:  doing the dumbest thing, they're like overthinking it. So my setup
Speaker 4:  is super dumb. I am rethinking it 'cause we just moved and I, I've got some
Speaker 4:  new dedicated space to, to to monkey with, but it is
Speaker 4:  Sony's ZB ones. I use them both as the webcam for my meeting camera
Speaker 4:  at work and is the camera for the podcast setup. So it's a ZB one, they're
Speaker 4:  mounted on arms, they're fed into HDMI capture cards. That's
Speaker 4:  it. And I turn them on and it is a hardware solution
Speaker 4:  that looks good
Speaker 2:  Other than being expensive. That sounds like a pretty straightforward
Speaker 2:  setup. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  What I wanna get to is a setup at home that
Speaker 4:  looks as much like the look that we have in the studio. So it's
Speaker 4:  not jarring to the audience. Depending on where I am, this is
Speaker 4:  much more of a big deal for decoder because we're subject to other people's
Speaker 4:  schedules. So I, just wanna make it look like no matter where I am
Speaker 4:  or where we're doing a show, the look is the same. So that's kind of on my
Speaker 4:  mind as we, as I build up my new space, but sort of as a pandemic
Speaker 4:  panic purchase. Like I need a webcam that looks good. The ZV one was perfect
Speaker 4:  in its moment. Now they're onto the ZV two. I bet you could find new ZV ones
Speaker 4:  are cheap, but there's a bunch of Sony menus you gotta dig through and and
Speaker 4:  settings and da da da da da. It is not happy doing this all the time. Sometimes
Speaker 4:  it overheats and you gotta put it in different one whatever. You can get
Speaker 4:  it to a place where it just reliably serves as a webcam when you turn it
Speaker 4:  on. And all of that is hardware and not software. And I
Speaker 4:  cannot convince these two to stop using software.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. All, right? Alex go. What's yours? Okay.
Speaker 6:  The one I'm currently using Bulletproof for the last
Speaker 6:  two, two weeks so far is the, the
Speaker 6:  Insta 360 link. Oh
Speaker 4:  Yeah. This is very popular in our reviews team. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Liam sent it to me because my last camera was the
Speaker 6:  Opal C one and it kept overheating and turning off during the recordings,
Speaker 6:  which was the theme for all of my cameras thus far. So we'll see how the
Speaker 6:  Insta 360 link does. But the, the Sony Sony
Speaker 6:  Imaging webcam was my original and it was plugging into
Speaker 6:  a Sony A seven three and it did not, did not do the
Speaker 6:  job very well.
Speaker 2:  The combination of old camera bad software is really just,
Speaker 6:  It was really bad. Well then I got like, I, like Peter was onto me and he
Speaker 6:  was like, just go get a cord and I got a cable. But unfortunately
Speaker 6:  it still would overheat constantly because the Sony A seven three is not
Speaker 6:  meant to be on no. Continuously shooting for an hour at a time. So
Speaker 6:  yeah, now I'm on that and I, I rock a seven or an SM
Speaker 6:  seven B Sure mic. Just the old fancy standard. It's very
Speaker 6:  fancy. It used to run into an MO two M two but there
Speaker 6:  was a terrible buzz periodically that no one could figure out
Speaker 6:  why it started or would stop and fine. Our audio
Speaker 6:  producer said Stop it and sent me a scarlet
Speaker 4:  They sent you the other entry level Yeah. Interface that no one likes
Speaker 2:  Alex has steadfastly refused to stop using her stupid hardware and
Speaker 2:  software. So I love it. Many times over the last 12 months we're like, Alex,
Speaker 2:  stop using the weird Nvidia thing. And she's like, no, I want to use the
Speaker 2:  weird NVIDIA
Speaker 4:  Thing.
Speaker 6:  It should work. Damn it,
Speaker 4:  It should work. By the way, what I'll tell you if if you go out to buy AUSB
Speaker 4:  to htm I capture card, you, you think they're all the same. They're not.
Speaker 4:  So you're not, you instinctively refuse to pay for a name brand. You'll go
Speaker 4:  on Amazon and be like, I could spend $20 in the name brand one or I could
Speaker 4:  spend seven on the alphabet soup brand. And there's a difference. I
Speaker 4:  just promise you there's a difference. Once you're like find yourself troubleshooting
Speaker 4:  like one UB dongle for three weeks, you're like, oh I should've just
Speaker 4:  spent this month. My time is worth infinitely more than $23.
Speaker 4:  And I, I'm not telling you that that happened to me, I'm just, I'm warning
Speaker 4:  you against an outcome
Speaker 6:  Hasn't happened to anyone on this show.
Speaker 2:  Do you guys ever feel like it's a miracle we actually successfully make a
Speaker 2:  podcast? Everything?
Speaker 2:  My setup is actually very similar to Alex's. I think I've been through an
Speaker 2:  even longer series of insane webcam ideas. I also had
Speaker 2:  an opal for a long time and then I got so annoyed with the Opal. I went back
Speaker 2:  to the Logitech C nine 20 that everybody has, it doesn't look very
Speaker 2:  good but It works really well. I had a long run of using
Speaker 2:  my phone as my webcam with the camo app, which is
Speaker 2:  wonderful. The only downside, which
Speaker 4:  Was hilarious because we couldn't text David, we couldn't send, he couldn't
Speaker 4:  use his phone while we were podcasting, which
Speaker 2:  Is on one hand like useful that it forced me to pay attention to meetings
Speaker 2:  more, which was good. But the other part is like you're just constantly
Speaker 2:  rigging up and de rigging your webcam, which is very annoying but it looked
Speaker 2:  really good. Worked super well. So if you just like have a second phone lying
Speaker 2:  around, that's a great idea. But yeah, I'm also now on the Insta 360.
Speaker 2:  It works fine. I occasionally accidentally turn on the auto tracking and
Speaker 2:  it just follows me around my room, which creeps me out. But that's the best
Speaker 2:  part. Other, other than that, no complaints. It works pretty well. Webcams
Speaker 2:  are not as good as they should be is my overarching takeaway.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, you just buy a Sony ZV one, you put it on an arm, you mount the arm
Speaker 4:  at a ba eye level and you look down the barrel and everyone's like, what
Speaker 4:  magic are you doing? And it's like, I spent $500. That's the magic.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So do you have it? You have it in front of your computer screen?
Speaker 4:  So I have two. I have two setups 'cause I, I need to have physical
Speaker 4:  distance between podcasting mode and work mode. So I've got
Speaker 4:  the 2015 iMac, which is the podcast rig. And on that one the arm
Speaker 4:  comes down over in front of the screen. So I can have my notes
Speaker 4:  behind the camera, but then I can just like look down the barrel of the lens
Speaker 4:  and it, because it's a 27 inch screen, you can kind of just like make it
Speaker 4:  all work. And then on the sort of like the Zoom setup, I've got
Speaker 4:  my delightful Samsung Curve TV off to the side. It is actually great
Speaker 4:  for this purpose and the camera is on an arm and it's right in the
Speaker 4:  middle of that display. Got it. So I'm kind of just like always looking.
Speaker 4:  It looks like I'm looking at people and then I have my laptop there and that
Speaker 4:  that, I don't know if that is, I don't know if that's gonna persist. That
Speaker 4:  was like a, I made it during the pandemic and I convinced myself it was good.
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 6:  Mean It works except for whenever there's someone directly behind your camera.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And you're like, I got everybody and one person
Speaker 4:  And I forget the one person in the Zoom square. If you're listening to this,
Speaker 4:  the Google Meet team is listening to this. Make it So. I can block out the
Speaker 4:  middle square So I can put the camera in front of it like
Speaker 2:  The free space on the bingo card. Just
Speaker 4:  Block that. I just, just leave one square blank.
Speaker 2:  Alright, let's move on. This one we're just gonna do, because we get this
Speaker 2:  all the time and we should answer it on the show Again,
Speaker 2:  this is an email we got from George that says, it's been a while since I
Speaker 2:  heard why you all don't do chapters. Figured I'd see if you all are using
Speaker 2:  the same reason. If it's not possible with your current contract, are you
Speaker 2:  all considering moving to another service? Please let me know who I should
Speaker 2:  be directing my inquiry to and I would bug them. People are so
Speaker 2:  mad that we don't have chapters in the audio version of this podcast. Liam,
Speaker 2:  our lead producer, Liam, do you wanna come answer this question? I'd like
Speaker 2:  you to answer this question.
Speaker 7:  The answer is that we use megaphone
Speaker 7:  product owned by Spotify. I think a vast majority of
Speaker 7:  large publishers use them because it allows us to manage
Speaker 7:  our advertising inventory effectively. Unfortunately
Speaker 7:  it does not support chapters is crazy and
Speaker 7:  something we've talked to them about many times and we are promised that
Speaker 7:  it is coming soon. But thus far we have not gotten that feature.
Speaker 2:  That answer is both true and complete and fills me with rage.
Speaker 2:  Surprising that Spotify is not a terrific place to listen to podcasts. Who
Speaker 2:  would've thunk? Yeah, that. I just wanted to get that outta the way. It is
Speaker 2:  real. We would like to do it. Chapters are great. They're so
Speaker 2:  good and I wish we had them and someday we will. And that will be, that will
Speaker 2:  be a great day. Alright, let's move on to the next one. We have a question
Speaker 2:  from Dennis. Dennis's question is, ever since the last redesign of The Vergecast,
Speaker 2:  I was wondering if you could tell us more about the new jingle. I really
Speaker 2:  dig it and maybe you could give some insights into the process of creating
Speaker 2:  this. Also, if you could publish a full version somewhere, I could really
Speaker 2:  see myself listening to it on its own. Mila, you really led this. You wanna
Speaker 2:  talk about the jingle?
Speaker 4:  So we were just rethinking how everything looked and we'd been using the
Speaker 4:  same theme, which I believe Josh Polsky just like made on his computer in
Speaker 4:  2011. And it's great. We love it that I I, we should
Speaker 4:  use it again. Classic Vergecast theme. One thing about things people like
Speaker 4:  is if you take 'em away for a while and you bring 'em back, people get really
Speaker 4:  excited. So I'm always thinking about that with our logos, with our themes,
Speaker 4:  all that stuff. Yep. But you gotta refresh and update. And we were launching
Speaker 4:  the second episode and sometimes the stuff you make just isn't, can't get
Speaker 4:  big enough. Like we didn't have enough stems. We didn't have enough like
Speaker 4:  bits and bobs to extend the show the way we needed to. So we went out to
Speaker 4:  Breakmaster Cylinder who also did the decoder theme. And it was amazingly
Speaker 4:  fun working with them. And we, the only note I will give is we did a bunch
Speaker 4:  of rounds. We, it's built on the old theme so you can hear it's the same
Speaker 4:  pieces of music. And I just kept giving notes that I wanted it to
Speaker 4:  sound more like fascination Street by the Cure. And at some point Breakmaster
Speaker 4:  Cylinder was like, oh I get it, you want a rock song? And I keep making hip
Speaker 4:  hop songs and that was the, like the Heavens Burst
Speaker 4:  open. And then we had the theme. But the real piece of it, the real
Speaker 4:  important part of it was we needed something that was much more flexible
Speaker 4:  so we can make all the new kinds of shows that we were setting out
Speaker 4:  to make.
Speaker 2:  So speaking of that particular reboot, another question we got
Speaker 2:  was from Rafael and essentially says, I love the new
Speaker 2:  art formats and especially sound design. The podcast got, it's easy to relate
Speaker 2:  it to David's comeback, but I think it would be interesting to hear from
Speaker 2:  you how that went. If you have any other plans coming and your thoughts and
Speaker 2:  feelings in general, which is a very vague question, but I think generally
Speaker 2:  it's like we're we some point decided like we're gonna reboot The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast a bit and the the sort of impetus for that happened before I got
Speaker 2:  here. So like rewind, I don't know, 18 months we'd
Speaker 2:  been doing the show for 11 years at the time.
Speaker 2:  What was the conversation like that it was like, let's change what this thing
Speaker 2:  is a bit.
Speaker 4:  Well there are two things. One Dieter had just left. So
Speaker 4:  there was a big conversation about like how will we do this?
Speaker 4:  Will Neli just rant about USPC for one hour a week? Will that, is that an
Speaker 4:  acceptable show? Will that make us any money? Is that a good use of time?
Speaker 4:  The answer is no. I think very obviously. No. And so when I went to see if
Speaker 4:  David wanted to come back to The Verge, the thing I said was host The. Vergecast
Speaker 4:  like it is a big property. People care about it a
Speaker 4:  lot. It needs a lot of focused attention from someone who gets it.
Speaker 4:  And David was like, yes. And then five minutes later he showed up. So that
Speaker 4:  was like a big part of it was like if you're gonna change the host, you're
Speaker 4:  gonna change the show. The other part of it, which is the business part of
Speaker 4:  it is that the show is successful. And so our company
Speaker 4:  wants more of it all the time. Just an infinite amount of
Speaker 4:  Vergecast and You know the, the dynamic there. The tension there is, I don't,
Speaker 4:  I don't think everybody like, I don't think the audience wants an infinite
Speaker 4:  amount of Vergecast. So it has to be really good and we have to like put
Speaker 4:  a boundary on how much we're gonna do. 'cause there's You know our effort
Speaker 4:  has to be sustained. So I think that's, that's it. Like I think
Speaker 4:  we're at a moment where we have the Friday show, which is like loose and
Speaker 4:  I think David once called them like the DVD liner notes of The Verge. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And it's like really good. And then we have the Wednesday show, which
Speaker 4:  is much more focused and and narrative. And I think that is a really good
Speaker 4:  dynamic between those two episodes. I can see a world in
Speaker 4:  which we do something every day. I just dunno how to do it.
Speaker 2:  Like literally logistically.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. It's, it's like the, the bits and bobs of like who will go
Speaker 4:  where when we used to do it, we used to do 90 seconds on The Verge, I remember
Speaker 4:  this. That required us all to be very young and
Speaker 4:  mostly unmarried and have no children.
Speaker 4:  And hammered like also it required like an infinite amount of booze to pull
Speaker 4:  that off all the time. And some very dedicated people who are like fully
Speaker 4:  in startup mode if we wanna do that again. And I, I, I suspect we
Speaker 4:  should. I think we just have to build some systems. And I don't know that
Speaker 4:  that should be The Vergecast, but I that's like, I'm, I'm saying all this
Speaker 4:  stuff but I think we've all talked about it loosely. This is as specific
Speaker 4:  as we have ever been about this idea. Like where could we go?
Speaker 2:  Alex, you kind of came into The Vergecast in the middle of that
Speaker 2:  transition, right? What was that like?
Speaker 6:  It was kind of exciting and also alarming and terrifying
Speaker 6:  mainly to like come in with Neli and Dieter who are really, really,
Speaker 6:  really good at this. And I think like 90% of my early episodes I
Speaker 6:  don't say anything 'cause I'm just watching them and like studying
Speaker 6:  them the whole time.
Speaker 4:  No, no one understands that this is a test. It's like you have to talk and
Speaker 4:  if you don't talk and then it's not gonna
Speaker 6:  Work. And then it'd be like, oh God, I gotta talk, I gotta say something.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And so like trying to figure that out, trying to figure out like what
Speaker 6:  are the things I want to talk about on the show and, and make kind of part
Speaker 6:  of my character on the show. It was a lot of work and it was a lot of like
Speaker 6:  thinking about it and and talking with Dieter about it and and figuring it
Speaker 6:  all out. And then David came and was like, David, hello guide me. And
Speaker 6:  it was great.
Speaker 2:  Then I screwed everything up for you again. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You ruined everything. So thanks a lot.
Speaker 2:  I think the way you describe it, at least from my perspective, Neli, I was
Speaker 2:  pretty much about right. It was like, we want more Vergecast, come do it.
Speaker 2:  And I got a text from Dieter on my first day who was like,
Speaker 2:  You know good luck if you ruin The Vergecast, I'll kill you. Like in in
Speaker 2:  those words, in that order is what he said. And I sincerely hope I have not
Speaker 2:  ruined The Vergecast. I'm trying very hard to ruin it every single day. But
Speaker 2:  I don't think we've gotten quite there yet.
Speaker 4:  Success is right on the edge of ruining it. Oh yeah. That's the thing about
Speaker 4:  the show that no one quite understands. Agreed.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we have one more about The Vergecast and then
Speaker 2:  we're gonna take a break. This is from Ben and it's my favorite voicemail
Speaker 2:  we've gotten recently.
Speaker 8:  Hey, this is Ben. Oh really a question. Just wanna let Neli
Speaker 8:  know that pop up the volume is currently streaming on Max.
Speaker 8:  Alright. Have a nice day.
Speaker 2:  That's all you need to know about the first cast.
Speaker 4:  It's very, it's very important information. So I think that we should do
Speaker 4:  a, like a watch party of this movie. The problem is that the movie
Speaker 4:  was made a while ago. There are, there are topless people
Speaker 4:  in it. There are some ideas in it that maybe don't hold up.
Speaker 4:  I would love to do this watch party. I just think we all have to sign contracts
Speaker 4:  agreeing that we know what we're getting into together before we begin.
Speaker 4:  But I'm promise you the scene and pump up the volume where
Speaker 4:  Christian Slater is driving around in his girlfriend's Jeep broadcasting
Speaker 4:  a pirate radio station while the FCC chases him in little vans.
Speaker 4:  That is as clear a statement of the editorial mission
Speaker 2:  Of The the verges I can give you that is what we do here.
Speaker 2:  There you go. That's all you need to know. And if somebody would like to
Speaker 2:  remake that scene playing The Vergecast as the underlying audio and send
Speaker 2:  that to me, it would, it would make us very happy. Vergecast Verge dot com
Speaker 2:  All right? We're gonna take a break and then we're gonna hang back and we're
Speaker 2:  gonna do some ER questions. We'll grab
Speaker 3:  Support for this show comes from Wix web agencies. You're gonna like this
Speaker 3:  one. Let me tell you about Wix Studio. The platform that gives agencies total
Speaker 3:  creative freedom to deliver complex client sites while still smashing
Speaker 3:  deadlines. How? First, let's talk about the advanced design capabilities.
Speaker 3:  With Wix Studio, you can build unique layouts with a revolutionary grid
Speaker 3:  experience and watch those elements scale proportionally by default. No code
Speaker 3:  animations at sparks of delight while custom CSS gives total design
Speaker 3:  control, but it doesn't stop there. Bring ambitious client projects to life
Speaker 3:  in any industry with a fully integrated suite of business solutions from
Speaker 3:  e-comm to events bookings and more and extend the capabilities even further
Speaker 3:  with hundreds of APIs and integrations. And You know what else? The
Speaker 3:  workflows, they just make sense. There's the built-in AI tools, the
Speaker 3:  centralized workspace, the on canvas collaborating, the reuse of
Speaker 3:  assets across sites, the seamless client handover. And that's not all. Find
Speaker 3:  out more at Wix dot com slash studio.
Speaker 9:  Support for this show comes from American Express business.
Speaker 9:  Resourceful small business owners know how to get value from the purchases
Speaker 9:  they already make for their businesses each month. That's why the
Speaker 9:  enhanced American Express Business Gold Card lets you earn up to
Speaker 9:  $395 in annual statement credits on
Speaker 9:  eligible business purchases at select shipping, food delivery, and retail
Speaker 9:  subscription merchants. The Amex Business Gold Card now
Speaker 9:  smarter and more flexible. That's the powerful backing of
Speaker 9:  American Express enrollment required terms apply.
Speaker 9:  Learn more@americanexpress.com slash business Gold
Speaker 9:  Card
Speaker 2:  All. right, we're back. So the second category of questions we got was about
Speaker 2:  like The Verge in general and Neli I think in particular. A
Speaker 2:  bunch of these are more for you as You know the boss,
Speaker 2:  but we got a bunch of good ones. So let's just dive in. First one is from
Speaker 2:  John Paul.
Speaker 10:  Hi, this is John Paul and I have a couple of questions for the meta episode
Speaker 10:  you guys have said is coming up. First question, can you tell me how The
Speaker 10:  Verge is structured for someone who likes org chart so much? What, what's
Speaker 10:  the org chart look like and why did you set it up that way? Also, what's
Speaker 10:  The Verge relationship with Vox? How is it structured within the larger
Speaker 10:  organization? Also, similar question. You are on a pretty big
Speaker 10:  newsroom and you make lots of decisions. Can you tell me how you make decisions?
Speaker 10:  What's your decision making framework? These questions might sound a little
Speaker 10:  familiar. Looking forward to hearing your answers. Bye.
Speaker 2:  I wish you all could see the smile on Mila's face right now. This is gonna
Speaker 2:  be the longest Vergecast of all time.
Speaker 4:  Your children have grown up to hoist you on the, on your own guitar. That
Speaker 4:  is the phrase. It's like, oh no, I did it to myself. Let's
Speaker 2:  Just do it in order. So the the first question is, how is The Verge structured?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think The Verge is structured, it's like a high performance
Speaker 4:  Montessori. Like my goal for The Verge is everyone just does whatever they
Speaker 4:  want and it's awesome. So we are structured to enable that
Speaker 4:  and that's like a very top blind thing. But basically we have desks,
Speaker 4:  right? We have a reviews desk, we have a policy desk, we have a creator's
Speaker 4:  desk that ladders into like just very top
Speaker 4:  line subjects like Jake Kakis is our tech editor.
Speaker 4:  It's basically by, by subject matter expertise is how we are structured.
Speaker 4:  And you can look at our mass set, you can see how that goes. Then next to
Speaker 4:  that we have audio and video, which is a format. So then we have
Speaker 4:  like a format specific division basically. And that's because
Speaker 4:  the tools and the processes and the cadences of that work
Speaker 4:  are different than the newsroom in text. Those are the two sort of
Speaker 4:  axes that I think about is our features program runs on like
Speaker 4:  a year long cadence. And so they're thinking on very different timelines
Speaker 4:  than our news team. And so in the formats we have to manage
Speaker 4:  different cadences and then we need to make sure that we have subject matter
Speaker 4:  expertise through all of that. And that is like you might
Speaker 4:  surmise that I enjoy messing with our org chart because those things are
Speaker 4:  intention. So you're, I like we are just always kind of like rebalancing
Speaker 4:  how that works and thinking about it. But those are the two things just
Speaker 4:  operationally that we have to manage. Like how long it takes to make something
Speaker 4:  and then how much you need to know to make the thing and like where that
Speaker 4:  knowledge get concentrated and then how those timelines should be managed.
Speaker 2:  Alex, you're the person who spends all of your days like making all of that
Speaker 2:  work.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, Alex is the actual managing editor. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I was like, I was like, I've memorized the org chart, I can list every single
Speaker 6:  person and who they report to at at The Verge. I don't know
Speaker 6:  if I should have that information in my head, but there it is.
Speaker 2:  Does that structure make sense to you? Like is you, you're sort of operating
Speaker 2:  that structure day to day. Does that, does his description feel right to
Speaker 2:  you? Yeah, yeah
Speaker 6:  It does. I think like having different mediums is really,
Speaker 6:  they, they function totally differently, right? Like, like how the ideation
Speaker 6:  works, how the timeline to getti things up works is totally, totally different.
Speaker 6:  So you kind of need a little bit of separation there, but then you also have
Speaker 6:  to make sure they overlap enough and they communicate enough that like good
Speaker 6:  conversations are happening and you don't have like somebody writing
Speaker 6:  a story and somebody doing a podcast that they are the exact same thing,
Speaker 6:  doing 'em in parallel without talking to each other. And so
Speaker 4:  This is especially hard remote. Yeah, I would say.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So it's like constant, constant communication. But yeah, I think,
Speaker 6:  I think it makes sense and it's helpful to like, like I have like the big,
Speaker 6:  like the deputy editors and I go talk to the deputy editors and figure things
Speaker 6:  out. But then I also know, okay, I can drill down, I can go to
Speaker 6:  down to a desk editor, I can go down to, to a staff writer that reports up
Speaker 6:  to them and and get those details. And so it kinda like trickles down like
Speaker 6:  that. And It works really well. Yeah, I
Speaker 4:  Think my goal is that again, everyone just does whatever they want. There's
Speaker 4:  a moment about a year into a new Verge
Speaker 4:  reporter's tenure where like they learn how to play the piano and
Speaker 4:  they're like, I can just do anything. And that's like, that's all that structure
Speaker 4:  is designed for that, for that moment to happen. 'cause that's the best.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. And I think the, the like eternal struggle of the Virgin in
Speaker 2:  every organization is how to like that overlap. You're talking about Alex
Speaker 2:  where it's like how do we, how do we do really great stuff at
Speaker 2:  like the speed of the news business and also how do we, like when do you
Speaker 2:  take the moment where it's like, okay, I'm gonna go disappear for six months
Speaker 2:  and do this story even though there's constant news all the time. And
Speaker 2:  Nila, your immediate instinct is always just like news run faster, run faster,
Speaker 2:  run faster in so many ways. And it's really good in some ways. But it's also
Speaker 2:  like as The Verge has gotten bigger, figuring out how to do that and do all
Speaker 2:  the other stuff we have to do at the different speeds at which they happen
Speaker 2:  is like every newsroom's kind of constant struggle. 'cause like
Speaker 2:  things keep happening.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And,
Speaker 2:  And you, you can be reactive to it forever and that works and you have to
Speaker 2:  do that. But also there's other stuff we wanna do that isn't just run as
Speaker 2:  fast as the news cycle all the time.
Speaker 4:  Well, I'll give you one very specific example that I think for chess
Speaker 4:  listeners will deeply understand news and reviews operate on
Speaker 4:  different timelines like they just do to review a product. Well you have
Speaker 4:  to just fall into it. Like you have to pay attention to it for a significant
Speaker 4:  period of time and then you can like put out a good product review that takes
Speaker 4:  longer than writing the news. However, we have competitors that have
Speaker 4:  solved this problem by totally divorcing their news and reviews operations.
Speaker 4:  The reviewers never write news. The news reporters never write reviews. And,
Speaker 4:  what you get is a bunch of reporters who have
Speaker 4:  never used the products, who just don't understand the products and a bunch
Speaker 4:  of reviewers who have, who are writing reviews as though the news
Speaker 4:  is not happening. And like we talk about this, we've talked about this since
Speaker 4:  the beginning of The Verge. Like we see these other places that do this.
Speaker 4:  We don't ever wanna do that. The problem is that as you get bigger and you
Speaker 4:  wanna review more things and write more news, there's a reason that they
Speaker 4:  split those things up. Like there's a totally rational,
Speaker 4:  explainable, deeply understandable reason why you would pull those teams
Speaker 4:  apart because they, they need to run in different directions and different
Speaker 4:  timelines. We're just insistent about smashing them together so
Speaker 4:  that our reviews read as though they take place on the same
Speaker 4:  planet except everyone lives on. Yeah. And our news reporters
Speaker 4:  understand that you can't just assume that tech companies can
Speaker 4:  make every decision perfectly because they're actually using the products
Speaker 4:  and they're aware of the trade-offs that are inherent to like building any
Speaker 4:  product. And that I think is, that's what we do here. But
Speaker 4:  it after a while you're like, oh, this is the problem that I've signed up
Speaker 4:  to manage forever. Like the job is actually just this problem. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. And I think you, you've kind of halfway answered this already,
Speaker 2:  but John-Paul did ask about how you make decisions, which is the decoder
Speaker 2:  question. So answer the damn decoder question Neli.
Speaker 4:  So if you listen to decoder and you listen to people and ask this question,
Speaker 4:  some people are not prepared for it, which is very funny. Like just immediately
Speaker 4:  the funniest thing to me, like how do you not know this is coming? And then
Speaker 4:  there's like four or five variations and I am very much on the Amazon end
Speaker 4:  of that variation, which is you just need to divide up your decisions
Speaker 4:  into things that you can quickly undo and have low stakes and things that
Speaker 4:  have high stakes. And you need to make the low stakes decisions as fast as
Speaker 4:  you can and be ultra decisive about them.
Speaker 2:  That's the one-way door and two-way door strategy. Right? That's that's how
Speaker 2:  they talk about it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Or it's a type A and type B decision or type one and type two. And I always
Speaker 4:  forget which one's which. But yeah, there's the two-way door. You can just,
Speaker 4:  you can just go back and do it again. And then there's the like, oh this
Speaker 4:  is an existential important and So I try really hard to
Speaker 4:  make is to everyone's chagrin. I'm like, we should just do this all the time.
Speaker 4:  But I think that's really important for a newsroom. I think the challenge
Speaker 4:  is for a newsroom, a thing like a headline or an image choice or like, those
Speaker 4:  are actually one-way doors. You don't get to go back like your credibility's
Speaker 4:  on the line. So you have to build a set of instincts about that stuff that
Speaker 4:  I think is just hard fought and you need a lot of scar tissue.
Speaker 4:  But we are very blessed to have a large group of people that has honestly
Speaker 4:  worked together for a very long time comparatively to any
Speaker 4:  media organization and So I think there's, there's sort of a collective intelligence
Speaker 4:  about what The Verge is that allows us to make those decisions very quickly.
Speaker 2:  Do you wanna say anything about the Verges relationship with Vox before we
Speaker 2:  skip onto our next person? We're a
Speaker 4:  Pirate ship. I, I dunno what they do. Here we go.
Speaker 4:  It's a very honest, and our CEO has said this, like, for us, our audience
Speaker 4:  moves faster. It's a tech audience. It moves faster than a general news audience
Speaker 4:  or whatever. Our audience is younger than everybody else. This is a true
Speaker 4:  thing. I think the only, only polygon singer to us, we have been given the
Speaker 4:  opportunity to, to run as fast as we want in, in the directions that we wanna
Speaker 4:  run it. And that's honestly great.
Speaker 2:  And speaking of one of those changes, here's our next voicemail from Austin.
Speaker 11:  Hey Bridge cast. This is Austin from Seattle. I got a question,
Speaker 11:  what has the emotional journey been like while y'all transition to
Speaker 11:  WordPress? Thanks. Hope to hear from you.
Speaker 2:  This is why I love Vergecast people, right? Like they understand that this
Speaker 2:  is an emotional journey and it has been one, how,
Speaker 2:  how do you guys feel about it? This hasn't happened yet. It's still very
Speaker 2:  new, but we know it's happening. Y'all have been on chorus a lot longer
Speaker 2:  than I have. How are you feeling?
Speaker 4:  I feel joy. I feel nothing but joy.
Speaker 6:  A hundred percent. Yeah. Like Chorus is exceptional,
Speaker 6:  right? It's it's an exceptional CMS I've used a lot
Speaker 6:  of CMSs. There was one where you couldn't use that I used where you couldn't
Speaker 6:  use the same image twice like ever. You would have to like ever.
Speaker 6:  So you'd have to like upload it flipped or like slightly
Speaker 6:  cropped. It was so dumb. That was horrible. And, and, and Chorus
Speaker 6:  has been really, really great. But I'm excited for WordPress. Like
Speaker 6:  that's where I first started. That was like my very first website that I
Speaker 6:  went and put on the web and and blogged on was a WordPress site. Yeah. And,
Speaker 6:  and I'm excited to go back there
Speaker 4:  To be clear it's joy because like we haven't yet gone on the first date.
Speaker 4:  We're just looking forward to it. You know.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's like the anticipation we're like, ooh, yeah, what's
Speaker 4:  Gonna happen? But like fundamentally a lot of ideas that we have
Speaker 4:  are bottlenecked by the limitations of having to build our own
Speaker 4:  proprietary software. So there's a lot of things I wanna do. For example,
Speaker 4:  clicking more stories at the bottom of our homepage that should just infinite
Speaker 4:  scroll, right? It should obviously just infinite scroll. We either
Speaker 4:  have to re-architect our own CMS and its API
Speaker 4:  to enable that. Or a million people have solved this problem or a press already.
Speaker 4:  And So I. I'm just excited about that. I'm excited about being able to trade
Speaker 4:  on a ecosystem like a huge software development ecosystem
Speaker 4:  and instead point our development resources at user
Speaker 4:  experiences. 'cause ultimately the media stopped trying to
Speaker 4:  compete with platforms and user experience. And I think that's take a look
Speaker 4:  around and we, we should try. So like that's, that's where the joy comes
Speaker 4:  from is, oh, why is our development effort pointed at a database and a word
Speaker 4:  processor like
Speaker 2:  Solve the problem's worth solving.
Speaker 4:  We should build user experiences. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I agree. I think everyone I've talked to is like deeply nervous because
Speaker 2:  we're a bunch of nerds who are like extremely attuned to the user experience
Speaker 2:  of the products that we use. And like we just got an email that we're about
Speaker 2:  to switch to the new slack and everyone is terrified. And so there's like
Speaker 2:  a lot of that energy in the WordPress transition too, that it's like we're
Speaker 2:  all sort of used to the good and bad things about Chorus, which is
Speaker 2:  a very good piece of software. We've been on it for a very long time. Like
Speaker 2:  the it's the devil You know and the devil you don't, right? But I, I do think
Speaker 2:  being open to like the entirety of the WordPress ecosystem is going to be
Speaker 2:  super, super cool and there's all kinds of stuff we can do.
Speaker 4:  And then we haven't even talked about Activity Pub yet, like,
Speaker 2:  Oh, we're getting to that. Yeah. Don't you worry. The last question is just
Speaker 2:  four hours of Neli ranting about Activity Pub. So don't worry. Alright, let's
Speaker 2:  get to our next one, which comes from Charlotte.
Speaker 12:  Hi, my name is Charlotte. You guys talk a lot about other
Speaker 12:  journalists and other publications such as TechCrunch
Speaker 12:  and it seems like people move from The Verge to TechCrunch, et cetera,
Speaker 12:  all over. What's it like being friends with
Speaker 12:  your competitors and how do you kind of balance that work and
Speaker 12:  having to compete with them and also still being friends and collaborating.
Speaker 12:  Thanks, bye.
Speaker 6:  They're our enemy. We don't collaborate.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, David's moved around the most. Yeah, so you should answer this one.
Speaker 2:  I think it's hard to explain, but really easy in
Speaker 2:  practice. Like I, I both love a lot of the people who work at a lot
Speaker 2:  of other publications and absolutely earnestly want to kick their ass to
Speaker 2:  every story all the time. And I understand that there is like
Speaker 2:  cognitive dissonance there, but it's just true. And I think part of it is
Speaker 2:  also like this part of journalism is
Speaker 2:  relatively small. Like even the way that we think about tech,
Speaker 2:  everybody covers tech now. It's all over the place. It's huge in a way that
Speaker 2:  like in 2011 it was not right. Like it, the, the world of people who cared
Speaker 2:  about tech the way that we do is much smaller then it's still pretty small
Speaker 2:  now. Like there are a lot of people who cover these companies as big businesses.
Speaker 2:  There are a lot of people who cover them from like varying different
Speaker 2:  perspectives. But in this space of like people who cover
Speaker 2:  technology as technology, it's very small and having like
Speaker 2:  a bunch of other nerds around to talk about this stuff with is just
Speaker 2:  always fun. And there's so much to do in this space that I feel
Speaker 2:  like I, I probably feel less competitive than I should sometimes.
Speaker 2:  But at the same time, like we, we just see each other all the time in a way
Speaker 2:  that you don't in a lot of businesses, right? Like yeah, when companies do
Speaker 2:  investor events, they don't have like hundreds of reporters that they
Speaker 2:  make stand in a room for hours drinking coffee before they go
Speaker 2:  see the, like quarterly earnings be unveiled. But we do that, we see all
Speaker 2:  these people at Apple events, we see them all at, at Google events. We see
Speaker 2:  them a bunch of times a year and we're just all talking about the same stuff
Speaker 2:  every day. So it's like natural. I think that you build a real like
Speaker 2:  kinship with these people and there's only like six publications. So we've
Speaker 2:  all worked together at one point or another. Yeah. We've,
Speaker 4:  We've killed most of the others. I want to be clear, we are soaked in blood,
Speaker 4:  we are smiling and blood drips down our fangs.
Speaker 4:  It wasn't us though, it was the, the larger, but it is true that our early
Speaker 4:  competitive set has been winnowed way, way, way down.
Speaker 4:  And that You know that I don't, I don't love that. I actually, we talk a
Speaker 4:  lot about needing great competitors because that, that's what keeps us
Speaker 4:  sharp and respecting your great competitors and being friendly with them
Speaker 4:  does not negate the fact that you feel competitive with them. Like in,
Speaker 4:  in like big ways. I would say this, like the power of The Verge over the
Speaker 4:  past decade has been, it's graduating classes. Like
Speaker 4:  we've graduated a lot of people out into a lot of publications,
Speaker 4:  most notably Bloomberg now. Like Bloomberg is just like Verge Midtown.
Speaker 4:  Like you just go, it's just a bunch of people we know. And so like that's
Speaker 4:  great. Like I, I like being the place where
Speaker 4:  people get good You know and like can go on and do other things. I like being
Speaker 4:  the place where when our competitor publications look for leadership and
Speaker 4:  that's like the thing I like graduating at. I like graduating at senior people
Speaker 4:  and editors and leaders. I think that's just a good cycle. Like I I, the
Speaker 4:  earlier question where I was like, the main thing I think about is our culture.
Speaker 4:  Like that's what the culture develops and then all obviously all those people
Speaker 4:  are still very friendly with us, but we call 'em expats. Like they're still,
Speaker 4:  they're still The Verge. I, there's a lot of power in this world. I always
Speaker 4:  joke with David that I have a theory of true power and it's like, by the
Speaker 4:  end of this we'll just run every publication. That's the goal.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's a hundred percent it. Yeah. The, the The Verge diaspora is a
Speaker 2:  like extremely cool and increasingly powerful group of people.
Speaker 2:  It's pretty awesome.
Speaker 4:  The editor of Wired, by the way is a Verge expert. I just wanna put that
Speaker 4:  out there in the world.
Speaker 2:  We're taking over. It's what we do.
Speaker 4:  That's like a, and Katie's great and she, that has nothing to do with her
Speaker 4:  Verge history. Like she's just great. If you had told us in 2011 that that
Speaker 4:  would be the direction I would've never believed you. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Alright, next one. I, this is an email we got from Paul
Speaker 2:  that says, I think the casual reader at The Verge might assume the staff
Speaker 2:  are all very heavy tech users, constantly scrolling and getting notifications
Speaker 2:  from multitude of apps, upgrading the flip phones and MacBooks frequently.
Speaker 2:  But listening to the show, it seems like quite the opposite. Neli has mentioned
Speaker 2:  he blocks almost all notifications from his phone and that he removed apps
Speaker 2:  with endless feeds. David mentioned before becoming a father that he wanted
Speaker 2:  to avoid becoming a tech dad. I'm curious what views the rest of the team
Speaker 2:  has that may be counterintuitive for people who spend so much time thinking,
Speaker 2:  writing, and talking about tech. I guess what I'm asking is who is the biggest
Speaker 2:  Luddite at The? Verge, which a is a very good question and BI think the,
Speaker 2:  the sort of underlying question here is basically like, are you
Speaker 2:  still a bunch of tech nerds who just love tech all the time? Wait,
Speaker 4:  Can I reject the premise of this question? Sure. Is that allowed? I mean,
Speaker 4:  I, I love you for listening and I love you for asking. I appreciate that
Speaker 4:  you're asking. I I just don't think I agree with the premise that being a
Speaker 4:  heavy user of tech requires you to have your notifications on.
Speaker 4:  Okay.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right. Like I, I think that this is actually a, a thing that gets conflated
Speaker 4:  like quite a bit. Like I am an intense user of technology. I will,
Speaker 4:  I spent my train ride to the office today reading about matter, adaptive
Speaker 4:  lighting upgrades, like that's where I'm at in life. You know what I
Speaker 4:  am selfish about And. what I'm not a heavy user of is like
Speaker 4:  unfiltered garbage information and like mostly what, what people
Speaker 4:  think of as tech products. Like just provide that to you like a, a nonstop
Speaker 4:  flood of garbage. And like, I would say that the the power
Speaker 4:  user move is to use the tools in the way that these companies do not want
Speaker 4:  you to use them and turn 'em all off and then only take what you want. And
Speaker 4:  what I want is for home kid adaptive lighting to be compatible with
Speaker 4:  matter, which it is not at this time. You're
Speaker 2:  A simple man of simple needs.
Speaker 6:  It's not, it's really brutal.
Speaker 4:  You can disagree with me. I think that's totally fair. But I I think there's
Speaker 4:  a, there's a thing in there, right? Which is like, are you a Luddite? 'cause
Speaker 4:  you don't have all your notifications turned on. And it's like, no, I just,
Speaker 4:  I just don't need people to interrupt me. I'm busy You know, like I'll take
Speaker 4:  information on my terms, You know and I'm a in the news, so my terms are,
Speaker 4:  I want a lot of it. I just want to be focused. Most of these
Speaker 4:  platforms like Elon Musk is just like mask off with Twitter, right? He's
Speaker 4:  like, my focus is keeping you on the platform. I'm taking the headlines away.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, oh, I don't, I don't care about what you think. Like I'll,
Speaker 4:  I'm turning off your notifications. You can't have me. That to me
Speaker 4:  feels like more of a power user move. Like, maybe I'm wrong, maybe everyone's
Speaker 4:  gonna disagree with me, but that I would just, that's the turn I would make.
Speaker 6:  I think you're right. Like I think the power user move is to figure out which
Speaker 6:  bits you actually want to use and use them and incorporate them into your
Speaker 6:  life in a really like satisfying way. And I would say the majority of
Speaker 6:  the staff does that. Like not everybody has the newest phone or, or
Speaker 6:  the newest laptop, but they have figured out a workflow that is
Speaker 6:  deeply profoundly nerdy and, and, and made
Speaker 6:  that work. And I think that's kinda like the core of The Verge is finding
Speaker 6:  those solutions that work for you. And it doesn't necessarily mean that you
Speaker 6:  have to have every single app constantly filtering things
Speaker 6:  in or you have to be like, like for the longest time I thought the real tech
Speaker 6:  nerd was the person who mastered rain meter on windows.
Speaker 6:  Like that was it for me. And I think that is like, there's, there's definitely
Speaker 6:  tech nerdery to it, but it's not like the only part. And and,
Speaker 6:  and everybody's a different type of tech nerd. I know people who are super
Speaker 6:  into phones and have no idea what matter, like how to use matter, what,
Speaker 6:  what the process there is. And I have friends who are super into their home
Speaker 6:  theater systems to an alarming degree and they
Speaker 6:  have like a six year old phone. Everybody's got a different kinda love of
Speaker 6:  tech.
Speaker 2:  I do think there, there was a long period of tech where there were like a
Speaker 2:  small number of things to be really into. And so it was like, I mean you,
Speaker 2:  you rewind whatever 40 years and the only thing to be into was like PCs,
Speaker 2:  right? So you were just like, and then, and then we got You know it expanded
Speaker 2:  a little and then there were like phones and everybody's really into phones.
Speaker 2:  And now it's like, if you wanna be super weirdly into some
Speaker 2:  line of tech, there are a billion to choose from. And I feel like what,
Speaker 2:  what's been fun about The Verge is watching everybody sort of pick their
Speaker 2:  thing, right? It's like, it's like being a, it's like being really into movies.
Speaker 2:  You end up sort of picking a thing that you care about more than everybody
Speaker 2:  else and wanna talk to everybody else about, even though they don't care.
Speaker 2:  And like that's The Verge with tech. We all have things that no one else
Speaker 2:  caress about that we do. And that's the prerequisite of working here.
Speaker 4:  Like I said, everyone's just doing whatever they want. Yeah, yeah. No, I
Speaker 4:  will talk your face off about building. I I need to build a new
Speaker 4:  home theater rig for the new house. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Every time Neli brings up Dolby Atmos, that's when I just like, turn off
Speaker 2:  my microphone and walk away for a few minutes of the podcast.
Speaker 4:  At this point Dolby's like, come to the office. Just come here. Just
Speaker 4:  by the way. But can I just answer that question Rick? It's Liz Lato. It's
Speaker 4:  the biggest sled I've ever
Speaker 6:  Oh, a hundred percent
Speaker 4:  Friend of The Verge, Brian Merchant who has written for us. We've exerted
Speaker 4:  his previous books. He's got a new book out, by the way, about the history
Speaker 4:  of Luddites And, what they were actually after. And it's like mind
Speaker 4:  blowing when the book comes out, we'll like have him on or something. It's
Speaker 4:  great. Alright,
Speaker 2:  One more before we take a break. This is from Will Get Ready.
Speaker 13:  Hey, this is Will in San Diego. A two part question. Is
Speaker 13:  Neli a cool boss and does he give
Speaker 13:  nice back rubs? All. right? Thank you.
Speaker 4:  Well, it's 2023 sir. No bosses should have given back rubs legally
Speaker 2:  We cannot answer that Second question.
Speaker 4:  I'm, I'm out here being like, I don't know if I can watch pump up the volume
Speaker 4:  with these people.
Speaker 2:  I will say we got this question a lot, which makes me think we should like
Speaker 2:  actually try to answer it. The
Speaker 6:  Back rubs
Speaker 2:  Question, not the back rubs question. Will's the only one who wondered about
Speaker 2:  the back rubs. Will, whatever that says about you, we'll, we'll come back
Speaker 2:  to that. But the, is Neli a good boss question is when we actually got a
Speaker 2:  lot So Alex, I think we should attempt to answer this as earnestly and honestly
Speaker 2:  as possible while
Speaker 4:  I'm here.
Speaker 2:  While Neli is here, we're gonna, this is,
Speaker 4:  Well Neli is about to not be a very good boss. I'll tell you that one.
Speaker 6:  Neli is an exceptional boss.
Speaker 2:  I will say it. The question was not Is he a good boss? It's is he a cool
Speaker 2:  boss? Subtly? Oh yeah. All, right? We did get good boss, but I like Cool
Speaker 2:  boss as a question more.
Speaker 4:  No, I'm like cool boss. You should, you should just drink at home so you're
Speaker 4:  safe.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Neli and I have had like meetings about stuff while having a drink.
Speaker 6:  It's great. Like who doesn't love a drinking working meeting?
Speaker 6:  It's wonderful. I think that's the definition of a cool boss.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's literally the definition of the cool mom from mean girls. I just
Speaker 4:  wanna be
Speaker 6:  Clear that too, that too,
Speaker 2:  I think the, the way I always describe Neli as a boss is that if you
Speaker 2:  want to be as chaotic as Neli wants you to be,
Speaker 2:  he is the best boss in the world. If, if Neli gets bored,
Speaker 2:  it's a problem. So
Speaker 4:  Then
Speaker 2:  This is true in all things bored. Neli is a dangerous Neli. This is why we
Speaker 2:  get worried when Neli iss like on a flight with no wifi. Like bad things
Speaker 2:  happen when, when Neli has five hours to sit and think by himself.
Speaker 2:  The
Speaker 6:  Ideas are always great that come out of those flights.
Speaker 2:  There's always a Google doc. It's terrifying. But I think to me, one of the
Speaker 2:  things that is like fun about having you as my boss Neli, is that
Speaker 2:  you're like forever trying to do bigger,
Speaker 2:  weirder different things. Like I have worked at places that are very much
Speaker 2:  like, here is what we do and our job is to keep doing it. And I understand
Speaker 2:  why that's good and valuable and it has just like never been what like excites
Speaker 2:  me day to day to just like keep doing my job every day. And I
Speaker 2:  feel like every three weeks Neli shows up and is like, what if we just did
Speaker 2:  everything super differently just to see what happens? And that's like, it
Speaker 2:  is never boring with Neli is your boss, it's chaos.
Speaker 4:  This is horrible. But it's, this is like having someone write your resume
Speaker 4:  in front of you. I I cannot tell you how much I dislike this
Speaker 2:  Neela. Do you think you're a good boss? Cool
Speaker 6:  Boss. Cool boss. Cool.
Speaker 4:  You are definitely, I'm definitely a cool boss. Yeah. Which means drunk.
Speaker 4:  I just wanna be clear, which means a lightly sauced. I've been watching a
Speaker 4:  lot of Mad Men clips on TikTok. I've got a, I've picked up a bunch of ideas.
Speaker 4:  I don't know, I try really hard to be a good boss. I I, some days
Speaker 4:  I'm much worse than other days. The only thing that I
Speaker 4:  can measure that against is how confident our most junior
Speaker 4:  people are. Like, I don't worry about David. David's gonna tell me to fuck
Speaker 4:  off. Like it's fine. And we have a lot of people on our staff who've been
Speaker 4:  with us for a long time who are very confident in telling me what to do and
Speaker 4:  that's great and I love them and cherish them. What I am always
Speaker 4:  thinking about is the youngest, most junior person on our staff and
Speaker 4:  how far along they're on the road to playing the piano and being able to
Speaker 4:  do whatever they want. And if they are unsure or they are
Speaker 4:  unclear or they are not confident, like we,
Speaker 4:  the whole organization is fucked up, the culture's fucked up. I dunno if
Speaker 4:  that's like the right measure. I don't know if I should measure like page
Speaker 4:  views instead or like whatever. But that's, that's the thing I've been focused
Speaker 4:  on and and the reason I'm always trying to blow everything up and I really
Speaker 4:  am always trying to blow everything up is like the media industry is a disaster
Speaker 4:  so we should probably try to invent a new one. Right? And and again, we've
Speaker 4:  been given the license to go try to do it and along the way you've gotta,
Speaker 4:  you've gotta, I I just want the virtue to be a place where I would wanna
Speaker 4:  work You know and like there's not a lot of places that like as evidence
Speaker 4:  by the fact that I've been here for a decade, not a lot of places I wanna
Speaker 4:  work. That's it. That's what I dunno. I dunno if that's the right answer.
Speaker 4:  This is horrible. I wanna die is really the answer. I'm like full body cringing.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we have a couple more quick ones. Let's take a break. We're gonna
Speaker 2:  do the last couple and then we'll get outta here. We'll
Speaker 15:  Good evening, I'm Noah Hassenfeld and there have been hundreds of reports
Speaker 15:  recently of orcas doing strange things to boats
Speaker 16:  Around the world. Killer whales are attacking boats. We lost both
Speaker 16:  Rogers 30
Speaker 17:  Orcas responded in moderating a killer Whale off twos
Speaker 17:  authorities are warning sailors to immediately,
Speaker 15:  But the question is, is this a coordinated series of
Speaker 15:  attacks or is it something else?
Speaker 18:  They have these fads and rims and it's important for them
Speaker 18:  to be part of the group and to show that by yeah, we're all
Speaker 18:  doing this stupid thing together. All that is culture
Speaker 15:  This week. Un unexplainable. Do whales have culture
Speaker 15:  and if so, how might that explain this mysterious kind of
Speaker 15:  behavior? Follow unexplainable for new episodes every Wednesday
Speaker 19:  To all my podcast enthusiast, it's your boy Andrea Alala.
Speaker 19:  Alongside my co-host Evan Turner.
Speaker 20:  We're not just any podcast where former NBA players with a story to
Speaker 20:  tell. Get ready to step into a world of captivating stories, insightful
Speaker 20:  conversations, and thought provoking discussions. With our podcast point
Speaker 20:  forward,
Speaker 19:  We're talking to some of the most successful people in all facets of life.
Speaker 19:  That's right. My people point forward isn't just about sports, it's
Speaker 19:  about life growth and the journey to success.
Speaker 20:  We're talking about how to chop wood and carry water,
Speaker 19:  Then filtering it. And we're not just asking questions, we're asking the
Speaker 19:  right questions.
Speaker 20:  So if you want to gain valuable insights, learn from some of the most successful
Speaker 20:  people in the world and enjoy entertaining and thought provoking conversations.
Speaker 20:  24 is a podcast for you.
Speaker 19:  Don't miss out on the wisdom, the humor, and the secrets to success
Speaker 19:  that we plan to share with you.
Speaker 20:  Make sure you subscribe now to 0.4 to lock in
Speaker 2:  All. right, we're back. Next question. Tell us the top worst 10 things about
Speaker 2:  Neli. As a opposed
Speaker 2:  no. Let's, we're we're gonna, we're gonna hard pivot away from that too.
Speaker 2:  We have two, I think sort of bigger picture questions about how we think
Speaker 2:  about tech and The Verge and the future. So we're gonna do those before we
Speaker 2:  get outta here. Here's the first one from Santiago.
Speaker 21:  Hey Verge team, this is Santiago from Orlando. I want to ask, how has
Speaker 21:  your role in editorial stand shifted from the start of The Verge to today
Speaker 21:  as we're more conscious of the possibility for technology misuse And how
Speaker 21:  have you seen your coverage on AI evolve as the product is more broadly
Speaker 21:  used and becomes more integrated in everyday technology? Love the show.
Speaker 21:  Thanks for everything.
Speaker 2:  I included this question because this is literally a conversation we have
Speaker 2:  been having internally about how we think about tech
Speaker 2:  now. Like I look back to 2011 and, and Neli, the thing you used to always
Speaker 2:  say is one of the things we do at The Verge is we pedal hope that like the
Speaker 2:  world can get better and technology is part of that. And that one
Speaker 2:  of the things we do is try to point people at what a better world looks like.
Speaker 2:  Does that hold 12 years later with everything we know about what
Speaker 2:  technology is and does and all the bad things we've seen in the last 12 years?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think So I think we saw hope. Fundamentally we report on other people
Speaker 4:  working really hard, right? I mean that's, the phone gets, well hopefully
Speaker 4:  the phone gets a little thicker than the battery. Life gets longer, but You
Speaker 4:  know the phone gets thinner, the screens get bigger, they get brighter, the
Speaker 4:  networks get faster. To what effect, who knows? But that dynamic right,
Speaker 4:  that I'm describing is a lot of people have to work really hard to put capabilities
Speaker 4:  into the world and to give you new tools. I think that is good. I i
Speaker 4:  like the most important thing is that is a positive feedback loop that
Speaker 4:  like we invent things and we try hard and like there's a,
Speaker 4:  there's an earnestness to that that I never wanna lose sight of. The other
Speaker 4:  side of it is, well we made five G networks and we spent a lot of money and
Speaker 4:  why did we do anything good with it? Has anything good happened? Is there
Speaker 4:  a robot surgery? And I think that is the side that the rest
Speaker 4:  of the media has focused on and obviously we've, we've layered a lot of
Speaker 4:  that into our coverage too, especially with social networks and things like
Speaker 4:  that. It's weird that you that it is easier and faster to lie than
Speaker 4:  ever before. Should we have built those capabilities? Should we have stopped
Speaker 4:  ourselves? May maybe. And those are societal questions. So I think in
Speaker 4:  2011 that was our thesis, right? Like, oh the world because of phones
Speaker 4:  in particular, the world is on the cusp of a massive change and we should
Speaker 4:  have a publication that like technology is culture, tech, culture, that whole
Speaker 4:  thing. All that stuff we said over a decade ago is now everything
Speaker 4:  it, everyone gets it. And so our differentiation I think is not
Speaker 4:  taking it for granted. The other line I always use is it's fun to be smart.
Speaker 4:  You know, like we spend a lot of time just like thinking about stuff like
Speaker 4:  our show our audience. That's why it's big 'cause there's actually way
Speaker 4:  more people out there that wanna spend their time deeply thinking about
Speaker 4:  these things than not You know. I would say that when I think about
Speaker 4:  our differentiation in the media landscape, a lot of people take it for granted.
Speaker 4:  They just take it for granted that these are problems or these are trade-offs
Speaker 4:  or you can come to other solutions or even that it is fun to be smart about
Speaker 4:  them. That being a, it's like too nerdy or too weedsy and it's like, no
Speaker 4:  actually you can walk up to any person on earth and ask them about their
Speaker 4:  phone and they will tell you something deeply nerdy. Like it is
Speaker 4:  a, an absolute unifier that this technology exists and people have emotional
Speaker 4:  relationships with it and you can take it seriously. So I, I think
Speaker 4:  it's You know many things have happened since we launched The Verge. Many
Speaker 4:  things continue to happen. AI is when I say it's easier to lie than ever
Speaker 4:  before. Oh boy do I have thoughts? But the flip side of it is like, well
Speaker 4:  people, a lot of people have to work really, really hard to make
Speaker 4:  these things and we should not take it for granted. And that like just
Speaker 4:  in and of itself is like I to me is still a hopeful idea.
Speaker 2:  Alex, one of the things you and I talk about, I feel like half our Slack
Speaker 2:  dms are, we're covering this cool thing that exists and like AI is actually
Speaker 2:  the perfect example of this right now. Now it's like this cool new thing
Speaker 2:  that exists that You know OpenAI just launched Dolly three and look at all
Speaker 2:  the wild stuff you can do. How many paragraphs do I have to
Speaker 2:  write about all the awful things that can be used here? Does every story
Speaker 2:  about AI need to mostly be about the bad possibilities and the
Speaker 2:  side effects and the, and the things we haven't had when we cover meta? Do
Speaker 2:  we need to re-litigate all the bad things that meta has done over the years?
Speaker 2:  Like how do you talk about this stuff in a way that is both
Speaker 2:  like hopeful and realistic and honest and
Speaker 2:  self-aware? Like do you feel like you and we have cracked that
Speaker 2:  yet? I
Speaker 6:  Think it kind of hinges on the fact that one, we, we care about this stuff
Speaker 6:  and we're really passionate about it and and our readers are passionate about
Speaker 6:  it. Our writers are passionate about it and, and we're, we're covering it
Speaker 6:  every day. Like if you're only covering AI once a year, then
Speaker 6:  you really do have to re-litigate things because your audience may not be
Speaker 6:  familiar with it, but our audience is typically pretty familiar with what's
Speaker 6:  going on. So we don't need to be like, oh remember that time? Like rehash
Speaker 6:  everything that meta's done. That's awful. We all know they've done a lot
Speaker 6:  of awful stuff. We can spend a line being like, Hey, by the way,
Speaker 6:  meta did something awful once six years ago and continue on. Right? Like,
Speaker 6:  like we could, we, we don't have to reeducate people. And I
Speaker 6:  think that's something that a lot of publications like can kind of fall into
Speaker 6:  the trap of of wanting to re-litigate things, wanting to
Speaker 6:  really focus on on the crummy stuff and the crummy stuff is crummy and we
Speaker 6:  need to talk about it, we need to write about it. But there's also really
Speaker 6:  useful things and beneficial things and I think what we see with AI is kind
Speaker 6:  of similar to what we saw with deep fakes where there was a lot of panic
Speaker 6:  around deep fakes because oh my God, it's gonna change everything. And yeah,
Speaker 6:  it does change things and it does demand better literacy from from
Speaker 6:  audiences but at the same time it does a lot of really cool stuff. It
Speaker 6:  enables a lot of really fun stuff. And as long as you find that balance and
Speaker 6:  remember that and, and it doesn't go into like supervi land
Speaker 6:  then then it's fine. AI's a little trickier 'cause it is so
Speaker 6:  easy to lie with ai. But it does a lot of really cool stuff.
Speaker 6:  Like one day I'm not gonna have to schedule all my meetings. AI will do it
Speaker 6:  for me and I cannot wait.
Speaker 2:  Neil, I will never have to use software again because of AI
Speaker 4:  Software is the worst hardware only. That's the new Verge.
Speaker 4:  No software
Speaker 2:  Coverage. No, I think that's right. And I think like to the point about You
Speaker 2:  know it's fun to be smart is like being alive right now means holding a lot
Speaker 2:  of competing ideas in your head about what's good and what's bad and what's
Speaker 2:  safe and what's problematic and how much you should care about your privacy
Speaker 2:  versus all the cool stuff that exists. Like the goal I think is just to engage
Speaker 2:  all of that as honestly as we can rather than like try
Speaker 2:  to pretend it's all one or all the other or just ignore it all and talk about
Speaker 2:  stock prices, right? There's the, that's one really easy shortcut to a lot
Speaker 2:  of this is when the stock goes up it's good and when the stock goes down
Speaker 2:  it's bad. And that's a really handy way to cover tech that I think just like
Speaker 2:  ignores what it's like to be a person in the world. And I think just
Speaker 2:  coming into everything, acknowledging that it's all kind of a mess is a thing
Speaker 2:  The Verge is really good at and makes it like it's,
Speaker 2:  it's why it's fun to be engaged with this stuff every day. 'cause it doesn't
Speaker 2:  get less messy. It just gets messy in new ways, which is really fun.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Can I tell you my favorite Walt Mossberg story? Not that I experienced,
Speaker 4:  I have favorite ones that I experienced, but just in the legend of Walt Mossberg,
Speaker 4:  there's a, I believe it's a wired profile of him just like moving
Speaker 4:  through CES and he had just written some like horrible review
Speaker 4:  of like a serious XM radio or something. And the CEO of the company
Speaker 4:  stops and is like, you trashed my stock price, like on the floor of CSS and
Speaker 4:  on the floor of css. Walt Mossberg looks at him dead in the eye and says,
Speaker 4:  I don't give a fuck about your stock price.
Speaker 2:  Hell yeah,
Speaker 4:  I just like have held this in my heart the entire time.
Speaker 2:  I like that a lot. All, right? We have one more and then we're gonna get
Speaker 2:  outta here. The last question we have comes from Kevin.
Speaker 22:  Hey, this is Kevin Lagree from beautiful Winona, Minnesota and I've been
Speaker 22:  an active reader of The Verge since around
Speaker 22:  November 1st, 2011. You've been around for a long time doing great things.
Speaker 22:  And I guess my real big question for everybody on The Vergecast, when you're
Speaker 22:  talking about Hot Takes and hot questions is what is your next,
Speaker 4:  Well, I'm here to announce,
Speaker 2:  This is where he rans bad activity pub.
Speaker 4:  Is this where I ran about activity pub for four hours? Yeah, yeah. Okay.
Speaker 4:  My, my plan for our site is to federate our content
Speaker 4:  and to be more natively integrated with whatever new
Speaker 4:  class of social networks that exist. I have no idea how any of this is gonna
Speaker 4:  work. You can see the loose beginnings of how it might work on our
Speaker 4:  site. You can see that people have built hacks to make it happen. I
Speaker 4:  love it. The space is great. Don't bother that guy too much. Don't overload
Speaker 4:  his server. But you can see how we're building towards, and then you can
Speaker 4:  see things like, well we've got a one column story stream. What if we
Speaker 4:  had two of them? What if we had three of them? What if you could follow our
Speaker 4:  writers in the column or topics? What if, what if you could just follow gadgets
Speaker 4:  and get a stream of gadget news on our homepage? I dunno if any of that's
Speaker 4:  gonna work. I just think we have to build cooler user
Speaker 4:  experiences for people in media and not just be a
Speaker 4:  supplier of cheap undifferentiated content to Elon Musk. Maybe
Speaker 4:  this is not like the most insane business proposition in the world, by the
Speaker 4:  way. If you like go anywhere else, you're like, what should you do? Should
Speaker 4:  you have a relationship with your customer or should you give your shit away
Speaker 4:  for free to the richest man on earth like anyone else in the world who
Speaker 4:  knows the answer to that question. Media executives like, I don't know. I
Speaker 4:  think we should give our shit away for free. And I just dunno why that is.
Speaker 4:  Like our industry just like know has no self-esteem. So, I would like The
Speaker 4:  Verge to, to lead the way in having some confident ideas on like,
Speaker 4:  how do we build stuff that's cool? How do we compete in like software
Speaker 4:  in addition to having really, really good work that is like has journalistic
Speaker 4:  ethics and all the other stuff. Yeah, that's, that's kind of my, my big idea.
Speaker 4:  I've, again, no idea how this will work. We have to build a lot of it.
Speaker 4:  We have to invent a bunch of it, but again, we've been given the license
Speaker 4:  to do it, which I think is a pretty incredible position to be in. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I think we, we've entered this place where like the media industry has spent
Speaker 2:  the last 15 years basically playing everybody else's game in the social world
Speaker 2:  where it's like you, you, you play somebody's game, you get free traffic,
Speaker 2:  you lightly monetize that traffic seems sort of like victory for
Speaker 2:  a minute. And we are coming out of that game in a pretty real way.
Speaker 2:  Like just the fact that Twitter is now not showing headlines on link cards.
Speaker 2:  Like Elon Musk does not want you to leave his platform and so he's going
Speaker 2:  to make it very hard for you to leave his platform.
Speaker 4:  But, and Elon is just like a very convenient villain. This
Speaker 2:  Is what's happening to everybody, right? Like Google is less interested in
Speaker 2:  sending you stuff. Everybody is doing that now. And so this idea of like,
Speaker 2:  I think the the thing you're gonna see from a lot of media organizations
Speaker 2:  is like, how do we build a place you want to be, which I think is, is correct.
Speaker 2:  And then the, the thing that we're also gonna try to figure out how to do
Speaker 2:  on top of that is how to like be out in the rest of the internet in
Speaker 2:  a way that makes sense and isn't just like a devil's bargain with Facebook,
Speaker 2:  which I think, I have no idea what it looks like, but I think it's gonna
Speaker 2:  be very cool.
Speaker 4:  I'll connect that You know. There's an earlier question about like how things
Speaker 4:  have changed since the beginning. And the beginning. We were just like pip
Speaker 4:  squeaks. Like I was at this last Apple event, I think I said this in the
Speaker 4:  show earlier, like, I was at this last Apple event and like the Cambrian
Speaker 4:  explosion of like TikTok rigs just like blew my mind.
Speaker 4:  Like people inventing things to make videos fast that we would've just never
Speaker 4:  seen before. And the way that some of those folks were talking to me,
Speaker 4:  like, I love it when people call me the legacy media. Like, say it again,
Speaker 4:  You know, like, I love it. Thank you for calling me the winner. I'll, I'll
Speaker 4:  take it all day long. But the thing that has changed is like our role in
Speaker 4:  the ecosystem has changed. And so we should build a product that is reflective
Speaker 4:  of that role in the ecosystem. A lot of which is like a linking to other
Speaker 4:  people, right? Like our homepage is very much designed to link to
Speaker 4:  other great work to embed other great work on other platforms. I, I wanna
Speaker 4:  put some focus on that as much as like we're going to,
Speaker 4:  I mean, we are always gonna make beautiful reviews and investigations and
Speaker 4:  write news fa like, but I think that piece of it where we're, we're a
Speaker 4:  utility and we're a trusted part of an ecosystem.
Speaker 4:  Most publishers have just gotten away. Like the New York Times won't even
Speaker 4:  like link to other like, they're like, Ugh, another someone else read this.
Speaker 4:  Ugh, how dare you. And like we're, we're just
Speaker 4:  not gonna be that. Right? We, we want to, we want to be the, the thing that
Speaker 4:  connects all kinds of smart people together.
Speaker 2:  Alex, any thoughts last, what's, what's on your mind for the next 12
Speaker 2:  years?
Speaker 6:  No, I I think you guys are exactly right. Like, like media's in a weird kind
Speaker 6:  of crisis point and finding a way to establish
Speaker 6:  yourself and not have to like constantly go and, and pay
Speaker 6:  homage to all of these big social media platforms is really, really important.
Speaker 6:  And it's the way you survive and it's the way you stay independent and it's
Speaker 6:  the way you actually cover what you wanna cover and not what some
Speaker 6:  algorithm you don't have any control over thinks needs to be covered.
Speaker 6:  And I think that's what we need to do at The Verge and that's what we do
Speaker 6:  at The Verge. So I'm really excited about it. It's a great, I like,
Speaker 6:  I'm excited about the next couple of years, even though I'm sure it's gonna
Speaker 6:  be kind of a hellscape for other people
Speaker 2:  12 years from now on your, on your brain machine implant that
Speaker 2:  is screwed into your head. We'll be there. I dunno what it's gonna
Speaker 2:  look like. We'll be
Speaker 1:  There, but we'll be there.
Speaker 6:  We'll be
Speaker 2:  There. All, right? We gotta go. Thank you both for doing this. Thanks to
Speaker 2:  everyone who's sending questions. This was very fun. Yeah, this was really
Speaker 2:  fun. I mean, there was one part of it that was horrible. The rest of it was
Speaker 2:  fun. Coming up next week, everybody's ratings on Neli as
Speaker 2:  the host of The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  All, right? That's it for The Vergecast today. If you have thoughts, questions,
Speaker 2:  feelings, weird ideas about microphones we should have or frankly
Speaker 2:  anything else you wanna know, you can always email us at Vergecast at The
Speaker 2:  Verge dot com or keep calling the hotline. 8 6 6 Verge one
Speaker 2:  one. Send us all your questions. We're gonna keep answering Verge questions
Speaker 2:  over time. I'm sure this will not be the last time, so keep 'em coming. This
Speaker 2:  show is produced by Andrew Moreno and Liam James The. Vergecast is Verge
Speaker 2:  production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli Alex and I will
Speaker 2:  be back on Friday to talk about Matter 1.2 weird
Speaker 2:  internet standards about how to post on the internet and much more. We'll
Speaker 2:  see you then rock and roll.
Speaker 23:  From the moment Twitter was founded, no one knew what it was supposed to
Speaker 23:  be exactly, which was kind of great.
Speaker 24:  Some people would look at it and say, this is the future of communications.
Speaker 24:  Others would look at it and say, this is the public square.
Speaker 23:  Eventually it became not so great.
Speaker 25:  What we didn't foresee was that everybody having
Speaker 25:  a voice might produce a global
Speaker 25:  voracious mob, and there was only one place that that was happening.
Speaker 25:  It was Twitter
Speaker 23:  A year ago in what was essentially the world's most expensive impulse
Speaker 23:  purchase. Elon Musk bought Twitter that made him
Speaker 23:  Twitter's most important user, but he's certainly not the only
Speaker 23:  one to fall for. Its spell. It's a spell. It promises attention, connection,
Speaker 23:  and power.
Speaker 23:  I am Peter Kafka and I'm hosting Land of the Giants, the Twitter fantasy.
Speaker 23:  It's from Vox on the Vox Media Podcast Network. This season is sponsored
Speaker 23:  by Mint Mobile to learn how Twitter got started, how it got to where it
Speaker 23:  is today and where it's going next, follow land of the Giants wherever you
Speaker 23:  listen to podcasts and get our first episode on Wednesday,
Speaker 23:  October 25th.