# Transcript
ID: 6b43ed96-745f-4939-94d5-b43ef8a37b70
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Into the iPad Confusion Zone
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4275624472876022741/8566832865730004904/s93290-US-4981s-1697819581.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss a whole bunch of tech news from this week — a new Apple Pencil, the latest Cybertruck confusion, streaming updates, and more.
Speaker 3:  Hello? And Welcome To, the Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the Confusion
Speaker 3:  Zone. We'll, we'll explain what we mean soon. Hi, I'm your friend. Neli Alex.
Speaker 3:  Cranz is here. I'm your friend
Speaker 4:  Who is always confused.
Speaker 3:  So not in the Zone. I'm,
Speaker 4:  I'm, no, I live in the Zone. Oh,
Speaker 3:  I see. Yeah. David Pierce is here. I'm never
Speaker 1:  Confused about
Speaker 3:  Anything. David's out the Zone. He's like, I'm not going in there. Not
Speaker 4:  In the Zone.
Speaker 3:  We have quite a lot to talk about. We're, we're structuring the show. this
Speaker 3:  week is a series of lightning rounds, which I assure
Speaker 3:  you that I am working on finding a sponsor for.
Speaker 3:  There's one I have in particular in my brain, starts
Speaker 3:  with a eh and ends in a tell. If you are listening
Speaker 3:  and you're from one of America's most important ship makers,
Speaker 3:  call our people. I don't do any of that side of the, the, that's, that's
Speaker 3:  the other side of the house. But they're waiting to catch your money and
Speaker 3:  rebrand this The Vergecast Thunderbolt four round, sponsored by
Speaker 3:  You. know what I'm saying? Yeah. Anyway, so show of Lightning Arts. There's
Speaker 3:  a lot of news. We gotta get through it all. Yeah. But before we begin, I
Speaker 3:  want to, I want to shout out to two listeners who I would like to give t-shirts
Speaker 3:  to. One, I literally just ran into me on a train today, looked
Speaker 3:  surprised. Said they were a big fan, and I forgot to say, gimme your email
Speaker 3:  address. So just send me an email. Tell me what your name was on the train
Speaker 3:  platform and I'll make sure you get a t-shirt. I'm not saying their name
Speaker 3:  because I want, that's my verification scheme.
Speaker 3:  So the second one is more, a little more of a story and is truly one
Speaker 3:  of the funniest moments that I've ever had hosting the show. Okay.
Speaker 3:  Which is 10 years now.
Speaker 3:  So we are in New York. Like lots of people just expect to
Speaker 3:  see people in New York. It's like a, a normal thing that happens is
Speaker 3:  someone's like, Hey, ver the The Verge. Yeah. You're a guy.
Speaker 3:  I'm super mad at you about head fun jacks and like, we're off to the races.
Speaker 3:  Right. We
Speaker 5:  Should say, by the way, that that is what 95% of people say when they meet
Speaker 5:  one of us. They just go The Verge.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It's like a real thing. Look, there are creators who are vastly more
Speaker 3:  popular than we are. Yeah. So we're, we're, we're down here. But one of the
Speaker 3:  best aspects of this is because it's a podcast and people have been listening
Speaker 3:  to us for so long, people just come up to us and start talking to us. Like
Speaker 3:  they, they know us. Yeah. And often whoever's partner is like, do You
Speaker 3:  know each other? And I'm like, no. And that's, it's
Speaker 3:  always very funny. So I, I appreciate this. Happy to talk to whoever at any
Speaker 3:  time, but I'm saying in New York that's normal 'cause people know that we're
Speaker 3:  in New York. Like Right. You have some baseline expectation that we're at
Speaker 3:  least supposed to be in this city or at an Apple event or whatever. It's,
Speaker 3:  I was in Boston this week where Harvard is
Speaker 3:  launching something called the Applied Social Media Lab. And it's a
Speaker 3:  big fancy event and big fancy people and You know it's like a launch.
Speaker 3:  There's panel interviews and da dah dah dah, dah. And how can we help social
Speaker 3:  media reinforce democracy? Like Neli stuff, You know
Speaker 3:  the stuff. And So I was there.
Speaker 4:  The stuff
Speaker 3:  And You know at, at the event watched the thing. We did a decoder episode
Speaker 3:  with Larry Las Vegas all great. But like eight 15
Speaker 3:  in the morning, I met Walgreens in Cambridge. And a
Speaker 3:  Vergecast fan just looked like utterly perplexed.
Speaker 3:  As I'm walking into the Walgreens, they walked up to me and the very politely
Speaker 3:  and all the, they had headphones in and they were listening to the last episode
Speaker 3:  of the Sonos episode. Whoa. And all this person could do was just like, point
Speaker 3:  at their phone. They were just like, that's you.
Speaker 3:  I was like, yeah, it's me. And then they said their name, So I.
Speaker 3:  Thank you for listening. I'm sorry. But I was like not supposed to be in
Speaker 3:  Boston. Like I could see the, like Yeah. It was just like
Speaker 3:  unwired. Like why is this person here? And I get it. 'cause why was I there
Speaker 3:  at eight 15 in the morning at Walgreens? This poor person was gonna work.
Speaker 3:  Send me an email. Say your name. I I remember your name. We'll get you a
Speaker 3:  t-shirt. It was just like one of the purely funniest moments. Like, it's
Speaker 3:  like, honestly, like why was I there? Yeah. There's no explanation. I had
Speaker 3:  not tweeted I'm in Boston. Like nothing. Just context free. See, a person
Speaker 3:  that you're listening to must've been truly strange. So send me an email
Speaker 3:  with your name and I'll send you a t-shirt. Is is
Speaker 5:  It because of your tremendous brand loyalty to Dwayne Reed that no one could
Speaker 5:  believe you would ever
Speaker 3:  You know Walgreens.
Speaker 4:  C v s.
Speaker 3:  So yeah, there's two, there's two T-shirts I wanna send out. If you saw me
Speaker 3:  on the train today or if you saw me randomly in Boston,
Speaker 3:  which again, truly random situation. I like
Speaker 4:  That they didn't point at you because that's what I do when I see someone.
Speaker 4:  No, it was, I just point,
Speaker 3:  It was, it was showing me the, the activity widget on their iPhone
Speaker 3:  home screen way more point. Like just really got me like I would've done
Speaker 3:  the same thing. Yeah. Like if I, if I was like, I don't know, watching Red
Speaker 3:  Zone on my phone and Scott Hanson was there, like all I would've done is
Speaker 3:  just like point at my phone against
Speaker 5:  You.
Speaker 3:  That's you,
Speaker 3:  you're
Speaker 5:  There and here at the same time. Wait, Neli, before we move
Speaker 5:  on, I have a really important question. Yeah. How many gadgets did you bring
Speaker 5:  on the train today? I cannot tell you the response that we have gotten
Speaker 5:  to your thesis that you would like to be the guy who just walks under the
Speaker 5:  train like a murderer with
Speaker 3:  Nothing. Yeah. Nothing.
Speaker 5:  The number of emails and posts. We got so much response to this being like,
Speaker 5:  this is the way Yeah.
Speaker 3:  This is all anybody wants to do.
Speaker 5:  Have you made progress? How are we doing So
Speaker 3:  I since that episode, I had not been back in the office,
Speaker 3:  so my plan was to sneak into the office reviews closet today and see
Speaker 3:  if we have a galaxy fold with decks. Mm. And I was
Speaker 3:  gonna give it a shot in the, the coming week.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 3:  'cause I, I'm, I'm commuting in the office like two or three times a week.
Speaker 3:  So, I'm gonna give it a shot one of these days. Okay.
Speaker 3:  This requires like an enormous amount of upfront work as
Speaker 3:  all assassinations require. Just a lot of planning and
Speaker 3:  preparation. I have to set up a Dex Workstation in the
Speaker 3:  office, which is like perhaps not the best use of my
Speaker 3:  time in the office.
Speaker 4:  I'm sure that it can help
Speaker 3:  You. No, no, no, no. That's not a ticket you wanna file. Hello?
Speaker 3:  I would like to put an unvetted third party operating system on this
Speaker 3:  network.
Speaker 4:  That's fine.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Just can I, can I full access to the land? Please.
Speaker 3:  You've never heard of this operating system. It runs on a phone.
Speaker 3:  We don't even own You know. I gotta do some prep work, which
Speaker 3:  I'll attempt to do today. Yeah. Okay. I don't know why in
Speaker 3:  my head this has to be a folding phone.
Speaker 4:  No, I'm, it makes sense.
Speaker 5:  Right? It makes like a regular
Speaker 4:  Phone's not, but like
Speaker 3:  Many Samsung phones run decks
Speaker 5:  But not as well. It's for the reading on the train, right? Yeah. Like it's,
Speaker 5:  it's like you want, you want the something to like sit down on the seat
Speaker 5:  and You know cross your legs into your crossword puzzle. Like that's the,
Speaker 5:  that's the interim stage. That's where you open the phone.
Speaker 3:  That's right. But there's no part of, I'm not bringing up my laptop on the
Speaker 3:  train. I'm just using my phone. Yeah. Shut
Speaker 5:  Up. It doesn't matter. I don't,
Speaker 3:  I don't have the middle ground between phone usage and laptop usage.
Speaker 5:  It's 'cause you don't have a foldable phone. I don't understand. This is
Speaker 5:  it.
Speaker 3:  The other side of it is, at my house, I have to set up an always on desktop
Speaker 3:  computer to run beeper So I can get my iMessages. Yeah. So if you just think
Speaker 3:  about the amount of prep work I have to do, So I can just roll
Speaker 3:  up onto the train.
Speaker 5:  Okay. No, but here's, here's the real thing.
Speaker 3:  Like I to set up two different extremely weird computing environments
Speaker 3:  and make them both work perfect. So I can execute this plan
Speaker 5:  If there, if The Verge believes in anything, it's in doing so much work.
Speaker 5:  So you don't have to carry anything anywhere. Yeah. Like that is what we
Speaker 5:  stand for. I
Speaker 3:  Saw those notes and I was like, people get it? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  You just wanna roll up. It's the
Speaker 5:  Dream. But Neli the, the middle ground is you, you open it up and you
Speaker 5:  accomplish your other dream, which is to write on stories with a
Speaker 5:  red pen as an editor. So you get on the train, you
Speaker 5:  unfold your
Speaker 3:  Phone. If Google wants me to switch full-time to Android, just
Speaker 3:  make it in the, the Android Google Docs app.
Speaker 3:  You can circle things and that shows up as an edit everywhere in Google
Speaker 3:  Docs. Make that exclusive to the Android version of Google Docs. I'll switch
Speaker 3:  tomorrow. All I want to do is circle things with a red pen and send them
Speaker 3:  to David where it says clunky.
Speaker 3:  That's it. As an editor in chief, I've had but one goal and
Speaker 3:  I've saved laser focused on it this entire time. David's
Speaker 4:  Less excited about that goal.
Speaker 3:  Oh. At the very beginning of The Verge, Joanna Stern had a post-it note on
Speaker 3:  the side of her monitor that just said clunky. So she would, she, she'd be
Speaker 3:  like, I know what you're gonna say. So she would just remember it. I'm very
Speaker 3:  predictable man. All. right. The, that's all the preamble. I'm, I'm working
Speaker 3:  on my deck situation, David. That's
Speaker 5:  Okay. We're gonna check in next week. This is not, this is not a task. You
Speaker 5:  are allowed, if, if you have things on the train next week, we The
Speaker 5:  Vergecast public will be disappointed
Speaker 3:  In you. I hate it. I carried my backpack on the train today. I was like,
Speaker 3:  why do I have all this stuff? This bag exists solely to have my laptop in
Speaker 3:  it, no bag. And I don't need all the stuff that's in it. But once you have
Speaker 3:  a bag, you start filling it with stuff.
Speaker 5:  Some people would say the answer is buy another laptop. I say, that's not
Speaker 5:  thinking hard
Speaker 3:  Enough. Yeah. A good answer is that I could actually ask our office people
Speaker 3:  for a desk. Yeah. And You know we're in return to work and nobody has desks.
Speaker 3:  It's all the stuff. I don't No, I'm not, I don't use software at
Speaker 3:  work. I'm not filling out it tickets and none of this is happening. You
Speaker 3:  know my dream. It's to never use enterprise software. Yeah. I'm gonna
Speaker 3:  get, I I would bet that I get closer to consistently having emails
Speaker 3:  printed out and handed to me than using D at work. I,
Speaker 3:  yeah. Like long term, what is more likely to be a real thing that
Speaker 3:  happens? It's, I get to the point where people hand me printed out
Speaker 3:  emails, then I consistently every day use Dexa
Speaker 4:  Work. I think if you don't, if you have a bag next week, then yeah, we're,
Speaker 4:  we're just gonna start only communicating with you with like printed emails.
Speaker 4:  Be like, can you check this in Slack? No. Email All, right?
Speaker 3:  We there's news. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  There is
Speaker 3:  News. There's a lot of news. But I'll, I'll, I'll work. I'm gonna go check
Speaker 3:  out the deck situation in the closet after this. Okay.
Speaker 3:  Lightning rounds. Let's start with gadget Lightning round. Yeah. David, you
Speaker 3:  got the first one. What's up?
Speaker 5:  I wanna talk about the Apple Pencil. The
Speaker 3:  Confusion Zone. The
Speaker 5:  Confusion Zone. We are entering the Confusion Zone, who knows how
Speaker 5:  long we'll be here, but we are here now. Thank
Speaker 4:  You Rod Sterling.
Speaker 5:  So Apple launched a new Pencil. It's a, it's a Pencil
Speaker 5:  but it charges with USB C. That is the
Speaker 5:  only thing about it that I understand. There is now an Apple Pencil that
Speaker 5:  charges with USB C. What Apple also did was
Speaker 5:  make the entire situation of buying an iPad and an Apple
Speaker 5:  Pencil vastly more confusing on top of already being more
Speaker 5:  confusing. And the funniest thing that has happened this week is that there
Speaker 5:  are, I would say a set of people on the internet who spend a lot of time
Speaker 5:  explaining weird decisions Apple makes as if they are not weird decisions.
Speaker 5:  And Apple lost everybody on this one. Yep. This was one of those, everybody
Speaker 5:  was like why on earth are there three pencils? There's now the Apple
Speaker 5:  Pencil first generation, which works for a subset of iPads. There's the Apple
Speaker 5:  Pencil second generation, which works for a subset of iPads and there's an
Speaker 5:  Apple Pencil USB C, which works for a different subset of iPads. And
Speaker 5:  there, there is just no world in which any of this makes any sense anymore.
Speaker 5:  And it has led a lot of people to reconsider whether the iPad makes any sense
Speaker 5:  anymore. Yeah. And I just, I just need you guys to feel as annoyed about
Speaker 3:  This. That's the ass dome, right? Where it's like they released the apple
Speaker 3:  Pencil u s pc. It's the first little domino and like the last one is someone
Speaker 3:  is like, I'm switching to Windows. Right?
Speaker 3:  I saw, I saw this happen this week. They're gonna go
Speaker 3:  full surface. Yeah. They're like, at least the surface pen makes sense. And
Speaker 3:  I can, I can just buy the one. And It works everywhere. Yeah. So the, I get
Speaker 3:  why they needed to make an Apple Pencil with USB C and I like the little
Speaker 3:  design. It's a slide ecap. So just opens maybe
Speaker 3:  the first affordance to charging an
Speaker 3:  accessory that makes sense that Apple has released
Speaker 3:  ever, at least in the context of Of compute. Compute. Like obviously AirPods
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Are fine. You don't have to plug it in. It's, it's not in the bottom
Speaker 3:  bottom. You don't have to take the cap off. It's not only magnetic to some
Speaker 3:  iPad,
Speaker 5:  You plug a thing into it instead of plugging it into a thing. Yeah. Which
Speaker 5:  is the obviously correct and better way to do everything. Yes.
Speaker 3:  It support people recognized and might have charging cables for all, all
Speaker 3:  very good. Yes. Great. So that part's cool. It's missing a bunch
Speaker 3:  of features. There's like a, there's a chart. Apple released a chart
Speaker 3:  with check marks of what all the things do. And it looks like one of those
Speaker 3:  charts of like when you go to buy health insurance or something and you're
Speaker 3:  like, I don't know what any of these words mean or whether I want this and
Speaker 3:  this is definitely gonna put me in debt. Like it's like that level of confusing
Speaker 3:  in the chart. Yeah. And there's a bunch of features that if you don't know
Speaker 3:  you need them, you, you're like, do I need hover?
Speaker 3:  Do I need double tap to switch? Yeah. Like it's,
Speaker 3:  it's hard to convey the value of the features in a chart like this.
Speaker 5:  Well and there's also the fact that the USB c Apple
Speaker 5:  Pencil, which is ostensibly the newest Apple Pencil, is missing a bunch of
Speaker 5:  features including features that exist on the first generation Apple Pencil
Speaker 5:  like pressure sensitivity, which I would argue is a very important feature
Speaker 5:  in like a high-end. Silas, this thing is $80. It does
Speaker 5:  not have pressure sensitivity. The very first Pencil Apple ever made
Speaker 5:  has pressure sensitivity. Like what are we doing here? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Well it's not us. It's dapper. It's not circling things.
Speaker 3:  It's definitely not. Also the image they released to promote this
Speaker 3:  new Pencil. Just go look at it. We had a full slack conversation about it.
Speaker 3:  It is ridiculous. It is. It's a picture of a, like a
Speaker 3:  boba tea custard and it, I don't want to, it's like an
Speaker 3:  illustration of it. Parts of it look like a recipe.
Speaker 4:  Arrows go nowhere.
Speaker 3:  The recipe would not help you. Like if you just like look at an
Speaker 3:  illustration of a custard and there's just like some words on it that are
Speaker 3:  like bake until three 50. You're like, I don't know what I'm baking.
Speaker 3:  And then yes, there are arrows that go to nowhere. Yeah. And then it says
Speaker 3:  how many there might be as though this is like a catering order, but then
Speaker 3:  it's beautifully illustrated.
Speaker 4:  I like that the highlights were all the exact same width because there's
Speaker 4:  no pressure sensitivity.
Speaker 3:  I didn't notice that. So it's can be the same width. I know. Just gonna look
Speaker 3:  at, I don't mean to whatever. It's, it's marketing material. It's an ad it,
Speaker 3:  we did that post a long time ago. It's like the only thing people can think
Speaker 3:  of to do with the service pen is circling things. And this is
Speaker 3:  like the ultimate exercise in nonsensical circling of things like
Speaker 3:  this image. No one would ever make it unless
Speaker 3:  they had been assigned to making an image to market a stylist.
Speaker 3:  That is the only reason it exists. And I think that's kind of indicative
Speaker 3:  of this whole exercise of the iPad. They sell a lot of
Speaker 3:  them, they have a lot of different kinds of uses.
Speaker 3:  It is 500 different kinds of appliance to people. But that
Speaker 3:  means it has no narrative. It's just a thing.
Speaker 3:  And it's like you can sell the ninth gen one with a lightning port.
Speaker 3:  You shouldn't, so kids can watch Disney plus I, but it's cheap. It's like
Speaker 3:  that thing needs to compete with fire tablets that are essentially
Speaker 3:  free or you can sell one at the top end that has all
Speaker 3:  the features in the world and is meant to compete with Windows laptops.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. There were a bunch of rumors before this announcement that we were
Speaker 5:  gonna get a big iPad refresh this week. That there was gonna be some
Speaker 5:  much bigger news about tablets. And I think
Speaker 5:  a, the fact that that didn't happen is sort of telling, I mean the iPad is
Speaker 5:  way overdue. That whole lineup is overdue for like a real
Speaker 5:  serious refresh. It's been, I mean the, the ninth generation one
Speaker 5:  has a home button and a lightning port, like it's way behind and you can
Speaker 5:  still buy it. And it's still, I think $329 is the starting price
Speaker 5:  for an iPad is really important to Apple. And I think the new low end
Speaker 5:  iPad is, is like 450 bucks. And I'm just, I'm betting Apple
Speaker 5:  just cannot figure out how to sell that thing at its margins for
Speaker 5:  $329. But we're getting to the point now where it just
Speaker 5:  doesn't make any sense that lineup anymore. It's like if you're an
Speaker 5:  iPad mini person, it's easy. You just buy an iPad mini, that thing kicks
Speaker 5:  ass. I'm an iPad mini person. Buy an iPad mini same. Beyond that,
Speaker 5:  there's an entry level iPad and another entry level iPad. There's an iPad
Speaker 5:  Air. There are the iPad pros. Like we, they've just lost
Speaker 5:  the plot here. And I think you're right. It's because Apple is increasingly
Speaker 5:  unclear what this thing is for like, I think that the MacBook was gonna
Speaker 5:  die and the iPad was gonna be the computer of the future. And then actually
Speaker 5:  the MacBook got awesome and has had a real resurgence.
Speaker 5:  And now the question is like, we're back to, is there a space between your
Speaker 5:  increasingly large, increasingly powerful phone and you're increasingly
Speaker 5:  long lasting, increasingly portable laptop and
Speaker 5:  You know what, 13 years ago when the iPad came out, there actually was a
Speaker 5:  lot of gap that your phone didn't cover in your laptop, didn't cover. And
Speaker 5:  those two things have both come closer together. And I feels like the space
Speaker 5:  for the iPad is shrinking and shrinking and shrinking.
Speaker 3:  Yes. I would remind you that we open the show with a
Speaker 3:  ludicrous but entirely realistic conversation
Speaker 3:  about whether I can just walk onto a train with a folding phone that turns
Speaker 3:  into a desktop PC at this office. Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  again, ludicrous but not a thing I
Speaker 3:  can't do. Like I, it's just a thing I can do right now.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. As I, I can buy a phone that opens into a tablet,
Speaker 3:  arrive at work and turn it into a reasonable
Speaker 3:  facsimile of a desktop computer. Yeah. Because it will be running decks
Speaker 3:  which r it will have to, let me put on something.
Speaker 3:  The iPad does not like it. It's not cognizant
Speaker 3:  of that reality. Right. In the application ecosystem, in the user
Speaker 3:  interface with stage manager, like all that stuff, it still thinks
Speaker 3:  that people don't want laptops. I think that's just getting increasingly
Speaker 3:  untenable for No,
Speaker 4:  I think they know it, it about the laptops because half of those
Speaker 4:  iPads become laptops. You know you have to spend like 150,
Speaker 4:  $200 for the case. But you can turn most of those iPads into
Speaker 3:  The magic keyboard is $300. I was gonna
Speaker 5:  Say I wish it was 150.
Speaker 4:  Look, it's been like four years since I bought one. But that's brutal.
Speaker 4:  But, but like they're very aware and they, they, they try to go after that
Speaker 4:  kind of surface pricing. They try to tr position it as a surface, but then
Speaker 4:  they have the cheap ones and the, and the mini. And they're like, well no,
Speaker 4:  no, these are iPad iPads and these are iPad laptops.
Speaker 4:  But what's
Speaker 3:  Really interesting, what has changed my mind about the iPad is watching two
Speaker 3:  people in my family use them. Okay. Max, who is five, who
Speaker 3:  watches YouTube kids and plays Minecraft and
Speaker 3:  there's actually a really tight nexus there. She watches people play
Speaker 3:  Minecraft on YouTube kids and then she plays Minecraft and that means
Speaker 3:  she's now great at Minecraft because she's five. She doesn't have to
Speaker 3:  make any money. She's
Speaker 4:  Terrified.
Speaker 3:  We feed her, we take her everywhere. We can just pick her up and move her
Speaker 3:  if she's not in the right place. You know. Like she can, all of her mental
Speaker 3:  energy is focused on Minecraft. Yeah. A way that is wonderful and
Speaker 3:  I miss it. But like the thing is perfectly adequate
Speaker 3:  for that task. She is not like, I want a newer better
Speaker 3:  iPad. It doesn't even matter to her. Right. The thing is a window to, to
Speaker 3:  Minecraft. I don't even know how she does it. 'cause she's using touchscreen
Speaker 3:  controls to move around in Minecraft. It makes me dizzy watching her play
Speaker 3:  this game. Yeah. I'm like, do you want a control her? She's like, get outta
Speaker 3:  here old man. It's weird. She's five. She's mean. No,
Speaker 3:  she's not.
Speaker 5:  And it by the way, in a, in a certain way that is like perfect.
Speaker 5:  The dream state of the iPad. Like what an unbelievable success story of
Speaker 5:  a device you just
Speaker 3:  Described. Yeah. Right. It's an appliance for Minecraft. Yeah. Yeah. Is doing
Speaker 3:  that job perfectly and it charges using the same cable as her mother's iPhone,
Speaker 3:  which makes life very convenient for those two. Right.
Speaker 3:  Very inconvenient for me at this juncture. It used to charge the same cable
Speaker 3:  as my phone. Now I'm just like a weird old guy in the corner
Speaker 3:  being like, it's a USB C cable. Like I'm just like left out
Speaker 3:  of my family. That's her right appliance for
Speaker 3:  consuming video on like handful of video apps and playing one, one game.
Speaker 3:  Then there's my sister who is a full like
Speaker 3:  iPad as a laptop person.
Speaker 4:  Love this.
Speaker 3:  So my sister's a doctor. She goes to work Windows is
Speaker 3:  foisted upon her. She comes back and she has no desire to
Speaker 3:  further use traditional desktop operating systems.
Speaker 3:  She just is on her iPad and she's ultra effective.
Speaker 3:  She's like an iPad person. And I watch her use this thing and it's like literally
Speaker 3:  just a relief from desktop operating metaphors. Hmm.
Speaker 4:  Yes. I mean I do that. Yeah. I, I've got one where like if I,
Speaker 4:  if I have to do work on the weekends or something, sometimes I'll go and
Speaker 4:  use my, my computer. But a lot of times I'll be like, I'm gonna pull up my
Speaker 4:  2018 iPad Pro and use that just to escape. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Just to not feel like I'm at work. 'cause Slack will probably still be open.
Speaker 4:  'cause I probably left it open and like some drafts that I owe edits on or
Speaker 4:  there and I'm like, I don't wanna look at that. I just wanna go and do things.
Speaker 4:  And so it's really nice. And then I got my, my other iPad, which is just
Speaker 4:  for in bed reading and, and looking at YouTube
Speaker 4:  and not going to sleep.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's great.
Speaker 3:  You're hitting a point that I've, I'm starting to hit now, which is like,
Speaker 3:  I should have computers per room.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I, that's, that's basically what's happened.
Speaker 3:  Like, I used to like have a laptop that I would carry around. I'm like, what
Speaker 3:  if I get a Chromebook for the living room? And it's like, it's right over
Speaker 3:  there. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I I don't have anybody to be like, no.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So I try to do this with my iPad. I was like, the iPad will just
Speaker 3:  like live in the living room. It's hard be my TV computer and an iPad on
Speaker 3:  a magic keyboard is like not a good laptop. So if anything at work happens,
Speaker 3:  it's like I can't do it and I have to go get my laptop. And then the magic
Speaker 3:  keyboard is like not great for lap. Yeah. Like if you're on a couch with
Speaker 3:  it, it's like, oh, this is somewhat uncomfortable. I put
Speaker 4:  It a pillow. Yeah. And then I put it on top. That's, that's my little habit
Speaker 4:  when
Speaker 3:  I say this is the domino, by the way, apple released the USB c
Speaker 3:  Apple Pencil and here we are. I'm like, I gotta get a Chromebook for my living
Speaker 3:  room. Yeah. I'm telling you people are like evaluating all the places
Speaker 3:  they would otherwise put an iPad and be like, oh, there's a slightly better
Speaker 3:  product to put in that place unless you're using it as an
Speaker 3:  appliance. Unless it has a single purpose. And you've, you've
Speaker 3:  jammed an iPad into that purpose. Like playing my, again, playing Minecraft,
Speaker 3:  watching videos for the longest time. We, my oldest iPad
Speaker 3:  lived on our old treadmill and Becky just used it
Speaker 3:  to do Peloton treadmill workouts. Like it was just a Peloton tv.
Speaker 3:  And then we moved and she's like, I'm buying a real Peloton. And we threw
Speaker 3:  that iPad away. Yeah. But like that's all, it's the thing is an
Speaker 3:  appliance. And I think Apple has not, it has not marketed the thing well
Speaker 3:  as like, it is an appliance. It's like, here's all the iPads you can buy
Speaker 3:  and it, assuming the market will just figure it out. But then you get
Speaker 3:  to the Pencil and you're like, I don't even know what to buy. Right.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I think the, the thing that Apple has held onto all this time is
Speaker 5:  that it is possible to be all things to all people because
Speaker 5:  it's just a screen. Because it has the accessories, because it
Speaker 5:  has a gigantic app ecosystem. It can solve everybody's
Speaker 5:  problems because everybody has different problems, but everybody has problems.
Speaker 5:  Right. And the iPad can be the solution to all those problems. And if you
Speaker 5:  have a subset of problems, I think that's true. Like if you want to play
Speaker 5:  a certain kind of game, the iPad is the best thing that exists on earth to
Speaker 5:  play that kind of game. Alex and I talk about reading on the show all the
Speaker 5:  time, and it's like the iPad is the best reading device. Like it's not close.
Speaker 5:  Yep. It just is. It's the best Minecraft device. If you
Speaker 5:  wanna watch videos about Minecraft and then play Minecraft. Right. Like if
Speaker 5:  you have this one need, it's a really expensive device, but It works.
Speaker 5:  The problem is Apple has made it so vastly complicated to figure out which
Speaker 5:  one is the right one for your needs that you're gonna start to like literally
Speaker 5:  push people away. Because it, I just, I, I'm, I'm looking at these pencils
Speaker 5:  and the answer for me is I'm not gonna buy one because like yeah. What is
Speaker 5:  happening? I'm gonna go buy the $10 knockoff on Amazon that just works with
Speaker 5:  all of them. It's gonna be fine. Like Apple
Speaker 4:  Used to be really, really good at this too. Right? Like Apple would go and
Speaker 4:  and kill something just to keep their lineup as clean as possible.
Speaker 4:  And over the years it's gotten messier and messier and, and
Speaker 4:  that's fine in a lot of ways. It's, it's good. Like there's a lot of phones
Speaker 4:  you can choose from. They're very affordable. Yeah. All of that. But with
Speaker 4:  the iPads in particular, it's like, no, you've got made it too messy. It's
Speaker 4:  just too messy. Like,
Speaker 3:  Because they don't know for most, well, Apple's so big now they sell so new
Speaker 3:  products. Yeah. They need something at every price point. Right. And so they
Speaker 3:  just bring things down to price. So that makes a little bit of sense to me
Speaker 3:  a little. But the old one's still here if you want it. They particularly
Speaker 3:  do that with the iPhones, with the iPad. I think they don't,
Speaker 3:  they have to articulate a reason that you're not gonna buy the cheapest thing,
Speaker 3:  which I think in this case is a fire tablet.
Speaker 5:  Well, and and not only that, I mean I, I think we could sit here and I
Speaker 5:  could pretty quickly explain to you the difference between the four models
Speaker 5:  of the iPhone, right? Like there are, there are features that you get on
Speaker 5:  one that you don't get on the other other than screen bigger
Speaker 5:  thing more expensive. Can you tell me the difference between the entry level
Speaker 5:  iPad and the 12.9 inch iPad Pro?
Speaker 3:  It has a LIDAR sensor. David,
Speaker 3:  I don't know what you're talking about. Everyone is constantly out here doing
Speaker 3:  LIDAR stuff. It's, it's a future. I will say that in our, my
Speaker 3:  new office in the new house, Liam, Liam, our producer
Speaker 3:  legitimately has like carpet samples for me to like deco
Speaker 3:  this room and treat this room that I have to go look at. And he was like,
Speaker 3:  send me some dimensions. And I did the lidar room scanning thing with the
Speaker 3:  iPhone and it was super cool. And then I ended up with like a file
Speaker 3:  that I had no idea how to use it or send it to anyone.
Speaker 4:  You're like, it's here.
Speaker 3:  This lightning round has gone on way too long. I'm telling it's a Confusion.
Speaker 3:  Zone. Yeah. That's all I'm saying. But
Speaker 5:  It also, my prediction is at some point in the next 12 months, either this
Speaker 5:  is gonna get much worse or Apple is just going to clean it up drastically.
Speaker 5:  And I would bet on that. I think we're gonna get a bunch of new iPads that
Speaker 5:  make a lot more sense very soon. I
Speaker 4:  Hope the latter.
Speaker 3:  I am gonna bet on more confusing. Just to be contrary.
Speaker 3:  I have no insight. One
Speaker 5:  Of the iPads is gonna be a soundbar.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  We got a lot of emails of people who are like, don't know what you're talking
Speaker 3:  about. They're definitely making a soundbar. Thank you. No way. I'm gonna
Speaker 3:  get printed out emails delivered to me at work before Apple releases a soundbar
Speaker 4:  And they're all gonna be the soundbar.
Speaker 3:  T M I card and you're not leaving the office before. I have a folding
Speaker 3:  phone and you have an H T M I card. You've seen the thing like, it's like
Speaker 3:  a center cam it, I think that's what it's called. Yeah. And it's just like
Speaker 3:  a little itty bitty camera sensor on a stick. And the idea is that it, it
Speaker 3:  is not in the way and it's just a bad camera. Like this, this
Speaker 3:  is my problem with, it's like I want it to look good because I'm a
Speaker 3:  freshest camera. Right. Do
Speaker 5:  You wanna look nice? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So this is like, what gets me at this is like, oh, you can put a good camera
Speaker 3:  back there. Yeah. Yeah. And that, that I think changes my
Speaker 3:  relationship with, I dunno, I'm definitely getting one. The other thing that
Speaker 3:  I think is super important about this is we, we just
Speaker 3:  keep seeing this over and over again. All these companies,
Speaker 3:  the little companies are making gadgets for creators. Like there's a
Speaker 3:  real market there. Those people have needs, the needs are not
Speaker 3:  perfectly met by pro hardware or pro cameras.
Speaker 3:  There's a a sweet spot there for Twitch streamers and YouTubers and all that.
Speaker 3:  And I think it is fascinating. I thought we would
Speaker 3:  see a bunch of that stuff or work from home in the pandemic. And we're, we,
Speaker 3:  we've definitely seen some of it, some like cooler little docs that market
Speaker 3:  petered out because people were not like, you buy it
Speaker 3:  once and it goes away and there's, it's not growing. Hey, I want to grow
Speaker 3:  up to be a streamer, or Hey, I run a small company and making
Speaker 3:  content is the best market I can do and these things and I need some help
Speaker 3:  doing it. Well that is a large and growing market and I
Speaker 3:  just, the amount of gadgets that are coming out to solve that problem is
Speaker 3:  actually pretty fascinating. Yeah. And I like I You know I'm a gadget nerd.
Speaker 3:  So, I'm excited about it. But I, I think there's something durable there
Speaker 3:  about the creator platforms that we haven't quite seen yet.
Speaker 3:  Like YouTuber's been around for a long time. The stuff to make YouTube videos.
Speaker 3:  Well there's not actually a lot of it. Like
Speaker 3:  you still kinda get funneled into buying a Sony camera and Premiere if you
Speaker 3:  wanna make a
Speaker 4:  YouTube video. Yeah. It's like podcasting where the first time you do it,
Speaker 4:  you have to go and you Google and there's like three websites. They look
Speaker 4:  like absolute garbage and they give you the actual Yeah. List of stuff you
Speaker 4:  wanna buy. And it's all like pro stuff if you want it to be good.
Speaker 3:  Even that market, there's like a new shore mic that's a Qs C. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  Th and then, and we've started to see in the last couple of years, we started
Speaker 4:  to see like, oh, used to, I'd have to go buy a whole rig in order
Speaker 4:  for my, my podcasting setup to sound nice. And now it's like pretty
Speaker 4:  inexpensive for most people to just sound nice Yeah. Outta the box. And,
Speaker 4:  and I think we're getting rapidly to that place with cameras and, and that
Speaker 4:  whole setup and soon in the lights and everything else. Like, everybody's
Speaker 4:  gonna look the same.
Speaker 3:  I can't wait to put up the camera lights in the office. Liam. They're coming.
Speaker 3:  They're coming. This lightning round just keeps going on. Alex, what's yours?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. All. right. So mine is Analogue who makes really, really good
Speaker 4:  emulation emulator slash consoles is doing an N 64.
Speaker 4:  And I'm personally am very, very excited 'cause the N 64 is the
Speaker 4:  hardest, maybe not the hardest, but probably one of the hardest
Speaker 4:  consoles to emulate. It's super hard to emulate in software
Speaker 4:  because the, the processor was all custom. And so
Speaker 4:  you have to have a really, really powerful computer to play a lot of N 64
Speaker 4:  games. If you're emulating them this, you'll be able to play carts. It's
Speaker 4:  got an F P G A that like mimics the original hardware. So it should be
Speaker 4:  a lot faster. It should play carts natively. And then if you do somehow get
Speaker 4:  software on it, it would play the software natively. The the emulated games
Speaker 4:  natively. And I'm just like super, super excited for this thing. Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  a little too excited. I'm gonna have one. The
Speaker 3:  Lack of emulation for N 64 has made it like almost a forgotten console. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Because everybody's like, okay, what was on it? Goldeneye,
Speaker 4:  which like important
Speaker 3:  Greatest game of all time. Yeah. Like Mario 64 perhaps the most important
Speaker 3:  game of all time. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I mean Mario 64 there was ob obviously the two legends that
Speaker 4:  Zel does and those are about it when people talk about it. But if you grew
Speaker 4:  up in that age, it was like, nah. Played a lot of games. Like Chris Welch
Speaker 4:  is always like W C W. There
Speaker 5:  Was also the first Mario Tennis, which was the video game
Speaker 5:  in my life I have been best at. It wasn't
Speaker 4:  The first Mario Tennis that was for the virtual boy.
Speaker 3:  Wow. David. How dare you forget the virtual
Speaker 4:  Boy. How dare you.
Speaker 3:  How dare
Speaker 5:  You. Yeah, it was the first one.
Speaker 3:  Let's
Speaker 5:  Not, not
Speaker 4:  The first one. People play it. Do you mean technically
Speaker 5:  The first one was like the one someone made in their lab in Japan,
Speaker 5:  but I don't consider that one reel
Speaker 3:  Either.
Speaker 5:  The first one was for the N 64
Speaker 3:  All. right. I'm excited about this. There's no pictures of it yet. There's
Speaker 3:  like shadowy Yeah. Rendering things.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna come later. I I I know we'll probably be talking to that
Speaker 4:  team and, and, and hearing more from Analogue soon. So I'm really, really
Speaker 4:  excited and it just looks cool and also closer to a Game
Speaker 4:  Cube from Analogue. And that's what I really want. 'cause they are so
Speaker 4:  expensive on eBay and I really regret selling mine.
Speaker 3:  Can I tell you my story of game group regret?
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  This is, this is
Speaker 4:  So the the face alone says it's gonna be a great story. All right.
Speaker 3:  I'll tell you after the break. Liam says, I have to tell you with the break.
Speaker 3:  We'll be right back. Everybody with the story of Game Cube Regret
Speaker 3:  All, right? We're back. What is it? Here's a story from my youth about the
Speaker 3:  Game Cube. Okay. So there is a bar by my apartment in college called the
Speaker 3:  Cove All. right. And on Thursday nights the Cove would've $4 pitchers.
Speaker 3:  So we all went to the cove quite a bit. This is a
Speaker 5:  Story from like the 1930s. Yeah. Like what are we
Speaker 3:  What This is like a real thing in Hyde Park in Chicago, the Cove
Speaker 3:  had $4 pitchers on Thursday. So we're just there. We were there a lot.
Speaker 3:  This is Milwaukee's best though, right? Like no was Miller Light? It was
Speaker 3:  like any any garbage domestic pier. Okay. But you can tell that I grew up
Speaker 3:  again in the fifties and this is the time that the, the Game Cube
Speaker 3:  was the state of the art console. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The war had just ended
Speaker 3:  Everybody. And yeah. So we're there a lot. We know all the You know the,
Speaker 3:  the people who come through and one day Heineken
Speaker 3:  is at the Cove and they're having a Madden tournament
Speaker 3:  and I'm like, I'm in the Madden tournament. I don't know if you've ever tried
Speaker 3:  to play Madden on the Game Cube controller. It, it makes
Speaker 3:  no sense. Like everyone was horrible at Madden on the game
Speaker 3:  Cube. Like I want you to go pull over in your car and look at a picture of
Speaker 3:  a game cube controller and imagine trying to play Madden on this thing.
Speaker 3:  Best controller ever made for playing three games Soul
Speaker 3:  caliber like in classic Nintendo style. They're like, we made
Speaker 3:  this controller to play one specific Mario game. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It's a game where Luigi fights ghosts with water
Speaker 5:  And there's only one, there's essentially one button on the game cue controller
Speaker 5:  and all the rest of them are tiny and thousands of miles away from each other.
Speaker 3:  I love it. And Madden is about quickly deciding what button press
Speaker 3:  and everyone's like, I don't know, yellow and like it's a disaster. So this
Speaker 3:  is the longest Madden tournament of all time fueled
Speaker 3:  by $4 pitchers of beer. Oh. So on top of it, everyone
Speaker 3:  is destroyed. The long story is I won the Madden tournament
Speaker 3:  and I came home with a game cube with the Heineken logo. Silk
Speaker 3:  screened all over the top, which my friends and I all called the Heine cube.
Speaker 3:  And if I only had held onto this thing, max would be going to
Speaker 3:  college tomorrow. Yeah. I'd be like, take her now. Harvard. Yeah. Heine
Speaker 3:  cube baby. That's my story. I
Speaker 5:  Thought that was a sad story. That's an awesome story. Well,
Speaker 3:  I don't have it anymore. Oh, okay. It's the loss of money. I think I gave
Speaker 3:  it to my friend Robert when he, when he graduated. Robert, if you're listening,
Speaker 3:  I'll send you a t-shirt in exchange for the heine cube
Speaker 5:  Neli. I have really good news for you. Huh? I you can buy right now
Speaker 5:  six Nintendo Heineken game cubes for the low low price of
Speaker 5:  $20,000.
Speaker 3:  No. Are you kidding me?
Speaker 5:  No, that's real. I just found this uneven
Speaker 3:  But like, like a lot of six Hena cubes. Six
Speaker 5:  Hena cubes, three purple, three black. There were only a hundred of them
Speaker 5:  made according to the eBay listing. Jesus fucking Christ. $20,000.
Speaker 3:  I had one
Speaker 4:  That could have been you.
Speaker 5:  33 people have this on their watch list. I'm just saying
Speaker 3:  I had one of these things for three years.
Speaker 4:  Not anymore.
Speaker 3:  I'm so annoyed with myself. Oh, the verse cast is over everybody.
Speaker 4:  We're done
Speaker 3:  For the game. I've gotta go back in time to play Madden on GameCube
Speaker 3:  so my daughter can go to college. I have to invent a time machine
Speaker 3:  and tell my, tell my drunk 22 year old self You
Speaker 3:  hold onto that game cube,
Speaker 4:  Don't you give it away.
Speaker 3:  I'm much worse. I've been playing the new Madden. I have no idea how this
Speaker 3:  game works anymore. When I describe Madden as knowing what button to push
Speaker 3:  quickly, that is no longer true. Yeah, it's
Speaker 4:  Like team management now, right?
Speaker 3:  No, that's a whole other part of it. There's like a whole Pokemon version
Speaker 3:  of manic Madden that you can play. But
Speaker 5:  Now you have to know, you have to know where to look and you have to like
Speaker 5:  aim. It's, it's, it's, you have to know like six buttons to press at the
Speaker 5:  same time.
Speaker 3:  The game is so hard that they've added bullet time to it.
Speaker 4:  Nope. Nope. Your football's gotten too hard.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's like this isn't how this works for anyone. All. right. Let's
Speaker 3:  carry on with our all lightning round show. Although this is kind of like
Speaker 3:  the Tesla round, 'cause Tesla had earnings. There's a lot of news
Speaker 3:  buried in Tesla earnings. I'll quickly start by saying as long as you're
Speaker 3:  talking about Elon X, the artist formerly known as Twitter
Speaker 3:  rolled out a plan where in two countries they're gonna start charging people
Speaker 3:  a dollar to sign up on the web to keep away the bots.
Speaker 3:  I dunno about you. If I for example, had access to a bot farm, I would
Speaker 3:  quickly realize that I could just bankrupt you on Musk with credit card fees.
Speaker 3:  I dunno this plan's gonna work. I don't have access to a bot farm. I wish.
Speaker 3:  No ill will to anyone. I'm just saying it's a thing. It seems like you open
Speaker 3:  the door to a particular kind of problem with this plan. We'll, we'll set
Speaker 3:  that aside. Yeah. Tesla earnings though are kind of like
Speaker 3:  all over the place. Do you wanna start with the Cybertruck or do you wanna
Speaker 3:  start with the money? Let's
Speaker 5:  Start with the Cybertruck
Speaker 3:  All, right. Here's the quote Elon Musk says we dug our own grave with the
Speaker 3:  Cybertruck
Speaker 3:  'cause it's so complicated and so hard to make
Speaker 4:  And ugly.
Speaker 3:  There's that aspect of it. I would say just
Speaker 3:  throwing
Speaker 4:  It out there, just a little feeling I have.
Speaker 3:  They're going to deliver the first few on
Speaker 3:  November 30th at the factory in Texas. The Gigafactory in Texas. They have
Speaker 3:  not said how much these will cost I or to whom they will be
Speaker 3:  delivered
Speaker 4:  Concerning.
Speaker 3:  You get the feeling these first, these are like show deliveries. Yeah. Like
Speaker 3:  Kimball Musk will take delivery of a Cybertruck. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  it's, it's like one of those things, it's like who is buying them for what
Speaker 3:  price? There's no price release. The only people buying them are obviously
Speaker 3:  a pre-existing relationship with Tesla and they will take delivery upon
Speaker 3:  delivery. The price will be revealed again, not how most people buy a car.
Speaker 3:  Just putting that out there.
Speaker 5:  Although I will say if any company can make that a thing,
Speaker 5:  it's Tesla like.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I think that's
Speaker 5:  The specific hold this company has over a subset of people where
Speaker 5:  they can just like, oh and
Speaker 3:  And like Ferrari,
Speaker 4:  I guess Ferrari does kind of do that now. Yeah. The
Speaker 3:  Ultra high-end hypercar manufacturers. It's like
Speaker 4:  Invitation only. Yes. And then you find out afterwards. Yeah, but look at
Speaker 4:  a Ferrari and look at a Cybertruck. Which one of those do you wanna have
Speaker 4:  enough money and spend it on it? Like if you're that rich,
Speaker 3:  I can't wait for that moment to be a TikTok with a picture of a Ferrari
Speaker 3:  in a picture of a Cybertruck
Speaker 5:  Also because
Speaker 4:  Which one do you want?
Speaker 5:  The, the Cybertruck that we've seen and we've now seen a lot of pictures
Speaker 5:  of these things in the wild. They look like crap. Like Yeah. Like yeah. I
Speaker 5:  think reasonable people can disagree on whether the Cybertruck is a cool
Speaker 5:  looking vehicle or not. It's personally not my thing, but I know it is lots
Speaker 5:  of people's thing. Fine. The ones they're making look like
Speaker 5:  shit. Like they, they are poorly made. Elon Musk has
Speaker 5:  talked a lot about the, like the machine tolerances and how close everything
Speaker 5:  has to be. They're, they're out there with like essentially like duct tape
Speaker 5:  holding the pieces together. Like they're not making this thing well right
Speaker 5:  now. And I think it's very funny that the people who are gonna get the first
Speaker 5:  ones are like the diehards. Either the Tesla diehards or the
Speaker 5:  Elon Musk diehards or the Cybertruck diehards. And they're essentially gonna
Speaker 5:  get cars that look like I built them and like that's not good. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So lemme read you this quote. The rest of the, we dug our own grave quote
Speaker 3:  and I want to see if people can make the connection to the other person who
Speaker 3:  spoke like this. We dug our own grave with the Cybertruck
Speaker 3:  at Musk. The Cybertruck is one of those special products that only comes
Speaker 3:  along once in a long while and special products that come along
Speaker 3:  once in a long while are just incredibly difficult to bring to market, to
Speaker 3:  reach volume and to be prosperous. So the first part of that
Speaker 3:  is Steve Jobs. Yep.
Speaker 3:  I'm very excited to be standing here to do today. Every now and again, you're
Speaker 3:  lucky to make one special product like the Mac or the iPod or the
Speaker 3:  iPhone,
Speaker 3:  that that's how we in, that's how we began The iPhone event is almost this
Speaker 3:  line. Exactly what he did not say at the end of the iPhone event was
Speaker 3:  the iPhone is gonna be incredibly difficult to bring to market in a way that
Speaker 3:  is prosperous.
Speaker 5:  We barely know how to make this thing.
Speaker 3:  And the thing is like Apple didn't make phones at the time. Tesla
Speaker 3:  is an existing high volume car company.
Speaker 5:  The iPhone at the time was barely existent. Like Right. The,
Speaker 5:  all the stories we've heard is like, it barely worked. It's a miracle. The
Speaker 5:  demos came off as well as it did. There were like two of them on earth. Nobody
Speaker 5:  knew how to do anything. And still Steve Jobs got up there and was like,
Speaker 5:  it's fine. We got this
Speaker 3:  Today. Apple revolutionizes the phone. Like that's what he's saying. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So I get and You know, you look at the cover of the book, there's a real
Speaker 3:  Steve Jobs thing happening with Musk.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 3:  You can see he's he's now he's saying the lines, right? He's, he's doing
Speaker 3:  covers. I'm just saying the Cybertruck the competition is
Speaker 3:  real and exists at volume and scale.
Speaker 3:  And the market for electric pickup trucks right now is
Speaker 3:  not great. Yeah. Like you can just go get an F one 50
Speaker 3:  lightning even in the middle of the U aaw strike because
Speaker 3:  the people who wanted them bought them. I think GM just cut back
Speaker 3:  production of its electric pickup trucks because they're, they're trying
Speaker 3:  to figure out where the demand is. Mm.
Speaker 4:  I asked a friend who only owns trucks. Yeah. Everybody in our
Speaker 4:  family, they're ranchers, so they all own trucks. Everybody around them only
Speaker 4:  drives trucks. You'll like don't have small children in their parking lots.
Speaker 4:  'cause all the trucks, the trucks are so big. Yeah. Yeah. And I said, are,
Speaker 4:  are you excited about the Cybertruck? It's coming? And she's like, what is
Speaker 4:  that? And I was like, Ooh, that's, yeah. That's like the
Speaker 4:  core. That should be the core audience. Like, oh, you, you drive it all over
Speaker 4:  the ranch and then you come back and you plug it in at night and they're
Speaker 4:  like, who? Yeah. So
Speaker 3:  I, I'm, a lot of people are gonna, a lot of people buy Tesla cars. We should
Speaker 3:  get in the rest of the earnings and we Yeah. Can dive into what that exactly
Speaker 3:  means. I'm just saying this product is entering an incredibly saturated market
Speaker 3:  full of very strong opinions. And its competition
Speaker 3:  did not sit still. I think what Musk is talking about here is like
Speaker 3:  stainless steel manufacturing techniques and like
Speaker 3:  unibody casting and that stuff makes the product special,
Speaker 3:  but then it still has to go be a product. And in
Speaker 3:  particular, Alex know pickup truck owners. I know pickup truck owners,
Speaker 3:  if you read pickup truck forms, these are some of the most customized, most
Speaker 3:  highly personalized vehicles that exist. And they
Speaker 4:  Spend a ton of money on them.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The amount of money you can throw at a pickup truck, they're, they're
Speaker 3:  like platforms unto themselves. And if this one isn't durable and it
Speaker 3:  doesn't work, whew.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Hey, do you think people in America have opinions about pickup trucks? Like
Speaker 3:  if you're driving your a hundred thousand dollars triangle down the road
Speaker 3:  and there's panel gaps, do you do, do you think that the
Speaker 3:  people who've been doing like screaming matches about Ford versus
Speaker 3:  GM for a hundred years Yeah. Are gonna have opinions about this? It's gonna
Speaker 3:  be amazing anyway. November 30th, the first deliveries.
Speaker 3:  But I don't think a regular person, let alone a car reviewer, is gonna get
Speaker 3:  their hands on this thing until next year. Yeah. I think that's right. Maybe
Speaker 3:  late next year. So that's the Cybertruck. There was no
Speaker 3:  discussion of the wiper. I know everyone wants to know nothing. There's only
Speaker 3:  one thing I care about. People have seen them, they've taken pictures of
Speaker 3:  the truck. I'm saying if you encounter one of these trucks, don't take pictures
Speaker 3:  of the side. We can know what shape that is.
Speaker 3:  Take pictures of the wiper man, get up in it. I want macro
Speaker 3:  shots of the wiper. Take the wiper off the
Speaker 3:  Cybertruck and bring it to Neli. I've heard a theory about how that wiper
Speaker 3:  is constructed and none of the images I've seen so far, confirmer,
Speaker 3:  is it gonna like
Speaker 4:  Whip?
Speaker 3:  I can't, I don't wanna, it's an unsourced. I don't even wanna put the energy
Speaker 3:  into the world. Okay. It's gonna whip. I need some photographs of this thing
Speaker 3:  up, up close and personal to, to confirm or deny the theory
Speaker 3:  that I've heard.
Speaker 3:  I'm not telling you what it's okay.
Speaker 3:  Other little Tesla earnings news, the actual money at Tesla
Speaker 3:  was looking pretty weird, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's good and bad all at the same time. I think the, the numbers
Speaker 5:  they reported, I, I just wrote it down. It was $23.4 billion in
Speaker 5:  revenue, which was up from the same time last year. Like they're, they're
Speaker 5:  making money, they're selling cars. Earnings weigh down. They made about
Speaker 5:  two little less than $2 billion in profit down from
Speaker 5:  3.3 billion on about the same amount of revenue last year.
Speaker 5:  So Tesla has a bunch of reasons for this, right? They're like,
Speaker 5:  they are making big upgrades in the factories. So production goes down a
Speaker 5:  little bit, which means you're gonna make less money.
Speaker 5:  Also something something AI and
Speaker 5:  supercomputers that I don't like, I don't know Elon, Musk just like says
Speaker 5:  robots a lot and people are like, oh, that makes sense for your earnings
Speaker 5:  and I don't care about that. The biggest thing is they keep cutting the
Speaker 5:  price. Like these used to be expensive cars and they're really not expensive
Speaker 5:  cars anymore in a lot of places. And I think what is happening
Speaker 5:  is that Tesla is selling more cars because it's making them
Speaker 5:  much, much cheaper to get in a time when that
Speaker 5:  is not a lot of company strategy at the moment, which has been sort of
Speaker 5:  fascinating. And Tesla for a long time had like crazy profit margins. Like
Speaker 5:  cars. Nila, you, you probably understand this much better than I do, but
Speaker 5:  my impression is cars are not a high margin industry and for Tesla they have
Speaker 5:  been, and that is starting to go away in a big way. It was like
Speaker 4:  20% margin in in some of the earlier years. And now it's
Speaker 4:  like, not
Speaker 3:  That most car, big car companies make all of their money on financing.
Speaker 3:  And so they, they have just sort of brought the margin of the cars themselves
Speaker 3:  down because they assume that you're gonna lease the car and
Speaker 3:  they'll make all the money on the lease and then you'll give the car back
Speaker 3:  to them and they'll sell it again at a much higher margin. So like
Speaker 3:  a company like B M W basically assumes they're gonna sell every three series
Speaker 3:  twice. And that's just like baked into the model. And that's why B M W in
Speaker 3:  particular is like CarPlay is here when you lease it and when you buy a pre-owned
Speaker 3:  one, it costs $40. Like Right. They're just, they're, they're able to monkey
Speaker 3:  with it. 'cause they know the dynamics of how they sell that vehicle are
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Are not what people expect. Tesla also
Speaker 3:  had the benefit early on of having
Speaker 3:  consolidated basically all of the car into a single compute stack. Right?
Speaker 3:  So like your average GM or Ford vehicle has like 5,000
Speaker 3:  suppliers in it and 5,000 different microcontrollers. And Tesla is like,
Speaker 3:  there's one, right? And, and they consolidate and it was more
Speaker 3:  expensive and it was a harder way to architect a car. And now it's You know
Speaker 3:  every car company co will tell you that's what they're gonna do too. But
Speaker 3:  they just had less stuff in the car. Yeah. Less engine stuff, less
Speaker 3:  transmission components, less exhaust stuff, but also more importantly,
Speaker 3:  less fewer microcontrollers and computers. And they owned all the
Speaker 3:  code. So they just had this ability to create all that margin. But now if
Speaker 3:  you look at Tesla's financing rates sky high while
Speaker 3:  the big automakers are like back to 0.9% 'cause
Speaker 3:  they just desperately want you to buy a car. You know. And it's like they're,
Speaker 3:  they're fighting a war there where they're just lowering prices. Elon went
Speaker 3:  on a rant about interest rates
Speaker 3:  'cause he hasn't, I don't think they have that business that like the
Speaker 3:  financing business the big car makers do. So like in the middle of this earnings,
Speaker 3:  they asked him something really silly. Right?
Speaker 5:  Let's see, he answered a question about the
Speaker 5:  Tesla and he compared it to the RAV four for some reason, which I thought
Speaker 5:  was interesting. So he says if our car costs the same as a RAV four, no one
Speaker 5:  would buy a RAV four. Or at least they would be very unlikely to, which is
Speaker 5:  a bold proclamation. But then, then he
Speaker 5:  said, I think since so many people who buy cars,
Speaker 5:  especially in the US can't afford to wait for
Speaker 5:  tax credits or something, our cars still much more expensive than a Rav
Speaker 5:  four when you look at it that way, which is like, I'm not a hundred percent
Speaker 5:  sure what he's talking about, but he's, he's got a lot of thoughts about
Speaker 5:  how people who make a lot of money don't understand what life is like for
Speaker 5:  people who don't make as much money. And I think the case he's trying to
Speaker 5:  make is that it's good that prices are going down, which like, yeah, sure
Speaker 5:  I am, I am pro this. I'm not sure how he ties
Speaker 5:  that back to interest rates. Maybe you can make sense.
Speaker 3:  So he's basically like, interest rates are too high, people can't finance
Speaker 3:  these cars. Right. And then he is saying our car's more expensive
Speaker 3:  and so it's even harder to finance them. And that's what I'm saying, Tesla
Speaker 3:  has not built up that like low zero interest
Speaker 3:  rate financing. Like that's just not where they've made their money. And
Speaker 3:  you can have like, they're valid opinions. So that's a better way to do it.
Speaker 3:  Like B M W selling every car twice because they assume the first per purchase
Speaker 3:  or will finance or lease it. You can have a lot of opinions, right? I I think
Speaker 3:  you should, but it's just true that in the market today,
Speaker 3:  Tesla just like sells cars.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, and and it doesn't sell them very well. Like, like this is
Speaker 4:  a company that is actually pretty bad at the whole finance and just like
Speaker 4:  right
Speaker 3:  On Tesla's website, they're like, here are the three ways you can buy this
Speaker 3:  car. You can finance it, you can lease it, or you can buy it in cash and
Speaker 3:  like they kind of want you to just buy it in cash. Right. And I think they
Speaker 3:  probably sold a lot of mono ss in cash actually.
Speaker 3:  And You know they want to take Bitcoin for their cars. Like they've pioneered
Speaker 3:  a new way and they don't move the prices and there's no negotiation, all
Speaker 3:  that stuff. But what is happening is he's bringing the price of the cars
Speaker 3:  down, reducing the margin, and his investors on the call are
Speaker 3:  asking him, are you also reducing the cost of the car to preserve
Speaker 3:  your margin? And he's got a quote here that says it's like Game
Speaker 3:  of Thrones for pennies. That's how he describes
Speaker 3:  reducing costs mean to Tesla, which is actually a great quote.
Speaker 3:  And I think what is happening is he's feeling all of this pressure from high
Speaker 3:  interest rates, weird economic environments. He calls credit card interest
Speaker 3:  rates. He's serious. Yeah, right. He he's got this real
Speaker 3:  populous streak in him. Yeah. And I, I think what he's
Speaker 3:  basically saying is, the market isn't fair to me
Speaker 3:  at Tesla. Everyone should want to buy my car. Like
Speaker 3:  why are you pushing a RAV four You know. Like you should, you should want
Speaker 3:  a model three, which
Speaker 4:  Is goofy because nobody wants a, I mean a lot of people obviously do want
Speaker 4:  a model three, but it's not a well-made car. Like
Speaker 4:  at a, a RAV four is pretty well made. It's not gonna have enormous panel
Speaker 4:  gaps. I can fit my whole hand in. It's true. I can't
Speaker 4:  guarantee the same on a Tesla.
Speaker 3:  Right. And then this all transitioned by the way, into a rant against work
Speaker 3:  from home where David, I believe he compared
Speaker 3:  people who work from home to Marie Antoinette, which is pretty good.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It is very good. Yeah. And he, I think the, the question was something relatively
Speaker 5:  benign. Like do you think that more people working from home
Speaker 5:  and thus not commuting and caring a lot about gas mileage in their cars might
Speaker 5:  have an effect on, on Tesla, which I would argue is like a perfectly fair
Speaker 5:  question to ask any car company right now. Yeah. And I think that the quote
Speaker 5:  was, yeah, he said these are some real Marie Antoinette vibes
Speaker 5:  from people who say, why doesn't everyone work from home? What about all
Speaker 5:  the people that have to come to the factory and build the cars? Which is
Speaker 5:  a funny thing to say from Elon Musk who has been like very demanding about
Speaker 5:  people coming back to work and all the people who have to go to the restaurant
Speaker 5:  and make your food and deliver your food. It's like, what are you talking
Speaker 5:  about? How detached from reality does the work from home crowd have to be
Speaker 5:  while they take advantage of those who cannot work from home?
Speaker 5:  Interesting. Again, sort of populous streak funny thing to say from the guy
Speaker 5:  who has been spelling very expensive electric cars for a really long time
Speaker 5:  and is also the richest man on earth. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And also by the way, the c e o of four companies, thus
Speaker 3:  by definition working remotely at three jobs at
Speaker 3:  all times
Speaker 5:  And has been very demanding about bringing people back to work.
Speaker 3:  Just just saying always working remote. Yeah. If you can, there's
Speaker 3:  one person who is definitionally always remote from at least one of his
Speaker 3:  jobs.
Speaker 3:  It's, he seems like he's getting it done. Hmm. We'll see. So there's
Speaker 3:  just a lot going on with Tesla. I think that company, particularly as some
Speaker 3:  of the Twitter debt comes due and there's lots of questions about how that
Speaker 3:  will be secured. Yeah. And whether those bankers, that's all Tesla money.
Speaker 3:  It's it's propping that up. So just a lot of pressure Yeah. On Tesla
Speaker 3:  right now. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it does seem like the, the push that they've been making is to
Speaker 5:  make like a thoroughly mainstream, everybody can afford it kind of car.
Speaker 5:  And you can see, I think he said something, it, it
Speaker 5:  was like digging a tunnel with a spoon I think was the way he phrased it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And like, I I believe him. Right. Like it's, I think it, it's going
Speaker 5:  every dollar to get out of that car from now on in
Speaker 5:  order to make it the price of a like Honda Civic is
Speaker 5:  gonna be a fight. And especially in a time when money
Speaker 5:  is hard to come by and lots of things are really expensive for lots of people.
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be interesting to see. Yeah. Which is like why you would think
Speaker 5:  the Cybertruck, which is presumably going to be very expensive, would be
Speaker 5:  like a solve for a lot of that stuff. Except they can't figure out how to
Speaker 5:  make it, which seems like a problem.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna be like a hundred thousand dollars. Right. I
Speaker 3:  If it ever comes out man, look, all I'm saying is I've heard a rumor about
Speaker 3:  the Cybertruck windshield wiper. Yeah. If you can just send me some
Speaker 3:  really close photos of it. I'm not gonna tell you what it's two
Speaker 3:  other lightning round pieces of the puzzle. Also important in the context
Speaker 3:  of Tesla in its future. Yes. You can argue about if the cars are
Speaker 3:  well-made or not, not You know. You're to argue they're not. It's really
Speaker 3:  just can you justify, can you, can you make an emotional argument about why
Speaker 3:  it doesn't matter? Sure. You can a lot, lots of people can. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  The moat for Teslas for so long is if you are in the market for an EV, they
Speaker 3:  have the single best charging network
Speaker 3:  and then they opened up the standard NACS, the Biden administration said,
Speaker 3:  do you want this money? You gotta open your network. Tesla chose the money.
Speaker 3:  They could have not chosen the money. I've, I've seen a lot of people say
Speaker 3:  the Biden administration forced Tesla into opening its network.
Speaker 3:  If dangling huge sums of money in saying I will give you this money if you
Speaker 3:  make this decision is is forced. That's fine. You can believe that that's
Speaker 3:  true. But that is the dynamic here. The Biden administration said we're gonna
Speaker 3:  invest in charging infrastructure, here's a bunch of money for it. And Tesla
Speaker 3:  said we'd like some of that money. So they open up their network.
Speaker 3:  ChargePoint is gonna do NACS plugs into its network
Speaker 3:  of
Speaker 3:  medium experiences.
Speaker 3:  That's Yeah. It's it's fair to say about all of the non Tesla charging network.
Speaker 3:  This
Speaker 4:  Is the one like you are Yeah. Behind the gas station that you have to charge
Speaker 3:  In ChargePoint and Electrify America are like the two big networks. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  ChargePoint is the one where like if you were in a small town and you're
Speaker 3:  like, is there a charger here? There's like one in front of the library and
Speaker 3:  You know like, it's running, it's running on one 20. It's like,
Speaker 3:  that's George point. Yeah. El America is like, we've built a thing
Speaker 3:  to launder VWs reputation for Keel Gate
Speaker 3:  and they're slightly better. Okay. This is, correct me if I'm wrong, but
Speaker 3:  this is broadly true of these two networks.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no that's, that's, that's basically right. And no one is very good
Speaker 5:  at making chargers that like work over time and aren't broken
Speaker 5:  or wildly complicated whenever you pull into them.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So, but ChargePoint is gonna do it. So, and they have a picture. The
Speaker 3:  funniest thing about this is Evie se charging plugs are the
Speaker 3:  least exciting thing to take a picture of, but they have to put photos
Speaker 3:  in their press releases. So it's just like a guy holding a block.
Speaker 4:  Like,
Speaker 3:  I dunno how to describe this. Like here's the photo of us with a Tesla charger
Speaker 3:  and it's like, here's a guy,
Speaker 4:  The photo, he's just hand out. It's like, it's just guy
Speaker 3:  Here's, he's almost charging the car but he isn't You know. It's like great,
Speaker 3:  they're gonna do it. There are other new chargers,
Speaker 3:  a company called Gravity has new, much smaller chargers designed for urban
Speaker 3:  environments. So really fast, actually faster than any car in America to
Speaker 3:  take right now. So you see there's a lot of action on the charging front
Speaker 3:  because of NACS. Yeah. B m W just said they're gonna do like a bunch of
Speaker 3:  other car companies are gonna start doing this by 2025. So you, you
Speaker 3:  see, okay, this thing will be the standard and we're going to
Speaker 3:  eventually stop talking about the supercharger network as a mote.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna start talking about charging cars and that that, I
Speaker 3:  think that's gonna change the dynamic of Tesla's yet again. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I I I don't think Tesla's long for this world. Like 1515 years.
Speaker 3:  You're crazy. Yeah. I'm sorry. I love you. It's crazy. And I end this by
Speaker 3:  saying this 'cause I know what you think. Yeah. You think that Teslas have
Speaker 3:  bad build quality and people are going to Yeah. Over time it'll, the
Speaker 4:  Batteries are all gonna die or explode and people are gonna be pissed.
Speaker 3:  That's true. All cars people love Range Rovers.
Speaker 3:  Mm.
Speaker 4:  They shouldn't
Speaker 3:  Like a modern Range Rover mostly does not work.
Speaker 4:  Looks pretty.
Speaker 3:  They look amazing. But I like went to buy one or
Speaker 3:  just like look at one 'cause it's like Becky's dream car. Yeah. And then
Speaker 3:  like people are jumping out bushes being like don't stay away.
Speaker 4:  My dad was not one of them. He would say Katie
Speaker 3:  Has one. Yeah. He'd
Speaker 4:  Be like get not anymore.
Speaker 3:  We did not buy a Range Rover. Good. I'm just saying you right now. But I'm
Speaker 3:  just saying I people love cars. Like they keep selling
Speaker 3:  Range Rovers, they love them.
Speaker 4:  That's Tesla's future.
Speaker 3:  They keep selling Ford and Chevy pickup trucks. Tesla has fans like that
Speaker 3:  way longer than 15 years. Yeah, that's All right? We gotta take a break.
Speaker 3:  More lightning round to come but this time they're actually gonna be bolts
Speaker 3:  of lightning. Not extended deliberations. We'll
Speaker 3:  grab it.
Speaker 3:  All. right? We're back. It has been a very philosophical sort of lightning
Speaker 3:  show trail.
Speaker 4:  Like let's go back to my, my feelings on Tesla's
Speaker 3:  Longit. What is a car?
Speaker 3:  All, right? I've got a few telecom lightning round ones. A few.
Speaker 3:  Just a couple. I'm gonna try to bundle 'em together. All, right? So today
Speaker 3:  McKenna Kelly is in Washington DC as we speak, watching the s e c
Speaker 3:  vote to restore net neutrality, which is not done. But
Speaker 3:  Biden finally fully staffed his FCC did by
Speaker 3:  the pure failure on Joe Biden's part to just not have a
Speaker 3:  functioning FCC for most of his administration. Yep. Thus, thus far. But
Speaker 3:  he finally pulled it off. He's got all the people, they're gonna go do it.
Speaker 3:  A lot of people are gonna tell you it didn't matter, we haven't had it this
Speaker 3:  long. The telecom companies didn't do bad things. No one's
Speaker 3:  straddled their data. They're lying to you. They're lying to you. They're
Speaker 3:  lying to you for two reasons. One, there's a bunch of state net neutrality
Speaker 3:  laws in the books in New York and California and all these other big populous
Speaker 3:  places. And two, the telecom companies have done a bunch
Speaker 3:  of dumb dumb things and blown a lot of money
Speaker 3:  and attempted to do bad things. They were just such
Speaker 3:  horrible ideas. They blew up in their faces and resulted
Speaker 3:  in massive layoffs across the industries that they covered. For example,
Speaker 3:  a company called at t I dunno if you never heard of them. They're just a
Speaker 3:  little, little thing you can You know. A funny thing about at t I dunno if
Speaker 3:  people know this, you can actually split it up into hundreds of little
Speaker 3:  companies and it will slowly reform over time. You know it'll just
Speaker 3:  blob back together. It there is again. And one of
Speaker 5:  Those companies will be H B O for 10 minutes.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's amazing. Anyhow,
Speaker 4:  It's like
Speaker 3:  Mercury lightning round. Anyhow, at t bought
Speaker 3:  Time Warner in order to zero rate data on its network and make
Speaker 3:  you watch a gray scale Justice league
Speaker 5:  Because my data cap was the reason I was worried about streaming services
Speaker 5:  that tracks
Speaker 3:  It's a real, it's a real thing. Anyhow, so
Speaker 3:  net neutrality going back in the books, if you are the sort of person who's
Speaker 3:  generally worried about censorship on the internet,
Speaker 3:  I would say that free speech online a set of keywords
Speaker 3:  that usually implies people slightly different politics than mine. But
Speaker 3:  if you are worried about censorship on the internet, you should be worried
Speaker 3:  about it at the pipe layer. Most of all because it is the least transparent,
Speaker 3:  the the least accountable, the least competitive part of
Speaker 3:  the internet stack. You should say, okay, we should definitely not have any
Speaker 3:  control over data here. Now I guess I firm, I firmly believe this,
Speaker 3:  that that is an inappropriate place for any kind of censorship or throttling
Speaker 3:  or business model interference with information. So that's what we're doing.
Speaker 3:  Again, McKenna's there we're gonna have a weird fight about it. Brendan Carr
Speaker 3:  classic bad faith. FCC Huckster is like giving PowerPoint
Speaker 3:  presentations about, well everything's great with internet access in America
Speaker 3:  that we're gonna cover you again. Does it have
Speaker 4:  Like a little sponsored by at and t at the bottom of the deck?
Speaker 3:  It's just, it's a death star.
Speaker 3:  Similarly, you might have noticed that I've paid a lot of attention to
Speaker 3:  the end of the five G era as I've taken the calling it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I was like, Neil is looking towards seven G. What are you talking about?
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Whenever I get one of the PR emails about talking about six G Innovations,
Speaker 3:  I'm like, you dummies, I've been on nine G this whole time.
Speaker 3:  Turn that frown upside down. Nokia is cutting
Speaker 3:  14,000 jobs. By the way, do You know what Nokia tells? 80 success employees.
Speaker 3:  They became an infrastructure provider and there
Speaker 3:  was a thought that Huawei would take over the world of infrastructure and
Speaker 3:  then we like basically banned Huawei. The Europeans basically banned Huawei
Speaker 3:  from providing cellular infrastructure. So companies like Siemens and Nokia
Speaker 3:  all invested heavily into five G equipment. That's the stuff that's running
Speaker 3:  right now. Nokia has now cut 14,000 jobs.
Speaker 3:  The reason
Speaker 3:  the operators have found it challenging to monetize their five G investments.
Speaker 3:  That's
Speaker 5:  A quote. Oh that's a quote.
Speaker 3:  That's a quote from, that's a quote from the c e O of Nokia. This is why
Speaker 3:  we're cutting 14,000 jobs. The operators invested so heavily into five G
Speaker 3:  with no plan. Yeah. To make money
Speaker 3:  and now they're cutting back on their further investment
Speaker 3:  because there's no money here. So we know Kia are cutting 14,000 drops.
Speaker 3:  Here's where you could put a bunch of five G towers. Rural America,
Speaker 4:  But the backhaul. Sure.
Speaker 3:  But I'm just saying like what are the promises of these networks
Speaker 3:  is that you will bring broadband to more people more effectively.
Speaker 3:  That is not done. We have lots of listeners, readers in rural America. We,
Speaker 3:  Alex and I both care about this quite a bit. Yeah. McKenna caress about it
Speaker 3:  quite a bit. We pay a lot of attention to it. The broadband deployments,
Speaker 3:  I don't
Speaker 5:  Care. Just apparently, I don't care at all about rural broadband. I'm not
Speaker 5:  interested.
Speaker 3:  You're a city slicker Pierce,
Speaker 4:  City slicker urban
Speaker 3:  Cowboy. David Pierce
Speaker 4:  All. right. Little John Travolta.
Speaker 5:  What floor of a New York skyscraper are you guys on right now?
Speaker 3:  Anyhow, all I'm saying is it, it didn't happen. They did the thing
Speaker 3:  that they always do. Yeah. They blew a bunch of money. They made a bunch
Speaker 3:  of promises. They served urban areas and covered the highways of
Speaker 3:  America
Speaker 4:  And nowhere else. I would argue Internet's actually gotten
Speaker 4:  worse in rural America. Interesting. Like especially phones
Speaker 4:  used to. I could drive from one
Speaker 4:  town to another and my mom's to visit my mom have phone the whole way.
Speaker 4:  And now every time I go down this little hill I say, I'll call you back at
Speaker 4:  the end of this hill every time. It's very consistent.
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 3:  True. If you stand on a street corner here in New York City under a streetlight.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You can get like 10 gigs down.
Speaker 4:  I just tell my mom, they're like, go, go up to New York. Stand
Speaker 3:  Under, get to that street corner. Look, all I'm saying is the amount of
Speaker 3:  nationalist rhetoric that we heard about five G. Yep. We have to win the
Speaker 3:  race. Otherwise China will win the race and then they'll be doing the robot
Speaker 3:  surgery and you'll be, I don't know, working with a
Speaker 3:  shovel for the rest of your life. Do you remember this? I remember it very
Speaker 3:  clearly. It was last week and I'm still on the hunt
Speaker 3:  for five G applications that require five G at and t released a helmet. They
Speaker 3:  did G at university. I think that's how you pronounce it. They made a
Speaker 3:  helmet for, for football players who are deaf and has
Speaker 3:  displays in the visor so they can like call plays and very cool. Where,
Speaker 4:  Where, where's the football played? Like in rural
Speaker 4:  America. It's
Speaker 3:  True. It just, I'm just like looking at this thing, I'm like this is not,
Speaker 3:  you don't need five G for this helmet.
Speaker 4:  You just need wifi.
Speaker 3:  Good wifi would've gotten you there. Right. This is kind of
Speaker 3:  the level that we're at with this technology to this day. We're
Speaker 3:  pretending that five G is enabling applications. Well and
Speaker 5:  It's part of the reason stuff like the Noia news is so disappointing is that
Speaker 5:  we were promised that the reason five G was gonna win was because
Speaker 5:  it was so deployable. You don't have to dig trenches in the same way you
Speaker 5:  can. You can actually get this thing to people more easily and they
Speaker 5:  can use it using like devices, infrastructure. They already have
Speaker 5:  sounded good. And now to see everyone pulling back because they can't figure
Speaker 5:  out how to like immediately monetize this small speed increase
Speaker 5:  that people like the three of us got from five G means
Speaker 5:  the people we're talking about who actually could have benefited from
Speaker 5:  five G being rolled out in their towns where digging trenches is hard work
Speaker 5:  not gonna happen. That sucks. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I just can't there the pivot to six G is coming so hard. Just wait,
Speaker 3:  what? What
Speaker 4:  Will the surgery be?
Speaker 3:  They're like, they appeal the carrot. It's gonna be amazing. All, right?
Speaker 3:  Cranz, what's yours?
Speaker 4:  Okay, so w w Netflix raised prices again, which
Speaker 5:  We knew was coming. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 4:  We knew. We knew it's happening. It's only for two
Speaker 4:  of the plans this time. One is, is the basic plan. It's gonna
Speaker 4:  be 1199. The other is the premium plan, which gets you
Speaker 4:  four K and everything that's gonna be 2299. Ooh,
Speaker 3:  That's right on the,
Speaker 4:  That's I see. I'm upset but at the same time
Speaker 4:  I thought I was paying that already for that. So I'm like,
Speaker 4:  this sucks. But
Speaker 3:  All, right. Disclosures. I have an at t account. I have for some time. I'm
Speaker 3:  a Netflix producer.
Speaker 3:  We made Netflix show, it's called The Future Hub. We can go watch on Netflix
Speaker 3:  for any number of prices apparently, including with ads. There
Speaker 4:  Is a little, a little silver lining.
Speaker 3:  We've done a little telecom dunking and I've talked about net neutrality
Speaker 3:  Comcast through its subsidiary n BBC Universal and Starbucks Media.
Speaker 3:  I think that's it for now. Yeah. We'll see what else we have to cut into.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Comcast provides my internet and it's very slow most of the time. There you
Speaker 5:  go.
Speaker 3:  We've gotten some notes that like you're not taking 'em seriously. Those
Speaker 3:  are serious disclosures. Those are all real conflicts that you can evaluate.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. We want you to know
Speaker 4:  The, the only kinda like bright side of this is the basic plan
Speaker 4:  or the No, the ad supported plan. The 6 99 plan used
Speaker 4:  to, you couldn't get offline downloads. So if you were gonna go be on a plane
Speaker 4:  sucks to be you. No,
Speaker 3:  You do you get the ads to the offline downloads. I don't know. The idea of
Speaker 3:  paying money to download someone else's ads is a lot that said we run,
Speaker 5:  That seems fine To me that's like, that doesn't bother me at all. And they'll,
Speaker 5:  they'll get good at like dynamic ads the way that like podcasts work. There's
Speaker 5:  a good chance if you're listening to this show, you've heard dynamically
Speaker 5:  placed ads based on what you downloaded. If
Speaker 3:  There's one thing that I've list I've heard from our listeners is that our
Speaker 3:  dynamic ads work great. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's perfect. Nothing ever goes wrong with dynamic ad placement, but no,
Speaker 5:  what's truly wild to me about this is, so the, the thing you get
Speaker 5:  for the premium price, which is $23 now, is you get four
Speaker 5:  K streaming and I believe you get four at a
Speaker 5:  time. So like you can you up to four people can be
Speaker 5:  watching. Which isn't really true because of the way that the password sharing
Speaker 5:  stuff works. So like I used to have the four screens account because it
Speaker 5:  was feasible that four different people might be using our account at the
Speaker 5:  same time. That's probably not realistic for most people anymore. So I think
Speaker 5:  you're already probably overpaying, but that's also the only way to get four
Speaker 5:  K. So if that's a thing you care about, Netflix just knows it can charge
Speaker 5:  you whatever you want. But you can now get the ad
Speaker 5:  supported version on six screens for
Speaker 5:  less than the cost of the premium account. Like it, it's just so transparent
Speaker 5:  that Netflix will charge you whatever it has to in order to get you to
Speaker 5:  switch to ads. Like that's just what it is going to be. They're going to
Speaker 5:  price gouge you until you switch to ads. Yep. And the upper limit of that
Speaker 5:  godly nose like premium might cost $50 in a year because if
Speaker 5:  there will be pe it's like the people who still pay for a o l on disks, there
Speaker 5:  will be some of those people. Yeah. And Netflix will gouge them for every
Speaker 5:  penny they're worth.
Speaker 3:  So we, I understand the dynamics of this pretty easily, right? We have a
Speaker 3:  lot of people who ask us why you can't just pay us turn off ads. And
Speaker 3:  the answer is if you just look at the revenue
Speaker 3:  drop that would cause the price I would have to make you pay
Speaker 5:  More than you think
Speaker 3:  Be too high. Especially in a market where like
Speaker 3:  the basic thing that we provide, which is tech news is readily available
Speaker 3:  for free all the time. Like kids on TikTok, just reading Verge
Speaker 3:  articles is a thing that I, I can't price outta the market. Right. I think
Speaker 3:  Netflix is discovering the same thing, but
Speaker 4:  The bigger issue is for me as a big media
Speaker 4:  nerd is four K. The only way I can get four K is to be price
Speaker 4:  gouged and like
Speaker 3:  Right. 'cause they know that, that there's like perfect price elasticity
Speaker 3:  there. If you want four K Yep. If you're us, yeah. There's a
Speaker 3:  0% chance I'm paying anyone anything for less than four K. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I, the, the, the only reason I do it is for four k I don't have four
Speaker 4:  TVs running Netflix in my house all the time. I should,
Speaker 3:  You get those data caps Alex,
Speaker 4:  Just hit 'em. Use that Fios and
Speaker 5:  I, I guarantee you Netflix is going to spend the next three years
Speaker 5:  testing that theory of you. Like the question is, will you
Speaker 5:  cancel before you switch to hd? Yeah. That's the thing Netflix
Speaker 5:  is trying to figure out.
Speaker 4:  Yes, I will cancel before I switch to hd.
Speaker 5:  I don't believe you and I don't think Netflix does either, but we're, we're
Speaker 5:  gonna test that theory.
Speaker 4:  They don't know. What I know about websites on the internet
Speaker 4:  sucks to be,
Speaker 3:  We're just gonna start writing headlines that are like the four K on
Speaker 3:  h b o Max is free. You know. Yeah. Like just shaming them into
Speaker 3:  competing. That's, that's our function in journalism. It's
Speaker 4:  True. It's true. David,
Speaker 3:  Take your Spotify victory lap.
Speaker 5:  Mine's very quick and it's just because I'm very proud of myself. I said
Speaker 5:  on this show not terribly long ago that Spotify
Speaker 5:  should stop mucking around with trying to be the TikTok for audio
Speaker 5:  or whatever that means. And just try to win at music because for
Speaker 5:  all of the stuff going on in the world and all of the audio things out there,
Speaker 5:  we actually don't have a really great music app at this moment in time.
Speaker 5:  There are a lot of like Apple music nerds who are gonna email me and tell
Speaker 5:  me why I'm wrong. But you're wrong. Apple Music is not a good product either.
Speaker 5:  They're all bad. And Spotify appears to be
Speaker 5:  slowly taking my advice. It has sold merch through
Speaker 5:  Spotify for a long time. If that's a thing you want to do, there are tools
Speaker 5:  for that. But it has now rolling out a, a dedicated
Speaker 5:  hub for artist merch on Spotify.
Speaker 5:  This is a thing you're gonna start to see a lot of, you're gonna see merch,
Speaker 5:  you're gonna see ticket sales, you're gonna see all kinds of ancillary.
Speaker 5:  So you like this music, here's how we can make money from you stuff coming
Speaker 5:  to Spotify. But I just, I, Andrew Marino, our producer went back and
Speaker 5:  found the TikTok that we published of me saying this and I was exactly right
Speaker 5:  and I'm very proud of myself And also, good job, Spotify. Stop trying
Speaker 5:  to pretend that all the other stuff you're doing is gonna work. Exclusive
Speaker 5:  podcasts. Were a stupid business. You wasted a lot of money.
Speaker 5:  Merch is actually gonna work.
Speaker 3:  Tech companies are really bad at being media companies. The only tech companie
Speaker 3:  that's ever been good at being a media company, Netflix, you don't think
Speaker 3:  they're a good media.
Speaker 5:  I think there are a lot of people who argue. Netflix was never really a tech
Speaker 5:  company. That Netflix was always a media company masquerading as a tech company.
Speaker 5:  It
Speaker 4:  Was never a tech company and
Speaker 5:  Got valued like a tech company.
Speaker 4:  I would agree. But it's also, it's a bad media company. It is
Speaker 4:  not a very well run media company because it can't put out bangers.
Speaker 4:  It puts out like maybe
Speaker 5:  Yeah, but you're paying $23 a month for that Alex.
Speaker 4:  I know. It's because I'm watching Ugly Betty right now and I don't have it
Speaker 4:  on D v d
Speaker 3:  All. right. Well, email us. Tell us, tell us if you will quit.
Speaker 3:  Tell us your price Netflix before you drop four K I'm actually really curious
Speaker 3:  where, where the audience is on this. I this is a
Speaker 3:  self-selecting group. I think I already know the answer, but I I would like
Speaker 3:  a little data from the VIRs audience. Will you quit Netflix
Speaker 3:  before you downgrade from the four K plan and tell me why.
Speaker 3:  'cause I'm, I'm sort of desperate to know. I think I'm gone before I lose
Speaker 3:  four K. I don't believe that for one second. Yeah. I have a, I'm married
Speaker 3:  to someone who watches a lot of comedy on Netflix who probably doesn't care.
Speaker 3:  And that peacock, this is gonna be a, this is gonna be a whole conversation.
Speaker 3:  We have
Speaker 2:  Frazier's on
Speaker 3:  Paramount. We're gonna be, we're watching like ads supported SD comedy specials
Speaker 3:  in our house before I drop this thing. All, right? That's it. We're way over.
Speaker 3:  Liam's spitting mad. He's not actually, he's smiling. He loves it.
Speaker 3:  Everyone write Liam a nice note, a nice note. We'll see it later.
Speaker 3:  Lots of great stuff on the site this week. There's a bunch of YouTube news
Speaker 3:  actually, like incremental YouTube changes that are really interesting, including
Speaker 3:  an AI feature where when people say like, and subscribe, the bell starts
Speaker 3:  shaking, which is just hilarious. Like a perfect creator economy moment.
Speaker 3:  Gen Tuy has a great piece on Ecobee and it's like ever
Speaker 3:  expanding ambitions in the home. She compares it to Nest. The headline is
Speaker 3:  it's becoming the company Nest wanted to be. If You know anything about me
Speaker 3:  and The Verge You know that we start, our first big feature was on
Speaker 3:  Nest. Like I wrote it with Tony Fidel and I remember him telling me his
Speaker 3:  ambitions for the company. It obviously like failed in spectacular fashion
Speaker 3:  because of Google So. I loved this piece about Ecobee B and how they're building
Speaker 3:  up their ecosystem. Very cool. All kinds of other great stuff on
Speaker 3:  the site. And then we would be remiss to not note that
Speaker 3:  there's a war happening in Israel and Gaza. We have a lot of coverage with
Speaker 3:  the information space of that war on our site. There's a lot going on with
Speaker 3:  misinformation. Misinformation. I just need to take a break
Speaker 3:  from it. During The Vergecast, I, many of our listeners have told us the
Speaker 3:  same, but there's a lot of coverage on the site. We're taking that stuff
Speaker 3:  seriously. Go look at that. Particularly what is going on
Speaker 3:  in Europe with the Digital Services Act and the European governments. Being
Speaker 3:  able to issue take down requests of social networks is new
Speaker 3:  and it's gonna have a lot of implications for a lot of things in the future.
Speaker 3:  Okay. That's all on the site. That's it. That's for our Chest rock roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.