# Transcript
ID: eb42cb08-1e5f-47e5-a2e5-7b080499aa52
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Good Pixels, better Watches, great Chromebooks
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5153055419752692191/3858394519982645826/s93290-US-5342s-1697047553.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of AI-generated wallpapers:
03:22 - The Verge's David Pierce chats with Allison Johnson about her review of the Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro.
Pixel 8 and 8 Pro review: in Google we trust?
29:18 - Victoria Song joins the show to discuss her review of the updated Pixel Watch 2.
Google Pixel Watch 2 review: better battery, better watch
56:02 - Monica Chin stops by to explain the new "Chromebook Plus" certification on higher-end Chromebooks.
Chromebook Plus is Google’s new certification for premium Chromebooks
1:22:42 - Keep listening for the Vergecast Hotline question all about music playlists.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (1 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To, The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of AI generated
Speaker 2:  wallpapers. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am currently wandering
Speaker 2:  around my house redoing I guess what you would call my
Speaker 2:  charging strategy. If you hear that and you think, David, who has a charging
Speaker 2:  strategy, that's ridiculous. A, I agree with you and B, you're
Speaker 2:  totally wrong. So the way I've set it up is that basically instead of just
Speaker 2:  like having a charger that I use, I have a bunch of
Speaker 2:  like charging stations around the house. There's one in the kitchen
Speaker 2:  where a couple of things are plugged in. There's one upstairs, there, have
Speaker 2:  one in the basement. There's one right next to the couch. And basically the
Speaker 2:  idea is like where you are most of the time, you should be able to charge
Speaker 2:  things. This is great now because my wife and I both have
Speaker 2:  phones that use U S B C. She's on a Pixel. I'm on an iPhone right now and
Speaker 2:  so I get to just redo some things. The most annoying part of this process
Speaker 2:  has been Apple Watch chargers because actually I need to charge the Apple
Speaker 2:  watch probably more than I need to charge my phone. But having a bunch of
Speaker 2:  those like pucks sitting around is sort of stupid. So I'm reworking the
Speaker 2:  whole system. I bought a bunch of those big anchor wall warts that
Speaker 2:  have a couple of plugs in them that look really nice. It works great. Cannot
Speaker 2:  recommend enough spending way too much time overthinking where all of your
Speaker 2:  charging cables are in your house. Anyway, we have an awesome show coming
Speaker 2:  up for you today. We're gonna talk all about Google gadgets. We're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk about the Pixel eight and Pixel eight pro reviews that are coming out.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna talk about the Pixel Watch two, which I think is sneakily kind
Speaker 2:  of fascinating and maybe very good. And then we're gonna talk about this
Speaker 2:  new Chromebook Plus designation that Google just put out where
Speaker 2:  it thinks it can help make better Chromebooks and convince you to buy better,
Speaker 2:  slightly more expensive. Chromebooks, all of that is coming up in just a
Speaker 2:  second, but I have this one 10 foot long U S
Speaker 2:  B C cable somewhere. It's braided, it's awesome, it was really
Speaker 2:  unnecessarily expensive, but it makes it so that you can sit anywhere on
Speaker 2:  the couch and charge your phone. It's the dream except I don't know where
Speaker 2:  it's anymore, so I'm gonna go find it. Wish me luck. This is The Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  I went to the precinct and I said, look, I
Speaker 3:  wanted to talk about a murder that I think happened happened
Speaker 4:  In 1993. Travell Coleman shot a man but was never
Speaker 4:  a suspect. He kept the secret for years and years.
Speaker 5:  I've heard of people turning themselves in, but it's usually soon
Speaker 5:  thereafter the crime. I've never experienced anything like someone coming
Speaker 5:  forward 17 years after the fact. So no, this is absolutely extraordinary
Speaker 4:  Here. TLS story on the latest episode of Criminal Listen
Speaker 4:  wherever you get your podcasts.
Speaker 6:  Hey, this is Neela Patel, editor-in-chief of The Verge and host of Decoder.
Speaker 6:  This week in the Decoder Feed we're dropping interviews from Vox Media's
Speaker 6:  code conference, an exclusive event for some of the most influential names
Speaker 6:  in tech. I talked to a lot of folks like A M D C E O, Lisa Sue. We're
Speaker 4:  Betting on
Speaker 7:  What the, the next big thing in AI is.
Speaker 6:  Getty Images, c e o, Craig Peters, I think there are others that are just
Speaker 6:  kind of off doing what they want to do and damn the consequences. And
Speaker 6:  Kevin Scott, Microsoft c t o and executive vice president
Speaker 6:  of ai. Like honestly like that would've been a little bit better if there
Speaker 6:  had been more ai. We had a blast over the next few days. We'll bring you
Speaker 6:  those interviews and more recorded live on the stage at the code conference.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back, great news. I found the cable, all my stuff is gonna
Speaker 2:  be so charged. I really by the way, cannot recommend enough having
Speaker 2:  one wildly long charging cable. It's the kind of
Speaker 2:  thing that just like makes a bunch of things in life easier when
Speaker 2:  you're traveling or sitting on the couch or whatever. We love a 10 foot charger
Speaker 2:  in this house. Alright, let's get into today's show. The first thing I wanna
Speaker 2:  talk about is the Pixel eight and Pixel eight Pro. Google's latest phones,
Speaker 2:  they came out last week. Reviews are hitting now. Lot going on as far as
Speaker 2:  we can tell. These phones are really about two things, the cameras
Speaker 2:  and the ai. We've been hearing about these phones for months and I've been
Speaker 2:  wondering over the last week if that's the reason I was left a little,
Speaker 2:  not disappointed but I guess underwhelmed by the stuff Google
Speaker 2:  announced. If not underwhelmed then like Whelmed You know.
Speaker 2:  But as they say, the proof is in the pudding. Allison Johnson has been using
Speaker 2:  and reviewing the two phones to see if all that camera and AI
Speaker 2:  stuff adds up to a winner in the Android world. So
Speaker 2:  let's find out. Allison's here. Hi Allison. Hello. We have the Pixel eight
Speaker 2:  in the Pixel eight Pro and one of the things I feel like you have to
Speaker 2:  do in this process is like figure out how to explain kind of which
Speaker 2:  is which and which is for what. Where have you landed? How do you sort of
Speaker 2:  explain the difference between the Pixel eight and the Pixel eight Pro?
Speaker 10:  I think the thing I landed on like literally five minutes ago is that
Speaker 10:  it feels like with the main Pixel eight, Google is trying to position
Speaker 10:  it as like the mainstream phone. Like the one I would
Speaker 10:  recommend to my mom or dad when they're Pixel seven A
Speaker 10:  or six A, like gives out in X number of years, whatever. And
Speaker 10:  then if you're eight Pixel nerd, which I
Speaker 10:  love the Pixel nerds, but the You know they're nerds. That's the eight pro
Speaker 10:  and that's where you get like all the extra things and it's, it's a
Speaker 10:  more of a distance between the two of them than there's been in previous
Speaker 10:  years, which I think was a little like not everybody felt great
Speaker 10:  about that. Sort of felt like Pixel eight was missing out on a
Speaker 10:  bunch of stuff that the eight pros suddenly getting. I was like why? And
Speaker 10:  they both got more expensive this year, so that's sort of made it harder
Speaker 10:  to swallow. But that's where I've landed I think. I think it's making sense
Speaker 10:  as like Pixel eight is just kind of might be the phone for everybody.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And that's, I mean that's, that's a little bit like what Samsung has
Speaker 2:  been doing with the SSS and the Ultras. Like it's kind of landed in that
Speaker 2:  same place I would say. And I think that works. Like the alternative would
Speaker 2:  be like the iPhone where there are four models and I feel like I have no
Speaker 2:  idea how to explain to people which iPhone to buy. So the idea of like there's
Speaker 2:  one that is one price and then for like a few hundred dollars
Speaker 2:  more and a whole bunch of extra stuff. You get this other one?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, the Normie phone. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It works.
Speaker 10:  I think so. Okay.
Speaker 2:  So we gotta, we should just talk about the camera first. Yeah 'cause that's
Speaker 2:  the thing, right? I feel like the two stories of this phone are camera and
Speaker 2:  AI and there's kind of an overlapping Venn diagram there. I have a bunch
Speaker 2:  of specific questions but give me just some overall impressions of the
Speaker 2:  Pixel eight and pro cameras.
Speaker 10:  So it's so weird you have to kind of think of it as like a three
Speaker 10:  part thing because there's the hardware, which there have been
Speaker 10:  some upgrades on both models to the hardware. There's like a new
Speaker 10:  main camera sensor, new lens, like some little
Speaker 10:  upgrades here and there. Nothing earth shattering but there's that.
Speaker 10:  There's all the software stuff that the camera app itself does. And then
Speaker 10:  there's the things in Google Photos, which is the whole Pandora's
Speaker 10:  box of what is a photo.
Speaker 2:  We'll do that last because I do, I do wanna talk about that and I'm very
Speaker 2:  curious like how all of that actually works in practice. But I agree that
Speaker 2:  that is kind of a separate thing. So let's come back to that. But like just
Speaker 2:  the actual photos coming outta the camera. What have you seen so far? It's
Speaker 10:  Very Pixel to me. I think it's kind of settled into this, like
Speaker 10:  you sometime get like a cooler tone in your photos.
Speaker 10:  I feel like that was more pronounced in like previous years on the Pixel
Speaker 10:  and I still see some of that creeping in on some of my shots. But overall
Speaker 10:  I'm just like happy with them. Skin tones can kind of
Speaker 10:  look like a little waxy sometimes, but I like,
Speaker 10:  there's sort of like outliers but I think I'm just, we're overall happy
Speaker 10:  with it and if when it fails it kind of does so in a
Speaker 10:  predictable way. It's not kind of just like throwing a
Speaker 10:  purple shade into a sunset like other phone will do.
Speaker 10:  So yeah, I think it's kind of reliable. It's, it's occasionally like
Speaker 10:  very good and most of the time it's like just pretty good at
Speaker 10:  everything.
Speaker 2:  Okay. If I'm remembering this right, the big spec difference between the
Speaker 2:  eight and the eight pro is the telephoto camera, right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Have you, have you noticed the difference like when you're using the
Speaker 2:  eight, do you find yourself being like, oh I wish I had the pro for this
Speaker 2:  so I could use the the Zoom
Speaker 10:  A little bit? Yeah and that's the thing with the, with like an iPhone
Speaker 10:  15 and then the 15 Pro Max You know like a five time
Speaker 10:  telephoto zoom, which is what is on the eight pro in the iPhone
Speaker 10:  15 Pro Max is like, it feels like a real
Speaker 10:  zoom lens. You can actually get like quite a bit closer to something. You
Speaker 10:  can do a real kind of like compression shot.
Speaker 10:  My husband was running in a race like of for funsies five K this
Speaker 10:  weekend. You can get that like cool shot of like the starting line
Speaker 10:  and a bunch of people in the foreground. You just can't do that
Speaker 10:  with a three times lens or no telephoto lens, just
Speaker 10:  just what you get on the Pixel eight. You do get that like
Speaker 10:  two times lossless crop zoom on both of them and that was
Speaker 10:  introduced last year. It's good. Most of the time I have
Speaker 10:  like notes on it. That is one thing that is like I think a
Speaker 10:  lot of people would appreciate having that and you just kind of have to
Speaker 10:  make a call whether you're gonna shell out quite a bit more
Speaker 10:  money carry around a bigger phone or just sort of settle for
Speaker 10:  for what you get.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I, it seems sort of silly to say that the difference between
Speaker 2:  like two and three X and five x is so big but
Speaker 2:  it really is like it goes from, I'm taking the photo slightly closer to
Speaker 2:  I'm actually taking a different looking photo. Yeah. Which
Speaker 2:  is a bigger deal than I think I've given it credit for. Like I in the, the
Speaker 2:  iPhone cycle this year got a 15 pro instead of a 15 pro max and just
Speaker 2:  noodling around with other people's. I kind of regret it. I don't Yeah. Want
Speaker 2:  the bigger screen normally and this is why like I just wish for more feature
Speaker 2:  parody in general because I want the smaller screen but all the camera stuff
Speaker 2:  and you just kind of can't have that in life right now.
Speaker 10:  Why can't we have it All?
Speaker 2:  Right. I just want all the things. Yeah. But in general you, you think
Speaker 2:  that we've settled into kind of knowing what a Pixel is like? I feel like
Speaker 2:  at this point if you show me a photo I can tell you
Speaker 2:  10 times outta 10 whether it's a Samsung photo or an Apple photo. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  I feel like Pixel has been kind of increasingly that way too.
Speaker 2:  Do you think it's as distinct a, a vibe as
Speaker 2:  Samsung and Apple are at this point? I think so.
Speaker 10:  I think it's like it's inoffensive. That's kind of how I would describe
Speaker 10:  it. Samsung has a look, iPhone kind of has a look
Speaker 10:  and Pixels sort of somewhere in the middle and occasionally like kind of
Speaker 10:  goes off in one direction or another. And I, I'm annoyed
Speaker 10:  with portrait mode. I really want that to be better. Like, oh no the next
Speaker 10:  time it's like it's fine, it's inoffensive.
Speaker 2:  Wait but no, tell me more. 'cause I, so the single
Speaker 2:  biggest technology change for me that happened with having a
Speaker 2:  kid this year is that all I care about is portrait mode. Like
Speaker 2:  yeah I just, all I do, I just run around shooting in portrait mode. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So is it not, it's not great. It's okay.
Speaker 10:  I mean you have a wide portrait shot and then you can do
Speaker 10:  the two x on either of the phones and
Speaker 10:  the two times portrait mode just doesn't look very good. I'm not
Speaker 10:  really sure what it's doing. It looks kind of crunchy and
Speaker 10:  that's like, I like that little bit of extra reach when
Speaker 10:  you're taking the portrait photo. Yeah. So the wide shots still
Speaker 10:  kind of have that like hardboard cutout look where your
Speaker 10:  subject is like super in focus and everything else is super not You know
Speaker 2:  It's just full, there's no like gradation at all. Yeah. It's just like it's
Speaker 2:  blur more than it is like Boca in general. Yeah. Yeah. I get that.
Speaker 10:  It'll do that Sometimes I've taken some really lovely portrait photos with
Speaker 10:  it and they tend to not be the, the two times lens. Okay.
Speaker 10:  But yeah, it's not, not my absolute favorite. I think it could be better
Speaker 10:  but it's, it's not terrible. Okay,
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. What about the pro controls on the, on the pro where you actually
Speaker 2:  get some of that manual controls in the camera app? Have you enjoyed
Speaker 2:  having that? Yeah,
Speaker 10:  I, I'm not one like, like when you're chasing a toddler around,
Speaker 10:  I'm not one to get in there and be like, let me dial up the i s o
Speaker 10:  or You know. I tend to like just trust the phone camera to do
Speaker 10:  its thing. But going in there you actually get, you can turn on like
Speaker 10:  picture and a picture like focusing and
Speaker 10:  you can turn which has focus peeking attached to it. Oh
Speaker 2:  Nice. Okay. It
Speaker 10:  Actually makes the macro mode like worth anything.
Speaker 10:  'cause you can actually see if your picture's in focus. Right. Which is
Speaker 10:  cool what
Speaker 2:  A world.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. You can see like what part of your subject is actually in focus.
Speaker 10:  So that was kind of a revelation. I was like, oh I would actually use the
Speaker 10:  macro mode now. But it's nice. The, the controls are nice, it's cool
Speaker 10:  having it there. It's not, it's not in your way if you don't want it
Speaker 10:  like it, it's not gonna hurt you. Yeah. I appreciate it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Okay. I'm, I'm glad to hear that All. right. So let's talk about the
Speaker 2:  AI stuff. The two things in Google Photos and you should tell me if there
Speaker 2:  are more that I should be interested in. But the two that I have found myself
Speaker 2:  obsessively wondering how you have found them are
Speaker 2:  best take, which is the one that takes a bunch of photos and then lets you
Speaker 2:  sort of pick and choose the parts of each photo that you liked best and combine
Speaker 2:  'em all into one photo and then the magic editor, which lets you like
Speaker 2:  move stuff around to frame the shot better. Let's just
Speaker 2:  start with Best Take because we spent like, dear God like two hours on The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast last week talking about this. How has it been so far? What do you
Speaker 2:  make of it? Is it, is it like as cool a feature enough to like change the
Speaker 2:  world and make us all terrified about the truth of photography forever? It's
Speaker 10:  Somewhere in there like okay, it's, I don't,
Speaker 10:  I don't know how afraid we should be of it. It's like
Speaker 10:  occasionally really good at what it's supposed to do,
Speaker 10:  especially when there's really good lighting. Like the demo we did
Speaker 10:  at the Google event, it's like a horror movie almost where you switch
Speaker 10:  the face on someone and like nothing else moves except their
Speaker 10:  expression and sometimes it looks really seamless and you're
Speaker 10:  like, oh my God this is terrifying. What does this mean for humanity? Sometimes
Speaker 10:  it looks pretty bad and like my toddler like suddenly
Speaker 10:  has another arm.
Speaker 10:  Here's like gesturing. I'm like okay, well this is not gonna end
Speaker 10:  society as we know it. And so it is, it's like somewhere in the middle
Speaker 10:  like I took some group shots with it and there's, you can sort of feel
Speaker 10:  like alright this is just, this is just a tool. Someone had their eyes shut,
Speaker 10:  I can change it so their eyes are open, this is fine, this is great, I enjoy
Speaker 10:  having it. But then you can kind of get in there and like
Speaker 10:  there's just totally changed the expression on someone's face
Speaker 10:  and it sort of feels like I don't think I like it. Even if it's not,
Speaker 10:  I'm not like, like doing an evil deeded with it.
Speaker 10:  I'm just like changing the expression on my toddler's face.
Speaker 10:  Right. I still feel sort of weird about it. I'm like, well I know he
Speaker 10:  wasn't making that face when he was doing that exact thing. And
Speaker 10:  I think we're all gonna have to kind of find where we're comfortable with
Speaker 10:  it. And for me personally, I'm like, like also with
Speaker 10:  Magic Editor you can do some wacky stuff with it and like
Speaker 10:  there was a picture of my son and one of his friends You know
Speaker 10:  at a baseball game and they're like hanging on the fence and I can just
Speaker 10:  like cut him out and move him over. So he's next to his friend
Speaker 10:  and it looks like that's exactly how I took the photo
Speaker 10:  and nothing evil has happened there but I feel
Speaker 10:  strange about it and I don't, I don't really like it.
Speaker 2:  Do you go and look at that photo then the next day or whatever and
Speaker 2:  feel differently about it? Like this is one of the things I keep thinking
Speaker 2:  about with this is like if I do that to a photo will I always
Speaker 2:  remember that I did that to that photo or that You know the fifth time I
Speaker 2:  look at it I will have forgotten and it's just a, it's just a cool photo
Speaker 2:  but does the fact that I've done something to it change my relationship
Speaker 2:  to that photo? And I feel like with Best Take in particular, I think I
Speaker 2:  would You know what I mean? Right. But I it does sound like you're having
Speaker 2:  that experience a little bit with all of this stuff.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I think it's just a question of like how far you wanna
Speaker 10:  take it and like where your comfort level is. Like I have no
Speaker 10:  problem like taking some minor thing out of the
Speaker 10:  background of a photo that's like You know take a picture and there's something
Speaker 10:  like on the counter behind my kid. Sure. And I'm like, that's garbage.
Speaker 10:  Let's pretend it was never there. Or yeah, with Best take
Speaker 10:  when someone's eyes are closed you open their eyes like this is fine,
Speaker 10:  but where's the line for you and where you're going to look at
Speaker 10:  that photo and feel icky about it after you make the
Speaker 10:  edit is like, maybe it's a little different for everybody. I'm
Speaker 10:  learning for myself.
Speaker 2:  Totally fair. Yeah. Have you seen any sort of
Speaker 2:  guardrails that Google is putting on that experience? Like is there a limit
Speaker 2:  to what it'll let you do kind of in the name of improving your photo or is
Speaker 2:  it pretty much the sky is the limit inside of the tool?
Speaker 10:  It'll put the brakes on if you try and do too
Speaker 10:  much. The UI is pretty limiting. Like to start
Speaker 10:  with, you basically have the options of like you are
Speaker 10:  selecting things in the scene to either like erase
Speaker 10:  or you have a little magic wand you can tap and
Speaker 10:  it'll suggest like change the sky or change the lighting
Speaker 10:  I think. And so you, you can't, it's not like a generative
Speaker 10:  like anything you want, do you want unicorns, rainbows like
Speaker 10:  throw 'em all in there kind of experience. So that's a good
Speaker 10:  thing I think. And it sort of, it limits how you
Speaker 10:  approach a photo of like okay, I know I can only do
Speaker 10:  so much here. It's, it's not a free for all.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. So when you're, when you're done testing all this stuff, are
Speaker 2:  these still features you think you'll use like in, in your day-to-day life
Speaker 2:  as like a regular person, if you remember life as a regular person
Speaker 2:  before you had 700 phones barely in your room at all times. Yeah. Is this
Speaker 2:  the kind of thing that like every time you You know take a bunch of family
Speaker 2:  photos? Like I had this experience over the weekend and I was thinking about
Speaker 2:  this all the time. We went to a pumpkin patch as you do in October and
Speaker 2:  it was five adults and three kids under two years
Speaker 2:  old. So the idea of getting all of us in a photo where we're all going to
Speaker 2:  be looking at the camera smiling at once, impossible, just literally never
Speaker 2:  gonna happen. And so what I have on my phone is 200 pictures.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I just stood there for five minutes and just took pictures constantly
Speaker 2:  and literally zero out of 200 everyone is making the face you'd want them
Speaker 2:  to make. And I had this moment of thinking like, oh this is what this is
Speaker 2:  for. Between these 200 photos there is one perfect
Speaker 2:  photo and if I could make it, I could share it with my whole family and everybody
Speaker 2:  would go ah and then move on with their lives and everything would be great.
Speaker 2:  But I also like, I don't know if I'm going to have an
Speaker 2:  existential crisis every time I open up my camera from now do You know what
Speaker 2:  I mean? Yeah. Like what do you think when you stop sort of thinking about
Speaker 2:  this in like a reviewer, what does this mean for the world mindset and just
Speaker 2:  start taking pictures of your family and life. Do you think this is the kind
Speaker 2:  of thing that'll end up sort of in your day-to-day workflow? Yeah,
Speaker 10:  I think it would like in those exact situations where I
Speaker 10:  am always finding that situation where I look back at the
Speaker 10:  photos I took of some particular like moment and
Speaker 10:  You know if it's a toddler and an adult, like
Speaker 10:  it's hard to, even with two people get like You
Speaker 10:  know the right moment. Yeah. And the right the expression I'm like oh well
Speaker 10:  this photo has this and yeah it's, it is the kind of thing you find yourself
Speaker 10:  wishing for and in testing you just kinda
Speaker 10:  wanna do the most ridiculous things and break it. So
Speaker 10:  we've did like normal faces and then silly faces and then
Speaker 10:  you're swapping in someone's like ridiculous face when everyone else is
Speaker 10:  making a normal face and you're like, that's kind of weird and
Speaker 10:  creepy. But I think in just a day to day like
Speaker 10:  I am so used to taking those 200 photos
Speaker 10:  and now yeah I think I would just have something to
Speaker 10:  do with them now rather than just kind of settle on like well
Speaker 10:  I'm gonna look weird in this one and everyone else looks fine.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The other AI feature I'm very curious about and is one I'm
Speaker 2:  personally invested in is the Audio Magic Eraser
Speaker 2:  which is supposed to cut out, what is it, background noise and just kind
Speaker 2:  of all unwanted audio from the video you're taking. Is that essentially the
Speaker 2:  idea?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, you just record your video like usual and
Speaker 10:  then you go into the editing tools and Google photos and there's a little
Speaker 10:  audio tab and it separates into some different
Speaker 10:  like very basic channels that are labeled like speech
Speaker 10:  and noise and Wind.
Speaker 2:  Super exciting if it works, does it work?
Speaker 10:  It works, yeah. Yeah, that this is another one I'm like I
Speaker 10:  would use this all the time if this is actually on my phone. So I recorded
Speaker 10:  a little test clip just walking down the busy street near where I live.
Speaker 10:  It's like raining a little bit, there's all kinds of unwanted
Speaker 10:  noise going on and you can hear what it does.
Speaker 2:  Let's hear the before with no touching. This is just what the phone
Speaker 2:  itself picks up,
Speaker 11:  Just taking the Pixel eight out for a stroll in the rain. And
Speaker 11:  something I've noticed is that, so Audio Magic Eraser
Speaker 11:  really does best with constant kind of
Speaker 11:  background noise. Something like a crowd or traffic
Speaker 11:  like you're hearing right now sort of comes in and out. It's a little bit
Speaker 11:  harder to control for but still, I don't know, it's
Speaker 11:  pretty impressive.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And here is the after with the Audio Magic
Speaker 2:  Eraser turned on,
Speaker 11:  I'm just taking the Pixel eight out for a stroll in the rain and
Speaker 11:  something I've noticed is that, so Audio Magic Eraser,
Speaker 11:  it really does best with constant kind of
Speaker 11:  background noise. Something like a crowd or traffic like
Speaker 11:  you're hearing right now sort of comes in and out. It's a little bit harder
Speaker 11:  to control for but still, I don't know, it's pretty impressive.
Speaker 2:  Okay, that's really impressive. It definitely like clips and compresses your
Speaker 2:  voice a bit but it just, I mean it gets, it got rid of all of the background
Speaker 2:  noise That's wild. And
Speaker 10:  You have like a degree of control over that was like turning
Speaker 10:  everything all the way down so you could leave a little bit in if you didn't
Speaker 10:  want it to sound, you can definitely hear those moments when it's like kind
Speaker 10:  of juddering and Yeah and trying to figure things out. But yeah, it's
Speaker 10:  super impressive.
Speaker 2:  Yeah for everyone on the Birch Cast who has had to listen to me like shout
Speaker 2:  into my phone over traffic, this is gonna be a huge win.
Speaker 10:  There you go. Alright,
Speaker 2:  Three more things I'm curious about and then I'm gonna let you go. The first
Speaker 2:  one is the new tensor processor, which
Speaker 2:  the last Pixel performance was kind of
Speaker 2:  at times it got hot, it just wasn't the best, what's the verdict this time?
Speaker 2:  And
Speaker 10:  I gotta say personally I never had too much trouble with the ELAs
Speaker 10:  tensor but I've seen the reports of like You know the overheating and
Speaker 10:  I did notice on this one I was out standing
Speaker 10:  outside on on like a pretty hot day and there's
Speaker 10:  the screens will get a little bit brighter this year. Like the high brightness
Speaker 10:  mode on the eight pro actually goes up to 2,400 knits
Speaker 10:  was just super bright. I saw that kick in and I was like, this is great,
Speaker 10:  I can read what's on my phone now. And a couple minutes in like
Speaker 10:  phone got pretty hot and it just went back down. Oh
Speaker 2:  Wow. Okay.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, which is the, usually the case on iPhones too.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Not uncommon but with the device kind of in that state,
Speaker 10:  I flipped into the video recording and it gave me a little warning like,
Speaker 10:  eh, your phone's too hot, it's probably not gonna record at the highest
Speaker 10:  quality. So if that is a concern,
Speaker 10:  I, this is, it was a warm day, but I live in Seattle, I don't live
Speaker 10:  in the tropics. If that's a concern for you then
Speaker 10:  I am sorry to say that it might be a little bit more of the same on
Speaker 10:  Tensor G three.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So the, the problems maybe not totally solved, but in
Speaker 2:  general the Pixel seven other than when it was sort of at its threshold
Speaker 2:  did pretty well. And I'm as I, I would assume the same is true this year.
Speaker 2:  Like I can't imagine you're having sort of day-to-day performance issues
Speaker 2:  on this phone.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, no, it, it handles everything fine. It says a little edge cases
Speaker 10:  where you're really pushing it, like I'm trying to take a whole
Speaker 10:  bunch of portrait mode shots really fast and it, it's
Speaker 10:  just kind of like slow down lady but
Speaker 10:  overall it's fine.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And then temperature sensor, which it has. Okay. Is that useful for
Speaker 2:  anything? This is like, this strikes me so much as a thing that like Google
Speaker 2:  just happened to have a bunch of these lying around a factory somewhere so
Speaker 2:  they put them in. Have you found it valuable at all to have in these funds?
Speaker 10:  No, not, not at all. Like I have a moment
Speaker 10:  where I'm like, oh I'm drinking, this is a hot cup of coffee. I'll get
Speaker 10:  the phone and see what the temperature is and it, it gives you
Speaker 10:  You know degrees or whatever. It's just like, but there's text on it, it
Speaker 10:  just says hot. I'm like yeah All.
Speaker 10:  right. I I knew that actually I didn't need a sensor to tell me
Speaker 10:  that. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Thanks Google. That's AI at work right there. That's
Speaker 10:  Our AI dollars at work. I don't know.
Speaker 2:  And then last thing is battery life. How do the Pixel eights stand
Speaker 2:  up? You know
Speaker 10:  It seems to be fine. I think like Google
Speaker 10:  very smartly doesn't make any particular claims of like
Speaker 10:  better battery life or better power efficiency
Speaker 10:  and I'm finding that both of the phones will get through a full day
Speaker 10:  with varying degrees of like a comfortable percentage
Speaker 10:  left at the end of the day. Sure. But yeah,
Speaker 2:  Presumably the pro does a bit better just by virtue of being larger. Yeah
Speaker 10:  That one you could, if you're just kind of a moderate user you can
Speaker 10:  push into the next day. But yeah, full day of use
Speaker 10:  is just a kind of a blanket like yeah you'll, you'll get that.
Speaker 10:  Okay,
Speaker 2:  That's good. So overall it seems like there's no kind of
Speaker 2:  one mind blowing earth shattering new thing here, which in a
Speaker 2:  smartphone in 2023 is not entirely unexpected but I do think
Speaker 2:  Google has been on this grind of like we can do a lot of
Speaker 2:  little AI things. There's a bunch of that in here where they're doing the
Speaker 2:  summaries of web pages in the browser with AI and the better spam call filtering
Speaker 2:  and all that kind of stuff. Does that all add up to much for you?
Speaker 2:  Like does, does the full sort of AI story make the Pixels
Speaker 2:  more compelling than what you're getting from Samsung or Apple or any of
Speaker 2:  these other companies at this point?
Speaker 10:  It's starting to and I feel like that's kind of been Google's
Speaker 10:  pitch with the Pixels for the past couple years is like it's gonna,
Speaker 10:  it's so smart, it's gonna do these things for you, it's gonna make your
Speaker 10:  life easier. And You know the Pixel six and Pixel seven, like
Speaker 10:  they're good phones. I don't feel like there was anything it was doing that
Speaker 10:  was just really making my life easier. I think that
Speaker 10:  promise is like could start to come true in the Pixel eight and some of
Speaker 10:  it depends on assistant with Bard which is
Speaker 10:  going to come at some point in the future
Speaker 2:  Potentially.
Speaker 10:  Yes, this is Google so take that as you will.
Speaker 10:  But that could really make Google Assistant very
Speaker 10:  useful to be able to ask it like questions
Speaker 10:  that require checking multiple sources or
Speaker 10:  looking in your email. And I think there's a lot of
Speaker 10:  potential there. There's also you get seven years of OSS
Speaker 10:  updates,
Speaker 2:  Which is a big deal. It, it really is. I remain as
Speaker 2:  we've talked about unconvinced that Google is only even going to make phones
Speaker 2:  still in seven years. So who knows? But I do think that's a real promise
Speaker 2:  and that's a big deal if if that is actually true and seven years from
Speaker 2:  now your phone is still good and functional and up to date. Like that's huge
Speaker 2:  and that's a real reason to buy these phones.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, yeah. So it seems like there's potentially like
Speaker 10:  really useful things coming to it. The assistant voice typing
Speaker 10:  is quite a bit better in the Pixel eight. It
Speaker 10:  actually will like understand your sort of inflection and pauses and
Speaker 10:  it'll put punctuation in rather than like an entire
Speaker 10:  long string of text which is like God bless my mother but that is what
Speaker 10:  I get from her every time she texts me. And you kind of seem like
Speaker 10:  a sociopath when you do that but I'm like, I would actually maybe
Speaker 10:  use voice texting on this phone and that's not a thing I
Speaker 10:  consider. So there's a lot of potential. I think there's more potential
Speaker 10:  for the Pixel eight and the eight Pro to be this phone of like it actually
Speaker 10:  does make your life a little easier but it's you, you gotta put
Speaker 10:  your trust in Google to get there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. As with so many things, I just reviewed the Meta Quest three and it's
Speaker 2:  the same thing. It's like look, no wrong answers. If you feel good about
Speaker 2:  it, knock yourself out if you don't. I totally understand but like let's
Speaker 2:  all be clear-eyed about what you're signing up for here. Yes, yes. And it
Speaker 2:  all means somebody is going to see a lot of what you do in your life all
Speaker 2:  the time.
Speaker 10:  Oh yeah, yeah. You gotta be good with that too. Yeah, no big deal
Speaker 2:  All. right. Well I should let you get back to deciding which score you're
Speaker 2:  gonna give it to piss off everybody on the verse.com. Thank you. But thank
Speaker 2:  you as always, really appreciate you coming on.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, thanks
Speaker 2:  All. right, let's switch gears and talk about the Pixel Watch two last year's
Speaker 2:  Pixel watch had a bunch of good ideas and nice designs but it felt
Speaker 2:  very much like a first generation product. It had all the kind of stupid
Speaker 2:  mistakes and weird build issues and all the stuff you do when you've
Speaker 2:  never done this before. So I've been looking forward to this one, the second
Speaker 2:  one ever since. Super curious what the second gen watch might
Speaker 2:  fix or improve upon and rethink after
Speaker 2:  a year of doing this Victoria song on our team has been reviewing it and
Speaker 2:  I'm desperately curious to hear how it's going. So let's hear how it's going.
Speaker 2:  Hi Vee.
Speaker 12:  Hello.
Speaker 2:  You were just telling me right before we started recording that the Pixel
Speaker 2:  watch two currently on your wrist is not the first Pixel
Speaker 2:  watch two. My first question was going to be is the Pixel watch
Speaker 2:  two less breakable than the original Pixel watch and suddenly I am
Speaker 2:  nervous. Tell me what's going on.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, so day two I was on day two with the Pixel watch two
Speaker 12:  I wake up and I look down several deep scratches
Speaker 12:  like all over the Pixel watch at like You know it was dark, it was
Speaker 12:  rainy so I was having a hard time telling if it was a crack or scratches.
Speaker 12:  So I was like oh my god I've had this for like two days.
Speaker 12:  I'm racking my brain to be like what did I do to do
Speaker 12:  this to the watch? And I couldn't remember anything. So You know I had to
Speaker 12:  go up to Google and be like, Hey guys, this is not gonna work.
Speaker 12:  We need review photos so can you get
Speaker 12:  me a new watch? And they actually did hand deliver a new watch and they
Speaker 12:  had a guy take a look at my scratched up Pixel watch and we were just standing
Speaker 12:  there in a circle for a bit being like what could have possibly caused this
Speaker 12:  And it So I still haven't heard back. They said they would get back to me
Speaker 12:  with like if there were any trace materials and the scratches that might
Speaker 12:  indicate what caused the scratches. But as far as I know
Speaker 12:  I went to bed, it was fine, woke up, scratches all over the
Speaker 12:  place.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so one of two things is happening here. Either you encountered
Speaker 2:  Wolverine but like tiny, tiny wolverine or two,
Speaker 2:  this is a really bad sign for the Pixel watch two because my main thing
Speaker 2:  with the Pixel watch one was like they did a lot of things right and we're
Speaker 2:  just missing kind of the like fit and finish and
Speaker 2:  structure of the thing that often you get right with the second one, first
Speaker 2:  one you're like learning how to make these things it's hard work, Watches
Speaker 2:  are hard, it's a circle, I get all that stuff. But the second one is like
Speaker 2:  we had this problem with the first one, the things got scratched. This feels
Speaker 2:  like a very bad sign. Does this strike you as a very bad sign?
Speaker 12:  So my main concern is that, and I like ran this story a couple
Speaker 12:  weeks ago, is that there's no current repair option
Speaker 12:  for the Pixel watch. And You know if you drop your watch and you
Speaker 12:  crack it, if you scratch your watch yourself, technically that's not covered
Speaker 12:  under a warranty. I'm not gentle with these Watches Watches just
Speaker 12:  in case people are wondering. Yeah I am. I'm very klutzy. I fall down
Speaker 12:  constantly. The original Pixel watch I was running once and I didn't do
Speaker 12:  the class properly and it went flying. Oh boy. Almost flew into the East
Speaker 12:  River and it was fine, no scratches and it was like skinning across asphalt.
Speaker 12:  So I really thank you have to be quite unlucky in some
Speaker 12:  respects. So You know, I wanna say I had the original for
Speaker 12:  a year and nothing bad happened to it. I had the new one for two days and
Speaker 12:  something bad happened to it. Yikes. So the second one I've had for
Speaker 12:  about five days now and nothing has happened to it. Okay. I've also been
Speaker 12:  a lot more conscious of where I put it down because that happened to
Speaker 12:  me. But like I'm hesitant to say that the Pixel watch is like
Speaker 12:  bad for that reason but just because of the curved display and
Speaker 12:  the way it looks, it is a little more prone to it. And other smartwatch
Speaker 12:  companies have moved on to like either sapphire crystal or
Speaker 12:  stronger materials. So that is just like a thing to keep in
Speaker 12:  mind. You just kind of have to be a little more careful with this one. I
Speaker 12:  think that's the lesson I learned with the Pixel watch too.
Speaker 2:  All. right. So let's talk about the rest of this watch. 'cause I think where
Speaker 2:  you and I landed last year was basically like pretty
Speaker 2:  good first start. Really excited to see the second one 'cause there
Speaker 2:  were a lot of things like we're talking about that felt like a company's
Speaker 2:  first wearable. The Fitbit thing was still relatively new. The integration
Speaker 2:  was kind of messy. The processor was old and not good enough. They did some
Speaker 2:  wonky stuff with the straps so it's like this was gonna be the one where
Speaker 2:  it was like, okay, if Google is serious about this and gonna do it, well
Speaker 2:  it's gonna start to put the pieces together. So
Speaker 2:  I have a bunch of specific questions for you but like big picture,
Speaker 2:  does it feel like a big step in that direction this time?
Speaker 12:  Yes. Aside from the fact that it's one size, usually it's
Speaker 12:  like one gigantic size and the small wrist that among us are complaining,
Speaker 12:  it's the opposite problem here. If you have big wrist, this is gonna look
Speaker 12:  very small and dainty on you. Aside from that and the issues
Speaker 12:  with the screens that I just mentioned in every other way, this is a pretty
Speaker 12:  sizable step forward. So that's like what stuck out to me the most
Speaker 12:  that usually the sequel isn't good. And I talk about this in my review
Speaker 12:  but we never talk about the Apple Watch series two. Like we talk about the
Speaker 12:  three, we talk about the original, we talk about the four or five six for
Speaker 12:  whatever reasons we never talk about the series two. Samsung
Speaker 12:  legitimately skipped a Galaxy Watch two, it didn't even bother with two,
Speaker 12:  it just went from the original to the three. Right. So You know generally
Speaker 12:  the second is either something that the first should have been
Speaker 12:  or it's just like the forgotten middle child of of
Speaker 12:  gadgets that we just don't ever talk about. And I think this is
Speaker 12:  the rare sequel that is definitively better than the original
Speaker 12:  with with a few caveats and exceptions which we'll get it to.
Speaker 2:  Okay so let, let's run down some of it. 'cause I, I went back to your review
Speaker 2:  last year and pulled out some of the things you liked and disliked and I
Speaker 2:  think the one that jumped out to me the most was battery life because you
Speaker 2:  had, I would say like middling battery life last year sort of in
Speaker 2:  normal use. It wasn't like dramatically worse than any other
Speaker 2:  smartwatch but it also wasn't particularly impressive. But then as soon as
Speaker 2:  you started doing stuff, especially exercising, the battery life was
Speaker 2:  kind of a mess. How is it this year?
Speaker 12:  It is a massive improvement. So like people asking for
Speaker 12:  multi-day battery life like Garmin levels or like truly Fitbit levels
Speaker 12:  stop. You're gonna be disappointed because you still have to charge this
Speaker 12:  every day. Sure. But you are gonna get 24 hours with
Speaker 12:  always on display enabled. Last year you could
Speaker 12:  get 24 hours if you turned off tilt till wake and you turned off the
Speaker 12:  A O D and you were just like super babying the watch
Speaker 12:  being very intentional with how you're using it when you're using it, you
Speaker 12:  don't have to do that as much this year because one it charges
Speaker 12:  a hell of a lot faster. Like this morning I went on a run,
Speaker 12:  I did all my like little exercise duty, dotes, whatever after a whole
Speaker 12:  night of charging. I had about a hundred percent at like
Speaker 12:  11:00 AM yesterday. Okay. So I'm, I'm here at
Speaker 12:  10:00 AM with 15% left and here we are about an hour later I'm
Speaker 12:  at full. I just went about my like shower putting on
Speaker 12:  clothes becoming a human again ritual and it was done
Speaker 12:  That's fast charge. Like I think 45 minutes to an hour is what most people
Speaker 12:  will need if you're not getting it down to zero. So that's pretty
Speaker 12:  great. And then just in terms of general usage, I
Speaker 12:  was writing down statistics left and right just because last year was
Speaker 12:  so bad. Like I went I think on a 30 minute to 45 minute run last
Speaker 12:  year and it drained
Speaker 12:  41%, 41%, which is absurd. That's terrible for such a short period of time.
Speaker 12:  And subsequent software updates fixed that so that it was less bad
Speaker 12:  but it's actually good now it's on par with Samsung in terms of battery
Speaker 12:  drain now. So I went on a bunch of two mile runs, I went on
Speaker 12:  a bunch of walks with the G P S enabled and I wanna say
Speaker 12:  that in general I was not losing anything more than six to
Speaker 12:  15%. And that's in a bunch of various like
Speaker 12:  situations. Sometimes when I'm streaming music offline, sometimes
Speaker 12:  I am actually using safety check while I'm doing my
Speaker 12:  workout. So that's enabling cellular the entire time kind of.
Speaker 12:  So You know there's just a lot of different scenarios. I never lost more
Speaker 12:  than 15% in a 30 to 45 minute time period, which
Speaker 12:  for most people that's like a solid workout. That's what you're gonna do.
Speaker 12:  And I had some really active days where I was getting a bunch of
Speaker 12:  auto auto workout tracking, which was a big issue with last year
Speaker 12:  as well. So You know I'm going about my day. I never really had to
Speaker 12:  worry about the the battery and I, I just
Speaker 12:  so everyone knows, I did not use a single battery saving
Speaker 12:  feature this entire week,
Speaker 2:  Which is good and you shouldn't have to, right? Like I think what you're
Speaker 2:  describing to me is like what a smartwatch should be, which is basically
Speaker 2:  like I should take it off and charge it when I shower and get ready in the
Speaker 2:  morning and then I should never ever, ever think about its battery otherwise.
Speaker 2:  And it sounds like what you're describing is basically that, right? Like
Speaker 2:  it charges pretty quickly so that you can shower and get ready while
Speaker 2:  it charges. And then once again we're coming around to I need to put a
Speaker 2:  watch charger in my bathroom and I hate this And I still, people
Speaker 2:  sent me a bunch of pictures of like dangly Apple watch chargers in their
Speaker 2:  bathroom when I talked about this on The Vergecast a while back and I hate
Speaker 2:  it and it makes me so angry and yet this is the life I have to live. But
Speaker 2:  it sounds like it's as good as it needs to be for you to like live your life
Speaker 2:  and not be annoyed by the battery And that feels like a huge win over last
Speaker 2:  year.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, it's a huge win and I think for the average person it's gonna be
Speaker 12:  great if you're a Garmin head and you're wondering
Speaker 12:  whether this is gonna last you a 14 hour hike with G P s
Speaker 12:  on, I don't, I wouldn't, I wouldn't bett all my chickens on that. That's
Speaker 12:  not like what you're not gonna be happy, this is not
Speaker 12:  enough of an improvement. But for the average person, the person who's looking
Speaker 12:  at a flagship smartwatch because they want all the Google services or because
Speaker 12:  they want to do something other than track fitness but also track
Speaker 12:  You know a reasonable walk every day or something like that. This is, this
Speaker 12:  is finally good enough.
Speaker 2:  So you mentioned two things in that description that were also issues that
Speaker 2:  the Pixel watch one had, which was the G P S, which was
Speaker 2:  sort of wacky and weird on the first watch and
Speaker 2:  automatic workout tracking, which was a thing it didn't do
Speaker 2:  at all I don't think, despite the fact that this is like a thing Fitbit's
Speaker 2:  pretty good at
Speaker 12:  It, did a version of it but not what people were wanting.
Speaker 12:  Okay,
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. Again, both of those better this year, hopefully supposedly
Speaker 2:  better this year. What have you found so far? So
Speaker 12:  The auto tracking is definitely better. I went on several walks
Speaker 12:  and You know do, do doting not starting a walk on purpose.
Speaker 12:  And I did get notifications that were like, Hey it looks like you're doing
Speaker 12:  a walk, would you like to record? And I was like Ah, here we go.
Speaker 12:  Great. On the other side they also have reminders to
Speaker 12:  stop your workout. Okay. So if you're the type of person that's just like
Speaker 12:  you get home, you lie down on the couch and you're like, why did I exercise?
Speaker 12:  This was a terrible mistake and you forget to turn off your activity
Speaker 12:  after about five minutes it will be like, yeah I I do you wanna stop
Speaker 12:  and You know? It did that for me like a couple of times when I was just
Speaker 12:  like sitting on a park bench taking in the sites or just
Speaker 12:  forgetting to turn off my walk. It did remind me to do that. So
Speaker 12:  on that front, yes it is better. G p s is a
Speaker 12:  mixed bag. I basically tested it without my Pixel phone when I went
Speaker 12:  on run so that I could use the Pixel Watches built-in G
Speaker 12:  P s. It takes a while to find a signal You know I've got an
Speaker 12:  ultra two on the other hand and the ultra two will find a signal like boom
Speaker 12:  done. Like I have to wait a second for it to find a signal. This sometimes
Speaker 12:  I have to wait around and I have to walk like 10 feet before it finds
Speaker 12:  a signal. Sometimes it's a little longer. And I live in an area
Speaker 12:  that's very challenging for G P s, I'm surrounded by water, I'm surrounded
Speaker 12:  by tall buildings. That's understandable. This is not necessarily a
Speaker 12:  thing that's limited to Google. A bunch of some aren't watch
Speaker 12:  companies, even those with good g p s have this issue where I live. It's
Speaker 12:  just something that I clocked and I had a weird instance
Speaker 12:  where I went on a run, the G P S map was only half
Speaker 12:  right And it said I only did 1.3 miles,
Speaker 12:  which is wrong. I never do just 1.3 miles on a run
Speaker 12:  two minimum is my, is my thing. Like I, I feel like I need to do two miles
Speaker 12:  to feel like I got at least some sort of cardio release going on. So I had
Speaker 12:  done about a a two mile run feeling like really good wanting to check
Speaker 12:  my stats after and it's like 1.3 miles in the app on on
Speaker 12:  my wrist. It was like 2.1 and then I was like this is, this is bull honky
Speaker 12:  so I'm trying to update it wouldn't update 24 hours later. It's like
Speaker 12:  you did 2.1 miles. Oh weird. So I feel like I've been gaslit
Speaker 12:  with G P S and I had this problem last year. Yeah
Speaker 12:  the maps were a lot less accurate last year. So there is some
Speaker 12:  mild improvement there. I just think there's something wonky going on in
Speaker 12:  the backend and I've reached out to Google like what's up? Why is it
Speaker 12:  doing this for this particular run? But I also have to mention that I went
Speaker 12:  on four runs total and it only did that for one of them
Speaker 12:  And I went on, according to this watch, like several walks this
Speaker 12:  weekend and those were all generally pretty accurate. So just on this one
Speaker 12:  run it had a 24 hour meltdown as to how far I actually
Speaker 12:  ran. And so my stats were wrong, which if you're like me, that's
Speaker 12:  unacceptable. It drives, it ruins your whole day, you get no credit. Oh
Speaker 12:  a hundred percent. Yeah for anything. So You know if that's
Speaker 12:  you, you might not be happy with that 'cause there
Speaker 12:  is some wonky backend going on and You know I've had that issue with Fitbit
Speaker 12:  over the years off and on. So that just might be a thing that they're still
Speaker 12:  kind of working out.
Speaker 2:  Speaking of the Fitbit thing, the last year we had a lot of questions
Speaker 2:  about Fitbit and Pixel and whether these two
Speaker 2:  companies that are now one company kind of understood how they work together
Speaker 2:  and then just before the Pixel watch two came out, Fitbit launched a new
Speaker 2:  Fitbit. Does this ecosystem make more sense to you than it did
Speaker 2:  like, it seems like they did a bunch of new Fitbit stuff in the Pixel watch
Speaker 2:  too. There's new sensors, skin temperature and stress and heart rate stress
Speaker 2:  I think is one of the things that Fitbit itself has been really, really You
Speaker 2:  know promoting and and spending a lot of time talking about over the last
Speaker 2:  year or so. Does the integration work better for you? Like do you, do you
Speaker 2:  kind of understand where Pixel ends and Fitbit begins now?
Speaker 12:  Yes. So last year was a total shit show. Like it was three
Speaker 12:  smart Watches, they nerfed the Google smartwatch in terms of fitness features
Speaker 12:  and health features and they took the the Fitbit Watches and went, we will
Speaker 12:  take everything that mildly made you slightly smarter and take it all
Speaker 12:  away. And so that's less of a problem this year because I think
Speaker 12:  last year by the nature of having three smart Watches, it was
Speaker 12:  very confusing and there was no real honest way to differentiate them
Speaker 12:  in a way that made sense. This year you have the Charge six, which is a
Speaker 12:  fitness band and you have the Pixel watch and the delineation between these
Speaker 12:  two And what features they offer is a lot clearer
Speaker 12:  and thank the fricking Lord that it is because when you have the Pixel
Speaker 12:  watch too, you're not wondering like, well Fitbits can do this, so why
Speaker 12:  can't this do that? Don't you have a Fitbit integration?
Speaker 12:  What's the deal? So yeah, there's, there's none of that This
Speaker 12:  year you get all the abnormal high low heart rate notifications. You
Speaker 12:  get all the E K G AFib notifications, both
Speaker 12:  passive and spot checks. You get the stress tracking which they introduced
Speaker 12:  with the Sense two last year. You get the continuous stress, stress
Speaker 12:  tracking, which is hilarious in many different ways. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Speaking of making you feel feelings, like there's nothing quite like a notification
Speaker 2:  being like, are you stressed when you're stressed? Yeah. And you're like,
Speaker 2:  yes, thank you Fitbit. I am stressed. Thanks so much for asking.
Speaker 12:  Fitbit actually has the best implementation of stress tracking of
Speaker 12:  anybody out there. In my humble opinion. It's just a lot
Speaker 12:  more thoughtful. You could tell a lot of like thinking went into this
Speaker 12:  because you are not going to get notified when the stress is happening,
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. They try to do it after, which I appreciate
Speaker 12:  You're gonna get a delay. Which it comes with its own trade offs because
Speaker 12:  I, I'll get notifications and I'll be like, what was I doing three hours
Speaker 12:  ago when I was having this bodily stress response? Right? Was
Speaker 12:  I happy? Was I sad? I don't know. But sometimes it is very
Speaker 12:  relevant. Like I actually got some bad personal news last week my
Speaker 12:  grandma died and like in the moment I was just like, I'm going
Speaker 12:  to shut down and compartmentalize because I have work to do and
Speaker 12:  also Korea's a different time zone so we'll deal with this later. And then
Speaker 12:  later when I actually did get to deal with it, about an hour after I had
Speaker 12:  processed all the feelings, it was like, hey, we found a stress response.
Speaker 12:  Would you like to look your mood? And I was like,
Speaker 12:  sure. Sad. That's what it was. That's what it
Speaker 12:  was. But You know, it does take, it does like give you a second to kind
Speaker 12:  of think and log the mood and if
Speaker 12:  you're in a place where you can whip out your phone and write
Speaker 12:  a sentence or two, there's at least a prompt there. I don't think that
Speaker 12:  mood journaling is a natural human impulse. So when we saw this
Speaker 12:  with watchOS 10 where apple's like you have these abstract
Speaker 12:  moods that you can log on your watch. Yeah. I, I never used it because
Speaker 12:  I'm not gonna be like in a moment where I'm stressed and like, wow, this
Speaker 12:  was really stressful. I should log this for posterity.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it it, that never did anything for me.
Speaker 12:  That never did anything. So this is actually, it's not perfect. There is
Speaker 12:  a delay. You have to remember how you were feeling when you were feeling
Speaker 12:  and be in a position to be able to log the mood. But there's context for
Speaker 12:  it. Okay.
Speaker 2:  I like it. Anything else about the watch that that jumps out to you? It strikes
Speaker 2:  me as like as a, as an everyday fitness tracker, it is like
Speaker 2:  unambiguously much better than last year. It seems like Google's kind of
Speaker 2:  right there now, right?
Speaker 12:  It's surprising because You know when you have the Pixel phones, you're
Speaker 12:  just kinda like why are you making this Google with this? You kind of get
Speaker 12:  why they're making it and they actually have a shot to be the
Speaker 12:  best at something. So I don't do, I think that the Pixel watch too
Speaker 12:  is the best Android smartwatch out there right now. I'm still kind of
Speaker 12:  like, no. Okay. I still think Samsung is slightly better but the gap is
Speaker 12:  a lot, lot smaller. It is a lot smaller. They did a lot better
Speaker 12:  than I thought they were going to do And some of that actually is because
Speaker 12:  I think they were pretty unique in the safety features this year with safety
Speaker 12:  check and safety signal. So I actually just used safety signal this morning
Speaker 12:  'cause I was like, I'm leaving this watch at home but I'm going to like
Speaker 12:  see how this affects my battery to use safety signal and You know I
Speaker 12:  don't have an L T E plan on the watch, but I was still able to send notifications
Speaker 12:  about where my location was to my husband while I was out there. And
Speaker 12:  You know if you ever see any girl with her girlfriends
Speaker 12:  when they're leaving, they're like, text me when you get home. So that's
Speaker 12:  sort of like a, an acknowledgement that that is a cultural thing that
Speaker 12:  yeah, I have to do. And it's kind of nice that I can just set a
Speaker 12:  timer and it gives the reason why I am setting that timer and
Speaker 12:  my location now. My husband was just like, oh she's just testing something
Speaker 12:  Ignore. So like if something had happened to me, I
Speaker 12:  don't know that it would've been particularly useful. Yeah. For that particular
Speaker 12:  use case. Yeah, I do think that's cool. There is, there's some little wonkiness
Speaker 12:  there though because safety signal is basically you being
Speaker 12:  able to access emergency features without having an L T E
Speaker 12:  plan. But you still need to have the L T E watch. So
Speaker 12:  that is a little inelegant if you ask me. And you also have to
Speaker 12:  have a Fitbit premium subscription in order to have the safety
Speaker 12:  signal. So it's just like kind of saving maybe $10 a month
Speaker 12:  max in order to have the emergency features. It's kind of a
Speaker 12:  nice option to have but also doesn't fully
Speaker 12:  make sense. And you would think that why not just also offer
Speaker 12:  that to non L T E models, but it's not on the non L T
Speaker 12:  E models. So there's like a lot of stuff like that, small things
Speaker 12:  that are just kind of like, well why did you do it this way? And it leads
Speaker 12:  into my other kind of quandary in question with the Pixel watch too. Is
Speaker 12:  that, are we heading towards more ecosystem fragmentation
Speaker 12:  because the thing about the original Pixel watch that I was just like yes,
Speaker 12:  was that it was for everyone who had an Android phone. Yep. Samsung Gate
Speaker 12:  keeps health features. Samsung Gate keeps certain things to Samsung
Speaker 12:  phones and that wasn't a thing that you had to think about with
Speaker 12:  the Pixel watch, but it is something you have to think about now with the
Speaker 12:  Pixel watch too in that like do you want this to automatically
Speaker 12:  recognize that it's bedtime and turn on low power mode so you get an extra
Speaker 12:  10 to 15% battery when you wake up in the morning? 'cause it does save about
Speaker 12:  that much. Cool. If you have a Pixel phone, you can go into the digital
Speaker 12:  wellness settings and make it so that it auto syncs with your
Speaker 12:  watch and will automatically go into bedtime mode, which the original does
Speaker 12:  not do. You have to manually do it and who falls asleep going
Speaker 12:  must, must put bedtime mode into to my watch. I never did that
Speaker 12:  so that was a huge problem. I don't have to do that with this because I've
Speaker 12:  paired it to a Pixel phone. I'm still gonna have to do this manually if
Speaker 12:  I pair it to a Samsung phone. So like we're starting to have instances
Speaker 12:  like that where I'm just like, hey you guys were supposed to be
Speaker 12:  the ecosystem like agnostic watch
Speaker 12:  and now you are kind of putting some things in there that make it better
Speaker 12:  with Pixel phones. So like it's not
Speaker 12:  available now, but they were saying that it could screen your calls in a
Speaker 12:  future software drop. So that is also gonna be limited to
Speaker 12:  Pixel phones only. So I'm like aha, I see we are introducing
Speaker 12:  some ecosystem nonsense into the mix. There
Speaker 2:  Was a lot of that this year. I think in the, in the phones too, there's a
Speaker 2:  definite sense that Google is getting more comfortable keeping stuff for
Speaker 2:  itself and it's like, it's still probably like if you
Speaker 2:  don't own a Samsung phone or a Google phone, it seems like the
Speaker 2:  Pixel watch is probably the more ecosystem friendly of the two if
Speaker 2:  you're gonna pair it to some other Android device. But it is, I I agree with
Speaker 2:  you. It's still a little concerning to see Google sort of slowly start
Speaker 2:  to close the doors and they're like, we just mostly wanna sell you Pixel
Speaker 2:  stuff
Speaker 12:  Because like I get, if you don't want a Pixel phone, especially if you're
Speaker 12:  in the us like Android users tend to have Samsung phones. They're
Speaker 12:  totally makes sense. I really hate how it seems companies
Speaker 12:  are using Smart Watches as cudgels to keep you in a, in an ecosystem
Speaker 12:  like Yep. I occasionally want to switch to an Android phone just 'cause
Speaker 12:  my iPhone is pissing me off but I'll never do it because I have an Apple
Speaker 12:  watch. So like that's very annoying to me. Yeah and I
Speaker 12:  see Google doing this here and it was just sort of like, ah you guys,
Speaker 12:  you you I was, I was rooting for you to keep it platform agnostic
Speaker 12:  and Garmin is still the only truly platform agnostic thing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I agree. But I think in general the story you're telling about the
Speaker 2:  Pixel Watch two makes me excited. I feel like, I think you're right that
Speaker 2:  Google has a lot of incentive to keep building this thing, not least because
Speaker 2:  it's spent a hell of a lot of money on Fitbit and the fact that it is
Speaker 2:  sort of systematically improving the things that weren't great give me hope
Speaker 2:  that like as it keeps working on this stuff, I think the the form factor
Speaker 2:  ideas it has are right. I think some of the assistant stuff, especially as
Speaker 2:  they start incorporating the large language model stuff is gonna start to
Speaker 2:  be very cool. There are a lot of interesting places this could go and I,
Speaker 2:  I think it gives me hope that Google might actually know how to build a good
Speaker 2:  smartwatch over time, which I was not sure of last year.
Speaker 12:  I was not sure of that either. But I really do think that if they get
Speaker 12:  their shit together and they really stay on top of the Fitbit
Speaker 12:  integration, which it's kind of rocky at this point, not a lot of people
Speaker 12:  are loving the Fitbit app redesign, which I can kind of understand having
Speaker 12:  played with it for a few days more deeply. But it's just like if you can
Speaker 12:  stay on top of that, if you can manage to not piss every Fitbit user
Speaker 12:  who's been there for the last 20 years or however off, if you can
Speaker 12:  continue to innovate and I, I really do think Samsung should be worried
Speaker 12:  they should start not resting on their loyal laurels. 'cause the
Speaker 12:  Galaxy Watch six was incredibly iterative. I almost fell asleep writing
Speaker 12:  the review even though it's a great watch. I was just like, it's the same
Speaker 12:  as last year kind of. Oh my god. So by
Speaker 12:  nature of being new, even if it's not perfect, it's still more
Speaker 12:  exciting than the existing Android options. And because it's Google
Speaker 12:  and because they own the software platform, I dunno they
Speaker 12:  have the chance to be the best at something which besides search engines,
Speaker 12:  what can you say that Google is the best at? So I don't know. It's very
Speaker 12:  interesting
Speaker 2:  And maybe not even search engines but that's a different podcast. We will
Speaker 2:  come back to that All. right. We should take a break. But vie thank you as
Speaker 2:  always. If you figure out your tiny Wolverine problem come back on and let
Speaker 2:  us know. Okay,
Speaker 12:  I I
Speaker 2:  Will Thank you All right, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come
Speaker 2:  back. We're gonna talk about Chromebooks
Speaker 2:  Welcome back a couple of weeks ago Google announced a new program called
Speaker 2:  Chromebook Plus basically a designation for computers that meet a certain
Speaker 2:  set of criteria for processors, screens, webcams, that sort
Speaker 2:  of thing. And thus all in should be up to a slightly higher
Speaker 2:  standard as a pc. As a person who loves Chromebooks and hasn't
Speaker 2:  frankly seen one that I actually wanna buy in a few years, this
Speaker 2:  makes me happy. But it's also kind of confusing. I've sincerely
Speaker 2:  never been able to tell exactly how much Google cares about Chromebooks.
Speaker 2:  They're hugely successful in schools, which is obviously great for Google
Speaker 2:  because it gets young users using Google products. Obviously a big win for
Speaker 2:  the company. But is that it or does Google really want to compete with
Speaker 2:  Windows and Mac OSS and Dell and HP and whoever else and be a serious
Speaker 2:  player in the PC market? It honestly feels like some days it does
Speaker 2:  and goes all in on this idea and then it cancels a bunch of products and
Speaker 2:  changes its mind like four months later and then four months after that
Speaker 2:  decides to go all in again. I just sincerely don't understand.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, Monica Chin on our team has been covering Chromebook Plus over the
Speaker 2:  last couple of weeks and has been reviewing Chromebooks for years. So
Speaker 2:  I brought her in to help me figure out what this actually means for the future
Speaker 2:  of Chromebooks Monica Welcome back to The Vergecast, thank you very much.
Speaker 2:  Thank you for allowing me to drag you here to talk about Chromebooks, which
Speaker 2:  is a thing I think I care about more than possibly any other person.
Speaker 14:  Look, you don't have to tell me twice. I could talk for days and days about
Speaker 14:  Chromebooks. This could be the Chromebook podcast
Speaker 2:  I'm in. But the reason we're here is because of Chromebook Plus,
Speaker 14:  Chromebook Plus.
Speaker 2:  I feel like the Chromebook world is forever whipsawing in
Speaker 2:  Google's mind between like we wanna make this good and make
Speaker 2:  great computers and Chromebooks can be competitive. We think they're the
Speaker 2:  laptops of the future and swinging back the other way of just
Speaker 2:  like Chromebooks surfer kids in school and they're designed to be as cheap
Speaker 2:  as possible and who cares And then they just sort of swing back and forth
Speaker 2:  between those two. Where do you feel like we've been on that pendulum
Speaker 2:  for let's say like the last 12 months?
Speaker 14:  Yeah, so companies have been trying to make
Speaker 14:  the quote unquote premium Chromebook into a thing for like
Speaker 14:  quite some time now.
Speaker 2:  Like a decade. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. And by premium I mean like a Chromebook that you could charge more
Speaker 14:  than a thousand dollars for and like people would buy it that
Speaker 14:  in the Windows laptop world we are at a point where that is not
Speaker 14:  like a super super high price. It's certainly a lot of money, like no one's
Speaker 14:  like owe a thousand dollars super cheap. But we're at a point where like
Speaker 14:  that is a price that like is not only reserved for super
Speaker 14:  expensive gaming laptops like that is something you would pay for maybe
Speaker 14:  a Dell X P S 13 or a Galaxy Book like something like that.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. But for Chromebooks that is still very much like a You know you put
Speaker 14:  a Chromebook out that costs that much, that is not that much less than
Speaker 14:  the MacBook Air You know it needs to be really well built and the question
Speaker 14:  is like can we convince people to pay that much for Chromebooks? So we had
Speaker 14:  Samsung which has tried the Galaxy Chromebook which was
Speaker 14:  beautiful and gorgeous had an OLA screen. Just honestly one
Speaker 14:  of the prettiest computers I've ever used. Battery lasted like four hours
Speaker 14:  was not not a good time to actually use, they tried the Galaxy Chromebook
Speaker 14:  two, it was a little less expensive still like very
Speaker 14:  red. That was like one of the big things about the Galaxy Chromebook line
Speaker 14:  is you get a red one.
Speaker 2:  I love the red,
Speaker 14:  Love the red. Really gorgeous Galaxy Chromebook two was like not as
Speaker 14:  beautiful. Screen was like not as premium but it was a little
Speaker 14:  bit less expensive that I think everyone kind of agreed was a better way
Speaker 14:  to go about it. HP has tried like a dragonfly Chromebook,
Speaker 14:  they started out putting out like this gorgeous like reminiscent of
Speaker 14:  the actual HP dragonfly line, which is a very big famous business line.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. Like something that they were trying to push on like oh this is for
Speaker 14:  the C-suite. They also kind of ended up knocking that down to something
Speaker 14:  that to the HP Dragonfly Pro is like one they put out
Speaker 14:  now, which is like more of a, again, more of a modest like
Speaker 14:  not quite as ole gorgeous beautiful but it has an R G
Speaker 14:  B keyboard. It's still kind of cool prices and more closer to a thousand
Speaker 14:  dollars. Like they've also sort of bumped down to sort of more of a mid
Speaker 14:  range tier. So You know you see companies here and there sort of try this
Speaker 14:  thing and then I haven't really seen an example of
Speaker 14:  one that has become so successful that they've continued putting out
Speaker 14:  tons and tons more versions of it. Right. Which is what you do
Speaker 14:  see with some Chromebooks that do become very successful. Like Acer's Chromebooks,
Speaker 14:  spin seven 13 or You know stuff that's in that tier.
Speaker 2:  So do you think it's even possible, this is a a thought experiment I have
Speaker 2:  been through many times over the years that if you could get
Speaker 2:  everything else right, like I think, I think we agree that the the MacBook
Speaker 2:  Air is probably the closest to doing all of the laptop things right As
Speaker 2:  anyone at this moment. If you just took a MacBook Air and all of the things
Speaker 2:  that it does very well, battery life and performance and the way it looks
Speaker 2:  and the keyboard and all this stuff took out Mac OSS and put in Chrome oss,
Speaker 2:  could you sell that to people for a thousand dollars?
Speaker 14:  Yeah. So it's tough because the number of like
Speaker 14:  full fledged apps you can use on Chrome oss,
Speaker 14:  the options you have are not as many at this point. Now there
Speaker 14:  are ways to use lots of the big
Speaker 14:  Windows apps, the big like quote unquote premium Windows apps on
Speaker 14:  ChromeOS. Like there are versions of like Photoshop for
Speaker 14:  web and like the different Adobe apps office is on there
Speaker 14:  in some form. And then there are of course Android apps which like You know
Speaker 14:  that is a whole separate conversation about like how well Android apps
Speaker 14:  on Chromebook are or are not going. Yeah. But like there are versions of
Speaker 14:  things like Spotify, there's a version of it you can use on ChromeOS
Speaker 14:  Slack. As far as I know there is not still. Although it's always
Speaker 14:  hard to know 'cause that one has been like coming and going yeah seriously
Speaker 14:  the store for years, like literally I could say it Today and tomorrow it
Speaker 14:  could come back or go right? It's hard to know. You know PWAs are like
Speaker 14:  things that you can use. So there are options but it is
Speaker 14:  still a little bit more complicated. Like if you were on Windows and you
Speaker 14:  wanna use a professional app that leverage your G P U
Speaker 14:  or You know play a game, whatever it is, you go on Steam you on
Speaker 14:  the Microsoft store, you just download it and then it's there. And on Chrome
Speaker 14:  os it is still more complicated to figure out like okay, do I have to use
Speaker 14:  this on the web? Is the Android app the best option? Maybe there is an Android
Speaker 14:  app option but maybe instead I should be using the pwa. Like there's just
Speaker 14:  a it it's a little bit more complicated and not as robust of
Speaker 14:  a software ecosystem. Yeah. That said there certainly are other
Speaker 14:  benefits to Chrome OSS over like something like Windows or Mac oss.
Speaker 14:  People love how quick it is to boot. I mean it boots like almost instantly.
Speaker 14:  Yep. That's like a big draw of it. Background security updates, those are
Speaker 14:  like a thing that people really like. A lot of people like to run
Speaker 14:  Linux on their Chromebooks. That is a thing you can do. The
Speaker 14:  crowd that these quote unquote premium Chromebooks have sort of
Speaker 14:  been targeting is a crowd of people that You know Chrome OSS
Speaker 14:  for ages and ages. Many people have associated with like this is for students,
Speaker 14:  this is for like kids or budget shoppers. The
Speaker 14:  contingent of people that the premium Chromebook has sort of been trying
Speaker 14:  to target is people who are not students. People who are like, who have
Speaker 14:  some deep pockets who are your engineers or creators
Speaker 14:  or You know business executives, whatever job they have. But you
Speaker 14:  prefer Chrome OS to Windows or Mac OS because of these other benefits that
Speaker 14:  it has. But they don't wanna be limited to like cheap devices that are
Speaker 14:  built for students. They want the kind of premium hardware that You know
Speaker 14:  there are coworkers in the C-suite are all on Think pads or HP
Speaker 14:  dragonflies and they want a laptop that runs Chromes but has that same kind
Speaker 14:  of You know really nice build.
Speaker 2:  I think you just described like the perfect second
Speaker 2:  device, right? Like the thing you're describing where it's like you can do
Speaker 2:  almost everything but some of it is gonna be kind of hacky is also kind of
Speaker 2:  the way the iPad works. And so I think if you like want
Speaker 2:  to be the person who uses an iPad for work, like you can do it, but
Speaker 2:  you're gonna do a bunch of things in these really wacky hacky ways that
Speaker 2:  aren't as easy as on some other systems. And I feel like Chromes has a handful
Speaker 2:  of those, which I guess has always been the problem. 'cause it's like if
Speaker 2:  you want a light thin, simple computer
Speaker 2:  that boots really fast and you just like wanna send a bunch of emails while
Speaker 2:  you're on a plane, like Chromebook is perfect but for most people that can't
Speaker 2:  be the only computer you own.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. And when you get above a thousand dollars, that just starts becoming
Speaker 14:  expensive for most people. You know as a second device
Speaker 14:  and You know I write about Chromebooks every time I write something like
Speaker 14:  this. The comment section is full of people who are just like, well actually
Speaker 14:  it's really easy to use blah blah blah program if you just get on Linux
Speaker 14:  and do blah blah blah blah. And it's like, yeah that's that's great. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  But it is like a slightly more of a hiccup than it is to just download on
Speaker 14:  Windows.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. If your, if your answer to a problem is download Linux like you're,
Speaker 2:  you're telling on yourself in a way that I don't think you understand.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. And so there, there is certainly contingent there are in in my comment
Speaker 14:  section it's full of, of people who You know are in that group. The question
Speaker 14:  is really how big is that group and is that group big enough to really sustain
Speaker 14:  a rigorous ecosystem of these products that goes on for years and years
Speaker 14:  and years.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So Google I guess to its either detriment or
Speaker 2:  credit seems committed to this idea that it is going to figure out how to
Speaker 2:  sell high end Chromebooks. So tell me about the Chromebook
Speaker 2:  Plus program that was just announced. Yeah,
Speaker 14:  So the Chromebook Plus is a certification and if you're familiar with what
Speaker 14:  Intel EVO is, it's kind of a similar idea.
Speaker 14:  Evo was previously Project Athena and previously before that was the, the
Speaker 14:  ultra book label. It's kind of like companies will
Speaker 14:  roll out these certifications. They, they have like a list of
Speaker 14:  requirements and if your computer meets that list of requirements you can
Speaker 14:  put that label, you can license that brand and you can put it on your
Speaker 14:  product. And then You know in, in this case if your laptop qualifies
Speaker 14:  for the Chromebook Plus branding, you can then put your laptop
Speaker 14:  on the Best Buy shelf. It'll have a big sticker that has like Chromebook
Speaker 14:  Plus or whatever it is. You can have Chromebook Plus in the name You know
Speaker 14:  in the Best Buy listing. It might say like a use Chromebook Plus and then
Speaker 14:  You know the idea is they'll promote this Chromebook Plus label as You know
Speaker 14:  these are the plus laptops.
Speaker 2:  I mean these are the good ones is what it's saying. Right?
Speaker 14:  Yeah. And then Chromebooks without label will be more likely to be purchased.
Speaker 14:  That's the idea of programs like this,
Speaker 2:  Which I, which I think is fine. Like part of me wants to make fun of Google
Speaker 2:  for essentially having to come up with a label that says these are our good
Speaker 2:  computers. Which implies that most of your computers are not good computers.
Speaker 2:  But I also understand that there's a gigantic portion of the Chromebook world
Speaker 2:  that is incredibly price sensitive and is just
Speaker 2:  like, is buying these things in bulk is buying these things for schools.
Speaker 2:  Like I get that what's on the list of things you have to
Speaker 2:  do to be a Chromebook Plus computer?
Speaker 14:  Yeah, so compared to the Intel Levo standard, which is this kind of thing
Speaker 14:  that Intel runs or something like a M D Advantage which a MD runs for
Speaker 14:  gaming stuff, it is not a particularly extensive list. So
Speaker 14:  we, you have to have an Intel core I three or a Horizon 7,000
Speaker 14:  processor, which
Speaker 2:  Is basically just like a quality class PC processor.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. So if you have a seller on like that, that's not a core i three or
Speaker 14:  higher, that doesn't count an I P S panel with at least 10 80 p resolution,
Speaker 14:  a 10 80 P webcam, eight gigabytes of ram and 128
Speaker 14:  gigabytes of storage. That is pretty much all we were given in terms of
Speaker 14:  what the, the requirements are.
Speaker 2:  That seems like, I mean and I guess maybe this is the idea but that is like
Speaker 2:  bare minimum decent laptop specs. Anyone who is like, I want
Speaker 2:  a laptop that is pretty good. I would tell everyone to
Speaker 2:  not get anything less than any of those things. Like you're just sabotaging
Speaker 2:  yourself if you get anything lower than those specs.
Speaker 14:  I mean I don't know that I think a Chromebook needs to have a Windows laptop.
Speaker 14:  Yes, sure.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 14:  Chromebook I think these are, some of these to me would be like okay, this
Speaker 14:  is a quote unquote good Chromebook that you're shopping for in particular.
Speaker 14:  I mean the 10 80 p webcam, like that's
Speaker 2:  Fair. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  128 gigabytes of storage. Like there's a time when I would've said that
Speaker 14:  was a little high higher than is necessary. Every Chromebook just ChromeOS
Speaker 14:  doesn't take up as much space as Windows does the Ram similarly. But
Speaker 14:  I think they are sort of meant to signal like this is a Chromebook that
Speaker 14:  has like some pretty solid specs for the category.
Speaker 2:  Two things I noticed missing in those specs. One,
Speaker 2:  anything having to do with design or materials or fit and finish or
Speaker 2:  weight or whatever. No sense of like what this thing is supposed to look
Speaker 2:  like.
Speaker 14:  Yep. No sense of that. The
Speaker 2:  Other one is battery life, which I would argue yeah for a Chromebook
Speaker 2:  is maybe the single most important spec that exists on a device
Speaker 2:  like that. You asked them about the battery life emission. Right? What did
Speaker 2:  they tell you?
Speaker 14:  So I tried very hard to find out about this and it was a little bit of an
Speaker 14:  adventure. So at the Chromebook Plus like event that we were all at
Speaker 14:  where they announced it, we were like looking at the list, they put the
Speaker 14:  list up on the big screen when they were like giving the speech or whatever.
Speaker 14:  And I immediately said, why is battery life not on there? So You know after
Speaker 14:  the talk gets out I hunt down one of the Google people and I'm like hey
Speaker 14:  so why isn't battery, why isn't there a battery life requirement? And he's
Speaker 14:  like Oh there totally is. There's definitely a battery life requirement.
Speaker 14:  We just like, we didn't announce it on stage. And I was like, I feel like
Speaker 2:  Lead with that. Like
Speaker 14:  I was like what's the battery life requirement? And he was like, oh I don't
Speaker 14:  know but like it'll be in the press release. So we wait You know a couple
Speaker 14:  days press release comes out, there's no battery life requirement in there.
Speaker 14:  I email, I email him back. Cool. I'm like hey. So You know you
Speaker 14:  said there was a battery life requirement in the press release. There's
Speaker 14:  not You know is is there a battery life requirement? What's going on? Couple
Speaker 14:  days later to my recollection Google gets back to me and they
Speaker 14:  say the following, all Chromebooks are required to meet a 10 hour battery
Speaker 14:  life requirement based on internal testing standards. Well not a new requirement
Speaker 14:  for Chromebook Plus dot dot Chromebook Plus laptops must also
Speaker 14:  adhere to this. So that's their claim. Now I have
Speaker 14:  no idea what testing sta their internal testing standards are for that 10
Speaker 14:  hour battery life requirement in the first place. So that's not really saving
Speaker 14:  that means much to me. Can
Speaker 2:  You remember the last Chromebook you tested they got 10 hours of battery
Speaker 2:  life?
Speaker 14:  No, I'm there. There has certainly been some but I don't remember. I
Speaker 2:  Think it's been a while. Well and and to your point, I mean some of the ones
Speaker 2:  that we've liked in the past, even the high end ones have been crushed
Speaker 2:  by their battery life. The Galaxy Chromebooks were a really good example
Speaker 2:  of this that like beautiful machines did a lot of things right. Really short
Speaker 2:  battery life.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. And I mean it's worth noting that well You know my battery life that
Speaker 14:  I get is only my battery life 'cause I'm testing with my workload. Like
Speaker 14:  you might get something totally different but I don't know what Google I'm,
Speaker 14:  I don't know if they're doing video playback like I don't know. I just dunno
Speaker 14:  how they're, if they're doing one of those things where it's like you turn
Speaker 14:  off the wifi and you put the screen at like a hundred knits and you turn
Speaker 14:  off the speakers and you play
Speaker 2:  A local video file and they're hours
Speaker 14:  Reverse local video, that also to me is not a good
Speaker 14:  reflection of how much battery you can expect. So I think my result is
Speaker 14:  probably a little bit better but I don't claim that it's identical what
Speaker 14:  you're gonna get.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. So one thing I thought was interesting about the way Google
Speaker 2:  is approaching this is that if you qualify for the Chromebook Plus
Speaker 2:  certification, not only do you get the sticker that says this is one of the
Speaker 2:  good ones, you actually get some more stuff. Like from a software
Speaker 2:  perspective these things are gonna be better than the lower end
Speaker 2:  Chromebooks. Right. That surprised me a little bit. Actually part of the
Speaker 2:  appeal of Chrome OSS has been that it's this like very simple straightforward
Speaker 2:  thing. You can kind of log in anywhere and all of your stuff appears. But
Speaker 2:  now it seems like Google is starting to say like we're gonna, especially
Speaker 2:  with AI stuff right. Give you more to do on these more powerful
Speaker 2:  machines.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. So the main thing is that there are some AI powered features
Speaker 14:  which we were told are as of now going to be exclusive to
Speaker 14:  Chromebook Plus devices. I, it seems to me plausible
Speaker 14:  that they will end up on all Chromebooks eventually.
Speaker 2:  Okay. It's like what they're doing with the Pixels. Like the stuff starts
Speaker 2:  there and then kind of works its way down through the ecosystem just based
Speaker 14:  On like how I see that they do this kind of thing with Android. Like I don't
Speaker 14:  know that I would assume like this will never leave the plus line. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  But yeah, there's a magic eraser tool in Google Photos. There
Speaker 14:  are improvements to lighting and noise cancellation in
Speaker 14:  video conferencing which we got a demonstration of.
Speaker 14:  And then there's like an offline file sync thing which automatically
Speaker 14:  downloads stuff from drive onto the device. Oh. Which we also got to see
Speaker 14:  in action
Speaker 2:  Suddenly 128 gigs seems like not enough that
Speaker 14:  That was in my re I was like oh I have a lot of stuff in Drive. I don't
Speaker 14:  know but I assume it's, it's theoretically supposed to like save you from
Speaker 14:  having to do that if you are someone who would be You know going on and
Speaker 14:  doing that manually. Well and it's smart
Speaker 2:  'cause Google has fought against this thing for years where the perception
Speaker 2:  of CR the Chromebook is still, it only works when you're online. Right.
Speaker 14:  And there are lots of people who still think that. Right.
Speaker 2:  And on the one hand I think that's like a fake fear because like my MacBook
Speaker 2:  is more or less useless when I'm not online anymore. Like I don't, it
Speaker 14:  Turns out there's very little you can do without the internet and
Speaker 2:  Yeah, exactly. But also Google I think is is smart too. And I remember they
Speaker 2:  did this with docs and stuff back in the day. They were like, no, you can
Speaker 2:  do this stuff offline. Yeah your computer will be okay.
Speaker 2:  So doing the offline stuff makes a lot of sense to me that that seems smart.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. And then there are gonna be like AI generated wallpapers,
Speaker 14:  which you like type in a text prompt and it like generates a wallpaper.
Speaker 14:  Love it. That's the idea. We didn't get to see that that wasn't ready at
Speaker 14:  the time. There's a quote unquote personal writing assistant. Oh lord.
Speaker 14:  Very curious. Excited to try that out. I love
Speaker 14:  to be assisted with my writing so You know I well welcome that
Speaker 14:  tool. And then there's like a three month subscription to Photoshop on the
Speaker 14:  web and there's like three months of GForce now is priority tier. There's
Speaker 14:  like a couple things like that where you get some free trials of some stuff
Speaker 14:  and I mean
Speaker 2:  That's a decent amount of stuff. That's a, that's a pretty strong push to
Speaker 2:  buy the better Chromebook. It
Speaker 14:  Certainly is. It will be interesting to see how long all of those things
Speaker 14:  remain. Yeah. You know plus exclusive before it becomes less
Speaker 14:  before they sort of trickle down. Yeah. That
Speaker 2:  That's very fair. So I'm curious what you think the
Speaker 2:  manufacturers of Chromebooks are gonna do because like you were saying at
Speaker 2:  the beginning, all of these hook have been burned by trying to charge a lot
Speaker 2:  of money even for a very good Chromebook. It just, it has been
Speaker 2:  hard. I've been out here banging the drum of like a thousand dollars Chromebook
Speaker 2:  can actually be a really good idea. I think the Pixel book is like one of
Speaker 2:  the all time best laptops. I still believe that
Speaker 14:  That was a good one.
Speaker 2:  Most people didn't like I, I grant that I am not most people in that particular
Speaker 2:  way. And so if I am, I don't know Jesus or Samsung or
Speaker 2:  Lenovo or HP or whoever, I have a lot of experience not selling
Speaker 2:  high end Chromebooks And now Google's out here saying again, sell high end
Speaker 2:  Chromebooks, it's totally gonna work this time. Do you think they're gonna
Speaker 2:  try, are we gonna get a real pushback to the premium in the Chromebook space
Speaker 2:  here or has everybody been burned too much by now?
Speaker 14:  From what the evidence that we have so far, and again this is evidence is
Speaker 14:  highly curated by Google. Sure. Like they You know have decided which ones
Speaker 14:  they are gonna announce on stage it. It seems like a lot of these
Speaker 14:  are pretty solidly mid range so far. Okay. The ones that have
Speaker 14:  been announced, the cheapest one I think is, it's 3 99
Speaker 14:  0.9 which is the Acer Chromebook Plus line. Okay. And then a bunch of the
Speaker 14:  other ones that were announced were sort of in the like 500
Speaker 14:  $800 range. So these are high end quote unquote
Speaker 14:  I and Chromebooks and that they're not, they're above the like school laptop
Speaker 14:  cart tier but these are not HP Dragonfly Pro
Speaker 14:  like $2,000 executive devices. That does not seem to be, I
Speaker 14:  think who they're going for with this label. It seems to me they're more
Speaker 14:  looking for, these are like parents shopping for their kids or something
Speaker 14:  and they don't necessarily know anything about specs but they see plus and
Speaker 14:  they're like oh plus sure. I think that must mean it's good. And I actually
Speaker 14:  that is similar to how if you look at like what tends to get
Speaker 14:  certified as Intel evo, they sort of have very specifically targeted that
Speaker 14:  label towards like these are the best like consumer things that you might
Speaker 14:  buy rather than like we're shoving this at the enthusiasts and
Speaker 14:  the the enterprise customers.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So yeah it seems like what we're gonna get is likely a lot of things
Speaker 2:  that are right at that minimum spec range, which like you
Speaker 2:  said for a Chromebook is fine. My initial reaction as soon as you said I
Speaker 2:  three was to be like that's not enough. But for a lot of Chromebook
Speaker 2:  uses it probably is So is eight gigs of ram. Yeah. So is 128 gigs of storage,
Speaker 2:  like that's a pretty good Chromebook. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  In my experience at Core I three often flies on Chrome
Speaker 14:  oss.
Speaker 2:  I think maybe what I need to do is just let go of the idea that I'm ever
Speaker 2:  gonna get like the really beautiful, perfect,
Speaker 2:  spectacular Chromebook that I want. There
Speaker 14:  Certainly are some you can try. They they get, they get pretty pricey
Speaker 14:  what's
Speaker 2:  Like the best one out there If I want like America's fanciest Chromebook
Speaker 2:  in
Speaker 14:  My opinion, which is just my opinion, it is the Asus
Speaker 14:  Chromebook CX five flip CX five. But that is not, that is actually not
Speaker 14:  a super, super fancy one. That is just one that I think is really
Speaker 14:  good.
Speaker 2:  Oh this thing looks nice, I just googled this, I'm into this. Okay. It
Speaker 14:  Is really, really nice and the battery life is so good.
Speaker 14:  That was my experience with that one. But in terms of like one that's actually
Speaker 14:  super like quote unquote luxury, what you wanna try is the h HP Elite
Speaker 14:  Dragonfly Chromebook or something that's in that line Dragonfly
Speaker 14:  Pro. I think that's like more of a consumer version of
Speaker 14:  the Elite Drive Fly Chromebook. But the elite Dragonfly Windows laptop
Speaker 14:  is like one of the absolute nicest computers you can buy. It
Speaker 14:  is a business laptop. It is like $4,000. Like it's some crazy price.
Speaker 14:  The Drive Fly Chromebook is kind of the Chromebook version of that and it
Speaker 14:  is really, really nice. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I love the Dragonfly because it's another one of those like, it's like black
Speaker 2:  on black on black. It's super simple. It reminds me of like the CR
Speaker 2:  48, the very first Chromebook from a million years ago where they just
Speaker 2:  sort of made a black prototype and then shipped it. And I mean that in like
Speaker 2:  the best possible way. The dragonfly kind of reminds me of that. It's just
Speaker 2:  like, yeah they didn't try too hard. They're just like here's a cool, it's
Speaker 2:  like a thing a spy would use in a movie and I appreciate that.
Speaker 14:  It's very nice. It's really expensive. I, but if you're looking for that,
Speaker 14:  that's kind of the one that's currently floating around.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Do you think we're gonna get a good push here? Like Chromebooks
Speaker 2:  had this gigantic spike during the pandemic because everybody bought them
Speaker 2:  for school, kind of crashed back to Earth over the last couple of years.
Speaker 2:  Is the plus thing gonna work do you think? Like do it, does it have a real
Speaker 2:  chance of convincing some more people to get Chromebooks?
Speaker 14:  I imagine that this year it seems like everyone's kind of
Speaker 14:  doing it like Ace is doing some HP's, doing some
Speaker 14:  Acer's, doing some, whether that like pushes
Speaker 14:  Chromebook purchases back to where they were in 2020. I think that's probably
Speaker 14:  unlikely because that was a pretty specific event that pushed the sales
Speaker 14:  that high. Whether it brings in new customers or whether
Speaker 14:  it just drives the people who would already be buying Chromebooks to instead
Speaker 14:  buy Chromebook Pluses is sort of hard for me to judge at this point.
Speaker 14:  I wouldn't be surprised if it's like somewhere in the middle there.
Speaker 2:  That's a good point. And I think Google in this case is probably smart to
Speaker 2:  look at that sort of four to $600 price range and
Speaker 2:  be like, we can make some real noise there. 'cause right now, even on the
Speaker 2:  Windows side, I feel like I start to get really nervous recommending people
Speaker 2:  computers in that price range because odds are you're making some
Speaker 2:  sort of catastrophic sacrifice, but Chromebooks in most cases are
Speaker 2:  like cheaper than that. Like substantially cheaper than that in a lot of
Speaker 2:  ways that people are buying and using and mostly being okay with. So if Google
Speaker 2:  can make like the best $500 laptop and not worry about being the best a
Speaker 2:  thousand dollars laptop, like I'll be sad, but that's probably better for
Speaker 2:  the actual future of Chromebooks in the long run.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. And I, I think it probably will have the impact of making it easier
Speaker 14:  for some people to shop without paying more than they need to is what
Speaker 14:  I'm seeing right now. And that to me seems like a, a good thing. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I think that's right. Like the, the laptop world right now is just one sort
Speaker 2:  of relentless upsell until you get to about 1800 bucks and all you walk in
Speaker 2:  and they just suddenly they just, everything goes up a hundred dollars at
Speaker 2:  a time until you're like, how did I buy a MacBook Pro? Like that's not right.
Speaker 2:  I here for Adele XPS 13. Like what are we doing here? Yeah, I'm I'm
Speaker 2:  still sad that I'm not gonna get the like kickass Chromebook. I'm just
Speaker 2:  mad at Google really for canceling the Pixel book. Do you think that'll ever
Speaker 2:  come back based on nothing? This is based on nothing. Just make me feel better.
Speaker 2:  No,
Speaker 14:  I mean anything's possible. Yeah. You know there's, there's always a possibility
Speaker 14:  that in the infinite expanse that it's time something will happen. So I
Speaker 14:  don't wanna say no, it won't happen. I mean if you wanted me to take the
Speaker 14:  side of a of, of like a bet here. No. Yeah. I think that when, when you
Speaker 14:  look at where they went with the Pixel book Go and how much better a response,
Speaker 14:  it seems like that got, I think if there's another Pixel book, it's closer
Speaker 14:  to the Pixel book go than it is to like the funky convertible thing
Speaker 14:  the Pixel book was. But I, that was a very cool product and at the time
Speaker 14:  I remember when it was like trying to figure out, oh, what's the best Chromebook?
Speaker 14:  Like that was the obvious 'cause there had been nothing like it before.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. But that wouldn't really be the case I think if it came out today.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no, I I think that's right. I hope Google makes another one, but I,
Speaker 2:  I'm not holding my breath.
Speaker 14:  Make one just for you and bring it to your house and that's
Speaker 2:  All I want. If there's a prototype lying around somewhere that nobody wants
Speaker 2:  anymore, just, just sell it to me. I'll take it. I'm, I will happily, happily
Speaker 2:  take whatever Pixel book two exists somewhere in Mountain View. Alright,
Speaker 2:  I can talk to you about this forever sometime. You're gonna come back on
Speaker 2:  and we're just gonna talk about Windows apps and Android apps and the connect
Speaker 2:  to phone thing and like all the ways the Chromos almost gets it right and
Speaker 2:  doesn't quite get there. Oh yeah. But for now we gotta take a break. Monica,
Speaker 2:  thank you as always.
Speaker 14:  Thank you very much.
Speaker 15:  Support for this show comes from Intel. Where do world
Speaker 15:  changing ideas get their start at Intel. It starts with
Speaker 15:  real solutions and real solutions start with
Speaker 15:  exceptional engineering. Empowering those with disabilities
Speaker 15:  starts with assistive AI and discovering new galaxies
Speaker 15:  starts with supercomputing. The intelligent factory
Speaker 15:  starts with edge analytics while the sustainable supply chain
Speaker 15:  starts with open manufacturing. And that's just the start.
Speaker 15:  The quantum computing revolution, the next generation of AI
Speaker 15:  experts, the renewable energy grid, liquid cooling, data
Speaker 15:  centers, early diagnosis for cancer, water
Speaker 15:  restoration, farmland protection, they all start
Speaker 15:  with Intel. The examples are countless, the impacts are
Speaker 15:  endless, but the foundation is always the same.
Speaker 15:  It starts with Intel. Learn more at Intel dot com
Speaker 15:  slash stories
Speaker 2:  All. right. We're back. Let's get to a question from The Vergecast Hotline
Speaker 2:  as we do on the show every week. As a reminder, the Hotline number is
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 Verge one one. And truly,
Speaker 2:  I love all of the weird questions you've been sending us. We've been getting
Speaker 2:  some really fun, really wonky ones recently. Thank
Speaker 2:  you for everything you've been calling and asking about and if you don't
Speaker 2:  wanna call, you can always email us Vergecast at The Verge dot com. That
Speaker 2:  works just as well. Thank you again to everyone who's been emailing and calling
Speaker 2:  super fun times on the Hotline. Our question today comes from Tyler.
Speaker 16:  Hey David, this is Tyler. Hey, I was just thinking back to
Speaker 16:  this maybe blog post or something that went viral in the late two
Speaker 16:  thousands and it was all about how to use iTunes to create custom
Speaker 16:  playlists. You know we sort of forget about this, but iTunes had so much
Speaker 16:  data baked into it and so many fields where we could add our own data to
Speaker 16:  it. I feel like me and everybody else I knew, we all rated our songs, we
Speaker 16:  had custom genres and you could tell iTunes,
Speaker 16:  Hey, please make me a playlist with everything I've
Speaker 16:  rated three stars or higher that I've not listened to in the past
Speaker 16:  four months. And then maybe mix in with that music that I have bought in
Speaker 16:  the past two months that I have not rated yet. And it was just this great
Speaker 16:  way to kind of control what you're listening to. And I just feel so sad
Speaker 16:  that You know with most of the streaming services, like none of that
Speaker 16:  control is there anymore. And I'm just so curious if
Speaker 16:  anybody in that streaming world thinks that there's an appetite
Speaker 16:  for people that care about organizing their music and being kind of a
Speaker 16:  music nerd about it. Anyway, thank you so much. Love the show. Bye.
Speaker 2:  Okay, I love this question because I think Tyler, like a lot of
Speaker 2:  us at The Verge and also all The Vergecast family, were a lot of
Speaker 2:  like music nerds and metadata nerds. And so the idea of like, I would like
Speaker 2:  to go in and type in a lot of information about all of my songs so that I
Speaker 2:  can do things with, it just feels right to me. I have two things to say about
Speaker 2:  this. The first is just a frankly hard truth about the way that
Speaker 2:  the world works. Most people, Tyler, do not want the thing
Speaker 2:  that you described. I agree that that's unfortunate. I agree that there are
Speaker 2:  lots of people out there who do want that and would like to have more control
Speaker 2:  over their music. But we've been in this phase really for the last decade
Speaker 2:  where the idea of having your own music collection
Speaker 2:  with You know things that you've ripped from CDs and stuff that you've downloaded
Speaker 2:  and this sort of carefully curated beautiful library of stuff is
Speaker 2:  just a dying art. There are people out there who do it and there are lots
Speaker 2:  of great apps out there, particularly on iOS. There are some really good
Speaker 2:  local music playing apps that actually give you some of the stuff that you're
Speaker 2:  talking about. But in general, that's a dying behavior. People want these
Speaker 2:  algorithmically generated playlists. They want to use things like new music
Speaker 2:  Friday and release radar to discover new music. People wanna
Speaker 2:  find all the stuff without all the work. And that is what I've been hearing
Speaker 2:  from streaming services for years, that the idea of building a library of
Speaker 2:  music is just a dying art. I think that's sad. I wonder if it'll come back
Speaker 2:  around. But I think asking any of these streaming services to
Speaker 2:  invest in that is just probably not gonna happen at least for the next
Speaker 2:  few years. Maybe that'll change. Vinyl is coming back in a big way. This
Speaker 2:  sense of ownership is coming back in a lot of ways in media I think
Speaker 2:  because things move around a lot and things come and go and the idea of like
Speaker 2:  I want to have a collection that is mine, I think is kind of coming back
Speaker 2:  so maybe it'll get better, but for now I would not hold my breath but
Speaker 2:  I have better news, which is that I think AI is going to go
Speaker 2:  a long way towards solving part of what you're asking for. I think
Speaker 2:  being able to say, I have input all this data about what I like And, what
Speaker 2:  these songs are and stuff, probably not gonna happen. But the thing about
Speaker 2:  a service like Spotify is that it has a ton of that
Speaker 2:  metadata about these songs. It knows the style of the songs, the style
Speaker 2:  of the singing, how much guitar there is, how much piano there is, what the
Speaker 2:  B p m is, And, what Spotify it has been
Speaker 2:  reported and revealed is working on is basically a way to
Speaker 2:  use AI prompts to generate these kinds of playlists. So
Speaker 2:  you could say, I want music with You know this genre
Speaker 2:  and this kind of singer and a twangy guitar that is under four minutes
Speaker 2:  and 108 beats per minute. That is also good to listen to
Speaker 2:  by the pool and it will just make you that playlist. I have no idea how
Speaker 2:  good it will be. As we've seen with a lot of these chatbots, it's kind of
Speaker 2:  iffy in a lot of ways. And I actually just recently talked to Gusav Soderstrom
Speaker 2:  who's the president at Spotify and has been working on all of this stuff
Speaker 2:  for years. He's very into the idea that AI can
Speaker 2:  be a way to filter and sort and search through and discover
Speaker 2:  new music. That's a big thing Spotify is investing in. You see it already
Speaker 2:  with things like the day list playlist, which is this sort of endlessly changing
Speaker 2:  set of songs depending on what time of day it is And, what mood you're in,
Speaker 2:  And, what you like to listen to at certain times. So not only does Spotify
Speaker 2:  have this access to this sort of huge corpus of music,
Speaker 2:  but also it knows what you listen to and when And what you like
Speaker 2:  and when you listen to it. And for me in particular, I've been a Spotify
Speaker 2:  user for like 12 years now and it knows more about
Speaker 2:  my music taste frankly than I do, especially how it's changed over time.
Speaker 2:  So the idea that not only could it take all of its knowledge about music,
Speaker 2:  but all of its knowledge about me and put it into this system where I can
Speaker 2:  just query, like play me songs that I really liked
Speaker 2:  in 2006, like last time I went through a
Speaker 2:  breakup, what songs did I listen to, right? Like all this stuff is out there
Speaker 2:  and findable. And one of the cool things about a lot of the AI tools that
Speaker 2:  we've seen is when you really constrain it down and instead of just saying
Speaker 2:  all of the information in the world, you say music or movie
Speaker 2:  recommendations or whatever, it won't always be perfect, but it's much more
Speaker 2:  likely to actually put you in sort of a useful interesting place
Speaker 2:  with some of these tools. So I think that is potentially very exciting. I
Speaker 2:  know it doesn't solve your whole problem of being able to say, play me everything
Speaker 2:  that I've rated three stars, but maybe we get to a point where you can say,
Speaker 2:  make me a playlist of songs I've listened to more than 25 times. That's a
Speaker 2:  cool idea. And would essentially gin up all of the things you've been obsessed
Speaker 2:  with over the years. So I'm hopeful that we're actually gonna get a lot of
Speaker 2:  what you're talking about even though we, the users are not going to have
Speaker 2:  quite as much control over it as I think you would like Tyler. And I would
Speaker 2:  like also, we'll see what Spotify launches and I think a lot of other companies
Speaker 2:  are gonna follow, but I am sort of fascinated by that. And also my interview
Speaker 2:  with Gustav is going to be on The Vergecast sometime in the next couple of
Speaker 2:  weeks and we talk about AI and playlists and lots of other stuff. So
Speaker 2:  keep an eye out for that one.
Speaker 1:  Alright,
Speaker 2:  That's enough for The Vergecast today. Thanks to everybody who came on and
Speaker 2:  thank you as always for listening. There's lots more about everything we
Speaker 2:  talked about at The Verge dot com. We're covering all of the Pixel stuff
Speaker 2:  where our reviews are up. The Chromebook Plus stuff is up. There are new
Speaker 2:  devices coming out, a lot going on in Google Land right now. So keep it locked
Speaker 2:  on The Verge dot com. And as always, if you have thoughts, feelings,
Speaker 2:  questions or other wacky things you think you can do with the
Speaker 2:  Pixels AI stuff, please let us know. Call the Hotline eight
Speaker 2:  six six Verge one one email Vergecast at The Verge dot com. Super fun to
Speaker 2:  hear from you all the time. Please keep it all coming. I'm sorry we don't
Speaker 2:  answer emails in particular as quickly as we'd like to sometimes. It's been
Speaker 2:  a busy few weeks, but we, we read them all. Love them all and we're
Speaker 2:  gonna get back to as many you as we can. Thank you as always for emailing.
Speaker 2:  This show is produced by Andrew Moreno and Liam James The. Vergecast is The
Speaker 2:  Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli, Alex, and
Speaker 2:  I'll be back on Friday to talk about the Quest Review all the trials
Speaker 2:  going on and a whole bunch more in tech news. We'll see you
Speaker 2:  then. Rock and roll.