# Transcript
ID: e0e03e66-c9c9-4336-a8f6-a1c984c805da
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Microsoft beat the FTC, and the Nothing Phone 2 is here
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-3477106268568543744/-1277868483262785650/s93290-US-4822s-1689326560.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss Microsoft winning the case against the FTC for its Activision Blizzard deal. Also: the Nothing Phone 2 and more gadgets.
Speaker 1:  You've probably heard about the job of an intimacy coordinator,
Speaker 1:  but do you know what they actually do?
Speaker 2:  And every intimacy coordinator's kit is gonna be some form of mint. Really?
Speaker 2:  I think most of the time Wait. Oh a hundred percent, huh? Then we add in
Speaker 2:  the full retro Listerine breath strip, which is crucial
Speaker 1:  Several years into the era of the intimacy coordinator.
Speaker 1:  We ask what they've changed for the better in Hollywood
Speaker 1:  and what still needs work. This week on Intuit
Speaker 1:  Vultures Pop Culture podcast
Speaker 4:  On criminal, we bring you true crime stories told
Speaker 4:  by people who know them best.
Speaker 5:  We didn't believe in setting fires cuz that was too dangerous. We were, you
Speaker 5:  know, kind a gentler kind of crooks so to speak.
Speaker 4:  So the best plan you had was that you'd LaSow it?
Speaker 6:  Yes. Never imagined I'd use it for a camel.
Speaker 4:  I'm Phoebe Judge and this is criminal. Did you have to say what
Speaker 4:  was in the box,
Speaker 8:  Phoebe? We told lies.
Speaker 4:  Listen to criminal every week, wherever you get your podcasts.
Speaker 7:  Hello and Welcome to our chest, the flagship podcast of an algorithmic
Speaker 7:  following feed. You're gonna like it. It doesn't matter what you
Speaker 7:  think. Have you followed the Nugget account yet? Nugget. It's
Speaker 7:  gonna follow you. That's my impression of Instagram adss. That's a whole
Speaker 7:  review. Hi, I'm your friend. Neli Alex. Cranz is here.
Speaker 10:  I haven't used the feed despite being on Threads Daily.
Speaker 7:  David Pierce is here alone
Speaker 11:  In the studio's. Weird.
Speaker 7:  This is a real inversion. If you're watching us on video, David's in New York
Speaker 7:  and we're both at home. That's not how this usually goes.
Speaker 11:  No, I came to the office today and you said no, it's just you and
Speaker 11:  the Nugget account in the office. You don't get to be around people you
Speaker 11:  like
Speaker 7:  Nugget account's killing it. And then you know, our friend Taylor Loren's
Speaker 7:  like oh has a deep intuitive understanding how social platforms work and
Speaker 7:  she's like, A new social platform is defined by volume and she's going ham
Speaker 7:  and God bless her. Oh yeah. It's like some people know And I can't do it,
Speaker 7:  but like the Nugget account Pop Crave and Taylor, they're like, we're gonna
Speaker 7:  dominate threads.
Speaker 11:  Yep. For me it's memes are Oh, memes are, I don't know where memes are came
Speaker 11:  from but like every other post is memes are and it is true. It's a, it's
Speaker 11:  a algorithmic land grab. They're like, oh, you don't know who to follow.
Speaker 11:  Here's some posts.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, just fire shit into the algorithm and maybe it will
Speaker 7:  reward you. Adam Aer will be like turn up the knob on that person. Pop Crave.
Speaker 7:  For a while there I was getting Bible verses. I think Casey was getting bible
Speaker 7:  verses too. And I was like this algorithm. It's not very good. This,
Speaker 7:  no, thank you.
Speaker 10:  It's just the Wendy's account for me on Sunday only Wendy's.
Speaker 7:  All right, we should start with Reds. There's a bunch of stuff to talk about.
Speaker 7:  Microsoft FTC resolved, FTC lost. Microsoft may be
Speaker 7:  able to buy Activision. That's a big deal. Big big deal. We should talk about
Speaker 7:  that. There's new Apple beta to talk about. There's a Senate hearing
Speaker 7:  right now about OpenAI and its data practices. the Nothing
Speaker 7:  Phone two came out. There's just like a lot. Bob Eger just like randomly
Speaker 7:  said he was gonna sell ESPN today. Yeah, there's all kinds of stuff going
Speaker 7:  on, but let's start with threads just like a quick vibe. Check on
Speaker 7:  threads. How are you feeling?
Speaker 11:  I'm torn. So I feel like we've, we've been through this thing. What
Speaker 11:  Eight Threads is now eight days old? Yeah. As we're recording this has
Speaker 11:  over a hundred million users. The growth is insane. Seems to be going
Speaker 11:  very well. Everyone at Meta is very excited and keeps talking about how
Speaker 11:  this has exceeded their wildest imaginations. But I also feel like it's
Speaker 11:  not even a backlash. It's like a pre backlash. Like everyone is talking
Speaker 11:  about how mad they're about to be at Threads for all the things that it
Speaker 11:  isn't and all the features it doesn't have. And the fact that your whole
Speaker 11:  feed is just the Nugget account. There was definitely, it had that energy
Speaker 11:  for like four days of just like pure summer
Speaker 11:  camp Joy. It was just like a bunch of posters found each other again and
Speaker 11:  it was very exciting. And it feels like that is already kind of starting
Speaker 11:  to turn off and at least my feed has gotten very
Speaker 11:  like engagement porn.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 11:  Constantly. It's just like interact with this,
Speaker 11:  look at this meme. Do you like this meme? Here's the Spider-Man meme. Remember
Speaker 11:  you found the Spider-Man meme funny. Here's some more Spider-Man memes,
Speaker 11:  And I. Still think it's more fun than Twitter.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. But it is definitely like, it's settling in into I think
Speaker 11:  a, a slightly less enthusiastic phase at least is my read so
Speaker 11:  far.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. My feed is a combo platter of jaded
Speaker 7:  tech journalists being like all the problems are coming and then yeah, the
Speaker 7:  Nugget account and then Shakira being like, what's your favorite color? you
Speaker 7:  know, and it's like, blue, will you talk to me
Speaker 7:  Shakira, I hear you're single. Like, you know, it's like
Speaker 7:  what are we supposed to do with this And I think that's kind
Speaker 7:  of exactly what they want. Yeah. One thing that's really interesting right
Speaker 7:  now, blue Sky is in the middle of some sort of content moderation scan.
Speaker 7:  Like they always will be, they don't have any that's the's the issue. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  They don't have any trust and safety. Like they're just always gonna have
Speaker 7:  scandals. Like they didn't have any filters. So people put the N word in
Speaker 7:  their usernames, like that's just right baby stuff. Right? Like baby problems
Speaker 7:  for babies. Instagram has it all. So I've seen all these people
Speaker 7:  talk about like, oh, why are the vibes nice? And like they've said on the
Speaker 7:  answer is like, because we're behaving ourselves. And the answer is like,
Speaker 7:  no. The answer is a gigantic metadata center
Speaker 7:  is keeping you away from it and it works and it's good and the product
Speaker 7:  is content moderation. And so you see stuff that's good and you don't see
Speaker 7:  stuff that's bad. And then occasionally the Nugget account is like, do you
Speaker 7:  remember the eighties? And you're like, yes. And they're like, people, it's
Speaker 7:  crazy, but like they're good at it. They're good at that thing in that way.
Speaker 7:  That's my vibe. Check on it right now is like people are sort of, they're
Speaker 7:  pre mad because they think the problems will happen again in exactly the
Speaker 7:  same way that they've always been happening. But Meta has like lived through
Speaker 7:  most of those problems. So they're gonna have new problems.
Speaker 7:  Don't get me, they're still Meta and we should talk about that a little bit,
Speaker 7:  but it just seems like that first wave of disillusionment of new social
Speaker 7:  platforms is definitely not gonna happen to threats.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. I I have found myself in the unusual position this week of spending
Speaker 11:  a lot of time running around reminding people that actually Meta is better
Speaker 11:  at running social networks than any other company on the planet. Which is
Speaker 11:  like a deranged thing to have to say and feels not true. But
Speaker 11:  it is true. Like Meta is better at this than everybody else. It's so much
Speaker 11:  bigger at it that it gets to deal with all the problems that no one else
Speaker 11:  has. They're
Speaker 10:  Better to an extent. Right. Like I
Speaker 11:  Think, I think the truth is it's impossible to be good at it. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 11:  But no one else is doing this better at any kind of scale
Speaker 11:  than Meta.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, that's
Speaker 10:  Right.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. Which is a deeply sad state of affairs, but seems true. And so I'm
Speaker 11:  like, it's weird to be that guy. I'm like defending meta's content moderation
Speaker 11:  abilities. But like it's, I think you're right, Nili.
Speaker 10:  I found myself defending Meta a lot this weekend. Like I didn't realize
Speaker 10:  so many people I followed were very like, we hate Facebook so we just hate
Speaker 10:  being here at all. And it's like, well you don't, you don't have to be here.
Speaker 10:  You can go somewhere else. And they're like, no, but I wanna be here because
Speaker 10:  I need to like be here.
Speaker 11:  Please follow me.
Speaker 10:  So I'm gonna be just very angry here. And. I'm like, that's just like a
Speaker 10:  we. And so it's like I'm having to be like, well you don't have to be here,
Speaker 10:  you can just turn this off. I don't like, you're just railing at the injustice
Speaker 10:  of Meta existing. Yeah. And that's a weird space.
Speaker 10:  But by actual like the interactions I'm having there are good, I've just
Speaker 10:  realized like, oh, if someone's being dumb, I don't have to interact with
Speaker 10:  them. And, I can like mute them or, or block them.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I think that's the other thing. Like you're a pro, you're like a social
Speaker 7:  media pro. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  We're a pro Now.
Speaker 7:  No one has to convince you to use the block button button. You're just doing
Speaker 7:  it. I
Speaker 10:  I can just not do that. And I can go and like interact with people who just
Speaker 10:  wanna talk about cool stuff and like, that's really, really nice. I'm not
Speaker 10:  having to worry about getting pulled into Culture wars. At one point some
Speaker 10:  guy was like, oh, you're saying this but you're trash or you know, whatever
Speaker 10:  random troll thing. It was And I was just like Mute. Yeah. Done
Speaker 10:  in scene. And my life went on And I didn't get really upset for an hour.
Speaker 10:  Like have to call somebody and be like, do you believe what this guy said
Speaker 10:  on threads? Which was far too common Occurrence on Twitter.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And I. Just think in general, people are
Speaker 7:  overestimating how much the vibe is good because people are generally
Speaker 7:  cool and underestimating how much it is that Meta is good at
Speaker 7:  content moderation. And to your point, I'm, they're not perfect
Speaker 7:  at it and they're, they're still, it's still Facebook, right? Like
Speaker 7:  they're still biased towards, and Shakira asking you what your
Speaker 7:  favorite color is like that. It's just they want engagement and they're good
Speaker 7:  at getting it. And sometimes that means just the weirdest stuff is happening
Speaker 7:  on this platform. And like drl, like basically, do you know
Speaker 7:  the fourth most popular Facebook page last week was like a picture of a
Speaker 7:  potato.
Speaker 7:  Oh it's, it was in Garbage Day by Brian Brodock, who's, who's great, we'll
Speaker 7:  link it. But it's like it's, he just had a great piece about how like the,
Speaker 7:  just the cultural impact of Facebook itself is almost nil
Speaker 7:  because being so weighted towards engagement
Speaker 7:  means that you have to acknowledge that the fourth most popular page is a
Speaker 7:  picture of a potato, right? It's up against Barbie Heimer. you know, like,
Speaker 7:  it's like, which movie are you gonna see first Barbie, Oppenheimer or look
Speaker 7:  at a picture of a potato? Like they're not on the same cultural scale.
Speaker 7:  And so Facebook has tons of engagement and, but it just doesn't have the
Speaker 7:  impact Threads is an opportunity for impact. And I think they're taking that
Speaker 7:  seriously. The last two things I'll say about this one, a lot of people have
Speaker 7:  asked me in particular if I believe them about Activity Pub
Speaker 7:  because I have said very loudly, the only reason I feel comfortable using
Speaker 7:  this platform is Federation and Decentralization. The evidence that they
Speaker 7:  are serious about it continues to grow, right? I've been sent screenshots
Speaker 7:  of Meta employees very sincerely engaging in like mailing
Speaker 7:  list discussions about the standard. I've seen Meta employees on threads
Speaker 7:  itself, like soliciting feedback for how Activity Pub should work. Like
Speaker 7:  being involved in the technical side of it. I think they have to do it to
Speaker 7:  launch in Europe. I I, I actually don't think they have a choice for any
Speaker 7:  number of like regulatory reasons now. It's like
Speaker 10:  A get outta jail free card. I don't know why they wouldn't do it.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Like it just in so many regulatory
Speaker 10:  discussions, it cr brings up a whole bunch of new ones, but it ends so
Speaker 10:  many of the big ones.
Speaker 7:  Well it's your choice is, it's like a very contradictory
Speaker 7:  regulatory position that they're in in Europe, which is you have to be interoperable
Speaker 7:  so you can get past the competition concerns, but then you've created a bunch
Speaker 7:  of illegal privacy practices because you're interoperable and that's like,
Speaker 7:  yep.
Speaker 11:  Oh
Speaker 7:  Look, I don't know the answer to that, but if anyone can figure it out, it's
Speaker 7:  Meta, And, I think also on top of all of that,
Speaker 7:  they want to, I think they just want to, I think they think it's a neat technical
Speaker 7:  challenge that their company is able to solve like
Speaker 7:  technical legal compliance, like all that, all that machinery.
Speaker 7:  This is the hardest problem for that machinery to solve. So I think
Speaker 7:  they want to And I think they might have to, but I think they're excited
Speaker 7:  about applying themselves to that problem.
Speaker 11:  I think the Instagram team is excited about it. Like Adam Maser just cannot
Speaker 11:  stop talking about Activity Pub. Like I believe him when he says how excited
Speaker 11:  he is about integrating. But I think one of the things that I have
Speaker 11:  wondered a lot about is because it's gotten so big so quickly and because
Speaker 11:  Meta clearly now sees this as like a real player and a real revenue opportunity
Speaker 11:  for the company, does this start to look less like a place we can
Speaker 11:  experiment with? What sort of might be the future and more like
Speaker 11:  we have to make money to make the metaverse happen and it's suddenly gonna
Speaker 11:  look really profitable short term to keep the doors closed. The part of
Speaker 11:  me that is cynical about this happening says that actually the more
Speaker 11:  successful it gets, the harder it will be both technically and
Speaker 11:  like culturally within Meta to do this. But I do think all
Speaker 11:  the people who are actually building this thing seem to be genuinely serious
Speaker 11:  about it. And I, I believe them. Yeah. At least at this point it's
Speaker 10:  A pretty small team, right? I think that's what Alex Heath said last week
Speaker 10:  on the show. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  I think Moster has said it's like a couple dozen people. Like it's not,
Speaker 11:  it's not huge.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Like this isn't been a big time sucker financial suck for the company
Speaker 10:  and like the upsides just enormous. so like yeah, right.
Speaker 7:  And I think the money importantly is also not, they don't have to invent
Speaker 7:  a business model. They have to get some data and do some ad targeting
Speaker 7:  and deliver some impressions that convert into e-commerce and they know how
Speaker 7:  to do that. Like it's, it's just
Speaker 11:  Meta's good at this.
Speaker 7:  Like the Facebook ad units exist today. If all Meta was saying
Speaker 7:  was run these Facebook ad units and you can now target people on threads,
Speaker 7:  they make the money,
Speaker 7:  will they convert? Like are they good? Who, who knows? But they don't have
Speaker 7:  to like invent it from whole cloth and go out to the market
Speaker 7:  and say like, here's a new thing to buy. They're just like, can you extend
Speaker 7:  the reach of our existing things that are, this thing is Facebook. Yep. It
Speaker 7:  is the Facebook newsfeed. It's kind of funny that we, you know,
Speaker 7:  we're, we're excited about it. It's 2011 again. It's just, here it is again.
Speaker 10:  But key difference. I have not had to watch someone make a horrible, horrible
Speaker 10:  dish in a video yet yet. Like I haven't gotten that that like tastes give
Speaker 10:  it time m but oh it's coming
Speaker 7:  By God. The celebrities are there to cook at you in any minute. It's coming.
Speaker 7:  I will say it is still Meta this story. you know, good
Speaker 7:  vibes on Meta Z Hero, he's got a six pack, whatever,
Speaker 7:  it's still Meta. The the flip side of Meta is still Meta, right? All the
Speaker 7:  problems are still there with the other platforms. They do not have end-to-end
Speaker 7:  encryption enabled in Messenger by default. And so just this
Speaker 7:  week a woman pled guilty for exchanging messages
Speaker 7:  with her daughter that enabled her to get abortion pills in a state in which
Speaker 7:  abortion was legal. The cops were able to go get a warrant to search her
Speaker 7:  text because Meta has not enabled and then encryption by default, they should
Speaker 7:  do that. They should take the political hit and just do that and they haven't
Speaker 7:  done it. And this is, people have been asking 'em to for years, I would make
Speaker 7:  the direct comparison to Apple, right? Which is insistent upon
Speaker 7:  encryption. And yes, there are ways around it, especially if iCloud on all
Speaker 7:  that stuff. But when there was a San Bernardino attack and the FBI said unlock
Speaker 7:  the phone, apple said, we won't, we have these principles. And so I just,
Speaker 7:  it's great that Zuck is jacked and flexing on
Speaker 7:  Elon like all great, right? They still run some large platforms with
Speaker 7:  some real problems and that, that story about the woman going to jail, like
Speaker 7:  that is a horrible story. Yeah. Like I, I'm outraged by that story. Every
Speaker 7:  time I think about it, I mean
Speaker 10:  There's a lot of those horrible stories. We're not gonna get into 'em all
Speaker 10:  today, but like Meta consistently has said profit
Speaker 10:  over people and they're gonna continue to do that just right now
Speaker 10:  it's really fun for the people. So yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Take some of those good vibes. Make
Speaker 10:  Money off of me. I'm having a great time.
Speaker 7:  This is like an old political quote. Like when you have the chips, you gotta
Speaker 7:  cash 'em. They don't hold so you got the political chips, cash
Speaker 7:  'em on end to encryption. That's all I'm saying. The other thing we should
Speaker 7:  talk about real quick before we go into FTC, it's Apple public beta week.
Speaker 7:  They just hit, we've got a bunch of coverage, although apple's we like all
Speaker 7:  the people have had them forever. Like people have been breaking the nds
Speaker 7:  in these forever. But the Official public betas are, are here.
Speaker 7:  They're fun. They're they're, they're like, it's a fun set of updates.
Speaker 11:  Widgets, man. It's just widgets. Yeah. Life is widgets now.
Speaker 11:  2011 again, David,
Speaker 10:  You're very happy.
Speaker 11:  I love widgets. I will die. And my last breath will be
Speaker 11:  to say smartphones should not just be things you use to open
Speaker 11:  apps. That'll be, write that on my tombstone. What
Speaker 10:  An epitaph.
Speaker 11:  Monica wrote a really good thing about how the Mac is just turning into
Speaker 11:  the iPhone. Yeah. Which I think is exactly right. Like you, you can have
Speaker 11:  desktop widgets on your Mac now Standby is a thing.
Speaker 11:  The smart display stuff is starting to become interesting. I I think it's
Speaker 11:  very cool. I have also installed all of these betas and they have just absolutely
Speaker 11:  decimated the battery life on every single one of my devices.
Speaker 11:  My, my phone now runs really hot for about four hours every single day.
Speaker 11:  It's really great. I really recommend the public pay us. I talked a bunch
Speaker 11:  about this with, with a bunch of our team on the Wednesday show. What are
Speaker 11:  you guys psyched about? Have you tested anything? Is there anything you're
Speaker 11:  seeing that you think is cool?
Speaker 10:  I have been terrified to test it because I need my battery life. I already
Speaker 10:  have bad battery life. I can't make it worse. So I have, I've put it off
Speaker 10:  so far, but the standby mode like that, I just got one of the mag safe
Speaker 10:  chargers but for my bedside table and I'm like, Ooh.
Speaker 7:  Oh nice.
Speaker 10:  Oh I want this. I also got one for my car and you're a liar. Nili, they
Speaker 10:  suck. Good. Just throwing
Speaker 7:  It out there. Which one did you get? Someone hit me up on threads and said
Speaker 7:  there's a new one. Okay, I gotta find the brand. But they're like, you should
Speaker 7:  buy this one. It's, it's the new, it's the newest hottest one
Speaker 10:  I put, it's like a Balkan one. And I stuck it in my vent and it immediately
Speaker 10:  just tipped down
Speaker 7:  And starts drooping. Yeah. It's too heavy for the vents. All that's better
Speaker 7:  than CarPlay. So you know, whatever. Nope. So I'm an every other year
Speaker 7:  Mac os updater. So I haven't, I I just skipped Ventura like I
Speaker 7:  was like miss me with it. Like come at me the next year when you figured
Speaker 7:  it out, you know? Sure. So I'm just, I'm just excited about like a fresh
Speaker 7:  coat of paint on Mac Os and then I missed out on all the Ventura
Speaker 7:  features. So I'm excited about dumb stuff like continuity camera that I just
Speaker 7:  haven't used for a year. And that's a, it just seems like there's a layer
Speaker 7:  of polish on that stuff. Stage manager on the iPad. David, you wrote about
Speaker 7:  it. It's not great, but it's not just a
Speaker 11:  But it's not awful anymore.
Speaker 10:  David's no longer like furious every time he mentions it. Like
Speaker 10:  previously we would've heard a loud groan as soon as you said stage. And
Speaker 10:  we didn't get that.
Speaker 11:  It's gotten to the point where like, I no longer think you're a bad person
Speaker 11:  if you use stage manager. Wow.
Speaker 7:  It was a, it was a moral flaw.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. Like if you used stage manager, you And, I are just not on the same
Speaker 11:  page how the world works. But now it's like they're doing
Speaker 11:  a thing. I don't think they've done it yet. There's a lot of work left to
Speaker 11:  do. And I, like I feel the same way about standby actually, which is that
Speaker 11:  standby is like an amazing idea that basically has no idea the rest of the
Speaker 11:  iPhone exists. so like you, you put your phone up landscape and
Speaker 11:  then you tap the thing to open the app and it just opens an app sideways.
Speaker 11:  Yep. And it's like, well that's not right. Like this is not how this is
Speaker 11:  supposed to work, but you can see where it's going and stage manager I think
Speaker 11:  now you can see where it's going and that makes me very happy.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I wonder if I'm ever gonna use standby mode. It's one of those things
Speaker 7:  where like, I'm gonna, I'm gonna buy a dock and be excited about it and it
Speaker 7:  will never happen. You're
Speaker 10:  Going to use it when you get in your car and CarPlay comes on and you're
Speaker 10:  like, oh actually CarPlay is good and your phone will just go into standby
Speaker 10:  mode.
Speaker 11:  No Neli, do you wanna know my theory? The, the thing of all of this that
Speaker 11:  is going to be the best for you is the redesign on the watch
Speaker 11:  where you just scroll the digital crown, the revolutionary input device
Speaker 11:  on par with the mouse and multi-touch and it's just widgets. Yeah. Just,
Speaker 11:  just a bunch of widgets. Neli is gonna be out here just widget all day.
Speaker 11:  I read
Speaker 7:  V's. Preview of watch I was 10 where she was like, and now you use the Digital
Speaker 7:  Crown more. And. I was like, oh, we're going backwards. Like we just got
Speaker 7:  Kevin Lynch got in that car and he was like junk and put it in reverse and
Speaker 7:  was like speed it off the cliff backwards. People,
Speaker 7:  nobody
Speaker 11:  Understands the magic of it. He has to make you use it Now
Speaker 7:  He's Like he will use it. Yeah. I'm using, I I don't want to
Speaker 7:  pre-judge. I I get, I I understand why you would head that
Speaker 7:  way, right? These like app clippy widget things
Speaker 7:  where you get lots of slices of different apps on a, a screen that's getting
Speaker 7:  ever larger. I I get it all sort of emotionally,
Speaker 7:  but I'm just kind of like, I don't know man. I'm not, I'm not out here trying
Speaker 7:  to like fiddle with the watch all day long. Like give me the modular face
Speaker 7:  with as much text on it as I can get. And, I will be happy,
Speaker 7:  but we'll see just
Speaker 10:  A little book on your phone on your watch. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  But the betas are out. Go. If you're, you know, the sort of person who downloads
Speaker 7:  Vedas, go hit 'em. Like use them and then send us a note. I I, I'm very curious
Speaker 7:  to see what you all think of them. And,
Speaker 11:  I will say the one I I would most years, I
Speaker 11:  would say at this point in time, everyone, almost everyone should feel comfortable
Speaker 11:  downloading the public betas this year, especially on iOS.
Speaker 11:  I have had more weirdness than usual. There's this weird keyboard
Speaker 11:  bug in a lot of apps that like, it'll just sort of disappear the
Speaker 11:  text box and so you'll be kind of typing into nothing. It's gone in some
Speaker 11:  apps, but like it's still there for me in messages. So it's still like,
Speaker 11:  if you are not a person who wants to spend your day like closing and reopening
Speaker 11:  apps to make things work, I would probably wait one more Rev on the public
Speaker 11:  beta before you download it.
Speaker 7:  Okay. Two things. I just thought, two things I have, I have a, I have a much
Speaker 7:  better answer to my favorite public beta moment. Okay. So
Speaker 7:  we are like long past the point where Apple can even talk about all the
Speaker 7:  features of iOS. Yeah. Like do you remember when Apple is like, and now you
Speaker 7:  can copy and paste and that took an hour to announce Right?
Speaker 7:  And now it's just like there's too much
Speaker 11:  Long Press was like an entire Apple event.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. They could not, they could not announce all this stuff this year.
Speaker 7:  And one thing they didn't really announce or spend time on is this personal
Speaker 7:  voice assistant thing and accessibility where you can train it on your voice
Speaker 7:  and then it can speak for you. So you do 15 minutes of training and then
Speaker 7:  overnight locally it processes an AI voice for you. Cool as hell.
Speaker 7:  Straight up. Cool as hell.
Speaker 11:  Have you done yours yet?
Speaker 7:  I have no, I don't have the betas yet. I'm not brave enough. Oh yeah, that's
Speaker 7:  right. Look, this is a production environment, David. All right. We don't
Speaker 7:  mess around.
Speaker 11:  So I, I have recorded the requisite 150 sentences.
Speaker 11:  My, my thing is still processing. It takes a long time to do it. It
Speaker 7:  Turns out data centers are faster at this than your folk. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  Yeah. But I will, I will come on the show next week. And. I will, I will
Speaker 11:  play for you some of what we have and then we're working on some other fun
Speaker 11:  stuff for later this month. So
Speaker 7:  Here's my absolute favorite public video moment and shout to our friend Marquez
Speaker 7:  Brownley cuz I understand exactly why this happened. He made it TikTok
Speaker 7:  demoing this feature and it was obviously in drafts and TikTok has a bug
Speaker 7:  where if the video's in drafts and you publish it, it will just play
Speaker 7:  whatever music you picked at full volume and not run your audio. And it was
Speaker 7:  just the Paw Patrol theme song. And it was
Speaker 7:  just the funniest thing I've ever seen. And I was like, I really hope they
Speaker 7:  leave it up. And they took it down and they put it up and it's the real video
Speaker 7:  now it's great. Marquez did a great job, but there was just that brief like
Speaker 7:  50 minutes where it was just, it was a regular Marquez demo
Speaker 7:  video like he's talking, but instead of any audio it was just full
Speaker 7:  volume Paw Patrol. Incredible. I was like, this is what we're, this is what
Speaker 7:  the internet's for. We don't worry. We saved a clip if you need it, you know,
Speaker 7:  send us a Bitcoin. Okay. Don't do that. That's horrible for
Speaker 7:  the environment. Okay. But if you're using it Vercast to The Verge dot com,
Speaker 7:  I'd love to hear, understand, I'm always curious. Okay, we should talk about
Speaker 7:  the big, big news of the week. There's just a lot of
Speaker 7:  interpretation of this, a lot of ways you can think about it. But
Speaker 7:  Tom Addie, Andrew, we covered the hell out of the FTC versus Microsoft
Speaker 7:  trial. Ups downs, twist turns decision came
Speaker 7:  out. FCC lost like in pretty thorough fashion I would say.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, it was, this whole thing went very quickly because
Speaker 11:  Microsoft had this July 18th deadline by which it had to acquire or
Speaker 11:  it had to finalize the deal to acquire Activision Blizzard or not. So this
Speaker 11:  all happened super fast. And the thing I really wanna talk about and the
Speaker 11:  thing I want you specifically to explain to me and Eli because you've been
Speaker 11:  sort of talking about this obliquely all week, And I want you to like put
Speaker 11:  all your thoughts in one place for me is this entire thing turned
Speaker 11:  out to be about Call of Duty. Yeah. In the judge's ruling, like the second
Speaker 11:  or third sentence was about Call of Duty. It says the gist of the FTCs complaint
Speaker 11:  is Call of Duty is so popular and such an important supply for any video
Speaker 11:  game platform that the combined firm is probably going to foreclose it from
Speaker 11:  its rivals for its own economic benefit to com customers detriment. And
Speaker 11:  then it goes on to basically say that's not the case. And so they lose How
Speaker 11:  is that what this trial was about?
Speaker 7:  Like
Speaker 11:  If, if just this became, can everyone have Call of Duty or not?
Speaker 11:  And Don don't feel like that was what the FTC actually meant to argue
Speaker 11:  if it was gonna try to win this case. What is happening here? Yeah, explain
Speaker 11:  this to me.
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna respond to this by offering a statement that I can not back
Speaker 7:  up but which I believe is true.
Speaker 11:  Okay.
Speaker 7:  Sony doesn't think cloud gaming will happen. Ooh. That's what I believe.
Speaker 7:  Okay. I don't know if that's true. I don't know if inside of Sony there's
Speaker 7:  some, you know, they, we've, we've reported on and Sean Holster has reported
Speaker 7:  on, you know, the hires that Sony has listed to build a new cloud gaming
Speaker 7:  service and they've had their fits and starts and whatever. They've got this
Speaker 7:  weird handheld that only runs over wifi. It doesn't seem like they're working
Speaker 7:  on it very hard. Right. They bought Guy Kai and killed it like right to Sony,
Speaker 7:  I think at a, at a base level is like the future of consoles is giant
Speaker 7:  ass GPUs in your living room and will send code
Speaker 7:  to you and you'll run them locally. Right? Like I think that's Sony's bet.
Speaker 7:  If you're Sony, that's a good bet. It has won you every generation of the
Speaker 7:  console work.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. Every time Microsoft is like, we have a new idea and Sony is like,
Speaker 11:  we have more powerful games and Sony just keeps winning.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It it's, it's fi it's just the way it goes. you know, Microsoft's point
Speaker 7:  of view, And, I've had Phil Spencer on decoder and he has said this out loud,
Speaker 7:  I think he said at trial, I was like, look, the console market is shrinking.
Speaker 7:  We are losing to mobile. So winning this small ever smaller
Speaker 7:  slice of pie is not the point. And he has said to me and he said to the court,
Speaker 7:  call of Duty is not the point of this acquisition. The point of this
Speaker 7:  acquisition in the present is like Candy Crush the
Speaker 7:  King, which acquisition also owns that makes a ton of money on mobile games.
Speaker 7:  The point of this acquisition is building a library for our cloud gaming
Speaker 7:  future, which, hey, we own Azure, this is a great business for us to be in.
Speaker 7:  We, we, we've got all these ideas about cloud gaming. One day we'll solve
Speaker 7:  the Apple problem and ship a Xbox cloud gaming app on the phone. And so you're
Speaker 7:  like, that's why they're doing it. And so if you're the FTC, I think they
Speaker 7:  kind of got baited by both Microsoft and Sony
Speaker 7:  into endlessly talking about Call of Duty. Because what Sony
Speaker 7:  wants is Call of Duty.
Speaker 11:  So Sony's version of this is we don't care about any of the rest of this.
Speaker 11:  We just want some kind of assurance that we're gonna keep getting Call
Speaker 11:  of Duty. Right.
Speaker 7:  That this is the only game that Activision makes, that Sony gives a shit
Speaker 7:  about.
Speaker 11:  Right.
Speaker 7:  Apparently I I they haven't talked about any others. They don't care about
Speaker 7:  Diablo for, they don't care about Diablo, they don't care about Starfield.
Speaker 7:  Like all, you know, all this other stuff Microsoft makes, like they don't,
Speaker 7:  they have a lot of exclusives.
Speaker 11:  Right. And the numbers we've heard are are insane and back that up, right?
Speaker 11:  Like the, the numbers that came up about the, the huge percentage of people
Speaker 11:  who game, who only play Call of Duty and the billions of dollars in revenue
Speaker 11:  that this is means to Sony every single year. Like you can see why.
Speaker 11:  But yeah, again to your point, like this actually should not have been a
Speaker 11:  lawsuit about Call of Duty because no one was actually in disagreement
Speaker 11:  about Call of Duty.
Speaker 7:  If you're saying we're worried about this and your opponent is like, here
Speaker 7:  you go like over and over again, it's like here you go, you want it on the
Speaker 7:  switch. What's some no name, third rate game streaming service,
Speaker 7:  crackle, we'll put Call of Duty on Crackle. Anything you want, call of Duty,
Speaker 7:  wherever you want it. Right. Microsoft's been saying this around the world
Speaker 7:  and you know, the court in its opinion said this is one of the biggest deals
Speaker 7:  in the world. It deserves scrutiny, it got a lot of scrutiny. This is fine.
Speaker 7:  Guess what? All the scrutiny resulted in Call of Duty. Microsoft was showing
Speaker 7:  up at the table with that deal for everyone. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  Can I just read you that chunk of the opinion? Cuz actually it think it's
Speaker 11:  super interesting. It says Microsoft's acquisition of Activision has been
Speaker 11:  described as the largest in tech history. It deserves scrutiny that scrutiny
Speaker 11:  has paid off. Microsoft has committed in writing in public and in court
Speaker 11:  to keep Call of Duty on PlayStation for 10 years on parity with Xbox. It
Speaker 11:  made an agreement with Nintendo to bring Call of Duty to switch and it entered
Speaker 11:  several agreements to, for the first time bring Activision content to several
Speaker 11:  cloud gaming services. And then it's basically the, the implication there
Speaker 11:  is like, and we're done here. Yeah. Yeah. And And I think you're right.
Speaker 11:  Like that's everyone at Microsoft was up there yelling that they, this was
Speaker 11:  what they wanted to do through the entire process. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Here's the deal that we would like to give you and the court's like they're
Speaker 7:  gonna give you that deal and that's fine. I just think that there's something
Speaker 7:  in there that's like everyone wants to pile in the FTC for losing this case
Speaker 7:  and you should, I think they did a bad job. I think they got distracted into
Speaker 7:  this Call of Duty side show. Right. And it's because Sony wanted this deal.
Speaker 7:  so like Sony is screaming
Speaker 7:  like give us Call of Duty and the FTC is like, all right, that's our way
Speaker 7:  in. Like this other big company is mad about it and like we'll find some
Speaker 7:  anti-competitive stuff and then you've got Sony's own executives and emails
Speaker 7:  in evidence being like, I'm not so worried about this. Yeah, whatever. But
Speaker 7:  then you look around the world, right? It's still not done in the uk and
Speaker 7:  the UK is like focused on cloud gaming. You look at the EU which focused
Speaker 7:  on cloud gaming and Call of Duty and got Call of Duty and said, all right,
Speaker 7:  we'll see if the Americans can do this. It's not that the FTC shouldn't have
Speaker 7:  done the scrutiny, every other big regulatory body applied the same
Speaker 7:  level of scrutiny and is getting various kinds of deals. I think
Speaker 7:  what people are looking at is the FTC lost this case in court
Speaker 7:  and they've lost some other cases and you're like, maybe this isn't, maybe
Speaker 7:  they're just always gonna lose and they should never try And I just I, that
Speaker 7:  to me is the mistake. And it's a mistake for two reasons. One, the court
Speaker 7:  itself saying, look at what this scrutiny got you. It got you Call of Duty.
Speaker 7:  If Microsoft wasn't anticipating the scrutiny, they wouldn't have started
Speaker 7:  with we'll give you Call of Duty. They would've started with, we're gonna
Speaker 7:  make Call of Duty exclusive like they did with their other dames. So weird.
Speaker 7:  Right? Like that's just a weird thing to be like, if you take away the threat,
Speaker 7:  they'll still behave. I don't believe that. Then there's the second thing,
Speaker 7:  which is like very, very, very wonky, but the Lena
Speaker 7:  Khan project at the FTC and Lena Conn has
Speaker 7:  been on this show before. She was the chairperson at the FTC. You can go
Speaker 7:  listen to her. Her project is that the antitrust laws of this country are
Speaker 7:  bad. Right? Right. That they were reinterpreted in the eighties by Robert
Speaker 7:  Borg and Ronald Reagan, all this stuff. And that we got to a place where
Speaker 7:  we no longer think about competition. We just measured prices. And that has
Speaker 7:  led to all kinds of bad effects. And I think that is true, it's
Speaker 7:  true for a variety of reasons. And her project is to go get the courts or
Speaker 7:  Congress or someone to reset antitrust law. And there's two ways
Speaker 7:  to do it. One, you create a lot of political capital, you make a lot
Speaker 7:  of angry people so that Congress does something. So
Speaker 7:  Amy Klobuchar and Elizabeth Warren and Ken Buck, who's a Republican who's
Speaker 7:  on that committee can pass the antitrust bill that they've had in their back
Speaker 7:  pocket forever, right? Saying, look, this wasn't the right outcome under
Speaker 7:  the existing law. Here's a new law. Or you take it up to the appeals court
Speaker 7:  and say, the way we've been applying this law for ages is
Speaker 7:  inappropriate because of these effects in this thing. We want you to
Speaker 7:  write a new precedent. And then you take that to the Supreme Court, which
Speaker 7:  I would just point out this particular Supreme Court is like new precedent,
Speaker 7:  here you go. Like they're just into it. So you, she's just playing
Speaker 7:  a long game. I think she's played the early innings of that long game
Speaker 7:  kind of stupidly. Like candidly, I think she has done a bad job at these
Speaker 7:  things. She certainly has not explained that she's playing a long game.
Speaker 11:  And you would think it would help to have some kind of like small wins along
Speaker 11:  the way to prove that. Like we are stepping in the right direction and instead
Speaker 11:  it's just like, I'm gonna lose aggressively and then I'm gonna win. And
Speaker 11:  that, that gets harder. I think
Speaker 10:  Could she have ever won this case? Because like even the, the, the
Speaker 10:  deal for the, so the Sony deal, that's only 10 years. Call of
Speaker 10:  Duty's been around for what, more than 20. It's been a huge, huge thing
Speaker 10:  for more than 20 years. So nothing's to stop Microsoft 10 years from
Speaker 10:  now from just saying, okay, that's it. Exclusive. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  But we'll all be dead then there'll be like a new generation of dancing teams
Speaker 7:  on a different platform and like whatever that
Speaker 10:  That even that felt kind of anti-competitive to me and, and the court court
Speaker 10:  saying, no, this is fine. Like was there any hope of winning
Speaker 10:  this case if she'd gone after the other stuff, if she hadn't gone after
Speaker 10:  Call of Duty?
Speaker 7:  I don't know. I I I think we just won't know. I think the Call of Duty
Speaker 7:  stuff was just such a distraction and somehow we ended just talking about
Speaker 7:  it. And I just will point you to Phil Spencer on decoder. It's like
Speaker 7:  this deal is not about Call of Duty. Who wants it? Well
Speaker 7:  we're gonna run Call of Duty and an iframe on The Verge dot com like 10 years.
Speaker 7:  He'll, he'll write that deal with us tomorrow. He fine. As long as you're
Speaker 7:  paying 70 bucks a pop for Call of Duty, it's a great business. They're not
Speaker 7:  gonna change it. This thing is about, okay, how do we create a new paradigm
Speaker 7:  for games that ends the console era and
Speaker 7:  creates new market share? And that's why we end up talking about like the
Speaker 7:  Switch and all this other stuff, right? Like okay may and maybe they should
Speaker 7:  have a big library of exclusives to do it, but you just see how
Speaker 7:  with every other kind of streaming media, that cycle
Speaker 7:  is bad for consumers. It leads to less choices, it leads to
Speaker 7:  less content and it leads to higher prices. Like just
Speaker 7:  look at the streaming television industry. Not everything is on every service.
Speaker 7:  All the prices are completely insane and the apps are not good. And you're
Speaker 7:  like, do we, is that how you want this to go? Like shouldn't we make sure
Speaker 7:  there's like a lot of competition here or a lot of like developers across
Speaker 7:  these services so they have to compete for our dollars with quality as
Speaker 7:  opposed to competing for dollars with content that comes and goes. Like,
Speaker 7:  that's the thing I'm worried.
Speaker 10:  My question is why didn't the judge see that? Cuz they, they made that case
Speaker 10:  like during the thing they maybe didn't hammer on it the same as Call of
Speaker 10:  Duty.
Speaker 7:  David's got the opinion. If you look at the opinion where the judge deals
Speaker 7:  with cloud gaming, she's kinda like, I don't know, this seems weird, we're
Speaker 7:  not gonna
Speaker 10:  Do it. Yeah. Like that's, that's my thing is like how could she have won
Speaker 10:  if the, the judge doesn't even like understand cloud gaming, right? Like
Speaker 10:  if the judge is kind of being a dumb ass.
Speaker 7:  Wait, I, I realize I've been very strident, but I think if we get to a place
Speaker 7:  where like how can the American legal system not understand cloud gaming?
Speaker 7:  We might have already lost.
Speaker 10:  Right? That's true. That's if that's her, if her strategy
Speaker 10:  is to overturn antitrust law at a higher court, they still have to get,
Speaker 10:  or they're gonna have to understand cl cloud gaming, right? Like they're
Speaker 10:  gonna have to understand this stuff. Yeah. If we can't get this judge to
Speaker 10:  understand it, how are we gonna get the next judge to understand it?
Speaker 11:  But this is where we come back to it. I, I feel like so many of these
Speaker 11:  fights and trials end up coming down to market size
Speaker 11:  definitions and this was the case again, right? They had this giant fight
Speaker 11:  over, is Nintendo a genuine competitor
Speaker 11:  to Sony and Microsoft? And is the cloud
Speaker 11:  an actual threat to the console world? And, I think
Speaker 11:  in that case, if Sony is in the ear of the FTC being
Speaker 11:  the one sort of explaining the other side of this fight and Sony is out
Speaker 11:  here saying, yeah, we're not that worried about cloud gaming, that's fine.
Speaker 11:  Then I can see how you would sort of write it off as like a lark that Microsoft
Speaker 11:  is on and Microsoft has been on many larks that have not worked
Speaker 11:  out. And so I think Microsoft is also sitting there saying
Speaker 11:  Cloud gaming is like cool and fine, but we don't really care about it. Like
Speaker 11:  they spent so much time they tell investors it's the future. They tell the
Speaker 11:  world it's the future. They talk a ton about it and then they sit on the
Speaker 11:  stand and say, oh, we've pretty much paused all of our cloud gaming stuff.
Speaker 11:  We don't care all but care about it all that much.
Speaker 10:  Is that like where the screw up happened for Kahan? Like is that where she,
Speaker 10:  her her team screwed up is they didn't try to explain the actual technology
Speaker 10:  stuff?
Speaker 7:  No, I think the screw up happened that Sony basically
Speaker 7:  was like, we are the competitor and we will be harmed and the judge will
Speaker 7:  understand us, Sony saying this is anti-competitive and then
Speaker 7:  they fell down the rabbit hole of Call of Duty.
Speaker 10:  Okay.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I think that's
Speaker 7:  Right. The one I'll compare to, and this is really interesting, antitrust
Speaker 7:  is broken. So this is, so why just go with me on this. This is what's a
Speaker 7:  vertical merger, right? Where you buy the next company up and down the stack
Speaker 7:  from you. So Microsoft needs games, it buys games. They're not direct competitor,
Speaker 7:  it's a vertical merger. Microsoft bought Sony, that'd be a horizontal merger,
Speaker 7:  right? They're direct competitors, vertical mergers, like never get challenged
Speaker 7:  there, there hasn't been one in like 40 years. The last one, the
Speaker 7:  challenge was at and t Time Warner by the Trump administration.
Speaker 11:  The answer to every antitrust trivia question in like the best way. It's
Speaker 7:  It's a very good, so this, this opinion like has to cite the
Speaker 7:  most recent precedent and yeah, it just has to continuously cite
Speaker 7:  at and t and Time Warner as good precedent for allowing vertical
Speaker 7:  mergers. And it's just like, my dude did that work?
Speaker 7:  Was that a good idea? Is anyone happy about that? Except for
Speaker 7:  David Zoff. Zack Snyder.
Speaker 7:  Like Zack Snyder got to put out like a weird gray square version
Speaker 7:  of
Speaker 11:  The eight people who watched that are probably happy.
Speaker 7:  I watched all three hours. I thought about watching it again the other day.
Speaker 7:  And I sat down. And I was like, I can't do this.
Speaker 7:  Like I can't be watching a square movie right now. Like if there's, you know,
Speaker 7:  those AI things where it's like we made the thing wide, it's like just do
Speaker 7:  that for, for Justice Lee. Just please just AI the
Speaker 7:  shit outta it.
Speaker 11:  Just expand the phrase
Speaker 7:  Please. You let me use my whole tv. That's it. It's, it's like super didn't
Speaker 7:  work. It was a disaster idea that caused
Speaker 7:  thousands of people to lose their jobs, right? Because the theory of
Speaker 7:  the merger was bad and yeah, you could say maybe the market will sort out
Speaker 7:  over time, but like the government could have stopped it by saying this will
Speaker 7:  reduce competition. Which it definitely did. We
Speaker 7:  definitely ended up with more consolidation on the other end of that
Speaker 7:  in streaming. And we ended up with a less competitive wireless marketplace
Speaker 7:  over time. Like it's just all that happened, like at and t did not
Speaker 7:  spend money on its network cuz they were busy spending money on
Speaker 7:  fucking Gray Justice League. Why? But that's the only other
Speaker 7:  vertical merger case that we have. And in that case, the, the court in at
Speaker 7:  TT Warner is constantly talking about how there's no precedent. Like this
Speaker 7:  is the first one in 40 years. That's weird. We should have more of these.
Speaker 11:  Oh wow.
Speaker 7:  So like, I I would just take a beat. Like this is a big project
Speaker 7:  to reset how we think about competition in this country. It will, the
Speaker 7:  beginning of it will be more losing than winning. I I I just inevitable
Speaker 7:  and maybe we need a new law. But like you get to the new law by a
Speaker 7:  bunch of senators and congress people saying, well the FTC
Speaker 7:  does not have the tools it needs to create competition. We have to give them
Speaker 7:  some new tools.
Speaker 10:  I guess my my concern is we, we did have some, some protections for
Speaker 10:  vertical integration. There was like the Paramount consent decree, which
Speaker 10:  was from the thirties, which told like film studios that they
Speaker 10:  couldn't own the theaters. Yeah. Now they own the theaters again, they're
Speaker 10:  just streaming. And that also in the Trump era got overturned cuz they were
Speaker 10:  like, no, we don't need this anymore. So it's like the court seemed to be
Speaker 10:  like, yeah, vertical integration, coolest thing in the world. So how, how
Speaker 10:  is, how do they go through the courts to stop something like Microsoft acquiring
Speaker 10:  Activision or at and t acquiring Warner Brothers?
Speaker 7:  I I just wanna be clear at this point, a workable antitrust law in this
Speaker 7:  country would to just be, to make it illegal for at and t to buy
Speaker 7:  anything or for anyone to buy Time Warner
Speaker 7:  Like you. If that was just the rule, I it might be fine.
Speaker 7:  Like more people would keep their jobs. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  That's like a and that's a way to measure like what's a good policy is like
Speaker 7:  when you have mergers, people get laid off, it ruins
Speaker 7:  lives. Maybe some shareholders will make more money, but along the way, a
Speaker 7:  bunch of like secretaries, like that redundant function, like your
Speaker 7:  back office merged and you like lay off your accounting department, right?
Speaker 7:  Like the, the, those are destructive actions for like thousands of people.
Speaker 7:  If you just banned at and t from buying stuff, like more people would've
Speaker 7:  kept their jobs like straight. Like that's just a way to measure it. If you
Speaker 7:  could ban any, anyone from buying Time Warner, like AOL might still exist.
Speaker 7:  Like it's just like one of those things.
Speaker 11:  Do you buy the logic that the, the FTC and even the judge in this case have,
Speaker 11:  have said, which is basically just that the existence of
Speaker 11:  cases like this and the fact that there is someone paying attention and
Speaker 11:  willing to pick this fight is gonna do a lot of the work all by itself.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, because before I think we, we spent a generation with companies just
Speaker 11:  being like, no, what everyone at the FTC is asleep at the wheel. This is
Speaker 11:  a non-issue. We'll get anything through. We want to, and now
Speaker 11:  the case for Lina Con would be at least someone is willing to pick the fight
Speaker 11:  and that's, that's gonna make fewer people want to be on the other side
Speaker 11:  of it.
Speaker 7:  Wait, I have two questions. I have two questions for you. Name one other
Speaker 7:  commissioner of the FTC.
Speaker 11:  No. Okay. I don't, I don't want, I know them all. I don't want
Speaker 11:  to,
Speaker 7:  I don't wanna pick favorites name the previous
Speaker 7:  chair of the FTC, right? It's tough. Todd
Speaker 10:  Siegel,
Speaker 11:  Ronald Ray,
Speaker 7:  Herbert.
Speaker 7:  I dunno, it doesn't, like she has a reputation and her reputation
Speaker 7:  is that she thinks big mergers and consolidation are bad.
Speaker 7:  Maybe she'll win, maybe she'll lose. But that is like a drastic change.
Speaker 7:  And I do I, I wanna be clear two things. One, I think that she did a bad
Speaker 7:  job arguing in this case the trial. I think that Call of Duty head fake,
Speaker 7:  she just got lost in it. Two, the more I think about it, it's
Speaker 7:  more like, I don't care if Microsoft owns Activision.
Speaker 7:  Like
Speaker 10:  Oh, I do.
Speaker 7:  Why?
Speaker 10:  Because vertical as we saw with streaming vertical integration is bad.
Speaker 7:  But like the, the actual bad outcome of that, when Sony is dominant
Speaker 7:  and Apple is not gonna let anyone do cloud gaming anyways. Like,
Speaker 10:  Because Sony is dominant today and they have Call of Duty today.
Speaker 10:  Is there anything in that decision to stop Microsoft from
Speaker 10:  saying, okay, Diablo four no longer works on PS five?
Speaker 7:  Well, so now there's there's a lot of Phil Spencer running around saying
Speaker 7:  that would be bad. There's all of this. And then on top of it,
Speaker 7:  Microsoft is in third place. so like if the market's more competitive, is
Speaker 7:  that bad? Like it I
Speaker 10:  Mean that theoretically that's it. If at any point micro like this is all
Speaker 10:  dependent on Microsoft being like, yeah, we're just good guys, we're fine
Speaker 10:  with third place because we're keeping an open like we're altruism.
Speaker 7:  No, I don't think they're fine with third place. I'm saying if they're not,
Speaker 7:  if they flip out and they make Call of Duty exclusive and then
Speaker 7:  sales between the Xbox and PS five even
Speaker 7:  out and the market is more competitive. Is that a bad th like, I
Speaker 7:  don't know the answer to that question.
Speaker 10:  Is the market more competitive if one of the largest gaming
Speaker 10:  console makers in the world owns the majority of the studios? Cuz Activision
Speaker 10:  Blizzard is just one of many studios they've acquired. They've been
Speaker 10:  on a buying spree. Yeah. They own most of the big studios, like with the
Speaker 10:  exception of think of like ea they own just about everything Buddy. After
Speaker 10:  they acquire Activist and Blizzard.
Speaker 7:  But even in that case, Sony's still winning for
Speaker 10:  Now.
Speaker 7:  Well, well, but I'm sure but like, okay, so let's say it evens out and Microsoft
Speaker 7:  goes from third to first. That means the market's more competitive.
Speaker 7:  Like,
Speaker 10:  And then they go from third to first and then they say, okay, it's been
Speaker 10:  10 years. Call of Duty is now exclusive. Diablo five or six or
Speaker 10:  whatever is now exclusive. If you wanna play any of these games, you have
Speaker 10:  to play them on an Xbox. And so now Sony has nothing,
Speaker 10:  no leg to stand on cuz it's been 10 years, they bited their time and
Speaker 10:  they're having a great time. Like we saw this happen over and over with
Speaker 10:  streaming. Streaming was like, yeah, we're gonna acquire this stuff, we're
Speaker 10:  gonna do this vertical integration and then we're gonna pull the rug out
Speaker 10:  from under people. And because it's, it's financially
Speaker 10:  expedient for us. And I'm just like, I don't trust
Speaker 10:  companies to do what's best for the people. They do what's best for their
Speaker 10:  bottom line and their bottom line does not always mean what's
Speaker 10:  best for people. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I I don't think we're, I don't think we're agreeing. I'm just saying that
Speaker 7:  instinct to do what's best for your bottom line is usually tempered by competition
Speaker 7:  in the market. You only have two choices. Like either I can set prices
Speaker 7:  for every product in America, vote Patel, that'd be a great benevolent king.
Speaker 7:  Or you can have like actual market competition that people can vote with
Speaker 7:  their dollars. And right now you kind of don't. Right. And I think that's
Speaker 7:  the thing that I'm getting at is Microsoft is so far behind that if you want
Speaker 7:  a new console, you kind of end up buying a PS five, right? Like, because
Speaker 10:  They have exclusives, that's why it's doing better is because it's got all
Speaker 10:  the, it's got Naughty dog and now Microsoft owns everybody. That's not Naughty
Speaker 10:  dog, but
Speaker 7:  That's market competition. Like if Sony wait sits on its ass for
Speaker 7:  10 years Yeah. And then Call of Duty goes away and they're like, whoops,
Speaker 7:  Microsoft. Like that is their fault. Like it's so Sony's like
Speaker 7:  a also a multi-billion dollar self-interest company. And that's all I'm getting
Speaker 7:  at is like it, the the harms here are hard to see and they're definitely
Speaker 7:  more pronounced in cloud gaming and the FTC kind of blew it. But the bigger
Speaker 7:  projects, the FTC is to say like any antitrust enforcement is
Speaker 7:  good and the law should change. And I, I think everyone is kind of missing
Speaker 7:  that second turn that they were always walking into a
Speaker 7:  loss because the law does not support their Lena Khan's
Speaker 7:  theories for how this should work. And again, you can go listen to her
Speaker 7:  on this show before she worked at the FTC talking about her theories.
Speaker 7:  And it's basically like this kind of consolidation creates
Speaker 7:  a ton of bad outcomes for consumers that aren't just measured in raw prices.
Speaker 11:  So in that case it's, and and we really should take a break here, but in
Speaker 11:  that case, it sounds like what you're saying is it's not so much the loss
Speaker 11:  that's the problem, it's the fact that the FTC allowed itself to fall down
Speaker 11:  this distraction of Call of Duty being the problem that is
Speaker 11:  actually the thing that's gonna pull it away from getting to where it was
Speaker 11:  trying to go.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think that's right.
Speaker 11:  But at least we get Call of Duty. Call of Duty on the switch. Yeah, it's
Speaker 11:  animated. It's like Call of Duty, but you're Yoshi. It sounds awesome. I
Speaker 7:  Think a real problem for me is that I do not play Call of Duty. so like whatever,
Speaker 7:  you can have it Phil. If you're listening, I wanna run it on the homepage.
Speaker 7:  Okay, we'll, we'll, we'll sign the deal. 10 years of Call of Duty at The
Speaker 7:  Verge dot com. Love it. All right. We should take a break. We'll be right
Speaker 7:  back.
Speaker 13:  Hello, I'm Mr. Perel. I'm a psychotherapist and host of
Speaker 13:  the podcast. Where should we begin? Relationships, expectations
Speaker 13:  are at an all time high and yet the norms are
Speaker 13:  less and less clear. And we are literally making up the new norms
Speaker 13:  as we go. Whether it's your work, relationships,
Speaker 13:  friendships, or romantic relationships. I invite you
Speaker 13:  to enter into my office and listen in on my
Speaker 13:  sessions where I help people explore the challenges
Speaker 13:  and choices in their relationships. You will
Speaker 13:  listen intensely to them, but you will actually
Speaker 13:  see yourselves and in the process you become unstuck
Speaker 13:  and empowered in your own relationships.
Speaker 13:  Join me in my office every Monday morning for a new
Speaker 13:  episode, listen and follow. Where should we begin
Speaker 13:  on your favorite podcast app?
Speaker 14:  I'm Naim Razza, executive producer of the podcast on with Kara Swisher.
Speaker 14:  This week we're talking to c n n Anchor Jake Tapper about the future of
Speaker 14:  C Nnn Trump and News writ large. My favorite part
Speaker 14:  might have been this description by Jake of how leaders at the highest level
Speaker 14:  get in their own way.
Speaker 15:  How great man rise to the level where they removed from their circle. Anyone
Speaker 15:  who will tell them when they're making mistakes, I call it the Jar Jar Banks's
Speaker 15:  theory. Someday I'll write a business book about it. Explain me Jar Jar
Speaker 15:  B'S theory is George Lucas rises to a level where some nobody's around him
Speaker 15:  to say, please do not include that Jamaican frog in the prequels. That's
Speaker 15:  an awful idea. What are you doing? And you see it all over,
Speaker 15:  all over with leader, after leader, after leader who does not have
Speaker 15:  anyone around them to say no. And that is, I never want to be that
Speaker 15:  person because that is always how it ends.
Speaker 14:  No one wants to be that person. Jake Tapper for the full episode. Search
Speaker 14:  for On with Kara Swisher wherever you get your podcasts.
Speaker 7:  We're back. David is just waving his computer around in the studio.
Speaker 7:  What is happening there? Man,
Speaker 11:  The thing that happened about 20 minutes ago on this podcast is I spilled
Speaker 11:  one whole pomp La Moose LaCroix just all the way over my computer.
Speaker 7:  Turn it upside down.
Speaker 11:  I did for a while. It was the, the key is to just
Speaker 11:  make a tent and put it on the floor. Yeah. And then that makes everything
Speaker 11:  better.
Speaker 11:  It it, luckily Liam, our producer, brought me what I would say as several
Speaker 11:  rolls of paper towels that I have now used.
Speaker 7:  Put it in some rice. Liam, get a bag of rice.
Speaker 11:  A really big bag of rice. The most astounding part is, it seems fine.
Speaker 11:  I think the software updated at one point,
Speaker 7:  But,
Speaker 11:  But now I'm just, I'm, I'm back. If it suddenly like lights on fire while
Speaker 11:  we're sitting here, that's why And I will probably have to leave briefly,
Speaker 11:  but I'm, I'm somehow
Speaker 7:  It's gonna make for great tv.
Speaker 11:  Listen, did I almost burn down the building when I tried to poke a
Speaker 11:  battery for a video at the Wall Street Journal? Yes, I did. And this can
Speaker 11:  be, this can be round two.
Speaker 7:  Gonna make a gif a bit pran. I have a stat for you. Okay. Hit me with it.
Speaker 7:  The average blockbuster store had between eight
Speaker 7:  and 10,000 videos in it. Some of 'em had 7,000 videos,
Speaker 7:  Netflix, 3,600 movies. so like
Speaker 7:  in moving to the streaming area, the amount of choice on the, on the
Speaker 7:  platforms has dwindled shrink. Yep.
Speaker 11:  Which is the opposite of what people think. I bet if you gave those two
Speaker 11:  numbers to a person and was like, which is which I bet almost everyone would
Speaker 11:  say Netflix is the bigger number. Yep.
Speaker 10:  But then you asked them to go find a movie they remember from their childhood
Speaker 10:  on Netflix. Exactly. And they'll be like, like, oh, yep, this is garbage.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I'm just saying pump up the volume not available on any streaming service.
Speaker 7:  Let's make it happen. It was definitely in Blockbuster.
Speaker 11:  You had that ready to, you did not just look that up. Ready? I want everyone
Speaker 11:  to know Neli did not just Google to confirm that that is a fact he
Speaker 11:  knew before this podcast began.
Speaker 10:  I think he just knows it at all times. Like if it, if, if it does appear
Speaker 7:  All right, that's why sad for you. But to, to, to Alex's point, like you
Speaker 7:  move to the streaming world and your choice gets lessened. Like
Speaker 7:  that's, that's a real stat about Blockbuster George I think is fascinating.
Speaker 7:  All right, let's talk about a gadget. There's a bunch of gadgets. Talk about,
Speaker 7:  there's, there's a new foldable from honor. There's some iMac rumors. We,
Speaker 7:  I think we should start with a Nothing Phone two. Is it in parentheses? In
Speaker 7:  my head. It's in parentheses because whenever I get a new iPhone, it's always
Speaker 7:  like iPhone four. And that's how it shows up on all the Bluetooth, you know,
Speaker 7:  and this Is, the Nothing Phone two and
Speaker 11:  It, it is in parentheses. Our, our style guide says that it is not
Speaker 11:  in parentheses. And I love our style guide for that. But if you ask nothing,
Speaker 11:  it is in parentheses the thing
Speaker 7:  Is like a vibes phone. It's like the first True Vibes phone.
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 11:  I think that's exactly right. It's like, I don't know the, the Nothing Phone
Speaker 11:  one was like cool because it was new, right? And I, like, I root
Speaker 11:  for every company that wants to make phones because we need more good phones
Speaker 11:  in the world that are not made by Apple or Samsung. And like we've been
Speaker 11:  talking about, competition is a good thing. And if someone could figure
Speaker 11:  out how to sell phones that isn't Samsung or Apple, that would be terrific.
Speaker 11:  But it it, it was like, it was a new phone, right? Like it had some weird
Speaker 11:  performance stuff. The camera wasn't amazing. The battery life was kind
Speaker 11:  of, eh, like it felt like a first phone. And this one, Alison Johnson
Speaker 11:  reviewed it for us and basically came out of it saying like, look, it's
Speaker 11:  a very good phone. It has a bunch of big ideas that either
Speaker 11:  work for your brain or they don't. It's big on like, we want to give you
Speaker 11:  tools to help you use your phone a little bit less. And one of those tools
Speaker 11:  is making all the icons look the same. Which is weird. It's like, what if
Speaker 11:  it was harder to find the Instagram app? Like I'm not No, that's a good,
Speaker 11:  good thing. So that's the thing, right? Like how you respond to that
Speaker 11:  idea. It's
Speaker 10:  Good. It's aesthetically pleasing.
Speaker 11:  Oh, it's beautiful. The home screen of the Nothing Phone is one of the best
Speaker 11:  looking home screens I've ever seen. It's gorgeous. It has the, the glyph
Speaker 11:  thing on the back. So if you put it down on the table, face down, it has
Speaker 11:  these lights that show up that will do some new stuff. It has the little
Speaker 11:  charging indicator, so like the light at the bottom will fill up as it charges.
Speaker 11:  It has a new countdown thing that if you have a timer on, it'll actually
Speaker 11:  sort of decrease the light as the timer countdown. There are these nifty
Speaker 11:  things like do any of these add up to like a transformational idea about
Speaker 11:  smartphones? Like, no, but there's some cool ideas here. And I think that's
Speaker 11:  what you mean Nila by calling this a vibes phone, right? Yeah. Like it's,
Speaker 11:  if if the things about it make you feel something awesome, you're gonna
Speaker 11:  love this phone and be super happy because it does all the phone things
Speaker 11:  pretty well, unlike the phone one. But it's still like, is this
Speaker 11:  the future of smartphones? Like there's really nothing here that screams
Speaker 11:  Yes,
Speaker 7:  We've just come to a place with smartphones where that question is kind of
Speaker 7:  like saying like, is this the future of shoes? It's like, it's just like
Speaker 7:  doesn't, what are you talking about? Like, and it, because
Speaker 7:  of the platform split, you're kind of always like, will the Nothing
Speaker 7:  Phone two capture share from the iPhone? It's like that doesn't matter. Like
Speaker 7:  if you're in the Android ecosystem, you now get to pick from
Speaker 7:  like a bunch of different vibes, right? Yeah. You
Speaker 7:  can pick a Galaxy fold and like run Subway
Speaker 7:  servers next to TikTok, next to Discord and like just
Speaker 7:  fully live in that zone, which is crazy. Or you can
Speaker 7:  like get this phone, which is like very chill and has lights on the back.
Speaker 7:  I, I think it's interesting, a neat place for phones to be in, at least on
Speaker 7:  the Android side of the equation where you can, you can almost buy a mood
Speaker 7:  or buy a style and Yeah, and it, it's only because this one has a
Speaker 7:  reasonably good camera and like it does phone things. Well, whereas I think
Speaker 7:  on the, on the iPhone side it has, it's kind of like, boy that camera bump
Speaker 7:  got even bigger. you know? It's like, and that's fine, that's fine. But it's
Speaker 7:  just, at least on the Android side of the equation, you can, you can now
Speaker 7:  kind of pick a style, which is interesting and it hasn't always been the
Speaker 7:  case.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I so I just like a few hours ago sat in this studio
Speaker 11:  wearing this shirt and talked to Carl, pay the CEO of nothing
Speaker 11:  that's gonna be on next Wednesday show. But one of the things he
Speaker 11:  kept saying that I thought was really interesting is, is kind of to your
Speaker 11:  point Eli, that like we're sort of at a point now where like if you just
Speaker 11:  want a phone, this is especially true in the us. If you want a phone
Speaker 11:  and you have no follow up questions, the answer is an iPhone, right? It's
Speaker 11:  like it is, it is sort of, it is the phonet of phones at this point
Speaker 11:  and Samsung is like kind of there on the Android
Speaker 11:  side, but it has some weird bad ideas and some wacky ideas
Speaker 11:  and some good ideas. But Android is the place where there should
Speaker 11:  be lots of different ideas about what a smartphone can like be and do and
Speaker 11:  how it can work. And we're finally, it seems like sort of turning
Speaker 11:  into that era and you mentioned like the honor phone that the foldable thing
Speaker 11:  is starting to happen and the tech is getting better really fast. The flip
Speaker 11:  phones are starting to be competitive. If it's like there are finally a
Speaker 11:  bunch of different kinds of phones you can buy in the Android ecosystem.
Speaker 11:  My issue with the Nothing Phone two is it doesn't push on any of those
Speaker 11:  ideas far enough to really feel big.
Speaker 10:  Can anyone push on those ideas? Like one of the reasons Samsung and
Speaker 10:  Apple have become such so big is because they were the ones that had the
Speaker 10:  resource to do things like make the camera not garbage.
Speaker 10:  Right. And everybody, nobody else had the, like you need a lot of really
Speaker 10:  good engineers to do that and nobody else could afford that. so like, it
Speaker 10:  seems like most of the big kind of ways to make the phones interesting are
Speaker 10:  expensive and nothing is like, okay, well we're just gonna go for the interesting
Speaker 10:  cosmetic stuff because that's a ring light on the back of your phone. It
Speaker 10:  probably costs 'em five bucks to stick it in there.
Speaker 11:  Right? It's like a thing they can do instead of pouring 10 billion into
Speaker 11:  camera R and d. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 7:  But like all things, even camera r and d got
Speaker 7:  commoditized, right? You can, right. Like this phone I think is an example
Speaker 7:  of it per Alison's review. Like it's fine. It's fine. Yeah. In a way
Speaker 7:  that I think when we were sort of on the cusp of computational
Speaker 7:  photography, like you needed the money and now you're like,
Speaker 7:  or I can just buy it off the shelf because it's a commodity.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. I mean. Yeah. And that's even true. Like the, the Nothing Phone has
Speaker 11:  the Snapdragon eight plus gen one, which is technically a last
Speaker 11:  year chip, but it's a very good chip. It does all the things you would need
Speaker 11:  a smartphone chip to do. It's pretty efficient. It's pretty fast. Like that
Speaker 11:  stuff just is widely available now, to your point. Which is,
Speaker 11:  which is really cool. But the weird central tension of all of that is
Speaker 11:  that all this stuff is so commoditized, but there are so many people
Speaker 11:  in the market that it can still be hard to get in because even
Speaker 11:  though everyone is out here building better cameras than ever that you can
Speaker 11:  buy, there's so much more competition to buy those cameras that
Speaker 11:  small companies have a hard time getting to these new supposedly
Speaker 11:  commoditized things. Because like Foxconn is just tapped
Speaker 11:  making all the phones for all the other companies making phones. And so
Speaker 11:  we, it's just, it's a weird thing where it's like the, the stuff is all
Speaker 11:  there. It's more accessible to more people than ever. And yet it's still
Speaker 11:  kind of on the other side of the wall unless you're a really big company.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Which is I think how you end up with, we're still, we're still here
Speaker 7:  talking about Apple, Samsung and nothing like Yeah. you know what I mean
Speaker 7:  and like nothing is connected to a much like, they have the ability
Speaker 7:  to capture some of the resources from big company just cuz the way cuz Carl
Speaker 7:  Pay basically. Yeah. It's so cool. I mean like, it has l e d lights in the
Speaker 7:  back. I want it, can I
Speaker 11:  Have it? The aesthetic, like honestly the home screen is so, so, so good
Speaker 11:  looking. They're doing this monochrome thing with the like old timey
Speaker 11:  pixelated text. It just, it just looks so good and it
Speaker 11:  makes me so happy. And it's like the first Android phone where they're like,
Speaker 11:  what if we actually gave like one whole shit about what it looked like when
Speaker 11:  you turned it on And I. Don't feel like there's any other Android manufacturer
Speaker 11:  out there doing that. And it makes me happy that nothing is doing that.
Speaker 11:  Yeah.
Speaker 10:  You know what it kinda looks like, it kinda looks like the, the books Palma
Speaker 10:  that was also announced this week, the Cinch six inch Android
Speaker 10:  e Ink phone.
Speaker 7:  I knew it was coming. It's not even on the list. And I knew it was coming.
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 10:  I I I I was sneaking it in. I was, I was waiting for the right moment and,
Speaker 10:  and the Nothing Phone gave it to me. But yeah, this thing is, I think this
Speaker 10:  thing is gorgeous for the same reason that I want the other one is like
Speaker 10:  I, something about that just monochrome sleek design. I'm like, yeah, all
Speaker 10:  right. I don't need colors. I got a TV for colors.
Speaker 10:  That's fine. Shreds doesn't have colors. It's great.
Speaker 11:  I got a TV for colors is a, is a stance. I would really like you to keep
Speaker 11:  on this show for a very long time. I'm gonna
Speaker 10:  See how long I can make that
Speaker 7:  All the colors I need in life
Speaker 11:  Are satisfied by my television. Is, is a, is an Alex
Speaker 11:  Cranz belief that I feel like you should carry on for a long time. It's
Speaker 7:  True. My gadget that I was inevitably gonna sneak into this conversation
Speaker 7:  is that telly has started shipping the free tv. Yes,
Speaker 7:  it's real.
Speaker 11:  Did you guys think it was real?
Speaker 7:  I knew I mean it's like not a hard product to ship.
Speaker 11:  It's a tough,
Speaker 7:  It's tv. They ship it to you for free.
Speaker 7:  I mean they didn't even have to turn on Stripe. They were just like, here
Speaker 7:  you go.
Speaker 10:  How much are they spending on the TVs like, or on the shipping
Speaker 10:  of the TVs? Cuz anytime I had to review a tv, that was always an
Speaker 10:  affair. Oh yeah. An expensive one for whatever the company
Speaker 10:  shipping it to be was.
Speaker 7:  They had to capitulate. Did you read this? They had to capitulate cuz it,
Speaker 7:  you know, it doesn't have any streaming software built into it. It just has
Speaker 7:  right intrusive advertising software. So they're just like, screw it. Here's
Speaker 7:  a Google TV dongle. Like in the box. I mean everything about this
Speaker 7:  is great. I cannot wait for people to get it. I hope
Speaker 10:  It's just rattling around in there just like, it's not even its own package.
Speaker 10:  It's like taped on the side.
Speaker 7:  It's sad to me that the Internet's like tearing itself apart right now. Like
Speaker 7:  it, I'm very happy about it for some reason. But like that Reddit is in turmoil
Speaker 7:  and like no one Twitter and threads. Like, there's a version of the internet
Speaker 7:  where immediately disassembling this thing and figuring out how it worked
Speaker 7:  would've been all we all did together for a minute. you know? And like, I,
Speaker 7:  I just can't wait for people to get this thing.
Speaker 10:  If you get one, please email us. We wanna know everything. Oh yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. If you have a telly, I am not allowing one in my home. But if
Speaker 7:  you get one, you know, let me know. Let me know On, on the
Speaker 7:  side securely from an honest account about how you act.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. Call the hotline and tell us about your telly and we we can change
Speaker 11:  your voice and play it on the podcast if that's what you want. I am desperate
Speaker 11:  to know more about this thing. I think I continue to think it's
Speaker 11:  actually an extremely good idea. I think it's going to work. I think it's
Speaker 11:  going to be very successful. I also think it is hilarious
Speaker 11:  nonsense in the best possible way. Do
Speaker 10:  We know what panels they're using? No. Like where they're sourcing them.
Speaker 11:  Free television, Alex. It has all the colors I need. I need
Speaker 10:  To, I need to know Howing.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I mean the whole thing is very, very good. Other gadgets?
Speaker 7:  There's a rumor that Apple's gonna do a 32 inch iMac. Yes. I'll buy this
Speaker 7:  thing in a heartbeat. I'm so close to always buying a Mac mini. Like
Speaker 7:  every time there's one on sale and there's one on sale lately all the time.
Speaker 7:  Especially M one, which is all that I need because all I would, I run one
Speaker 7:  app to podcast.
Speaker 11:  I have one and it's wonderful.
Speaker 7:  I'm always so close to buying one, but I'm like, then I gotta buy a display
Speaker 7:  and then, you know, you end up in that display thing where like I'm gonna
Speaker 7:  buy a cheap one, but then I'm, I'm me And I can't buy a cheap one. And I
Speaker 7:  like crap. I'm not gonna buy a studio. Like you
Speaker 10:  Spend so much money, it's great. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Just
Speaker 10:  Monitors. That's the other place I get my color. Oh,
Speaker 7:  You're like, I very, this is you should start like a wellness trend. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  Just have color on your TVs and your mom. Anything bigger than 27 inches
Speaker 10:  can have color. You can have color on it. I love it. Anything smaller? No,
Speaker 10:  you should black and white iPad. Like
Speaker 7:  A chroma diet. Like that's like the TikTok trend. A chroma fest.
Speaker 10:  Chromo
Speaker 11:  Fast. Gwyneth Paltrow just trademarked that while you were talking.
Speaker 10:  No goop. Don't steal her idea.
Speaker 7:  Goop don't steal. I'm watching you Gwyneth.
Speaker 11:  The the 32 inch iMac I think is super exciting. I think it's, if we get
Speaker 11:  a 32 inch iMac before we get a 27 inch iMac, I'm going to be furious because
Speaker 11:  the 27 inch iMac is a perfect product and the fact that it doesn't exist
Speaker 11:  is so stupid and bad. And a 24 inch iMac is a
Speaker 11:  dumb idea. But a 27 inch iMac is an amazing idea. But I also think
Speaker 11:  there was this rumor, I don't know if we've heard about it since like January,
Speaker 11:  but there was this rumor at the beginning of the year that Apple is starting
Speaker 11:  to think about smart display stuff. And like you look at like standby and
Speaker 11:  the lock screen widgets and there's like this thing starting to happen where
Speaker 11:  Apple is like, what can your screens be when you're not using them?
Speaker 11:  And, I think the idea of like Apple
Speaker 11:  basically doing that with my computer monitor is very
Speaker 11:  exciting to me. Like make that the hub of all of
Speaker 11:  my stuff because it's a big screen that just sits on my desk and I'm near
Speaker 11:  it all the time. Like, I love that. I I assume this thing will cost
Speaker 11:  $67,000 And. I will not buy it. What if
Speaker 10:  It's the iMac pro? Remember? Oh my God. Like if we just to get that
Speaker 10:  again, that's the 32 inch. You want a big screen, it can't be
Speaker 10:  cheap.
Speaker 7:  That's very, see this is the problem. It's like I want to buy just an M one
Speaker 7:  Mac and like a beautiful display that's not expensive or isn't
Speaker 7:  a panel from 1985, which is the current studio display.
Speaker 11:  Can I interest you in the Specter 4K monitor that I bought that just randomly
Speaker 11:  turns off three times a day for no reason. I
Speaker 7:  See I can't live that life, man. I'm too old now.
Speaker 10:  I refuse.
Speaker 7:  I got gray hair in the beard. I only the finest of
Speaker 7:  displays
Speaker 7:  when I break my chromo fast stated,
Speaker 11:  I only chroma between noon and eight p
Speaker 7:  I do a 16 eight chromo fast.
Speaker 10:  HDR is a treat.
Speaker 7:  All right. All this color has exhausted me. I gotta take a chromo fast. We
Speaker 7:  went back. By the way, did you know when I was in high school I stage
Speaker 7:  managed over 70 productions of Joseph in the amazing Tech and Color
Speaker 7:  Dream Code.
Speaker 10:  What
Speaker 7:  A hundred percent true. We'll be right back. Everybody
Speaker 16:  Unexplainable has got a new two-part series. We're calling the black box.
Speaker 16:  It's all about the mysterious hole at the center of modern artificial intelligence.
Speaker 17:  I've built these models, I've studied these models, we just don't understand
Speaker 17:  what's going on here.
Speaker 16:  Even the experts don't really know how these systems work or what they can
Speaker 16:  do
Speaker 17:  If we open up achi PGE or a system like it. You just see
Speaker 17:  millions of numbers flipping around and we just have no
Speaker 17:  idea what any of it means.
Speaker 18:  We are rushing at breakneck speed towards
Speaker 18:  more and more advanced forms of ai.
Speaker 19:  You know, when I see something that is well beyond my understanding,
Speaker 19:  I'm scared. And that was something well beyond my understanding.
Speaker 16:  I'm know I'm hassenfeld, but this isn't my voice and it hasn't been the
Speaker 16:  whole time. It's just an AI made that sounds sort of like me. An
Speaker 16:  unexplainable new series starts July 12th, wherever you get your podcast.
Speaker 7:  All right, we're back.
Speaker 11:  I have so many questions, Mila? Yes. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  We we've got something to talk. No. Lightning round.
Speaker 7:  This is just, just gonna talk about Joseph. All right. I'm just gonna tell
Speaker 7:  this, this one, there's so many stories embedded in this. So I was like a,
Speaker 7:  like a theater tech nerd kid. Same. This should be very
Speaker 7:  obvious
Speaker 11:  To everyone. Super off-brand for Neli. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And so it's like summer in Wisconsin in the
Speaker 7:  nineties by theater nerd friends, And I all just like descend on the
Speaker 7:  Racine Theater Guild, which is mounting a production of Joseph Mason's. This
Speaker 7:  is true happening. I don't know how I don dunno how to describe all the
Speaker 7:  things that happened there, but rest assured there's a scene in this Andrew Lloyd
Speaker 7:  Webber musical where Josephs and brothers have to destroy a goat. Are you
Speaker 7:  aware of this? This is a real thing that happens in the show. Yes. And there
Speaker 7:  Scene Theater Guild is theater in the round so that there's VMs down
Speaker 7:  the side of the stage. So to get the goat on at the stage, you couldn't build
Speaker 7:  the normal things that you would build. So I took a remote controlled truck
Speaker 7:  and disassembled it and built a goat on top of it. And we had a
Speaker 7:  remote controlled goat that, this is like one of my like highlight of my
Speaker 7:  use that's
Speaker 11:  Legitimately like peak nili. Would
Speaker 10:  It like drive in?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it would like, would like speed up the, the side of the sage
Speaker 7:  and then they would like rip its legs off and like, you know, he would sing
Speaker 7:  about how sad he he was or whatever. And then we would drive the disembodied
Speaker 7:  goat And I thing one time in the minute of these many shows cuz we were like
Speaker 7:  teenagers. We were like, go out and party after every single one of these
Speaker 7:  things. Of course, course I forgot to plug the, you know, the old school
Speaker 7:  RC battery back in his charger. So the the pork goat come back
Speaker 7:  down off the stage. It just went and yeah, that
Speaker 7:  thing just got kicked. Just straight up dance kicked off the
Speaker 7:  stage.
Speaker 11:  This really feels like the, the, the adult version of Neli needs
Speaker 11:  to disassemble his Ford Raptor and turn it
Speaker 11:  into a robot coat.
Speaker 10:  That's your weekend plan.
Speaker 7:  I hadn't thought about that until crumba fast. I'm gonna cry.
Speaker 7:  All right. It's a lightning round. Yeah. Cranz you should
Speaker 7:  start cuz as we've been talking there has been massive news
Speaker 7:  in the world of entertainment.
Speaker 10:  Yes. As we were talking, SAG declared that starting Friday at
Speaker 10:  midnight, they're on strike. So they're officially, if you're listening
Speaker 10:  to this SAG is on strike. They're picketing. This is the first time
Speaker 10:  both SAG and the writer skill. The WGA we're both
Speaker 10:  on strike since 1960. Yeah. So it's,
Speaker 10:  it's been a while. Like W G A goes on strike at the drop of a hat. Love
Speaker 10:  him for it. But SAG usually doesn't.
Speaker 7:  We should note a series of escalating disclosures here.
Speaker 10:  I know. I wanted to see how far it could get before you interrupted. Well
Speaker 7:  I think once he get to WGA strikes the drop of hat, I think we have to disclose
Speaker 7:  our newsroom. Wonderful people unionized with wga.
Speaker 7:  They're great. We love them. Great. I'm a member. Yeah. Cranz in it.
Speaker 7:  Great. We're fine. But we should disclose that. Yes, we make
Speaker 7:  television shows with Netflix and HBO. I'm the executive producer of a Netflix
Speaker 7:  show and then Comcast, which Trans NBC is an investor in the company. All
Speaker 7:  of them are on the one side of the table or the other.
Speaker 10:  None of them are making anything as you're listening because all the
Speaker 10:  actors and the writers are on strike.
Speaker 11:  Well and this is also happening as there was this big deadline
Speaker 11:  story in which a bunch of unnamed studio executives basically
Speaker 11:  said, not even basically said in as many words, we are
Speaker 11:  just going to wait out the writers until they lose their homes and then
Speaker 11:  they're gonna have to come back to the table and we're gonna win
Speaker 10:  Is incredibly stupid.
Speaker 11:  And there was apparently some backroom, this is not like a dumb thing an
Speaker 11:  executive said off the top of their head, there was some like backroom strategizing
Speaker 11:  among studio executives apparently who decided to say all this
Speaker 11:  stuff to a reporter who was going to put
Speaker 11:  it into a story as if it was like a negotiating
Speaker 11:  move. And instead I think it has,
Speaker 11:  to the extent that you can move things even more against a bunch
Speaker 11:  of billionaires who are mad at writers for wanting to have homes,
Speaker 11:  it has shifted it even further against the billionaires who don't want writers
Speaker 11:  to have homes. It's really something.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, it backfired terrifically. There are rumors
Speaker 10:  that there's like recording of the video call of all the producers arguing
Speaker 10:  about the deadline story after it went up. Which if you have that hit me
Speaker 10:  up. Yeah, I would love to see it.
Speaker 11:  Cranz posted the phrase And I quote. This is my peepee tape. I must
Speaker 11:  see it.
Speaker 7:  It's of our chest, everyone.
Speaker 10:  And we're done.
Speaker 7:  I think that's the fastest segue from Andrew Lloyd Weber to Peepee tape
Speaker 7:  in media history. That's a PhD thesis for you
Speaker 11:  Breaking records here on the first
Speaker 7:  Call. Dr. Guinness.
Speaker 7:  I don't know if there's a Dr. Guinness, I dunno how any of that works.
Speaker 10:  But yeah, this, this thing is, is popping off. And it didn't help
Speaker 10:  that Bob Iger today said that the, the writers were hurting the
Speaker 10:  industry. I think that probably only added fuel to the fire.
Speaker 10:  Fran Drescher spoke. She's the president of sag The Nanny.
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 10:  Yeah, yeah. That's her. She's the president of sag. She had a very fiery
Speaker 10:  speech saying that basically they're, they're ruining lives. They're getting
Speaker 10:  rid of residuals. That's, that's the big thing here. That's like the big
Speaker 10:  fight with both the W G A and SAG is they want residuals. If they
Speaker 10:  make product, they wanna make money from that years down the line because
Speaker 10:  that's how most of them support themselves. Especially like people who maybe
Speaker 10:  have big careers in their thirties and then nothing in their forties because
Speaker 10:  people start hiring them for a wide variety of reasons, usually due to
Speaker 10:  ageism. So they really want these residuals and the companies are like,
Speaker 10:  well no, because we are due streaming now and we don't make enough money
Speaker 10:  to pay you residuals. But I Bob Iger make 27 million
Speaker 10:  a year And I think you guys need to get back to work just
Speaker 10:  a terrifically tone deaf move on his part. That was a
Speaker 10:  real
Speaker 7:  Bummer. So I encourage everyone to go watch this Agar, we Iger was on cnbc.
Speaker 7:  It's the Sun Valley con. It's an incredible setting to be like, this strike
Speaker 7:  is disturbing and it should stop. Right? He's at Sun Valley. It's because
Speaker 11:  This is where all the billionaires go to make mogul deals
Speaker 11:  where they buy each other's companies.
Speaker 7:  Right. Like the next turn he's gonna be like, and we're consolidating all
Speaker 7:  the studios even for like, who knows. Right. But the occasion of it
Speaker 7:  is that he just signed it new to your contract. Like he's never leaving Disney.
Speaker 7:  No. They're like the last thing that they're gonna do at Bob Iger is instead
Speaker 7:  of the animatronic Spider-Man, they're just gonna yeat him into the sun.
Speaker 7:  That exhibit and that's how he's gonna go out. Right? Like it's,
Speaker 7:  he's, he's just in the company. And he said two things are interesting. One,
Speaker 7:  he said the strike is disturbing. Like the actors and the writers are not
Speaker 7:  paying attention to the economic reality of this industry. Which is fascinating
Speaker 7:  and you can feel any way you want about that. Like on some level
Speaker 7:  there is an a grain of truth in there, which is these companies do not make
Speaker 7:  as much money selling Seinfeld
Speaker 7:  60 billion times over and over again in different territories around the
Speaker 7:  world. Like that's the economics of that are not happening. Should they still
Speaker 7:  make it more equitable? They should. And like somewhere in there is probably
Speaker 7:  the right icon, but nobody knows what it's, and then he said, oh I
Speaker 7:  might sell ESPN and abc like linear television is like on its
Speaker 7:  way out for us and we might have to do something else. And that is like,
Speaker 7:  that's the end of Disney as we know it. ESPN funded
Speaker 7:  everything like the cable fees for ESPN funded the
Speaker 7:  acquisition of Marvel and Lucas film and all this stuff. And that
Speaker 7:  engine is gone is basically what he's saying. And I think that is utterly
Speaker 7:  fascinating.
Speaker 11:  Well, and not only that, ESPN like was the
Speaker 11:  shining star of the cable business. Yep. For decades. Like
Speaker 11:  a big part of the reason that the cable business has started to go away
Speaker 11:  comes back to what people say about espn, which is what, I don't wanna pay
Speaker 11:  these massive carriage fees for sports because I don't watch sports and
Speaker 11:  my cable bill includes $7 a month for ESPN because ESPN has to
Speaker 11:  pay billions of dollars to the NBA in order to get games. So they're charging
Speaker 11:  the cable providers who are charging me And, I don't watch sports. And so
Speaker 11:  like that is the single cleanest example of why unbundling is useful.
Speaker 11:  And it has just, it, it's destroying ESPN as it happens.
Speaker 11:  Like ESPN spent so much money because it could pass those fees
Speaker 11:  on to so many people. And it is now, I think very much an
Speaker 11:  open question of does that business continue to exist?
Speaker 11:  If you have to just charge directly the people who watch the sports.
Speaker 10:  Where are the sports? Oh that's like, are they still on
Speaker 7:  Espn? Yeah, they're on Reddit.
Speaker 7:  Like it's just, it's so true for so many people
Speaker 7:  that's so complicated to watch sports that piring the streams are right.
Speaker 7:  It is easier.
Speaker 11:  Oh yeah. And sports is a disaster and this will take a long time to play
Speaker 11:  out because they sell these rights like a decade at a time. And so it's
Speaker 11:  gonna get real weird. But also the thing that happened is companies like
Speaker 11:  Disney signed decade long deals thinking that cable was gonna vary
Speaker 11:  slowly and carefully. Decline and streaming was gonna grow and the money
Speaker 11:  was gonna offset and everybody was gonna get rich. And now what it looks
Speaker 11:  like is all the numbers are down big really fast. And so
Speaker 11:  Iger is saying like, we need a strategic partner for
Speaker 11:  ESPN was so like Disney other than money, Disney doesn't need anything
Speaker 11:  in terms of like how to do content. And so the
Speaker 11:  fact that even Disney can't figure this out is fascinating. You also just
Speaker 11:  stole my lightning round thing, which is the ESPN thing, so that's fine.
Speaker 11:  So I I'm I'm done.
Speaker 7:  That's you. I've got another, I got that Google thing in you for your lightning
Speaker 7:  round.
Speaker 11:  No, I don't even want to, I'm just mad about ESPN now.
Speaker 7:  You're just mad about espn. David, there's a big future
Speaker 7:  of sports media piece to be written cuz it is just a total chaos zone
Speaker 7:  right now. Yeah. And even just stuff like Twitter and Instagram threats,
Speaker 7:  like that's where the center of gravity in sports has been for a while.
Speaker 7:  Right? It's like I, here, here's a story I want, I'm desperate
Speaker 7:  for this. Do you know when, if you're a sports fan, you see this happen
Speaker 7:  like every season, like high school students get recruited by a college and
Speaker 7:  they say they're gonna commit to some college, right? This like happens in
Speaker 7:  every sport and they all put up like Instagram templates
Speaker 7:  where they've written a bunch of copy and they have a bunch of photos. I
Speaker 7:  just wanna know who designs the templates, who's doing it, who's opening
Speaker 7:  Canva and listening to some 17 year old talk about how Jesus is in their
Speaker 7:  heart and they were always meant to play for asu. Like who is it?
Speaker 7:  Let me know. Like I just wanna talk to you.
Speaker 11:  I have all the jerseys done. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  It's, it's amazing, right? And it's like where that's a whole economy
Speaker 7:  of creators and creatives and agencies and da da da da that exist because
Speaker 7:  of Instagram, not because of espn. And so like you just see like even
Speaker 7:  that part of it is shifting. I I just think it's like there's a whole thing
Speaker 7:  to be written about how all of it is shifting, but then the actual part of
Speaker 7:  it where you like sit down and watch the games is So Hard that it's easier
Speaker 7:  to open Reddit and just find them.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. And it's gonna cascade through everything else because sports have
Speaker 11:  been the richest thing in TV on all sides for a really long time. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  we'll we'll talk about that more Neli, what's your lightning round
Speaker 7:  I mean? Everyone saw this coming in my way. It's Sarah Silverman is suing
Speaker 7:  OpenAI and Meta for copyright infringement.
Speaker 11:  Oh weird. Neli wants to talk about legal things. Whoa. What?
Speaker 7:  I love it. I think enough
Speaker 11:  It How does this relate to Joseph in the technical dream code would you
Speaker 11:  say?
Speaker 7:  Well, so Sarah Silverman has a code of many colors and those colors
Speaker 7:  are a number of legal theories about ai,
Speaker 7:  you know, a real problem being authorized. I, I'm tweeting at lawsuits again
Speaker 7:  and people are like, yeah, this is what we came here for. And it's like,
Speaker 7:  this is not the feedback loop America needs
Speaker 11:  More lawsuits.
Speaker 7:  Like no, no, no, no, no. This is what I was trying to get away from easy
Speaker 7:  dopamine hit by saying I hate this judge. Like stop it bad, but I'll do it
Speaker 7:  anyway cuz I'm addicted to it. Anyway, Sarah Sullivan, there's a law firm
Speaker 7:  basically that is organizing itself around suing the AI
Speaker 7:  companies. So they had a couple other offer, they had a couple other
Speaker 7:  children's book authors and now they filed the second one, Sarah Silverman,
Speaker 7:  some other authors. And they're basically saying, look, you can ask these
Speaker 7:  tools to summarize these books and then they do it at some
Speaker 7:  point. That means you have made a copy of this book
Speaker 7:  and that copy was unauthorized. And that's the whole argument.
Speaker 7:  It's a pretty good argument. Like as far as legal,
Speaker 7:  it's not like out on a ledge, right? It's saying, Hey, did you have permission
Speaker 7:  to make this copy of this book? Because usually you don't,
Speaker 11:  Isn't that like, basically exactly what worked for the record
Speaker 11:  companies against all the free pirating websites was it was like,
Speaker 11:  we, we can worry about all the big picture stuff, but you're taking our
Speaker 11:  thing and you're putting it over here and that's not allowed.
Speaker 7:  No, it was slightly different. Like Sarah Jong And I could probably do like
Speaker 7:  two hours of our chest on that. They, they had to invent all these theories
Speaker 7:  about how they were enabling users to do copier infringement. Oh, okay.
Speaker 7:  Right. so like Napster wasn't doing any infringement on its own. Like I was
Speaker 7:  sending a file from my computer to your computer and that was unauthorized.
Speaker 7:  But Napster created a business that let us do that. And they knew that what
Speaker 7:  they, and they, they just had to like invent a bunch of legal theories about
Speaker 7:  contributory copy or whatever. So
Speaker 11:  This one's even more straightforward than
Speaker 7:  That. This is just straight up like, did you make a copy of this book? Did
Speaker 7:  you have permission to make a copy of this book? If you did not have
Speaker 7:  permission, is it fair use for you to have made a copy of this book, ingest
Speaker 7:  it into your servers, and then deliver what is obviously a
Speaker 7:  derivative work of this book, which is a summary of the book. Wouldn't
Speaker 10:  That have ramifications for like everything computers
Speaker 7:  Do? Yes. Without question, like
Speaker 7:  all computers do is make copies, right? Like the fundamentally in copyright
Speaker 7:  law is like very backwards in this way because it, I, I think I've said this
Speaker 7:  many times in the show, it's hard for people in the computer era to wrap
Speaker 7:  their heads around the, the basic of copyright law, which is that
Speaker 7:  it regulates the act of making copies. So if I make a copy of something
Speaker 7:  that implicates copyright law, if you don't make a copy, then there's nothing
Speaker 7:  duh, whatever. Like, right? so like you reading the book, you have
Speaker 7:  not made a copy of the book, you reading a book perfectly
Speaker 7:  memorizing it and then writing it all down is an
Speaker 7:  unauthorized copy of the book. Can you do that? Most people cannot do that.
Speaker 7:  Computers can do that at rapid scale. so like, there's a, just a
Speaker 7:  decade of law, like Furious Law Google Books. Like
Speaker 7:  go look at that case like ferocious lawsuit about the existence of Google
Speaker 7:  Books. Amazon, do you remember they had a Kindle and the Kindle had
Speaker 7:  text to speech built into it. Ferocious lawsuit from the
Speaker 7:  author's Guild about whether that was copyright infringement. That makes
Speaker 7:  no sense to me. Like just right. Like it's text, it's on my computer, I can
Speaker 7:  hit a button, it should read it to me. They're like, no, that's a derivative
Speaker 7:  work. We make a lot of money doing audio books. You can't have it.
Speaker 7:  Like, you we're not letting you make that copy. And they, they won
Speaker 7:  essentially like they got a settlement on Amazon. so like there's just this
Speaker 7:  thing where it's like, it's the simplest thing and like the hardest
Speaker 7:  thing in any conversation is to keep people focused on the simplest thing,
Speaker 7:  which is did you make a copy of the book? Like everyone spins off into like
Speaker 7:  the philosophy of it. It's like, no, no, no. Did they make a copy of the
Speaker 7:  book? Did they have permission to make that copy of the book? The
Speaker 7:  answer is like, obviously no And I. I think this is the,
Speaker 7:  these lawsuits are just gonna escalate because copyright laws is like not
Speaker 7:  ready for this problem. Well that's exciting. Yeah, I'm thrilled.
Speaker 11:  And then just to bring this all the way back around, the FTC is also now
Speaker 11:  investigating OpenAI for the way that it has gotten
Speaker 11:  some of that data to train its models and it just
Speaker 11:  feels like, like Sam Altman was out here a while ago being like, please
Speaker 11:  regulate us. We love regulation. And like boy is he about to get what he
Speaker 11:  asked for.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But he's like, he's like regulates some like mythical problem. He's
Speaker 7:  like, make it illegal for the AI to launch nuclear weapons. And it's like
Speaker 7:  fine. Good. The part where it's like the AI is hoovered up all the
Speaker 7:  data in the world without permission and hasn't returned any of that
Speaker 7:  value to any of the people who made the, the starting works that
Speaker 7:  is a decade of litigation, like straight up a decade of lawsuits to come,
Speaker 7:  which is great cuz we have a website and we like writing about lawsuits and
Speaker 7:  the people on threads are like super into it when I tweet about the lawsuits.
Speaker 7:  So off we go.
Speaker 11:  I think what we're gonna do is we're gonna, we're gonna have one Vergecast
Speaker 11:  episode a year that's just 19 hours long and it's just all of
Speaker 11:  NE's thoughts about copyright loss.
Speaker 7:  It's like a honey pot Vergecast episode. Right?
Speaker 11:  And we never even publish it. It's just, it's just on the internet. It's
Speaker 11:  gonna be great.
Speaker 7:  I think people, the the, we've been threatening that one. I keep threatening
Speaker 7:  an hour long about metadata on decoder. It's all, it's all coming.
Speaker 7:  That's what we're here for. Absolutely. We're the people who did to do
Speaker 7:  holiday spectaculars,
Speaker 7:  very few other publications at our scale or sustained success. People are
Speaker 7:  like, why is the purchase of sustained success? I'm like, hour long htmi
Speaker 7:  podcasts. Yeah. Get
Speaker 11:  Into it. We were asked the other day if that's a thing we intend to keep
Speaker 11:  doing and we said, absolutely You are. Damn right. That is a thing
Speaker 7:  We intend to keep doing. Without question, I will die before I don't do a
Speaker 7:  holiday spectacularly. That's how much I love. All right. I don't, I
Speaker 7:  was gonna end on another Joseph and the amazing technical dream cut joke,
Speaker 7:  but I actually, I don't remember any of the words. David, you're a musical
Speaker 7:  theater nerd.
Speaker 11:  I have never seen Joseph been the tech, the amazing technic cla dream code.
Speaker 11:  I could sing you several songs from Jesus Christ Superstar, which feels
Speaker 11:  like it's in,
Speaker 7:  This is the most Andrew Lloyd Webber that has ever been on the show. I think
Speaker 7:  it's time to stop. It has been wonderful. I love you The Verge cast audience
Speaker 7:  as David said, Carl pay on the on the show next week, right?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, we got some fun stuff coming up next week. But yeah, that's gonna
Speaker 11:  be a good one. All
Speaker 7:  Right. That's it. I got a ticket. Chroma fast. That's The
Speaker 7:  Vergecast Rock and Roll.
Speaker 20:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 20:  us an email at Vergecast at The Verge dot com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 20:  production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network. The show is produced
Speaker 20:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. Our
Speaker 20:  editorial director is Brooke Minters. That's it. We'll see you next week.