# Transcript
ID: a42c47b7-04be-46cf-b3fb-21da357a2e6c
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: How YouTube and ESPN control the future of everything
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-1255351432633899988/-1321129859519075202/s93290-US-5028s-1692172100.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of non-exclusive distribution deals:
02:15 - The Verge’s David Pierce, Nilay Patel, and Richard Lawler discuss how the future of sports streaming will have a lot to say about the future of entertainment.
41:57 - David chats with director Alex Winter about his new documentary The YouTube Effect.
1:12:00 - Keep listening for this week’s hotline question about Windows 11.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (7 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of non-exclusive distribution
Speaker 2:  deals. I'm your friend David Pierce. It's about 5 25 in the
Speaker 2:  morning and I am out on a walk with my eight month old
Speaker 2:  son and my dog because somehow along the way they
Speaker 2:  conspired and colluded to decide that this is the time that we get up and
Speaker 2:  go for a walk. I would've picked a different time, but
Speaker 2:  unfortunately I didn't get a vote. So every morning we get up, Arthur
Speaker 2:  has a snack, and then naps in his stroller, Freeda sniffs every leaf within
Speaker 2:  eight miles of our house. And I listen to
Speaker 2:  podcasts, so if you make an incredibly long and kind of
Speaker 2:  wacky podcast, just know that I'm probably listening and
Speaker 2:  I love you for it. Anyway, speaking of wacky podcasts,
Speaker 2:  we have a great show for you today. We're gonna talk about sports, which
Speaker 2:  we don't do a ton of on this show, but I think at this moment in
Speaker 2:  time, if you want to understand what's going on in streaming and
Speaker 2:  maybe with the future of entertainment in general, one
Speaker 2:  good way to understand it is to look at a couple of things going on in sports.
Speaker 2:  So we're gonna dig in and see if we can figure out where all this is headed.
Speaker 2:  Then we're gonna talk to Alex Winter, who you might know as an actor from
Speaker 2:  the Bill and Ted movies, or as a director from things like the
Speaker 2:  Deep Web and the Panama Papers. He just directed a new documentary
Speaker 2:  called The YouTube Effect, all about basically what YouTube has done to the
Speaker 2:  world, good and bad, and he has some really interesting ideas and thoughts
Speaker 2:  about where it's all headed. So we're gonna talk to him about that too. All
Speaker 2:  that is coming up in just a sec, but I think, yeah, Arthur just fell
Speaker 2:  asleep in his stroller, so I have a little more walking to do, but I'll be
Speaker 2:  back in the studio in just a minute. This is The Vergecast. We'll see you
Speaker 2:  in a sec.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. I'm in the studio. I've had several gallons of
Speaker 2:  coffee, let's get to it. So You know how they say that porn
Speaker 2:  is the forefront of the internet. It's the place that a surprising amount
Speaker 2:  of technical innovation happens before it ever actually gets to the rest
Speaker 2:  of the web. That's also how I feel about sports and TV
Speaker 2:  sports are the most valuable, the most expensive, the most watched
Speaker 2:  thing on television. And so what happens in the sports media
Speaker 2:  landscape dictates a huge amount about how the whole
Speaker 2:  entertainment world actually works. And the sports watching world is
Speaker 2:  in an unusual amount of fluxx right now. There's a lot going
Speaker 2:  on here, and I promise you don't have to be a sports fan to understand all
Speaker 2:  the stuff we're about to get into or care about what happens to ESPN because
Speaker 2:  this stuff matters to everybody. That's kind of the whole point.
Speaker 2:  You could make the case that what happens to ESPN will affect
Speaker 2:  everything everyone watches for a long time to come.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, we should sort through this all. So I grabbed the Verges, Richard
Speaker 2:  Lawler and my co-host Neli Patel to talk all of this through. Oh, but
Speaker 2:  before I bring them in a quick thing, we recorded this a few days
Speaker 2:  ago, and just to prove how fast this is all moving, a few things
Speaker 2:  have already changed since we chatted. We talk a bit in the
Speaker 2:  conversation. You're gonna hear about ESPN being reluctant to get into
Speaker 2:  betting, which it has been for a long time. Well, ESPN is now into
Speaker 2:  betting. It signed a big deal with Pen Entertainment to launch a gambling
Speaker 2:  app called ESPN Bet that's gonna be interesting to watch in the coming
Speaker 2:  months. Disney also just released earnings, which were pretty mixed this
Speaker 2:  quarter. One big thing that happened was that Disney plus subscribers were
Speaker 2:  way down in India in large part because Disney lost the rights to Indian
Speaker 2:  Premier League. Cricket matches sports. I'm telling you, they dictate
Speaker 2:  everything. Like I said, this is all changing really fast and however it
Speaker 2:  shakes out, the future of sports will have a lot to say about the future
Speaker 2:  of entertainment. So let's just get into it. Richard Lawler. Hello.
Speaker 2:  Hey, NELI. Hello. Hey, there are these two things going
Speaker 2:  on. There's a big story about the future of ESPN and there's a big story
Speaker 2:  about the future of college football that the three of us have been following
Speaker 2:  a lot over the last few weeks. And I think it turns out that those two stories
Speaker 2:  between them kind of tell the whole story
Speaker 2:  of what's happening in the streaming business and kind of like in the
Speaker 2:  tech industry and in the whole world of entertainment right now.
Speaker 2:  So I wanna both like explain what's going on and see if we can figure out
Speaker 2:  what to make of it. Does that make sense? Does this sound good? Am I, am
Speaker 2:  I totally insane here? How do we feel?
Speaker 6:  I think your goal to try to explain what's going on in college football
Speaker 6:  is optimistic, doomed, perhaps
Speaker 6:  doomed, but confident. And I've always appreciated your confidence,
Speaker 6:  David.
Speaker 2:  Well, the good news is I have decided to foist this goal upon
Speaker 2:  Richard
Speaker 7:  And I have been waiting. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  You have been in a Slack thread. Just drop in tweets for like two weeks now.
Speaker 2:  So now, now is your moment. Explain to us what's happening in college football.
Speaker 7:  This is the only thing that I wanna talk about because I think what it
Speaker 7:  comes down to is that crypto killed the PAC
Speaker 7:  12. Oh God. And not in the way that you would've thought like a year
Speaker 7:  ago. Like I thought that crypto would kill
Speaker 7:  college football because we would have too many shady sponsors giving kids
Speaker 7:  money that they didn't know the source of. And like everybody went to jail.
Speaker 7:  And I was wrong. I, I will admit it, I was wrong about crypto.
Speaker 2:  You're not wrong yet. There's still time on that one
Speaker 7:  Could happen. But in case you don't remember, the economy went
Speaker 7:  kind of bad last year. A lot of big companies had to kind
Speaker 7:  of reevaluate their plans. Banks crashed. It was a whole thing.
Speaker 7:  We came through it. The bad news is not everyone is spending money like they
Speaker 7:  were kind of thinking that they would two years ago. And how does that connect
Speaker 7:  to college football? Because when you look at these conferences, they sign
Speaker 7:  their TV rights deals years in advance. And what happened to the PAC
Speaker 7:  12 specifically is that last year they were kind of in line to
Speaker 7:  You know renegotiate their TV broadcast deal, I think starting for like 2024
Speaker 7:  or 2025 and on. And what they expected,
Speaker 7:  they, they had some decent offers on the table from the various broadcast
Speaker 7:  networks you have like the CCBs to Fox, the the ESPNs and whatever bidding
Speaker 7:  against each other. But they didn't set up a deal at that time because
Speaker 7:  they were looking at it. They thought that maybe they could get a better
Speaker 7:  deal in a year from someone like Disney, from like Disney and
Speaker 7:  ESPN bidding against someone like Amazon. However, back to
Speaker 7:  that home economic upset thing that I talked about, and all
Speaker 7:  the big tech companies suddenly tightening their, their wallets and those
Speaker 7:  offers weren't there this year. And so when the various college presidents
Speaker 7:  met You know specifically for the PAC 12 to look at their deal, they got
Speaker 7:  an offer and the best offer they got apparently, according to reports from
Speaker 7:  You know C N B C Sports Business Journal and others was from Apple
Speaker 7:  tv. And Apple was trying to set up a deal sort of like it has for m l s
Speaker 7:  where they agreed to pay a certain amount and they agreed to pay more if
Speaker 7:  they get a certain number of subscribers to add this, this particular sports
Speaker 7:  package onto their Apple TV plus subscription, which is great, but
Speaker 7:  it's risky because if enough people don't add it, you don't get all the money.
Speaker 7:  And so the, the presidents were like, yeah, no, we need to be on linear TV
Speaker 7:  because that's what recruits have and recruits want to be on the networks
Speaker 7:  that their parents have so they can play there so that you can recruit kids
Speaker 7:  to be good so that people wanna watch your games. And it's a whole snowball
Speaker 7:  effect.
Speaker 6:  Can I just pause there that colleges believe
Speaker 6:  that teenagers across America have linear tv.
Speaker 7:  Their grandparents, their grandparents do their
Speaker 6:  Grandparents. All right, that's fine. I just wanna, I wanna circle that because
Speaker 6:  that's important.
Speaker 2:  There's a twist on that that I, I've been reading a bunch about that I was
Speaker 2:  gonna bring up later. But I, I think is, is really interesting and worth
Speaker 2:  mentioning, and this is another piece of like the technical chaos that we're
Speaker 2:  going through right now is these name, image and likeness rights. So
Speaker 2:  as of very recently, players can now benefit from their name,
Speaker 2:  image, and likeness. They can get sponsorship deals. And one of the things
Speaker 2:  that universities and like students are saying
Speaker 2:  is we want the best players and what the best players want is the best
Speaker 2:  distribution because if they are on the things they get watched the most,
Speaker 2:  they'll get more money in their n I L deals.
Speaker 2:  So the kids who want the most money will go to the schools that have the
Speaker 2:  most distribution, which will mean that they get more good kids to
Speaker 2:  come. And so it becomes this crazy spiraling thing where it's like, if we
Speaker 2:  just get a lot of TV ratings, we're gonna get good players because that's
Speaker 2:  how the players make more money. And it just like spins in this insane circle
Speaker 2:  where suddenly being on linear TV means more money for
Speaker 2:  college football players. And it just like, it just blows my mind in a whole
Speaker 2:  bunch of different directions as, as this is going. But so Richard back to
Speaker 2:  the story here. So basically what this has led to is like the entirety of
Speaker 2:  the college football universe has like exploded into a thousand pieces over
Speaker 2:  the last two weeks.
Speaker 7:  So the landscape of college football, of college sports has changed. We've
Speaker 7:  been, we've gotten used to the kind of the conference system. We know what
Speaker 7:  the big ones are and now there's a few less of those big ones.
Speaker 7:  The PAC 12 is basically gone, it's down to four teams after this year.
Speaker 7:  We'll see if it survives or, or if those teams stick around or, or bring
Speaker 7:  in some new teams. The A c C could be next. So you're gonna end up with kind
Speaker 7:  of the big 10, the big 12, the s e c. And
Speaker 6:  Can we, can we just back up for one second? I, I grew up, I went to a big
Speaker 6:  10 school that was the center of my universe for like a
Speaker 6:  minute. But I think most people don't understand that the conferences
Speaker 6:  and college sports are the, they're like
Speaker 6:  how the competition between the colleges is organized. So
Speaker 6:  there's a conference like the Big 10 and it goes and
Speaker 6:  negotiates her TV rights and money and it splits those up against all the
Speaker 6:  schools in the Big 10. And what's happening is the smaller conferences are
Speaker 6:  going away and the bigger conferences are getting bigger and there's fewer
Speaker 6:  of them so that they can go negotiate for more money
Speaker 6:  from a smaller pool. Is that what that's what it feels like is happening
Speaker 6:  to me.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And and that is exactly what's happening that you and especially because
Speaker 7:  they want more geographic reach, they want more alumni reach, they
Speaker 7:  want to be able to negotiate better deals and being able to have teams in,
Speaker 7:  for example, Los Angeles for the Big 10 now means that you can negotiate
Speaker 7:  for much more money because you have teams in New York and Los Angeles that
Speaker 7:  doesn't make sense in terms of competition or location or history or heritage
Speaker 7:  or anything like that. But it does make sense in terms of money. So, so that's
Speaker 7:  why, why they're doing that and also why they can't count because they haven't
Speaker 7:  had 10 teams for a long time. It's like a
Speaker 6:  Long time.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The Big 10 is gonna be 18 teams just to deal with that. But yeah,
Speaker 2:  I think to your point, this used to be and was for a long time like
Speaker 2:  a regional thing, right? Like I'm in Virginia, which is a c C country
Speaker 2:  and here it's a lot of schools from Virginia and North Carolina and South
Speaker 2:  Carolina and Georgia and all these teams are kind of centered around
Speaker 2:  each other. And the idea was like, those are the rivalries. So these teams
Speaker 2:  have been playing each other for decades. That's like all the teams that
Speaker 2:  your college hates are probably the ones in your conference. And now as
Speaker 2:  far as I can tell, the whole reason this is all getting blown up is
Speaker 2:  because these teams are chasing the big TV deals that
Speaker 2:  already exist that got made before the economy turned around.
Speaker 2:  Richard. Is it more complicated than that? It really feels like if
Speaker 2:  I'm, I'm looking around and I'm saying, oh, there's a whole lot of money
Speaker 2:  going to the big 10 every year. If I go to the Big 10, I will get a slice
Speaker 2:  of that. If I say in the PAC 12 where the deal is up next year,
Speaker 2:  that deal is probably going to be a lot smaller. Smaller because the business
Speaker 2:  looks a lot worse than it used to.
Speaker 7:  I think that's true, but I, I think it's a little more complicated than that.
Speaker 7:  And sometimes I'm not sure that I get it myself because I'm looking at the
Speaker 7:  way that these leagues look and I think they're still operating under the
Speaker 7:  idea that they're going to be able to get big deals from the tech companies
Speaker 7:  to, to compete with whoever's left in traditional tv and that that that money
Speaker 7:  is kind of still going to be there, but just by getting bigger, that is
Speaker 7:  the way that you get more money and by being part of the, the bigger whole
Speaker 7:  and that that really is kind of how it has always worked. That's why the
Speaker 7:  Big 10 has had schools. That's why Michigan and Ohio State deal with
Speaker 7:  Iowa and Minnesota.
Speaker 6:  It's rough.
Speaker 2:  Richard
Speaker 6:  Lives in Michigan. I think it's important for everyone on this podcast to
Speaker 6:  know that Richard lives in Michigan. If
Speaker 2:  You're from Iowa or Minnesota, just know that we, we love you too. We,
Speaker 7:  We love you. You just don't have that many people who watch tv.
Speaker 6:  But no, this, this gets to harder the matter actually that statement, not
Speaker 6:  a lot of people watch TV because when you, when you were regional, right?
Speaker 6:  You had regional sports networks, so you had no choice if you wanted tv
Speaker 6:  but to sign up for your local cable system or put up an antenna that was
Speaker 6:  the eighties, right? Those are your two choices. And that meant the cable
Speaker 6:  system could go and sign a deal with the Big 10, distribute
Speaker 6:  big 10 games. And it was unlikely that they needed a deal to
Speaker 6:  go distribute PAC 10 games because it was unlikely that people in the
Speaker 6:  Midwest wanted to watch college football from the west coast. And when they
Speaker 6:  did, it was national games and there was a lot of money involved for everybody.
Speaker 6:  Now that's broken, right? If you wanna watch anything, you have the
Speaker 6:  internet which destroys that regional scarcity, which has made
Speaker 6:  everything vastly cheaper. And those regional
Speaker 6:  cable companies are no longer the wealthy middlemen in
Speaker 6:  the middle of all of this. And in fact, their television
Speaker 6:  distribution business is headed inevitably to zero.
Speaker 6:  And particularly over the pandemic seems to have taken a lot of shocks, bringing
Speaker 6:  it closer to zero in a way that no one's even denying it anymore. Like maybe
Speaker 6:  five or 10 years ago people would deny cord cutting was a thing
Speaker 6:  and that's over. And so now what you have is, okay, maybe Apple or
Speaker 6:  Amazon has the pockets to support these kinds of TV deals.
Speaker 6:  Richard, your point is they don't seem that interested in it.
Speaker 7:  No. And and like Apple of course we know that Apple has basically infinite
Speaker 7:  money. They could spend whatever they want to get a PAC 12 deal. They just
Speaker 7:  don't want to and they don't have to, right? And so they're like, we'll,
Speaker 7:  we'll give you a deal where maybe if you attract enough viewers,
Speaker 6:  Apple famously did not buy Sunday ticket, which is actually
Speaker 6:  like a crown jewel sports streaming package. And they didn't
Speaker 6:  do it. They were right. They were in the, the driver's seat. They were gonna
Speaker 6:  take it and then they didn't go. Something happened between Apple and the
Speaker 6:  N F L and the N F L went with Google, which is a much
Speaker 6:  more normal cable deal on YouTube tv.
Speaker 2:  Well, and I think the example there is actually really instructive because
Speaker 2:  one of the things that it broke down. Do you remember that whole kerfuffle
Speaker 2:  about how the deal broke down over VR rights? Yeah. What, what
Speaker 2:  Apple wants from these companies is basically complete control, right? Like
Speaker 2:  what the m l s gave to Apple was everything for
Speaker 6:  $250 million
Speaker 2:  A year, which was like a multiple of what the, the MLS had gotten before.
Speaker 2:  So it was a huge number, but Apple now completely
Speaker 2:  controls the ML S'S broadcast. If you wanna watch the
Speaker 2:  ML s, you are going to subscribe to Apple. Which is why when Lion o
Speaker 2:  Messi the best soccer player in the world went to the M L s, apple reportedly
Speaker 2:  like gave, it gave messy a special deal to be part of that
Speaker 2:  because it was a win for the M L s, which is directly a big win for Apple.
Speaker 2:  That's where we get to the ESPN side of this, which I think is the other
Speaker 2:  half of what's happening right now, which is ESPN more than any other
Speaker 2:  single company is the one paying all of that money and, and has
Speaker 2:  essentially in a lot of ways run out or
Speaker 2:  is starting to run out because of what you were just talking about Eli. We
Speaker 2:  were At this point a few years ago where everybody was kind of looking at
Speaker 2:  the cable business going, eventually this will
Speaker 2:  die. A lot of people subscribe to cable. That number is slowly dwindling.
Speaker 2:  There's still a lot of money in it. Someday in the future we're gonna have
Speaker 2:  to worry about what that transition looks like. That day in the future came
Speaker 2:  much faster I think, than anybody expected. And we are like deep in the thick
Speaker 2:  of everyone is canceling cable right now.
Speaker 6:  You know what's, what's fascinating for me is all of that is based on
Speaker 6:  physical scarcity. I love ranting about competition on the show. I will,
Speaker 6:  I will try not to do it too much. But you were stuck with Time
Speaker 6:  Warner or Comcast or whoever because they had the actual wires in the ground
Speaker 6:  to your house. Yep. And that that meant that they could do whatever they
Speaker 6:  wanted. Disclosure Comcast and the investor in the last meeting,
Speaker 2:  Whatever. And we all like football. That's a disclosure I guess. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I have not watched football in years. It's too dangerous. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  'cause the lions do No, no it's
Speaker 7:  Not because the lions suck. That's not, that's not it. They've won a
Speaker 7:  playoff game in my lifetime.
Speaker 6:  They're never gonna win again. Jordan left forever. The end of the, the story
Speaker 6:  here is the scarcity went away and we have
Speaker 6:  basically rebuilt all these cable bundles, right? YouTube TV is a cable
Speaker 6:  bundle. Hulu with live TV is a cable bundle, whatever. But the
Speaker 6:  cable companies utterly failed to do that for their
Speaker 6:  customers. I think this market looks different. If there was a
Speaker 6:  great Xfinity app or there was a great Time Warner app and
Speaker 6:  that's where you were still getting your programming from and they were competing
Speaker 6:  and they just blew it and now there's YouTube tv and YouTube
Speaker 6:  TV is national. That might be the pot of money. It is
Speaker 6:  growing really fast. David's reported on that. And it just seems like
Speaker 6:  there's an opportunity here for like people like bundles
Speaker 6:  like it signing up for different streaming services sucks. And no one
Speaker 6:  has really seizes that moment except for YouTube tv, which is becoming more
Speaker 6:  and more just a very standard cable package.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I saw this amazing tweet the other day from, it was River
Speaker 2:  AAV Blues tweeted it. It said you have to subscribe to four different services
Speaker 2:  to watch the next five Yankees game Sunday Peacock
Speaker 2:  Monday off day Tuesday, the Yes Network, which is the regional Yankees network.
Speaker 2:  Wednesday, Amazon Prime Video. Thursday. Yes, Friday Apple TV
Speaker 2:  plus like that is deranged. Like that is not how any of this is
Speaker 2:  supposed to work. And there are a lot of people who continue
Speaker 2:  to subscribe to Cable just because it is the best, best place to get sports,
Speaker 2:  right? Like that is and has been for a long time. The best reason to have
Speaker 2:  cable is if you're a sports fan because it's gonna have the most stuff for
Speaker 2:  frankly the lowest price and it's all in one place. And that's very useful.
Speaker 2:  And that's what a lot of these other bundles like YouTube TV are building
Speaker 2:  towards, right? Like that's why YouTube spent all that money on Sunday ticket.
Speaker 2:  It's reportedly paying $2 billion a year. Yep. And it's because if you can
Speaker 2:  have a good sports package, people will pay a lot of money for it. But
Speaker 2:  ESPN, I think more than almost anybody is stuck in this really
Speaker 2:  complicated place where sports is still a really
Speaker 2:  good business on cable tv. ESPN is still wildly profitable. It has been funding
Speaker 2:  Disney for years and it still makes a lot of money. But that
Speaker 2:  number is going down, it's going down really fast. And
Speaker 2:  ESPN is now at a point where it has been pretty publicly saying that at some
Speaker 2:  point we're gonna go direct to consumer with flagship ESPN, right?
Speaker 2:  ESPN Plus exists, it's mostly like little sports and documentaries and people
Speaker 2:  don't really care. But like the thing will be when like all
Speaker 2:  of the big sports that ESPN pays billions of dollars for like the
Speaker 2:  college football stuff that we're talking about moves exclusively
Speaker 2:  to streaming. And if ESPN does that, they're walking away from this gigantic
Speaker 2:  pot of money that is the cable business. And if it does that, it will kill
Speaker 2:  the rest of the cable business because all the people who watch sports will
Speaker 2:  no longer wanna be there. So it stuck in this place and like Bob Iger did
Speaker 2:  this interview with C N B C where it, it sort of just sounds like they're
Speaker 2:  throwing up their hands at me like we have no idea what to do here.
Speaker 6:  That interview that Iger did with C N B C and people should go watch it,
Speaker 6:  it's recent. He talked about the strikes. Every answer was like a
Speaker 6:  nuclear bomb that went off.
Speaker 2:  It really
Speaker 6:  Was. I suspect we'll not be hearing from Bob Iger again for some time, but
Speaker 6:  his answer about ESPN was eventually we'll go direct to consumer. His answer
Speaker 6:  about whether Disney should sell parts of itself were yes, eventually
Speaker 6:  we should sell parts of our linear, other linear networks because we need
Speaker 6:  to become a new kind of company. And what has funded
Speaker 6:  all of Disney this whole time has been ESPN, Disney
Speaker 6:  owns Marvel, Disney owns Fox and the rest of the Marvel universe,
Speaker 6:  all the stuff that Disney bought, Lucasfilm, all of that was funded
Speaker 6:  by excess cash from ESPN. And in that number coming
Speaker 6:  down has made it so that boy Marvel needs to make a lot of money all
Speaker 6:  the time. And like you can see how they got to, we'll just flood
Speaker 6:  Disney Plus with Marvel stuff because they were watching the ESPN cable revenue
Speaker 6:  come down and they needed all those subscribers to go to Disney Plus
Speaker 2:  And they're just not going to, and even if they do, the finances don't seem
Speaker 2:  like they work. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And and I think that's one of the, the main things is that really none of
Speaker 7:  the math works on this for ESPN, for Disney, for streaming, for all of
Speaker 7:  it. And no one is quite sure what's going to happen in the future. And when
Speaker 7:  you look at ESPN, people have said, oh, I would love to have ESPN and be
Speaker 7:  able to get that without cable. In the future, if and when it happens, you
Speaker 7:  might be paying like 30, 40 bucks a month for e, for just ESPN.
Speaker 7:  So
Speaker 6:  Let me, here, I'll throw this out there. Lemme spin out a version of the
Speaker 6:  future for you Richard. You get to a place where it
Speaker 6:  is nonsensical for YouTube tv,
Speaker 6:  let's say to have lifestyle programming on it. Anything
Speaker 6:  that is not time sensitive, right? It is nonsensical
Speaker 6:  for M T V to exist showing episodes of ridiculousness all
Speaker 6:  day and all night.
Speaker 2:  You end up basically being like sports news in the Oscars, right?
Speaker 6:  It's just live stuff. Like basically YouTube TV is there for things that
Speaker 6:  are really important when they're live and that is basically like the news
Speaker 6:  networks, sports programming and award shows.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Remember those bad shows on sci-fi network? Yeah. You're not gonna have any
Speaker 7:  more of those. Well,
Speaker 6:  But you can see how that there's pressure on the system.
Speaker 6:  Like I think if you pulled any listen and said what, what would you pay for
Speaker 6:  on a cable system? It's like that list in some order of priority,
Speaker 6:  right? Things that are live, there's, we've lost another plane and
Speaker 6:  C N N is gonna go wall-to-wall coverage on planes and
Speaker 6:  submarines and you just need that thing. You just gotta flip it on. It's
Speaker 6:  there, it's the Super Bowl. You need to flip it on. It's there. Everything
Speaker 6:  else moves to constellation of streaming
Speaker 6:  services. Like the future of Max is a streaming service
Speaker 6:  appears to be reality tv, right? Like that's what David SLO
Speaker 6:  wants. You get to that split and maybe that's fine. It just seems
Speaker 6:  like no one can get out of their way or leave the money on the
Speaker 6:  table to get to that end point. Like I would happily pay for
Speaker 6:  a YouTube TV that was cheaper and totally focused on live coverage.
Speaker 6:  It's the other way around than it used to be, right? You would pay for ESPN
Speaker 6:  and you would get like C n N along for the ride and people would be like,
Speaker 6:  I don't wanna pay for all these channels I don't need, it's just the order
Speaker 6:  of what channels you don't need has radically changed because now
Speaker 6:  you're prioritizing live stuff.
Speaker 2:  I sort of buy that theory and I think to some extent that is kind of
Speaker 2:  the world Disney is hoping comes to fruition, right? That
Speaker 2:  eventually ESPN Plus can get all the best stuff that's
Speaker 2:  on ESPN. A, B, C is a thing that Disney owns and doesn't know what
Speaker 2:  to do with. It gets a lot of the news coverage and award shows. Like that's
Speaker 2:  kind of what Max is talking about doing with C n N. There's like, there's
Speaker 2:  a version in which you can put those things together in a way that kind of
Speaker 2:  makes sense. I just think you'd have to charge so much money for it
Speaker 2:  that you wouldn't get nearly the number of people you need to make that
Speaker 2:  financially work.
Speaker 7:  And that's really the issue is like how, how do you make, how do you make
Speaker 7:  it work? Because the magic of ESPN and it its magic money pile
Speaker 7:  was that it was getting like 10, $15 a month from every single
Speaker 7:  cable subscriber in the United States.
Speaker 2:  A hundred million people at one point. Whether they watched sports or not,
Speaker 2:  were just giving that to ESPN every month. Didn't
Speaker 7:  Matter. And it was that money was actually making everything else go.
Speaker 7:  And so when you suddenly take that out, when you don't have that ESPN
Speaker 7:  in kind of any package, if it's by itself, if it's in the Disney bundle
Speaker 7:  or wherever, it's not propping everything else up. So how much is there
Speaker 7:  to pay for? How much is there to pay for ESPN? How much is there to pay for
Speaker 7:  everything else? How does it get balanced out? You have Max, they've been
Speaker 7:  talking over the last few days really about their sports programming that
Speaker 7:  they hope to build up. You've had Netflix, they're going to broadcast this
Speaker 7:  weird, or at least they were before the strike planning to broadcast this
Speaker 7:  weird like, like celebrity sports tournament as maybe they get into
Speaker 7:  sports because there was a report they bid for F one, so they, they probably
Speaker 7:  bid for something else. Apple tv, we know that they're doing sports deals.
Speaker 7:  But do you do those as a part of your main package or as an add-on and
Speaker 7:  people don't get the add-ons like, like we already know that. So how much
Speaker 7:  money is there really?
Speaker 2:  Well and this, this is where we go back to the college football thing is
Speaker 2:  college football people don't want a Netflix deal. Like they would
Speaker 2:  take it as part of another bigger deal, but they don't want that deal because
Speaker 2:  they want to be on linear television. They want to be in the biggest places
Speaker 2:  that people are watching. And even if there was a quote that I think it was
Speaker 2:  the president of the University of Washington gave to ESPN right after all
Speaker 2:  the PAC 12 stuff broke down where he was basically like Apple TV doesn't
Speaker 2:  give us enough reach. They could give us all the money in the known universe,
Speaker 2:  right? They don't give us enough reach And, and this is like, this is sort
Speaker 2:  of the story of the whole business right now. I was listening to the podcast,
Speaker 2:  the Town which is Pucks, Matt, Melanie, it's a really great podcast about
Speaker 2:  all things like the entertainment business. And he was talking to Rich Greenfield
Speaker 2:  who's an a very smart analyst on this stuff. And Rich's big theory was
Speaker 2:  that what every other content maker should do is have the
Speaker 2:  first run of their shows on Netflix. Because Netflix has the
Speaker 2:  biggest distribution. And if you want your IP to work, if you want stuff
Speaker 2:  to merchandise like Disney because it needs people to care about
Speaker 2:  its characters and watch them and see them and go care about the rides and
Speaker 2:  buy their toys, should actually be putting its stuff on Netflix before it
Speaker 2:  puts it on Disney Plus. And that's never gonna happen. But I actually think
Speaker 2:  is an incredibly interesting point that
Speaker 6:  Is bonkers.
Speaker 2:  It will never happen for a million reasons. But in the sense that it's like
Speaker 2:  if what I want is for people to care about my shows, it actually makes a
Speaker 2:  lot of sense that you should put them in the place where most people will
Speaker 2:  see them. And so for the football and sports people in general who
Speaker 2:  hold all the cards in all of these negotiations because they are the live
Speaker 2:  thing that people care about, increasingly like the only one, they're just
Speaker 2:  gonna go where the biggest audience is. And this has been ESPN's problem.
Speaker 2:  If it cancels its cable network and just goes to streaming, it will stop
Speaker 2:  getting these deals. Even if it has all the money in the world, it will stop
Speaker 2:  getting these deals because it loses the size and scope of
Speaker 2:  what it can offer. And so like that's just another reason that it's like
Speaker 2:  what do you even do?
Speaker 6:  So there, there's another piece to this, which I think is important to note.
Speaker 6:  The big tech companies suck at broadcasting sports.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Watching a football game, being broadcast by Amazon is a
Speaker 6:  chore. Not only because for whatever reason
Speaker 6:  Karmically, they get the worst football games in like broadcast
Speaker 6:  history last season, some of the worst games ever played were on
Speaker 6:  Amazon. That's not Amazon's fault. I'm just saying that's karma. They're
Speaker 6:  also just not good at it yet. Right? The pageantry of a
Speaker 6:  major national broadcast football game is a
Speaker 6:  thing that helps those athletes get their endorsement deals.
Speaker 6:  That is the scaffolding for the big advertisers to come
Speaker 6:  in and put big fancy ads next to premium
Speaker 6:  programming. And you look at a baseball game on Apple, they've gotten a little
Speaker 6:  bit better but's, still a pretty low rent operation, for example. They're
Speaker 6:  not in four K yet. Just putting that out there, that's, it's amazing to me.
Speaker 6:  You look at Amazon, Amazon is ready to broadcast those games in four K. They
Speaker 6:  own an entire streaming service that can do it. They haven't done it yet.
Speaker 6:  Maybe they'll do it this season. And they're You know they're not paying
Speaker 6:  the money for the biggest name broadcasters like
Speaker 6:  the Troy Aikman's and Joe Bucks of the world are they're, they're
Speaker 6:  on ESPN, right? They're doing Monday Night football on ESPN because that
Speaker 6:  is the best distribution for them. I mean Al Michael's basically retired
Speaker 6:  to Amazon. It's like more or less, yeah, he seems very bored. It,
Speaker 6:  there's just a piece of that puzzle where there's a product to be made here.
Speaker 6:  There's a literal show to be put on. And the
Speaker 6:  athletes and the coaches and the owners of the teams and the people who run
Speaker 6:  the conferences, they wanna be part of the fanciest show. And the tech
Speaker 6:  companies bizarrely have, they paid a lot of money and they're kind of cheaping
Speaker 6:  out on the show part of it, which is fascinating to me. They don't know how
Speaker 6:  to
Speaker 7:  Build the stage. Yeah, like, like that. That's a skill and, and something
Speaker 7:  that is, has been built up in these networks over the years, they, they just
Speaker 7:  have the institutional knowledge and the people to build the stage. And I
Speaker 7:  think that what David mentioned about like reach, it's not just like what
Speaker 7:  you think of like, oh they have x number of viewers when they're talking
Speaker 7:  about reach, especially for these college presidents who run these high,
Speaker 7:  these high profile universities who want to be seen, who want to be on
Speaker 7:  on that top level. It's that ESPN and linear TV
Speaker 7:  is just on and it's everywhere. And when you're on there, it
Speaker 7:  means that everyone is going to see you every week and they're never going
Speaker 7:  to forget about your university, university of Western, blah blah
Speaker 7:  blah is very important. And you've heard of it and you've heard of it your
Speaker 7:  whole life and You know it because they had a good football team 15 years
Speaker 7:  ago and if they're on Apple tv, that doesn't happen. The, I think the other
Speaker 7:  part of what, what you mentioned when you talked about like Disney and going
Speaker 7:  on Netflix for the first season, like Formula One I think is a great example
Speaker 7:  of that because they had that drive to survive that boosted the profile of
Speaker 7:  the sport in the United States because so many people have Netflix and they
Speaker 7:  started watching this sport that they've never paid attention to because
Speaker 7:  it comes on at 3:00 AM And they were like, actually I love this and I need
Speaker 7:  to see more of it. And because they were on the biggest distribution platform,
Speaker 7:  they got a huge boost and you could see that happen. Well, but
Speaker 6:  That show is also really fascinating. So we should talk about Drive Thrive
Speaker 6:  for a minute. We should disclose that. There's another version of that show
Speaker 6:  about golf called Full Swing the Vox Media makes, which is great, you should
Speaker 6:  watch it. The Drive Survive is this fascinating phenomenon because it is
Speaker 6:  owned by one company, right? Liberty Media owns F one,
Speaker 6:  they own the whole league and they're the ones who told their
Speaker 6:  entire league, you are gonna participate in this show. And the only
Speaker 6:  teams in the first season that could say no were the winning teams, right?
Speaker 6:  Like Mercedes and Ferrari said no and everyone else sort of
Speaker 6:  participated. And then those teams saw how much
Speaker 6:  play the drivers were getting, the league was getting and they came around
Speaker 6:  in the second season and participated and now everybody has to participate.
Speaker 6:  And the show is like turning into like a meta show. Like everyone's constantly
Speaker 6:  talking about the show on the show, which is very funny. Yep. Yes. That did
Speaker 6:  boost the profile of the league. But it's fascinating because it, it happened
Speaker 6:  because it's owned by one company. They could just make the deal and
Speaker 6:  instruct all the participants like, you're doing this and
Speaker 6:  this is a strategy would open explicit strategy of boosting our
Speaker 6:  profile. We're gonna turn you into reality television.
Speaker 6:  And every episode is basically Top Gun, right? A bunch of rich people
Speaker 6:  run around, they're beautiful. And then there's a race. The stakes of the
Speaker 6:  race are falsely amplified, which is great. I love it. Everyone should watch
Speaker 6:  Drive, survive. You see Netflix doing this with other, other sports. They've
Speaker 6:  done it with tennis, they've done it with golf. Like I said, they try
Speaker 6:  to do it with N F L with this new show quarterback. But because the N F L
Speaker 6:  insisted on making the show themselves, it's not as good. Yeah, right. It's
Speaker 6:  like, it's like very interesting. That Alone is like the league is
Speaker 6:  so involved in it on that, on that front that N F L films made
Speaker 6:  quarterback that the show isn't as good. And I think there's just
Speaker 6:  something there about trying to replicate these models
Speaker 6:  where like eventually you have like generational copy
Speaker 6:  loss. Like you make a copy of a copy of a copy and you start with Drive to
Speaker 6:  Survive and you end with quarterback, you're like, we made too many copies.
Speaker 7:  You've, you've seen that with Drive to Survive the subsequent seasons, as
Speaker 7:  you mentioned, it's gotten very meta, like even when you're in the season
Speaker 7:  that people are like, oh man, this is going to be on drive to survive. And
Speaker 7:  what you end up with is when it actually comes out, it's completely disappointing
Speaker 7:  or not in there in the way that people were expecting it. And it's just,
Speaker 7:  you can't, you can't do it again. You can't go back to that first one. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I just think there's something fascinating about that cycle. 'cause drive
Speaker 6:  to Survive happens after the season and it, they
Speaker 6:  release it before the next season. It just creates a cast of
Speaker 6:  characters. It creates a set of things to follow in a way that I think
Speaker 6:  kind of segues into more conversation about ESPN. That's what ESPN
Speaker 6:  is every day, right? Every day ESPN is just, I
Speaker 6:  mean it is basically just a 24 hour podcast that is interrupted by broadcasts
Speaker 6:  of major sports.
Speaker 2:  But it is increasingly becoming not that right? Like ESPN has gone through
Speaker 2:  a bunch of layoffs over the last couple of years, including some of its really
Speaker 2:  high profile talent. And it seems like what ESPN has
Speaker 2:  decided is that we are a place that airs sports
Speaker 2:  and Stephen A. Smith, like they, they have a couple of really big name people
Speaker 2:  that they really care a lot about and everything else that isn't
Speaker 2:  live sports.
Speaker 7:  I think that the counterpoint to that is that they just signed Pat McAfee
Speaker 7:  and gave him all of the money that they took from laying off all of these
Speaker 7:  other
Speaker 6:  People.
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Right. They took an independent podcaster and they said, okay, you're the,
Speaker 6:  you're the new face of ESPN. And Pat took that deal that I
Speaker 6:  watch a show mostly. 'cause Aaron Rogers experience was as
Speaker 6:  David and Richard know, very traumatizing for me over these past few years.
Speaker 6:  But Pat took that deal, oh, he left his gaming company deal
Speaker 6:  and said, ESPN is like the natural fit for what I do. And I think that goes
Speaker 6:  back to the prestige, right? It's the, it's still the
Speaker 6:  top. And so you might take the discount on
Speaker 6:  attaching yourself to the brand that is at the top and it also has the
Speaker 6:  massive distribution. I, I think that question like what is ESPN going to
Speaker 6:  be is really stuck in that tension of, okay, there's gonna be
Speaker 6:  YouTube TV and this is where a bunch of sports need to happen, so we're gonna
Speaker 6:  collect the sports and resell them YouTube tv and that's gonna be the cable
Speaker 6:  deal of old, or this is a network full of
Speaker 6:  personalities talking about sports and it's comfort
Speaker 6:  viewing for you to just have on in the background all the time. I don't think
Speaker 6:  they've made that decision.
Speaker 7:  One answer that was supposed to be there for like what ESPN and some of these
Speaker 7:  other sports networks is supposed to be is something that you mentioned there,
Speaker 7:  gambling and gaming that was supposed to help fill the hole
Speaker 7:  and was expected to Pat McAfee, as you said, I think had his show with FanDuel
Speaker 7:  or, or one of these other gaming companies. And ESPN had
Speaker 7:  been talking about betting, we wrote about it last year that gambling was
Speaker 7:  going to be a huge business for these TV networks, for fubu,
Speaker 7:  for everyone else. And it just has not worked out that way. Bob Iger
Speaker 7:  has not talked about gambling except for like one small quote in a time interview.
Speaker 7:  Ever since he came back, FUBU TV launched GA gambling kind of
Speaker 7:  features on their, their network, on their streaming network. They're gone,
Speaker 7:  they're out of that business. Fox shut down their Fox Bet app.
Speaker 7:  The gambling companies are not making as much money as people expected. Some
Speaker 7:  of them are losing money because it's so expensive to acquire customers.
Speaker 7:  And so that's another element of why everything has suddenly changed and
Speaker 7:  flipped up so quickly because that was supposed to help kind of bridge that
Speaker 7:  linear TV to streaming gap and it just didn't happen. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It turns out people want to gamble in casinos not on ESPN dot
Speaker 6:  com
Speaker 2:  And that it's more fun to gamble when you're getting stimulus checks than
Speaker 2:  it is when the economy is bad. Also,
Speaker 7:  Nerds aren't as good at running casinos as they think it's really hard to
Speaker 7:  make money. They found out. Yeah. Alright.
Speaker 2:  But we, we, we should wrap this up, but I I am curious, like if we cast this
Speaker 2:  out a couple of years, right? I think we're, we're in this interesting place
Speaker 2:  where like the N F L did this big deal a couple of years ago for like $110
Speaker 2:  billion. All these college sports have giant deals. There's,
Speaker 2:  they're forever coming up. The next big one is the N B A, which a lot of
Speaker 2:  people think is gonna sign a gigantic deal that's gonna change the way the
Speaker 2:  N B A works. But also ESPN is competing with like the
Speaker 2:  Warner Brothers discoveries of the world and some of these tech companies
Speaker 2:  to get it. Like if we fast forward a couple of years, let's just talk about
Speaker 2:  ESPN specifically. Richard give me like 20,
Speaker 2:  25 predictions for what ESPN looks like.
Speaker 7:  Frankly, I'm a bit worried. The N B A thing is a a great point because it's
Speaker 7:  something I've been thinking about. I, I watched the N B A I love the N B
Speaker 7:  A I would love N B A tv. I love the transactions, I love the games, all of
Speaker 7:  it. And they are expecting a huge broadcast deal. You
Speaker 7:  know, as you said, you have Disney still, you have Warner, you have all the,
Speaker 7:  all the tech companies, but I don't know who is going to pay that. I don't
Speaker 7:  know if they're going to have to expand their international deals or what
Speaker 7:  they're going to have to do to find this money so that they can pay all,
Speaker 7:  all of the players in Boston who maybe made the, the all N B A team once
Speaker 7:  $300 million or something like that. But that's where we are. And I just,
Speaker 7:  I don't know if we're going to have the same sports landscape that
Speaker 7:  we had, the the kind of thing that that we grew up with. The place where
Speaker 7:  I saw that Barry Sanders was retiring and it still traumatizes me to this
Speaker 7:  day. It just, I, I don't know. I'll probably hear about it on a podcast
Speaker 7:  and that that's going, that's going to be it. It's just podcasts and streaming.
Speaker 7:  That's my prediction.
Speaker 2:  Neil, what about you?
Speaker 6:  I think I agree with that. I think the idea that sports is the last thing,
Speaker 6:  driving the monoculture is gonna get pulled
Speaker 6:  into a smaller handful of leagues. Like Apple really wants m
Speaker 6:  l s to happen in the United States. Yeah. And signing messy is a great deal
Speaker 6:  and I've now seen a bunch of messy highlights on my TikTok
Speaker 6:  feed. I haven't signed up for Apple TV to watch the M l s. It's just like,
Speaker 6:  that hasn't converted me yet, but they've instituted it into the culture
Speaker 6:  in a way that's interesting now, but it's still the big moments, right?
Speaker 6:  Like the N F L still dominates American sports and that
Speaker 6:  is the thing that I think will continue to just drive a bunch of stuff as
Speaker 6:  people wanting N F L style deals. And I just dunno if they're there.
Speaker 6:  I I think the audience has fractured enough that that bet
Speaker 6:  that everyone will pay for ESPN and that will spend money and out
Speaker 6:  into all the leagues that enable lots of things to happen that's
Speaker 6:  gone, right? And more people are gonna spend more money on watching the
Speaker 6:  Witcher on Netflix or whatever, like the, the fandoms are gonna, are gonna
Speaker 6:  fracture and be in more competition with more kinds of things in a way that
Speaker 6:  I think is probably exciting over the long run just because I think
Speaker 6:  we'll get more kinds of new upstart
Speaker 6:  sports emerging or more opportunities like the
Speaker 6:  emergence of F one has been great for racing fans.
Speaker 6:  Like they ran a NASCAR race in Chicago because they were like, we need to
Speaker 6:  do some exciting stuff to capture the attention of a new class of race
Speaker 6:  fans. And that was the coolest race I've ever seen, right? It was, and
Speaker 6:  I was in Chicago that weekend, so it was very loud. That's cool, right? Like
Speaker 6:  a little kick in the pants to all these leagues, to not just milk money out
Speaker 6:  of big fat broadcast deals is great. But I think that moment
Speaker 6:  where all of my friends in school were always watching
Speaker 6:  ESPN and kind of always talking about the same things
Speaker 6:  that's gone. That's, that's gotta be gone.
Speaker 2:  I'm with you. I think the thing that is remarkable about
Speaker 2:  ESPN is that it continues to be as close to like a one-stop sports shop as
Speaker 2:  kind of anything else. And that's just, I I agree. I think that's gonna die.
Speaker 2:  Like I don't see the leagues making less money, at least
Speaker 2:  not in the relative, immediate future. They're just gonna keep making more
Speaker 2:  money and the deals are gonna keep going up. And so what's gonna happen,
Speaker 2:  I was reading a bunch about all the different deals that have been happening
Speaker 2:  and there was this big big 10 deal to go back to college football that
Speaker 2:  happened a couple of years ago. It was a seven and a half billion dollars
Speaker 2:  deal for seven years and it happened across three different
Speaker 2:  networks because basically no one network could afford this whole deal. And
Speaker 2:  so now if you wanna watch Big 10 football, you're gonna have to like
Speaker 2:  do a puzzle every Saturday morning to figure out what channel your game is
Speaker 2:  gonna be on. You can't just like know where your sports are. And I
Speaker 2:  think that's where we're headed is like we're gonna get more sports, more
Speaker 2:  places, but it is gonna be like vastly more distributed and going
Speaker 2:  forward, if you wanna watch the N F L, you're gonna need like 11 different
Speaker 2:  subscriptions because no one company ESPN or otherwise is gonna be
Speaker 2:  able to afford it. My my hottest take at the end of this is
Speaker 2:  that I think YouTube stands to be the biggest winner of all of this because
Speaker 2:  I think YouTube TV is like going to keep looking like a really compelling
Speaker 2:  sports bundle to a lot of people. But also the thing that YouTube does where
Speaker 2:  you can subscribe to other streaming services through YouTube
Speaker 2:  is going to be really powerful. So it's like, okay, I might have to
Speaker 2:  get Paramount Plus and Peacock and
Speaker 2:  Netflix and N F L plus or whatever the
Speaker 2:  hell all of that. I might have to get to watch sports, but YouTube wants
Speaker 2:  to be this sort of interface through which I can do that. So it's gonna be
Speaker 2:  expensive and annoying, but I will at least have a single location for
Speaker 2:  all of it. And I think that is gonna end up being the biggest fight is like
Speaker 2:  the collector on top of the subscriptions. And I think over the course of
Speaker 2:  the next like decade, YouTube looks pretty good there. Amazon's also gonna
Speaker 2:  try pretty hard to win that fight, but I I I would, I would bet on YouTube
Speaker 2:  more than anybody else in this space.
Speaker 6:  Expensive and annoying. Welcome to the future of tv. Yeah, right. It's, it's
Speaker 6:  very obvious like we're just headed back to cable companies and it, it
Speaker 6:  is I think important to note that none of the existing cable
Speaker 6:  companies built any of this stuff that is just recapitulating the
Speaker 6:  bundles. They were always worried about losing. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  No, I think, I think it's exactly right and it's, it's a shame because I
Speaker 2:  think as a, as a like fan and viewer, and this is true of the whole
Speaker 2:  streaming industry right now, it's like it's all gonna get worse before it
Speaker 2:  gets better. Yeah. It's, it's just, it just is where it's, there's too much
Speaker 2:  money and too much stuff and none of it makes any sense anymore.
Speaker 6:  And that's why I think you should subscribe to Alex Kranz, this Plex
Speaker 6:  server. Just put it out
Speaker 2:  There. All the good stuff. True cable bundle. Alright,
Speaker 2:  well we will come back, I'm sure during football season and be sad about
Speaker 2:  why we can't watch any of the games, but thank you both. We need to take
Speaker 2:  a break and then we're gonna come back and talk to Alex Winter, the director
Speaker 2:  of the new documentary, the YouTube Effect. See you a
Speaker 2:  sec.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. So there's this new documentary out called the YouTube
Speaker 2:  Effect that I found totally fascinating.
Speaker 8:  How did it go?
Speaker 9:  I feel
Speaker 10:  I'm Brookes and I'm an internet celebrity. I am.
Speaker 8:  Hi, how's it going everyone? Welcome back to my channel.
Speaker 2:  If you followed YouTube over the years, or even listened to this show, as
Speaker 2:  we've talked about YouTube over the years, there's not a ton about the
Speaker 2:  history of the doc shows that will surprise you, but it's still a really
Speaker 2:  good look at how YouTube became YouTube and really what YouTube has
Speaker 2:  done to the world, both good and bad. I'd liked the YouTube Effect
Speaker 2:  because it's not one of those like loud screeds against the
Speaker 2:  internet or a rosy story about disruptors changing
Speaker 2:  everything. It's both those things and it's a bunch of other things. And
Speaker 2:  it made me think a lot about what actually makes YouTube
Speaker 2:  unique on the web. There's something different about it and I've
Speaker 2:  always had trouble putting my finger on what that thing is and the doc did
Speaker 2:  a pretty good job of trying to figure it out. So I called up Alex Winter,
Speaker 2:  the director of the documentary to talk about it,
Speaker 11:  The sort of monetization of propaganda and misinformation and
Speaker 11:  disinformation is really what the film is about at his heart. You
Speaker 2:  Might recognize Alex from the Bill and Ted movies, he plays Bill
Speaker 2:  and a lot of other shows and movies he's done over the years. More
Speaker 2:  recently he's also directed a number of documentaries about things like the
Speaker 2:  Silk Road and the Panama Papers. He's just a guy who knows a thing
Speaker 2:  or two about how video works and why it's effective from a bunch
Speaker 2:  of different angles. So as soon as we got on the line, that's just what we
Speaker 2:  started talking about. One of the things that really jumped out to me was
Speaker 2:  there are a couple of little spots in the movie where you talk
Speaker 2:  about video as a medium and specifically sort of YouTube as
Speaker 2:  a medium. And I think one of the things we debate a lot internally at The
Speaker 2:  Verge is a this question of like, is this a
Speaker 2:  platform problem or a society problem? Right? And I think I, I'm pretty resolute
Speaker 2:  on the answer is both, but platforms play a real role and we, we can sort
Speaker 2:  of litigate that as much as you want, but I think think there's,
Speaker 11:  There's just inarguable. Yeah, I mean that's come on, that's inarguable
Speaker 11:  unless you're bananas, right? Yeah,
Speaker 2:  But I, I think the, the really interesting question to me is kind
Speaker 2:  of what is special about YouTube as a place, right? Because if you wanna
Speaker 2:  talk about algorithms on Facebook and Twitter and TikTok and
Speaker 2:  elsewhere, I think this idea of algorithmic recommendations is really interesting.
Speaker 2:  But there's something different about like the style and structure of
Speaker 2:  a YouTube video even that makes it Yes. Different. Can you explain
Speaker 2:  how you think about that?
Speaker 11:  Yes. In fact, I would say that I had an inkling about this going into the
Speaker 11:  film and obviously being able to immerse myself in it and go meet everyone
Speaker 11:  who was the smartest people in the world about these issues, which is what
Speaker 11:  I always go seek out, did give me some concrete answers
Speaker 11:  in this area that were very illuminating. And some of them
Speaker 11:  are common sense and some of them aren't. I went into the film feeling,
Speaker 11:  feeling exhausted by hearing about the algorithm and I kept, I was
Speaker 11:  thinking You know, I know I know enough about technology and the way
Speaker 11:  technology is spoken about to, to be, to be skeptical
Speaker 11:  of so much weight being put on anything that
Speaker 11:  fuzzy.
Speaker 2:  Everybody talks about the algorithm, like it's like the villain in the story
Speaker 2:  and it's like, that's
Speaker 11:  Actually not, yeah. And, and You know to me, you could be very cruel and
Speaker 11:  like stop anyone mid-sentence and say, can you just stop and tell me what
Speaker 11:  you think an algorithm is? And they would, they would spout utter nonsense,
Speaker 11:  right? So You know, most people don't know what an algorithm is at all,
Speaker 11:  who are even using this term all the time. They don't even know what it
Speaker 11:  is. They don't even know how it works. Most people don't even know that
Speaker 11:  the recommended algorithm in YouTube has largely been remedied
Speaker 11:  and has been not doing what it used to do for a very long time.
Speaker 11:  And so I started to to examine what is it that to
Speaker 11:  to exactly to your point, because YouTube has more views than any
Speaker 11:  other platform that we debate, it gets a lot less attention. And
Speaker 11:  I think largely 'cause it's overwhelming to people sometimes some of it's
Speaker 11:  lobbying power, like they, they spend a lot of money to get people to look
Speaker 11:  elsewhere, but we spend a lot more time looking at meta and a lot more time
Speaker 11:  looking at what used to be Twitter and, and TikTok and other platforms.
Speaker 11:  But you're talking about 4.6 billion views a day on YouTube
Speaker 11:  You know number two most viewed website after Google being number one, both
Speaker 11:  owned by the same company. So that's immediately
Speaker 11:  what makes it special is scale, right? As you guys well
Speaker 11:  know, scale is everything on the internet and
Speaker 11:  YouTube has far more scale than any of these other platforms in terms of,
Speaker 11:  of interactivity. And then you get to the video component and how the
Speaker 11:  video component works specifically. That's different than any other platform
Speaker 11:  in terms of how long these videos are,
Speaker 11:  how promoted and viral, a very select group
Speaker 11:  of influencers are on all sides of, of aisles and, and thought,
Speaker 11:  which is one of the things about YouTube I love, right? You can have Stephen
Speaker 11:  Crowder over here and Natalie Wynn and Contra Points over here and they're
Speaker 11:  both doing great and one of them is You know trying to promote
Speaker 11:  Civil War and the other one's kind of trying to stop Civil War, right? But,
Speaker 11:  but they're both getting, getting a lot of traction. They both have
Speaker 11:  the parasocial connection of, golly gee whizz, I'm your
Speaker 11:  buddy hanging out in my, in my bedroom talking into my webcam.
Speaker 11:  You feel You know me, but you don't at all. Hugely powerful
Speaker 11:  component. So I think for me it's the trifecta of
Speaker 11:  massive scale parasocial connection of
Speaker 11:  these influencers and the power of that monetized for
Speaker 11:  ad dollars, right? So it's an ad-based model, business
Speaker 11:  model that is gonna push You know, I wouldn't say without an algorithm's
Speaker 11:  help. 'cause I think that's going overboard. 'cause algorithms obviously
Speaker 11:  do things, but it's really not a technological issue.
Speaker 11:  It's a, it's a business model issue. You could change algorithms and
Speaker 11:  you would still have these influencers gaining enormous traction
Speaker 11:  given the way salacious content catches fire going back to
Speaker 11:  yellow journalism You know in the 1890s. And then you attach the
Speaker 11:  monetization to that and then you attach like whoever's funding
Speaker 11:  those influencers and giving them the power to be online
Speaker 11:  all the time in a powerful way and message correctly. Natalie
Speaker 11:  really is like a, a You know, a one woman band. People like Crowder
Speaker 11:  and Shapiro, I mean those are You know huge entities with a lot of money
Speaker 11:  behind them. So I think it's that trifecta and I think that makes YouTube
Speaker 11:  special in many good ways. I think that the way
Speaker 11:  they've, they've legitimately constructed a business model that
Speaker 11:  allows creators to actually earn a living, going back to SMASH and some
Speaker 11:  of the earliest players on the platform, I think has changed the world in
Speaker 11:  many ways for the better. I think it has democratized culture.
Speaker 11:  I think it has opened up people's ability to have a
Speaker 11:  voice, You know L G B T Q people in, in marginalized communities, people
Speaker 11:  in small foreign countries who would never get You know on any broad
Speaker 11:  based entertainment platform. And I think a lot of that stuff is good. I
Speaker 11:  think obviously the Dangerous You know we talk about quite a bit in the
Speaker 11:  film.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I think the, the intersection of those three things you talked
Speaker 2:  about is sort of forever fascinating to me. It's like YouTube
Speaker 2:  introduces mid-roll ads and so videos get longer so that they can have
Speaker 2:  mid-roll ads and the thus the structure of those videos change and the way
Speaker 2:  that people respond to 'em changes and then YouTube starts rewarding long
Speaker 2:  watch time so they make their videos even longer. Yeah. And so it just,
Speaker 2:  these things like cycle each other forever and ever. And it's just super
Speaker 2:  fascinating. But I think the, the parasocial thing was the thing that like
Speaker 2:  kept sticking with me as I was watching the doc. Like I was watching with
Speaker 2:  my wife and we got to the section about Ryan, the, the kid
Speaker 2:  who like does the toy stuff, made $22 million
Speaker 2:  wildly famous and super successful. And she was just like, why would kids
Speaker 2:  wanna watch this kid on YouTube? And it was a moment of being like, oh,
Speaker 2:  right, we're old people who don't get it. And also like these people like
Speaker 2:  think he's their friend in like a really real way. Like they have an
Speaker 2:  actual relationship in a way that like, I don't know if you
Speaker 2:  rewind 20 years, people liked and cared about movie stars but
Speaker 2:  didn't perceive them the same way. And I feel like we're still reckoning
Speaker 2:  with this idea that like I can watch somebody on my screen who I
Speaker 2:  now in some real way believe that I know
Speaker 2:  because I've been inside their house and I've seen them eat dinner in a way
Speaker 2:  that like watching somebody on a movie never did.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. And they're looking at a, they're looking at you, they're looking
Speaker 11:  at a webcam and you're often watching them on your phone or
Speaker 11:  on your laptop. I'm not in a sort of ritualistic
Speaker 11:  way of like, here is an icon a hundred feet tall on
Speaker 11:  a movie screen that I've like gotten in my car and driven to the movie theater
Speaker 11:  and gone to like bought popcorn and then for being presented with this
Speaker 11:  towering figure. It's the literal opposite of that and every
Speaker 11:  conceivable way. And in fact that's part of what we're dealing with with
Speaker 11:  a strike right now is like the advent of streaming has,
Speaker 11:  has broken that ritual to a degree that we're losing movie
Speaker 11:  stars. And and people don't feel that that
Speaker 11:  sort of opposite type of connection, that kind of epic connection
Speaker 11:  with with or interest in someone that you feel is larger than life that
Speaker 11:  you don't know. So, and Ryan You know just so it's been said, it's it's
Speaker 11:  a couple hundred million dollars a year, so Oh, sorry. It's it's a
Speaker 11:  vast sum. Sure. And they've been doing that year after year for a
Speaker 11:  long time. So I mean you are talking about an enormous,
Speaker 11:  enormous audience and, and that has gotten
Speaker 11:  Hollywood scare You know because it, it is, they're drawing numbers that
Speaker 11:  are not comparable in terms of what, what, especially in the streaming world,
Speaker 11:  which is, doesn't really monetize so well. So I think that the Parasocial
Speaker 11:  thing can't be understated. I think the work that Becca Lewis out of Stanford
Speaker 11:  has done and other people is really significant work. And it, it was
Speaker 11:  very important to me when I was making the doc 'cause it kind of answered
Speaker 11:  the question I had about, okay, if the algorithm isn't the secret sauce,
Speaker 11:  what is, Hmm. And I think the secret sauce is really the parasocial relationships
Speaker 11:  and I think it's what draws people to YouTube. I think it what makes people
Speaker 11:  feel like it's what's influential, but it's also a big part of what's
Speaker 11:  caused the societal impact because it's really much more than
Speaker 11:  just a political pundit saying go do this. It's someone that you think is
Speaker 11:  like your best friend saying go do this.
Speaker 2:  Was YouTube just first into that fray or is there something about it that
Speaker 2:  is still different? Because like TikTok plays on the same sorts of
Speaker 2:  things now, but I feel like maybe just doesn't have the history to pull that
Speaker 2:  off. Instagram was always kinda the opposite. It's like this airbrushed version
Speaker 2:  of everybody's life. Like why is it that after all these years, no one else
Speaker 2:  has figured out how to do this the way that YouTube has done it?
Speaker 11:  I think that it would be possible to have competitors in a marketplace.
Speaker 11:  I don't think TikTok is one for a number of of obvious reasons. The
Speaker 11:  way their algorithm works, the way their videos work, the way they don't
Speaker 11:  monetize creators. They're, they don't
Speaker 11:  have the scale that YouTube has. They don't have a Google behind them. Right.
Speaker 11:  And we chart this in the movie. It's the reason we spend time in the film
Speaker 11:  and act one charting the, the actual business growth of
Speaker 11:  YouTube because I think it's very important. And I think
Speaker 11:  that Susan Waki and other people's
Speaker 11:  vision in 2005, 2006, I think
Speaker 11:  you have to credit that vision. I think that, and especially given how much
Speaker 11:  flax she got and they got for, for buying YouTube for
Speaker 11:  1.6 plus billion dollars, which sounds like nothing now, but at the time
Speaker 11:  was like a preposterously large amount of money. Yeah. It was just, it was
Speaker 11:  an unimaginable, unimaginable number in the internet. A era of, of
Speaker 11:  that, of that time when, I mean when Apple was still this kind of ailing
Speaker 11:  company trying to get a foothold back in the business and
Speaker 11:  the prescience that they had of understanding that Google was becoming
Speaker 11:  a dominant figure in what was gonna be the You know
Speaker 11:  jockeying for the very few lanes of, of the highway, which
Speaker 11:  was true. Only few companies did survive and, and take those lanes and
Speaker 11:  Google is one of them. In fact they're the largest in terms of user interaction.
Speaker 11:  Apple I guess has a bigger market cap, but Google has a lot more people
Speaker 11:  using its tools. So I think that their vision
Speaker 11:  was not complete. It wasn't like we see the whole picture. But I do
Speaker 11:  think that that they knew that if you harness a video
Speaker 11:  platform that worked, that had a UI that people were responding to, which
Speaker 11:  I think was was not happening with Google Play. You harness that to the
Speaker 11:  Lar You know to one of the largest tech companies on the planet with enormous
Speaker 11:  reach and influence and lobbying power, which is
Speaker 11:  important that you would be able to dominate the market in that space
Speaker 11:  and that more people, you'd be able to create an entertainment infrastructure
Speaker 11:  that people would want to use. 'cause they did start to monetize their influencers
Speaker 11:  immediately. This wasn't like You know Masha was making money almost
Speaker 11:  immediately in the, in the early days of YouTube. Right. And other people
Speaker 11:  obviously that's, that was our, our ta use case in the movie. So I think
Speaker 11:  that's really important because I think that, and it's one of the things
Speaker 11:  that we get at is one of the problems. It's sort of how we wrap the movie
Speaker 11:  up. Not to spoil it for folks who are gonna go see it, but like You know
Speaker 11:  Google is a monopoly is one of the largest monopolies on the
Speaker 11:  planet. YouTube dominates the space because it
Speaker 11:  has the benefit of Google's monopoly power. I don't think that
Speaker 11:  if, if Google got broken up or if there
Speaker 11:  were other You know equally large tech companies, I think you would
Speaker 11:  see competitors in this space. And I do think honestly and You know, I'm
Speaker 11:  curious what, what you all think and, and You know what you think about
Speaker 11:  this given your understanding of this space. I do think it's where we're
Speaker 11:  headed, even though I don't think it's happening anytime soon. I do think
Speaker 11:  we're headed into a more fractured space You know in
Speaker 11:  terms. And I think that's a healthy thing where like it isn't just three,
Speaker 11:  four companies running everything and there is
Speaker 11:  more choice and there is more competition which gives way to
Speaker 11:  more policy and healthier regulation. I think it's gonna be a bit of a dog
Speaker 11:  fight 'cause who wants to give up dominance? But I do think we're heading
Speaker 11:  that way. And I think what's interesting to me is what Twitter, what Elon
Speaker 11:  Musk's kind of disastrous takeover of Twitter has
Speaker 11:  shown is that the public, everyone, I, I was interesting to watch people
Speaker 11:  who I, who were smart but I knew hadn't spent a lot of time online when
Speaker 11:  must did that. They were like, oh this is, I was kind of getting tired of
Speaker 11:  social media anyway, so this is kind of the end. I'm gonna probably back
Speaker 11:  off and not do this anymore. And within two weeks those same people were
Speaker 11:  like on Mastodon on post right on eventually on
Speaker 11:  Fred's. Like they figured out what a lot of us knew for years, which is
Speaker 11:  like, you don't need to be on one platform, it's okay. Right, right. You
Speaker 11:  can communicate cross platform. So I think that that's the
Speaker 11:  future on some level.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I I agree in most cases actually, and we, we've talked about it a lot
Speaker 2:  on the show actually is I think we are headed in kind of an
Speaker 2:  unbundling phase and it's where I think like things like Mastodon and the
Speaker 2:  sort of decentralized social media stuff is really interesting. We're headed
Speaker 2:  back towards like protocols being really interesting and exciting
Speaker 2:  and I think the future of social is definitely lots of places not one place.
Speaker 2:  And I think that's probably a good thing. I don't know about YouTube though
Speaker 2:  because the thing, the thing that jumps out to me even as you talk about
Speaker 2:  it, is there's no good reason for anyone to want to leave
Speaker 2:  YouTube. It's monetizing really well for everyone
Speaker 2:  involved. It's the best platform technically. It's a very
Speaker 2:  good search engine. It has a very good video player, like short of
Speaker 2:  some sort of spectacular own goal from Google At this
Speaker 2:  point I have a really hard time imagining what it would take to
Speaker 2:  unwind YouTube at this moment.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, and I agree with you. I mean I think that there at this moment, and
Speaker 11:  I think in the immediate future and even the not so immediate future,
Speaker 11:  they're it Yeah, tell me, don't get me, this is not changing tomorrow unless
Speaker 2:  Elon Musk buys YouTube and then all Betts are off and coddling this
Speaker 11:  And then just calls it X and and we all just go home and we do just get
Speaker 11:  off the internet and give up. But no, I I don't think it's gonna change
Speaker 11:  anytime soon. I mean I feel pretty firmly that they are an
Speaker 11:  entrenched entity and that they have the power. I don't know
Speaker 11:  if they have the desire, but they have the power to eat Hollywood without
Speaker 11:  blinking. Right? Yeah. And You know they could gobble up every single one
Speaker 11:  of these conglomerates and not bat an eye. I don't necessarily think that
Speaker 11:  they wanna do that. I think their forays into that level of
Speaker 11:  content distribution, which they played with in the
Speaker 11:  past was not particularly fruitful for them and they don't seem to need
Speaker 11:  it. Right. Right. But they could do it in a heartbeat. I don't think Google's
Speaker 11:  or YouTube are going to, is going to get smaller over the next few years.
Speaker 11:  I think it's gonna continue to get bigger, but I do think that there's going
Speaker 11:  to be pushback and I do think that harms are going to
Speaker 11:  increase and I think the general public will eventually, even though I think
Speaker 11:  they don't understand the internet, even lawmakers don't understand the
Speaker 11:  situation so well today. You know a lot of younger people are coming up
Speaker 11:  in law and government and, and in tech who absolutely do
Speaker 11:  understand much better what's going on. So I think we will stop,
Speaker 11:  hopefully stop seeing like really bad
Speaker 11:  legislation being put forward. Like Csosa and other You know forms of
Speaker 11:  really misguided attempts to dismantle section two
Speaker 11:  30. I think we'll stop seeing things like that soon and see a
Speaker 11:  shift towards legislation and policy ideas, even if they don't get implemented
Speaker 11:  right away, that at least make more sense.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I think that's right and I I do think, think it's gonna be good
Speaker 2:  when a generation of people who grew up with this stuff becomes the one legislating
Speaker 2:  this stuff. That's, that's gonna go a very long way. But I think the, the
Speaker 2:  thing about YouTube, I I'm fascinated by YouTube just like as a, as a product
Speaker 2:  because not only does it continue to be this sort of dominant video place,
Speaker 2:  it's also making big plays into essentially being a cable bundle.
Speaker 2:  It's a music app now. It's, it really is, like you've said, sort
Speaker 2:  of becoming all things to all people in a way that I, I don't even think
Speaker 2:  most people see yet. Like it has football now. Yeah. YouTube has football.
Speaker 2:  How did that happen? And one of the things you've said in other interviews
Speaker 2:  I was listening to is that one of the things you thought was funny is that
Speaker 2:  nobody can quite explain YouTube and because it's hard to explain
Speaker 2:  that's why like Susan Waki was never dragged in front of
Speaker 2:  Congress because like it's not, it's not social media, it's not
Speaker 2:  entertainment. It's too big to understand in the
Speaker 2:  course of doing this. Have you come up with like a good metaphor for YouTube?
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 11:  I it is Google's media front end. That's what it is. Okay. You know,
Speaker 11:  I mean it 'cause it's me, it's all media. I mean it's like You know, like
Speaker 11:  Howard Stern used to say I'm the king of all media. I mean YouTube
Speaker 11:  YouTube is truly the king of all media. And it's, it's absolutely
Speaker 11:  true. It's not just lobbying power though. I think that they are very good
Speaker 11:  at spinning a narrative that keeps people off their back because they
Speaker 11:  don't understand how to define it and they don't go to any lengths to define
Speaker 11:  it. But no, I mean it's on top of everything you just stated, it's also
Speaker 11:  You know I've got a, a kid in middle school that's his search engine. He
Speaker 11:  doesn't search on Google, he searches on YouTube, which is terrifying to
Speaker 11:  librarians who tell them that because they're like, oh my God, but it's
Speaker 11:  all wrong information. I'm like, it may be, but that's where they're You
Speaker 11:  know he is writing a term paper. He's got YouTube up. He doesn't have Google
Speaker 11:  up. Right. Or Wikipedia much to my chagrin sometimes.
Speaker 11:  But You know, at least he's not like You know listening to Andrew Tate for
Speaker 11:  like You know how to write his paper, but fair. Yeah. But it You know, but
Speaker 11:  it's also our repo You know it's our library Alexandria. I mean it's a repository
Speaker 11:  for pretty much all of recorded human history, right. Is that's on YouTube
Speaker 11:  and almost nowhere else. When I, when I'm looking for content of my own
Speaker 11:  that I've created over the years, that's the only place I find it. Like
Speaker 11:  it's literally the best archive tool for, from those
Speaker 11:  of us in the arts as well. And not just in the movie business but in all
Speaker 11:  areas of the arts as you said, and including in music. I watched
Speaker 11:  my el my now eldest son You know who's now outta college. I mean, as
Speaker 11:  he was coming up he sort of went from watching a TV
Speaker 11:  when he was like seven or eight to watching a TV with a laptop You know
Speaker 11:  on his lap to not watching the TV. And then, and then
Speaker 11:  all of his music was all YouTube like all the time. Even though we
Speaker 11:  had Spotify, we had all these other things. And this was probably
Speaker 11:  2006, 2007 like early days of YouTube
Speaker 11:  2008. And that was very fascinating to me. So I sort of watched the evolution
Speaker 11:  of YouTube through my son's eyes because he was getting pulled
Speaker 11:  into its multiple uses. I would say the least use I've
Speaker 11:  seen my kids using it for is social. Like You know they're on Discord
Speaker 11:  or they're on Twitch or they're in other areas where they can create their
Speaker 11:  own servers and talk, talk to the people they want to talk to. As you said,
Speaker 11:  social is for most internet users who are savvy, it's moved off
Speaker 11:  of these siloed platforms I think a while ago.
Speaker 11:  But I, I do think that that the You know, if we're looking at the labor
Speaker 11:  strike we're in right now and, and Hollywood, I think that the, one of the
Speaker 11:  areas of disconnect between You know my gang, the sort of the unions,
Speaker 11:  I mean all three of the unions that were up for contract negotiation, sag,
Speaker 11:  W J D G A and the A and P T P is that, I don't know how
Speaker 11:  well the, the unions understand the level of threat that the A and P T
Speaker 11:  P are under, right from larger tech
Speaker 11:  entities, some of whom right are in the A M B G B like Apple or Amazon or
Speaker 11:  whatever. But those are just little tiny pieces of their portfolio, right?
Speaker 11:  Like Apple's business is not making movies and neither is Amazon. They have
Speaker 11:  a little side hustle,
Speaker 2:  Right? But they can essentially swallow the movie business anytime they feel
Speaker 2:  like it completely.
Speaker 11:  And and so like all this talk of AI and like You know
Speaker 11:  negotiating contracts and like You know getting terms in
Speaker 11:  or even regulation like You know who are you
Speaker 11:  regulating against and who is really the power
Speaker 11:  and You know the, the disruption that's
Speaker 11:  coming over the next five to 10 years. To
Speaker 11:  your point about YouTube's growth is largely gonna be coming from these
Speaker 11:  big monopoly tech companies that are going to shape in whatever they way
Speaker 11:  they want the future.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean it's really interesting and I that that way of framing it is
Speaker 2:  really interesting to me. 'cause I think You know, one of the things we've
Speaker 2:  heard a lot about from the union side is, is this fear that
Speaker 2:  essentially AI will make real people irrelevant kind of in every step of
Speaker 2:  the process, right? We'll be able to digitize extras so that they won't need
Speaker 2:  them in the background anymore. We'll use chat G B T to generate scripts.
Speaker 2:  I think those are real fears. Not necessarily founded in like how
Speaker 2:  this tech works right now, but we're on a path where that seems reasonable
Speaker 2:  and I'm, I'm curious how you feel about that. But also at the same time
Speaker 2:  all of the studios and distributors like you're talking about also fear
Speaker 2:  being made irrelevant by technology. Yeah. And they're just afraid they're
Speaker 2:  gonna get eaten by these, this handful of big companies that has so much
Speaker 2:  money to throw at whatever they feel like that they could all just go away
Speaker 2:  and become a rounding error in Apple's budget. And it's just fascinating
Speaker 2:  to think that everybody is afraid of tech but in completely different ways.
Speaker 2:  And that's kind of why all of this becomes so hard to sort out.
Speaker 11:  It does and it also creates multiple conflicting conversations that
Speaker 11:  don't make it easier to have resolution, which is why the strike is
Speaker 11:  going on so long in in, in one area. 'cause there's other areas obviously
Speaker 11:  in terms of residuals and pay structures based on streaming, which is also
Speaker 11:  a result of big tech and their influence on, on the
Speaker 11:  entertainment industry, which is why we're in the streaming investor that
Speaker 11:  we're in in the first place. But no, I think that that's absolutely right.
Speaker 11:  I think that there's an existential concern on the part of the creative
Speaker 11:  community that AI and sort of big
Speaker 11:  technological advances 'cause some of those, even though they're, they're
Speaker 11:  put under the bucket of AI aren't really about ai, they're about other things
Speaker 11:  that are called ai but that these advances are going to
Speaker 11:  replace all workers with, with robots You know, some of which is
Speaker 11:  true. My fears are actually a little less grandiose, a little
Speaker 11:  more mundane in ways that workers will get replaced by by sort of AI
Speaker 11:  type technology. 'cause a lot of it will will be centered around
Speaker 11:  scheduling and budgeting and using You know like how
Speaker 11:  a lot of lawyers are gonna get replaced by certain types of AI at a certain
Speaker 11:  You know. I had this conversation with Lawrence Luting at Harvard. We had
Speaker 11:  a, I called him to sort of get his framing. He was like, look, mostly it's
Speaker 11:  going to eat up lawyers and we have too many lawyers anyway, so I'm not
Speaker 11:  particularly worried about it, but, but You know. But there are
Speaker 11:  obviously these technologies are gonna get used to cut corners and
Speaker 11:  costs by companies at the expense of workers. So yes,
Speaker 11:  labor-wise we are gonna have shrinkage. I wouldn't be blase about it. We
Speaker 11:  are gonna have shrinkage based on the advances in technology. We've all
Speaker 11:  known that's coming, been coming for a long time. There's actually, there's
Speaker 11:  very little we can do about it other than You know have
Speaker 11:  extremely blunt contract terms that kind of
Speaker 11:  shackle the studios or your work or your boss or whatever from
Speaker 11:  using these tools that exist because a lot of these tools are open source.
Speaker 11:  So there's very little you can do to You know. I hear so much talk in my
Speaker 11:  industry like, we gotta stop them from ingesting our material. I'm like,
Speaker 11:  that's not possible. Right. You will not stop them from ingesting your material.
Speaker 11:  They they will do that and
Speaker 2:  There are a hundred thems now.
Speaker 11:  Well yeah, there's th it's like Napster, right? It's whack-a-mole, right?
Speaker 11:  You know. Yeah. And you're gonna have a kid in, in Taiwan with an open source
Speaker 11:  tool that's making Star Wars all day long. And You know with
Speaker 11:  me starring Meryl Streep and, and You know Humphrey Bogart and
Speaker 11:  that's absolutely gonna happen. So You know there are contract
Speaker 11:  negotiations that you can get into. There is also, as you well
Speaker 11:  know, there are realities about what these, these technologies can
Speaker 11:  do and there are fears about their
Speaker 11:  potential that we're, that we're not at yet about what they can do. And
Speaker 11:  I think it's important to try to stay focused on what they can actually
Speaker 11:  do because we do still need people to tell these
Speaker 11:  stories. And we do still need to, to document human beings to tell
Speaker 11:  most of these stories. And AI will, will You know and
Speaker 11:  it's present and even it's potentially immediate future
Speaker 11:  self will create mostly garbage or sort of regurgitated
Speaker 11:  maybe curiosities. I'm more concerned about it being used
Speaker 11:  for You know calculation type stuff that will cut the workforce. Things
Speaker 11:  that I know AI can do and do quickly that
Speaker 11:  will You know will shove a lot of people out of the workforce.
Speaker 11:  But I think generally the bigger concerns I have are the concerns the A
Speaker 11:  M P G P are having, which is huge disruption to the
Speaker 11:  overall industry from these tech companies. And I think that's a
Speaker 11:  much bigger threat that will create much bigger
Speaker 11:  disruption.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think you're right. And I think one of the things I've heard you
Speaker 2:  say and and you can sort of feel in the YouTube Effect is you're,
Speaker 2:  you're interested in scale as a thing, right? That's like what happens when
Speaker 2:  things get huge I think is a really interesting question. And is one you've
Speaker 2:  explored in a bunch of different places, do you buy the idea that
Speaker 2:  these platforms and these companies are just too big that eventually you
Speaker 2:  hit a tipping point of that kind of scale where it's impossible to be
Speaker 2:  a good citizen of the internet and do content moderation? Well and I think
Speaker 2:  that there's one school of thought that says these are the companies that
Speaker 2:  have the resources to do this stuff well. And there's another school of thought
Speaker 2:  that says this is just too much stuff. Even if YouTube tries its hardest
Speaker 2:  with all the available resources, it is not going to be able to successfully
Speaker 2:  solve the problems that it has. Which side of that do you fall on?
Speaker 11:  I fall on the side that there is plenty of room for
Speaker 11:  accountability and no one should expect perfection. I think
Speaker 11:  a, a good example is YouTube was
Speaker 11:  removing content that pushed the stop the steal
Speaker 11:  lie until about two weeks ago. And then they, they reversed their
Speaker 11:  policy and began to let that content back on platform
Speaker 11:  right As we head into an election cycle, which is
Speaker 11:  bananas. Yes. That's a really good example of content
Speaker 11:  moderation that is doable that they were doing and then
Speaker 11:  decided to stop doing. I don't think that the problem, I think they're too
Speaker 11:  big for You know in general. They're too big in terms of not allowing competition
Speaker 11:  and other reasons that monopolies are bad. But I don't think they're too
Speaker 11:  big to self-regulate. I think that they don't self-regulate because it's
Speaker 11:  not profitable to self, it's a business model issue. So as we
Speaker 11:  talked about at the very beginning of this conversation, salacious content
Speaker 11:  draws eyeballs, eyeballs, dry draw, eye add dollars, and that
Speaker 11:  makes everybody lots of money. You know how are you gonna boot Stephen
Speaker 11:  Crowder off your platform when he is got 4 million
Speaker 11:  subscribers and you can tag that You know adds to that and everyone
Speaker 11:  makes lots of money and goes home happy And you go before your, your board
Speaker 11:  or your shareholders and say, You know stock is up. So I think it's a business
Speaker 11:  model capitalist thing I that makes a different, that's why we need, that's
Speaker 11:  why it took us so long to get the automakers to start putting seat belts
Speaker 11:  in their cars. It's the same old thing with industry over and over again.
Speaker 11:  And it does require policy. It just does. 'cause no, no company, just like
Speaker 11:  a little kid, you give a kid a You know bag of candy and tell 'em to share
Speaker 11:  with everyone else in the sandbox. They just aren't going to do that. It's
Speaker 11:  just not the way human beings are wired. So they have to have a teacher
Speaker 11:  or a parent or someone say, You know now Eddie, I'm going to take some of
Speaker 11:  those away and give them to the other kids. And I think that's kind of where
Speaker 11:  we're at.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. We need more grownups is not a bad diagnosis of a lot of things in
Speaker 2:  life right now. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  Exactly. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  All right, awesome. Well Alex, thank you again. I really enjoyed the documentary
Speaker 2:  and this was, this was really fun. I really appreciate you coming on and
Speaker 2:  doing this.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, likewise. Yeah, thanks for having me.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna come back and
Speaker 2:  we're gonna answer a question from The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  hotline.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's do the hotline. Tom Warn is here to help us
Speaker 2:  with the hotline. Hi Tom. Hello. It's gonna be very clear to you very
Speaker 2:  shortly what we have here. But first the hotline is 8 6 6
Speaker 2:  Verge one, one call. Ask us all your deepest darkest questions. We do at
Speaker 2:  least one every week. It's very fun. This time we have a
Speaker 2:  Windows question which we don't get a lot of from Jim. Let's hear it real
Speaker 2:  fast.
Speaker 13:  Hi, this is Jim. I'm calling asking about Windows 11. I
Speaker 13:  seem to have kind of memory hold everything I've ever heard about it. Is
Speaker 13:  it actually time to upgrade to Windows 11? Just lemme know.
Speaker 13:  Thanks.
Speaker 2:  So fairly straightforward question, right? Like is it time to upgrade to
Speaker 2:  Windows 11, which is like the funniest Windows question of all time. Everybody's
Speaker 2:  like, I have Windows from 11 years ago slash Windows
Speaker 2:  95, do I need to upgrade? But it, it sent me down this weird rabbit
Speaker 2:  hole of, I kind of forgot about Windows 11
Speaker 2:  and, and I kind of feel like Microsoft is perfectly happy with that being
Speaker 2:  the case. But let's just start at the very top, like answer the question
Speaker 2:  what do we think? Is it, is it time for everyone to be on Windows 11?
Speaker 14:  This, this is one of those questions where it's like You know when someone
Speaker 14:  asks you what's the best laptop And you're like,
Speaker 14:  well that's like a, a very big question. So I guess the the
Speaker 14:  basic answer is it depends what you use your laptop for or your, your
Speaker 14:  PC for wherever you need to upgrade or not. But on the flip side, it's like
Speaker 14:  if you upgrade you're not gonna like lose anything potentially. I
Speaker 14:  mean I think initially when Windows 11 came out there were some issues
Speaker 14:  particularly around the taska, but they've, they've kind of improved that
Speaker 14:  so you're not gonna lose some of that functionality and stuff. So yeah,
Speaker 14:  I think my general very quick answer to that and we'll obviously go very
Speaker 14:  deep into it, but the very quick answer is yeah, it's probably time to upgrade
Speaker 14:  now. I think it's it's it's a good time to upgrade now after, after, what
Speaker 14:  is it? Two years now? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It does seem like, I mean the, the sort of standard operating procedure
Speaker 2:  for Windows was like wait for two security patches, right? And then it was
Speaker 2:  like, then it was like okay you can update. And it feels like we're well
Speaker 2:  past that. We're to the point now where like if you get Windows 11, assuming
Speaker 2:  your computer can support it, whatever, it's not going to be broken.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. It used to be like wait for service packs and we've essentially had
Speaker 14:  the, those service packs used to be You know once a year and, and they kind
Speaker 14:  of changed them into updates now essentially is the naming of them. So
Speaker 14:  it'd be like the 2022 H two update,
Speaker 14:  which which sounds very like a code name, but it just means
Speaker 14:  it's the second half of the year. So essentially we've had a couple of those
Speaker 14:  and we've had a bunch of sort of updates in between as well. So Microsoft
Speaker 14:  has, has been doing all sorts really. So when I first reviewed
Speaker 14:  Windows 11, I think the main negatives I had about it was
Speaker 14:  it was a bit inconsistent. It felt like a work still in
Speaker 14:  progress and there was some missing stuff around the task bar like for power
Speaker 14:  users and just a, a bunch of stuff related to to to how you
Speaker 14:  say, say you like drag and drop files into Photoshop and, and work on
Speaker 14:  them. Like some of that stuff was just missing and it was just, it just
Speaker 14:  felt like a little bit of a work in progress. So, and I think like two years
Speaker 14:  later it's still a work in progress but it's got
Speaker 14:  better. So like some of the UI stuff that was a bit inconsistent
Speaker 14:  where they didn't have dark mode in certain places, like they've added it
Speaker 14:  to like the task management for example and places where it just hasn't
Speaker 14:  had it for years. So it, it's, it's getting there with the inconsistency
Speaker 14:  front and like I mentioned the taskforce a lot better now. Stuff like
Speaker 14:  if you use a tablet for example, you've got a tablet that you're thinking
Speaker 14:  of upgrading to Windows 11, the touch experience is a lot better now than
Speaker 14:  it was when it first shipped. And they've done stuff like add tabs to file
Speaker 14:  explorer, like tabs in apps like Notepad and those sort of like small little
Speaker 14:  things. You might not notice them like immediately. But I think it's one
Speaker 14:  of those cases where if you upgraded to Windows 11, you started using that
Speaker 14:  stuff and then you went and used Windows 10, you'd be like, huh, where's
Speaker 14:  my tabs gone? You know. Like it's stuff you get used to when when they do
Speaker 14:  that. So
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's what my experience too is there's, there's not a ton about it
Speaker 2:  that is like immediately sort of slam dunk life changing
Speaker 2:  and it seems like copilot, which I think is coming this fall
Speaker 2:  just to Windows 11. Yes, that's right. Might be that thing. But until
Speaker 2:  then it, it does seem like it's, it's like whatever the opposite of death
Speaker 2:  by a thousand cuts is right? It's like a, a lot of tiny little things that
Speaker 2:  add up to like it, my experience with Windows 11 over time has gotten
Speaker 2:  meaningfully better but not, I couldn't point you to like one specific
Speaker 2:  thing that has totally changed my life about it.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. And I think that that's exactly it. Like there's, there's not something
Speaker 14:  I can say right, you should get 11 because it's gonna do this for you. But
Speaker 14:  you could say You know there's this tiny bunch of things that add
Speaker 14:  up into being like a meaningful update that you will
Speaker 14:  get used to. There'll be some changes like the start button changes
Speaker 14:  to the center, you can move it back to the left. There's some stuff to sort
Speaker 14:  of get used to when you first sort of upgrade but once you're used to all
Speaker 14:  those sort of changes, I think it does improve the way you use Windows for
Speaker 14:  sure. Like if it is, it's definitely, it's not the horror update that you
Speaker 14:  usually get.
Speaker 2:  It is amazing to me how much I think Vista and
Speaker 2:  Windows eight have like left this scary taste in people's mouths
Speaker 2:  about upgrading. 'cause I also feel like it's just just true that it's good
Speaker 2:  to update for like security reasons, right? Yeah. And I feel like that was
Speaker 2:  my immediate answer to this is like you should always try to be on the latest
Speaker 2:  version of software because it will be better and safer and more secure if
Speaker 2:  nothing else that's a victory. And I think that's true, but I
Speaker 2:  also think people's reluctance to upgrade their perfectly
Speaker 2:  functional piece of software and gadget is
Speaker 2:  well-founded. And I think over the years every company has
Speaker 2:  given people reasons not to upgrade.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. You know what, you don't want something that's working fine to just
Speaker 14:  randomly break because you've updated Windows and Windows usually in that
Speaker 14:  in the past has been a bit clunky when you've updated it. So, but the, the
Speaker 14:  other aspect though is can you even upgrade to Windows 11? Like that's,
Speaker 14:  that's the sort of bigger question because you might have hardware that
Speaker 14:  just isn't compatible. So obviously Microsoft cut the, the list of
Speaker 14:  processes only to ones that were available in the sort of last,
Speaker 14:  well by now like four four to sort of five years also. So
Speaker 14:  talking roughly 2018 onwards I believe in the processes
Speaker 14:  both on Intel and a md. So you might even be thinking, oh we're not upgrade
Speaker 14:  to Windows 11 being, might not actually be able to like in an official capacity.
Speaker 14:  There are workarounds out there and all that sort of stuff, but who knows
Speaker 14:  when those are stopped working and they're not officially supported and
Speaker 14:  stuff. So, so you might be thinking I wanna upgrade, I've heard good things
Speaker 14:  about Windows 11, but you'd have to get a new PC technically
Speaker 14:  to, to upgrade officially. Which obviously that's good for Microsoft bottom
Speaker 14:  line 'cause they sell another Windows license and it's good for OEMs and
Speaker 14:  stuff, but it's not good for consumers, right. Whereas in the past Windows,
Speaker 14:  you've able to upgrade pretty much freely. You know, unless you've got a
Speaker 14:  really ancient pc, you're going back You know 10 or more years. But we
Speaker 14:  we're seeing increasingly people like the look of Windows 11 and
Speaker 14:  then they're like, I can't upgrade. So that's, that's definitely another
Speaker 14:  part of this question is like, you might like the look of it, but you need
Speaker 14:  to go check to actually see if your system is actually capable of that.
Speaker 14:  So
Speaker 2:  Yeah, and it does seem to me that like if you're in a position where you
Speaker 2:  can get another year out of your computer before you upgrade, but you
Speaker 2:  can't yet get Windows 11, like wait a year, right? Like there's nothing to
Speaker 2:  me so great about Windows 11 that you have to sort of rush out to buy a computer
Speaker 2:  to get it. But also if you can get it, it's, it's better. You should get
Speaker 2:  it. For me, honestly, just the part where they've designed most of the
Speaker 2:  settings menus in a new way and nothing falls back to like 20 year
Speaker 2:  old Windows designs when you click on a folder worth it alone, it
Speaker 2:  just, it's so much better. It just makes me so happy. It's, it's a, it's
Speaker 2:  a nice little thing and there's a lot of things like that like we were talking
Speaker 2:  about that it, it feels worth it but don't break the bank for it.
Speaker 14:  Yeah, like one of the small additions they did do is when you, when you're
Speaker 14:  like multitasking with different apps and you're trying to like lay them
Speaker 14:  out, there's like a nice feature that will sort of really guide you
Speaker 14:  through laying them out in the, in in the perfect way, like snap assist
Speaker 14:  and I think that is, that's definitely worth upgrading for
Speaker 14:  alone. And, and the tab stuff really depends how you use your PC and
Speaker 14:  what PC you have. Laptop or, or tablet or desktop pc.
Speaker 14:  There, there are some like stuff stuff, there's some stuff in there for
Speaker 14:  like on the gaming side like we've been saying, it's not one of those sort
Speaker 14:  of like big features where you go, you should upgrade for this, but there
Speaker 14:  is some improvements to window mode performance and latency for gaming,
Speaker 14:  which is actually kind of useful if you have like a massive ultra wide monitor
Speaker 14:  that you run a game on in a window, you'll get all the sort of
Speaker 14:  latency performance improvements rather than having to run it full screen
Speaker 14:  in that way. And a lot of games aren't obviously optimized to, to run those
Speaker 14:  sort of ultra wide monitors. So, so there's some, there's some improvements
Speaker 14:  there as well if you're thinking on the gaming side. So yeah, it's way too
Speaker 14:  many to to list but it's, it's a bunch of of improvements that sort of
Speaker 14:  all add up
Speaker 2:  And like you said, we're pretty much out of reasons to be afraid to upgrade.
Speaker 2:  Like I think if, if you can do it, it's time. You're good, you're safe.
Speaker 14:  Yeah, I think so. Like yeah I think unless you really love the
Speaker 14:  old look of Windows, like the old start menu, you really love
Speaker 14:  those live tiles, which I can't imagine as many people
Speaker 2:  If you're the one person who loves live tiles.
Speaker 14:  Yeah, yeah. Like if you're in that very small category of people,
Speaker 14:  then sure you might wanna hold off and if you're on a Windows 10 PC and
Speaker 14:  you're like, everything's working fine, what do I really need? Then sure
Speaker 14:  You know you can hold off 'cause you're probably gonna buy a new PC at some
Speaker 14:  point, which will then have probably Windows 12 by that point. So I
Speaker 14:  wanna see what they do with that. So, 'cause there's, there are rumors of
Speaker 14:  Windows 12 and they're gonna do some like AI stuff with the chips and stuff.
Speaker 14:  So there's gonna be new hardware coming probably next year that will enable
Speaker 14:  all that sort of stuff. So that's another potential reason to hold off if
Speaker 14:  you're thinking about getting a new machine. But I think if you've, if you've
Speaker 14:  got a machine where you're, you're curious about Windows 11 and you see
Speaker 14:  all the improvements and you are like stuck on Windows 10, you're like,
Speaker 14:  I'm not getting any new features here. 'cause nothing is changing, it's
Speaker 14:  just, it stays as it is then I think you're probably good to upgrade.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. I like it. All right. Well Jim, I hope that helps Tom. Thank
Speaker 2:  you. Appreciate it. No
Speaker 14:  Worries, thanks.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thanks to everybody who's on
Speaker 2:  the show today, and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more
Speaker 2:  from all of our conversations, especially the chat with Alex at The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com. We'll put some links in the show notes, but You know it's a good
Speaker 2:  website. There's a lot going on right now. It's so surprisingly busy August,
Speaker 2:  so keep it locked on The Verge. If you have thoughts, questions, feelings,
Speaker 2:  or YouTube videos you really want me to see, you can always email us at Vergecast
Speaker 2:  at The Verge dot com or call the hotline, like I said, 8 6 6 Verge one,
Speaker 2:  one. We'd love hearing from you. Send us all of your thoughts and questions,
Speaker 2:  and we will do at least one hotline question every single episode.
Speaker 2:  Oh, and specifically, we're doing an episode in a couple of weeks all about
Speaker 2:  cybersecurity, so call us for sure if you have
Speaker 2:  cybersecurity questions, no question. Too small, no question, too weird,
Speaker 2:  bring 'em all on. This show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James.
Speaker 2:  Brooke Miners is our editorial director of Audio The. Vergecast is Verge
Speaker 2:  production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli, Alex, and Nile
Speaker 2:  will be back on Friday to talk about presumably Zuckerberg and
Speaker 2:  Musk fighting or not fighting, plus some news in the YouTube
Speaker 2:  world. Big stuff going on in ai, like I said, surprisingly
Speaker 2:  busy summer. We'll see you then. Rock and
Speaker 2:  roll.