# Transcript
ID: 022af8bd-f7aa-4e91-8f76-fe11895784bd
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/2840723305610264508/5539584907600292/s93290-US-5458s-1729854825.mp3
Description: Nilay, David, and Richard Lawler talk about all of the coming Apple gadgets and software, from the new iPad Mini to the upcoming week of Mac announcements to the many flavors of iOS and Apple Intelligence heading to a device near you soon. Then they talk about the other news in AI, from Anthropic's new computer-using model to the growing set of lawsuits against AI companies. In the lightning round, they discuss the Boox Palma 2, T-Mobile's "lifetime" deals, and the battle over FTC's click-to-cancel rule.
Speaker 3:  Hello and welcome to Vergecast the flagship podcast. I'm jolly scrolling.
Speaker 3:  We're sorry. It's still there. All right, use your eyes.
Speaker 3:  I'm your friend. Neli David Pierce is here.
Speaker 4:  Hi. I hate that I know what jelly scrolling is. You
Speaker 3:  Got in a lot of trouble this week, buddy.
Speaker 4:  I did, and then I was immediately vindicated and it's been, it's been a fun
Speaker 4:  week. I would like to, I'm excited to talk about
Speaker 3:  This. We'll, we'll come back to this in a moment. Richard Lawler is here.
Speaker 5:  Hello. I'm somehow unaware of the massive jelly scrolling scandal.
Speaker 4:  Richard doesn't jelly scroll. That's one important thing to know about Richard.
Speaker 3:  How do you know Richard doesn't pay attention? Not once to stakes free Apple
Speaker 3:  drama. He doesn't know about Jelly scrolling.
Speaker 3:  Welcome back Richard. By way, fan favorite Richard Lawler.
Speaker 5:  My people, they, they made the request and we came through
Speaker 5:  there. There will be crypto in all of your wallets. It's coming.
Speaker 3:  Richard will give you a Bitcoin If. you vir vote for The. Vergecast
Speaker 5:  It. It's quantum lock. So it's already there and it's coming all at the same
Speaker 5:  time. It's, it's a, yeah, it's a thing.
Speaker 3:  I believe it was Richard who today pointed out what was Starbucks is failing
Speaker 3:  and some other companies failing. And you're like, these are the two companies.
Speaker 3:  Nike, Nike, Starbucks, and Nike. Tell your theory. Say your
Speaker 3:  theory about Starbucks and Nike.
Speaker 5:  Starbucks and Nike. They were both out there just promoting NFTs. There were
Speaker 5:  lots of companies and lots of brands doing NFT things a few years ago that
Speaker 5:  now have, are acting like they didn't, but they were out there and they,
Speaker 5:  and they were doing it big. They were really, really pushing it. And I don't
Speaker 5:  think that they are going down now or that they're having the struggles they're
Speaker 5:  having because they did NFTs. But I think that If, you look at the companies
Speaker 5:  that were really into it, where the executives looked at NFTs
Speaker 5:  and didn't immediately say that is nothing and move on. That they
Speaker 5:  had something wrong in their boardroom that, that their executives, they,
Speaker 5:  they weren't focused on what was going on and what their customers really
Speaker 5:  wanted.
Speaker 4:  Right? The NFTs aren't the, aren't the cause, but they're, they're a symptom
Speaker 4:  of the problem that is causing all these other problems. Right?
Speaker 3:  And the problem is you have no idea what you make or sell and you think selling
Speaker 3:  nothing is a, is a functional business. You
Speaker 4:  Think NFT shoes are the same as shoes? Is is, yeah.
Speaker 3:  Should we make a coffee or the idea of coffee
Speaker 5:  If we will sell experiences behind digital tokens?
Speaker 3:  Hey, hey, hey, don't knock selling experiences behind digital tokens.
Speaker 3:  What is a podcast in our RSS s feed except an
Speaker 3:  experience behind a deeply fungible digital token. But
Speaker 3:  nevermind, there's a lot to talk about this week.
Speaker 3:  Quite a lot to talk about. There's David reviewed an iPad. Mini I would
Speaker 3:  say that as someone who edited that review felt like a hostage situation
Speaker 3:  for David. We'll talk about that. There's a bunch of other Apple
Speaker 3:  News iOS 18.1 is coming out next week with Apple
Speaker 3:  Intelligence, which means Apple is already started seeding iOS 18.2,
Speaker 3:  which has the actual features in it. Very confusing. What worked through
Speaker 3:  all of that. Then there's a week of Mac announcements to come. Greg Jozwiak
Speaker 3:  is posting at that right now. There's a bunch of AI news as always,
Speaker 3:  including some deeply funny humane news and then we got a lightning round.
Speaker 3:  Alright, but let's start with the drama. Look,
Speaker 3:  every now and again, The Verge gets itself mixed up in a bunch of high
Speaker 3:  stakes drama, journalism ethics, what
Speaker 3:  are we doing here? and we did that this week. And then David also pissed
Speaker 3:  off a bunch of people by talking about the iPad.
Speaker 3:  So the iPad Mini came out, they updated the chip. It supports Apple Intelligence
Speaker 3:  at eight gigs of Ram. David, you reviewed it, you were disappointed.
Speaker 3:  I There's no other way to put this.
Speaker 4:  No, that's, that's right. Disappointed is fair. So I, I have been
Speaker 4:  an iPad mini person forever. I think I've owned two
Speaker 4:  different generations. I bought my wife and my dad
Speaker 4:  iPad minis over the years. Like I, this thing is awesome and I love it and
Speaker 4:  believe in it and have used it many times or many for many years.
Speaker 4:  Apple shipped this one and like I, I don't know how else to
Speaker 4:  frame it except it did the literal least it possibly could
Speaker 4:  in a way that felt rude. Like this was not
Speaker 4:  a case of, of just sort of chip upgrades that
Speaker 4:  make the thing not necessarily brand new, but like
Speaker 4:  commensurate with the times. Apple gave this a worst version of
Speaker 4:  last year's chip and changed nothing else. And and
Speaker 4:  you're supposed to be like, oh, thank God a new iPad mini. And the thing
Speaker 4:  that Apple knows, and Nathan Edwards who worked with me on this
Speaker 4:  piece a lot, the thing he kept pointing out is like Apple knows that If,
Speaker 4:  you want an iPad mini, you're gonna buy an iPad mini because it's the iPad
Speaker 4:  mini and you want an iPad mini and that is how Apple has
Speaker 4:  you, it is, it is the most like self-selecting device Apple makes.
Speaker 4:  And so why would Apple try if it doesn't have to try? It's just
Speaker 4:  gonna do the absolute literal bare minimum.
Speaker 4:  And just, here you go. Do you, do you want it?
Speaker 4:  You're gonna have it if not like, and, and So, I just got to this point
Speaker 4:  where I was like, this thing is, it's not that it's not good, it's just that
Speaker 4:  it's not nearly as good as it could be. And Apple only had to
Speaker 4:  try a tiny bit to make it way better. And it just
Speaker 4:  didn't. And the thing I wrote was like, this feels like an iPad designed
Speaker 4:  by a supply chain, not by a designer. And it,
Speaker 4:  it's, it's just true. I cannot shake that feeling. And so it is both
Speaker 4:  a good tablet and a deeply disappointing one, which is a very strange,
Speaker 4:  it's a thing we deal with a lot with the iPad, honestly, frankly is like
Speaker 4:  we want the iPad to be more than it is, but what it is is very
Speaker 4:  good for what it is in a lot of ways. And so we, we felt this tension
Speaker 4:  more and more. And I feel like with this one, it just tipped the other way
Speaker 4:  for me where I was like, this is just not, it's just not a good buy. Lots
Speaker 4:  of people are gonna buy it. Lots of people are gonna like it, but it is not
Speaker 4:  good.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And it's funny 'cause you know, the old one will be around on sale
Speaker 3:  for quite some, like in true Apple fashion you'll be able to get the old
Speaker 3:  one for a minute right on, on some discount. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And the only meaningful difference is it doesn't run Apple Intelligence.
Speaker 4:  And like, is that a meaningful difference to anyone and will it be anytime
Speaker 4:  soon? Well,
Speaker 3:  Especially 'cause the iPad Mini in particular is a secondary
Speaker 3:  device. Like almost definitionally you have another thing If, you have an
Speaker 3:  iPad mini, right? Like the iPad maybe
Speaker 3:  can replace your laptop and maybe you want Apple Intelligence there.
Speaker 3:  I'm, I'm struggling to make the case, but you know, maybe you do the,
Speaker 3:  there's no one who's like, I need my notifications on my iPad mini
Speaker 3:  summarized,
Speaker 4:  Right? My travel laptop is my iPad Mini is not a sentence.
Speaker 4:  People say, yeah, it's just not. And so it's like, yeah, all this stuff
Speaker 4:  that Apple does where it's like, help me write this email is not an iPad
Speaker 4:  mini thing. They're like really good. Siri might someday
Speaker 4:  be, but, but again, like I,
Speaker 3:  But you have your phone. I don't
Speaker 4:  Think anyone should buy any Apple product on the basis of Apple Intelligence
Speaker 4:  right now. And the iPad Mini might be the one that needs it the least
Speaker 4:  at this moment. And so, yeah, I just got to this point where I was like,
Speaker 4:  I, unless your iPad mini is broken and you are desperate
Speaker 4:  for a new iPad mini, there is no reason this thing is
Speaker 4:  compelling. And it turns out a lot of people disagreed with me about that.
Speaker 3:  Or
Speaker 4:  What is actually true is there are a lot of iPad mini people out there. So,
Speaker 5:  So what's their, their case and, and I guess my question is what's the problem
Speaker 5:  with this one? So it's using the a 17 processor from the iPhone and not the
Speaker 5:  M four that the other tablets and the laptops use
Speaker 3:  A 17 pro from the iPhone 15 pro, but it appears to be the, like the
Speaker 3:  Bend version,
Speaker 4:  Right? So it, it benchmarks slightly below
Speaker 4:  the iPhone 15 pro and it also has one
Speaker 4:  fewer GPU core, which in both cases suggests that it's
Speaker 4:  basically a chip that came off the manufacturing line for whatever
Speaker 4:  reason, not up to full capacity. And that's like a normal thing. A lot of
Speaker 4:  companies do this, right? Like when they sell you a, a middle range
Speaker 4:  processor, often it is a a, a sort of imperfectly
Speaker 4:  manufactured version of a better processor. Like that's a super normal thing.
Speaker 4:  People do it, it's fine, but it's just like this, this brand
Speaker 4:  new product is giving you a worse version of last year's chip
Speaker 4:  in a time when Apple is like a telling you that you need all the performance
Speaker 4:  you can possibly get in order to run Apple Intelligence has massively upgraded
Speaker 4:  a bunch of its other iPads. There's just no way to look at this other than
Speaker 4:  it got the worst of the worst.
Speaker 3:  Like literally the part spin. Yeah. Like it's a Chevy with a Cadillac logo
Speaker 3:  on it.
Speaker 4:  Exactly. The
Speaker 3:  Pontiac iPad is just fine. Yeah. So we should talk about the jelly
Speaker 3:  scrolling because I think if people understand the iPad mini got a chip bump
Speaker 3:  and nothing is very compelling and that's why And the iPad Mini has effectively
Speaker 3:  no competition. There's not some like eight inch Android tablet that's
Speaker 3:  crushing it. Right. And the iPad mini has for whatever it's worth
Speaker 3:  the iPad app library, which doesn't exist on the
Speaker 3:  Android side. Correct.
Speaker 4:  Also, pilots use it. I dunno, If you knew that
Speaker 3:  The pilots are outta control
Speaker 4:  The pilots and apparently there are like hundreds of millions of pilots out
Speaker 3:  There flying planes directly to Apple stores. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Exactly.
Speaker 3:  Like landing right on Michigan Avenue and go
Speaker 4:  Outside of the Fifth Avenue store instead of people. It's just a bunch of
Speaker 4:  tiny planes lining fifth Avenue to get to
Speaker 3:  The store. Right? Right. In Lake Michigan in the pontoons
Speaker 3:  swimming up to the Apple store.
Speaker 3:  Okay, don't do that. If you're listening to this and you're like, I should
Speaker 3:  fly my float plane to the Chicago Apple store, I'm just
Speaker 3:  encouraging you not to do that If,
Speaker 4:  You do send us a video because we will put it on our website.
Speaker 3:  That's, that's the opposite of not showing the person running under the field
Speaker 3:  during the football game.
Speaker 3:  Opposite incentive. All right, so there's whatever, this is a spec bump.
Speaker 3:  The thing that got people really lit up is not you dare to criticize an Apple
Speaker 3:  product. It's that the screen on
Speaker 3:  the iPad mini is notorious for jelly scrolling. Yes. Which is when you
Speaker 3:  scroll, one side of the screen moves faster than the other, which
Speaker 3:  warps everything on the screen. This is one of those things where some people
Speaker 3:  can see it and some people can't. But unlike 120 hertz
Speaker 3:  refresh, like once you see it, you're done. You're hooped a
Speaker 3:  hundred percent. Like it's, it's never, it's like motion smoothing. It's
Speaker 3:  like you can ruin someone's life by pointing this out.
Speaker 4:  And do you know who ruined my life? Dieter Bone. Thank you Dieter
Speaker 4:  with his 2021 review of the iPad Mini
Speaker 4:  in which he spent a long time talking about how bad the jelly scrolling is.
Speaker 4:  And I think he, he either there or somewhere else linked to a test
Speaker 4:  you can do to test for jelly scrolling that actually it just basically moves
Speaker 4:  a thing across the screen so you can see it and it's a line. And the
Speaker 4:  idea is if the line appears to bend, it means the screen is not refreshing
Speaker 4:  in a uniform way. And once you see it,
Speaker 4:  holy Lord, can you not unsee it? Yeah. And you can, you can super see it
Speaker 4:  on the, the 2021 mini. So yeah, the here are several things that I
Speaker 4:  know. I know that jelly scrolling was a big problem on the 2021
Speaker 4:  mini. I know that Apple said in 2021, it's not a real
Speaker 4:  problem, don't worry about it. Everything's fine. That's you. You can go
Speaker 4:  back and find that those are statements Apple gave that was like, yeah, this
Speaker 4:  is a normal thing that happens on screens, don't worry about it. Like
Speaker 4:  bad response. But that was the response. I also know that Apple this
Speaker 4:  year tried to fix it. They changed the way the display controller works
Speaker 4:  in order to ostensibly refresh the screen more uniformly
Speaker 4:  this one is better. It, it is certainly less
Speaker 4:  jelly than the 2021 model I sat. I mean
Speaker 4:  I like, so our, our reviews all went up at nine and at like
Speaker 4:  nine 30, a bunch of like the, the Apple blogs and stuff do the
Speaker 4:  roundups of reviews and because the jelly scrolling was a tiny low
Speaker 4:  stakes, you know, controversy in 2021.
Speaker 4:  They all are talking about the jelly scrolling. I was the only reviewer of
Speaker 4:  that early batch that said jelly scrolling still existed.
Speaker 4:  And these, it's a bunch of other like good smart reviewers, people whose
Speaker 4:  work that I like. So I was like, oh my god, did I get this wrong? So I went
Speaker 4:  upstairs and got Anna's 2021 mini
Speaker 4:  grabbed the 2024 mini and sat here for, I don't know, 90 minutes just
Speaker 4:  scrolling, scrolling everything I could find up and down. Do you believe
Speaker 3:  Your own eyes?
Speaker 4:  That's the like I didn't for like an hour and a half. And then even our own
Speaker 4:  staff, I think it was Chris Welch who posted a link and was like, everybody
Speaker 4:  else disagrees with you, David, are you sure you're right? And I was like,
Speaker 4:  no I'm not.
Speaker 3:  That's that's one of the most in character Chris Welch things I've ever
Speaker 4:  Heard. Yeah. Oh, for sure. Yeah. Yeah. And it's like typically when I disagree
Speaker 4:  with like Federico vii, it's like I should internally really think through
Speaker 4:  life, but I went and looked and
Speaker 4:  like it is, it is better than it was in 2021. Like you can really
Speaker 4:  see it's, it's like the, the 2021 screen is like
Speaker 4:  a ship on the ocean. Yes. Right. It's like rolling waves as you scroll. The
Speaker 4:  new one is better. It is, it is meaningfully better. It's still Jelly
Speaker 4:  Scrolls. Like, and, and the way I think about it is like the, the easiest
Speaker 4:  one to see for me was you go to the Amazon homepage and it's a bunch of
Speaker 4:  white boxes with like images and texts and seven side
Speaker 4:  and If. you scroll quickly, the right side of the box appears to pull down
Speaker 4:  and then up faster than the left side. So it just, it just every,
Speaker 4:  and then it catches up and it, but it's like you're, you're turning a rectangle
Speaker 4:  into a parallelogram and then back into a rectangle as you scroll. And it's
Speaker 4:  not horrible. Like on the 20 21 1, Anna has
Speaker 4:  never looked at me and been like, is this scrolling weird? Like it's not
Speaker 4:  never
Speaker 3:  Tell
Speaker 4:  Her I'm not going to. So thi this is the thing, right? It's like it's not.
Speaker 4:  And even a lot of the reviewers were like, I didn't really notice it then
Speaker 4:  and I definitely don't notice it now. And that's a fine and BI think representative
Speaker 4:  of just about everybody's experience. But once you see it, you can't unsee
Speaker 4:  it and it is there. And the great thing for me was our reviews ran
Speaker 4:  on Tuesday. The things started, shit, I, I got 24 hours of people
Speaker 4:  being like, you're a monster who has an agenda against Apple or
Speaker 4:  for jelly scrolling or something. Yes. And then 24 hours later a bunch of
Speaker 4:  people who reluctantly were like, oh no, he's right. There's some jelly scrolling.
Speaker 4:  Some people still don't notice it, some people see it. I am
Speaker 4:  absolutely confident it's there. But it's also fine. Like don't not
Speaker 4:  buy it because of the jelly scrolling. Well
Speaker 3:  You have no choice.
Speaker 4:  It doesn't make it better or worse. But also you have no choice.
Speaker 3:  If you're a pilot, you have no choice. You're like, this is what I, this
Speaker 3:  is who I am now I have to see this parallelogram.
Speaker 4:  I think If, you have the thing strapped to your thigh jelly scrolling is
Speaker 4:  not going to be a huge issue. It's just a thought.
Speaker 3:  That's a sentence that only makes sense in the context of aviation and almost
Speaker 3:  in no other context.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like as you walk about the subway in New York City,
Speaker 3:  you'd be like, jelly scrolling is an issue. Would you like to scroll up my
Speaker 3:  thigh?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's too big for a pocket. So you just kind of wrap it around your
Speaker 4:  thigh.
Speaker 3:  That experience of writing the review that everyone disagrees with and then
Speaker 3:  being fully vindicated by it much later. The longer it
Speaker 3:  takes, the better it is. I'm just telling you like you had 24 hours,
Speaker 3:  I'm, I'm reading they cut Vision Pro production this week and I'm like
Speaker 3:  told you so
Speaker 3:  yeah. So that's the iPad mini. You get one scroll away. Let us know
Speaker 3:  what you think if, if like motion smoothing, it's the thing you start to
Speaker 3:  see and then you blame us forever. That's not our fault.
Speaker 4:  If, you don't see jelly scrolling. Don't run the test and
Speaker 4:  just believe that I'm wrong. Like truly your life will be better If. you
Speaker 4:  just send me a mean message about how I'm wrong and then move on with your
Speaker 4:  life. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  There's nothing worse you can do for yourself than learn how to evaluate
Speaker 3:  screens.
Speaker 4:  That's really true. This is why Neli has been so ruined.
Speaker 3:  Why am I a cranky monster?
Speaker 4:  And Richard, for that matter, both of you are pixel, like pixel true pixel
Speaker 4:  monster. You
Speaker 3:  Should not do it. Yeah, yeah. It's why are Richard and I trauma
Speaker 3:  bonded for life? We can look at screens.
Speaker 3:  Okay, so that's the, I've had many, we can set that aside. Although please
Speaker 3:  continue sending David notes about the words jelly scrolling. That's very
Speaker 3:  good. Then there's what's going on with like this next week of
Speaker 3:  announcements to come, which it seems like Apple has
Speaker 3:  very purposefully lined up a bunch of things in a way
Speaker 3:  that I, I don't wanna say it's confusing, it's just noisy,
Speaker 3:  right? Like there's just a lot of Apple noise coming next week. There's Apple
Speaker 3:  intelligence launching, there's a week of Mac announcements.
Speaker 3:  18.2 is in developer beta. I If you
Speaker 3:  were a casual, I don't know that you would understand what shipping, what's
Speaker 3:  not, what works with what, right? Because there's just gonna be this like
Speaker 3:  flood of stuff and in particular 18.1 is coming
Speaker 3:  to the phone. So now Apple intelligence really is here. But then
Speaker 3:  you're gonna see a bunch of demos of like Gen Moji, which is not only
Speaker 3:  in the developer beta for 18.2, which most people can't get, but on a wait
Speaker 3:  list inside that developer beta. Can you peel this apart for me David?
Speaker 4:  No.
Speaker 4:  And I, I honestly I have, I I think that's on purpose, right? Like
Speaker 4:  every time I watch an ad for the iPhone 16
Speaker 4:  and it's running Apple intelligence, I wanna like throw things at my tv.
Speaker 4:  It's so just disingenuous at this point to sell this stuff
Speaker 4:  based on, look, here's a Siri feature you can't use. But anyway,
Speaker 4:  So I think just to like run down the list of
Speaker 4:  stuff. And Richard, you should tell me what I'm missing because I'm, I'm
Speaker 4:  pretty sure I'm missing stuff. iOS 18.1 is
Speaker 4:  launching for real like out of beta and onto people's phones
Speaker 4:  on Monday. Yep. That's the very first run of Apple
Speaker 4:  intelligence stuff. Some of the like help me write stuff, some of the
Speaker 4:  message summaries which appear to mostly just be funny for
Speaker 4:  hilarious reasons and not actually useful in anyone's life. Did
Speaker 3:  You see the one that's ring notifications and it was summarized as five to
Speaker 3:  10 people are at your door easily The best one.
Speaker 4:  That's very good.
Speaker 3:  That's very good
Speaker 4:  There. Yeah, there's one running around that I think is like, I think it's
Speaker 4:  a, it's a joke but it's like it's a text from somebody that's like very busy
Speaker 4:  right now. Semicolon not ready for a relationship and it's like well I
Speaker 4:  got dumped I guess but so 18.1 is coming
Speaker 4:  but 18.2, which as you mentioned I think is gonna be a much bigger change
Speaker 4:  for some reasons we should get into is in developer beta now.
Speaker 4:  Which typically means we're somewhere between a few weeks and a couple of
Speaker 4:  months from shipping for real. I don't know if Apple has promised when that's
Speaker 4:  supposed to be coming. I've lost track of that timeline but it's basically
Speaker 4:  all supposed to happen somewhere between right now and like spring. So
Speaker 4:  do it that which you will
Speaker 3:  But 18.2 seems like the real iOS 18.
Speaker 3:  That's what I that that's what I'm getting about by how noisy next week is
Speaker 3:  going to be. We don't know what week of Mac news is coming.
Speaker 3:  We can guess right? There's been a lot of leaks. I think we're gonna get
Speaker 3:  M four MacBook Pros. I think we're gonna get this new Mac mini that's
Speaker 3:  in a much smaller case that looks like an Apple TV
Speaker 3:  that maybe some other Macs but like maybe the Smac the people
Speaker 3:  have been talking about, I don't know but like so there's a week of Mac news
Speaker 3:  to come. So a bunch of Apple noise
Speaker 3:  which is great. I'm actually, if they do a Apple, if you're listening If
Speaker 3:  you do a 32 and chime mac, I'll buy that thing tomorrow. Just saying jaws.
Speaker 3:  So that's great. So like dead ahead Mac News there are New Macs, they look
Speaker 3:  different, at least in the case of Mac Mini we'll generate some headlines
Speaker 3:  then on Monday you get iOS 18.1 is here, apple intelligence
Speaker 3:  is here and then what actually people will have on their phones
Speaker 3:  is almost nothing, right? Like truly almost nothing.
Speaker 3:  It's message summaries. A little bit of help me write, it's a new
Speaker 3:  Siri animation that isn't connected to an actual new Siri. Weird.
Speaker 3:  Yeah that's just weird all the way around. Yes. But then what people
Speaker 3:  also see if they go to any tech website including our own, is a bunch of
Speaker 3:  coverage of 18.2 which is now out which has the features people want and
Speaker 3:  not just the AI features. People want like big features, people want like
Speaker 3:  alternative browsers set as default alternative message clients
Speaker 3:  set as default, other browser engines being able to set
Speaker 3:  web apps on the home screen in the eu like big sweeping changes
Speaker 3:  to iOS 18. And then also the the good
Speaker 3:  Apple intelligence features like visual intelligence in Gen
Speaker 3:  Moji like things at chat GPT integration,
Speaker 3:  the stuff that people thought would be there from the beginning. So I. That
Speaker 3:  just feels like a lot of stuff to parse out at once.
Speaker 4:  My ongoing theory about Apple intelligence is that the only
Speaker 4:  three features most people will like think are
Speaker 4:  cool and get excited about are gen moji. Which I
Speaker 4:  actually think is gonna be a big deal. I think like it might be
Speaker 4:  sticky but I think a lot of people are going use it in the way that like,
Speaker 4:  I dunno if this has been y'all's experience but like tap back emoji now are
Speaker 4:  like completely normalized in my life. Like the every, everyone I text with
Speaker 4:  uses the tap backs now, which I think is awesome. And like that is
Speaker 4:  the gen moji is like the next step to that, which I think is
Speaker 4:  gonna be cool. By
Speaker 3:  The way, can I just say I desperately wish email had tap backs?
Speaker 4:  Yes it is. It is such good messaging
Speaker 4:  ui like bring it everywhere. Let me like an email like and let them
Speaker 4:  see that I liked the email So I can just be like, yep, I read it. Please
Speaker 4:  don't follow up again. Like we're
Speaker 3:  Good when If you ever liked an email?
Speaker 4:  That's fair.
Speaker 3:  Well no
Speaker 4:  Thumbs down an email.
Speaker 3:  You know everybody watched the show The Bear and then everyone went through
Speaker 3:  the phase where they talked like a Chicago line cook for like a summer and
Speaker 3:  heard the word heard is just a IRL tap back.
Speaker 3:  That's all it is. Yeah. And that's all I want do with most of my email
Speaker 3:  is just signify receipt. Yep. Yeah, I I see what you
Speaker 3:  said here. I have no further reactions.
Speaker 3:  That's it. That's nothing. You are getting nothing else from me.
Speaker 4:  What is the emoji for that? Is it the, is it the face that's not smiling
Speaker 4:  or frowning? It's just the, the
Speaker 3:  Co neutral face That's that face is theater. Mm.
Speaker 4:  So then what's the, what's the, is it just a, is it just a here by
Speaker 3:  The way that's true that he sent me that emoji more than anyone else in my
Speaker 3:  entire life.
Speaker 3:  No, I don't think there is one. You just need a like a check.
Speaker 3:  That's the one I'm
Speaker 4:  Check is good. I use the raise hands emoji for that a lot.
Speaker 3:  That's horrible. That's like a celebration.
Speaker 3:  No, no, no that's good. That's what it's for. Yeah, the raised hands.
Speaker 4:  Hands raised hands can be like oh thank you. Or it can just be like, got
Speaker 4:  it. Or it can just be like sick.
Speaker 3:  I'm under arrest.
Speaker 4:  It's just a, it's a sort of, I'm under arrest. It's just, it's just
Speaker 4:  acknowledgement. That's all it is.
Speaker 3:  If, you think raised hands is, I'm so confused. A lot of our conver,
Speaker 3:  I have to rethink a lot of our conversations.
Speaker 4:  Do you think? I'm telling you, I'm being arrested every time.
Speaker 3:  All right so Jen Moji tap backs of being arrested are coming to iOS 18.2.
Speaker 3:  That's where we're getting.
Speaker 4:  But yeah, anyway, so Gen Moji is, is the first thing I think people are gonna
Speaker 4:  care about. That is actually like a net new thing. The second one is chat
Speaker 4:  GPT, which I think it remains to be seen if that's actually going
Speaker 4:  to really be baked into iOS in a way that people care about right now.
Speaker 4:  It seems kind of clunky but it is a thing people will like go find and do
Speaker 4:  on purpose. Yeah. And then the third one is visual intelligence, especially
Speaker 4:  because of the camera control. So I, I totally agree with you that like the
Speaker 4:  first sincerely new Apple intelligence things
Speaker 4:  are all in 18.2 and they're also
Speaker 4:  pretty big complicated things. So I would not be shocked to see this in a
Speaker 4:  dev beta longer than some features we've seen from iOS before.
Speaker 3:  But also the part where 18.2 everywhere
Speaker 3:  including the United States, lets you set default phone and messaging apps
Speaker 3:  is a big change to iOS. And that's 18.2, the part of
Speaker 3:  18.2 where the beginnings of different browser
Speaker 3:  engines in the EU huge like earth shattering change
Speaker 3:  to iOS 18.2. Richard,
Speaker 4:  What do you know about how this is actually gonna work? Because I'm skeptical
Speaker 4:  of this being actually a big deal
Speaker 5:  In terms of the browser changes and the default changing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like what does that mean when you do that? Do we know anything? The
Speaker 5:  Way that I am reading it is that you will actually be able to have a different
Speaker 5:  browser and engine and because what what we've had so far is people, you
Speaker 5:  can have Chrome on your iPhone, right? But it's still safari underneath,
Speaker 5:  right? It just looks a little different. But you can a If, you can actually
Speaker 5:  have your own your own browsing engine. You can have a lot more features.
Speaker 5:  You can enable a lot more things than they, they are able to right now. Right
Speaker 5:  now they're limited by what Apple wants to do. I think that those are things
Speaker 5:  that, that they will be massive as they're saying they lot. But
Speaker 5:  the things that people might notice, I know at least in our newsroom, Jen
Speaker 5:  was excited seeing this announcement about the mail app having categories
Speaker 5:  like Gmail has had forever.
Speaker 3:  Yeah
Speaker 5:  Like there's on, we've seen the on device AI scanning, they talked about
Speaker 5:  how that's gonna do it. Child safety thing and iMessage. I think there are
Speaker 5:  gonna be a lot more like kind of small features of things that it does on
Speaker 5:  the device now that just haven't been there. And those may be bigger
Speaker 5:  than any of the Apple intelligence features right away.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I think upgrading the apps people use, yeah that's always
Speaker 3:  better than use a new thing, right? Like If, you use mail every day
Speaker 3:  and now mail has new features, you'll be happy. I'm just getting at the idea
Speaker 3:  that iOS 18.2 is gonna fast follow
Speaker 3:  18.1 when it is actually full of huge changes. Yeah. To how
Speaker 3:  iOS works and Apple Intelligence, the the first
Speaker 3:  real set of Apple intelligence features, I just suspect that one's gonna
Speaker 3:  be longer in the future. And then we're gonna talk about AI agents and stuff
Speaker 3:  in the second section 'cause there's a bunch of that news. But you
Speaker 3:  know, the real promise of Apple intelligence is a sir that is actually smart
Speaker 3:  and can do things for you. And that is a million years away from what I can
Speaker 3:  tell.
Speaker 4:  Yes it is not. It is not here. We can say that with great
Speaker 4:  confidence but the thing on the defaults that I can't figure out is
Speaker 4:  I think a, the browser thing is very cool
Speaker 4:  in theory but Thomas Ricker pointed out this morning that it's been
Speaker 4:  nine months and no one has built the browser. So like
Speaker 4:  Google and Mozilla like where you at friends build us, build
Speaker 4:  us the better browser prove to us this will actually work. And the second
Speaker 4:  one I really wanna know is about messaging apps. 'cause I actually think
Speaker 4:  being able to change your default messaging app on iOS could be like
Speaker 4:  massively consequential but only If.
Speaker 4:  you can do SMS and RRCs in the US on those
Speaker 4:  things. Yep. Like what this will mean for a lot of people, especially in
Speaker 4:  the EU is that when you tap a phone number it'll go to WhatsApp, right? Like
Speaker 4:  that's a, that's a big victory for all those people and I think is like a
Speaker 4:  pretty neat sort of one-to-one mapping of
Speaker 4:  features that is just, it just makes more sense, right? Like that is instead
Speaker 4:  of having to copy it and then paste it, you just tap it and it'll go to
Speaker 4:  WhatsApp. That's great for me personally and for people in the US the question
Speaker 4:  is can ISMS from another app and I'm assuming the answer is no
Speaker 4:  and until you can, the default is sort of
Speaker 4:  meaningless. So my, my theory as to why Apple is willing
Speaker 4:  to do this everywhere specifically with messaging is that it actually
Speaker 4:  isn't gonna do very much.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Apple always gives up the ones that it's like fine. Yeah, right. You
Speaker 3:  wanna leave on, you can leave on us. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Do you wanna switch to a browser engine that doesn't exist or like go use
Speaker 4:  a messaging app that's worse, knock yourself out
Speaker 3:  The browser one in particular is interesting because
Speaker 3:  you know the Safari team will be upset that I say this because I say it a
Speaker 3:  lot and they're always upset. But Apple has intentionally limited
Speaker 3:  what Safari can do on the phone to keep web apps from
Speaker 3:  competing with app store apps. That is real like yeah
Speaker 3:  that is in the heart of the Department of Justice's
Speaker 3:  antitrust case against Apple. Evidence of that is presented and
Speaker 3:  every browser maker will tell you we would love to do more things
Speaker 3:  on the, on the phone browser and let web apps flourish like they have on
Speaker 3:  the desktop. But there's only Safari and Apple has
Speaker 3:  carefully calibrated Safari at exactly the level they need to
Speaker 3:  to keep everyone away until, I dunno the DOJ woke up and filed a lawsuit.
Speaker 3:  So things like game streaming, Microsoft really
Speaker 3:  wanted to do that. They tried to do it in the web browser, If you will recall.
Speaker 3:  And they just kinda like couldn't get there. Like it's not compelling. The
Speaker 3:  apps don't feel like real Apps Safari will just like be like, you know what,
Speaker 3:  I'm outta memory shut everything down. Like there's a million things that
Speaker 3:  are a problem there. So the idea that Chrome can show up
Speaker 3:  and build, let you build real web apps inside of Chrome or
Speaker 3:  Chrome will be more powerful. All of that is great. But then the reality
Speaker 3:  of it's still a mobile phone, it still has a battery, it still has a limited
Speaker 3:  amount of Ram, it's still often on a cellular connection. I think
Speaker 3:  those, those things are real, you know, there's meaningfully real
Speaker 3:  and I think that a lot of people are taking a lot of time with it. And then
Speaker 3:  on top of it, who do you really want here? You want Google to show up with
Speaker 3:  Chrome and Google and Apple are currently in a
Speaker 3:  international regulatory dog fight about how much Google
Speaker 3:  pays Apple to be the default. And then opening up a
Speaker 3:  new sphere of competition for applications in
Speaker 3:  the app store versus WebKit versus Blink web apps. I mean I,
Speaker 3:  that seems like Google would have to give up
Speaker 3:  negotiating with Apple in the future, right? In like a very real way. Do
Speaker 3:  you know what I mean? Like Google's like screw it, here's Chrome
Speaker 3:  on the iPhone. You can run web abstinent that are great,
Speaker 3:  this will disrupt the iOS app store. It feels like
Speaker 3:  that is a move that's nuclear enough to foreclose any amount of future
Speaker 3:  Google Apple negotiating, which they need to do because Google is
Speaker 3:  about to be forced to stop paying Apple billions of dollars a year to be
Speaker 3:  the default search. All very complicated.
Speaker 4:  It's essentially like a declaration of war if Google does that. And, and
Speaker 4:  the thing I keep thinking about is from the search trial, one of the things
Speaker 4:  that Apple was really worried about with Google and their
Speaker 4:  deal was that if Apple didn't set Google as the
Speaker 4:  default, Google had a bunch of apps on the iPhone that were
Speaker 4:  super popular and it was really worried that Google would just start getting
Speaker 4:  people to use the Google app and that because it had such a
Speaker 4:  wide surface. Like if Google put a banner at the top of YouTube and Gmail
Speaker 4:  and Docs and everything else that they have on the iPhone
Speaker 4:  saying download the Google app and do all of your searching there, it could
Speaker 4:  do that. Like Google could engineer scale in that way
Speaker 4:  unlike almost any other company. And Apple was really worried about that
Speaker 4:  happening if they took Google out of the default position in Safari.
Speaker 4:  This is the, this is the inverse of that, right? What Google could say is
Speaker 4:  now you can run full featured Chrome
Speaker 4:  web apps, which have become very powerful in the last few years
Speaker 4:  as progressive web apps on your phone like Google. It could essentially like
Speaker 4:  undo the whole app store model under this new system.
Speaker 4:  And if in a purely competitive world that is obviously what Google would
Speaker 4:  try to do right? Is say don't don't download apps from the app store and
Speaker 4:  give up 30%, just install the app running on Blink and chromium
Speaker 4:  because now you can on your iPhone and that would,
Speaker 4:  that would put these two companies at like incredible odds with each other.
Speaker 4:  But is also if there weren't many billions of dollars between the two of
Speaker 4:  them, exactly what Google would do.
Speaker 3:  And that is the heart of the DOJ case against Apple. Right? Totally. Like
Speaker 3:  inside of that case that the thing that that lawsuit
Speaker 3:  claims like at its core is, well web apps did this
Speaker 3:  to Windows, there's a reason they haven't done it to phones, right? And it's
Speaker 3:  not battery life, it's because Apple has kept blah blah blah blah blah. We'll
Speaker 3:  see it. It's like, it's very funny to go from, you can install native web
Speaker 3:  apps in iOS 18.2 to look at this thicket of
Speaker 3:  lawsuits. But that's really what's happening here. Like that thicket of
Speaker 3:  lawsuits is directly impacting how these products are signed. Yeah, I think
Speaker 3:  it is also, we should just talk about this Tim Cook, big
Speaker 3:  Tim Cook interview in the Wall Street Journal magazine. 'cause it's a big
Speaker 3:  argument for being, I think his, his quote is
Speaker 3:  best not first.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Right. Like he, he's like, we'll make the best products, not the first products.
Speaker 3:  And that is in reference to the Vision Pro, which we should talk about for
Speaker 3:  one second. And definitely in reference to ai,
Speaker 3:  right? He is like, we're not first outta the gate but we're gonna do the
Speaker 3:  best with these over time. These are our big bets with the Vision Pro. He
Speaker 3:  basically is like, here's how I use it. I lie flat on my back on the couch
Speaker 3:  and I watch tv. It's a real quote. Fun
Speaker 4:  Fact. That's how Richard watches TV too.
Speaker 3:  And he is like at 3,500 not Division Pro. Yeah. At
Speaker 3:  $3,500. It's not a mainstream device. Fine. Right? Like they took a shot
Speaker 3:  on a weird product and whatever and they did admit there was a VR headset,
Speaker 3:  fine, they're gonna make a cheaper one with ai. It's like,
Speaker 3:  I get that you're saying, you know, you wanna be the best thing and you certainly
Speaker 3:  have the distribution advantage 'cause you, you have the iPhone, you can
Speaker 3:  just get it in front of more people fastest. But If, you looked around
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 3:  This week philanthropic is saying Claude can now just
Speaker 3:  use computers for you. Like there's just a, there's
Speaker 3:  the level of innovation in the industry is like out of control. Like
Speaker 3:  everyone is racing as fast as they can. Whether or not that's gonna come
Speaker 3:  to anything we should talk about. But it's this thing that where
Speaker 3:  Tim Cook is saying, these glimmers of Apple intelligence are evidence that
Speaker 3:  will make the best thing. I'm not, I'm just not, I'm not so sure about it.
Speaker 5:  It's evidence that they're making something now. They are sort at least in
Speaker 5:  this kind of artificial intelligence race that Google and Microsoft and everyone
Speaker 5:  have been just driving forward over the last, I guess year, 18 months now.
Speaker 5:  But it, I I think that's the question. Is it any good? Is it what people
Speaker 5:  want? Is it going to do something other than generate a new emoji
Speaker 5:  that you'll send to only other people with iPhones?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I dunno.
Speaker 5:  Is it gonna kill your battery? We don't know that
Speaker 3:  Part actually. We, we definitely do not know. Like If, you make Gen Moji
Speaker 3:  all day, are you gonna destroy a battery? David will soon find out.
Speaker 4:  And also potentially the world. Yeah, I I don't know. I I
Speaker 4:  read a lot of this Wall Street Journal piece is like, what else is Tim Cook
Speaker 4:  supposed to say? Right? Like seriously, I i, I don't even, I don't even blame
Speaker 4:  the guy like this is
Speaker 4:  seven months ago he was telling everybody how he liked to do everything in
Speaker 4:  addition Pro. Like this is just what you do. And I think Apple
Speaker 4:  is in a position now where it is forced
Speaker 4:  to try to make the case that this stuff is really great. So Tim Cook is waking
Speaker 4:  is saying he like wakes up in the morning and checks his email and having
Speaker 4:  summaries of his emails as a game changer. Like, I just don't believe that
Speaker 4:  like maybe having a bunch of emails
Speaker 4:  slightly better triaged for you is a game changer in your life.
Speaker 4:  I don't think that's true for very many people.
Speaker 3:  Can you imagine If, you were an Apple executive and you're like, this
Speaker 3:  email got summarized. Yeah, Tim Cook didn't read my shit.
Speaker 5:  I think, I think Tim Cook can afford an assistant. Like if, if that were
Speaker 5:  the game, if that were truly the game changer that he needed, what has he
Speaker 5:  been doing until now and why has someone not been summarizing Tim Cook's
Speaker 5:  emails for
Speaker 5:  like, like how much value have Apple shareholders lost? Because Tim
Speaker 5:  Cook insisted on reading every word of every email for the last 10 years.
Speaker 5:  Well,
Speaker 3:  No, he's famous. He's he's one of the CEOs who's famous for reading customer
Speaker 3:  emails and like forwarding 'em off. But you emailed Tim Cook in like
Speaker 3:  some Apple SVP three layers down the chain. We'll write back to you
Speaker 3:  because he'll, he'll do that. I don't know if he does it the way that Jeff Bezos
Speaker 3:  used to do it, which is forward the email to a deputy with just a question
Speaker 3:  mark. Like just
Speaker 4:  At, at like all hours of the day at night. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  What is this? Which is truly incredible. Why am I getting this email? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Do you think Tim cooks his enterprise software at work?
Speaker 3:  No. I'm just asking like, has this man ever logged into Con Concur? No.
Speaker 3:  Do you think he knows his frequent flyer number? He has a plane.
Speaker 4:  I was gonna say bet he does. I bet he knows his United number.
Speaker 3:  No way. He has a,
Speaker 4:  Because Apple famously has like a big thing with United
Speaker 3:  For people who are not Tim Cook Apple's famous thing with United is they
Speaker 3:  own a plane and sometimes they say the word united on it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's, that's reasonable.
Speaker 3:  I'm reading this profile and I'm looking at the two big product
Speaker 3:  launches this year. And the profile is very much about Tim Cook making big
Speaker 3:  bets, right? And it's okay, the Vision Pro whatever you, you
Speaker 3:  gotta put one foot in front of the other and yes, the meta glasses exist
Speaker 3:  and yes, the Quest three s is even cheaper than before. Whatever.
Speaker 3:  It's much more like, his argument is we will
Speaker 3:  eventually do this best and that will win. And I actually don't know if that
Speaker 3:  is the case right now for in these two categories.
Speaker 5:  Well, his argument for the Vision Pro is that they're getting this started
Speaker 5:  for the developers. They're getting the ecosystem kickstarted
Speaker 5:  and that, you know, the, these early adopters, the people who are going to
Speaker 5:  make things are getting into it. But I'm not seeing that yet. I'm not seeing
Speaker 5:  the, the people who are making and using these tools and that, that that's
Speaker 5:  kicking a flywheel of innovation that's gonna help them make something that
Speaker 5:  someone else will use years from now. Have we actually gotten anywhere with
Speaker 5:  this $3,500 device?
Speaker 4:  Isn't that also the opposite of the best not first strategy?
Speaker 4:  Like yes.
Speaker 3:  There
Speaker 4:  Nothing, nothing about the Vision Pro suggests. Best not first.
Speaker 4:  Nothing.
Speaker 5:  $3,500.
Speaker 3:  3,500.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Seven outta 10,
Speaker 3:  God dammit. All right. He said one other thing in this profile that I just
Speaker 3:  want, I want to sit with for a second. He said he
Speaker 3:  uses every Apple product every day, every product, every day. That's a
Speaker 3:  quote Our own West Davis tried to figure out how you would do
Speaker 3:  that. Apple makes a lot of products. Wes owns a lot of them, including
Speaker 3:  a 3,500 vision pro. And I would say that he, he,
Speaker 3:  he made a valiant effort and failed because there
Speaker 3:  are too many Apple products. Like using every kind of iPad in a
Speaker 3:  single day is not a good idea.
Speaker 4:  It's not just that there are too many Apple products, it's that they overlap
Speaker 4:  in complicated ways, right? So that, like, even even
Speaker 4:  Cook's thing is he, he claims to have an a
Speaker 4:  MacBook Air, a MacBook Pro and an iMac at the office and
Speaker 4:  like God help you If you try to use all three of those devices during a
Speaker 4:  single workday. Like how, what?
Speaker 3:  Well, so that's what kicked me off. 'cause I was like, Wes, you should do
Speaker 3:  this story. 'cause it's, it's one thing If, you say, I use
Speaker 3:  every one of every kind of product we make every day, right? I use one Mac,
Speaker 3:  one iPad, one phone, one AirPods. I think that's what you use every product
Speaker 3:  every day. And then specifically calling out three Macs is like,
Speaker 3:  oh, you mean every product, right? The every, does
Speaker 4:  That that include both sizes of the Apple watch?
Speaker 3:  Both sizes, apple watch all 15 skews of the Apple
Speaker 3:  watch. Do you think he's like, well time to switch the Apple watch with cellular.
Speaker 3:  Like that's a
Speaker 3:  and I actually think the evidence is that he doesn't use most of the products
Speaker 3:  most of the time.
Speaker 5:  The number one thing that came up in the comments was this guy does not use
Speaker 5:  Apple Home. There's no one,
Speaker 3:  Right?
Speaker 5:  No one believes it.
Speaker 4:  No. Tim Cook's a Sonos guy. Let's be real with each other. He's definitely
Speaker 4:  a Sonos guy.
Speaker 3:  He'd buy it. Well, Sonos supports airplay.
Speaker 3:  Joanna CERN interviewed Craig Federighi at Wall Street Journal Tech Live
Speaker 3:  this week. You can watch that. She has some Apple intelligence and two things
Speaker 3:  she said of note related to that, Richard, she asked him about Siri
Speaker 3:  and he said, I use Siri every day. Siri serves
Speaker 3:  1.5 billion queries a day, which is an interesting number we should come
Speaker 3:  back to. And he said, I use it to open my garage. Which
Speaker 3:  is fine, implies that Craig Feder has a home
Speaker 3:  kit garage door opener, which is challenging actually
Speaker 3:  for a variety of ways. And that he does not,
Speaker 3:  he chooses to say, Siri open the garage every single day
Speaker 3:  instead of just pressing a button
Speaker 3:  as somebody with two different kinds of home kit garage door openers. I love
Speaker 3:  the idea of Apple's SVP of all software
Speaker 3:  going on Amazon and ordering a $30 Mi Ross garage door opener and wiring
Speaker 3:  it into a thing like I love it with all of
Speaker 3:  my heart. And I, I'm absolutely certain that did not happen. I don't
Speaker 3:  know how he's opening his garage door home kit, but that's the way you do
Speaker 3:  it. And I just, I love the idea of him being like, my ecosystem is
Speaker 3:  working while he's like screwing the thing into the terminals.
Speaker 4:  I wonder if it Apple, when you get like promoted to SVP
Speaker 4:  instead of getting, you know, a a a Rolex or a company car
Speaker 4:  or whatever, they just hand you a giant box full of Apple
Speaker 4:  connected gear and they're like, you have to have this in your house now.
Speaker 4:  Like this is, this is the setup. Yeah. Welcome.
Speaker 3:  You're now in charge, you're in home kit. Now you're actually, I, you know,
Speaker 3:  as somebody who runs HomeBridge to bridge a lot of stuff into
Speaker 3:  HomeKit, I know that a lot of the people who work on HomeKit at
Speaker 3:  Apple also run HomeBridge. This is a real thing, huh?
Speaker 3:  Like a lot of HomeKit engineers are like, yep, we're gonna build the plugins
Speaker 3:  to integrate rings. It's a real thing. And If, you are those
Speaker 3:  people. Let us know 'cause I have a number of feature requests for you. And
Speaker 3:  also I just wanna say thank you.
Speaker 3:  I don't know, I don't know that you can use every Apple product every day.
Speaker 3:  But If you are listening to this and you, you can figure it out. Send us
Speaker 3:  your chart. We'll read the chart next week. That's all I really wanna say.
Speaker 3:  We
Speaker 4:  Think Tim is mostly an iPad guy, right? Tim? Tim in my head, Tim is an
Speaker 4:  iPad guy.
Speaker 3:  Tim has got it figured out. He's circling things in red and sending PDFs
Speaker 3:  back to people. Okay. All right. We gotta take a break. If you again. If.
Speaker 3:  you can figure it out. Let me know. We're
Speaker 3:  This is gonna be incredible. Get ready Richard. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. We're gonna let AI drive this segment. It's gonna
Speaker 3:  be great. Take it away. Claude.
Speaker 4:  Hello. Welcome to just,
Speaker 3:  We should let Notebook LM do a segment that should, that's a pretty good
Speaker 3:  gimmick
Speaker 4:  Actually. That is actually fun. Maybe I'll do that for the next one. I'll
Speaker 4:  just upload all the stuff in our rundown to Notebook lm and let it make the
Speaker 4:  podcast and then we'll run it. 'cause it makes like a 12 minute podcast.
Speaker 4:  We'll run it at the end of an episode and people can decide which one they
Speaker 4:  like better.
Speaker 3:  That's actually pretty good. We'll do that. I will say that the chances that
Speaker 3:  that is a more evenly
Speaker 3:  paced Vergecast is very high.
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  More focused. Anyway. Do
Speaker 4:  They have more catchphrases than Eli is really the question That's
Speaker 3:  Absolutely not. So there's a lot of AI news this week. The
Speaker 3:  big theme is that everyone figured out that chatbots aren't
Speaker 3:  gonna make them enough money. And so now we have to build robots that can
Speaker 3:  take actions on our computer. Is that about right David?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think there's, there's basically like two big pieces
Speaker 4:  of AI news this week, which is
Speaker 4:  we have to give AI more stuff to do and then, oh
Speaker 4:  God, what if we give AI more stuff to do? Let's sue the AI
Speaker 4:  companies. So I'd say those are the two things. So let's, let's just take
Speaker 4:  them one at a time. The biggest news
Speaker 4:  I would say in terms of like things that got the AI people excited
Speaker 4:  was the new update to Claude, which is Anthropics
Speaker 4:  chatbot. It's, it's it's competitor to GPT-4 Oh and Llama and whatever
Speaker 4:  else it can now use a computer for you.
Speaker 4:  They, they released a very cool demo video, which is just one of the
Speaker 4:  researchers sitting there and he basically opens up a, a spreadsheet and
Speaker 4:  is like, Hey, I need you to pull data out of this and put it into an email
Speaker 4:  for me. And it goes through and it clicks around and it says, oh, I can't
Speaker 4:  find this data in here. So it opens, I think it's like a vendor software
Speaker 4:  thing, searches through that, finds the information, puts it where it's,
Speaker 4:  the idea is that it can actually click around and look at and use your computer
Speaker 4:  and pull data from it. It was actually tracking what it was doing as it was
Speaker 4:  going. So it was saying like, I hit the page down button and I put the cursor
Speaker 4:  over here and I typed this into the, seems to work very well. It is
Speaker 4:  one demo and it's not a product that Anthropic is shipping. It's a
Speaker 4:  thing in the API that other people can build on top of.
Speaker 3:  I've already seen someone build an app that can sort of do this on a Mac.
Speaker 3:  Oh
Speaker 4:  Really? Yep.
Speaker 3:  Sort of.
Speaker 4:  I I will say Anthropic is productizing,
Speaker 4:  its AI better and faster than any of its competitors right now in a way
Speaker 4:  that I think is really interesting. But that is, that is the thing,
Speaker 4:  right? That's what everyone is out there trying to build that it, it's a
Speaker 4:  more elegant version essentially of what Rabbit is doing with the large action
Speaker 4:  model. I mean, it's the same thing. It just clicks around a webpage for you.
Speaker 5:  I mean, is Rabbit doing it? They they said they would do it and they have
Speaker 5:  built something that does something and some people have tried it and
Speaker 5:  it does mostly nothing but some things.
Speaker 3:  I'm
Speaker 4:  Sorry, they've built something that does something and so people have tried
Speaker 4:  it is the AI industry,
Speaker 3:  Right?
Speaker 5:  Can you actually do anything useful with what they built? No,
Speaker 3:  I, yes. I, we again, we, we, the CEO of Rabbit on decoder, you can
Speaker 3:  listen to it. They're at a very different spot than
Speaker 3:  Anthropic. and we had Mike Krieger, who's the head of product at Philanthropic.
Speaker 3:  And your point about they're better at productizing is because they have
Speaker 3:  a great product person. Yeah. And all the AI companies are trying
Speaker 3:  to hire product people.
Speaker 4:  I hire Kevin Wheel, who's done a bunch of really interesting product stuff
Speaker 4:  for social companies over the years. Like this is the playbook now everybody's
Speaker 4:  after this.
Speaker 3:  And so the, and the, the first product everyone's thinking of is beyond a
Speaker 3:  chatbot, what can we do? And it appears to be
Speaker 3:  super Siri, right? Like the thing that everyone is
Speaker 3:  trying to build is the ultimate Google assistant or super Siri or this
Speaker 3:  vision that everybody had when Alexa first hit the scene ages ago,
Speaker 3:  which is you're gonna talk to the computer and the computer's gonna do stuff,
Speaker 3:  and then the sort of how underneath this user story,
Speaker 3:  no one could do forever, right? Like, well, here's what Alexa can do.
Speaker 3:  You can play music and set timers and not much else. Here's what Siri can
Speaker 3:  do, apparently open Craig Federer's garage door. That's what
Speaker 3:  it can do. But then you, because it can't understand actual language,
Speaker 3:  you're stuck it, you have to write every query
Speaker 3:  and match every query. Now you can understand actual language. Now you gotta
Speaker 3:  do the next thing. And then the solution seems to be we'll just have it
Speaker 3:  use a computer to do that for you. And then AI will
Speaker 3:  solve that problem too.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And it's actually the, the, I encourage everyone to watch the Anthropic
Speaker 4:  video because it's actually sort of inadvertently a really
Speaker 4:  interesting breakdown of how this tech works. Like it essentially just goes
Speaker 4:  through and takes a series of screenshots and OCR is the information
Speaker 4:  out of the screenshots and then says, oh, I don't have what I need from this
Speaker 4:  screenshot, but I see, I, I see from the scroll bar, I can page down or I
Speaker 4:  see there's a thing over there. Like the, the key here is
Speaker 4:  basically taking this thing that people know how to do,
Speaker 4:  but is very complicated to teach computers and just
Speaker 4:  breaking it down to a bunch of very simple things, which is like, look for
Speaker 4:  this number next to this name. And If, you don't see the name search
Speaker 4:  for it in this, like, it's actually a bunch of pretty discreet steps.
Speaker 4:  It's just very hard to explain to a computer in an efficient way. But like
Speaker 4:  you said, now that a computer can understand
Speaker 4:  language and images, essentially all you have to do is figure out a way to
Speaker 4:  keep feeding it language and images and it can do something with it. And
Speaker 4:  I think like the Anthropic video was the most convinced I've been that
Speaker 4:  this is doable because it's like, here's just a bunch of screenshots. And
Speaker 4:  it's like, it's the same thing that Microsoft is pitching with recall. And
Speaker 4:  we've seen from some startups and stuff that, like If, you just turn
Speaker 4:  the universe into a series of screenshots. AI can
Speaker 4:  actually make a lot out of that for you.
Speaker 5:  Well, it's not that far off from the way that autonomous vehicles work. I
Speaker 5:  mean, they, they're not necessarily looking at things the way that a driver
Speaker 5:  does, but they're taking these, these pictures many, many, many times a second.
Speaker 5:  Totally. And reacting based on that. And it's just doing this on a computer,
Speaker 5:  which to some extent more and less complicated because of the way things
Speaker 5:  are already labeled.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It, it is amazing to me how many people building all kinds of
Speaker 4:  AI products I talk to who just want to use the self-driving
Speaker 4:  car metaphor. It's very funny. And I think you're right, it is, it is a really
Speaker 4:  similar problem. It's also a really similar like challenge over
Speaker 4:  time to get from like very good to perfect. But it is
Speaker 4:  like I, you're totally right. I think that's exactly the right comparison.
Speaker 3:  The really interesting thing on the computer side
Speaker 3:  is self-driving cars can't like be recursive in that particular way.
Speaker 3:  The most interesting Claude demo I saw was Claude asking itself
Speaker 3:  to generate code to solve a problem.
Speaker 4:  Whoa. You can Claude with Claude.
Speaker 3:  So it's like, you're like, do you solve this problem for me? And it's like,
Speaker 3:  okay, the best thing I know how to do is open a web browser, open Claude,
Speaker 3:  ask prompt myself, get an answer. Wow. And like,
Speaker 3:  that is really clever. You know, there's all these benchmarks that
Speaker 3:  candidly, I, I, I think are too early in the world of
Speaker 3:  AI benchmarks to mean anything. But they're like, here's a test we ran that,
Speaker 3:  that humans score 70% on Claude is at like seven. You know,
Speaker 3:  like yeah, it's nowhere, but it's, it's, it's
Speaker 3:  twice as good as the next nearest thing. And then Rabbit is like,
Speaker 3:  we we're not doing a good job with Spotify.
Speaker 3:  Sorry, I'm gonna get another angry email. I can, who is doing a good job
Speaker 3:  with Spotify? Can you use Spotify? Well, I think we were all older, about
Speaker 3:  7% using Spotify. Spotify is like, it's a podcast.
Speaker 3:  Like that's not what I wanted. But the, the idea that the
Speaker 3:  computer will figure out how to use itself is powerful. The idea that the,
Speaker 3:  the computer can generically use any computer and reason its way
Speaker 3:  to, I should just use Claude to solve this powerful. And then underneath
Speaker 3:  it is,
Speaker 3:  I think just a, like the industry has to come to grips with the idea that
Speaker 3:  we're, we're not programming computers anymore. Like
Speaker 3:  an API is the best way to use Spotify. Yeah. Right. Like there's
Speaker 3:  a lot of tasks where just telling the computer what to do and having it do
Speaker 3:  it deterministically is the correct solution. And we're headed towards a
Speaker 3:  place where a robot taking an infinite
Speaker 3:  number of screenshots of a Windows desktop clicking on stuff
Speaker 3:  is the, is gonna support the billion dollar valuations of the AI
Speaker 3:  companies. And it's like, I don't actually know about, I don't, I don't know
Speaker 3:  about that. I, I don't know. It's probably broken and I don't believe you.
Speaker 4:  Well this is, this is a good pivot into the humane stuff, which
Speaker 4:  is the other kind of, I don't know, agent might
Speaker 4:  even be too kind to what Humane is trying to do.
Speaker 3:  I mean every company's doing Microsoft announced some agency stuff this week.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. In response to the Anthropic News and some of the Microsoft News
Speaker 3:  OpenAI leaked out that it's working on some agent stuff. Like again,
Speaker 3:  the future of Siri that they have described is a,
Speaker 3:  the, the, I'm so sorry for this word. Age agentic. Yep.
Speaker 3:  Whatever I keeps saying. So the future of Sirius age, agentic
Speaker 3:  Apple has a different way of building it. 'cause they actually have the apps
Speaker 3:  running locally in their operating system and they control the operating
Speaker 3:  system so they can, they can do more API layer stuff, but everyone's
Speaker 3:  headed here. And then Humane sort of like here they are.
Speaker 4:  You skipped right past that by the way. But that is Apple's single biggest
Speaker 4:  advantage in all of this. I'm increasingly convinced is that Apple
Speaker 4:  is going to, with the new Siri, just launch a thing. I think
Speaker 4:  it's either called Siri intense or app intense. And basically it, it
Speaker 4:  allows developers to open up things that Siri can go do inside
Speaker 4:  of their apps. That's the answer, right? Like the, the only
Speaker 4:  reason to go do this much more complicated deterministic thing is If.
Speaker 4:  you can't convince the world to open up a APIs to you
Speaker 4:  and Apple is maybe the only company that can just
Speaker 4:  tell developers to give it access to stuff. And most of them will do it.
Speaker 4:  And I think
Speaker 3:  It's, it's we'll see about that. We
Speaker 4:  Will, it's, it's possible that I'm wrong, but historically speaking,
Speaker 4:  Apple is the only company on earth that tells developers to jump and they
Speaker 4:  jump And Netflix
Speaker 3:  Still
Speaker 5:  Not on Apple TV or Vision Pro or or integrated into the Apple TV app or
Speaker 5:  on Vision Pro.
Speaker 4:  True. That is true. There are not many companies as powerful as Netflix in
Speaker 4:  those negotiations. That's true. But So I think it, it's, if Apple
Speaker 4:  can do that, it puts Apple way ahead because you don't have to solve really
Speaker 4:  complicated a AI problems If, you just are handed the structured data,
Speaker 4:  then Siri has to do the beginning and end. Right. Which is understand what
Speaker 4:  you want and figure out how to go do it. Make sense of the universe is not
Speaker 4:  part of it. And that, that is the hard part. But the humane
Speaker 4:  thing is, so there were two bits of Humane news this week that I very much
Speaker 4:  enjoyed. One is that Humane drastically
Speaker 4:  cut the price of the AI pin from $699 to
Speaker 4:  $499. And if you're saying David, that sounds too expensive, is there's still
Speaker 4:  a $24 a month subscription. The answer is yes it is. There is,
Speaker 4:  but they're still here. They're still trying to ship stuff and do stuff.
Speaker 4:  And the other bit of news that has been,
Speaker 4:  it's like kind of news but kind of not news. Oh, Malick went
Speaker 4:  and met with Bethany and Iran, the co-founders and
Speaker 4:  saw their operating system, which they call Cosmos, but it's os
Speaker 4:  at the end capitalized 'cause it's an operating system. It's very good
Speaker 4:  running on a, some kind of car dashboard. It was not exactly clear,
Speaker 4:  but the idea was Humane now wants to license
Speaker 4:  its AI operating system to other
Speaker 4:  companies.
Speaker 3:  The web os story. Yes, exactly. That's what I said. This is Blackberry, it's
Speaker 3:  Palm, it's web os, you name it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. And so
Speaker 4:  a perfectly reasonable idea. I think there are a lot of
Speaker 4:  bets right now about who the AI operating system is going to be.
Speaker 4:  Every Google would
Speaker 3:  Like it to be generated. Wait, is there, is that a bet? Is that a it's, I
Speaker 3:  don't get it.
Speaker 4:  Amazon is about to spend an awful lot of money and try to
Speaker 4:  convince you to spend some money on the idea that it might be Alexa that
Speaker 4:  can underpin all of your AI devices. Google. That's what Gemini
Speaker 4:  is trying to be. I mean that's what, that's what GPT-4 oh is like, all these
Speaker 4:  companies are going to make most of their money baking their stuff into other
Speaker 4:  products. Like it it that is, that is the win here. If. you can pull it off.
Speaker 3:  That's what I mean. But that's not an os like I'm looking at this
Speaker 3:  humane image of what cause most comos,
Speaker 3:  Cosmo os, whatever it's called Cosmos.
Speaker 4:  It's called Cosmos.
Speaker 3:  Well let's, but the, the the os are is capitals. You
Speaker 4:  Just have to kind of hit it hard. You hit the last cosmos,
Speaker 4:  it's ovn like,
Speaker 3:  Like
Speaker 3:  I don't wanna talk about Ovn at this time, but so you look at their block
Speaker 3:  diagram of how Cosmos works and all they've really done is they've sort of
Speaker 3:  replaced like applications with the word agent and then added like
Speaker 3:  15 more blocks on top of that that are basically like, we
Speaker 3:  hear you speak and then we understand what you want. and we go to one of
Speaker 3:  these agents and it, the part where you replace the application layer
Speaker 3:  with agents is a, is a big deal. If that's a thing
Speaker 3:  that's gonna happen that is like a 50 year industrywide project,
Speaker 3:  not a thing. You can ship to HP to put in a car,
Speaker 3:  which is kind of what the article says is gonna
Speaker 3:  like, it's very confusing, easy. You still need
Speaker 3:  applications. Sure. Like you still need a Spotify
Speaker 3:  to exist so you can like click on it.
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  As long as you need Spotify to exist. The easiest way to play the music
Speaker 3:  is to pay Spotify money to use the API to just play the music.
Speaker 3:  Rivian ISS gonna get Apple Music. And you're like, cool. And I was like,
Speaker 3:  here's how they're gonna do it. You're gonna ask Alexa to open a web browser
Speaker 3:  and open Apple Music and click on Apple Music and App. You'd be like, what?
Speaker 3:  And I'd be like, or you can sign a deal with Apple to put the Apple Music
Speaker 3:  app running on the Rivian. Right. Which is what they did. Because that is
Speaker 3:  sane. And like I, there's no reason that
Speaker 3:  you have to give up on the way that we've run computers up until now
Speaker 3:  just because you need to license your It's I'm deeply confused by this.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I I it's, it's, I think the same argument we've had a
Speaker 4:  lot about all of these AI devices is like, isn't this just another app on
Speaker 4:  your phone? Like, is could, could an AI system
Speaker 4:  like credibly replaceable a lot of what you do in Android Auto or CarPlay
Speaker 4:  over time, like Yes, absolutely. Is is good Siri, the solution to
Speaker 4:  CarPlay a hundred percent. That is not
Speaker 4:  the future of iOS.
Speaker 4:  It, it's part of it. Right. And I think there are, there are a lot of instances
Speaker 4:  in which agents are going to be useful and powerful and valuable,
Speaker 4:  but the idea that they're going to like immediately overthrow
Speaker 4:  the whole ecosystem we currently have is just wrong.
Speaker 4:  And So, I think again, if you're, if you're an OS maker and,
Speaker 4:  and if you're humane and you're desperate to have a reason to stay alive,
Speaker 4:  you have to make this bet, right? Like the, the big swing is we are
Speaker 4:  going to be the one who controls all the agents. And If, you're the one who
Speaker 4:  controls all the agents. You, you become very powerful. The problem is there
Speaker 4:  aren't any agents. The ones that there are, aren't very good. And also no
Speaker 4:  one needs them yet. Yeah. So like, it's a, it's a tough sled.
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 5:  Think the thing I struggle with every time we we get into this discussion
Speaker 5:  or we're talking about these things is let's say that it works perfectly.
Speaker 5:  That they get all the bugs out. That it, it's smart, it's fast, it's
Speaker 5:  efficient, it's still like clicking around and using a thing. How many times
Speaker 5:  a day do you click on something and like the page doesn't load?
Speaker 5:  Like, and, and maybe they can make it smart enough to, okay, now I need to
Speaker 5:  refresh, or I got an error and I need to go back and I need to do it again.
Speaker 5:  But like, if I'm just sitting there saying, Hey man, I told you to do the
Speaker 5:  thing. And it's like, yeah, the page isn't loading. Sorry bro.
Speaker 3:  Honestly, if my computer would be more honest with me about why it's not
Speaker 3:  working in that specific way, in that specific tone that would rule.
Speaker 3:  Like it was like, I'm sorry bro, like this connection's shit,
Speaker 4:  That's what Siri should do whenever instead of being like, here's some stuff
Speaker 4:  I found on the web, it should just be like, sorry bro. I don't know. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like I,
Speaker 4:  I would like
Speaker 3:  It better. Do you have Verizon? 'cause at and t's sucking right now. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That would be, I'm incredible.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Or just
Speaker 3:  That's what AI is for.
Speaker 4:  Think for a second. And then it's just like, I don't know, does it matter?
Speaker 4:  Who
Speaker 3:  Cares? The vibes are off. The vibes are off. Vibes are off. I just like,
Speaker 3:  I'm very curious about all these like AI agents, everyone's pitching them
Speaker 3:  now because they have to like, I, I really think
Speaker 3:  the business imperative for why are we spending all this money?
Speaker 3:  Why are we running all these GPUs all day and all night is not chatbots,
Speaker 3:  it's not image generators, it's not disinformation at scale.
Speaker 4:  Like it's a little bit disinformation at scale.
Speaker 3:  That's like a, that's like fun, you know, it's like a, it's like a fun little,
Speaker 3:  it's, it's like the garnish like of the business. You know, like
Speaker 3:  do you wanna see a picture of Elon Musk jumping up and down and turning into
Speaker 3:  a monkey and then exploding? We can do that for you. Is that a business?
Speaker 3:  I don't know, like it does not appear to be paying anyone's bills,
Speaker 3:  but
Speaker 3:  I can make you an all powerful robot that can use a computer for you and
Speaker 3:  fill out and do this spreadsheet work that you don't wanna do.
Speaker 3:  Maybe maybe someone will pay a lot of money for that. And so you just like
Speaker 3:  see them charging towards, well hopefully we can pull this off.
Speaker 3:  Hopefully we can get so good at this to the business basis for it. And I
Speaker 3:  you are gonna, we're gonna cover it a lot. 'cause it, it is the dream, right?
Speaker 3:  You just talk to a computer and goes off and does something for you. I'm
Speaker 3:  just not sure any of this technology can actually pull it off yet. And then
Speaker 3:  underneath it, this is the next thing we should talk about is the fact that
Speaker 3:  all of this is built on a bunch of models that
Speaker 3:  are trained in a much of copyrighted information that none of the
Speaker 3:  lawsuits have been resolved yet and more of them show up every day. So
Speaker 3:  just this week, news Corp, which owns the Wall Street Journal and the New York
Speaker 3:  Post, it's Murdoch Empire Company,
Speaker 3:  they sued perplexity for infringing on all of its content. Perplexity gets
Speaker 3:  to their paywall. Perplexity is sad. Perplexity is sort of like
Speaker 3:  perpetually sad that it's getting sued for copyright infringement.
Speaker 4:  Perplexity is the one that Wired and Forbes and others have
Speaker 4:  repeatedly also pointed out is I think the wired headline was Perplexity
Speaker 4:  is a Bullshit Machine, which is very good. Yeah. And then wrote another story
Speaker 4:  about how Perplexity stole the story about
Speaker 4:  perplexity being a bullshit. And it was just very good.
Speaker 4:  This and Perplexity so far has basically been like, ah, it's the
Speaker 4:  internet, everything's probably fine. We can just have it. Yep. And
Speaker 4:  it's really only been a matter of time until this came for perplexity in
Speaker 4:  a pretty big way. I think it was, was it this week or last week that the
Speaker 4:  New York Times sent a cease and desist to perplexity essentially alleging
Speaker 4:  the same thing. Yep. Is that last week? It was last week. It
Speaker 3:  Was last week. and we should know the Times also sued Open ai. That's an
Speaker 3:  ongoing lawsuit. Our company, Vox Media, the business side of the company
Speaker 3:  signed a deal with OpenAI, as did Conde Nast, as did a bunch of
Speaker 3:  other publishers. Like this is in the air, like
Speaker 3:  that's a disclosure by the way. You have nothing to do with that deal. But
Speaker 3:  this is just like in the air. The Atlantic signed a deal like that. And they
Speaker 3:  actually have a cool set of open AI powered
Speaker 3:  tools on their website, one of which is just a Chrome plugin that
Speaker 3:  as you click, like as you browse the web, it shows you
Speaker 3:  relevant stories from like the 150 year history of the Atlantic. Which
Speaker 3:  is neat. Like yeah, I wouldn't read Old Atlantic stories if not for an ai.
Speaker 3:  Like it does, it works like c plus let's not get ahead of
Speaker 3:  ourselves, but like they're building stuff with it. Yeah. But this is the,
Speaker 3:  the foundation of this entire industry is like copyright infringement or
Speaker 3:  alleged copyright infringement just this week as well. Kevin Bacon, Kate
Speaker 3:  McKinnon, 11,500 other creators
Speaker 3:  just like issued a letter saying this is an unjust value
Speaker 3:  transfer. We made all this work. We, this is our life's work.
Speaker 3:  You've taken it all and now you're supporting these valuations without giving
Speaker 3:  us anything in return. You can feel about that any way you want. I know a
Speaker 3:  lot of people who feel like this is history's greatest crime and Sam Altman
Speaker 3:  should be in jail. I know those people exist because they write to us every
Speaker 3:  time we talk about this on The Vergecast, we, we welcome you here. Then there's
Speaker 3:  another group of people who say, well look, it's just a computer reading
Speaker 3:  everything in the world. The same way that If, you could read everything
Speaker 3:  in the world and then summarize iMessage notifications. You would do the
Speaker 3:  same thing, which is a stretch but also an argument you can make.
Speaker 3:  And I have no, I, this is a coin flip, pure coin flip. I have no idea how
Speaker 3:  this is gonna take off. But If, you believe that the future of Alexa and
Speaker 3:  Siri and Google Assistant and Humane and Anthropic
Speaker 3:  is do like taking a million screenshots of your computers and clicking around
Speaker 3:  for you. All of that is built on the foundation of copyright lawsuits that
Speaker 3:  have not yet been resolved in any way, shape or form. And it's kind of like,
Speaker 3:  you know, this industry is headed towards the cliff, like full cliff,
Speaker 3:  like
Speaker 4:  Yes. One way
Speaker 3:  Or another.
Speaker 4:  The one other part of this backdrop that we should talk about is
Speaker 4:  all of these companies right now are trying to raise gigantic,
Speaker 4:  astonishing amounts of money. OpenAI just raised the biggest round of
Speaker 4:  funding ever. Anthropic is out trying to raise a ton
Speaker 4:  of money. Perplexity is out trying to raise a ton of money. Like there, there's
Speaker 4:  a real sense from all of these companies that they are going to need just
Speaker 4:  vast oceans of cash to do some combination of build
Speaker 4:  God, find a way to sell this stuff to enterprise customers
Speaker 4:  and protect themselves from lawsuits. Like I, I think I
Speaker 4:  every one of these companies is trying to make the case that this
Speaker 4:  stuff is going to be so big and so lucrative in order to be
Speaker 4:  able to fund the fight to get there. And it's such a
Speaker 4:  bizarre dynamic where it's like they're simultaneously promising
Speaker 4:  how great the world is gonna be and like battening down the hatches, right?
Speaker 4:  And they're like, Microsoft and open AI this week was another piece of, of
Speaker 4:  news that they're giving a bunch of money to newsrooms
Speaker 4:  to make them make more AI stuff. And it's just like, what,
Speaker 4:  what a bizarre inversion of this same thing where they're like,
Speaker 4:  we are gonna give you money to take your stuff or we're just gonna
Speaker 4:  take it for free, but here's some money to make AI stuff.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, well they're, they're giving some money. They announced $10 million
Speaker 5:  and 5 million of it is in credits for the software.
Speaker 4:  Oh, is it really? That's annoying. Which
Speaker 5:  Is not the same thing as money. Exactly.
Speaker 4:  No, it's not. It is super not, but all of this stuff is like, it's,
Speaker 4:  everything is running as fast as possible in these
Speaker 4:  like mutually exclusive ways
Speaker 4:  except that it sort of feels like if the money gets big enough,
Speaker 4:  it'll just be okay. That,
Speaker 3:  So this is, I I haven't thought this all the way through and
Speaker 3:  I'm curious for reader feedback on this. What
Speaker 4:  The first cast is for,
Speaker 3:  If the money gets big enough, I think the judges and the copyright cases
Speaker 3:  are gonna be like, look at all of your money.
Speaker 3:  Pay it to them. Like at some point you're like, I made
Speaker 3:  a thing so valuable by taking all of this stuff without
Speaker 3:  permission. A judge is gonna say, well, that, that is actually a
Speaker 3:  value transfer That doesn't make sense, right? If, you needed all of
Speaker 3:  this to raise your $6.9 billion
Speaker 3:  OpenAI. Then it stands to reason that that stuff is
Speaker 3:  valuable and you should take some of the money you raised and pay it to the
Speaker 3:  people whose work you need to make your product that supports the valuation.
Speaker 3:  But
Speaker 4:  That's kind of my point, right? I think if you're open ai, you say, okay,
Speaker 4:  listen judge, fine us fine us
Speaker 4:  $1 billion. That's so much money. One whole billion
Speaker 4:  dollars. Oh it's cool. We got five and a half other and
Speaker 4:  this, this is what I mean. Like I think there is a sense among these companies
Speaker 4:  that if they can just build a big enough war chest, they can either buy
Speaker 4:  out or wait out all of their problems and that those are tech problems. Those
Speaker 4:  are regulatory problems. Those are fights with publishers. Like that just
Speaker 4:  gives them the money to wait. And I I I,
Speaker 4:  there's a reasonable evidence that they're gonna be right about that.
Speaker 4:  The the wild card is, are we due for some
Speaker 4:  kind of
Speaker 4:  judicial end to this that just knife through the whole industry And that
Speaker 4:  I think everybody is lying to you if they think they know the
Speaker 4:  answer.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, that's definitely a coin flip.
Speaker 5:  The the other thing that's happening is that they're also getting attacked
Speaker 5:  from the other side on the, the output side. Not just the copyright
Speaker 5:  infringement accusations of what they've done, but who is responsible for
Speaker 5:  what these tools do? There's a lawsuit that has been publicized written by
Speaker 5:  the New York Times and other outlets we wrote about it where character, AI
Speaker 5:  and Google are being sued after this, this teen died. And
Speaker 5:  one of the main questions about this is this. So if I interact with
Speaker 5:  your generative AI tool, and maybe I put in a prompt and it says something
Speaker 5:  back to me, is anyone legally responsible for what happens next? Who, how
Speaker 5:  much, what, what are you supposed to do? What, what should be the rules there?
Speaker 5:  What should, what safety should you implement? Should these things be usable
Speaker 5:  by children? None of these questions have been answered yet and they're,
Speaker 5:  that could be another problem.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And that is the realist problem, especially for
Speaker 3:  the character as of the world where there's sort of like advertising that
Speaker 3:  these are therapy tools and it's like, well If,
Speaker 3:  you lead people to these outcomes, you're probably responsible for them.
Speaker 3:  And no one has thought any of this through. I'm just saying it's neat to
Speaker 3:  talk about agents and Siri or Alexa that
Speaker 3:  can just do stuff for you. And then there's like, oh shit. It's doing stuff
Speaker 3:  for you. Also, the foundation of this might be Kevin. Bacon
Speaker 3:  gets a billion dollars like weird,
Speaker 3:  weird outcome. Can I
Speaker 4:  Just read you the one sentence thing that they all signed onto?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It says the unlicensed use of creative works for training generative
Speaker 4:  AI is a major unjust threat to the livelihoods of the people behind those
Speaker 4:  works and must not be permitted.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Like I'm just, I'm amazed they got
Speaker 4:  11,500 people to care about that. Enough to sign.
Speaker 3:  Oh no. A piece of paper. No, we could get 11,000 people to sign a statement
Speaker 3:  like tomorrow. The Verge commenters alone would sign that statement.
Speaker 3:  It's
Speaker 4:  Just such a like, I don't know, it's just such a milk toast way to
Speaker 4:  be like, I am gently mad at the AI industry.
Speaker 3:  I don't think that's gentle. It's a major unjust threat that must not be
Speaker 3:  permitted. What do you want them to say? Sam Altman should be arrested
Speaker 3:  11,000 people. It's
Speaker 4:  Just like money. Please.
Speaker 3:  No, it says must not be permitted.
Speaker 4:  It says livelihoods. You know what that is? It's, this is not, it's
Speaker 4:  not. It's money. Money.
Speaker 5:  The unfortunate part is that it already happened. Yeah. So
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Cat's outta the bag. Kevin Bacon Bacon. No, Dan in this town, bro.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Open AI raised $7 billion so that it can give Kevin Bacon one of
Speaker 4:  them and then it can move on.
Speaker 3:  The other thing that's going on in the AI world, which we just skim over
Speaker 3:  'cause it is an election year and everyone can see the weird AI election
Speaker 3:  misinformation for their own eyes, is that the, the companies that make these
Speaker 3:  tools and have promised labeling and metadata for years and
Speaker 3:  have done nothing while all of this is getting fully outta control,
Speaker 3:  are slowly starting to add labels and metadata to their own work.
Speaker 3:  So Google is gonna open source its watermarking tool for AI
Speaker 3:  generated text. We'll see how that goes. That one's is, that's the hardest
Speaker 3:  one. But Google Photos is now gonna show AI
Speaker 3:  generated metadata in the photos. Like there'll be a label if we
Speaker 3:  can detect the metadata. We're just, it's a slow,
Speaker 3:  slow burn. And then, oh, apple Craig Feder in that same interview, Joanna,
Speaker 3:  so that he wants photos to be photos. He doesn't want real photos to be fantasy
Speaker 3:  and that they are also showing some information in the photos. This is
Speaker 3:  not enough flatly. None of these companies are doing enough. They've all
Speaker 3:  talked a huge game about things like C two
Speaker 3:  PA and content authenticity. And we're kind of at like, we're
Speaker 3:  gonna do exif data and labels that people can
Speaker 3:  change while the misinformation is like running rampant everywhere. Has
Speaker 3:  Craig
Speaker 5:  Federighi seen that, seen that photo The bridesmaid with like three arms?
Speaker 5:  Because somebody should tell him about that. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  But that was like a panorama mode thing, right? It wasn't even ai.
Speaker 3:  It wasn't even ai. It's
Speaker 4:  Just the, the pace of all of that is so backwards to me because what the,
Speaker 4:  the logic for going slow on all of this from all of these companies is like,
Speaker 4:  we have to really test this stuff and harden it and make sure it works
Speaker 4:  and make sure it can't be,
Speaker 3:  Fire, fire
Speaker 3:  If assigned to Richard. I'm gonna just gonna be very honest with you, I'm
Speaker 3:  very excited. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. The lightning round sponsored by no one,
Speaker 3:  no one for all of your not not money needs.
Speaker 3:  See, see what I yet that's what it could look like. If, you paid
Speaker 3:  us money. Someone money, not me. We'll get there one
Speaker 3:  day. All right. It's lightning around.
Speaker 3:  David, I think you need to start with honestly the news that
Speaker 3:  should have led the entire vergecast.
Speaker 4:  I just want you both to be very proud of me that I made it o over an hour
Speaker 4:  into The Vergecast. And I have not mentioned the books Palmer two once. I
Speaker 4:  haven't even, I haven't even teased it.
Speaker 3:  The best thing about the BWA two is that we've entered the stage of covering
Speaker 3:  this thing where we, there was a leak of it and we covered the leak
Speaker 3:  and then the announcement of the tiny e-reader
Speaker 5:  We're, we're deep in the weeds. The Verge
Speaker 4:  Is the official news source of the
Speaker 4:  book's Palmer and I feel very good about this. What I
Speaker 5:  Like is that they got the sequel out fast enough that my prescheduled six
Speaker 5:  month out tweet asking people if they know where their books Palmer is,
Speaker 5:  hasn't even gone up yet. And they're already selling the sequel. They, I
Speaker 5:  got, they got me on this one.
Speaker 4:  Somebody posted on Threads today accusing me of being in
Speaker 4:  league with books to get rid of all their inventory on the, on the one
Speaker 4:  before the two came out. And they're like, you, you timed this on Burs,
Speaker 4:  didn't you?
Speaker 5:  Big books is
Speaker 4:  Big books, yeah. That's, that's, that's me. They, they fund everything.
Speaker 4:  Everything in the basketball hoop you see behind me. So the books
Speaker 4:  Palmer two still $280, which is still too expensive,
Speaker 4:  but it's, it's still, it's a smartphone sized e-reader. To answer
Speaker 4:  your question, Richard, I use mine every single day and I love it
Speaker 4:  very much. It fixes a couple of the things that were wrong with the last
Speaker 4:  one. Mostly it was a little slow and it ran a really
Speaker 4:  outdated version of Android. Now I suspect it will be less slow and it runs
Speaker 4:  a less outdated version of Android. It doesn't run a current version of Android,
Speaker 4:  but it's better.
Speaker 4:  It's still, it's the same size, it's the same screen.
Speaker 4:  It has, I believe, the same amount of ram and the same amount of storage.
Speaker 4:  It's just like a gentle upgrade of the same
Speaker 4:  device,
Speaker 4:  which I think is fine. I, to me, honestly, the fact that books just made
Speaker 4:  another one of these is the thing that is most exciting and
Speaker 4:  interesting books is basically like a spaghetti at the wall kind of company.
Speaker 4:  They just make every single product size
Speaker 4:  nsq, you can imagine
Speaker 3:  They're Dyson, but for e ink screens. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And, and that's fine, right? Like you can go on their website and buy just
Speaker 4:  about any dimension of e ink device that you want. And I think just the fact
Speaker 4:  that this one is getting a second rev suggests
Speaker 4:  that it is successful and and meaningful to people.
Speaker 3:  Just by the way, just in case people are wondering, what I mean by Dyson
Speaker 3:  is If, you want something with a fan in it, Dyson will sell it to you. Oh
Speaker 3:  yeah. Suck, blow anything with a fan,
Speaker 4:  However tall you'd like your vacuum to be. Dyson has you, they got you so
Speaker 4:  good. There was, there's one I believe that
Speaker 4:  launched in just China that also doesn't have a
Speaker 4:  camera. Yeah. Which I think is pretty cool and is a thing. There were a bunch
Speaker 4:  of people when I wrote about the poem in the first place, we're like, I would
Speaker 4:  love for one of these without a camera for just a variety
Speaker 4:  of, you know, security and privacy and family reasons. But the one
Speaker 4:  that's shipping around the world still has a camera.
Speaker 3:  Why
Speaker 4:  I they say say,
Speaker 3:  Have you ever used the camera on your books? Poi No.
Speaker 4:  Literally not once. When I wrote about it, I forgot it existed until
Speaker 4:  somebody I was talking to asked me if I had ever used the camera and I said,
Speaker 4:  no, I forgot it had a camera.
Speaker 4:  But their thesis is that you might use it for
Speaker 4:  like scanning and digitizing stuff, which like, sure. But to me it's like,
Speaker 4:  get rid of the camera and knock the price down. 40 bucks. Everybody wins.
Speaker 4:  Yes. Way better. But yeah, I, I think this thing is,
Speaker 4:  I'm excited about it. I'm hopeful that they'll ship me one and I can review
Speaker 4:  it. I, I think the thing books is
Speaker 4:  trying to do it got kind of right the first time. Like that combination of
Speaker 4:  the size of the thing and the fact that it's e inc and the fact that it runs
Speaker 4:  Android apps is awesome.
Speaker 4:  We tried to get Anos Pinene to look at one. He refused, he refused to do
Speaker 4:  it on camera. It was very upsetting.
Speaker 4:  And yeah. We'll, we'll we'll see. I got a lot of people asking me,
Speaker 4:  should I buy this one or the new Kindle paper? White people want E Ink devices,
Speaker 4:  man. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I will say I encourage everyone to pull over in your car and then look at
Speaker 3:  our article with BMA two, click on it and scroll down and look
Speaker 3:  at B'S own press photo of a guy holding The Boox Palma two.
Speaker 3:  He's very much like, what am I doing here? Yeah,
Speaker 4:  He's, he's like, what is this thing?
Speaker 3:  He's like, how did I get here? He is like, yep, I'm looking at a little phone
Speaker 3:  with me and scream.
Speaker 4:  It's true. It's just a guy in a beige sweater who's like, why does this have
Speaker 4:  no colors?
Speaker 3:  It's like his face is like, I I hate this book. I don't want to be reading
Speaker 3:  it. It's very, it's very much the face. I imagine Richard made
Speaker 3:  the first time he had the books spot.
Speaker 3:  Like this is the, the face that that made you pre-schedule the tweet like
Speaker 3:  right here. It's good. And,
Speaker 5:  And I'm, I'm glad that these things exist. Like someone should make like
Speaker 5:  an Android thing with an eating screen that runs apps.
Speaker 5:  It's great. I just think that people will probably put them down
Speaker 5:  and forget that they bought them. I
Speaker 3:  Just as I believe this gentleman put this one down.
Speaker 4:  It's why, it's
Speaker 5:  Why the If you If, you asked him about it right now. He wouldn't be able
Speaker 5:  to tell you what a book
Speaker 3:  Home. He's like, whatcha talking about
Speaker 4:  The the what
Speaker 3:  Now? That was a job. Like that's his face. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  This is why the problem is the price with Yeah, really with all of these
Speaker 4:  devices like the Palmer or something like it at
Speaker 4:  99 bucks, like sold, right? Like the, the Kindle
Speaker 4:  succeeds for that same reason. It's like If. you buy a Kindle and use it
Speaker 4:  a bunch and then forget about it for a while and then use it a bunch and
Speaker 4:  then forget about it for a while. You've paid the correct amount for it.
Speaker 4:  280 bucks is too much for that use case. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  that's said I'm gonna, I'll be purchasing one.
Speaker 3:  I gotta go use my books Pomo one at least one more time to make it worth
Speaker 3:  it apparently. All right, Richard, you've got the best one at all.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Senior citizens, very, very upset at
Speaker 5:  T-Mobile of all companies because it won't honor its lifetime price
Speaker 5:  guarantee. Turns out they lived, I guess longer than T-Mobile
Speaker 5:  thought. When you, when you tell people that they're going to, that you're
Speaker 5:  gonna give them a lifetime price lock. You figure how long could that last
Speaker 5:  longer than you think T-Mobile, they, they probably figure that out the
Speaker 5:  same way they do security.
Speaker 3:  That's rough. Which
Speaker 5:  Is why everyone
Speaker 3:  Has security number now That's a stab right there.
Speaker 3:  Thousands of FCC complaints
Speaker 3:  that from people saying they, they signed up for price lock in what,
Speaker 3:  2015. So 10 years ago. Yes. So T-Mobile assumed everyone would
Speaker 3:  die within one decade.
Speaker 5:  They had a senior plan that was marketed specifically to people 55 and up
Speaker 3:  With lifetime price lock.
Speaker 5:  Yes. And it included this. And those are not people who you want to disappoint
Speaker 5:  on a lifetime offer.
Speaker 3:  Like they will remember.
Speaker 4:  Has anyone ever not lived to regret the lifetime
Speaker 4:  price guarantee? Like this always makes me think of back in the day when
Speaker 4:  the airlines would sell the people like the
Speaker 4:  $250,000 lifetime fly wherever you want first
Speaker 4:  class thing. And then there were the people who were like, all right, challenge
Speaker 4:  accepted. I live in the sky now. Yeah. And eventually all the airlines are
Speaker 4:  like, well you can't do that. And they're like, remember when you said
Speaker 4:  Lifetime and like the everyone is j
Speaker 4:  just don't do this If. you can't do it. Just don't do it. And then
Speaker 4:  there are the companies that offer a lifetime deal and then go out of business
Speaker 4:  and it's like, what are, what are we doing? Y'all like, well
Speaker 3:  That's a win. That means you outlived the,
Speaker 5:  It's the lifetime of the executive who approved it,
Speaker 4:  Right? Yeah, a hundred percent
Speaker 3:  In the FCC complaints. There are some, some choice quotes. AZ Technica dug
Speaker 3:  them all up. One of them, I am not dead yet. A customer
Speaker 3:  in New York wrote bluntly.
Speaker 3:  That's, that's very good.
Speaker 4:  There was one person who complained that their price is going up $50 a month
Speaker 4:  because they had 10 lines. I'm like, wow, 10 lines.
Speaker 3:  That's good. Well if you've got that lifetime guarantee, that's,
Speaker 4:  I mean that's fair. I'd get everybody on that plan. You guys wanna join my
Speaker 4:  plan?
Speaker 3:  I will take this opportunity to remind the Vergecast audience that T-Mobile
Speaker 3:  exists in its current state. Because the government allowed it to buy Sprint
Speaker 3:  in a deal which took our nation's number of viable
Speaker 3:  nationwide wireless carriers from four to three. And to solve that problem,
Speaker 3:  the government made dish network make
Speaker 3:  a network. That pro network is called Project Genesis or Gen five sis.
Speaker 3:  That network does not exist. Just, I don't know what to tell you. You can
Speaker 3:  go to the website. The website sometimes doesn't load when you go to the
Speaker 3:  Dish Network project. It's sometimes just isn't there.
Speaker 3:  Like just physically doesn't load. And then If,
Speaker 3:  you do get it to load. You can buy a, what is it, a Motorola Edge plus
Speaker 3:  like a 2023 Motorola Edge plus Plus. That's the phone they sell and that
Speaker 3:  phone If you go look at the subreddit will mostly roam onto at
Speaker 3:  t's network.
Speaker 4:  Perfect. I don't see the pro That's competition baby.
Speaker 3:  What I, I'm just saying, you know, I know it's election season, I'm, that
Speaker 3:  was the deal negotiated by Donald Trump's antitrust
Speaker 3:  division to preserve competition in the wireless market.
Speaker 4:  We did it y'all.
Speaker 3:  When I think of at and t, Verizon and T-Mobile and the biggest threats they
Speaker 3:  face every
Speaker 4:  Day is, Zach, can I just read you one paragraph from their story? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's like an aside in the middle of the story, but it is, it is the best
Speaker 4:  knife in the whole story. Last year, T-Mobile notified some customers that
Speaker 4:  it would automatically switch them to newer more expensive plans unless the
Speaker 4:  customers called the company to opt outta the change. T-Mobile customer service
Speaker 4:  reps were instructed to tell users we are not raising the price of any of
Speaker 4:  our plans. We are moving you to a newer plan with more benefits at a different
Speaker 4:  cost. It's not whether the price is more or less, you guys,
Speaker 4:  it's just different.
Speaker 4:  It's just different.
Speaker 3:  I'm sorry and I'm just reading the the project Genesis subreddit, none of
Speaker 3:  it's good man. Anyhow. Wireless carriers and ISP your favorite.
Speaker 3:  Now to further enrage you about our nation's wireless carriers
Speaker 3:  and ISPs, I will inform you of my lightning round item,
Speaker 3:  which is that the Federal Trade Commission passed what's called the click
Speaker 3:  to cancel rule. This is the rule that says If,
Speaker 3:  you sign up for something canceling, it has to be as easy as signing up,
Speaker 3:  right? So you can click on something to sign up for a subscription or a yearly
Speaker 3:  membership or whatever to get out of it. You gotta be able to click one button.
Speaker 3:  These are called negative option contracts. There's a whole thing. There's
Speaker 3:  like three or four different laws to try to solve this problem. And
Speaker 3:  the FT C put up a rule a while ago everyone complained about the rule and
Speaker 3:  now they pass the rule. This is like Lena con's FT C saying this is bad for
Speaker 3:  consumers to make people dance through cancel
Speaker 3:  flows or to hide, you know, options where the price
Speaker 3:  escalates. It's gotta be as easy to get out as it was to get in.
Speaker 4:  This is an objectively correct stance, right?
Speaker 3:  Everyone loves this rule.
Speaker 4:  There's not like a secret thing that I'm missing about why this might suck
Speaker 4:  for consumers. This is just great.
Speaker 3:  No, it's totally, this is, this is
Speaker 7:  What happens when you make millennials call the New York Times to
Speaker 3:  Cancel their subscriptions.
Speaker 7:  Millennials hate phone calls
Speaker 4:  A hundred percent.
Speaker 3:  And so, you know, the lean con FCC is like doing its thing.
Speaker 3:  Guess immediately. Who sued to stop this rule?
Speaker 3:  If, you guessed our nation's ISPs and wireless carriers. You would be correct.
Speaker 3:  So I
Speaker 4:  Was gonna guess gyms that was gonna be my other
Speaker 3:  Gyms is in there. A bunch of advertisers are in there.
Speaker 3:  A-D-T-A-D-T is in there. So it's, it's they're trade groups,
Speaker 3:  right? So the nash, the NCTA, which is the, the
Speaker 3:  ISP trade group that represents Comcast Charter Cox,
Speaker 3:  it represents streaming services like Disney, A MC, paramount, Warner Brothers,
Speaker 3:  discovery Disclosure, Comcast is an investor, our
Speaker 3:  parent company,
Speaker 3:  I'd take that from what it's worth, I think they suck in this case,
Speaker 3:  the IAB, which is the advertising, the internet advertising bureau,
Speaker 3:  that's Google, Netflix, Amazon Meta Vio and the NFL,
Speaker 3:  the ESAs, A DT. So all of these huge companies are through their
Speaker 3:  trade organizations basically suing the
Speaker 3:  FTC and saying, no, we do not want you to
Speaker 3:  make click to cancel mandatory. And the argument is
Speaker 3:  the FTC is trying to regulate consumer contracts for all companies in all
Speaker 3:  industries across all sectors of the economy, from forbidding businesses
Speaker 3:  for making customers cancel services using a method that differs from
Speaker 3:  how they signed up.
Speaker 4:  Yes. That is what they're trying. That's correct.
Speaker 3:  And so the, the argument here is freedom in America
Speaker 3:  requires us to be able to fleece our customers.
Speaker 3:  Like get the nanny state outta here. It's wild
Speaker 3:  underneath that this is some real wonky legal stuff
Speaker 3:  is how they will probably attempt to go after this. So the
Speaker 3:  FTC is a, you know, executive agency of the government. It has some
Speaker 3:  powers or some powers. It doesn't have the main power is like
Speaker 3:  its rulemaking authority. It's like ability to like make decisions
Speaker 3:  basically. And that was basically
Speaker 3:  just overturned by this Supreme Court.
Speaker 3:  We'll link to it. But there was this concept called Chevron deference where
Speaker 3:  the courts would defer to the agency like, you know best, like you're staffed
Speaker 3:  by experts. You made this decision, we will defer to your rulemaking
Speaker 3:  process. If you get sued. But this Supreme Court threw that
Speaker 3:  out. So now the courts get to decide if these rules make sense,
Speaker 3:  which is basically just like an explosion of how our government works Anyway.
Speaker 3:  All that means is Comcast gets to Sue Lehan for
Speaker 3:  making easier sort of get outta your ISP agreement. And that is stupid.
Speaker 3:  So that's good. This is going to, it's amazing that these companies are buying
Speaker 3:  this amount of bad press. They should just make better products.
Speaker 3:  But here we are.
Speaker 4:  This always just makes me think of the, the place we've gotten to with streaming
Speaker 4:  TV where basically what we've done is just very slowly reinvent
Speaker 4:  cable, but it's easier to cancel now and in, in a
Speaker 4:  very real way. That's a giant victory that like I pay as much,
Speaker 4:  it's a worst user experience in a lot of ways, but at least I can cancel
Speaker 4:  it success. And it is just
Speaker 4:  bonkers how few things have gone that way. Yeah, like it's, I,
Speaker 4:  there are so many things I pay for because I just can't figure out how to
Speaker 4:  cancel it. Like literally the the just to name one, the Wall Street
Speaker 4:  Journal, which I'm not important enough to need
Speaker 4:  to
Speaker 3:  care of your health. So sign up for another gym membership and then never
Speaker 3:  get outta it. Thanks.
Speaker 3:  That's it. We we're way over. I'm furious that I can't
Speaker 3:  cancel more things more easily. I don't even know my Hulu
Speaker 3:  Password, but I'd cancel it. That's what
Speaker 4:  If you want to cancel The? Vergecast. You have to call Eli and we'll never
Speaker 4:  tell you his number.
Speaker 3:  That's it. Call The Vergecast line and explain to us why you need to cancel
Speaker 3:  the show. That is a dangerous prompt. Think twice. Make it
Speaker 3:  funny. That's it. That's The Vergecast. Rock and roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one. One The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Liam James Wil Pour and Eric Gomez. And that's it. We'll see
Speaker 1:  you next week.