# Transcript
ID: 529644a5-45d3-46b4-850e-4746c9ba2bf6
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2344718276481201612/-2971917372811609962/s93290-US-6563s-1730456682.mp3
Description: Nilay and David discuss a big week in AI news, including the new web search features in ChatGPT and the reporting that Meta is working on something very similar. They also briefly talk about this quarter's tech earnings, and what they say about the ways AI is really being used. Then, Wall Street Journal columnist Joanna Stern joins the show to talk about Apple Intelligence, Apple's week of Mac launches, and why Siri still can't open her garage. Finally, in the lightning round, the hosts talk about Netflix's gentle push into social features, Tony Fadell's AI thoughts, and our endorsement of Kamala Harris.
Speaker 3:  Hello and welcome to Vergecast Flagship podcast,
Speaker 3:  searching using artificial intelligence. Welcome to the future.
Speaker 3:  Hi, I'm your friend Neil. I, David Pierce is here.
Speaker 4:  Hello.
Speaker 3:  Joanna Stern is gonna join the show in a little bit. There's a lot of
Speaker 3:  news this week. Search, GPT is here. That's open AI's
Speaker 3:  competitor to Google that's built right into chat. GT, we gotta talk about
Speaker 3:  that. Meta is apparently announcing AI powered search. iOS
Speaker 3:  18.1 with Apple Intelligence arrived
Speaker 3:  with something.
Speaker 4:  It did arrive. We can say that with certainty with
Speaker 3:  A puff of smoke. And then there's just like earnings to talk about. We got
Speaker 3:  a lightning round. I'm very excited about some of the lightning round items.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Oh, and we should mention Apple also announced a whole bunch of New
Speaker 3:  Macs. Yeah. So we're gonna save a bunch of the Apple conversation for
Speaker 3:  when Joanna joins us. We should start with the news search
Speaker 3:  GPT launching, or I guess search in chat. GPT is how they're framing it.
Speaker 3:  It's funny how much we talked about Google and Google search changing
Speaker 3:  and the web and whether AI would kill Google and, and here it
Speaker 3:  is and it's kinda like, huh?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I I'm, I'm actually really glad that was your reaction because that
Speaker 4:  was mine too. It's like If, you just imagined
Speaker 4:  what a, I don't know, three quarters baked search product
Speaker 4:  would look like from OpenAI. You would've gotten it almost a hundred
Speaker 4:  percent. Exactly right. And I think two things about this are
Speaker 4:  really interesting to me. One is that a, this is the
Speaker 4:  thing that OpenAI has been signing publisher deals for disclosure,
Speaker 4:  Vox Media, the VIRs parent company signed one of those deals. That's
Speaker 4:  all I know about it. It exists, but they've signed lots of these deals in
Speaker 4:  recent months. They've had this web crawler doing stuff for a long time now
Speaker 4:  that web crawler has been really controversial, like it's all been building
Speaker 4:  to this and in open AI's sort of typical
Speaker 4:  fashion. They don't make a giant deal out of their biggest launches, but
Speaker 4:  like this is a big one for OpenAI. It, it is the thing that gives
Speaker 4:  Chad GBT real time information, which is I would say the single biggest
Speaker 4:  hole it has had so far. I also think it's fascinating that they just
Speaker 4:  built it into chat GPT, like when it first was a thing, it was gonna be,
Speaker 4:  you know, search GPT. And I think OpenAI has struggled to figure
Speaker 4:  out how exactly to package and productize all of this stuff
Speaker 4:  and just shoving it in all inside of the chat bot has turned
Speaker 4:  out to be the answer. Yeah, and I think this thing looks fine. I think
Speaker 4:  OpenAI is making some wild, obviously incorrect claims about it,
Speaker 4:  but the idea of what it is seems pretty straightforward and
Speaker 4:  useful.
Speaker 3:  The shove it all in the chatbot is super interesting, right? Because Google
Speaker 3:  and opening Eye are coming at the same problem from radically
Speaker 3:  different directions. They have kind of the same idea and
Speaker 3:  they're arriving at very different rifts on the
Speaker 3:  same core user interface. Yeah. So Google's right, Google wants to be an
Speaker 3:  answer engine. They've, they've talked about Google search that way for such
Speaker 3:  a long time. So you ask Google a question and 10 blue links and
Speaker 3:  then answer cards and knowledge panels, and now you get AI overview, which
Speaker 3:  are still kind of a mess. But the idea that you, you just ask a question
Speaker 3:  in Google and it delivers you an answer has been the core thesis
Speaker 3:  of Google search for quite some time.
Speaker 3:  And they've, they're getting there, but it's still very structured, right?
Speaker 3:  You are not supposed to chat with Google search, right? But it's still like,
Speaker 3:  ask a freeform question in this text box and Google search will figure it
Speaker 3:  out and deliver you some answer. OpenAI started not with the web,
Speaker 3:  but with just like freeform chat, right? Just like talk to this
Speaker 3:  robot, it might try to bang you. Let's find
Speaker 4:  Out where did this information come from? Who knows,
Speaker 3:  Right? Like here's just some weird stuff and they're adding all of this
Speaker 3:  structured information to it with search now, right? By crawling the web.
Speaker 3:  And so they, it it's, they're just coming at it from two, like two
Speaker 3:  radically different positions and they're, they're closer to
Speaker 3:  each other than I think they want to admit.
Speaker 4:  I, I think that's right. And I think it's because in a lot of ways
Speaker 4:  there just aren't that many answers to this. I will say one of the things
Speaker 4:  that strikes me just looking at even some of these early screenshots
Speaker 4:  of what OpenAI is doing, OpenAI actually appears
Speaker 4:  to be a better citizen of the web than Google
Speaker 4:  in the way that they're implementing the AI search stuff. So like, it, it,
Speaker 4:  we'll, we'll put the link in the show notes to Kylie Robinson's story. She
Speaker 4:  saw it, got a demo of it, talked to the folks who were making it. But let
Speaker 4:  me, let me just describe like this one screenshot in the middle of her story.
Speaker 4:  So on the left side, which is the, the sort of OpenAI chat g
Speaker 4:  PD chat window, this person has typed what are some great ways to fix up
Speaker 4:  a backyard? and it goes out and looks at the web and then comes back.
Speaker 4:  And by
Speaker 3:  The way, totally normal query.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's not,
Speaker 3:  That's how everyone talks about fixing up the backyard.
Speaker 4:  Backyard. What do
Speaker 3:  Question mark?
Speaker 4:  Alright,
Speaker 3:  When I think about sitting down on my computer for search, that's exactly
Speaker 3:  how I would phrase it. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Go ahead then. But so the, the first thing it delivers is a, a thing that
Speaker 4:  appears to be an article from the spruce.com called 54 Backyard
Speaker 4:  Ideas to Upgrade Your Outdoor Space, which a is very funny because that headline
Speaker 4:  is so clearly written for Google. Yeah. That it is
Speaker 4:  borderline nonsense. Yeah. 54 Backyard Ideas doesn't
Speaker 4:  mean anything. But anyway, so
Speaker 3:  It's So I. Just wanna say within the first two lines of this demo,
Speaker 3:  we've just left the English language. Oh yeah,
Speaker 4:  We're gone. This is, yeah, but it has,
Speaker 4:  it, it says the spruce.com on right underneath it, it has the
Speaker 4:  Spruces logo right next to it, the little favicon and then
Speaker 4:  four images underneath it that I assume are pulled from that article. And
Speaker 4:  then basically a, a sort of multi-step summary of some of the stuff
Speaker 4:  in that article. Then off to the right, it has a whole sidebar
Speaker 4:  that says citations. And then here it has five links to a
Speaker 4:  bunch of different websites showing similar stuff.
Speaker 4:  Right. 50 stunning backyard ideas that fit every kind of space. Your DIY
Speaker 4:  guy do a backyard makeover on a budget, like all of this is just Google
Speaker 4:  Ease. It's so funny and it's just being surfaced in these new ways. But
Speaker 4:  like in in, in the guise of being
Speaker 4:  like a publisher who cares about having your stuff surfaced and not
Speaker 4:  just like stolen and repackaged looking like a chat bot,
Speaker 4:  this is actually pretty good. This is just one screenshot and I, I am
Speaker 4:  confident that OpenAI is going to pick the things that make it look good
Speaker 4:  in its marketing, but like, it's not a particularly attractive
Speaker 4:  user interface, but it's pretty honest about the web.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Again, we dunno anything about our deal. We had Nick Thompson, who
Speaker 3:  is CEO of the Atlantic, the former editor of Wired on
Speaker 3:  Decoder, and he talked about what he wanted out of the Atlantics deal with
Speaker 3:  OpenAI. And a lot of what he talked about was, I want, I want
Speaker 3:  influence over what these results look like.
Speaker 4:  Right?
Speaker 3:  Right. So the, the publisher deals, a lot of, a lot of it is they,
Speaker 3:  they all gave up too much to Google. It was too much for a free for all.
Speaker 3:  They were mad about it. Now they have a licensing deal, they have a contract,
Speaker 3:  presumably they have points of contact and they, there's some back and forth
Speaker 3:  here about what, how to make this best for everyone. And So I think you can
Speaker 3:  see that here. I'll also, just to keep harping on this one example
Speaker 3:  point out that for all this ai, for all these millions
Speaker 3:  of GPUs running nuclear hot, boiling the
Speaker 3:  ocean, the answers the most cutting edge
Speaker 3:  AI in the entire world came up with for what are some great ways to
Speaker 3:  fix up a backyard are create a seating area, incorporate
Speaker 3:  outdoor lighting and add a fire pit. That's what we got.
Speaker 3:  Boom. That's, it's in incredible. So
Speaker 3:  it's chairs, lights, and fireplace.
Speaker 4:  We, we did it everybody.
Speaker 3:  And maybe look, maybe the person doing this demo has never been in a backyard
Speaker 3:  before. I come back to that all the time. That's really where the huh
Speaker 3:  came from for me. Is that, yeah, I mean
Speaker 3:  maybe If, you ask Google this question a few years ago and you got one of
Speaker 3:  these extremely over SEOed articles that are loaded
Speaker 3:  up with affiliate links and not really written for people, and that's a worse
Speaker 3:  experience. And so maybe just presenting these
Speaker 3:  extremely basic ideas in a nicer experience is all the innovation we need.
Speaker 3:  But then you're like, so all we did was we just cleaned up a little bit,
Speaker 3:  we just took out some of the, the hum boxes. Like there's not a belly fat
Speaker 3:  ad in here, right. That took all of the GPUs in the world.
Speaker 3:  Sam Altman is literally traveling the world asking kings
Speaker 3:  and queens for billions of dollars to build chip fabs. So the robot can say
Speaker 3:  incorporate outdoor lighting. That's what we're doing. Okay.
Speaker 4:  A I think the answer is closer to just straightforwardly Yes. Than
Speaker 4:  anyone would like to admit, which we're gonna get to in a minute when we
Speaker 4:  talk about earnings. But the, the fact that this thing is just
Speaker 4:  a slightly cleaner interface on top of roughly the same information
Speaker 4:  is kind of what everyone is landing on, right? Like whether you're
Speaker 4:  perplexity or what Bing has been trying to do, or now
Speaker 4:  OpenAI like even even Google's thing is like, yeah,
Speaker 4:  we agree that the search page is kind of a mess. Let's,
Speaker 4:  let's do something better. And the question then of how do you
Speaker 4:  monetize any of that, who knows?
Speaker 4:  The OpenAI wouldn't really tell Kylie, they're only rolling it out now for
Speaker 4:  paid chat GBT users. So that's one pretty straight path.
Speaker 4:  But eventually this will be available to free people.
Speaker 4:  And how that makes money free, free, especially because this is very expensive.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's not easy to run these kind of
Speaker 4:  searches in real time in like, it's expensive to run inference on an
Speaker 4:  existing model. It's a whole nother thing to go get real time information
Speaker 4:  from the internet. Like that's a much harder problem to solve computationally.
Speaker 4:  I, yeah, we will see if this becomes a thing that actually works at any scale
Speaker 4:  for any of these companies, but like it is
Speaker 4:  so, so straightforwardly just a slightly better interface
Speaker 4:  on top of things. And you even listen to these companies talk about it and
Speaker 4:  it's like, oh, clicking is so arduous. You have to find
Speaker 4:  information for yourself. And there are certain things in which sure,
Speaker 4:  like sometimes there is a piece of information buried at the bottom
Speaker 4:  of a support document. And what I would like my search results to do
Speaker 4:  is just pull that piece of information out and give it to me. Right? Like
Speaker 4:  I, I need to know how to hard reset a gadget. I just
Speaker 4:  wanna know the answer. I don't, I don't wanna, and, and often you do have
Speaker 4:  to look on 10 websites to find how to hard reset your gadget. This one,
Speaker 4:  what are some great ways to fix up a backyard? This is like
Speaker 4:  very slightly better than what you would get just by clicking any
Speaker 4:  of these webpages on Google.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And I will say, you know, we're we're Cherrypicking the one example,
Speaker 3:  but it's the example they gave us, right? Right. Like there are other things
Speaker 3:  and we have to use it and we have to, it's interesting to try to review search
Speaker 3:  engines. We, we've like had this concept for a long, we should review Google
Speaker 3:  and then it doesn't mean anything like try to give Google a
Speaker 3:  score out of 10, it's seven. Like that's the answer. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like, so, and we have to find some ways, ways to evaluate these tools
Speaker 3:  to actually like address the breadth of how people use them.
Speaker 3:  But right now it is very much, we just got rid of the ads. Like this
Speaker 3:  market had a monopoly player, the monopoly player basically, and ified
Speaker 3:  the whole thing, the entire economics to make the content are people will
Speaker 3:  click on one webpage on your entire site maybe once a year
Speaker 3:  because they search for backyard ideas. So that webpage has to make all of
Speaker 3:  the money all at once. That's weird. So that's how
Speaker 3:  we've loaded up all the pages of the ads and chum boxes and dah da da da
Speaker 3:  and like, maybe this breaks it, this isn't gonna send a lot of traffic to
Speaker 3:  the spruce or whatever sources are in here. We don't know.
Speaker 3:  So it might, there's just a long road to come.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well, and I think your your point about the, the tension they're feeling
Speaker 4:  with these publisher deals, I think probably says more about this design
Speaker 4:  than you, than OpenAI would like it to. Because
Speaker 4:  like, this is what's happening with Meta too, right? There was news this
Speaker 4:  week that Meta is working on a search engine
Speaker 4:  of its own partly just to reduce reliance on Google and
Speaker 4:  Bing, because I think everybody would like to reduce reliance on Google and
Speaker 4:  Bing, but also because as meta AI gets more useful, they announced it has
Speaker 4:  500 million monthly active users. Like it's big, it's working, people are
Speaker 4:  using it. Having good realtime
Speaker 4:  internet information just allows you to do lots of new things. Right. And
Speaker 4:  I have to assume, if I'm OpenAI, the best case scenario
Speaker 4:  here would be something that doesn't feel anything like search at all and
Speaker 4:  is not a list of links, but just has this giant
Speaker 4:  new capability of real-time information, which just opens
Speaker 4:  up a huge set of things you can suddenly do with chat GPT that you
Speaker 4:  couldn't before because its information ended. Like Yeah, it, it literally,
Speaker 4:  it would tell you I only have information up to, I think it was like mid
Speaker 4:  2023 the last time I checked.
Speaker 4:  Once you get rid of that cap and I can just start to ask questions about
Speaker 4:  like the world as it is happening, chat GBT becomes much more powerful. It
Speaker 4:  also runs you into lawsuits from every publisher on planet earth, which is
Speaker 4:  what has happened. And so you can, you can see how like
Speaker 4:  OpenAI kind of lawyered its way into this design where it's like, okay, we're
Speaker 4:  gonna do some AI stuff, but also there's gonna be a bunch of big ass links
Speaker 4:  on the right side. Like, is everybody happy now? I don't know if they will
Speaker 4:  be.
Speaker 3:  We, we, we paid you money, will you shut up? Right. Like and that's the back
Speaker 3:  and forth here. And I think, you know, Kylie asked the questions in the,
Speaker 3:  in the briefing and you can see it in the, in the story that we'll link,
Speaker 3:  but they're like, we're working with our publisher partners and now the game
Speaker 3:  is instead of doing SEO to get to the top of the rankings,
Speaker 3:  it's do deals with OpenAI Right. To get in the list and get the money and
Speaker 3:  hopefully have influence over what these things look like. And that's just
Speaker 3:  gonna be a whole different world when you look at meta and meta doing search.
Speaker 3:  I think one, this is just evidence that ai, regardless of whether it's
Speaker 3:  good or bad or whether it works or doesn't, has created the feeling
Speaker 3:  that search is now a competitive market.
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  If the Google antitrust case, you know, goes the way that
Speaker 3:  we think it will go on appeal and Google remains unable to just pay its
Speaker 3:  way into default payments, well that means a lot of
Speaker 3:  people could get placement in iOS to be the default search
Speaker 3:  engine. Those browser ballots that
Speaker 3:  have not worked in Europe for a decade, but like might get
Speaker 3:  imposed on Android in this country as well. Maybe you wanna put
Speaker 3:  the meta logo there and say meta powered AI search or OpenAI chat
Speaker 3:  GBT powered search to say there are other options for you for search engines
Speaker 3:  beyond Google. And so the market is opening some
Speaker 3:  combination of just like regulatory effort and the existence of AI as
Speaker 3:  a whole, plus Google search as a product
Speaker 3:  having plateaued into whatever it was last year.
Speaker 3:  All of this is just conditions for web search to change.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  The question that I have very like
Speaker 3:  existentially is does any of this create incentives for people
Speaker 3:  to put information on the web? Because right now all the incentives
Speaker 3:  are for you as a creator or a publisher or whoever to put new
Speaker 3:  information on TikTok Yeah. Or Instagram reels or
Speaker 3:  YouTube where you might actually make some money. Like the A to B of
Speaker 3:  I made some information on the web and made some money is as fuzzy as it
Speaker 3:  has ever been.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I I've spent a lot of time talking to and
Speaker 4:  reading kind of OG bloggers recently we
Speaker 4:  just did The Vergecast about the origin of the Word podcast. And a lot of
Speaker 4:  the folks involved with that were also like really early bloggers, So
Speaker 4:  I ended up sort of back in this sphere. And the the
Speaker 4:  overwhelming thing I keep hearing from these early bloggers is like
Speaker 4:  the, we we blog because we want to, it's not about the money, it's about,
Speaker 4:  it's about having something to say and it's like that's well and good that
Speaker 4:  the, the like number of people for whom that applies is this big.
Speaker 4:  And and it is like a, in a lot of ways it's like a bunch of dudes who sold
Speaker 4:  startups in the nineties and needed something to do all day. Yeah. Like not
Speaker 4:  to be an asshole about it, but like that's what it was. And, and, and you're
Speaker 4:  right. And the idea that I'm going to be able to do this
Speaker 4:  open web something blog, find other
Speaker 4:  ways to make content, the i there is not
Speaker 4:  any more a a sort of obvious or even like
Speaker 4:  straight line to I can make a business out of this because
Speaker 4:  all of the interface is just getting subsumed. And even
Speaker 4:  if you're, if you're competing to be a link in Chatt t you don't have the
Speaker 4:  lawyers to make the deal with OpenAI. So you may not show up in there. Yep.
Speaker 4:  So suddenly the, the list of even available sources to you
Speaker 4:  might be much smaller than it once was because you just don't have the engine
Speaker 4:  with which to play the game. And OpenAI might decide that
Speaker 4:  it's easier to just shut everybody else out than to fight the fight
Speaker 4:  website by website all around the internet.
Speaker 3:  And I, the weird danger of this is
Speaker 3:  that we'll go back to a media ecosystem that looks like the
Speaker 3:  one we had before the internet, which is I think
Speaker 3:  hard for a lot of people to understand or see. But
Speaker 3:  what I'm describing is you'll have a lot of people who write paid newsletters
Speaker 3:  or have small audiences that pay money behind
Speaker 3:  paywalls or even medium sized audiences behind paywalls because
Speaker 3:  that's the best way to make the money. and we can see that all over the place.
Speaker 3:  Creators are just making money directly. They're Casey Newton a great friend
Speaker 3:  of The Verge platform is doing great, but he,
Speaker 3:  that's the size of the audience, right? And like there's a lot of newsletters
Speaker 3:  that have hit escape velocity like Platformer has and they're, they're doing
Speaker 3:  really, really well, but that they're just paywall. They're just that
Speaker 3:  and that's how big they're gonna be or and there are some that are even smaller.
Speaker 3:  And then you have the mass outlets that are free,
Speaker 3:  that are gate kept by weird deals. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And that is cable news or like whatever other big free distribution
Speaker 3:  where everyone has made the deals to support that. And so most people will
Speaker 3:  experience the things that can be subsidized in that way. And then a lot
Speaker 3:  of people are gonna have small magazines or small blogs that are pay walled.
Speaker 3:  And that, that weird thing that the internet did, which is let everyone
Speaker 3:  just sort of compete freely against each other is kind of just like
Speaker 3:  getting crushed by all of this. What amounts to just a bunch of
Speaker 3:  interface changes, right? Like it's a cleaner search inter
Speaker 3:  interface and then behind that is like a total reordering of
Speaker 3:  the internet into paywalls and not,
Speaker 4:  I think the question implicit in that is how different
Speaker 4:  is, at
Speaker 3:  Least for writing, I wanna be clear that's for writing. Yeah. On the video
Speaker 3:  side it's just very different on the podcasting side it's very different.
Speaker 3:  Well,
Speaker 4:  But even, even on that side, I think the question, the question I was
Speaker 4:  about to ask is like how different is kind of the
Speaker 4:  unknowable TikTok algorithm versus like the
Speaker 4:  unknowable guy in the corner office who decided what was fit to print,
Speaker 4:  right? Like it is, it is rules, it's just a
Speaker 4:  question of which rules and how transparent are they and do they make sense
Speaker 4:  to you? Yeah. And the idea of there being this ecosystem that was
Speaker 4:  too big for any one player to control
Speaker 4:  that's gone, right? Like that, that's long gone. And I think it's been gone
Speaker 4:  longer than a lot of people realized. It's just that now
Speaker 4:  we're getting new interfaces to see some of this stuff and it's, it's making
Speaker 4:  it really obvious how hard it is to make it If. you
Speaker 4:  don't have either the sort of unknowable
Speaker 4:  blessing of an unknowable algorithm or some big thing
Speaker 4:  to fight on your behalf in some way or another.
Speaker 3:  Well, I'll give you an example and So I think about it all the time. So
Speaker 3:  Becca Fache was just on the waveform podcast with Marquez and David, we
Speaker 3:  wish Becca all the best with her YouTube channel. I hope she does really
Speaker 3:  great. It's a good pod. Yeah, it's a good podcast. You should go listen to
Speaker 3:  it. And they had a, just a brief conversation about
Speaker 3:  a thing that I've heard so many tech YouTubers talk about all the time, which
Speaker 3:  is the audiences on tech YouTube are overwhelmingly male
Speaker 3:  and even getting to 10% female audience breaking
Speaker 3:  two digits on tech YouTube is like hard. Like people talk about it.
Speaker 3:  I think Mark has said, I've never, I've only seen one and it might be another
Speaker 3:  one like that's true for our channel as well. It's impossible.
Speaker 3:  That is not reality, right? That is an algorithmic truth
Speaker 3:  of YouTube. The YouTube algorithm has decided that
Speaker 3:  women are not interested in tech videos and so it doesn't show them to them.
Speaker 3:  And so all of these channels have these horrible skews
Speaker 3:  and you can't, you have to fight it. I don't know how to fight it. I know
Speaker 3:  that this is an algorithmic truth because we run a giant website where
Speaker 3:  our gender breakdown on our website of people who come to our website directly
Speaker 3:  looks nothing like that. Right? It is way closer to 50 50
Speaker 3:  because that is fucking true. Like, like everybody
Speaker 3:  likes technology like stat from our sales team all the time
Speaker 3:  is like women make like 80% of technology purchasing decisions in the average
Speaker 3:  household. That's just a real thing that we think about all the time and
Speaker 3:  we are able to address it. And yes, we are buffeted by algorithms,
Speaker 3:  we're buffeted by search for buffet by all stuff. But the algorithm truth
Speaker 3:  of YouTube is that that's your whole audience and you
Speaker 3:  will, you will have to fight it. And I hope that all of them fight it. I'm
Speaker 3:  glad that they're all talking about it. It's good that they're transparent
Speaker 3:  about it. Hopefully there'll be some change. But that is the,
Speaker 3:  that's the mass media now is like algorithmic media. And so I'm, I'm just
Speaker 3:  hopeful that as the AI search and all these other kind of distribution algorithms
Speaker 3:  hit the mix, there's some resorting in
Speaker 3:  a way that makes more sense. Yeah. Right. Like there, there's some resorting
Speaker 3:  in a way that allows small players to not have to chase scale. Which was
Speaker 3:  the big, that was the big miss of like the Facebook video era is like
Speaker 3:  the small recipe site was like, now we make Facebook videos too, right?
Speaker 3:  Something horrible was happening there. It was the big miss of the search
Speaker 3:  era where everything got blanded down into this weird semi robotic English
Speaker 3:  that makes no sense to anyone. And if the next turn is the AI can just read
Speaker 3:  everything as it's written and make it sensible and still distribute it well
Speaker 3:  that will allow things to be more different. But the danger is you're gonna
Speaker 3:  end up with small to medium sized paywall media
Speaker 3:  and then mass algorithmic media and the middle of that will be,
Speaker 3:  I dunno what the fuck the middle of that will be. It'll be weird. Like that's
Speaker 3:  what
Speaker 4:  I got. and it will feel like all you're doing is feeding some
Speaker 4:  AI system more training data. Yeah. Can I give you a better
Speaker 4:  case scenario in news this week that makes me very excited about AI search?
Speaker 4:  So Google just launched a new thing in Google Maps
Speaker 4:  that it calls Ask Maps. And I think this rules, and it's basically, it's
Speaker 4:  just Gemini search, but pointed only at
Speaker 4:  Google Maps data. And so you can, you can start to do things like
Speaker 4:  ask it. The example they give is things to do with friends
Speaker 4:  at night, which again, not, not English,
Speaker 3:  The by the way, the range of answers to that question Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Acceptable to unacceptable is wild.
Speaker 4:  Okay. But like think about your own Google Maps usage, or at least the, the
Speaker 4:  one I encounter all the time is I'm like, okay, we we wanna go out to dinner,
Speaker 4:  right? I wanna like find a place that I've been before,
Speaker 4:  which is in theory information Google has or like what's the best pizza place
Speaker 4:  around here for? But does
Speaker 3:  Google know about me? Is it using the, like my previous Google search history,
Speaker 3:  like if I'm out here, like, it's Halloween, so I'm out here searching
Speaker 3:  for like masks black clothing and I'm like, what to do at night? And it's
Speaker 3:  like Rob Bank
Speaker 3:  things to do
Speaker 4:  With friends at night who rob several banks.
Speaker 4:  I, I don't know. I doubt it. Okay. That's, that's everybody's long-term plan.
Speaker 4:  But what I think is happening here is that Google is actually just doing
Speaker 4:  this with the existing maps data, which is basically like
Speaker 4:  all the place data, it has all the navigation data it has and crucially
Speaker 4:  all of the like reviews and stuff that are in there. So the thing that I
Speaker 4:  encounter all the time is looking for a place to eat dinner.
Speaker 4:  And then I, I find myself combing through reviews looking for one of two
Speaker 4:  things. Either there is good outdoor seating or it it is
Speaker 4:  meaningfully kid friendly in some way. And just the
Speaker 4:  ability to like ask that question at the top of the search
Speaker 4:  becomes incredibly useful. And this I feel zero
Speaker 4:  qualms about because no one is on Google Maps for the purpose of being
Speaker 4:  on Google Maps, right? Like Google Maps is a means to an end every single
Speaker 4:  time. And all of these places that put their information on Google Maps do
Speaker 4:  it so that I will go to a place and, and there the goal is to get
Speaker 4:  me to the place I want to be more quickly. And I think there are lots of
Speaker 4:  interesting complicated like bias problems to figure out with all of this
Speaker 4:  AI stuff. Yeah. But the idea of just being able to be like,
Speaker 4:  what kid friendly place can I go to this weekend that isn't
Speaker 4:  likely to be super busy on a Saturday night? Like
Speaker 3:  Haven't you just described Yelp?
Speaker 4:  I've described what Yelp would like to be and has pitched itself as for forever.
Speaker 4:  But what I just described on Yelp involves opening a filters menu and
Speaker 4:  selecting 31 things and combin through a hundred listings and like Right.
Speaker 4:  But is
Speaker 3:  The whole point of the LLM is like, it will understand natural
Speaker 3:  language and it will be able to communicate in a more naturalistic language.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean we, I we get comments on our site and I
Speaker 3:  almost a 10 outta 10 can tell when they've been written by an LLM like, oh
Speaker 3:  yeah, there's a stilted form that is just the way it goes.
Speaker 3:  But the idea that the compute, the input and output of the computer is much
Speaker 3:  more natural language. That's the thing everyone's freaking out about. Right?
Speaker 3:  That's the platform shift. That's your click wheel. It's not
Speaker 3:  your digital crown, I'm sorry, but Right. That's your multi-touch. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like that's the thing people are freaking out about. And so you get to,
Speaker 3:  okay, I can just talk to Google Maps and Google Maps and just talk back to
Speaker 3:  me all, you're still just looking at a database of information inside of
Speaker 3:  Google, right? Yeah. And it's still, you're, you're clicking the filters,
Speaker 3:  but just with natural language.
Speaker 4:  Right? But that's, that's the thing, right? Like that that changes
Speaker 4:  the whole interface. Like they, they have a, a gif in this story that Emma Roth
Speaker 4:  wrote that it, it opens up a, a
Speaker 4:  bars page on Google Maps and then you, you type in
Speaker 4:  under a thing that says Ask maps about this place. You say, do they have
Speaker 4:  a full bar? and it it, what it appears to be doing is it go, it looks at
Speaker 4:  the menu to see that it serves beer, wine, cocktails and liquor and
Speaker 4:  then looks at the reviews to see what people like and just puts that into
Speaker 4:  three sentences and hands it back and says, yes, it is a full bar.
Speaker 4:  Some people say, what are the cocktails are delicious. Like
Speaker 4:  that's excellent. That is an extremely good user interface
Speaker 4:  that takes something that would've taken a bunch of filtering and
Speaker 4:  collating and searching through reviews and just answers
Speaker 4:  the question. And that is like, that's always been there inside of Google
Speaker 4:  Maps and they've just never quite put it all the way together before. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And if they have this time, I think that's awesome.
Speaker 3:  It's funny 'cause I, I think Amazon is launching that same feature for ask
Speaker 3:  questions about this product and we will search reviews and stuff. Yes. And
Speaker 3:  my experience with that is, yeah, you can do it and it'll work and
Speaker 3:  everything is so depressingly averaged out. Yeah. Like the AI
Speaker 3:  generated summary of the average set of Amazon reviews is like, some
Speaker 3:  people liked it, some people said it set their house on fire. Right. What
Speaker 3:  am I supposed to do with
Speaker 4:  Yeah, well, and and again it like, it it's AI all the way down,
Speaker 4:  right? Yeah. Because you get more and more people who are using AI to write
Speaker 4:  these reviews. The, the AI is like naming the products for
Speaker 4:  god's sake. Like the, the promotional images are being made by Gen ai. So
Speaker 4:  it's like there is a mess that gets created in all of this if it doesn't
Speaker 4:  go well. But I think the idea of it, and same on Amazon. Nobody cares
Speaker 4:  about the content of their Amazon page. They want me to buy their thing.
Speaker 4:  And So I think the, the extent to which AI search can get down to
Speaker 4:  that more quickly. That's the stuff I think is really exciting.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Well it's very obvious that the race is on like Yeah. We have spent
Speaker 3:  so much time talking on Google and pissing off so many SEO people by the
Speaker 3:  way. The SEO people have all come around. They know. They know. and
Speaker 3:  it, it is very funny. They were all real mad and now they're like, oh shit.
Speaker 3:  You were right about the comment. A Google this week by the way,
Speaker 3:  in a workshop basically said, we don't know if search traffic is gonna back
Speaker 3:  to small websites. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And that you should prepare for it not to.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Brutal. Everyone's just saying it. Everyone yelled at me
Speaker 3:  now everyone's just like, here it is. Yeah. So we're gonna track this very
Speaker 3:  closely. David, you've been making the point that the, the money behind this
Speaker 3:  is just all over the place and no one really knows how it's gonna go. And
Speaker 3:  there was a lot of earnings this week. Yeah. Google had earnings, Microsoft
Speaker 3:  head earnings. Reddit is profitable first, first time ever. Snap. Not
Speaker 3:  so much snaps wrap. What do you, what do you, what do you see in here?
Speaker 4:  So, okay, I, I took a bunch of notes on the earnings reports this week and
Speaker 4:  I think as everyone knows, we kind of hate talking about earnings on this
Speaker 4:  show. Yeah. And also in general because who cares? Companies make
Speaker 4:  money, it's fine. But going through the earnings reports and
Speaker 4:  listening to the calls and stuff, just a bunch of the same things
Speaker 4:  kept jumping out to me and So I just wanna, I wanna just throw a couple of
Speaker 4:  the things I have noticed at you and I'm, I'm curious how it makes you
Speaker 4:  feel. The thing number one that just
Speaker 4:  jumps out to me over and over and over again is that the thing that AI is
Speaker 4:  being used for is to make everybody's very good ad businesses
Speaker 4:  even better. That actually it might be true right
Speaker 4:  now that the single thing AI does best, and I mean best in the
Speaker 4:  terms of like most money making is connect
Speaker 4:  an ad to a person, right? Which is like fundamentally a
Speaker 4:  big data problem. And, and ad targeting has been a question on the internet
Speaker 4:  for forever. And that Google talked about this, about how
Speaker 4:  YouTube advertising has gotten better. Meta talked about it, about how its
Speaker 4:  own advertising has gotten better, their revenue is going up as a result.
Speaker 4:  But the fact that AI is being fundamentally monetized
Speaker 4:  as an ad targeting thing is just so fascinating to me. And
Speaker 4:  I think, I think we're we're due for a long run of that that Yeah. What it
Speaker 4:  is is there is a mountain of data about me, there's an advertiser who is
Speaker 4:  looking for me and AI can find me faster than any
Speaker 4:  database software we've had before.
Speaker 3:  Oh you you, that's just scratching the surface. That's just step one.
Speaker 3:  'cause step two is what ad are you gonna see? Right?
Speaker 4:  Totally.
Speaker 3:  And every one of these companies is explicitly talking
Speaker 3:  about, well we'll just have the AI generate a custom ad
Speaker 3:  for you. Yep. Millions and millions and millions of iterations
Speaker 3:  of the same creative generated for, for people
Speaker 3:  specific taglines or specific needs. We know you were searching for
Speaker 3:  capes and, and black boots. Have you thought about grappling
Speaker 3:  hooks? Like, like exactly that thing. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It's gonna be weird. And there's a reason that they're all chasing video
Speaker 3:  generation. 'cause the thing they absolutely wanna do is make video ads
Speaker 3:  with influencers in them. Yes. And they're already, they're, they're
Speaker 3:  priming. And I don't mean to sound this in a conspiracy way. I mean this
Speaker 3:  is the reporting and this is what is happening. They're priming
Speaker 3:  the creators and their audiences to interact with ais
Speaker 3:  Meta. Meta has a thing where if you're an Instagram influencer, you can have
Speaker 3:  people talk to your AI trained on your Instagram data, which by the way includes
Speaker 3:  your threads posts. Which is wild. So our friend Katie
Speaker 3:  Pols at Business Insider, she's been engagement baiting
Speaker 3:  on threads just as a bit, yeah. Forever. And then she lit up her Instagram
Speaker 3:  bot and it trained on her threads. So her Instagram
Speaker 3:  bot is just an engagement bait bot. It's like perfect, that's perfect.
Speaker 3:  YouTube has this thing, right? They say out loud to creators, don't,
Speaker 3:  don't worry about all this like fan audience engagement. We want you to make
Speaker 3:  videos, make great content. We'll let the bot chat with your, with your viewers.
Speaker 3:  The turn to you can make the branded content with
Speaker 3:  an AI video of yourself is, it's not, that's not
Speaker 3:  a conspiracy theory. That is the plan. No. And I, I think that's from one
Speaker 3:  perspective that is fascinating. Will The Verge have something to write about
Speaker 3:  for the next 10 years? Yeah. Yes. I think we're gonna
Speaker 4:  Be okay.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Go get it. Like I'm, there's, there'll be a lot to unpack with all
Speaker 3:  that, but you just see where it's going and it is all, all of this effort
Speaker 3:  right now is pointed at advertising.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Lemme just do one more thing really quickly on the earnings thing because
Speaker 4:  I don't wanna talk about earnings because I hate earnings. But I found this
Speaker 4:  fascinating quote from Jen Wong, the CFO of Reddit talking about exactly
Speaker 4:  the thing you're describing. Lemme just read you this quote. She says, so
Speaker 4:  we launched a couple of quarters ago a headline generator using gen AI where
Speaker 4:  you can just put in the URL from your website and it actually gives you reddity
Speaker 4:  headlines that actually drive improved ad performance. And having reddity
Speaker 4:  type headlines in your ads really does make a difference in the ad resonance.
Speaker 4:  So that's just an example of I think what's possible in terms of ad creative.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And that is actually such a simple version of the thing that it's just
Speaker 4:  like here, here's a Reddit bot that you can just plug a headline
Speaker 4:  into and it will teach you how to Reddit. And like I just think about all
Speaker 4:  the brands who did all that like awful cringey stuff on Twitter for all those
Speaker 4:  years. This is about to get so horrible and so AI
Speaker 4:  driven in so many ugly ways. By
Speaker 3:  The way Mark Zuckerberg said more AI generated content is coming to Facebook
Speaker 3:  and Instagram and maybe even threads.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And they're, they're fine with this. This is a feature on not a bug
Speaker 4:  like it to, it's so, it's so is and everybody is fine with this.
Speaker 4:  So that's one thing is the ads. And then just the two other things I just
Speaker 4:  wanna say out loud because I, I feel like I'm losing my mind talking about
Speaker 4:  AI with people. One is that I think we all
Speaker 4:  still massively underrate how expensive the infrastructure for all of this
Speaker 4:  is. Almost every one of these companies has like gone out of its way and
Speaker 4:  its earning reports to talk about the increased
Speaker 4:  cost just of physical infrastructure of supporting
Speaker 4:  ai. And so like Sam Altman was out there being like, I need
Speaker 4:  $7 trillion to build data centers to make all this AI stuff possible.
Speaker 4:  Like the money is going to be crazy. Yeah. And the numbers are only going
Speaker 4:  up. And I think like anyone who wants to say we're in an AI bubble, like
Speaker 4:  those are the costs that are going to pop the bubble. So that's thing number
Speaker 4:  two. And then thing number three, and this is just the, the most important
Speaker 4:  point and the thing I want everyone to remember about AI is that anything
Speaker 4:  other than like back of house AI that is doing like
Speaker 4:  data analytics and helping customer service and all that stuff,
Speaker 4:  anything other than that is a total money pit that there is very little evidence
Speaker 4:  is actually working for anyone in the world. Like go read these earnings
Speaker 4:  reports. They all start with the CEO being like, here are some cool magical
Speaker 4:  things that we think we're inventing. And then the CFO comes on and is like,
Speaker 4:  all of that has cost us $16 billion this year. Here's how we've made our
Speaker 4:  money. Like over and over and over. That's what it is. All
Speaker 4:  of this other stuff is being built in service of like being
Speaker 4:  cool and exciting and getting in front of users. All of the actual utility
Speaker 4:  and more importantly all of the actual money. Here is the
Speaker 4:  boring B2B crap that nobody wants to talk about. Yeah. That is the AI story.
Speaker 3:  If, you want to hear more about how AI is flipping over the
Speaker 3:  advertising industry and creators in general. You should go listen to the
Speaker 3:  decoder episode with Amy Landey, who is the CEO of Digitas.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah, that was a good one. and
Speaker 3:  We, we did that in front of an audience and there was a lot of like ooh moments
Speaker 3:  and that was fun. And I asked her, what is the difference between a creator
Speaker 3:  and an influencer that got nowhere? Great icebreaker by the way, if you're
Speaker 3:  ever an ad world. 'cause no one knows. No one really knows. But inside of
Speaker 3:  that, we talked about this boring B2B stuff and what they're using a for
Speaker 3:  and it yeah, there's a big, there's the, we're gonna have a GI
Speaker 3:  like flashy noise and then there's the, like we're doing better ad
Speaker 3:  targeting reality. Right.
Speaker 4:  And to be clear, the the ad targeting reality is fine. Right? Like all of
Speaker 4:  that is well and good and, and those things are going to be very meaningful
Speaker 4:  to a lot of people in their jobs that are gonna make a lot of companies like
Speaker 4:  that's all great. Let's just talk about what it is, right? Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  OpenAI makes most of its money from that stuff. Not by bid
Speaker 4:  building. Digital God
Speaker 3:  By the way open. They haven't actually made more money than they spend yet.
Speaker 3:  So it's, they got a waste to go close. Not, not anywhere close.
Speaker 3:  And by the way, what they will disrupt is Google search, which
Speaker 3:  is one of the richest businesses in the history of the world. Yeah. Like
Speaker 3:  pure margin businesses that has ever existed. It's a lot.
Speaker 3:  It's like I said, I know
Speaker 3:  Hey, we're gonna be back with Joanna Stern to talk about all the Apple News.
Speaker 3:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  We're back. Joanna Stern is here. Welcome Joanna.
Speaker 6:  I'm here. Thank you for having me.
Speaker 3:  We're excited to talk to you. There's, I mean it's Apple Intelligence has
Speaker 3:  arrived with iOS 18.1. All of our lives are different. You're a robot now.
Speaker 6:  I am.
Speaker 3:  There was what came before and now there's today.
Speaker 6:  Tim Cook did tell the Wall Street Journal that it did change his life.
Speaker 6:  He did.
Speaker 3:  So there's actually a lot of Apple needs to go through with you. Apple had
Speaker 3:  its Mac Week. They announced a Mac Mini with an M four chip. It's
Speaker 3:  tiny and cute. We gotta talk about, it's everything's on the bottom. The
Speaker 3:  power button's on the bottom of the Mac Mini, the USBC port is still on the
Speaker 3:  bottom on the new Magic Mouse. There's new iMac, very colorful,
Speaker 3:  also has an M four chip in it. And then iOS 18.1
Speaker 3:  hit on Monday with the first shreds of Apple
Speaker 3:  Intelligence. and it is true, Tim Cook said that having his emails
Speaker 3:  summarized for him changed his life. Let's just start with Apple Intelligence
Speaker 3:  because honestly we can get through it in 30 seconds David.
Speaker 4:  It took me three and a half days after installing
Speaker 4:  iOS 18.1 to realize that I had it on my phone
Speaker 4:  because I opened up the mail app to look for something and was like, oh,
Speaker 4:  it's doing some of the things. And that's the extent of my
Speaker 4:  experience so far with the mail app. There's been a lot of like
Speaker 4:  productivity apps out there that are very excited about integrating all of
Speaker 4:  the writing tools. I'm sure they are fine and useful for some
Speaker 4:  people. The notification summaries seem fine. I like, I cannot,
Speaker 4:  I was prepared to be disappointed by how little was actually going on in
Speaker 4:  this first round of Apple Intelligence and it's actually even less
Speaker 4:  exciting than I was afraid of.
Speaker 6:  Wait, but you use the Apple Mail app?
Speaker 4:  No, I use it when occasionally I have to search and Gmail
Speaker 4:  is busted. Gmail search is sometimes very good and sometimes a
Speaker 4:  nightmare. And for whatever reason Apple Mail search is actually
Speaker 4:  occasionally very good. So every once in a while I just wander through my
Speaker 4:  inbox. Okay.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I don't use the Apple Mail app and I'm always, it's just wild to me
Speaker 6:  that If, you use Gmail, you use the Apple Mail app, but that is not the point
Speaker 6:  of this conversation.
Speaker 4:  Well, but it kind of is and I think I, I've been thinking about this Tim
Speaker 4:  Cook thing a lot since that story came out. and we, we made a lot of fun
Speaker 4:  of Tim Cook on this show for saying he uses every Apple product every day.
Speaker 4:  But the thing about Apple Intelligence is I think If, you
Speaker 4:  religiously and exclusively use Apple apps, it is probably
Speaker 4:  appearing in your life in some way. You're getting some of the writing tools,
Speaker 4:  the keyboard stuff is popping up. It's at least like,
Speaker 4:  maybe slightly more present. But like I do
Speaker 4:  most of my email in Gmail, which offers me lots of other weird
Speaker 4:  AI things that I don't need. But has essentially no awareness of Apple
Speaker 4:  Intelligence, which is just like the, the splitting of this
Speaker 4:  ecosystem is just getting weirder and
Speaker 6:  Weirder. Well I think that's one of the reasons the notification stuff did
Speaker 6:  kind of go so viral. 'cause it's like right there on your lock screen and
Speaker 6:  you have AI straight in your face summarizing things in a
Speaker 6:  funny or disappointing way. Right.
Speaker 3:  But, but like, what an incredible example of how AI is not
Speaker 3:  actually intelligent.
Speaker 3:  That's the first thing that everyone is experiencing is notification summaries
Speaker 3:  that have literally no context or relevance
Speaker 3:  or understanding of what is happening. Like my ring camera
Speaker 3:  every morning, the notification summaries just crack me up. 'cause it, it
Speaker 3:  sounds like there's a home invasion every single day in
Speaker 4:  My house. What was the one you shared yesterday? It was like people at the
Speaker 4:  front door and back door and inside. Yeah. Several
Speaker 3:  People at the front door, back door and driveway.
Speaker 6:  Mine is right now literally And So I. Actually this I, this is why I'm here.
Speaker 6:  Let's be honest. I'm here to talk about the ring notifications that I, that
Speaker 6:  I, that I talked about with Craig Federighi. Well that was
Speaker 6:  the garage notifications. But the smart home notifications are the
Speaker 6:  best part. I don't care if they're not intelligent. They're amazing. This
Speaker 6:  is mine from Ring right now. I'm gonna, we should, we should bring up the
Speaker 6:  screenshot Missing dog with 99 on its back.
Speaker 6:  Multiple people at the front door two minutes ago. Yeah. Multiple people
Speaker 6:  are there. Yeah. Now it is a Halloween as we're taping this,
Speaker 6:  but there's no, I'm looking at my camera. No one is there and one person
Speaker 6:  showed up.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Well it's just, and that's because, yeah, it's because there were, you know,
Speaker 6:  people going in and out of the house from 8:00 AM on and it
Speaker 6:  summarizes.
Speaker 4:  So there was one person and there was one person and there was a dog. and
Speaker 4:  it goes, there are multiple people and a dog outside of your house. Yes.
Speaker 3:  And it, it's funny because that is, if there was actual
Speaker 3:  intelligence sort of noisy, smart home sensor
Speaker 3:  notifications are exactly what you would want that intelligence to help you
Speaker 3:  sort through. My back door opens and closes
Speaker 3:  500 times a day and I only want
Speaker 3:  notifications sometimes.
Speaker 3:  And you would think in AI would be like, okay, like we see this
Speaker 3:  pattern. We're going to, we're gonna pair this down and be like,
Speaker 3:  the normal stuff happened this morning. This one didn't happen at the right
Speaker 3:  time. And maybe that should be in Ring. Maybe the smart home vendor should
Speaker 3:  do it. Maybe it should be somewhere else. But Apple Intelligence as it summarizes
Speaker 3:  notifications, it, it's just the clearest demonstration
Speaker 3:  that it doesn't actually know any like a, these LLMs don't actually know
Speaker 3:  what they're talking about.
Speaker 6:  The part that I talked about with Feder in my interview was the example I
Speaker 6:  gave him, which was working really well for me and still does, is the garage
Speaker 6:  because it's very, it's up and open and close and
Speaker 6:  that's it. It open and closes all day long. And then
Speaker 6:  there's a summary. It says it repeatedly opened and closed
Speaker 6:  and then it was recently closed. And that usually is
Speaker 6:  like, that's very helpful to me. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Isn't that exactly the same thing as just putting the one that says
Speaker 4:  it's closed at the top of the stack, which is what it would chronologically
Speaker 4:  do. Like what, what new problem is this solving for you?
Speaker 6:  That I know it was opened and closed a lot of times by my family and
Speaker 6:  then it was recently closed.
Speaker 3:  I guess here's the question that I've been thinking a lot about and it, every
Speaker 3:  time I'm forced to reconsider the amount of smart home notifications I get,
Speaker 3:  I ask myself, do I need to know this?
Speaker 3:  Do I need to know that Max went in and outta the house 50 times through the
Speaker 3:  back door? Like that's just, my parents didn't know that in the eighties.
Speaker 3:  They, they had no idea where I was to be clear.
Speaker 3:  And I'm like, actually I don't need all this additional help and this AI
Speaker 3:  and we should get off smart home notification. 'cause it's a, it's a little
Speaker 3:  corner case. It is very funny. I do think it's a good demonstration of the
Speaker 3:  fact that LMS don't actually know what they're talking about, but in this
Speaker 3:  case it's almost blinding how useless most of these
Speaker 3:  notifications are. And the only thing that's happened is because they're
Speaker 3:  slightly different. You're paying attention to them again and you're like,
Speaker 3:  oh, this is still useless. And I will just quickly start tuning them out
Speaker 3:  the way that I tune out most of my smart home notifications,
Speaker 6:  I was just on the road for 10 days and I didn't turn off my smart
Speaker 6:  home notifications. Oh my God. And maybe there's
Speaker 6:  an emotional attach, like I feel a deeply emotional like
Speaker 6:  with these because I'm not at home deeply emotional. Some
Speaker 6:  emotional attachment to these smart home notifications, your
Speaker 3:  Connection to your family, to your
Speaker 6:  Two children. My only connection to my family for 10, 10 days, and that's
Speaker 6:  where I'm going with this, was was seeing these smart home
Speaker 6:  notifications went so dark. This
Speaker 6:  is really symbolic and they mean a lot to me. And I'm not going to let them
Speaker 6:  go. And I would like to thank Apple Intelligence for resurfacing
Speaker 6:  them in my life.
Speaker 3:  I feel like my children are here. You give a speech
Speaker 4:  Closed, you know, Joanna's like, oh,
Speaker 3:  20 years ago when I saw that first smart notification
Speaker 3:  with your, with your partner. I knew they were the one.
Speaker 4:  Joanna, I'm gonna make you like a yearbook of your kids. But it's just gonna
Speaker 4:  be smart home notifications about what they're
Speaker 6:  Doing. It's so true. It'll be like, it'll be like child playing
Speaker 6:  basketball on front, on front garage or
Speaker 6:  child now driving to prom. Yeah. It's
Speaker 6:  child's now bringing home man or woman and
Speaker 3:  They're gonna play that one Green Day song in the background as we do a slides
Speaker 3:  show. It's gonna be
Speaker 6:  Amazing. And Apple intelligence will slowly get more intelligent. As
Speaker 6:  Craig Federici said, this is a decades long arc Yeah. To getting it
Speaker 6:  better. That's a direct quote.
Speaker 3:  So I, I wanna come back to that conversation after Craig, which was a couple
Speaker 3:  weeks ago at the WSJ Tech live conference. I just wanna say notification
Speaker 3:  summaries for one more second outside of smart home stuff. The other promise
Speaker 3:  is we're gonna summarize your emails, we're gonna summarize Slack, whatever
Speaker 3:  other notifications you are getting. Has that been useful? Because
Speaker 3:  I will tell you, I laughed at it for a day or two and then turned them off
Speaker 3:  because I actually found those notifications because I actually found the
Speaker 3:  summaries to be more confusing. Like ultimately they were more distracting.
Speaker 3:  'cause I was like, what is going on here? I got one from the family group
Speaker 3:  chat that just said my niece was jealous and felt left out and it
Speaker 3:  all, it was, was her friends were going to an event.
Speaker 3:  Like she was just saying, I'm they're going and I'm jealous and I'm not going
Speaker 3:  to this concert. And that was it. and it was like other otherwise totally
Speaker 3:  normal except the summary made it seem like the highest stakes thing
Speaker 3:  in the world.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. My mom sent me like a really emotional text. She had to go to a funeral
Speaker 6:  and it was a whole thing and then it just said expresses gratitude and
Speaker 6:  it was like really, really long, like very long amount of
Speaker 6:  texts and I was like, oh, okay. I mean, yeah, I think the question
Speaker 6:  is they're funny and the point of them is to save time,
Speaker 6:  but they're not saving any time because you then go and read the full thing
Speaker 6:  anyway, so it doesn't really achieve anything. Well
Speaker 4:  It's that, it's that okay thing that is actually, I think in a weird way,
Speaker 4:  like the intended response and is also why I hate it
Speaker 4:  for texting. I actually think it's useful for email in the sense that you
Speaker 4:  get a lot of email and a huge portion of it. All you really need to know
Speaker 4:  is that it exists. Yeah. Right. Like it, it is, it is some piece of
Speaker 4:  information that you need to be made aware of or some kind of like confirmation
Speaker 4:  or status check. And that's the kind of thing you can take from a giant long
Speaker 4:  email into eight words and I can just be like tight and go on living my life.
Speaker 4:  What I have discovered with the AI summaries for text messages is they've
Speaker 4:  made me such a worse texter really. And I'm a bad texter
Speaker 4:  anyway, but the just the thing where I have to open a message in order
Speaker 4:  to understand what is in the message goes a long way toward
Speaker 4:  me being a reliable responder to that message. And so now I'm getting
Speaker 4:  a lot of things where it's just like, the message is just like mom
Speaker 4:  on her way. And I'm like, all right. And I just move on and I'm like, no
Speaker 4:  crap, I have to respond. All
Speaker 3:  You are to me is a status update.
Speaker 4:  Right. It's like it's, it's, it's not even as good as
Speaker 4:  like the tap back emojis. It's just, it's just me saying, okay, I
Speaker 4:  can now move on because I've been given this personality free piece of
Speaker 4:  information and then it's like, oh no, that's a text from my mom. I should
Speaker 4:  go respond to that. And that, that is, I turned that off immediately because
Speaker 4:  it was like preventing me from actually engaging, I actually think with messages
Speaker 6:  And to, yeah, to that point, So I found the text from my mom. It was really
Speaker 6:  long. It was, it was, you know, it's like one of those from your parents.
Speaker 6:  It's like, you know, they don't send it in chunks, they just send it all.
Speaker 6:  Like, they wrote a long, long letter. I don't know if,
Speaker 4:  Does she sign her messages at the end? She she
Speaker 6:  Does. She's she's better about that. But it, it just said, reflecting on
Speaker 6:  life, expressing gratitude and wishing a safe trip home.
Speaker 6:  And I found that so funny that I sent her the, the summary
Speaker 6:  and said, look how this summarized it. And I never actually responded to
Speaker 6:  her long thoughtful note.
Speaker 6:  You
Speaker 4:  Just sent her a screenshot.
Speaker 6:  I was like, look how it edited you.
Speaker 4:  You're like, this is so meaningful.
Speaker 6:  And she wrote back, she's like, I guess I could have been shorter. You know,
Speaker 6:  like,
Speaker 3:  So, you know, it's funny is a bigger feature in iOS 18 for me is send later
Speaker 3:  in messages. Oh yeah. Because I never
Speaker 3:  want to be the person who replies instantly, even though I see a
Speaker 3:  lot of things. And yeah, I just being able to like send this in five more
Speaker 3:  minutes makes me reply to more messages. It's a little hidden. They got
Speaker 3:  it wrong. They got the UI wrong. They should have done it the way that Slack
Speaker 3:  does it, which is you just hold down the send button and it, like, once you
Speaker 3:  schedule it, you gotta like dig through the menus. Find
Speaker 6:  You gotta go to the plus button. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's a little, it's a little messy, but it works. And that is like,
Speaker 3:  to your point, David, it makes, it takes me out of the this as a status message.
Speaker 3:  I've like seen and done it. I've taken the action and then I've moved on.
Speaker 3:  And because there's, I might be bonkers about this, but
Speaker 3:  my feeling is like, if there's a little delay in the response, it makes it
Speaker 3:  so that we are not about to have a conversation. Like I've just answered
Speaker 3:  your question. That's
Speaker 6:  So smart. I was about to say like, who are you playing it cool with?
Speaker 3:  But then I play cool with everybody all the time. Yeah. All of NE's texts
Speaker 3:  say, send this in three tickets. Sorry, I didn't see this. I
Speaker 3:  write, sorry, I didn't see this immediately. And then schedule it for a couple
Speaker 3:  days from now.
Speaker 6:  But actually that's genius because you are, you are indicating to the, to
Speaker 6:  the receiver, Hey, I'm not like available right now. Like, oh,
Speaker 6:  like I'm in the middle of something super important even though I just sat
Speaker 6:  here and scheduled my message. But you're, you're, you're unavailable. Like
Speaker 6:  you're available but you're not available. Your is your signal, which
Speaker 3:  Is Right. I'm, I'm being responsive. But this is not about to be a chat.
Speaker 3:  Like, I'm just letting you know that they, and I have a, the, an infinite
Speaker 3:  amount of incoming where I just need to deliver an answer
Speaker 3:  and not have like a 25 minute conversation. And that's fine. And like
Speaker 3:  people always see screenshots of my home screen. And it's always just like
Speaker 3:  so many unreads and it's like, this is what the
Speaker 3:  AI should help me do is be like, you're just gonna parse through all of these.
Speaker 3:  We figured out the ones you need to answer. We're gonna help you get through
Speaker 3:  it. And instead these summaries I think are just not useful. And I,
Speaker 3:  I, I keep coming back to like, we've invented LLMs. We are
Speaker 3:  desperate for them to solve problems. This problem seems
Speaker 3:  solvable. And then you like sit here holding the solution in your hand and
Speaker 3:  you're like, yeah, the door opened and closed a lot. Right. You know,
Speaker 3:  like, actually send later, which we could have invented 10 years ago,
Speaker 3:  is much more useful than the notification summary. Apple
Speaker 6:  Intelligence does include in this, the prioritize priority
Speaker 6:  notifications where the, it is supposed to help. I haven't used it
Speaker 6:  a lot. In fact, I probably should have turned that on here instead of do
Speaker 6:  not disturb for the podcast.
Speaker 6:  I used it once during, I was on a video shoot and it did, I mean, it did
Speaker 6:  send, it did prioritize like notifications for my wife and family
Speaker 6:  and like group chats over Slacks.
Speaker 3:  Children continue to grow up in the background
Speaker 6:  Over my ring notifications that I, I'm deeply emotionally attached
Speaker 6:  to.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I'm gonna put that on right now. Have
Speaker 3:  You used any of the other IS 18.1 Apple Intelligence
Speaker 3:  features? For real? I feel like the notifications are the ones everyone's
Speaker 3:  using for real because of what you said, Joanna, they're just in your face.
Speaker 3:  But the writing tools, the image tools
Speaker 3:  fine. Like I'm, I'm a very precious writer.
Speaker 3:  I'm just, I'm not really fond of letting AI write for me. I I've avoided
Speaker 3:  them mostly. They're a little buried. They're not in your face.
Speaker 4:  No, they're not. But I will say I've, I've just come to realize that I'm
Speaker 4:  not the target audience for the writing tools and that's fun. Yep. Right.
Speaker 4:  Agreed. We're we're three people who write sentences for a living and that
Speaker 4:  is not actually most people. And so like, I'm, that's just, that's fine.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I've used it like in notes. Like I'll sometimes draft like PR
Speaker 6:  notes and stuff in notes and so I've used it there, but I don't find it that
Speaker 6:  it's like doing much for me. I mean, I use notes a lot.
Speaker 6:  I use the Notes app a lot. But that's another place, like, like
Speaker 6:  I felt, I felt like the list and the summarization tool might be helpful.
Speaker 6:  'cause like sometimes I like make sloppy lists and like, okay, clean up the
Speaker 6:  list. But then it just, like, it adds bullets in front of my dashes
Speaker 6:  and like, I've already had dashes in my list and then I
Speaker 6:  just had put
Speaker 3:  List, these are problems that the very basic algorithms in Microsoft Word
Speaker 3:  solved 25 years ago. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But then it added bullets in front of my dashes and that's, I never used
Speaker 6:  it again.
Speaker 3:  I'm just telling you like if there were podcasts in like 1986, we would've
Speaker 3:  been like, I don't know, it's this, it is New Mac, like sadden
Speaker 3:  dashes to the bullets.
Speaker 3:  I have used the call recorder with the AI transcription. Oh yeah. It's very
Speaker 3:  good.
Speaker 4:  It's really, it's very, yeah, that was the one I was gonna say too. And you
Speaker 4:  can do a voice memo and dump it into notes with the transcription, which
Speaker 4:  is very handy. Like yes. That stuff is very cool. Well,
Speaker 6:  I would say the summary is not good. I don't know. If you found the summary
Speaker 6:  to be good, which is the actual intelligence. Yeah. But just having the
Speaker 6:  transcription there, which is not an Apple intelligence feature, and you
Speaker 6:  can get that, I think going back to iPhone thirteens or something like that.
Speaker 6:  There's a cutoff on
Speaker 3:  This. Wait, they're, they're not using any LLM stuff to make the transcriptions
Speaker 3:  better because like, you know, like OpenAI has Whisper, which is
Speaker 3:  its AI powered transcription. Right. and it, there are some reports that
Speaker 3:  it's inaccurate in some of its cases. I think there was one about people
Speaker 3:  using hospitals, right.
Speaker 6:  In hospitals. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And it's not being great, which is not great. And also just a classic AI
Speaker 3:  story, but it's better. I think the, the stat I saw is that the
Speaker 3:  AI transcription systems are now on average better than
Speaker 3:  the worst. Human transcriptions
Speaker 4:  Whisper's really good, right? Like I've, I've been using Whisper a ton. We
Speaker 4:  use it a ton for Vergecast stuff and it's really good. I'm not
Speaker 4:  surprised, like a hospital is the ultimate stress test of anything. It's
Speaker 4:  just full of words that don't exist outside of hospitals.
Speaker 4:  And so that's always gonna be tough and you should never rely on these systems
Speaker 4:  a hundred percent. But like all of this speech to text and
Speaker 4:  even basic summarization stuff has gotten pretty good.
Speaker 4:  Apple intelligence, I would not say is leading the summarization game.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But a lot of that stuff is, is pretty good at this point.
Speaker 6:  I mean, this is it. I do think that there's no AI
Speaker 6:  in the, I mean there's obviously an AI model that is on device that's doing
Speaker 6:  the transcription, but like anyone, you don't need Apple intelligence to
Speaker 6:  do that,
Speaker 3:  Right?
Speaker 6:  As that's what I'm reading right now, just to confirm what I said before.
Speaker 6:  So yes, the summarization part is Apple intelligence
Speaker 3:  And that's the part that's not very
Speaker 6:  Good and that's the part that's not very good. But the part that is really
Speaker 6:  good, that is, it really is a game changer for me. It's like, yeah, some,
Speaker 6:  you know, source just calls or I'm doing a quick and I'm Oh, hit record,
Speaker 6:  it works great and the transcription's fine. It Yeah. You know, you at least
Speaker 6:  can go like, it's great for scrolling and saying, oh, that's the part I need
Speaker 6:  to talk
Speaker 3:  To. Yeah. To find the audio I need. Yep. Right. Yep. And this is very, again,
Speaker 3:  to David's point, this is three people who just like do this task all the
Speaker 3:  time. And this is very useful, but it is a useful upgrade
Speaker 3:  to iOS 18. Everybody who has a pixel phone or an Android
Speaker 3:  phone. Yes. I'm aware that these phones have had this stuff and it has been
Speaker 3:  great for a long time. Yeah. I'm just looking at this sweep of things that
Speaker 3:  have been added to my phone with iOS 18.1 and Apple Intelligence.
Speaker 3:  And it's like this stuff, which I just keep coming back to is the
Speaker 3:  basics. Yeah. Should we be able to figure out when to add bullets instead
Speaker 3:  of dashes instead of adding them both solved problem?
Speaker 3:  Should we be able to send messages later solved problem?
Speaker 3:  Should my phone app have a call recorder and it that does reasonably good
Speaker 3:  transition solve problem? But now we're bundling them all up into Apple intelligence,
Speaker 3:  but obviously the developer betas of iOS 18.2
Speaker 3:  out at the same time. So there's a real mash of what people are
Speaker 3:  looking at, what people are talking about. The more interesting features
Speaker 3:  are in 18.2, visual intelligence chat, CBT integration,
Speaker 3:  I guess, we'll, we'll wait on that, but it's here. You know, we, we, a,
Speaker 3:  a big conversation we were having, and Joan, I'm curious how you have thought
Speaker 3:  about this is we reviewed the phones without Apple intelligence in them 'cause
Speaker 3:  of our rule review what's in the box. And then we're like, maybe we have
Speaker 3:  to re-review them now that it's here. And I'm kind of like, but you don't,
Speaker 3:  no, because there's nothing like, I don't know what to say about that. What
Speaker 3:  are you gonna do? Oh
Speaker 6:  No, I'm, I'm, I'm done with coverage. We've, we done now
Speaker 6:  we done now
Speaker 3:  All
Speaker 6:  Done 18.2. Yeah. I'll revisit
Speaker 6:  and maybe there's some significant stuff there. Let's just talk about the
Speaker 6:  most important thing that was added in 18.1. And I, I
Speaker 6:  mentioned this when I did your installer.
Speaker 6:  When I, what's my installer thing that I submitted the, anyway, I don't know
Speaker 6:  your home, just your home screen. My home screen that yeah, that section
Speaker 6:  in 18.1. You can finally in control center, add
Speaker 6:  a wifi widget.
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  Or control. So again, probably something they would've talked about
Speaker 6:  in, what was it, 86 you mentioned on the podcast
Speaker 3:  You had a wifi widget
Speaker 6:  On the screen. You can actually just do the wifi and now
Speaker 6:  you can just do the wifi and it's amazing.
Speaker 4:  Strongly agree. It's control center. I set mine up
Speaker 4:  after you sent me your home screen being like, control center's. The greatest
Speaker 4:  thing that ever happened to me. I was like, all right, cool. Whatever Joanna,
Speaker 4:  you're right. It's great. I now spend a lot of time just like mucking around
Speaker 4:  in control center
Speaker 6:  Doing stuff because smart home stuff,
Speaker 3:  I feel like the control center is Apple with. They're like, fine, you
Speaker 3:  want customization? Here's what it's like. And then next year they'll be
Speaker 3:  like, we're we're going back to telling you exactly how this works because
Speaker 3:  it's obviously crazy to do it this way.
Speaker 6:  Well there's one like me Murphy, it's
Speaker 3:  Going arounds. You're getting what you wished for
Speaker 6:  And somebody's just put wifi controls, the entire control center's wifi
Speaker 6:  controls. and it's like, that's dream. That's exactly what you're talking
Speaker 6:  about. And you're like, they're like, you wanted customization. Look at this.
Speaker 6:  Look at this asshole. Look what he's done. Yeah. Oh yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's the same with all the colors and stuff. Oh. They're like, oh, you, you
Speaker 4:  want your phone to be ugly? Knock yourself out. Have an ugly phone. Finally
Speaker 4:  enjoy your ugly phone. Finally, the
Speaker 3:  IPhone is brown. Like
Speaker 4:  You'll never ever figure out how to do it except by accident. But
Speaker 4:  Godspeed.
Speaker 3:  All right. That's iOS 18.1 Apple intelligence. It is a baby
Speaker 3:  step. As Craig told Joanna, you shall go watch that video of that interview.
Speaker 3:  It's very good. We gotta mostly talk about his garage door open our situation.
Speaker 3:  But we'll come to that. The other Apple news is the
Speaker 3:  week of max, which is mostly just spec bumps.
Speaker 3:  The new IMAX have an M four chip in them.
Speaker 3:  They're very nice. The new MacBook Pros have M four Pros and M four Max chips
Speaker 3:  in them. Very nice. There's new colors on the imax, which are very bold.
Speaker 3:  We have some beautiful pictures that Vier and we took of them, you know,
Speaker 3:  look at those. But they're the same. They're just spec bumps, right? New
Speaker 3:  chips. It's the MAC mini that's got everybody just
Speaker 3:  raving. It's like little baby Mac M four chip in
Speaker 3:  it. It's very small. It's, it's the same volume I think as the outgoing
Speaker 3:  Mac Mini, but it's taller instead of, it's like they un smed the
Speaker 3:  pancake.
Speaker 6:  I'm sorry to interrupt, but I did put on the priority
Speaker 6:  notifications or the whatever it is, reduced interruptions where Apple intelligence
Speaker 6:  is supposed to then surface the important notifications. And this is
Speaker 6:  just a chain of moms talking about when we are gonna be going trick or treating.
Speaker 3:  And that's a priority to interrupt our whole show with.
Speaker 6:  And I never ever respond quickly to these chain of moms to be clear,
Speaker 6:  I mean, if the chain of moms are listening to this, I'm sorry
Speaker 6:  that I usually mute the channel, but
Speaker 3:  Joanna, first of all, I don't think you understand how many New Jersey moms
Speaker 3:  listen to our show. That's a demo. I
Speaker 6:  Why, why I'm here. I'm here to bring them to the show.
Speaker 3:  Also, chain of Moms sounds like a doop group. And you should
Speaker 3:  absolutely start that immediately
Speaker 6:  Anyway. If we are doing a live review of Apple Intelligence, which I thought
Speaker 6:  we were doing on this show, I interrupt the show to tell you this chain of
Speaker 6:  moms is, it's now blowing up my phone and Apple Intelligence seems to think
Speaker 6:  I care. It says maybe important, maybe I, it's actually
Speaker 6:  really not important.
Speaker 3:  I do like our new segment where you just read us your notifications from
Speaker 3:  time to time on the air. We're gonna keep that going.
Speaker 6:  It's the new Joanna's on the case.
Speaker 3:  Joanna's on the case with the, with New Jersey moms. I'm
Speaker 4:  Realizing you both get a lot more notifications than I do. Maybe it's just
Speaker 4:  because I don't have the smart home stuff, but I have like systematically
Speaker 4:  turned off basically every notification that isn't texts
Speaker 4:  from people responsible for the life of my child. Like that's, that's essentially
Speaker 4:  it. Almost no one else gets to send me notifications.
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna install a ring camera in your house just to send you notifications
Speaker 3:  so that you can, it feels like a home invasion every single morning. We need
Speaker 3:  to talk about the Mac mini, which is actually the
Speaker 6:  New, I'm sorry, I'm very sorry we're going back.
Speaker 3:  We're we're It's fine. Tell the New Jersey moms that you're about to talk
Speaker 3:  about the Mac Mini.
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna buy them all one for for saying that I never respond to them and
Speaker 6:  muting their chain all the time.
Speaker 3:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  And you can, it's only $599. Right.
Speaker 3:  So David, the thing about this MAC Mini, you have been talking about wanting
Speaker 3:  to upgrade your M1 Mac mini that I basically cajoled you into buying
Speaker 3:  Correct. For a long time. Is this gonna do it?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Oh yeah. This is, I mean this is the M mini people wanted.
Speaker 4:  There are a couple of little less than ideal things. I think it's a bummer
Speaker 4:  that it doesn't have an ST card reader. You'd obviously like there to be
Speaker 4:  more IO all the time. This one has three
Speaker 4:  USBC ports on the back and two USBC ports on the front.
Speaker 3:  Well, no, it's Thunderbolt on the back. Thunderbolt four on the back and
Speaker 3:  SBC on the front, which is very confusing 'cause the ports are
Speaker 4:  The same. Oh, that's, yeah. Okay. That's actually a good distinction. I was
Speaker 4:  about to make a face at you for trying to distinguish all the dumb thunderbolt
Speaker 4:  stuff, but that's, that's a good distinction. But anyway, kill me.
Speaker 4:  So like more IO would be good. I personally, there are two things about this
Speaker 4:  thing that I don't care about at all, and I would just like to say them out
Speaker 4:  loud so that we can then move on. I don't care that it's smaller. The, the
Speaker 4:  Mac mini, the size that it was was fine. And I guess if you're
Speaker 4:  like rolling giant stacks of them into a server
Speaker 4:  array, so you can run a weird third party messaging app, hypothetically,
Speaker 4:  this would be very useful to you. I don't care. I'm going to stick
Speaker 4:  it where my current Mac mini is. It's going to take up slightly less space.
Speaker 4:  It'll be fine. That's thing number one I don't care about. Thing number two
Speaker 4:  I don't care about is that the power button is on the bottom. I just, I just
Speaker 4:  don't care. I also, I should say this out loud, don't care that you charge
Speaker 4:  the Magic Mouse on the bottom. Don't care about that either. That one I do
Speaker 4:  care. These are not problems. The, this is we, we can,
Speaker 3:  We can argue separate these about all these Let's separate, let's separate
Speaker 3:  these two.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So the power button is on the bottom of the MAC mini. That is fine.
Speaker 4:  Agreed. Would it be cooler if it were on the front? Sure.
Speaker 4:  Do I have any feelings about it at all? No. What I think is great is that
Speaker 4:  this thing is still 509 $9. It now starts with 16 gigs of ram.
Speaker 4:  Yep. Which is awesome. It has an M four chip, which is awesome.
Speaker 4:  Like this. This thing is just what it is supposed to be, which I think is
Speaker 4:  the thing that Apple is starting to do really well with Max is it just gives
Speaker 4:  you the computer that you feel like you should have. Right? Like this is
Speaker 4:  the one with the newest chip. It has most of the IO that I want. It still
Speaker 4:  has an ethernet port. It'll still plug into HDMI. Like this is just the computer
Speaker 4:  that I want and that is delightful. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  You know, it's interesting because they spent so much time trying so hard
Speaker 3:  to reinvent Macs or to kill them in favor of the iPad
Speaker 3:  or whatever they were doing. Just scattershot Mac ideas.
Speaker 3:  What if the keyboard sucked? Like just right. What if they were so thin the
Speaker 3:  batteries only lasted five minutes and now they're just like, they're really
Speaker 3:  good computers and we're just gonna keep iterating them, which is all they
Speaker 3:  needed to do. It's also kind of a sign that all of their most
Speaker 3:  innovative ideas are pointed elsewhere, which is kind of weird, right? Like,
Speaker 3:  you would like them to have one Mac that was just
Speaker 3:  bananas. But I don't think that Mac should be the, the Mac mini, to be clear,
Speaker 3:  it just, the thing you're talking about is just very obvious to the point
Speaker 3:  where the new MacBook pros, they didn't even update the wallpapers. They
Speaker 3:  were just like, here, here it is again. You know, like Yeah. And all that's
Speaker 3:  fine. Like I, I'm with you. I think this Mac mini is great. I do, I will
Speaker 3:  say there are a lot of people who deploy Mac Minis in things like racks
Speaker 3:  in other weird places where having to take the
Speaker 3:  thing out and turn it over in case something goes wrong and reboot it
Speaker 3:  will be a pain in the ass.
Speaker 4:  Sure. Fair. Yeah. Totally
Speaker 6:  Agree. But that's not like, not the complaint. Like I tweeted about this
Speaker 6:  and I always regret that. But, and also on Andreas, like,
Speaker 6:  I mean, just the anger of some people being like that this is on the bottom
Speaker 6:  and that like, 'cause I just asked a basic question, which is how often are
Speaker 6:  you people restarting or turning off your, your max?
Speaker 6:  and it turns out like there's a lot of people that turn off their max. I
Speaker 6:  don't, I don't know why. I mean, these are not built to be turned off every
Speaker 6:  day. At the end of the day, this is again, not a podcast in 1986,
Speaker 6:  but people do it and seem very angry about the
Speaker 6:  location.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I don't get it.
Speaker 4:  I will say I briefly went through a phase where I would shut down my computer
Speaker 4:  at the end of the day just as a like symbolic. My, my
Speaker 4:  computer day is now over thing and it was kind of great to be honest. There's
Speaker 4:  something nice about, like, I have now turned my computer off even though
Speaker 4:  it takes a grand total of like six seconds to boot a Mac now. Like it's not
Speaker 4:  slow, it's fine. But I, I don't know, I probably
Speaker 4:  restart my Mac mini once every two weeks and I
Speaker 4:  do it by software. Like I don't ever
Speaker 4:  hit the, I can't reach the power button on my Mac mini from where I'm sitting
Speaker 4:  right
Speaker 6:  Now. How do you turn it on?
Speaker 4:  I restart it. I literally don't think I've turned it on from
Speaker 6:  Dead. Oh. Like you haven't turned it shut down. You haven't done like shut
Speaker 6:  down. No.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. In a a year maybe. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Sometimes
Speaker 4:  The power goes out and I have to like pull the thing out. So I can reach
Speaker 4:  behind, but that's it. Like, I just don't think this is a real problem. And
Speaker 4:  again, for the people who use these things in server rack and stuff, I, I
Speaker 4:  grant that it's an issue. You're not the target customer, right? Like
Speaker 4:  this is not, that's not who Apple is making this thing for.
Speaker 3:  No, actually for the, the many, the many is the one where everyone
Speaker 3:  is the target customer in apple's own marketing kind of demonstrates this,
Speaker 3:  right? They're, they're showing here's this modular little box that you can
Speaker 3:  put in all these different environments and they can't, they have to, it's
Speaker 3:  Apple, right? So it has to be like a person with a guitar and a person
Speaker 3:  who's drawing. and it's never like the person who's running the third party
Speaker 3:  messaging service that hijacks iMessage. But like there are a lot of Mac
Speaker 3:  minis and server racks. This is a thing that these computers are used for
Speaker 3:  for sure. And fine. I, my thing that I don't understand about turning
Speaker 3:  off the computer is that actually whenever I cold boot a Mac, it
Speaker 3:  takes forever for it to just be fast again. Do you guys not
Speaker 3:  notice this? You
Speaker 4:  Gotta, you gotta, you gotta delete some login items, my man.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. I have the same, but like, it's because I, yeah. I have some
Speaker 6:  startup items that I just, like it's starting.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Whatever. I was just like, it's slower. I do think the idea that I
Speaker 3:  should keep my computer in like a library room or like a computer room
Speaker 3:  with like that weird eighties oak furniture and I should turn it
Speaker 3:  off every time I'm done using it. That might make me healthier. That might
Speaker 3:  be better for all of us. That will save America.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That's, that's David's version of the emotional notifications.
Speaker 4:  A hundred percent. Yeah. I, I get to walk into my computer room and sit down
Speaker 4:  at my computer chair in front of my giant computer box and it's great.
Speaker 4:  Wait, the, the point you just made about the way Apple is talking about this
Speaker 4:  thing, did that feel really different to you? Because my memory of the Mac
Speaker 4:  Mini was that it was always like kind of the iPhone SE that it's just like
Speaker 4:  a thing that some people like, but it's kind of over here and we're never
Speaker 4:  gonna really talk about it or pay much attention to it. Whereas this
Speaker 4:  time it feels very like front and center. This is a
Speaker 4:  mainstream Mac. Like they talk about this thing and market it and are putting
Speaker 4:  it in pictures the way that they do with like the MacBook Air. Yeah. Which
Speaker 4:  just really surprised me.
Speaker 3:  I think that's a weird post pandemic work
Speaker 3:  from home change.
Speaker 3:  There are lots of people out there who bought three monitors to work from
Speaker 3:  home in the pandemic. There are, we, we cover desk setups
Speaker 3:  on our own site all the time. There are lots of people who spend a lot of
Speaker 3:  time buying mechanical keyboards and like cool aesthetic monitors.
Speaker 3:  And I think how do you put a Mac into that mix?
Speaker 3:  This is the answer. You can just swap out whatever you have and here's this
Speaker 3:  little modular Mac and now it's part of a whole lifestyle. And I think that
Speaker 3:  the Mac mini before was like a utility computer
Speaker 3:  and now it is a lifestyle computer and it's be, I I really do
Speaker 3:  think that's just a change. Like even when I've had like CEOs from
Speaker 3:  peripheral companies like Logitech or whatever on decoder, they're talking
Speaker 3:  about this as a market. Like people are building desk setups, they're
Speaker 3:  building a gaming PC setup next to a productivity setup. They want them to
Speaker 3:  be beautiful. It's just a, people spend all day watching movies in these
Speaker 3:  setups now. It's like there's a lot going on in the computer room, which
Speaker 3:  is now every room.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I also think one thing that happened was that
Speaker 6:  they discontinued the 27 inch iMac. And
Speaker 6:  so That's fair I when that happened and they just went to
Speaker 6:  24 inches, I heard from a lot of readers who were pissed. Yep. And so the
Speaker 6:  best option was a Mac mini and a big monitor.
Speaker 4:  Yep.
Speaker 6:  Versus getting a Mac with a studio. Was it the Mac
Speaker 6:  studio? The
Speaker 3:  The studio display.
Speaker 6:  The studio, yeah. Well I, and I don't think a lot of people are buying, like
Speaker 6:  if you're getting a Mac mini, you wanted a, like an iMac competitor. Either
Speaker 6:  you're getting a studio display or just getting a cheaper 27 inch display
Speaker 6:  or bigger display. And I think that kind of took that market. So yeah,
Speaker 6:  that kind of became the
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I did that for my, in-laws maybe a year ago. They had like an
Speaker 4:  ancient 27 inch iMac and really did not wanna go down to 24 inches.
Speaker 4:  And so like every three months my father-in-law would hit me
Speaker 4:  up. He'd be like, so 27 inch iMac, when's it gonna happen? And I eventually
Speaker 4:  was like, I was like, Roger, I don't think it's gonna happen. No.
Speaker 3:  Do you remember Apple gave us the rare on the record statement, right?
Speaker 6:  Saying no. Oh yeah.
Speaker 3:  Saying we're not making another 27 trimac.
Speaker 6:  And but think about it. You're that person. You're, what was his name? You're
Speaker 6:  Roger. Roger. You're Roger. Roger and I, a lot of Rogers read the Wall Street
Speaker 6:  Journal and they really want a new desktop and
Speaker 6:  they are not gonna go get the Mac Studio, which costs $2,000,
Speaker 6:  but they're gonna get an iMac, so Okay. Makes it more mainstream.
Speaker 6:  They're gonna pair that with a display that they, you know, buy on Amazon
Speaker 6:  of Samsung or whatnot. Done.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well and it was, it was very funny going to that process with him because
Speaker 4:  he was really annoyed by the fact that the computer
Speaker 4:  inside of the iMac was old and slow and outdated. I know, but the screen
Speaker 4:  was awesome. He was like, why can't I just use this as an monitor, put another
Speaker 4:  computer inside of the screen. And I was like, what a terrific point that
Speaker 4:  you're making. And so it, it made it, it made it actually easier to sell
Speaker 4:  him on the idea of like, okay, we're gonna buy you a Mac mini and we're gonna
Speaker 4:  buy you a really nice 27 inch monitor and this monitor is
Speaker 4:  gonna sit here for a very long time and you can just upgrade this little
Speaker 4:  computer as you need to. And he's, he's been very happy with my
Speaker 3:  2015 iMac is in the corner over there and, and
Speaker 3:  I have all the parts to turn it into just a monitor and I have
Speaker 3:  to sit around and get it unglued and do all the stuff and
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna do it one day. But that is the plan for that machine. Actually
Speaker 3:  we should just have a party. We should have a bringing your iMac to turn
Speaker 3:  it into a monitor. It's a very nerdy kind of RG chess party. But I think
Speaker 3:  we could get people to come to it. And I know a lot of people who are sitting
Speaker 3:  around with old 27 inch iMac who are like, I can just turn this into this
Speaker 3:  way because the panel is the same as the panel in the studio display. Yep.
Speaker 3:  Apple has not meaningfully updated that LG panel for the studio display.
Speaker 3:  It's the same as the 27 inch iMac. Which I think we should talk about the
Speaker 3:  24 inch iMac, which was also just Rev to have an M four chip in it.
Speaker 3:  It's kind of weird that they're, that they just landed this thing at
Speaker 3:  24 inches. It is very colorful. It is very thin
Speaker 3:  in many ways. It's like an apex idea of the iMac. Like
Speaker 3:  I don't know where you go after this. Like it is as thin as any computer
Speaker 3:  can be to be that thing. But I feel like if they just made it
Speaker 3:  27 inches, like lots of more people would just buy 'em. Like you would just
Speaker 3:  buy, this would be the thing you would buy. And at 24, I think everyone has
Speaker 3:  that. I don't know.
Speaker 4:  It has to just be a price thing. Right? Like I I think keeping the
Speaker 4:  iMac as relatively speaking affordable as possible
Speaker 4:  is very important because this thing is like, it is such a family
Speaker 4:  computer. It's a, it's a like thing on the
Speaker 4:  reception desk at fancy doctor's offices. Like, it, it's, it's in so
Speaker 4:  many of those places that I think If, you have a bigger screen
Speaker 4:  that's good, but if it's suddenly $500 more expensive, you've kind of killed
Speaker 4:  the value prop of the thing. Yeah. And I was so surprised when they made
Speaker 4:  this change in the first place because my assumption would've always been
Speaker 4:  anybody wants an iMac is gonna want the bigger one. And that, I mean
Speaker 4:  Apple is not like famous for making stupid business decisions. So, I think
Speaker 4:  clearly that was not the case. But the fact that it is so locked in on
Speaker 4:  this one thing at this one size and it, especially with these colors,
Speaker 4:  like it just indicates there is, this is a very different Mac that
Speaker 4:  serves a very different kind of person than anything else in the
Speaker 4:  Mac lineup at this point.
Speaker 3:  It's interesting the way you describe it. 'cause it, lemme just throw this
Speaker 3:  idea out here. It sounds like we're describing the Mac Mini as the Go-to
Speaker 3:  Mac desktop, the lifestyle computer and the iMac is the
Speaker 3:  weird utility computer that goes in the receptionist desk
Speaker 4:  Maybe. Yeah. It's certainly the like plug and play
Speaker 4:  simplest version of that for Apple, right? Like the, there is
Speaker 4:  no easier Mac to just insert into a
Speaker 4:  receptionist's office than a doctor's appointment at a doctor's office than
Speaker 4:  an iMac. Yeah. You don't need other peripherals. You just sit the thing down,
Speaker 4:  plug it in and turn it on. And I think that's really enticing to a lot of
Speaker 4:  people. I think it's also limiting and problematic in the
Speaker 4:  ways that we're just talking about. But I get the appeal. What I don't
Speaker 4:  understand is why this is the only one that comes in purple. Right. And it's
Speaker 4:  like, who is this? And not just because I want them all to come in purple,
Speaker 4:  but like what is so different about the iMac audience that it gets
Speaker 4:  such an unbelievably different set of like aesthetic
Speaker 4:  decisions than any other Mac?
Speaker 6:  Well I think that's like where if they were to go to the 27 inch, I think
Speaker 6:  they would wanna attach a pro name to it. Hmm. And a pro
Speaker 6:  isn't coming purple because
Speaker 3:  Only professionals need slightly more screen
Speaker 6:  Because a pro does not come in purple.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  That is No, definitely not. That's the tagline there. So they,
Speaker 3:  That's how you know that you work at the Wall Street Journal and we work
Speaker 3:  at The Verge 'cause I'm like, our professionals come in purple. That's what
Speaker 3:  we do here. We're, we're purple to the Wall Street Journal. You do have a
Speaker 3:  lot of purple oppressive gray.
Speaker 6:  I I like purple, purple for everyone.
Speaker 3:  Joanna, you and I have kids around the same age. Are you going to,
Speaker 3:  I'm assuming they will just be sort of like given Chromebooks in your school
Speaker 3:  district that will happen.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, they were already
Speaker 3:  Right. And so then, okay, there's your like laptop for school. I've been
Speaker 3:  asking myself, am I gonna get max a laptop
Speaker 3:  or would I want a desktop like this to be like, this is here
Speaker 3:  and then when you go to your room it doesn't go with you. It's not
Speaker 3:  a portable computer. And maybe coming back to that like computer room idea
Speaker 3:  and I feel like that's part of this right? It, it's all part of that mix
Speaker 3:  is like people are expressing what they want computers to be and how they
Speaker 3:  want them to used very differently than just a few years ago.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like obviously very differently than just a few years ago. And part
Speaker 3:  of this is like this computer is stationary and friendly
Speaker 3:  and it, but it doesn't go with you and your laptop has to be rugged. If
Speaker 3:  a laptop was purple it would probably look like crap after a while
Speaker 3:  in a way that aluminum just looks worn in a nice way.
Speaker 3:  I dunno that I, I've been thinking about this a lot. Like, oh maybe I'll
Speaker 3:  just get the iMac the first time out and the fact that it's purple makes
Speaker 3:  it friendly and like that will be fun.
Speaker 4:  I think that's the move personally. I mean, and you even look at the way
Speaker 4:  Apple is marketing this thing. Like I'm, I'm just on the iMac page on
Speaker 4:  Apple's website and the images are like an iMac
Speaker 4:  on a counter in a coffee shop or in a bakery. There's one
Speaker 4:  that looks like it's in some cool like surfboard sales
Speaker 4:  shop. There's one that's clearly in a living room right next to the couch.
Speaker 4:  It's like these are, these are furniture in a way that no other Mac
Speaker 4:  is furniture. Yeah. Which I just find fascinating and I I
Speaker 4:  I have like, the older I get the more I believe in the idea of a computer
Speaker 4:  as like a place rather than a thing you carry around. So like
Speaker 4:  bring back the computer room. Honestly that's it as far
Speaker 3:  As I'm concerned. Actually the time when Vergecast listeners were sending
Speaker 3:  us pictures of their computer rooms so good was the best. Joanna you were
Speaker 3:  gonna say
Speaker 4:  Please keep doing that Vergecast at the virtual.com in 19 send
Speaker 6:  Us computer actually sent this computer room picture.
Speaker 3:  No, we asked people for pictures of the computer rooms when they were kids
Speaker 3:  and we got so many of them and they're all so cool and
Speaker 4:  Then we and they all look the same. Everybody had the same computer
Speaker 3:  Room. Everybody went to had the same soder, woodworking, computer
Speaker 3:  hutch like down the line. It was great. Okay. I wanna end by
Speaker 3:  talking about two things. One is a rumor that is my favorite rumor and two
Speaker 3:  is Joanna's garage door. The rumor is Apple
Speaker 3:  is working on a smart home display there. Mark
Speaker 3:  Erman has also reported that they're really gonna do it in this smart home
Speaker 3:  now they're gonna, they're gonna, they got matter out the door. The standard
Speaker 3:  is there, everyone's using it. There's the array of accessories. You can
Speaker 3:  buy all the stuff and they're gonna go for it. Sure.
Speaker 3:  But then they'll have a smart home display. And the other rumor is that
Speaker 3:  it will have, the display will be on an arm like the iMac G four, which is
Speaker 3:  the single greatest iMac ever made. The
Speaker 4:  G four is the, the one that kinda looks like the Pixar lamp. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 4:  Where it has like sun ball with the bottom and then the I loved
Speaker 3:  That. That was the best one. So if they make one of those, I'll buy that
Speaker 3:  right away and, and then I will, I will give my entire smart home to Apple.
Speaker 3:  My question is actually much simpler about this. What can
Speaker 3:  Apple actually do with a smart home display that hasn't been done by every
Speaker 3:  other company except have it be made by Apple? Because I have thought
Speaker 3:  about what I use my, my Nest hubs for. I've
Speaker 3:  got the Alexa displays for a while. When we were renovating
Speaker 3:  the kitchen, I was like, I'll put a tablet in the wall. Then I was like,
Speaker 3:  I will never use this tablet and I just didn't do it. I don't know that smart
Speaker 3:  home displays are actually a thing. I don't know. They're actually that useful.
Speaker 6:  I mean I guess I, I don't have a, I don't have a smart home
Speaker 6:  display. Everything is audio. It's mostly through
Speaker 6:  Sonos or my phone. I don't have any like what what are you
Speaker 6:  looking on on the display? I mean I guess like your camera feeds If, you
Speaker 6:  wanted to see them.
Speaker 3:  Sure. And everyone wants in the middle of their, but like their kitchen is
Speaker 3:  like a, like a security guard shack showing you
Speaker 6:  Live camera feeds and also how many camera feeds can actually go into Home
Speaker 6:  Kit and into the home app.
Speaker 3:  Quite a few. So,
Speaker 6:  But like, so but that's doesn't, that's
Speaker 4:  The problem is like if, if Apple you you,
Speaker 4:  like if I were to Galaxy Brain this moment, right, like If, you wanna look
Speaker 4:  at what is the closest to where the cell phone market was
Speaker 4:  right before the iPhone. It's definitely smart home,
Speaker 4:  right? Like there's tons of stuff out there. People are interested, but it
Speaker 4:  is just abject chaos everywhere you look. There are a
Speaker 4:  million competing operating systems and, and like in theory, someone
Speaker 4:  could come in and put it all together and everything would be amazing. Except
Speaker 4:  the difference is yes, you can't, you can't, it's not, not possible. The
Speaker 6:  Difference is not possible is that we have old crap that just doesn't
Speaker 6:  work with
Speaker 4:  Right.
Speaker 6:  Different stuff. Thus Apple
Speaker 4:  Would have to immediately turn HomeKit into the most
Speaker 4:  wildly compatible open and yet perfect and
Speaker 4:  closed and correct ecosystem in history. And that is not possible.
Speaker 4:  Like it's, I just don't, I just, I literally don't see how anyone Apple
Speaker 4:  or otherwise can like wrap their arms around the entirety of the
Speaker 4:  smart home right now in such a way that it's gonna work. Which is why matter
Speaker 4:  is in theory like the answer because it means you don't have to because it
Speaker 4:  means it all sort of sorts itself out. But like
Speaker 3:  It doesn't though we're not close to
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It really doesn't.
Speaker 3:  IIII run what is effectively a home kit house because if the
Speaker 3:  controls are not on Becky's phone, they don't exist. So
Speaker 3:  if I, if I want her to be able to change the temperature in her house,
Speaker 3:  it's, it's gotta be Home Kit. Your point about Ring Joanna, like I
Speaker 3:  I bridge everything through Home Bridge.
Speaker 6:  I bridge to get it Home Kit. So do I And
Speaker 3:  You bridge it in hoops, right? The other one?
Speaker 6:  Yes. and it fails
Speaker 3:  And it and we have you gotta switch to Home Bridge. I'm just telling you
Speaker 3:  right
Speaker 4:  Now. Do you think if I name this episode, I bridge it in hoops that anyone
Speaker 4:  will listen to it.
Speaker 3:  That's like when Neil and we get together to, we talk about the word hoops
Speaker 3:  a lot and it hilarious.
Speaker 6:  We talk about hoops a lot. I talk about IIII used to love hoops
Speaker 6:  and now I don't love hoops.
Speaker 3:  I'm so sorry.
Speaker 6:  And now I'm in a deep, I mean I'm really just em emotionally
Speaker 6:  so emotional on this podcast. Yeah. About my hoops, about my notifications.
Speaker 3:  I think Joanna like didn't they give you like an exclusive on like Hoops
Speaker 3:  Pro?
Speaker 3:  So just the, the brief history here is that If,
Speaker 3:  you wanna get stuff that do isn't supported HomeKit. In HomeKit there's just
Speaker 3:  a bunch of like middleware adapters. One of them is called HomeBridge,
Speaker 3:  that's the one I use. And then Hubs is like a commercial fork of HomeBridge.
Speaker 3:  There's a little open source fight and everybody makes the plugins and they
Speaker 3:  kind of work on both. And I think a lot of the plugins are secretly made
Speaker 3:  by Apple engineers 'cause they all wanna use their stuff in HomeKit.
Speaker 3:  I'm just saying we
Speaker 6:  Should report that out.
Speaker 3:  It's, it's just a rumor that I've
Speaker 6:  Heard a lot for the three of us
Speaker 3:  And So I, I have a, a raspberry pie in my, it's sitting right in
Speaker 3:  front of me that runs Home Bridge. It has my ring off in
Speaker 3:  it. It has my extremely garbage Honeywell
Speaker 3:  thermostat for the heaters in the basement. Fine.
Speaker 3:  It has some other stuff in it and all that stuff shows up in HomeKit. It
Speaker 3:  shows up in control center on my phone. And that is the problem. I would
Speaker 3:  have to tear out all that stuff and replace it with Matter compatible accessories.
Speaker 3:  And I have no inclination to replace the garbage Honeywell
Speaker 3:  thermostat in the basement with a new matter thermostat for
Speaker 3:  no upside. Like there's just no upside of me doing that. So I have to run
Speaker 3:  the home bridge. Joanna has to deal with hoops. This is very
Speaker 6:  Funny. Sorry to cut you off here in insert. Yeah. Is Home Bridge better
Speaker 6:  than hoops right now? Is what you're telling
Speaker 3:  Me? I think Home Bridge. Home Bridge is more stable.
Speaker 6:  Okay. So, I gotta get rid of my hoops.
Speaker 3:  But you can just re you can just install it on the same Raspberry pie. It's
Speaker 3:  fine. and we, and this is all like whatever.
Speaker 3:  But then you get to other stuff like garage
Speaker 3:  door openers where Chamberlain, which is the garage door
Speaker 3:  monopoly in the United States, which is ridiculous, wants
Speaker 3:  everyone to use my queue,
Speaker 6:  My queue and,
Speaker 3:  And they have my canceled. We actually, Jen two TUI broke the story.
Speaker 3:  Yep. They canceled not only their home kit support, they made a little adapter,
Speaker 3:  they broke the MyQ API so that
Speaker 3:  the Home bridge adapters, the hub adapters, the plugins would
Speaker 3:  stop working so that you would have to pay a subscription for MyQ.
Speaker 3:  That's like, that's where at in this smart home market. So
Speaker 3:  Apple cans show up with like a beautiful screen and be like matters
Speaker 3:  the real deal. And then you're stuck with even the
Speaker 3:  hacks to make it all work together or being broken. So you have to pay a
Speaker 3:  subscription fee to your garage door opener.
Speaker 6:  My dream in life is just to be able to drive away from my house
Speaker 6:  and say, Siri close the garage.
Speaker 3:  I can So I can,
Speaker 6:  You can help me with that. I know.
Speaker 3:  Look at me Johanna, I can solve this problem for you. So the best hack to
Speaker 3:  solve this problem, and this is where I want to get to your Craig Federici
Speaker 3:  conversation. But,
Speaker 6:  But, but what second? I just wanna, before you get to what could I used to
Speaker 6:  have this, I had this when home with when Hoops
Speaker 6:  was working with what you just described. Then Chamberlain
Speaker 6:  breaks that and now I have to use their,
Speaker 6:  I will not insert the word app. Okay.
Speaker 6:  And So I can no longer do this. Now you can go on,
Speaker 3:  Right? So the, the solution or all these little adapters you can buy on Amazon,
Speaker 3:  they're mostly made by a company called Miros. It seems like this is one
Speaker 3:  of those situations where one company made the thing and then 500
Speaker 3:  other companies rebrand it. Do you know what I'm talking about? You go on
Speaker 3:  Amazon, you're like HomeBridge or you go on Amazon and you type in like home
Speaker 3:  kit adapter for garage store and you see the same and
Speaker 6:  Then they all look the same.
Speaker 3:  You see the same product from 50 companies. Miros is the one that everybody
Speaker 3:  uses and it is just a little relay with a wifi
Speaker 3:  chip in it that connects to HomeKit and all it does is it
Speaker 3:  connects the two wires and pushes the button on your garage door
Speaker 6:  For you. Okay, am I installing this? I have to get up on a ladder and put
Speaker 6:  it onto my
Speaker 3:  Master. Have no, you have to invite your friend Neli to your house
Speaker 6:  And Neli will get onto the ladder.
Speaker 3:  I'll get on a ladder and I'll do, I mean we can do it together as, as this
Speaker 3:  is a service
Speaker 4:  He provide for all vergecast listeners. By the way, NELI will come
Speaker 6:  Your house. Here's my true payment for appearing on here. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Exactly.
Speaker 6:  So, but
Speaker 3:  You have
Speaker 6:  To plug
Speaker 3:  But you have but you have to wire it into your garage door opener.
Speaker 6:  I'm going to get on a ladder. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You get on a ladder, you gotta find the screws, you gotta plug it into
Speaker 3:  the terminals and you gotta run a sensor wire to the door itself so it knows
Speaker 3:  when the doors open or closed. You can't
Speaker 4:  Possibly think that is like
Speaker 3:  A reasonable thing for a person. Can't. But I'm, that's where we're at. When
Speaker 3:  Craig Fedi is telling Joanna that he uses Siri
Speaker 3:  to open his garage door, you gotta watch this video. Joanna is like,
Speaker 3:  how's Siri doing with Apple Intelligence? And he is like, Siri's great. We
Speaker 3:  a billion queries a day. I use it to open my garage door and just,
Speaker 6:  Well that's 'cause I had also asked about the garage I'd given the example
Speaker 6:  of the garage. 'cause again, I do think Apple and Touch saying is very helpful
Speaker 6:  for the garage door. But I'm,
Speaker 3:  But but I'm saying If, you just sit in, the guy who runs all of software
Speaker 3:  at Apple is asking his phone to open his garage door. What it takes to
Speaker 3:  actually get there is so complicated.
Speaker 6:  But Craig and I did talk after, but he did say it has HomeKit
Speaker 6:  integrated, which leads me to believe that he had an old model that
Speaker 6:  when LiftMaster was like friendly,
Speaker 3:  There was never
Speaker 6:  No they did. They had some old model that had some HomeKit integration.
Speaker 3:  All right, so here's my two theories and again, v has listeners can help
Speaker 3:  me figure this out. We believe there are only a few options here.
Speaker 3:  Craig has a secret model of garage door opener, like the
Speaker 3:  big motor thing, right? That has home kid in it that no one else has ever
Speaker 3:  had in their lives. Right? He's got a custom, custom
Speaker 3:  garage door opener two, he's got a home
Speaker 3:  bridge in his house, which would be hilarious.
Speaker 3:  Truly hilarious. Like he's, he's running a, a little
Speaker 3:  raspberry pie Tamagotchi or three, some Apple engineer
Speaker 3:  came to set up Craig's house, put in one of these MIAs adapters and never
Speaker 3:  told him about it.
Speaker 3:  The those are your choices. 'cause there isn't a garage door
Speaker 3:  opener with HomeKit built into it.
Speaker 6:  There wasn't like, I don't know, no seven years ago and they were like,
Speaker 6:  Hey, you can get HomeKit and it had the nice little like logo on everything.
Speaker 6:  I I'm pretty sure there was a, either it was a lift master or something
Speaker 6:  that had that. I
Speaker 3:  I'm I'm, I'm asking the listeners my this is what The Vergecast is for.
Speaker 3:  Okay. We are crowdsourcing whether or not the big motor
Speaker 3:  thing with home kitten it existed
Speaker 6:  Because look, I should have gone further.
Speaker 3:  What do you think Craig Feder
Speaker 6:  My 20 minute interview.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, actually, and the other thing is like, can you imagine Craig's garage
Speaker 3:  door? Like do you think it like opens with like a light display
Speaker 3:  in my, it's like a Batman's house.
Speaker 6:  I,
Speaker 6:  he, I I should have a, I'm now regretting that I did not spend the 20 minutes
Speaker 6:  that I had with him really going deep on this. But I did ask him
Speaker 6:  at the end and he said, yeah, I've had one with home kit integrated.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Craig, if you're listening and I know that you are as you always do, hi Craig,
Speaker 4:  come on the show and tell us about your
Speaker 3:  Garage door. It's, I'm telling you,
Speaker 6:  Write us email just telling us how the ho the how it's integrated.
Speaker 6:  There's
Speaker 3:  Only three options. Yeah. He's got, he has one that no one's ever heard of.
Speaker 3:  No four options. He's got one that no one's ever heard of, which would be
Speaker 3:  incredible. Craig, please come on the show and tell us about your custom
Speaker 3:  engineered home kit. Garage door opener. He has the discontinued
Speaker 3:  MyQ home kit bridge. He's got a home bridge or hoops
Speaker 3:  or he is got one of these Mi Ross adapters. Those are the only choices.
Speaker 6:  Oh, the bridge. So sorry, choice number two is that, who made that
Speaker 6:  bridge
Speaker 3:  My queue before? And they di but they discontinued it. So it's not a choice.
Speaker 3:  So
Speaker 6:  It doesn't work with the API anymore.
Speaker 3:  Right? So if you're gonna be like, I, you seared open my thing all the time,
Speaker 3:  you can't get it. It's not a choice anymore.
Speaker 6:  'cause they cut that off.
Speaker 3:  Because they cut it off.
Speaker 4:  This is the worst
Speaker 3:  Smart home commercial in the history of universe. This is what I'm saying,
Speaker 3:  the universe, you can make the display and then you get all the way to, I
Speaker 6:  Also talk about this with my boss by the way, all the time. The, the deputy
Speaker 6:  editor in chief of the Wall Street Journal also has this problem. I really
Speaker 6:  think a lot of people have this problem and and they're not talking about
Speaker 6:  it, right? We need to talk about it. We need to
Speaker 3:  Talk, we need to raise awareness. Joanna,
Speaker 6:  We need to talk about this more and we need to talk about the
Speaker 6:  symbolic. I I just wanna drive away and not have
Speaker 6:  to tap a button. Let's just be clear by the way, like they did
Speaker 6:  solve this problem decades ago with a button.
Speaker 3:  Okay, we gotta wrap this up. I'm starting a small consulting company
Speaker 3:  to help people get their garage doors and the home kit.
Speaker 6:  And I'm his first client.
Speaker 3:  This is my exit plan. Joanna, we were gonna have you around for the lightning
Speaker 3:  round, but we did this for so long that you have to go.
Speaker 6:  I'm sorry, I have to go see my child in a parade. A
Speaker 6:  Halloween parade.
Speaker 3:  All right, well, we'll, we'll we'll figure out how to fix
Speaker 3:  your garage door until later time. Thank
Speaker 6:  You so much. And I just also wanna say that I have gotten
Speaker 6:  many notifications in this podcast that were not
Speaker 6:  important to me and were not a priority.
Speaker 3:  All of them were from Liam, the producer being like, stop talking about the
Speaker 3:  garage
Speaker 3:  We'll let the AI figure out which ones to send you. I would
Speaker 6:  Like them to come to my house to fix my garage. Goodbye.
Speaker 3:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back.
Speaker 3:  I don't know what you heard in that last segment.
Speaker 3:  I don't know how much we're gonna keep. I just want you to know
Speaker 3:  that the garage door conversation with Joanna went on for
Speaker 3:  so long.
Speaker 4:  Oh my God.
Speaker 3:  Like however long you think that actually went for or whatever you just
Speaker 3:  experienced. It was at least three times as long.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We made Joanna late for her child because we were talking about garage
Speaker 4:  door openers
Speaker 3:  A child that she only experiences through smartphone notification
Speaker 4:  Who is named child according to her phone.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Alright. That also means the show is way
Speaker 3:  too long, so we gotta get through this lightning out real fast. David, do
Speaker 3:  you wanna start?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, So I. Just want to really quickly mention this
Speaker 4:  new thing Netflix launched called Moments, which basically lets
Speaker 4:  you just link to a specific part of a
Speaker 4:  TV show or movie. And on the one hand,
Speaker 4:  incredibly boring feature. Yeah. Right? Like
Speaker 3:  Netflix launches, anchor links. Yeah. 1986.
Speaker 4:  Yes, very true. Completely agree. On the other hand, Netflix has
Speaker 4:  been so incredibly averse to any
Speaker 4:  kind of social interaction with its product
Speaker 4:  over the years that I just find the existence of anything like this really
Speaker 4:  fascinating. Like we've talked many times on this show over the years about
Speaker 4:  how weird it is that you can't screenshot a Netflix show. Like in
Speaker 4:  in a, in the world in which we live where
Speaker 3:  On a, a phone,
Speaker 4:  Right? Sure. Yeah, you can, you can do it, you can hack your way into it.
Speaker 4:  But like if I'm watching something on Netflix and I'm like, whoa, and I wanna
Speaker 4:  send it to someone, you can't. It's, it's illegal and not
Speaker 4:  allowed and impossible.
Speaker 3:  Well, people do it on lap. I just wanna be clear on mobile devices
Speaker 3:  and TV devices on laptops. People are screenshotting and sharing
Speaker 3:  Netflix all over the place.
Speaker 4:  Sure. I don't think that's the primary place most people are
Speaker 4:  interacting with Netflix.
Speaker 3:  I guess the, the, there's like a weird measurement bias there because the
Speaker 3:  only screenshots I see of Netflix are from people with apps.
Speaker 4:  This is, this is the point, right? Yeah. But I think, and, and I think if,
Speaker 4:  if Netflix had better tooling to prevent you from doing it on a laptop, it
Speaker 4:  would do so too. That is all neither here nor there. Just the fact
Speaker 4:  that Netflix is engaging more in society
Speaker 4:  in this way I think is really interesting, right? Like there's a, there's
Speaker 4:  an alternate future of Netflix where it engaged much more and there
Speaker 4:  was like shorts inside of Netflix that creators were starting to do and Netflix
Speaker 4:  just like leaned into like we're gonna be premium TikTok in, in a
Speaker 4:  way that Netflix really talks about itself now as premium YouTube even
Speaker 4:  on their earnings calls. Like that's how the company frames itself in
Speaker 4:  very real ways. It's how they're selling ads. It's like Netflix sees
Speaker 4:  itself as high-end YouTube in so many real ways and
Speaker 4:  yet has tried so hard to be this little tiny insular, like this is where
Speaker 4:  you watch shows and nothing else universe. And so any tiny
Speaker 4:  moment where you can like capture something else and
Speaker 4:  take it out of Netflix, I just think is really interesting. I dunno if anyone
Speaker 4:  will use this feature, but I think it's
Speaker 3:  Really interesting. Here's my conspiracy theory, okay? This is pure conspiracy
Speaker 3:  theory. Love it. The single best discovery app
Speaker 3:  Netflix could launch would be TikTok for Netflix, right?
Speaker 3:  Where you just flip through clips. Yeah. and it just shows you this way that
Speaker 3:  people are watching pirate movies on TikTok today and they don't know what
Speaker 3:  clips to pick and they can't go through the whole catalog and pick everything.
Speaker 3:  Oh. So you watch a feature like this where people are bookmarking their favorite
Speaker 3:  parts of shows and suddenly you have a library of places to clip from. Oh.
Speaker 4:  And then that becomes the thing also when you go to the home screen and it
Speaker 4:  like, you know how it starts playing, maybe it starts playing a clip that
Speaker 4:  everybody likes. That's a good theory. If Netflix isn't doing that, they
Speaker 4:  should be and they should pay it. Me as consulting firm,
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna go to Ted Strand's house. We're gonna do, we're gonna work on the
Speaker 3:  garage door opener. I'm gonna pitch him TikTok for Netflix. I would love
Speaker 3:  that. We had Greg Peters the, the product CEO of Netflix on
Speaker 3:  decoder. Every time I have a streaming service, CEOI ask him about TikTok
Speaker 3:  and piracy to TikTok and whether there's a TikTok to streaming service
Speaker 3:  pipeline or whether they would build a TikTok and they all just sort of,
Speaker 3:  you know, they, they Westworld at me, they're like, doesn't look like anything
Speaker 3:  to me, and I'm gonna break through one of these days.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. There's just no way. It's true. And, and yeah, you would think I have
Speaker 4:  watched, so here's a fun example. I was home from work sick
Speaker 4:  on Monday, and I watched the movie in time with Justin Timberlake. Oh man,
Speaker 4:  that's, do you know why that's a great movie? Do you know why I watched that
Speaker 4:  movie? Because I've seen so many 62nd clips of
Speaker 4:  it on TikTok that I was like, I literally, I got to the point, I was like,
Speaker 4:  I need to just watch this damn movie. So I was at home and I watched it
Speaker 4:  and it rips and everyone should watch it. It's possible that I was
Speaker 4:  just sick and delirious. But
Speaker 3:  The movie, you have to be slightly altered to be like, this movie rips,
Speaker 3:  like, it's good. It's an underrated gem of a movie. It's a good time. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  The central conceit is good. The jokes are good. And then the cars are
Speaker 3:  awesome. And I'm pretty confident Hyundai is designing all of its cars to
Speaker 3:  look like they can bring the movie in time. Oh, they are. See what I'm saying?
Speaker 3:  Saying, whoa,
Speaker 4:  That's totally true. But no, but I think that that connection
Speaker 4:  is real. And, and I think it's the, in the same way that with music,
Speaker 4:  right? That it's always like, why isn't there just a listen to this on Spotify
Speaker 4:  button next to every TikTok video. And TikTok is in fact building a music
Speaker 4:  app to do just that. There is connection there that should exist
Speaker 4:  and it makes sense that Netflix might wanna do more of it on purpose. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  What's
Speaker 4:  Yours?
Speaker 3:  Mine is just a clip of our friend Tony Fidel. So it was
Speaker 3:  Tech Crunch Disrupt this week, big conference, famous
Speaker 3:  Matt Malig was on stage there. He said A fork of WordPress would be fine.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna keep hovering that somehow. I'm just, I'm letting you, there's
Speaker 3:  zero things that happen in TechCrunch Disrupt. And then Tony Fadell who
Speaker 3:  worked at Apple for ages was one of the
Speaker 3:  contested fathers of the iPod. That's a big fight. That's fun to talk about.
Speaker 3:  But he did the bring up of the iPod. He worked on the iPhone for several
Speaker 3:  generations and he left, he founded Nest, he sold it to Google. He fought
Speaker 3:  with everybody at Google, and now he's a vc. This is the short version of
Speaker 3:  Tony. Phil. Tony's a character. He's been on decoder a number of times. We've
Speaker 3:  known Tony forever. He's on stage a tech conscious disrupt talking
Speaker 3:  about ai, and he basically says, Sam Altman is full of shit.
Speaker 3:  We're just run the clip. Just run the clip.
Speaker 7:  We are using this stuff and we don't even know how it works. And believe
Speaker 7:  me, I understand. I've been doing AI for 15 years. People So, I, I'm, I'm
Speaker 7:  not just spouting shit. I'm not Sam Altman. Okay.
Speaker 7:  So, so seriously, you gotta know what you're
Speaker 7:  hiring here. You gotta know what you're using. Yeah. And if we don't have
Speaker 7:  transparency on data, we don't have transparency on hallucinations,
Speaker 7:  you are setting yourself up for a fucking disaster.
Speaker 3:  So I Wanna be clear? I love Tony Fidel.
Speaker 4:  My only note on this would be that when we were talking about this link in
Speaker 4:  Slack, and I forget who it was, but somebody was like, is this,
Speaker 4:  is this like what Tony is always like? And without missing a beat, Mila just
Speaker 4:  goes, yeah, this is Tony.
Speaker 3:  This is what Tony is always like,
Speaker 4:  This is a Tony.
Speaker 3:  I had Tony and Decoder talk about his book about how to be a good leader.
Speaker 3:  and it was this, yeah, you should go listen to that episode. He's
Speaker 3:  not wrong. He's not wrong. Right. Yeah. We, we,
Speaker 3:  we, I keep describing the current state of ai. We, we talked about this all
Speaker 3:  the beginning of the show, but I keep describing the current state of AI
Speaker 3:  is like, we are spending billions of dollars to build Bluetooth. And
Speaker 3:  no one knows what the headphones are gonna look like. Like no one can be
Speaker 3:  like, I'm gonna make really good headphones outta this. It's more like, these
Speaker 3:  headphones might kill you. We have to build Bluetooth as expensively as
Speaker 3:  possible. It's a great clip. I I, you know, readers are gonna say,
Speaker 3:  what does Tony know about ai? Fine. Whatever. It's not, I don't think my
Speaker 3:  Nest thermostat is a platform shift that threatens Google.
Speaker 3:  It did threaten Google for other reasons. It was a disaster of an acquisition.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it did do that. It is effectively come to nothing for that company.
Speaker 3:  But Sam Altman's spouting shit, man. That's some fighting words.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's pretty good. And you could tell he knew it was a line too. He
Speaker 4:  said it and then like kind of grins and sort of leans back in his chair a
Speaker 4:  little bit and he's like, yeah. Got him.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And then he stands up and starts screaming again. It's great. All right,
Speaker 3:  we gotta end with this one. Tim Walls and a OC played Madden on Twitch
Speaker 3:  together last week. I whatever. You got a campaign,
Speaker 3:  how we're gonna campaign or everyone's going on podcast, we're do a thing.
Speaker 3:  I just wanna point out, and I just wanna say this because I know David understands
Speaker 3:  this as deeply as I do. Playing Madden with an audience is
Speaker 3:  one of the most high stakes things you can do because Madden 24 is
Speaker 3:  so hard.
Speaker 4:  It, it really, it is such an intricate game that it's
Speaker 4:  like, it it, they should have just played Overwatch. Like it would've been
Speaker 4:  less complicated. They
Speaker 3:  Did at, at the end they started playing Crazy Taxi. That's after, after my
Speaker 3:  prediction came to pass, Tim wa threw an interception.
Speaker 4:  Didn't neither of them score. Like it's, it's
Speaker 3:  Pretty embarrassing. This game is too hard. I play this game almost every
Speaker 3:  night to unwind. I've been playing it since I was a child. I've won
Speaker 3:  a Game Cube playing Madden in a
Speaker 3:  Madden tournament in a bar hammered. I was good at this game. The new version
Speaker 3:  is so,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I just thought it was the, the riskiest campaign event I've ever seen. And
Speaker 3:  Indeed Tim Wall's Vikings fan tried to gun into
Speaker 3:  Justin Jefferson and immediately through an interception, which is,
Speaker 3:  I can't encapsulate what the new Madden is like. More than that.
Speaker 4:  It was very good. I I appreciated both the like
Speaker 4:  effort and the immediate understanding of, oh, this is not going to go very
Speaker 4:  well.
Speaker 3:  You shouldn't do this.
Speaker 4:  They just bailed. They didn't even finish the
Speaker 3:  Game. It just gave
Speaker 4:  Up. Which is, I've done that many times.
Speaker 3:  We are so over. We gotta wrap this
Speaker 4:  Thing up. Oh wait, before we go though, one, what re should just talk about
Speaker 4:  this real fast. It's an election on Tuesday. We did a whole
Speaker 4:  package of election stuff. The package is very good. You, you
Speaker 4:  wrote a big fiery endorsement that has caused a lot of feelings
Speaker 4:  on the internet. Should we talk about that? I'm like, I'm both, I want to
Speaker 4:  and I don't want to at the same time.
Speaker 3:  We, we can talk about it for a minute. Okay.
Speaker 3:  Wait, I got a lot of notes are like, let let politics bleed into the more,
Speaker 3:  and sometimes I do. There was a net neutrality hearing today. I
Speaker 3:  I can talk about that all day long. That's very political. But in this
Speaker 3:  case, I'll just say two things about the endorsement. One,
Speaker 3:  we, like every news organization we actually like went back and forth and
Speaker 3:  whether to do it. But that's just the thing that happened. Those were meetings
Speaker 3:  we were in. We published a lot of them before So I. Think we
Speaker 3:  endorsed Obama in 2012. We endorsed Biden last time
Speaker 3:  I wrote those. We did not endorse Hillary or Trump in 2016. And I'm
Speaker 3:  sorry, I'm sorry for that outcome. I think I could have swayed that election.
Speaker 3:  I would've really bounced out the Comey letter. I don't know.
Speaker 3:  We didn't. So that's the history. Those are the ones we've done in the past.
Speaker 3:  You can read the ones in the past that one of Biden in
Speaker 3:  2020, very similar to the one ever wrote today. It just, the thing that got
Speaker 3:  me and the thing I've been thinking about, we write about policy all the
Speaker 3:  time in The Verge, which all the time, and they are just systems, right?
Speaker 3:  Like the legal system is a system and congress
Speaker 3:  is a system. And when we describe the systems to the
Speaker 3:  audience of The Verge, who is, who are, which is comprised of a lot of people
Speaker 3:  who build things and make things and care about how things are made, fine.
Speaker 3:  Everyone gets it. And then the the turn is, but these aren't computers. They're
Speaker 3:  not predictable for any given set of inputs. You don't get a predictable
Speaker 3:  set of outputs. Right? And now in the age of ai, who knows? But Right. But
Speaker 3:  for the most part, people who like work with computers expect the systems
Speaker 3:  to be predictable. And the government isn't,
Speaker 3:  the legal system isn't. So that has always, that's always been the
Speaker 3:  key to how we cover policy here. We describe the system and then we point
Speaker 3:  out like, this isn't predictable. Like actual people have to just keep doing
Speaker 3:  it. Right? and it just really occurred to me that
Speaker 3:  all for all of the babbling about democracy that everyone is doing, no one
Speaker 3:  has explained like why it's important or like why that's the system. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So that was the approach I took with f-bombs. 'cause I, you know, I'm me,
Speaker 3:  I hope it worked, it, the feedback was great. I was expecting chaos
Speaker 3:  a nightmare. And I am just very encouraged and heartened that what I got
Speaker 3:  was the most comments on any article since we switched to Coral.
Speaker 3:  Mostly entirely respectful. Obviously we did some moderating into our house
Speaker 3:  Yeah. To keep it clean, but mostly respectful, mostly engaged. The feedback
Speaker 3:  from the social networks was mostly good. Obviously it's very distracting
Speaker 3:  at there. Like there are other things to talk about, but I am just, I was
Speaker 3:  very proud of our audience Yeah. For engaging with the thing. And I know
Speaker 3:  I gave it this like incredibly spicy headline, but I stand by the headline,
Speaker 3:  the argument and the piece is the headline. Yeah. And so I'm, I'm just happy
Speaker 3:  people took it seriously. They read it. They're paying attention.
Speaker 3:  They're bought into America, which is I think, important. So
Speaker 3:  yeah, that's, I don't, I don't, I don't wanna like overdo it. I, I said what
Speaker 3:  I needed to say, I published in text because I'm still a writer at heart
Speaker 3:  and I hope the internet continues to be a place for text to live. Yeah. I
Speaker 3:  don't, I don't know if there's much more to say.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, fair enough. Yeah, it's, we'll, we'll link all the stuff in the show
Speaker 4:  notes. The, the package is really great. Gabby DelVal, just one other shout
Speaker 4:  out, wrote a piece for us today, Thursday about all the tech leaders who
Speaker 4:  have basically fallen all over themselves to cozy up to Trump just in case
Speaker 4:  he wins. That is something we could spend many hours talking about. And I
Speaker 4:  super don't want to, so let's not, but go read that piece. It's very good.
Speaker 4:  We'll put all that in the show notes too. But yeah, it was, it was good.
Speaker 4:  I really liked the endorsement. It was a, it was a, it was a project for
Speaker 4:  you to get that thing done and, and out. And I think saying all those words
Speaker 4:  in a row takes a lot out of you sometimes. But it was very good.
Speaker 4:  It's good
Speaker 3:  Stuff. You know, it's funny, I'll just end on this note and just,
Speaker 3:  there's like, we have a lot of friends and colleagues who have gone off to
Speaker 3:  go be indies on various platforms in various ways, and we wish them well.
Speaker 3:  I, I, I hope people can see, we actively try to support all of
Speaker 3:  our former coworkers who have gone on to start things. I want them to succeed.
Speaker 3:  And that's a trend, right? Everyone's talking about that trend. This is what
Speaker 3:  you should go do for me to do this. Like, if I
Speaker 3:  ran a substack, I think it would be pretty empty. I don't know if it would
Speaker 3:  go anywhere. Like you need the platform, you need the group work.
Speaker 3:  I needed an art department that went and hired an amazing artist to put that
Speaker 3:  piece of art at the top of that and every other part of our package. And
Speaker 3:  I desperately needed a huge group of editors
Speaker 3:  who I trust to fight with me on almost every single sentence to make sure
Speaker 3:  the sentences were great. And that's, and then we needed the, you know, the
Speaker 3:  Virg logo and our big website and all this stuff. And that is important.
Speaker 3:  And like that, I just, I, we've talked a lot
Speaker 3:  about both garage doors and the future of media on this episode of Vergecast.
Speaker 3:  That's what we do here. That's, that's us. We published
Speaker 3:  a presidential endorsement on the same day as like a new Mac mini.