# Transcript
ID: e0f9a30f-d260-4553-b9c0-824362149b2c
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/8247022185882098068/5387478869855989365/s93290-US-4034s-1707815933.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of video podcasts:
02:52 - The Verge's David Pierce chats with 1Password's Anna Pobletts about good password hygiene, passkeys, and the upsides of a third-party password manager.
Passkeys: all the news and updates around passwordless sign-on support
Biometrics? Bring it on: why Okta’s Jameeka Green Aaron wants passwords to go away
How to use a passkey to sign in to your Google account
1Password’s passkeys explainer
31:56 - Victoria Song joins the show to discuss the state of wearables and why this may be the year for the smart ring.
Fossil is quitting smartwatches
This might be the year of the smart ring
The best smartwatches for Android
The best fitness trackers to buy right now
58:46 -Later, David answers a question from The Vergecast Hotline.
Apple Vision Pro review: magic, until it’s not
Here’s how much the Vision Pro’s accessories cost
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Subscribe to The Verge's YouTube channel for full Vergecast episodes.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (8 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of video podcasts.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend David Pierce, and if you're watching this on YouTube, there's
Speaker 2:  a decent chance you're noticing something slightly different for one of our
Speaker 2:  Tuesday episodes, which is my face. So we just finished moving the show from
Speaker 2:  The Vergecast channel to the Verges channel, and you should stay
Speaker 2:  subscribed on The Vergecast channel. By the way, we're gonna do clips there
Speaker 2:  and some extras and maybe even some live stuff over time. We have big plans
Speaker 2:  for that channel. But for the main episodes, Tuesdays and Fridays, stay
Speaker 2:  tuned to the Verges channel. You can Subscribe to the channel, you can Subscribe
Speaker 2:  in YouTube music, you can Subscribe to the podcast playlist specifically.
Speaker 2:  The world is your oyster. It should be very easy. I know we had some migration
Speaker 2:  issues the last few days, but I think those are solved now. And if they're
Speaker 2:  not, send us an email Vergecast at The Verge dot com, we'll get it fixed.
Speaker 2:  Oh, and by the way, if you're like, what are you talking about? I listen
Speaker 2:  to podcasts because people listen to podcasts and I have a podcast app and
Speaker 2:  I've never seen David's face and I don't ever wanna see David's face. Totally
Speaker 2:  fine. I get that all the time. Nothing should change. Everything will be
Speaker 2:  as normal, so don't worry. Alright, that's enough housekeeping for now. Let's
Speaker 2:  just get into the show. We're gonna do two things on today's episode. First,
Speaker 2:  we're gonna talk about pass keys, which are the supposedly revolutionary
Speaker 2:  technology that is going to make being online easier and simpler and more
Speaker 2:  secure all at the same time. It's very cool, it's growing really fast and
Speaker 2:  I have realized I don't understand Passkeys like at all. So we
Speaker 2:  found somebody who does and we're gonna figure it out together. Then we're
Speaker 2:  gonna talk about wearables and the idea that wearables are just
Speaker 2:  smartwatches feels wrong to me. Like I wear an Apple Watch, I love my Apple
Speaker 2:  Watch, but we were promised this big revolution in wearable
Speaker 2:  technology and I don't think we ever really got it. So we're gonna try to
Speaker 2:  figure out why all that is coming up in just a second. But first I have to
Speaker 2:  go home and make my face and hair look better before I have to do this again.
Speaker 2:  This is the VCH cast. Let's go.
Speaker 5:  Welcome
Speaker 2:  Back. All right, let's talk about how to have good password
Speaker 2:  hygiene on the internet, which is the least interesting
Speaker 2:  thing I could possibly imagine saying to begin this, but
Speaker 2:  that's actually part of why I want to talk about this. I feel like I've spent
Speaker 2:  most of my life scolding people to have better passwords and
Speaker 2:  use a password manager and get two factor authentication, but not
Speaker 2:  SMS two-factor authentication. And it turns out most people just
Speaker 2:  don't care. And even I still use the same password across way too many
Speaker 2:  services. It's a real problem. But there's this one new technology called
Speaker 2:  passkeys that in theory might be the solution to all of our problems.
Speaker 2:  It's designed to be more secure than passwords and also simpler than passwords
Speaker 2:  and basically just better in every imaginable way. And it's growing really
Speaker 2:  fast. Google supports passkey now. So does Amazon, iOS and
Speaker 2:  Android both do. You can passkey log into TikTok and WhatsApp
Speaker 2:  and Uber and PayPal and a whole bunch of other services. This tech is very
Speaker 2:  much catching on in a way. A lot of the supposed
Speaker 2:  replacements to the Password haven't in the past, but I have to confess,
Speaker 2:  I don't really understand pass keys. I mean I understand the theory.
Speaker 2:  They use an encrypted token on your device to authenticate you rather than
Speaker 2:  a Password that you type into a text box. That's about all I understand about
Speaker 2:  it. So I invited onto the show. Somebody Who knows much better.
Speaker 6:  Anna Pobletts head of Password list at one password.
Speaker 2:  Anna has been working on Password List Tech for a long time. So I
Speaker 2:  asked her to come on the show and explain to me how passkeys work, why
Speaker 2:  everyone is convinced they're The future and most of all how we as normal
Speaker 2:  humans are supposed to use them in our lives. One note
Speaker 2:  before we get into it, she talks a bunch about one password specifically,
Speaker 2:  which makes sense. I mean that's where she works, but a lot of what she's
Speaker 2:  talking about is true for most password managers and most platforms.
Speaker 2:  That's part of the point of pass keys is that they are the same everywhere.
Speaker 2:  She also makes a point later on in the interview about the upsides of
Speaker 2:  a third party cross platform password manager rather than using the
Speaker 2:  ones built into your device. And I actually think that argument is pretty
Speaker 2:  compelling, but again, there are a lot of good options there and you kind
Speaker 2:  of can't go wrong. Anyway, let's get into it. The first thing I asked Anna
Speaker 2:  about is basically why haven't we killed passwords yet?
Speaker 2:  It's been the death of password for forever Pass keys are
Speaker 2:  supposedly the end of passwords, but I've heard that so, so, so many times
Speaker 2:  before. So what is it about passwords that means they just won't go
Speaker 2:  away?
Speaker 6:  We've been talking about how passwords are bad for like 20, 25 years, right?
Speaker 6:  Like
Speaker 2:  Since passwords.
Speaker 6:  Yes, exactly. Like over and over again. So why now seems like a very
Speaker 6:  reasonable question and I think the truth is that this is the first
Speaker 6:  time where security and user experience aren't
Speaker 6:  mutually exclusive If. you think about previous attempts to either
Speaker 6:  like improve the security of passwords or replace passwords, they always
Speaker 6:  come at the expense of user experience. So for example,
Speaker 6:  multifactor authentication add security to passwords by you know,
Speaker 6:  requiring A-T-O-T-P code or an email or something like that.
Speaker 6:  But that's an extra thing that a user has to do to log in If. you think about
Speaker 6:  certain types of biometrics like proprietary biometrics, that's some sort
Speaker 6:  of hardware that you need to add into the mix. And so there's always this
Speaker 6:  extra step or extra thing that a user has to think about.
Speaker 6:  But with pass keys, the idea is that you don't have to compromise on those
Speaker 6:  things. You're gonna get better security and you'll also get a really
Speaker 6:  smooth frictionless sign in process.
Speaker 2:  So from a pure user experience perspective, I think it's, it's right
Speaker 2:  to say people will do the simplest thing, right? And even when we know
Speaker 2:  it's bad, even when it's terrible hygiene that everybody agrees
Speaker 2:  is bad, I think most people intellectually know don't use the same
Speaker 2:  crappy password for every single thing and yet most people do because it
Speaker 2:  is, it is just the easiest thing to do and it's very annoying to remember
Speaker 2:  all of your different passwords in, in a funny way, it seems like the bar
Speaker 2:  is both very low in that you have to replace people's crummy
Speaker 2:  passwords with something more secure but also very high because actually
Speaker 2:  remembering one password that is just 1, 2, 3, 4 and then typing that in
Speaker 2:  everywhere is actually a pretty good user experience.
Speaker 6:  Certainly a good user experience. Yes. But the bar is so low on
Speaker 6:  the security side it
Speaker 2:  Leads to bad things I suppose. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Exactly. So when I think about like all the things that are wrong with
Speaker 6:  passwords, for me it really comes down to the fact that passwords
Speaker 6:  put all of the burden on a user to be secure, right? It's on you
Speaker 6:  as a person to think up good passwords, remember them not use
Speaker 6:  the same one everywhere, not fall for a phishing attack, all of these things.
Speaker 6:  But with Passkeys the goal is we can actually remove the human
Speaker 6:  error completely from logging into apps. And so if we give
Speaker 6:  you something that's easy and frictionless and the security is actually built
Speaker 6:  into the technology, then there's nothing for you to do wrong, right? Like
Speaker 6:  it just works. So in the case at Passkeys, when you're logging in, all it
Speaker 6:  does, it looks and feels to you like you're just unlocking your device.
Speaker 6:  Usually something like Face Id touch, ID windows, hello. And
Speaker 6:  so it looks and feels like something that is familiar to you, something you
Speaker 6:  know how to do and there's nothing, there's no thought you have to put into
Speaker 6:  it of did I pick my most secure passkey, right? It's
Speaker 6:  just kind of all happening behind the scenes.
Speaker 2:  That's really smart because I think so much of this stuff, and we talk about
Speaker 2:  this with sort of security and privacy in all forms on the internet, it
Speaker 2:  all ends in scolding, right? You kinda have to make people feel bad and
Speaker 2:  scare them in certain ways in order to just like beat them into having good
Speaker 2:  behavior. And what it actually is is If, you give people a better product
Speaker 2:  that is also safer, they'll do it and If you make them feel bad, they still
Speaker 2:  won't change their ways and I think what this whole industry seems to be
Speaker 2:  coming around to in a cool way is like what if we just built better products
Speaker 2:  percent? And I think that's very exciting.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, totally. Like it's not that people don't wanna be secure,
Speaker 6:  I think that's not where this is coming from. That's not why passwords have
Speaker 6:  stayed around. It's sort of just like an inertia, like it is what people
Speaker 6:  know how to do and it's there and there's never really been an
Speaker 6:  option that feels a lot better. Like I used to do security consulting
Speaker 6:  for a number of years and we would work with these companies and they, we'd
Speaker 6:  tell them like, hey you have a weak password policy or you need to add two
Speaker 6:  factor, all these like controls around your account security and
Speaker 6:  especially for consumer facing applications, they'd be like, I mean I could
Speaker 6:  but that's gonna hurt my user conversions. People aren't gonna sign up for
Speaker 6:  my application. And so that trade off was never worth it to them, right?
Speaker 6:  But with Passkey you can actually, like we can say this is actually gonna
Speaker 6:  help your conversions. Users will sign up faster for your application and
Speaker 6:  so all of a sudden there's also a business reason to use Passkey, not just
Speaker 6:  a security reason. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Where did Passkey come from? I feel like in the time I've been covering
Speaker 2:  the space, there was a minute where it was like everybody's gonna have a
Speaker 2:  Yuba key and that's the solution. And then we got into two factor
Speaker 2:  in all of its many different forms and I think we, we went from bad two factor
Speaker 2:  over SMS to like pretty good two factor inside of apps like one Password
Speaker 2:  and Auie and some of the other stuff around. And Passkey kind of
Speaker 2:  crept up on me a little bit over the last couple of years, but my sense is
Speaker 2:  they've been around longer than most people realize as kind of a
Speaker 2:  possibility and an idea like where did this come from?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so there's a technology that kind of underlies passkeys called
Speaker 6:  Web that's been around for probably about 10 years I think.
Speaker 6:  And there's a group called the Fido Alliance that's like an industry organization.
Speaker 6:  A lot of big companies are a part of it and they're all focused on, you know,
Speaker 6:  bringing Passwordless authentication to the world. And so this protocol was
Speaker 6:  invented, it's the same thing that UB keys use that's used to provide
Speaker 6:  this sort of public key cryptography based
Speaker 6:  authentication. Okay? So it's been around for a really long time, but you
Speaker 6:  usually had to have some sort of hardware key, like a Yui key and so
Speaker 6:  you, it might work really well in a workforce or a corporate environment
Speaker 6:  but could be really challenging for the everyday people who don't just have
Speaker 6:  a yui key, right? I
Speaker 2:  Got a Yui key, I set up everything on my Yui key and then I realized the
Speaker 2:  place I leave my keys is several rooms away from where I sit, right?
Speaker 6:  It's not near your computer.
Speaker 2:  Like my keys are upstairs right now with my Yuba key on them and there is
Speaker 2:  no chance I'm gonna use it exactly
Speaker 6:  Like the fact that you even have one is really rare. And so a
Speaker 6:  couple years ago there's this big announcement from the major platform saying
Speaker 6:  we're now supporting what we're calling passkey, which is essentially web
Speaker 6:  ath credentials that can be synced between your platform account.
Speaker 6:  So now instead of being tied to hardware, those passkey are stored in
Speaker 6:  your iCloud account or your Google or your Microsoft account and more
Speaker 6:  recently maybe your one password account, which will obviously get into at
Speaker 6:  some point. But the idea is that now these credentials are a little bit more
Speaker 6:  accessible, you don't need special hardware, they'll sync between your
Speaker 6:  different devices a little bit better to make it a little bit easier for
Speaker 6:  you to access them. And that's been like the big push that you're
Speaker 6:  hearing about in the last couple years.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. And was there a technical development that made that
Speaker 2:  possible? Like what happened between a decade ago and maybe two
Speaker 2:  years ago when this really started to become a thing that kind of tipped
Speaker 2:  it into this is a thing thing we can do in a real mainstream way now?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it was really this syncing concept and so Apple, Google,
Speaker 6:  Microsoft saying like, yes, instead of storing these credentials
Speaker 6:  in like a secure enclave on a device, we can store them securely in your
Speaker 6:  cloud account. I see. And we can sync them between these different devices.
Speaker 6:  So you know, in some really, really high assurance environments that
Speaker 6:  might be a little bit of a security trade off, right? Because you don't have
Speaker 6:  as much hardware security there. But for most consumer use cases,
Speaker 6:  if you're logging into Home Depot or Netflix or things like that, that's
Speaker 6:  actually still a really good security story and it's way, way better than
Speaker 6:  passwords. So you're still getting all of those sort of unfishable
Speaker 6:  security benefits of pass keys but with a little bit more user
Speaker 6:  friendliness.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. Yeah, so talk to me about the unfishable part of this because
Speaker 2:  I think I was reading through in preparing for this a bunch of the
Speaker 2:  criticisms people have of kind of all of the password replacing technology.
Speaker 2:  And there are two I wanna talk about. One is now everything
Speaker 2:  is on my one device. What happens if I lose my device? We'll get to that
Speaker 2:  in a second because I think that's very interesting and also just happened
Speaker 2:  to me recently. So we'll talk about that. But the other one is people saying
Speaker 2:  well actually secure passwords are part of the problem, but the
Speaker 2:  bigger problem is phishing and it's people social
Speaker 2:  engineering their way into my accounts and actually what we have to solve
Speaker 2:  is that problem and not people having bad passwords because if somebody
Speaker 2:  can convince me to type in my password on a fake webpage, we've solved nothing.
Speaker 2:  But the belief with Passkeys is that they actually solve most if not all
Speaker 2:  of that problem too, right? How does that work?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so there's a few really big security benefits with Passkey.
Speaker 6:  So there's kind of the obvious of like, you know, there is no user
Speaker 6:  generated secret type of thing that someone could guess that they could
Speaker 6:  just, you know, reuse across a bunch of websites and guess
Speaker 2:  I can't leak you a password if I don't have a Password, I guess is something
Speaker 2:  exactly.
Speaker 6:  If I don't know what it is, you can't guess it. So that's really big,
Speaker 6:  right? There's a lot of attacks that can happen remotely and at scale
Speaker 6:  that things like credential stuffing are really common against websites.
Speaker 6:  So those things kinda all go away because there just really isn't a credential
Speaker 6:  in the traditional sense. Now the other big thing is of course
Speaker 6:  resistance to phishing attacks. So passkey are tied
Speaker 6:  to a specific website or domain and so if a, an
Speaker 6:  attacker were to make a lookalike site, you know, facebook.com with
Speaker 6:  zeros instead of os your passkey for facebook.com like will
Speaker 6:  not be used on Facebook the lookalike site, right? Like
Speaker 6:  those keys simply aren't transferable, they're not the same thing because
Speaker 2:  The key on your phone and the key on fake Facebook just will literally
Speaker 2:  will not understand each other
Speaker 6:  Exactly like that key won't be used on that site sort of at the
Speaker 6:  device level, at the browser level. Like all, there's a lot of protections
Speaker 6:  in place to sort of tie these pass keys to a specific domain.
Speaker 6:  And so at least for that specific type of phishing attack where, which is
Speaker 6:  really common, you know you have a lookalike site, they ask you for your
Speaker 6:  password and then they reuse it on the real site, that just kind of totally
Speaker 6:  goes away. And I think that's really big, especially right now there's
Speaker 6:  so many news articles around like AI and how AI is
Speaker 6:  making it even easier to make really realistic phishing attacks.
Speaker 6:  This type of prevention of that whole swath of attacks is really,
Speaker 6:  really big and just gives people a little bit more confidence I think
Speaker 6:  when using the internet that you don't have to constantly wonder is this
Speaker 6:  the real site? Is this a real email? Like do I need to double check? Like
Speaker 6:  I think just giving people a little more confidence in that way is helpful.
Speaker 2:  Well and there's a weird tension in that even that it feels too easy
Speaker 2:  honestly using past keys sometimes where it's like this can't actually be
Speaker 2:  solving my problem. All I did was tap the thing, the popup on
Speaker 2:  my phone that said we cool and I said, yeah, we cool. And then I, and now
Speaker 2:  I'm logged in like at least with a password you kind of understand I am
Speaker 2:  delivering something that is a secret in order to allow me in.
Speaker 2:  And there is something to the fact that this is so simple that it almost
Speaker 2:  feels less secure even that it's not, I don't know, part of me wants
Speaker 2:  you to like make it seem scarier every time I do it because it'll make it
Speaker 2:  feel more secure.
Speaker 6:  This is actually a very real thing that I think I've
Speaker 6:  seen that people in the Phyto Alliance have seen when you do research with
Speaker 6:  end users that they're kind of like, oh okay, I guess I
Speaker 6:  logged in. Like they maybe don't even recognize that they actually like registered
Speaker 6:  for or logged into an application and they're like, okay, I guess that was
Speaker 6:  okay, how am I gonna do that next time? Or they don't totally
Speaker 6:  understand. And so there's been a ton of research done on the best ways to
Speaker 6:  communicate to users what's going on, which I think is so important as websites
Speaker 6:  start to roll out pass keys that the user experience there is just so important
Speaker 6:  to make sure users are like, oh, okay, like this looks and feels
Speaker 6:  like my touch, ID like I understand what I'm doing here and kind of giving
Speaker 6:  them that experience. but it's really hard, which is, it's silly, kind of
Speaker 6:  silly that you know, security has to look hard. Like people are used to
Speaker 6:  security being hard, right? For it to work. And so it's kind of breaking
Speaker 6:  that stereotype
Speaker 2:  And that kind of goes to the other piece of feedback I've seen a bunch about
Speaker 2:  Passkeys, which is that we've all been trained now that you have to have
Speaker 2:  two factors, right? There's, there's the thing, you know, and the thing you
Speaker 2:  have and the thing I know is my password and the thing I have is my phone.
Speaker 2:  Great. That is better than just a password and there's something to
Speaker 2:  kind of compressing all of that back down into a passkey that
Speaker 2:  like I just, I, I don't even remember I like tweeted or something about
Speaker 2:  passkey in one password being like, this is cool, it's, I can now have all
Speaker 2:  of my stuff in both apps and I got a bunch of responses from people being
Speaker 2:  like that's not two factor security, that's one factor security because it
Speaker 2:  all just lives inside of one password. And I was like, I don't think that's
Speaker 2:  true
Speaker 6:  But I'm
Speaker 2:  Not. But I sort of see the point right where it's now as long as I'm holding
Speaker 2:  my phone there's no other jobs to do and I, I wonder
Speaker 2:  if part of that is again you're sort of obfuscating the steps in the name
Speaker 2:  of simplicity that actually makes it feel like I'm not doing the hard work
Speaker 2:  of being secure anymore.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think that's really fair. And I think, you know, we've talked about
Speaker 6:  these traditional authentication factors, something you know, something you
Speaker 6:  have something you are or whatever and talking about pesky in that sense
Speaker 6:  is like a little bit confusing but I think we, I kind of do it anyway to
Speaker 6:  help explain to people. I think the easiest way to think about it is it's
Speaker 6:  something that you have, it's whatever device you're currently logged onto,
Speaker 6:  say your Google device or your one password ever, your one password, your
Speaker 6:  browser extension or your desktop app and then it's also something you either
Speaker 6:  have or are or know or something like that depending on, you know,
Speaker 6:  it's either your touch id face id your pin, your one Password
Speaker 6:  password and secret key. It can be like whatever that other factor is that
Speaker 6:  you're actually using to log into the account where your passkey is stored.
Speaker 6:  But there's always a little bit of a like device ownership
Speaker 6:  aspect to that which kind of gives you that second factor. And so it's a
Speaker 6:  little bit like square peg, round hole, but I think you can kind of roughly
Speaker 6:  put passkey into that bucket to help people feel a little bit better about
Speaker 6:  that.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Yeah so the the two factors then If, you were to sort of boil that
Speaker 2:  all the way down would basically be my phone and the information
Speaker 2:  required to log into my phone.
Speaker 6:  Exactly. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Which is two things and I think I ironically back to the like this
Speaker 2:  is almost too easy thing. I think If you were forced to type in your passcode
Speaker 2:  every time it would make more sense. Whereas with the face ID or the windows,
Speaker 2:  hello, it kind of, it almost happens so fast that you lose track of it and
Speaker 2:  it's like well I didn't have to authenticate anything and I was like, no
Speaker 2:  you did, it just happened really quickly and automatically, which is a great
Speaker 2:  thing but kind of an alarming one to get used to at first. Yeah, like I I,
Speaker 2:  it certainly took me a few tries to realize oh it's doing face ID every single
Speaker 2:  time my pass key comes up because that's part of the authentication process.
Speaker 6:  Exactly and I don't think people think about that when they're just unlocking
Speaker 6:  their phone to use it. Like they don't necessarily think too hard about it,
Speaker 6:  it's just become sort of second nature. But maybe it was like that at the
Speaker 6:  beginning and it was like, oh my gosh, my password, my phone's not locked.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, I think it's like you almost don't notice because you're so used
Speaker 6:  to using your face ID or your touch ID for all sorts of things, right? Like
Speaker 6:  a lot of apps use that technology just to unlock an app and so the
Speaker 6:  idea is we are using the thing that's familiar to people, it's just you know,
Speaker 6:  getting people comfortable with that technology in a new context like a
Speaker 6:  website or an app.
Speaker 2:  What do you make of the idea of tying a lot of this stuff to a
Speaker 2:  device? I think on the one hand phones are sort of inextricable parts of
Speaker 2:  us at this point. Like my phone's right here or my UBI key is upstairs. Like
Speaker 2:  that is a telling fact, right? But at the same time, I had this moment the
Speaker 2:  other week where I woke up one morning and my phone had updated overnight
Speaker 2:  and was bricked the touch screen didn't work, I couldn't do anything and
Speaker 2:  I had this moment of realizing like, oh I can't do two factors because I
Speaker 2:  can't get SMSs, I can't see them anymore, I can't get into my one
Speaker 2:  Password account because it's, it's just sitting here on my phone. I can't
Speaker 2:  text my wife. And like I had this crazy moment of being like, oh I am way
Speaker 2:  too reliant on my phone to work and have a charge and be sitting here nearby
Speaker 2:  me all the time and otherwise my life kind of falls apart. And
Speaker 2:  I think there is a reflexive worry that people have about that. That it's
Speaker 2:  like the nice thing about having a bunch of insecure passwords stored
Speaker 2:  in my head is the battery doesn't die.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They're always there. Right?
Speaker 2:  And so like is it the right path to go down you think to tie it to
Speaker 2:  these devices in that way?
Speaker 6:  I think it's better to think about it less is tying it to a device
Speaker 6:  and more of tying it to your like platform
Speaker 6:  account. So if you're an Apple user primarily, you know you have an
Speaker 6:  iPhone and a MacBook and all that, you probably use your iCloud account to
Speaker 6:  store your contacts and to store a lot of stuff. And so when you
Speaker 6:  get a new phone for example, you log into iCloud and like you recover all
Speaker 6:  of your data in that way, right? Right. And So I think thinking about it
Speaker 6:  that way is a little bit more realistic to be honest of sort of the
Speaker 6:  current state of past keys where it's challenging. It's the same way
Speaker 6:  like you lose your phone, it's really annoying to recover all of that data
Speaker 6:  but Passkeys will get recovered. If you think back to like the old
Speaker 6:  web auth end days, your Passkeys were like impossible to recover in
Speaker 6:  that situation. And so that's one of the big problems we were trying to solve
Speaker 6:  is to make account recovery a little bit more possible. I think that's also
Speaker 6:  a really big benefit to using something like one Password So I
Speaker 6:  use a MacBook laptop but I have an Android phone and So I have this
Speaker 6:  like cross platform situation in my life that isn't really
Speaker 6:  ideal for Passkeys to be honest because a Passkeys on my Android
Speaker 6:  phone doesn't really naturally translate to my MacBook. It's this really
Speaker 6:  kind of weird QR code experience. But instead I use one
Speaker 6:  password for everything.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And then be the idea is that then because one password works
Speaker 2:  across platforms, my pass keys live in my one password
Speaker 2:  account, they don't live on my phone, they don't live on my laptop, they
Speaker 2:  live in my one password account. And as long as I can get into my one Password
Speaker 2:  account, which ironically soon you might do through a pass key which we should
Speaker 2:  talk about, then I kind of have it wherever I am.
Speaker 6:  Exactly.
Speaker 2:  That structure makes sense to me because then you're on, as long as you can
Speaker 2:  log into something, which I think in the year 2024 is a pretty
Speaker 2:  reasonable assumption to make. But that brings me to the question of
Speaker 2:  logging into all of my pass keys with a pass key
Speaker 2:  and and I just think part of what's really interesting about that is like
Speaker 2:  one password is very much starting to try to own like the whole security
Speaker 2:  stack, right? Like I now have two factor codes in my one Password I
Speaker 2:  have, I have my passkey in my one password and I would think that
Speaker 2:  raises the stakes pretty dramatically for one password
Speaker 2:  that now if something bad happens to my one password stuff, not only
Speaker 2:  are is someone gonna get a control of my passwords, they're gonna get control
Speaker 2:  of everything. And like one piece of security advice that I've heard
Speaker 2:  from people over and over and over is don't store everything in one place
Speaker 2:  because you should assume everything is insecure and essentially like don't
Speaker 2:  let the two sides of the coin talk to each other. And you're kind of saying
Speaker 2:  the opposite, which is like put everything in this one place because it's
Speaker 2:  simpler and better And I certainly agree that it's simpler but like does
Speaker 2:  it change the way you have to think about even the security of one password
Speaker 2:  itself? That's
Speaker 6:  A really interesting question. I actually don't think it does because our
Speaker 6:  whole thing from the beginning has been that we take
Speaker 6:  your security and privacy really seriously. Everything is end to
Speaker 6:  unencrypted. Like one password has no access to anyone's
Speaker 6:  actual credentials and I don't necessarily see a Password
Speaker 6:  as being any different from a passkey from like the one Password
Speaker 6:  perspective. It's ultimately just a credential material of some sort
Speaker 6:  that we're storing and we're gonna protect the same way that we would credit
Speaker 6:  card data or social security numbers or like whatever data
Speaker 6:  you wanna store with us, right? I I try my best instead of saying password
Speaker 6:  manager to say credential manager or something along those lines because
Speaker 6:  it is so much more than passwords and has been for a really long time and
Speaker 6:  So I actually don't think it changes our security model that much. We're
Speaker 6:  always looking to like upgrade that and like what can we do to improve?
Speaker 6:  Which is where you know obviously using a pass key to sign into one password
Speaker 6:  comes in. Right now we have that Password and secret key
Speaker 6:  sort of model. We have like SSO support if you're a business customer. But
Speaker 6:  for the most part it's kind of that two factor The, the secret key is sort
Speaker 6:  of a device key and so we're always looking for ways to upgrade that, which
Speaker 6:  is why we've been exploring passkey login which would be really incredible
Speaker 6:  to add to to one password.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Why does that feel like the right way to do the
Speaker 2:  sort of master login? I think part of what I'm getting at here is I think
Speaker 2:  what we're boiling down to is there being one sort of
Speaker 2:  crucial login, right? Whether it's the passcode on my phone or
Speaker 2:  my master password for one password, like there is going to be
Speaker 2:  one thing I have to know and that is the thing that opens up everything else.
Speaker 2:  And I think with phones, one reason people are nervous is like the Wall Street
Speaker 2:  Journal did a bunch of really good reporting about people having their phones
Speaker 2:  stolen and their passcodes read. And that becomes even scarier
Speaker 2:  in this world where my pass keys also live on my phone because now all you
Speaker 2:  need to know is the four digits I use to log into my phone and you can have
Speaker 2:  everything. And with something like one Password now it's like I don't, I
Speaker 2:  literally don't know any of my passwords except my one Password Password
Speaker 2:  anymore. Which I think in a lot of ways is the intended behavior and that
Speaker 2:  makes sense to me. I don't reuse that Password anywhere. I don't even have
Speaker 2:  that password written down anywhere. It's just, it's the one Password I have
Speaker 2:  memorized but now you're trying to even replace that Why?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so the good news is like in one password's case in
Speaker 6:  particular, so I'll speak really just about that, but you have this password
Speaker 6:  and you have this secret key and so even in just the, the
Speaker 6:  state of the world right now with one Password, if someone were to get your
Speaker 6:  master password that really long one, the one that you have to remember,
Speaker 6:  they actually still can't get into your one password account unless they
Speaker 6:  also steal a device that you have one Password on already, which is really
Speaker 6:  great, right? That's a good starting point. But now what if we also make
Speaker 6:  it even harder for someone to steal that Password because
Speaker 6:  it's not a password, right? It's not even something you know now Yes that
Speaker 6:  Passkeys does have to then live somewhere, right? So it has to live in your
Speaker 6:  platform account or in a UB key or something along those lines. So there
Speaker 6:  is kind of this like vicious cycle of where does the final
Speaker 6:  pass passkey live And I don't know that that's like a perfectly solved
Speaker 6:  problem right now but it still a way better experience than right now.
Speaker 6:  So we're working through it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I agree with that. I mean it is just really interesting. I think you're
Speaker 2:  exactly right that yeah at some point there is the one thing
Speaker 2:  and the question of what the one thing should be, I don't know that we know
Speaker 2:  yet. I don't know that we've answered it and I think the idea of it being
Speaker 2:  a a hardware thing that lives on my keyring makes a lot of sense but has
Speaker 2:  downsides. There's like the perfect version of it. It would be like it lives
Speaker 2:  in a safe somewhere far away where no one can get to it but that obviously
Speaker 2:  is a disastrous user experience
Speaker 6:  But also somehow you can get to it. Right?
Speaker 2:  Exactly. I I can teleport into it when necessary but that's it. Yeah
Speaker 2:  I don't Do you have any sense of what the best available version of that
Speaker 2:  is? Is it your phone at the moment? Like the the device you have?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think the current state of that is, you know, we recommend that
Speaker 6:  your passkey four one password lives in whatever your platform
Speaker 6:  account is or UBI key, right in your iCloud, your Google. We typically recommend
Speaker 6:  that you have a backup because obviously If you lose it. It's just kind of
Speaker 6:  a pain to be honest to recover If you kind of lose that master one. So we
Speaker 6:  recommend you have some backups and so that's kind of the state of the world
Speaker 6:  right now. I think in an ideal world it's something much more about your
Speaker 6:  real life identity like your, your human identity that can identify you to
Speaker 6:  a computer, right? And like none of that stuff is real yet. But there's a
Speaker 6:  lot of really exciting things that people think about in The future and are
Speaker 6:  working on of ways to kind of like tie those things together but in a way
Speaker 6:  that also still is like privacy preserving in in
Speaker 6:  some way, right? It still protects your identity online but it makes it
Speaker 6:  a stronger sense of who you actually are on the internet. And
Speaker 2:  How broad can passkey be in that sense? I mean you mentioned wanting
Speaker 2:  to log people in quicker and and making the case that they, they're more
Speaker 2:  likely to complete transactions that way, right? I just think about the number
Speaker 2:  of carts I have left Unpurchased because typing in
Speaker 2:  my address and credit card number is really annoying. Like much less setting
Speaker 2:  up an account. even that like guest flow is a giant pan, can Passkeys
Speaker 2:  be a store of information beyond passwords in that sense?
Speaker 2:  Is that even a thing people are thinking about?
Speaker 6:  It definitely is. It's not really inherent in pass keys themselves
Speaker 6:  but there's a lot of sort of like additional like wallet type of technology
Speaker 6:  or other types of technology that people are talking about and working on
Speaker 6:  that is kind of like that where it's more about other information that's
Speaker 6:  being stored. It's almost like that password manager experience, right? Where
Speaker 6:  you can store your address and your credit card information to autofill
Speaker 6:  because no one likes that. I don't wanna have to make an account, I wanna
Speaker 6:  be able to check out as a guest but I don't wanna type all that information.
Speaker 6:  So there is a lot of work to be done on like doing that in a more like cryptographic
Speaker 6:  secure way like passkey. But the technology as it exists
Speaker 6:  today doesn't really support that just yet. It's really exciting though.
Speaker 2:  It is really exciting. I mean and that's the kind of thing if it goes from
Speaker 2:  I have to type in all of this information about me on the internet over and
Speaker 2:  over ad nauseum to I have a secure version of all the relevant information
Speaker 2:  about me and I can just dole it out in secure ways whenever I need it.
Speaker 2:  Like that's just a better internet. That's how, that's how this should all
Speaker 2:  work. Yes.
Speaker 6:  That's the dream. Yes and
Speaker 2:  It does seem like increasingly the companies who are storing
Speaker 2:  things like my home address and my credit card information and my password
Speaker 2:  don't want that anymore because it's a security risk. Like I can't imagine
Speaker 2:  if I'm Best Buy or Home Depot, I want any of the risk that comes with that
Speaker 2:  anymore. So I would think most of these businesses would be psyched to figure
Speaker 2:  out how to make this stuff work, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah I think that's the same way that companies would wanna get rid of
Speaker 6:  passwords or any really like PII they're storing, right? If they can offload
Speaker 6:  any of that risk and not have a giant database table
Speaker 6:  full of something that people are looking for, you know, I think that's
Speaker 6:  obviously a win, right? And So I think Passkey solve that
Speaker 6:  security benefit. The sort of compliance regulations around like there's
Speaker 6:  a lot of good reasons and I think it's the companies who are
Speaker 6:  excited to make a like user and security
Speaker 6:  improvement. Like those are the companies that I'm seeing like most excited
Speaker 6:  about Passkeys.
Speaker 2:  So If you fast forward, I dunno 2, 5, 10 years, however long it takes for
Speaker 2:  passkeys to become like truly mainstream. Is there any
Speaker 2:  case left for either having a Password that I type
Speaker 2:  into a website or the flip side having like the
Speaker 2:  login with Google login with Apple stuff like as passkeys get really good,
Speaker 2:  does everything else disappear or do those things kind of have
Speaker 2:  their place too?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think passwords are never really gonna
Speaker 6:  fully go away, but I would hope that maybe like
Speaker 6:  90% of passwords can go away. Especially for
Speaker 6:  the types of apps that we as people just like use every day, right? Our
Speaker 6:  banks are Netflix, our online shopping, like those
Speaker 6:  types of things I think are kind of perfect use cases for
Speaker 6:  passkey. I think there's a lot of good uses for more like social login,
Speaker 6:  like a login with Google or something like that because maybe they need access
Speaker 6:  to your email, you're sharing other types of information that you get from
Speaker 6:  having that connection. And then there'll probably always be some apps that
Speaker 6:  just use passwords and maybe it's a password and a passkey as
Speaker 6:  a second factor of authentication or something like that. But I would hope
Speaker 6:  that you know, for most of the things you're using every day we could get
Speaker 6:  to a point where passkey are working for those types of apps.
Speaker 5:  Alright,
Speaker 2:  We gotta take a break and then we're gonna talk about wearables. We'll be
Speaker 2:  right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back over the last couple of years it feels like the wearable industry
Speaker 2:  has boomed. You have the Apple Watch and the Pixel Watch and the Galaxy Watch
Speaker 2:  all getting pretty popular and pretty good but it also feels like the wearable
Speaker 2:  industry has kind of died. I don't know, it just feels like a few years ago
Speaker 2:  there was all this energy to bring tech to our bodies and give us
Speaker 2:  stuff to hold and wear and clip on that would do all kinds of
Speaker 2:  computery things on our bodies in simpler ways. And now there's
Speaker 2:  just smartwatches and they're basically all just health devices and that's
Speaker 2:  just what there is now. So is this just the way it goes from
Speaker 2:  now on? Is this what the wearables industry has become and will be forever?
Speaker 2:  To help me figure it out, I grabbed vs song who is the verges wearables reviewer
Speaker 2:  and the person wearing the most gadgets at any given time that I have ever
Speaker 2:  met in my entire life. Fi Welcome back.
Speaker 8:  Hi.
Speaker 2:  How many wearables do you have on you right now?
Speaker 8:  Four.
Speaker 2:  What are they? Are you allowed to talk about all four of them?
Speaker 8:  Yes. Okay, I have the Wang Scan watch light. Okay I have the Apple Watch
Speaker 8:  Ultra two, the O Ring Gen three and the E
Speaker 8:  ring.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 8:  Two smartwatches, two smart rings,
Speaker 2:  Pure redundancy. So many things counting your step
Speaker 2:  and giving you dubious information about your sleep.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, yeah it, it's what we like to call a control device. So.
Speaker 8:  I actually use the ora ring to test all like sleep tracking. Okay. Just because
Speaker 8:  they're like, oh where sleep tracker, they're pretty accurate for certain
Speaker 8:  metrics. So I have that and my bed also tracks sleeping.
Speaker 8:  So there's just a lot of control devices to control for accuracy. There you
Speaker 8:  go. So do
Speaker 2:  You wake up in the morning and get like six different scores on how you slept?
Speaker 2:  Yes,
Speaker 8:  I do. That sounds awful.
Speaker 2:  It I, one score stresses me out. I
Speaker 8:  Get like six different scores and then while I'm brushing my teeth I
Speaker 8:  compare all of them and I go oh you're not accurate or
Speaker 8:  that sort of stuff. So yeah, so that's the, the behind the scenes of
Speaker 8:  wearables testing. That's
Speaker 2:  Good stuff. I gave up on sleep tracking like the third day that I woke up
Speaker 2:  feeling like crap and it was like congratulations on hitting your sleep goal.
Speaker 2:  It's like I don't know if I did or didn't but Screw you
Speaker 8:  To, to be fair, like a lot of sleep tracking is kind of dubious in terms
Speaker 8:  of accuracy. Yeah it's not, you know when you usually take a grain of salt
Speaker 8:  take two with sleep tracking Fair. So that's just how it's, yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. But I wanna talk about like the state of wearables 'cause it, I feel
Speaker 2:  like there's been a bunch of news about wearables in the last few weeks.
Speaker 2:  There was a bunch of stuff at CES, we're in kind of a weird place right
Speaker 2:  now and I have, I have a bunch of theories about this, but let's start with
Speaker 2:  Fossil. 'cause I feel like Fossil as a company was trying to do
Speaker 2:  something different and interesting and had a really sort of
Speaker 2:  cool idea about what smartwatches could be.
Speaker 8:  So you know it's, it's really sad that Fossil is now a Fossil but
Speaker 8:  I'm ch but like well
Speaker 2:  That's broadcast everybody. I
Speaker 8:  Didn't make that joke in the actual headlines. So I had to do it elsewhere
Speaker 8:  because everyone else was making that joke at me. But so Fossil basically
Speaker 8:  kept wear os afloat like almost by itself. 'cause
Speaker 8:  Fossil is not just Fossil, it's Diesel, it's Skain, it's all these other
Speaker 8:  sub-brands. And for the longest time If you bought a Wear Os watch, it was
Speaker 8:  a Fossil. So they kind of kept Google going
Speaker 8:  through all of that time. And so for them to actually just like call
Speaker 8:  it quits to completely exit the smartwatch industry,
Speaker 8:  that's really big. It's kind of just, wow, it,
Speaker 8:  it says a lot about where smartwatches are at this point in time and that
Speaker 8:  it's like, you know, there used to be this notion that Apple
Speaker 8:  was, its closed garden and Apple was the main smartwatch of toys for
Speaker 8:  iOS users. But it's sort of happening in the where West space now too
Speaker 8:  for Android. Because it used to be that, you know, Android was the wild west
Speaker 8:  of smartwatches, kind of like phones, right? But now it's Google and Samsung
Speaker 8:  also kind of like phones. So that's, that's just kind of where we are.
Speaker 8:  And Fossil leaving it kind of cements that and I'm actually pretty
Speaker 8:  sad about it.
Speaker 2:  I am too. 'cause it seems like, and I'm realizing now how long ago this was,
Speaker 2:  but If, you go back to like 2017, maybe
Speaker 2:  20 16, 17, there was this idea that
Speaker 2:  all watches or at least many watches of many different styles, many different
Speaker 2:  price points, whatever, were going to become some kind of smart, right? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  There was gonna be this whole interesting spectrum where I remember I went
Speaker 2:  to, I think it's called Basel World, this like very fancy watch show in Switzer.
Speaker 2:  Yes.
Speaker 8:  That world.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And it was, it was like the year everybody was into
Speaker 2:  smartwatches, So, I was wired at the time. And I'm sitting down with all
Speaker 2:  these people as they're explaining like the beautiful history behind this
Speaker 2:  $12,000 watch. And then they'd be like, and also Bluetooth wired it. I was
Speaker 2:  like, alright cool. But I liked that idea and it was like Withings was doing
Speaker 2:  cool stuff with that, this kind of like hybrid smartwatch idea where it looked
Speaker 2:  like a watch, it looked like a piece of jewelry but also still had
Speaker 2:  some tech in it. And it feels like everything on that spectrum that isn't
Speaker 2:  an Apple watch or something that looks like an Apple watch is just gone.
Speaker 2:  Like we've just given up on that idea almost entirely.
Speaker 8:  It is really weird because for right now, I, in the last couple of years
Speaker 8:  actually, smartwatches have just like slowly consumed everything. Like where
Speaker 8:  has the budget fitness tracker gone? China, that's it, right? Like that's,
Speaker 8:  that's where most of them are at the moment. And it used to be that Fitbit
Speaker 8:  had its own, Fitbit was the word that everyone used,
Speaker 8:  even that it was a brand, they used it to mean fitness tracker.
Speaker 2:  It was Kleenex. Like in a really real way it was Kleenex. Yes.
Speaker 8:  That's, that's what Fitbit was. And now, now where's, now where's Fitbit?
Speaker 8:  James Park has left right very suddenly during CES I like woke up and I was
Speaker 8:  like, are are you kidding me? I met CES please. Are you kidding me right
Speaker 8:  now? But yes, so that's kind of where Fitbit is and it is really
Speaker 8:  just the Apple watch, the Galaxy Watch or the Pixel Watch at this moment
Speaker 8:  in time. And that's really sad. But to your point, Fossil really
Speaker 8:  embodied that idea of we are gonna have so many different smartwatches in
Speaker 8:  so many different form factors and so many different like styles. There was
Speaker 8:  the Kate Spade watch, there was the, they bought Misfit for a
Speaker 8:  while. It used to be oh Misfit, right? They had
Speaker 2:  So many cool ideas
Speaker 8:  They did and like the the touch bezel that Samsung
Speaker 8:  basically managed to actually execute and all of that stuff. But
Speaker 8:  there used to be a joke I would tell my editors and it's like, it's a trade
Speaker 8:  show. I'm gonna go to Fossil. But, and I did this at Gizmoto a few times
Speaker 8:  where I was like, I'm not gonna cover every single watch that they release
Speaker 8:  because there's gonna be 20 of them. I'm just going to take a picture and
Speaker 8:  say look at all the freaking smartwatches that Fossil has brought. And they
Speaker 8:  would come to each trade show with I wanna say like 20 to 30
Speaker 8:  different watches and I'd be in a room and I'd be like, okay, what's new
Speaker 8:  about this watch, this watch is that watch but Armani right Or
Speaker 8:  this watch is that watch but diesel and you know, that kind of gets to
Speaker 8:  the, the problem of the Fossil watches as well. Well yeah
Speaker 2:  So but diagnose that for me 'cause I think you could make the case that that
Speaker 2:  is actually like an awesome outcome, right? Like nobody's mad that there
Speaker 2:  are lots of different brands of T-shirt that are all T-shirts. Like that's
Speaker 2:  how it should work. It's fashion. It lets you make choices. And we were in
Speaker 2:  this moment where technology was just gonna be sort of integrated into that.
Speaker 2:  And I liked the idea of having a watch that seemed like a watch but would
Speaker 2:  also buzz when I got a phone call and count my steps. Like that to
Speaker 2:  me was almost everything I wanted from a smart watch. And that has
Speaker 2:  died and I, what I can't tell is which of the many things that
Speaker 2:  went wrong are the real problem. Like I think there's a thing where Google
Speaker 2:  neglected ow s For a really long time and sort of hung Fossil and a bunch
Speaker 2:  of other companies out to dry. Yeah. There's a thing where maybe people just
Speaker 2:  didn't want those things. And maybe I'm wrong in the people who wanted any
Speaker 2:  kind of technology on their wrist wanted all the technology on their wrist.
Speaker 2:  So the Apple Watch and the Pixel Watch became the thing, I don't know what's
Speaker 2:  your read of like why that all fell apart?
Speaker 8:  It's a lot of of those things in small increments. Okay. So it is
Speaker 8:  like a fact that Fossil invested so much into to the Google system
Speaker 8:  and then, you know, a couple years back Google took about
Speaker 8:  $40 million worth of Fossil R and d and brought it over into Google,
Speaker 8:  right? So that was kind of one of the first big signals that
Speaker 8:  Google was gonna start taking wearables seriously again. But you know, it
Speaker 8:  kind of gutted Fossil a little bit. And then another problem with Fossil
Speaker 8:  is that the price for the price that you were getting their watches, you
Speaker 8:  got a software that was kind of not so
Speaker 8:  great. Yeah. Is what it, it was very like jittery
Speaker 8:  things would work and then they wouldn't, and more often they wouldn't, the
Speaker 8:  battery life was eh, so you were just getting a better
Speaker 8:  experience on other smartwatches but paying a similar
Speaker 8:  price. So what you really were paying for was the style and the fashion and
Speaker 8:  the fact that it didn't look, you know, like this this giant slab of phone
Speaker 8:  on your wrist. Right? You were, you were paying for a watch that looked like
Speaker 8:  a watch. And then I think another aspect of it is that the people who are
Speaker 8:  gonna go for something like Withings and the the hybrids is that they are
Speaker 8:  people who are not going to be buying on an upgrade cycle very
Speaker 8:  frequently. These things. True.
Speaker 2:  You don't buy a nice watch intending to replace it in two years.
Speaker 8:  Exactly. Yeah. And the battery lasts a long time. Like this has been lasting
Speaker 8:  me for I wanna say two weeks. Yeah, that's awesome. Like I haven't charged
Speaker 8:  it. That's, I want, I made it up, that's what I want. And that is what a
Speaker 8:  lot of people want, but those people aren't the ones going out buying and
Speaker 8:  upgrading every single year. Right. So that's not making the company a lot
Speaker 8:  of money. So it's, it's one of those paradoxes where planned obsolescence
Speaker 8:  is a shittier product but it makes, but it makes the company a lot more
Speaker 8:  money. Yeah. So that's kind of the conflict that you have there. And
Speaker 8:  I just think the other issue with where OS three and
Speaker 8:  that transition is that Google clearly put Samsung first
Speaker 8:  'cause everything comes to a Samsung watch first. Right. And then it'll come
Speaker 8:  to Google and then everybody who isn't Samsung or Google kind of gets the
Speaker 8:  short end of the stick mob. Voy was the other really well-known
Speaker 8:  Wear Os watch alternative and they didn't get Wear
Speaker 8:  os three upgrade until, I wanna say December. Oh wow. This
Speaker 8:  like this past December. Yes. It was a thing where Mob Voy users were like,
Speaker 8:  Hey, you told us that if we were gonna buy this particular tick watch with
Speaker 8:  the 4,100 chip we were going to get wear West three.
Speaker 8:  And basically they waited until December, that's when the, the
Speaker 8:  rollout happened and wear West Four is already here. Right.
Speaker 8:  So now they're just like a generation behind, they're barely catching up
Speaker 8:  and they don't even have Google Assistant on their wrist. Oof. And Fossil
Speaker 8:  did have where Google Assistant, but they also had to wait a really long
Speaker 8:  time to get that rollout out. So I can understand where from fossil's perspective,
Speaker 8:  they were just like, okay, we didn't even know where OS three was happening
Speaker 8:  until you announced it. Right. What the hell? Yeah. So, you know,
Speaker 8:  I had a sense something was ki something was not kosher. 'cause
Speaker 8:  Fossil had a very, very regular update cadence and they missed it.
Speaker 8:  Like 2023 was when the gen seven, if it was gonna come out, was gonna come
Speaker 8:  out nothing. Hmm. I reached
Speaker 2:  And they really were the one company you could rely on to keep caring about
Speaker 2:  this for a
Speaker 8:  Long time every single year. So CES is up and down with wearables, but every
Speaker 8:  single year it would be, I would reach out to Fossil and be like, Hey guys,
Speaker 8:  what you got going? And they're like, Hey, here's what we got going. And
Speaker 8:  this year I reached out and they're like, we're not gonna be at CES. And
Speaker 8:  I was like, excuse me, hold up the the whos, he was like, so many
Speaker 8:  just alarm bells were going off. And I think I reached out to them end of
Speaker 8:  November, early December and we were talking for a while and it wasn't
Speaker 8:  until after CES even that they got back to me and they're like, Hey,
Speaker 8:  we out. So,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. So that makes me sad. I have to say. And the other part that
Speaker 2:  makes me sad is I think we like skipped past the fitness
Speaker 2:  band thing way too quickly. This is a thing you and I have talked about before
Speaker 2:  and I, I still believe this very strongly, that like the original Jawbone
Speaker 2:  up was a perfect gadget and there should be more of them. And
Speaker 2:  I don't wanna watch, but I want something on my wrist that tracks basic things.
Speaker 2:  What it seems to be is that instead of bands rings are gonna be that
Speaker 2:  thing. Like it, it seems like the big bet now is that if we're gonna do a
Speaker 2:  non-screen, long lasting, simple kind
Speaker 2:  of wearable, everybody seems to think rings are the thing.
Speaker 8:  I mean, rings are big this year at CES there were more rings than I
Speaker 8:  could count. I would be like, do do, do, I've seen all the rings and then
Speaker 8:  I'd turn and I'd be like, Nope, there's more rings. And like from names that
Speaker 8:  I had never heard of before. So I was like, oh, is
Speaker 2:  It just because Aura worked? Like Aura's been in this for a few years, the
Speaker 2:  product seems to do really well. I feel like the, the like viral marketing
Speaker 2:  for Aura is very good. 'cause you, you watch a podcast or you see somebody
Speaker 2:  on TV and it's like a tech CEO and a vest and there's like a one in
Speaker 2:  two chance they have an aura ring on. And
Speaker 8:  It's not just the tech people, it's the celebrities. Jennifer Anon has true
Speaker 8:  an aura ring. A bunch of sports stars have it. There was a period of time
Speaker 8:  where I think Kim Kardashian and Gwyneth Paltrow maybe
Speaker 8:  Okay. Where having a sleep competition with their auras and these people
Speaker 8:  have millions of followers on Instagram. Yeah. And they were just like, ha
Speaker 8:  ha beat you in my Instagram stories. So Aura really had this, like
Speaker 8:  Prince Harry has, has an aura ring. So they had a lot of
Speaker 8:  buzz in that respect, but they weren't the only smart ring around. They just
Speaker 8:  kind of RIP motive. That was a smart ring, right? Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Had two, there was the motive and the motive ring two and they just kind
Speaker 8:  of like killed them. Mm. So to speak. And it was actually
Speaker 8:  really quiet in the smart ring space for several years. And
Speaker 8:  that's because smart rings compared to fitness bands have a lot of technological
Speaker 8:  challenges because they're so small. They're just so entirely small.
Speaker 8:  But I think we're starting to figure that out. And then there are some
Speaker 8:  health advantages to a smart ring compared to a fitness band
Speaker 8:  that really make them good for sleep tracking and sleep tracking.
Speaker 2:  And part of that is just like literally where it's placed on your body.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So actually your wrist is terrible for most
Speaker 8:  metrics. you
Speaker 2:  Know, I just learned this recently that they're like, oh, let's put all this
Speaker 2:  stuff on your wrist. even that your wrist is the worst.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So like the way these sensors work is that they're shining light into
Speaker 8:  your skin and it's reflecting off of your blood. And so that's how they read
Speaker 8:  your heart rate. It's, it's a proxy for your pulse, blah, yada, yada, yada.
Speaker 8:  I've written about it a ton, just read my stuff.
Speaker 8:  But the, the, the problem is, is that you have so many tendons, there's so
Speaker 8:  much movement in your wrist that there's so much signal to noise that it's
Speaker 8:  very difficult to get an accurate read. Which is why If, you have
Speaker 8:  a wrist based wearable and you're like, Hmm, this sounds wrong. That plays
Speaker 8:  into it. But the underside of your finger is
Speaker 8:  a lot more ideal. There's a lot less noise. The skin on your palm
Speaker 8:  no matter what, no matter how much melanin you have, the skin on your palm
Speaker 8:  is a lot lighter. Sure. So it kind of removes your skin color
Speaker 8:  a little bit as a barrier to accuracy. So there's just a lot of
Speaker 8:  reasons. It's a lot more comfortable to wear. You wear rings anyway. See,
Speaker 8:  and when you're going to bed, you're not, I have had a lot of watches
Speaker 8:  that are gigantic from Carmen, but you know, in the
Speaker 8:  middle of the night I'll wake up and I'll rip it off 'cause it's uncomfortable.
Speaker 8:  Sure. So sleep tracking has gotten a lot of popularity in the
Speaker 8:  last few years. This is the ideal form factor for it. So that's kind of why.
Speaker 2:  Sure. I, I agree with that. I will say the thing that I've had trouble with
Speaker 2:  with rings and the aura in particular is one that I would
Speaker 2:  say like every three months I'm like, I'm gonna become an aura person again.
Speaker 2:  And I pull the one outta my drawer, I charge it, I put it on, I like it for
Speaker 2:  the step tracking. I like it because the battery doesn't die all the time.
Speaker 2:  I'm like forever being driven crazy. 'cause my Apple watch battery seems
Speaker 2:  to always be dying no matter what is happening. It's always dying. And the
Speaker 2:  OA ring is like a sort of light tracker in a way that I really like. I cannot
Speaker 2:  type with that thing on comfortably really. And part of that is probably
Speaker 2:  just that I'm not used to it yet. In the same way that like when I started
Speaker 2:  wearing a wedding ring, it took me a while to get used to it. Now I don't
Speaker 2:  even notice it on my finger, but like it's a pretty chunky thing. I mean
Speaker 2:  you can, and it bangs around on the palm rest of my computer. Like I grant
Speaker 2:  that I'm not used to wearing chunky rings and lots of people are used to
Speaker 2:  wearing chunky rings. but it, it was harder for me to get used to having
Speaker 2:  on my body than I expected it to be actually.
Speaker 8:  Well yeah, like if you're in fashion, you definitely have a statement ring,
Speaker 8:  right? This is not statement ring size, but it is chunky. Like
Speaker 8:  I have several rings on my finger right now and like the normal not
Speaker 8:  smart rings are much thinner. Right. They're, it actually kind of looks funny
Speaker 8:  when, when you, it's like that's what the smart ring is. I
Speaker 2:  Mean it's like you're, you're wearing four rings and two of them look like
Speaker 2:  brass knuckles
Speaker 8:  Look like rings. That's basically, that's basically what it is. And a lot
Speaker 8:  of that is the tech. Yeah. There's just like what you, it's a miracle that
Speaker 8:  they can make it this small. It's actually a miracle that this particular
Speaker 8:  version of the ora ring is completely round. That was a huge engineering
Speaker 8:  challenge.
Speaker 2:  Right. It had a little flat tire for a long time.
Speaker 8:  Right. Yeah. The flat tire is where they put the battery. Mm. Because when
Speaker 8:  you have a flexible battery it's very difficult to make it round. So there's
Speaker 8:  just all these like technical challenges that come with smart rings
Speaker 8:  that make them big. 'cause I'm like this, this is pretty good
Speaker 8:  If. you think about what a smart ring is and I always get our readers
Speaker 8:  and some people in my dms just like, I'm not getting it until it's as
Speaker 8:  thin as a regular ring. It's like, okay, you'll be waiting for a while. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Like you'll be waiting for a very long time.
Speaker 2:  So, but then in that case, I understand why these things would exist, right?
Speaker 2:  Like the size of auras market makes sense to me. There are
Speaker 2:  people who want the things that it offers. What I can't figure out is why
Speaker 2:  somebody like Samsung would make this, because especially the thing we've
Speaker 2:  learned over the last bunch of years is that like a, you're right,
Speaker 2:  ecosystem is important, but B, the market even for a
Speaker 2:  smartwatch is significantly smaller than the market for a smartphone at least
Speaker 2:  right now. And then to take away all the computer stuff,
Speaker 2:  even on a smartwatch and say, okay, this thing is just
Speaker 2:  basically a lightweight tracker. It just feels like that, that just
Speaker 2:  seems like a thing that cannot possibly apply to as many people as a company
Speaker 2:  like Samsung is trying to reach. But maybe I'm underestimating how many people
Speaker 2:  want that thing
Speaker 8:  So. what I will say, and I think a lot of our readers who have Aura rings
Speaker 8:  will kind of back me up is that it's not a good primary tracker is a very
Speaker 8:  good secondary tracker. Okay. But having a very good secondary tracker
Speaker 8:  necessitates that you have a primary checker,
Speaker 2:  Right? You've already like we're way down the funnel of people who care about
Speaker 2:  this stuff at that point.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. but it is a thing where it's like if I care about sleep tracking, which
Speaker 8:  an increasing number of people do, and especially if you're an athlete and
Speaker 8:  you care about recovery tracking fair. Yeah. Like this is a very small subset
Speaker 8:  of people, but it is a very passionate subsect of people. Right. Then
Speaker 8:  a ring that is something that you can have on all the time is not like
Speaker 8:  held to the same battery constraints as a smartwatch. Then
Speaker 8:  it kind of becomes like a, a nice secondary and like I know I'm crazy
Speaker 8:  because I have four wearables on right now. No, I think you're
Speaker 2:  The average user. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I'm, I'm totally the average user. But basically, you know, I will
Speaker 8:  say that I, I definitely am like, oh yeah, if I have an Aura ring
Speaker 8:  and an Apple watch that is the perfect health tracking kind of
Speaker 8:  combo. But you have to care about health tracking. Which I think the thing
Speaker 8:  that makes wearables the like this subset of is the hardest
Speaker 8:  is that fitness and health is a very, very hard habit
Speaker 8:  to develop. Like
Speaker 2:  Well and this is kind of where I've landed with smartwatches, right? I think
Speaker 2:  it's definitely true that the most useful thing the
Speaker 2:  Apple Watch does for the most people is the health and fitness stuff. I totally
Speaker 2:  buy that. I still think that's only one slice of the
Speaker 2:  pie of like reasons to buy an Apple watch. And there are lots of them and
Speaker 2:  right, and I think Apple used to think the like get notifications on
Speaker 2:  your wrist slice was the biggest, it's not the health and fitness one is
Speaker 2:  clearly the biggest, but it's still, I'm, I mean I'm making up the numbers,
Speaker 2:  but like that's 40% of the thing that leaves 50 other things
Speaker 2:  that comprise the other 60%. And as we get to these other things, we're just
Speaker 2:  pulling all of that away and So, what I keep trying to figure out is like,
Speaker 2:  is Samsung gonna try and figure out how to put like a
Speaker 2:  microphone and speaker into the galaxy ring too
Speaker 2:  so that I can talk to my assistant through it? Or are we just gonna get
Speaker 2:  to the point where this stuff matters enough to enough people that it's a
Speaker 2:  real business?
Speaker 8:  I think it's gonna be probably the latter just because you know,
Speaker 8:  my grandpa, my family's full of doctors and my grandpa was like Mr. Doctor
Speaker 8:  in our family, he was the most esteemed one and he would always tell us
Speaker 8:  that your health is the most valuable thing you have. Sure. If, you don't
Speaker 8:  have health your life kind of is, it's not what it could be. It's one of
Speaker 8:  those things that I think the longer that we live, the more technology advances,
Speaker 8:  the more that we know about our health, like I think that's going to kind
Speaker 8:  of impress upon people that I wanna live longer, I wanna see my kids, I wanna
Speaker 8:  be able to, you know, do things with them that's gonna become more important
Speaker 8:  to people. And the thing that really stymie is that, is that
Speaker 8:  health is not built in spurts. It's not in New Year's resolutions,
Speaker 8:  it's in tiny things that you do every day. And that's very, very, very difficult
Speaker 8:  for most people to make that behavioral change. For sure. It's for sure the
Speaker 8:  number one thing that I think stands in the way of wearable adoption and
Speaker 8:  battery life, those two things. So you know, it's
Speaker 8:  just, I really do think the health aspect is big there, but don don't think
Speaker 8:  that Samsung would be smart to put microphones into the Galaxy ring.
Speaker 8:  I really don't. I think the smartest thing it could do is to bundle it with
Speaker 8:  the Galaxy Watch so that you're not buying it separately, you're
Speaker 8:  buying it for a discounted price. Interesting. And then you have the whole
Speaker 8:  picture of, of the Samsung Health experience and then
Speaker 8:  you're just in their ecosystem. I really think it's an ecosystem pay
Speaker 8:  play where you get an accessory for your accessory to your phone. And I think
Speaker 8:  if they're smart they'll do it that way. Where you're just like, oh are you
Speaker 8:  gonna upgrade to the Samsung Galaxy seven free galaxy ring for you? Right.
Speaker 8:  And then you know, you do that at first and then people get on different
Speaker 8:  upgrade cycles and then they buy in and that's my
Speaker 8:  insidious capitalism plan for
Speaker 2:  It tracks. No, it does. It does kind of make sense. And it also gets you
Speaker 2:  to the point where now you're literally wearing something from that company
Speaker 2:  24 hours a day
Speaker 8:  And I think it, it should be really scary for Aura or Unprompted
Speaker 8:  sent me a statement when the Galaxy ring was unveils. They're like, oh that's
Speaker 8:  never a good time.
Speaker 2:  They're like, did it say we're not scared? Yes, everything's fine. Yes.
Speaker 8:  They said we're not scared, we have hundreds of patents. We are the
Speaker 8:  leader. This is validation in the space. And I'm like, yes, but also you
Speaker 8:  should be scared because you charge a $6 monthly
Speaker 8:  subscription on top of a $300 ring. Samsung can go,
Speaker 8:  oh we don't need a, we don't need a subscription for you. Right.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Here have some rings we don't need have some
Speaker 8:  Rings have it with our, with our watch. That also doesn't come with rings.
Speaker 8:  We've also spent two years beefing up our sleep tracking like features.
Speaker 8:  So Yeah. Yeah. So I think, I think auras, I don't
Speaker 8:  think they have to worry now, but they should be a little
Speaker 8:  concerned is what what I think. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah that seems right. It has a lot of the vibes of like when
Speaker 2:  Slack took out that full page ad when Microsoft Teams came out being like,
Speaker 2:  everything's fine. We think our product is terrific and that went super great
Speaker 2:  for Slack. Last thing then we gotta go. Should I just give up on my idea
Speaker 2:  and dream of the like wearable computer as a
Speaker 2:  thing? Like ever since the beginning of the Apple Watch, I have loved
Speaker 2:  the thesis of the Apple Watch originally, which was basically like,
Speaker 2:  we wanna build a new, simpler, lower touch, more
Speaker 2:  personal device for you to use instead of pulling out your phone
Speaker 2:  all the time. And I think like if I were to get real Galaxy branded about
Speaker 2:  all of this, right? It's like you, you come back to all this AI stuff that's
Speaker 2:  happening and the stuff we're doing with voice and with transcription and
Speaker 2:  you can get to the point where like, okay, maybe actually talking to my wrist
Speaker 2:  is going to quickly become a thing I can do and it will be good. And at
Speaker 2:  the same time all of these products are running away from that stuff and
Speaker 2:  toward health and fitness. And so one of two things is either gonna happen,
Speaker 2:  it's either gonna come back around or it's just these are just going to be
Speaker 2:  health and fitness devices and we're either gonna have to invent something
Speaker 2:  new or the phone is gonna continue to be the computer. Which one do you think
Speaker 2:  it's,
Speaker 8:  I think in the short term the latter, but in the long term the former.
Speaker 2:  So you think we might come back around?
Speaker 8:  Actually I, I think we are gonna come back around and you can see it with
Speaker 8:  AR glasses. They are real, I just don't necessarily think it's gonna be a
Speaker 8:  wrist. I think it's gonna be your eyes. That's, yeah. So like it's just,
Speaker 2:  Yeah those Arabia meta glasses are like
Speaker 8:  That's, it's pretty wild.
Speaker 2:  You put them on and it's like, oh I kind of get it now.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Yeah. Like I, I get it. Yeah. Once they figure out how to do actual
Speaker 8:  AR and not mixed reality, that's gonna be, it's, it's gonna be a lot. But
Speaker 8:  the thing is, is point when you wear something on your body that's health,
Speaker 8:  right? That requires the FDA to get involved. Like we've been talking about
Speaker 8:  smart contacts for a long time, there's various prototypes in that. But when
Speaker 8:  you are shining light into your eye that way, that's a
Speaker 8:  are you gonna burn your ol It's the whole thing. Yeah. We don know, right?
Speaker 8:  We don't know. That's why, that's my theory is that why in the last versions
Speaker 8:  of iOS and Watch West, they included vision health for children
Speaker 8:  because children's vision health If, you mess up your health as a
Speaker 8:  child. You can't really get into a vision pro can you
Speaker 2:  Man, speaking of ruthless capitalism, like we're gonna, we're gonna save
Speaker 2:  children's eyesight so they can use our headsets.
Speaker 8:  I do, but actually I really, you probably right. Do think that's it. I really
Speaker 8:  do think that's part of the thing because you know, smart glasses leave out
Speaker 8:  a lot of people who don't have like, you know, normal vision
Speaker 8:  including myself with my terrible astigmatism. But
Speaker 8:  I really do think that we're gonna go all the way around. It's just that
Speaker 8:  we're in the very baby ages of wearables. It might feel like we've gotten
Speaker 8:  really advanced, but we are super early on it. The tech is not there yet.
Speaker 8:  It's not miniature enough yet as we saw with the Vision Pro, it's here to
Speaker 8:  sell you on a future and that's what smartwatches are here. The RayBan meta
Speaker 8:  glasses, that's what they're here. Like the ora ring. These are all selling
Speaker 8:  you on a future that hasn't arrived yet. 'cause technologically it's not
Speaker 8:  possible yet. And like are we going to get noninvasive blood glucose monitoring
Speaker 8:  someday? But they've been working on it since 1975.
Speaker 2:  Like
Speaker 8:  I should do not. Yeah, they've been working on it since 1975. It's gonna
Speaker 8:  take a long time. There's a lot of advances that have happened in the background
Speaker 8:  and I talk to all these vendors and it's really cool what they're doing.
Speaker 8:  They gotta deal what the FDA clearance process and that will take anywhere
Speaker 8:  between two to four years depending on how much money and testing capabilities
Speaker 8:  they have and the mountain of paperwork that they wanna do. They have to
Speaker 8:  do it in a medical facility, they have to have the, the security protocols
Speaker 8:  in place. It's, it's a lot of work. So yeah,
Speaker 8:  now wellness, future health, that's kind of the trade off that they're making.
Speaker 8:  Okay. And then
Speaker 2:  Long future David gets his risk computer
Speaker 8:  Long future David gets his face computer, his wrist
Speaker 8:  computer, his finger computer every on the computer. You will be a computer.
Speaker 2:  This is, this is all I've ever wanted. Thank you. All right, we gotta go
Speaker 2:  v. Thank you as always. All right.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna get to The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  Hotline. We'll be right back.
Speaker 9:  safely.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the Hotline as always. The number is
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 Verge one one and the email is Vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com. We love all your questions, we try to answer at least one on the
Speaker 2:  show every week. Please keep calling, keep emailing. I love hearing from
Speaker 2:  you this week we have a question about the Vision Pro. If you're tired of
Speaker 2:  hearing about the Vision Pro and Apple and headsets and the whole thing,
Speaker 2:  I'm really sorry, but it's what everyone keeps asking about. This question
Speaker 2:  comes from John.
Speaker 11:  Hello Vergecast team. I'm John in West Lafayette, Indiana,
Speaker 11:  apple Price, the First Vision Pro at $3,500
Speaker 11:  for getting Apple's, high profit margins for the moment. What would the
Speaker 11:  price need to be for your review to say we don't
Speaker 11:  yet know how much consumers will use this, but the price is attractive.
Speaker 11:  $1,500, $2,000. Optional follow up question
Speaker 11:  today, apple sells iPad models from 3 29 to
Speaker 11:  10 99. In two or three years, what will be the right
Speaker 11:  price range for two or three Apple Vision models? Thanks
Speaker 11:  everyone, love the show.
Speaker 2:  Okay, I picked this question not because I have a crystal clear answer, but
Speaker 2:  largely because I really wanna know what you all think. As you've heard
Speaker 2:  on this show, I have spent a lot of time yelling about how expensive
Speaker 2:  the Vision Pro is. I think the phrase all caps
Speaker 2:  $3,500 is like going to be written at the top of my
Speaker 2:  obituary at this point. But I think this is a really interesting and complicated
Speaker 2:  question and I, before I give my answer, I do wanna know what you think.
Speaker 2:  So call 8 6 6 Verge one, one Vergecast at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  Tell me what price feels like the tipping point where
Speaker 2:  this goes from sort of neat thing that exists but doesn't make
Speaker 2:  sense for most people to thing you would consider buying for
Speaker 2:  real and telling other people to buy and If, you already bought a Vision
Speaker 2:  Pro. I'm curious how much more you would pay. So think about that in both
Speaker 2:  directions and let me know. I have two answers. I think the consumer
Speaker 2:  price to make regular people buy this thing in
Speaker 2:  huge numbers is $999. I think we're a long way away
Speaker 2:  from that, but I think when you can get a thousand dollars version of this,
Speaker 2:  that is basically a very good iPad, it's a good entertainment device, it's
Speaker 2:  a thing you don't have to use all the time to feel like you've got your money's
Speaker 2:  worth. That's a nice price for that. It's right in that high end
Speaker 2:  iPad range. It's what you'd pay for a really good computer monitor.
Speaker 2:  It's about the price of a MacBook Air. It just feels like that is kind
Speaker 2:  of the top line. Buy this device, it'll be cool
Speaker 2:  and fun, you'll love it. In my dreams, we're more in like the
Speaker 2:  5 99, 6 99 kind of game console price, but I think
Speaker 2:  Apple is Apple and at 9 99 this thing would do just as well.
Speaker 2:  But also at 1999,
Speaker 2:  $1,999. I think the Vision Pro as
Speaker 2:  it exists now becomes an order of magnitude more
Speaker 2:  compelling at that point. You're in nice MacBook Pro range
Speaker 2:  and it's very much still a pro device for pro people who want to use it
Speaker 2:  for pro things, but even still it becomes
Speaker 2:  hugely more palatable. I mean, think of all the people who spent $1,600 on
Speaker 2:  a studio display or are happy to upgrade their
Speaker 2:  own PC for a thousand dollars just to get a little more
Speaker 2:  performance and a little more memory and all that kind of stuff. Those are
Speaker 2:  the sorts of people who I think a $2,000 price tag feels
Speaker 2:  right. This is a great television like you, you could honestly at $2,000
Speaker 2:  say this is the best tv, it's cool to wear, you'll love it, but it's a
Speaker 2:  television and it'll still be compelling to a lot of people at $2,000,
Speaker 2:  $3,500. You're just out of that range, at least for me. And I would
Speaker 2:  guess that long term, based on what I've seen so far and the way people are
Speaker 2:  talking about it and the way even Apple talks about the Vision Pro, I think
Speaker 2:  this thing will end up covering that gamut. I think this lands kind
Speaker 2:  of in MacBook Range where you can spend a thousand dollars for
Speaker 2:  the cheapest one and I think the cheapest one ends up basically just being
Speaker 2:  a screen with apps. It's an iPad on your face in a very real way. And I
Speaker 2:  think for a thousand dollars that's gonna be compelling to a lot of people
Speaker 2:  over and over. The thing that I'm hearing is that people like this most as
Speaker 2:  an entertainment device, it's a way to sit on the couch or lie in bed and
Speaker 2:  watch something. That's what people buy an iPad for. And I think
Speaker 2:  you can get to a point where if you're Apple and you can sell basically
Speaker 2:  an iPad, but it's cooler to use, you don't have to
Speaker 2:  hold it in your hands, which is actually valuable for a lot of things and
Speaker 2:  it has all this kind of gaming and productivity upside, I think you can sell
Speaker 2:  the base thing for a thousand dollars and then for more stuff, more power,
Speaker 2:  more productivity tools, more ability to like do cool
Speaker 2:  stuff, I don't know what they would add into these other things other than
Speaker 2:  just better specs. That's how you get up to two grand. So that's my theory
Speaker 2:  is that this thing wants to land basically on the whole spectrum between
Speaker 2:  one and $2,000 and when it gets there, that becomes pretty
Speaker 2:  powerful. I think it's gonna take a while to get there. I don't think Apple
Speaker 2:  is charging $3,500 for this because it is like a a massively
Speaker 2:  greedy company. I think this is a very, very, very, very expensive thing
Speaker 2:  to make and it's gonna take a long time before they can sell it to you for
Speaker 2:  one or even $2,000. But when they do, I will stop yelling about
Speaker 2:  how expensive it is and I'm very much looking forward to that day. But again,
Speaker 2:  tell me what you think. Email us Vergecast at The Verge dot com. Call the
Speaker 2:  Hotline eight six six Verge one one. I wanna know how you feel about the
Speaker 2:  Vision Pro price. Would you have paid more than you did? Are you waiting
Speaker 2:  for it to be a certain price? Are you like, David, you're insane. I'm only
Speaker 2:  buying this thing if it's 99 bucks. Tell me everything I desperately wanna
Speaker 2:  know. Hit us up. Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to
Speaker 2:  everybody who was on the show and as always, thank you so much for listening.
Speaker 2:  There's lots more from our conversation at The Verge dot com. We have now
Speaker 2:  posts on the site with all of our show notes for every episode. So If, you
Speaker 2:  wanna know more about everything that we did, go check it out. Also, like
Speaker 2:  I mentioned at the top, we are now on the Verges YouTube channel with all
Speaker 2:  of our full episodes. So go like Subscribe, smash all
Speaker 2:  the buttons say mean things about us in the comments. Hit us up. we love
Speaker 2:  hearing from you. This show is produced by Andrew Marino, Liam James, and
Speaker 2:  Will Poor The. Vergecast is Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast
Speaker 2:  network. NELI, Alex and I will be back on Friday to talk about all of the
Speaker 2:  Super Bowl streaming mishaps, more headsets, trillion
Speaker 2:  dollar AI ideas and lots more. We'll see you then. Rock and roll.