# Transcript
ID: 7de63d26-f9ba-4b9f-8809-0131b623d2a3
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1248338454115801698/2075373209630725615/s93290-US-3676s-1708857780.mp3
Description: Over the next two Sundays on The Vergecast, The Verge’s Jennifer Pattison-Tuohy and David Pierce dig into the dream smart kitchen, the less-than-dreamy reality of the situation, and what it might take to make cooking, cleaning, meal-prepping, and eating more efficient and more fun.
On this episode, Jen takes us on a tour of her own smart(ish) kitchen, and explains why the kitchen often feels left behind in the overall smart home race. Then, Jen and David are joined by Ben Harris, the CEO of Fresco; and Nick Holzherr, the co-founder of Samsung Food. They tell us about the opportunities and challenges in reinventing the way we cook and eat, and explain why the AI revolution might usher in huge change.
Speaker 4:  Welcome To. The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Automated
Speaker 4:  Pancake Flippers. I'm your friend, David Pierce, and this is the first
Speaker 4:  episode in our two episode miniseries all about the smart home. And
Speaker 4:  actually, we're even more focused than the smart home. We're just talking
Speaker 4:  smart kitchens. So for the next two Sundays, we're gonna get deep in the
Speaker 4:  weeds and in our feelings about smart kitchens and Jen Patterson Tui is
Speaker 4:  the only person I could imagine doing this with. Jen, thank you for being
Speaker 4:  here.
Speaker 3:  Thank you David. I'm so excited about this. I am a smart kitchen fanatic,
Speaker 3:  a frustrated, smart kitchen fanatic. So I'm really excited to
Speaker 3:  dive into this. The, the
Speaker 4:  Frustrated part is kind of why we both really wanted to do it.
Speaker 4:  Talking about the smart home, like our only rule coming into this series
Speaker 4:  was we can't make a series about matter. That was the only thing I believed
Speaker 4:  in my soul.
Speaker 3:  I was like, come on, David Matter. It's obvious. He's like, no,
Speaker 3:  but don't worry listener. We will talk about matter.
Speaker 4:  We are overdue for our quarterly is matter ever going to actually fix
Speaker 4:  everything conversation. So, we'll, we'll do that at some point. But you've
Speaker 4:  been covering the Smart Kitchen kind of as a concept for a long
Speaker 4:  time and you were, were were just taking notes, getting ready for this, and
Speaker 4:  you were like, here's some stuff I wrote 10 years ago about why the Smart
Speaker 4:  Kitchen was gonna be great. And I was struck reading it by how
Speaker 4:  little has changed, but also how sort of clear the vision
Speaker 4:  is for what we want this thing to be. So, I guess, like,
Speaker 4:  just to sort of set the scene for what we're gonna do in the next couple
Speaker 4:  of episodes here, like when you think about what a smart kitchen
Speaker 4:  could be, what, what is sort of the beautiful, perfect
Speaker 4:  vision that you think of in your head?
Speaker 3:  So. I. Just want my smart kitchen to
Speaker 3:  help me cook food. I mean it's a, it's a simple, it's a simple request.
Speaker 3:  I want, the kitchen is a complicated, expensive
Speaker 3:  space. you know, food waste, food management, cooking, lots
Speaker 3:  of meals. I have two kids and a husband and, and dogs that love
Speaker 3:  leftovers. So, you know, there's, there's a lot going on in the kitchen and
Speaker 3:  it feels like it's such a ripe space for technology to just be like, okay,
Speaker 3:  here we are gonna help you. So the ideal smart kitchen for
Speaker 3:  me is one that knows what food I have can tell me what to
Speaker 3:  cook. So I don't have to spend 20 minutes standing in front of the pantry
Speaker 3:  or can most importantly alert me when I'm at the store.
Speaker 3:  Okay, you're planning to cook chili tonight, but you don't have kidney beans.
Speaker 3:  Don't forget to buy them. You know, there's, there's so, but there's so many
Speaker 3:  parts and pieces to the kitchen. There's the pantry, there's the cooking,
Speaker 3:  there's the fridge, your stove, your microwaves, your Therma mix, your
Speaker 3:  blend. So, I mean, there's so many parts and pieces. And then the dishwasher,
Speaker 3:  the cleanup, So, I just, I feel like there's such a huge
Speaker 3:  potential in this space for technology to make it
Speaker 3:  easier but also better because the
Speaker 3:  default is, ugh, order pizza or ugh DoorDash.
Speaker 3:  Whereas, you know, that shouldn't be my default. But often on a
Speaker 3:  busy night I look at my fridge and I'm like, ah, no. But
Speaker 3:  really if the fridge could say to me, okay, no, no, no, no, don't, don't
Speaker 3:  call dominoes here. Don't forget you've got kidney beans,
Speaker 3:  you've got mince. Let's whip up a curry or a chili. But
Speaker 3:  then the one other thing that really is a struggle here is I want
Speaker 3:  everything in my kitchen to work together. And this is where the
Speaker 3:  smart home in general has had problems and the kitchen in particular even
Speaker 3:  more problems because there's so many legacy manufacturers in this space.
Speaker 3:  And then you have these sort of startups that have come in with like, oh
Speaker 3:  look, we have this great device for you, but it doesn't work with anything
Speaker 3:  else and it's just a single device. Whereas the kitchen is a big space
Speaker 3:  with lots of technology already in it. So my ultimate smart kitchen
Speaker 3:  is one where everything communicates with everything else.
Speaker 3:  My pantry talks to my fridge, my fridge talks to my oven. It sounds extreme.
Speaker 3:  Why do I need my fridge talk to my oven? But ultimately it's should be a
Speaker 3:  simple process and make my life easier.
Speaker 4:  I think that's right. The, the make my life easier thing is what I've really
Speaker 4:  come around to to, like I, I was making dinner last night thinking about,
Speaker 4:  okay, what parts of this would I like to automate away?
Speaker 4:  And the part where I'm like cutting carrots is like whatever, I, I don't
Speaker 4:  really mind cutting carrots and If you. They're, they make like things that
Speaker 4:  make cutting easier. Right? But the thing where I have to remember when to
Speaker 4:  preheat the oven and always forget to do it for too long, so I'm doing it
Speaker 4:  too late and then I'm standing around waiting for the oven to preheat. Like
Speaker 4:  I would just like it if the kind of balancing act that is being
Speaker 4:  in the kitchen all the time, were just a little better that it was like,
Speaker 4:  oh he started preheating the oven. I'm gonna start also preheating the air
Speaker 4:  fryer because I know what David's about to cook and it's gonna go in there
Speaker 4:  in 10 minutes. I made air fryer broccoli last night, by the way, for the
Speaker 4:  first time Ooh fantastic, easiest thing I've ever made and probably the
Speaker 4:  tastiest broccoli I've ever cooked. So that was cool. End upsetting
Speaker 4:  all at the same time. but it just feels like there's so many of these like
Speaker 4:  little tiny decisions you make in the kitchen all of the time. And I feel
Speaker 4:  like when we talk about the smart kitchen, we talk about, I always think
Speaker 4:  about the scene and beauty and the beast where the dishes are making dinner.
Speaker 4:  Like that's a version of the smart home that people talk about that I actually
Speaker 4:  don't really want. Right. Where you just kind of sit at the table and your
Speaker 4:  kitchen cooks dinner for you. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I mean I, I would like that but, but I feel like that's, that is, I
Speaker 4:  Guess that's fair. I would like that occasion
Speaker 3:  Perhaps pie in the sky. Right. We may be a ways away from that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's, that's like, like a pipe dream at best I think. But the idea
Speaker 4:  that I could just sort of do the things that are interesting
Speaker 4:  and useful and valuable and kind of my appliances know
Speaker 4:  what I need from them in that process. Yes. That feels like
Speaker 4:  it should be attainable. And I feel like as we talk about smart home stuff
Speaker 4:  in general, that is like the level we have to get to that with
Speaker 4:  so many things we're just not quite at yet.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I mean 'cause ultimately you could see, you know, one of the problems
Speaker 3:  with cooking is not nothing ever comes out at the same time. This is where
Speaker 3:  DoorDash is great 'cause everything's ready at once, but you know, you've
Speaker 3:  made mashed potato but the sausages are still an hour later and then you're
Speaker 3:  gonna have cold mashed potatoes or you have to stick 'em in the microwave
Speaker 3:  and it's like a juggling act and it feels like technology could really help
Speaker 3:  bring everything, you know, a great streamline
Speaker 3:  timeline and you know, you preheat the oven, the overhead fan
Speaker 3:  should come on automatically. I mean there's just so many small parts that
Speaker 3:  it feels like could all come together to just make the process easier and
Speaker 3:  also make us better chefs. Yeah. Like the air fry
Speaker 3:  for example is obviously a huge revolution in the kitchen and though it's
Speaker 3:  basically a convection oven, but you know,
Speaker 4:  But a small one, it's so fast. That's
Speaker 3:  Another story. Yeah. But yeah, technology can make us
Speaker 3:  better chefs, better cooks do better in the kitchen. That's where we're at
Speaker 3:  now. Perhaps eventually we'll have the kitchen that actually can
Speaker 3:  cook for us one day Beyond the Microwave, which already does a
Speaker 3:  pretty good job of that for, for you. True.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So you, you want the Beauty in the Beast kitchen? I mean I really,
Speaker 4:  I kind of do too. Like I guess I'm, I'm sort of lying to myself. It would
Speaker 4:  be great to have every once in a while.
Speaker 3:  Well, or the robot that you just say go, go cook, go cook my dinner
Speaker 3:  for me and it goes into the kitchen and gets everything for you.
Speaker 3:  but
Speaker 4:  It would be kind of nice.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean, you know, the Roy the robot dream, but yeah, I ultimately though
Speaker 3:  cooking is fun, right? A lot of people enjoy cooking. I I
Speaker 3:  am a huge home chef. I, I have a, you know, for my
Speaker 3:  last large birthday rather than, you know, get the sports car. My
Speaker 3:  midlife crisis was a brand new kitchen.
Speaker 4:  I love that.
Speaker 3:  I know. And I wanted to make it smart. I was like, I mean I'm a smart home
Speaker 3:  reviewer. I should have a smart kitchen and it was surprisingly hard.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So actually one of the things I was gonna ask you at the beginning
Speaker 4:  is like walk me through your setup because I think one of the things you
Speaker 4:  and I talk a lot about is how these things are getting sort of incrementally
Speaker 4:  better over time. And I think lights are sort of a fun example, right? Like
Speaker 4:  10 years ago it was like, oh you can turn on your lights and now you can
Speaker 4:  do some sort of interesting sophisticated stuff with the lighting in your
Speaker 4:  house. I think it's still relatively low stakes in the scheme of things like
Speaker 4:  when lights come on. But the idea that like I can sync up my lights to my
Speaker 4:  television so that what I'm watching affects the lighting in the room. Like
Speaker 4:  that's objectively like cool and pretend sort of bigger, more interesting
Speaker 4:  things over time. It feels to me like the Smart Kitchen is still sort
Speaker 4:  of a collection of individually smart things, but nothing
Speaker 4:  bigger than that. But I'm curious like you got to go through this actual
Speaker 4:  process as a person who does this for a living. Like paint us a picture of
Speaker 4:  of Jen's Smart Kitchen.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, so it's still very much individually smart gadgets and that's, you
Speaker 3:  know, that's kind of been the way the kitchen has has been, and I've said
Speaker 3:  this before but the, the kitchen is already the most technologically advanced
Speaker 3:  space in our home. So we've already got, you know, a robot that washes our
Speaker 3:  dishes. We've got, you know, a box that keeps our food fresh.
Speaker 3:  We've got an oven that can do a lot of really cool things. But one
Speaker 3:  of the problems I come across in the kitchen, and this is part of what I'm
Speaker 3:  gonna be experimenting over this next couple of episodes, is that
Speaker 3:  smart kitchen gadgets and just regular kitchen gadgets are really complicated.
Speaker 3:  They have so many functions like a microwave can do
Speaker 3:  some amazing things, but most people just hit that extra 32nd button
Speaker 3:  and come out with, you know, hot coffee or popcorn. We
Speaker 3:  don't take advantage of the technology we already have in the kitchen
Speaker 3:  and this is where apps and AI and the smart
Speaker 3:  kitchen could be so much more useful. Like actually helping us
Speaker 3:  use our appliances better. It is a lot easier to
Speaker 3:  use a smart, my Smart Oven for example, the features
Speaker 3:  on it, it's easier to program with an app than it is to use the tiny little
Speaker 3:  screen. And I have to answer your question, So I have it Thermador Oven,
Speaker 3:  which is owned by, what was it? It's Bosch. It's Bosch and
Speaker 3:  Thermador are kind of sister companies and then a Thermador dishwasher
Speaker 3:  and they're both smart using the Home Connect Appliance app,
Speaker 3:  which is Bosch's Home Smart Home app. And I, I was
Speaker 3:  able to connect it to voice assistance and I can start it remotely,
Speaker 3:  but there are all sorts of caveats. Like I have to turn a certain
Speaker 3:  knob on the oven in order to be able to access it remotely,
Speaker 3:  which half the time I've forgotten to do. So those types of
Speaker 3:  frustration, like small, I think it's a, it's the safety feature and I get
Speaker 3:  it. But those two appliances I got about
Speaker 3:  two years ago and I've really only just started to figure out the benefits
Speaker 3:  I can use from them from a, from a connected angle. My favorite
Speaker 3:  thing in my Smart Kitchen is a gadget that is siloed in its
Speaker 3:  own little ecosystem and that's the Therma Mix which we have talked about
Speaker 3:  before. Yeah. Which is the blender that can cook
Speaker 3:  and it is an amazing device but it
Speaker 3:  doesn't work with anything else. So I just have to do everything in this
Speaker 3:  little, little pot. And then other parts of my Smart kitchen are
Speaker 3:  my smart fridge. So I've actually had this Samsung Smart Fridge for a while.
Speaker 3:  It's one of the older models, but one of the nice things about the smart
Speaker 3:  fridges is that they get all the same updates. So even if I went and bought
Speaker 3:  a new fridge today, the capabilities are comparable, which is nice.
Speaker 3:  Samsung's done a good job there keeping the software up to date. but it is
Speaker 3:  still a giant Android touch touchscreen that's about five years old. So it's
Speaker 3:  a bit laggy.
Speaker 3:  And then I have a smart faucet, which I love and that's voice
Speaker 3:  controlled and that's again, that's Moen and again it's in its own
Speaker 3:  little ecosystem.
Speaker 4:  I need you to explain to me why you would wanna voice control your faucet.
Speaker 4:  I'm not convinced that's a real thing anyone ever does.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Two reasons. First, it, it does have a sensor so you
Speaker 3:  can just swipe on and off and that's the most useful because you know your
Speaker 3:  hands are greasy and, but you can say to your assistant,
Speaker 3:  I need three cups of hot water or
Speaker 3:  give it a specific temperature and it will dispense precisely three
Speaker 3:  cups at 50 degrees or 80 degrees whatever's hot water.
Speaker 3:  Okay. you know, and, and so I'm beyond this stage, but for example, If, you
Speaker 3:  have a baby and you're filling a baby bottle, you can have it dispense
Speaker 3:  exactly the type, the right type of water, exactly the right amount. And
Speaker 3:  you know when you go and put your teaspoon to get your teaspoon of water
Speaker 3:  and it all splashes in your face. Instead you can just have a little pot
Speaker 3:  and say dispense a teaspoon of water. So yes, it's a bit
Speaker 3:  gimmicky. I don't use it daily but there are times when I find that helpful.
Speaker 3:  And also, you know, if I'm cooking and I have a big pot and I can be like,
Speaker 3:  hey moan, start the hot water and I'll come over and I can put the pot in
Speaker 3:  the dish in the sink and it's already warm and ready to wash. So, but yes,
Speaker 3:  as we've said that right now, functionality is a little, it's
Speaker 3:  like we stick wifi chips in things and then we figure out down the road
Speaker 3:  whether there's something good that we can do here. And I feel like
Speaker 3:  we're at that stage right now where figurine out how all of these devices
Speaker 3:  can work well efficiently in our kitchen is is where we should be.
Speaker 3:  That's what I'm hoping to kind of find some solutions to over these next
Speaker 3:  two episodes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it it is really interesting. I think that the fact that the Thermo
Speaker 4:  mix is so useful to you and so many other people, like
Speaker 4:  people love the Thermomix, I feel like it is nearing like the
Speaker 4:  KitchenAid territory of just like people who buy one then sort of
Speaker 4:  obsessively talk about how much they love it. Yeah. And as somebody who relatively
Speaker 4:  recently actually went and finally bought a KitchenAid and a bunch of attachments,
Speaker 4:  like I get it now. I am one of those people. But I think the fact that the
Speaker 4:  thermo mix and things like the Instant Pot even like need to exist
Speaker 4:  is, is sort of telling on the smart home because the only way we've been
Speaker 4:  able to figure this out is to just shove as many things as we can
Speaker 4:  into a single gadget. They're like the the smartphone of the smart home,
Speaker 4:  right? Where it's just like, it just does all the stuff, it doesn't do any
Speaker 4:  of it as well, but it's all right there and that makes it useful,
Speaker 3:  Convenient,
Speaker 4:  Right? You can, you can control it in one app, you know where it is like
Speaker 4:  it's it You don, it doesn't have to learn how to talk to other stuff because
Speaker 4:  it's right there. But that for a bunch of just
Speaker 4:  practical reasons like can't be The future, right? Like the idea that
Speaker 4:  you're going to have one single Appliance that does everything and that's
Speaker 4:  how we solve the smart kitchen is just, that's just not it. No,
Speaker 4:  not least because it would require you to yet again like rip and replace
Speaker 4:  every single thing in your kitchen to make this work. But So I think we're
Speaker 4:  kind of in the, in the smartphone phase of the Smart kitchen where it's like
Speaker 4:  what, how can we put all of this stuff into one gadget and then the right
Speaker 4:  answer is like let's blow it all up back into sort of its original pieces
Speaker 4:  but make them all make more sense together.
Speaker 3:  Exactly. Yes. They all need to work together and that, and I think that starts
Speaker 3:  with the core really is the, is the fridge and you know,
Speaker 3:  Samsung and its smarts Fridge has has been mocked,
Speaker 3:  rightly true over the years but ultimately and in
Speaker 3:  that article that you were referencing that I wrote like 10 years ago, there
Speaker 3:  was some really good ideas about food management. And food management really
Speaker 3:  is the core sort of piece that you need to make the Smart kitchen
Speaker 3:  work. It's great to have all these appliances but If you don't have anything
Speaker 3:  to cook, you're not going to do much with them. So you know a fridge that
Speaker 3:  can know what it has in it, know when you are low on
Speaker 3:  supplies, know what you need for say the meal plan you've made
Speaker 3:  for the week and also tie in with your pantry. I know Amazon at some point
Speaker 3:  had like a, a shelf you could put in your pantry that would weigh your
Speaker 3:  ingredients and give you an idea of what you needed to buy.
Speaker 3:  RFID tags are a really interesting idea in this space. But
Speaker 3:  I feel like maybe a lot of the ideas we had 10 years ago
Speaker 3:  for the Smart Kitchen, there are so many developments in technology that
Speaker 3:  have come along that could supersede those and really bring us to that next
Speaker 3:  level. And AI is obviously one portion where I feel
Speaker 3:  like there's gonna be a huge step forward now in in the Smart
Speaker 3:  Kitchen now that we have that type of capability. And then one of the other
Speaker 3:  areas that I've really struggled with in terms of understanding
Speaker 3:  the benefit of the smart kitchen is the wifi connectivity. I think a lot
Speaker 3:  of people really just don't like the idea of all their appliances
Speaker 3:  being online and all their appliances talking to their
Speaker 3:  manufacturers. You know, Samsung knows every time I've opened my fridge
Speaker 3:  and so there's a privacy issue I think also that is worth sort
Speaker 3:  of considering when you are jumping into the smart kitchen. But on the flip
Speaker 3:  side, and I know we are not necessarily gonna go into this in a lot of detail
Speaker 3:  but it's an area I'm really interested in is energy management. When you
Speaker 3:  connect your kitchen, many of the devices in your kitchen
Speaker 3:  are using energy constantly. And if we can, if we can sort of
Speaker 3:  harness that power and end up helping save energy
Speaker 3:  in our kitchens, that gives you a really good reason right there to start
Speaker 3:  with the smart kitchen I think.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think that's right And that's a perfect segue to the next thing we're
Speaker 4:  gonna do On this episode, which is talk to some folks who are trying to build
Speaker 4:  all of this stuff. But first we need to take a very quick break. We'll be
Speaker 4:  right back.
Speaker 5:  Fox Creative, this is advertiser content from
Speaker 5:  Kohler.
Speaker 6:  I think when we think of design we're like beautiful poster
Speaker 6:  gorgeous graphics, but I also think design has like
Speaker 6:  a place in making sure that people feel the best that they can
Speaker 6:  be. Hi, I'm Laura Derado. I'm a group
Speaker 6:  creative director of Box Creative. During my nine to five and my five
Speaker 6:  to nine, I've always got good design on the brain.
Speaker 6:  It's metaphorically and physically
Speaker 6:  glowing. It's like the Aurora Borealis, which
Speaker 6:  is exactly why I was so excited to meet the new me
Speaker 6:  2.0 Kohler's smartest Toilet
Speaker 6:  on first introduction, it legit just
Speaker 6:  waved a hand at me, not actual waved at him but the lid
Speaker 6:  moved up and greeted me for
Speaker 6:  the use. But right now we're in a showroom. So I can't actually use it.
Speaker 6:  Functions like this. A hands-free greeting and form
Speaker 6:  combined in the new me to elevate the everyday. It's a sculpture
Speaker 6:  that begs for someone to like rest their
Speaker 6:  body on it and walk away feeling really comfortable. A
Speaker 6:  temperature controlled bidet, the heated seat, automatic self
Speaker 6:  cleaning cycles, access to smart home functions thanks to a
Speaker 6:  built-in Alexa. The Numis got it all for everyone.
Speaker 6:  The bottom has this really beautiful green glow and it's almost as
Speaker 6:  if they knew that was my special color because If, you go into my bathroom
Speaker 6:  at home, the entire bathroom is a mint green.
Speaker 6:  It's like the new, we knew that I was showing up. And what's really
Speaker 6:  cool about this is that there is this like circular sphere metal
Speaker 6:  piece that like allows for you to change the color on the bottom. So
Speaker 6:  if I'm not in my mint green era, which I'm often am, I
Speaker 6:  can be in another era, my like calming blue, my
Speaker 6:  like rosy pink, like whatever I need to feel. It's,
Speaker 6:  it's like the Sistine Chapel of Toilets
Speaker 6:  experience a fully connected oasis of clean and comfort
Speaker 6:  with the new Me 2.0. Learn
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. The next thing we're gonna do is talk to some of the
Speaker 4:  folks who are trying to build this Jen You. You found these two folks
Speaker 4:  we're about to talk to who I only discovered later, both have British accents,
Speaker 4:  which I found very rude to do to just spring on me in the middle of an interview.
Speaker 4:  The
Speaker 3:  British invasion of The Vergecast. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Set up who these folks are and and what we're about to talk to 'em about.
Speaker 4:  Why'd you wanna have them on the show?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, so I had spoken with both of these gentlemen
Speaker 3:  over the last few years as I've been covering the Smart Kitchen and
Speaker 3:  they've both been involved in the space for over a decade. The
Speaker 3:  first is Ben Harris and he has is the founder of a company
Speaker 3:  called Fresco. We're
Speaker 7:  A software company. We're working with many of the large Appliance
Speaker 7:  manufacturers to empower them to actually deliver on the promise of the
Speaker 7:  smart kitchen.
Speaker 3:  Its main sort of goal is to create a smart kitchen
Speaker 3:  os that all your appliances can work on. They've done a really
Speaker 3:  neat thing where they've managed to figure out exactly the number of
Speaker 3:  cooking terms there are out there and the types
Speaker 3:  of cooking you would do. So things like bake, boil,
Speaker 3:  sous, and then how you would describe them. And then they've managed to
Speaker 3:  standardize that format into operating system that will allow
Speaker 3:  you to control any Appliance from a single app. Their app is
Speaker 3:  one that you can use Fresco, but it also works in the Appliance app. So
Speaker 3:  for example, they work with Instant Pot. They've also just announced a
Speaker 3:  partnership with Viking and Panasonic
Speaker 3:  Thermomix, LG Kenwood, GE Appliances,
Speaker 3:  Electrolux. There's a whole load of brands that are working with them, although
Speaker 3:  this is still new and right now I think the only Appliance you can use with
Speaker 3:  the Fresco app is the Instant Pot. But it's an interesting approach and it
Speaker 3:  to that interoperability issue that we've been, we've been discussing. He
Speaker 3:  describes the Fresco Kitchen OS app as like Spotify connect
Speaker 3:  in the Sonos app. It's basically a layer that can go into any Smart kitchen
Speaker 3:  app and make your Appliance easy to use and interoperable,
Speaker 3:  interoperable with other appliances, which is a great idea. If, you ask me.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Agreed. And then the other is Nick Holzherr of Samsung Food.
Speaker 8:  I was the founder of Whisk, which was a startup that Samsung acquired and
Speaker 8:  turned into what is now Samsung Food,
Speaker 3:  Which anyone who has been interested in using apps to cook will
Speaker 3:  have probably used. It was a great app that basically let you pull
Speaker 3:  recipes from anywhere. You could scan your grandma's
Speaker 3:  curry recipe and upload it to the Whisk app. Or you could find
Speaker 3:  an recipe from the New York Times cooking app and you could just pull
Speaker 3:  everything into one place. It makes it a lot easier to manage
Speaker 3:  your meal plans, your cooking experience for the week.
Speaker 3:  And Whisk app has transformed into the Samsung Food app,
Speaker 3:  which was launched last year, although it's sort of Whisk has
Speaker 3:  been powering Samsung's food service, which has been part of its smart
Speaker 3:  things app, which is Samsung's smart home platform. And now
Speaker 3:  the Samsung Food app works with the smart fridge, Samsung Smart
Speaker 3:  fridge works with Samsung's smart ovens to do some of the stuff we've talked
Speaker 3:  about. So it can help you meal plan, it can help you
Speaker 3:  send recipes, say you can, your fridge can tell your oven what
Speaker 3:  you're cooking, that you're cooking a roast tonight and start preheating.
Speaker 3:  So there's some interoperability there, which is interesting. And as I said,
Speaker 3:  they've both been in this space for over a decade so they have
Speaker 3:  lots of strong feelings about the smart kitchen and they have great
Speaker 3:  accents too.
Speaker 4:  Well you know, they're, they're doing their best. No, it was a really good
Speaker 4:  conversation. They, they're thinking about things in both similar and different
Speaker 4:  ways in a way that I thought was really interesting. But they both have the
Speaker 4:  same sort of big vision for how all of this is supposed to feel as you cook,
Speaker 4:  which I thought was very cool. It's an awesome interview. Let's just play
Speaker 4:  it here. Let's roll it.
Speaker 4:  Alright, So I. Just wanna start with kind of a big picture version of this
Speaker 4:  question. What are we trying to do here? I think we talk about the smart
Speaker 4:  kitchen in these big broad sort of Jetson Z terms.
Speaker 4:  Maybe someday, you know, decades in The future it'll look kind of like that.
Speaker 4:  But I think you are both in a position of trying to figure out what is the
Speaker 4:  best and most useful and most interesting thing we can do, you know now and
Speaker 4:  in a year and in two years and in five years, just to frame a lot of what
Speaker 4:  we're gonna talk about here. What are you thinking about in that space? Nick,
Speaker 4:  you go first
Speaker 8:  We talk about joy making cooking more joyful. And I think
Speaker 8:  there's lots of things that can do that for people. For some people it's
Speaker 8:  taste, for some people it, which can include what you're cooking or the
Speaker 8:  cooking outcome. The other part is the, the joy of
Speaker 8:  actually the cooking process. Are you enjoying it? Is it fun? Is it, or or
Speaker 8:  are you constantly looking for facts? Health I think is an important part
Speaker 8:  for some people waste. It can be an important part. There's lots of different
Speaker 8:  parts. It means different things to different people, but joy is the word
Speaker 8:  that we center around in our team. Ben,
Speaker 7:  What about you similarly? Joy is definitely something that we have
Speaker 7:  latched onto and it is really unique in the kitchen from an experience point
Speaker 7:  of view. you know, when we really think about a, a moment I think that
Speaker 7:  we're most focused on is, you know, that inner glow or
Speaker 7:  that you have when you know, you've sat down the table and you know, your
Speaker 7:  friends or your family are, you know, licking a plate clean across from
Speaker 7:  you and just that inner pride that you have. I think
Speaker 7:  more so than anything that's really the experience that we're imply empowering
Speaker 7:  consumers to, to get and sort of get into that moment as as easily as
Speaker 7:  possible, you know, and giving them confidence to be able to get there. I
Speaker 7:  can add maybe a bit more context to that and sort of how we see we
Speaker 7:  can get there. Just sort of how we think about the space a little bit. you
Speaker 7:  know, I think one constant, I would say in the kitchen Appliance market over
Speaker 7:  the course of the last sort of a hundred years has been, you know, any
Speaker 7:  Appliance, any product that can make, give you better results, less effort
Speaker 7:  has ultimately been successful. The oven to a microwave
Speaker 7:  50 years ago to, you know, stand mixers a hundred years
Speaker 7:  ago to pressure cookers, to air fryers in the last couple of years. Just
Speaker 7:  how fast that has changed the market, you know, which I think air
Speaker 7:  fryers are an amazing example and now leveraging
Speaker 7:  iot and AI and content creators and screens out there.
Speaker 7:  Is there a potential for us to finally deliver that like friend
Speaker 7:  chef or a Jamie Oliver's sitting next to you in a kitchen essentially just
Speaker 7:  by leveraging technology to actually say, actually no, this is how you,
Speaker 7:  you know, get a, add a squeeze of lemon in here or you know, this is how
Speaker 7:  you can soften a, a cantaloupe or this is how you peel an onion and
Speaker 7:  now your steak is done. you know, I think it's, it's those little tips and
Speaker 7:  tricks and helpers that we believe we can leverage technology to deliver
Speaker 7:  that will ultimately be what the sort of smart kitchen is.
Speaker 7:  Which sort of has a bit of a dirty name at the minute I think.
Speaker 3:  So you think it's more about making the experience better
Speaker 3:  than necessarily making the kitchen smart
Speaker 3:  enough to like cook for us, because that's what the smart home today
Speaker 3:  seems like. It's moving towards a, everything being automated,
Speaker 3:  whereas the kitchen is already very automated. I mean, we have
Speaker 3:  a robot in our kitchen that washes our dishes. you know, we've already got
Speaker 3:  a lot of exciting useful technology in the kitchen and it feels
Speaker 3:  like that next step in the kitchen has been
Speaker 3:  really hard to get to. And my theory is it's already so
Speaker 3:  technologically advanced that it's kind of hard to get to that next step.
Speaker 3:  So I understand you, you guys are sort of saying, well, you know, the outcome
Speaker 3:  we're looking for is to make this kitchen experience seamless
Speaker 3:  and make us all Jamie Oliver's or Nigel Lawsons or
Speaker 3:  who's the American one, Martha Stewart. But yes, there's
Speaker 3:  that experience level, but how are we gonna get from where we are
Speaker 3:  today to that joy? I feel like there's a big leap there.
Speaker 8:  I think the way we, we look at it as like what are the problems that users
Speaker 8:  actually have when they're in the kitchen? And I think there are some incremental
Speaker 8:  changes you can make to appliances, but I agree there's a lot of automation
Speaker 8:  in there already. But If, you look at where the problems are. Like for example,
Speaker 8:  with food waste people, you know, you know that there's thousands of
Speaker 8:  dollars, the figurine, the US is $3,000 per person a year that they're
Speaker 8:  wasting on food and there's a, you know, the majority of consumers
Speaker 8:  want to reduce their waste whether it's for environmental reasons or financial
Speaker 8:  reasons or other reasons. So like that's an area where we know there's a
Speaker 8:  problem and that's where one of the areas we're tackling with things like
Speaker 8:  the family hub where we look at what's inside your fridge and create a pantry
Speaker 8:  and give you recommendations that's like, that is making the cooking process
Speaker 8:  more joyful. You're not watching soft scar in your fridge, you're saving
Speaker 8:  money when it comes to cooking. There's lots of things that are happening
Speaker 8:  there. They're a little bit, maybe a little bit more incremental than some
Speaker 8:  of the pantry stuff with health. I think people want to be healthier and
Speaker 8:  if they, if they achieve that, then it makes their life better.
Speaker 4:  When we think about the smart kitchen, I feel like the vision in people's
Speaker 4:  head is like, my stove flips my pancake
Speaker 4:  for me and it, right? And it's like these little things where it's like the,
Speaker 4:  the oven just makes the cookies for me and I don't even
Speaker 4:  have to think about it and I wanna talk about that road 'cause I think there
Speaker 4:  is some stuff down that road. but it sounds like the way you both are thinking
Speaker 4:  about it is actually sort of everything around that that like,
Speaker 4:  maybe I actually don't mind standing in front of my stove flipping my pancake.
Speaker 4:  And one of my questions for you was gonna be, do people actually wanna stop
Speaker 4:  cooking? I remember a couple of years ago when everybody was like, no one
Speaker 4:  will ever have to go to the grocery store again. Instacart. And like it turns
Speaker 4:  out actually a lot of people really like going to the grocery store. It's
Speaker 4:  like, it's a, it's a process, it's a thing. People enjoy it, people do it
Speaker 4:  on purpose. Like automating that out of existence is actually not what people
Speaker 4:  are looking for. And I think to some extent making food for your family is
Speaker 4:  that too. but it sounds like maybe we've been thinking about it as this very
Speaker 4:  specific like act of making food is the thing we have to solve. And you're
Speaker 4:  both sort of describing everything around that as the more interesting set
Speaker 4:  of problems.
Speaker 8:  I think it's really not joyful If you if you're cooking something and you're
Speaker 8:  burning it, right? That's a very non joyful experience.
Speaker 4:  Sure. And I think
Speaker 8:  It's definitely cooking things too. I don't think it's flipping your pancake
Speaker 8:  for you in my opinion, but there's lots of, you know, things like controlling
Speaker 8:  your oven or your, or your cooking device. But yeah, I absolutely agree with
Speaker 8:  you that we, I'm definitely thinking about it way more broadly than like,
Speaker 8:  you know, is there a a robotic part to my of, to my oven that does
Speaker 8:  something that I, I would usually do myself. And I actually think there's
Speaker 8:  a lot of joy in cooking. I love personally the cooking experience,
Speaker 8:  especially when it doesn't go wrong, if I haven't forgotten the ingredients,
Speaker 8:  when I've got everything I need for it. If I know that it actually fits with,
Speaker 8:  you know, my health goals that will make that process enjoyable and that's
Speaker 8:  not taking me outta the process. I, I want to be part of it. I enjoy making,
Speaker 8:  you know, it's like art. It's a, it's a, it's a, it's a hobby. It's in fact
Speaker 8:  it's the world number two hobby, right? Cooking If, you survey people, it's
Speaker 8:  number two hobby in the world. People like it, they do it not just
Speaker 8:  for the sustenance,
Speaker 3:  But that's when you have the time, right? Because also what I
Speaker 3:  see in the smart kitchen is making cooking easier so that I,
Speaker 3:  you know, yes, on Saturday morning when I wanna whip up, you know, the
Speaker 3:  pancakes and I wanna, you know, do the, the raspberry compote and I
Speaker 3:  want, you know, the French press coffee, I'm going to enjoy putting that
Speaker 3:  all together. But on a Monday afternoon when my kids coming home from
Speaker 3:  school and I got three meetings and I need to get dinner on the table, I
Speaker 3:  want those Samsung arms that they showed at CES one year that will come down
Speaker 3:  and just get the food out the fridge, put it in the oven, and then I don't
Speaker 3:  have to worry about it. Okay? I know I can order DoorDash, but you know,
Speaker 3:  I still want to use what I have in my kitchen. I want, I want the kitchen
Speaker 3:  to do as much of it for me as possible. Is there sort of, you know, both
Speaker 3:  sides to this coin?
Speaker 7:  I think that's a really interesting way of looking at it. And we sort of
Speaker 7:  look at it in a similar way from a, from a product point of view. It's like
Speaker 7:  when you come home, you know, you we, you sort of pure point and DoorDash,
Speaker 7:  we sort of have the, the promise of the food replicator that, you
Speaker 7:  know, I just push a button and then food arrives at my door and DoorDash
Speaker 7:  or Uber Eats and Deliveroo across Europe, you know, so it's, and
Speaker 7:  I think that's how we also think about it from a product point of view, sort
Speaker 7:  of when you arrive home in that moment and then it's like you have to make
Speaker 7:  that decision. Am I gonna cook tonight or am I gonna get DoorDash
Speaker 7:  or have a frozen pizza? you know? And after both of them,
Speaker 7:  you know, you feel that sort of guilt and sliminess and
Speaker 7:  a bit of dirtiness if you've gotten takeaway or you feel that
Speaker 7:  wholesomeness and happiness, if you've cooked, I'm sure you've all experienced
Speaker 7:  that sort of like couple of seconds, a few microseconds that you've made
Speaker 7:  that decision of which way you're gonna go. All the levers that
Speaker 7:  push you towards, oh Jesus, I'm just gonna watch Netflix and order Uber Eats
Speaker 7:  are the ones we're looking to remove. That it's the, okay, am I gonna fail?
Speaker 7:  Is it to next point, is this gonna burn? How do I get the ingredients? What
Speaker 7:  am I gonna say gonna what I'm gonna cook? But if we can give you all of the
Speaker 7:  helping hand and these monitoring pieces to ensure and give you confidence
Speaker 7:  that you're gonna get great results that we believe, you know, that's ultimately
Speaker 7:  what consumers want. So I think there's this amazing analogy from
Speaker 7:  the fifties that I'm sure many of your listeners have, have listened to as
Speaker 7:  heard as well. And this Betty Crocker analogy of when
Speaker 7:  it initially, when the powder mixes were released in the, in the
Speaker 7:  fifties and they were sort of like babbling on from a sales
Speaker 7:  point of view. So you had to, you know, add, I think just add water
Speaker 7:  and then bung it in the oven and the sales are sort of like tipping along.
Speaker 7:  And they did the consumer research and people just said, I just don't feel
Speaker 7:  like I'm cooking. you know, IIII don't feel that inner intrinsic
Speaker 7:  pride afterwards. And suddenly they're like, okay, let's remove the
Speaker 7:  dry egg from the mixture and get consumers to start just
Speaker 7:  crack the egg in and then add the milk, then mix and pud in. Suddenly
Speaker 7:  the dynamic changed to be, okay, I am
Speaker 7:  now cooking this and I am now gifting people this cake and
Speaker 7:  suddenly I have the pride and then suddenly, you know, sales
Speaker 7:  skyrocketed. And that's really, I think, think where we are in the
Speaker 7:  cooking assistant that we ultimately delivered
Speaker 8:  To Jen's point around being a busy parent, I, I'm a relatively new parent
Speaker 8:  as well, but I cook regularly. How do I do that? I I choose to
Speaker 8:  automate out the grocery shopping part, right? To David's point, I don't
Speaker 8:  choose to go to the grocery store if I'm trying to cook something. It is
Speaker 8:  actually takes a long time to walk around that store. And you know, even
Speaker 8:  If, you have a smart shopping list. It takes a while to go through that store.
Speaker 8:  I choose to have that part automated away from me. The second thing I do
Speaker 8:  is I, I batch cook. I, I think a lot of parents do do that
Speaker 8:  So, I cook, like three or four times the amount that's needed and then I
Speaker 8:  put it in the fridge or the freezer and I will like reheat it and, and make
Speaker 8:  it later. Right? And that's like So, I don't cook every day, but I have cooked
Speaker 8:  food almost every day. But when you're actually trying to scale a recipe,
Speaker 8:  that's also another area where technology can help. It's all these like small
Speaker 8:  incremental parts where when you add it together, it does get rid
Speaker 8:  of some of that like hassle and annoying stuff that you
Speaker 8:  have to go through to make a meal. And, you know, remember all the right
Speaker 8:  ingredients, make sure you've got the right quantities. Adapt
Speaker 8:  the recipe to make, to make, to make that right amount. Don't have to go
Speaker 8:  to the grocery store and have it just arrive for you. Someone brings your
Speaker 8:  bell and brings it to you. That makes you able to focus
Speaker 8:  on that cooking part. Which I think lots of people actually really enjoy
Speaker 8:  that part.
Speaker 3:  But now, okay, you mentioned the fridge. When am I gonna be able to have
Speaker 3:  my fridge do all of that for me though? Because that's what I want. I want
Speaker 3:  my fridge and my pantry to talk to each other and say, okay, she
Speaker 3:  doesn't have milk. She wants to do pancakes tomorrow, we need to make sure
Speaker 3:  she's got eggs and there's no flour in the, in the pantry. And, and
Speaker 3:  you know, that that convenience is like, I I don't think
Speaker 3:  anyone would argue with that.
Speaker 8:  I think the answer's yes, and I think it's possible to say that with
Speaker 8:  more confidence in the last year due to the advances of ai, right?
Speaker 8:  The challenge has been AI hasn't been good enough to kind of truly deliver
Speaker 8:  on that. The latest version of the Family Hub, which is released this year,
Speaker 8:  as you said, like it tracks in and out actions on the fridge
Speaker 8:  that is new and it does accurately understand,
Speaker 8:  you know, a, a good number of ingredients. No real user or
Speaker 8:  very, very, very few users are going to manually input that stuff into their
Speaker 8:  phones, right? Or, or their fridges or wherever it happens to be. You have
Speaker 8:  to automate it. And people have tried things like, you know, barcode scanners
Speaker 8:  on bins. So as you put things in the bin, it's you, you scan the bar, people
Speaker 8:  have tried all sorts of things and as soon as you ask the user to do a bunch
Speaker 8:  of stuff there, it basically fails. So I do think AI
Speaker 8:  means that it's actually, you know, it's, it's, some of it's here in
Speaker 8:  some of the latest appliances of course need the latest one, you know, last
Speaker 8:  year weren't do, hasn't got the right cameras in it and stuff. But like we
Speaker 8:  are gonna see across the whole industry some really interesting
Speaker 8:  capability jumps, leaps because of what AI
Speaker 8:  is now able to do and how, how, how accessible AI is to
Speaker 8:  all our, all our companies, right? To be able to leverage. It's, it's, it's,
Speaker 8:  I think that's, I'm, I'm super excited about AI and it goes beyond the fridge.
Speaker 8:  It goes into connecting data from health apps to food apps. It,
Speaker 8:  it goes right across the whole, the whole space.
Speaker 4:  Ben. What are you seeing on that front too? 'cause I think you're, you're
Speaker 4:  in a position of, of being kind of less specifically integrated with an
Speaker 4:  ecosystem, but also being able to like look more broadly at a lot of stuff
Speaker 4:  like Jen is talking about, you know, Nick I'm sure is like
Speaker 4:  required by company policy to exclusively have Samsung appliances everywhere,
Speaker 4:  but that's, most people have this kind of amalgamation of stuff, right? And
Speaker 4:  I think one of the things it seems like is maybe we don't need all of these
Speaker 4:  things to be sort of perfectly intimately connected to get some of this stuff
Speaker 4:  you're talking about, but you're also in a position of being able to kind
Speaker 4:  of make the whole greater than the sum of its parts of the kitchen,
Speaker 4:  right? Are you seeing the same stuff with AI there?
Speaker 7:  Yes, absolutely. It's been sort of transformational and I think has
Speaker 7:  yeah, accelerated what we've thought was only possible over the course
Speaker 7:  of a five year time horizon to, you know, 12 month time horizon.
Speaker 7:  you know, it's like rapid changes in what's
Speaker 7:  possible in the, in in the market. So yeah, for, for context, Fresco
Speaker 7:  are working with, you know, Panasonic, GE Appliances, lg,
Speaker 7:  Bosch, Kenwood Instant Brands, and for multiple other Appliance brands
Speaker 7:  on our, our platform. Actually today or when this podcast goes,
Speaker 7:  goes live, we're announcing a, a new partnership with
Speaker 7:  a group called Middleby, which own brands like
Speaker 7:  Viking and deeply integrating into their connected ovens
Speaker 7:  and delivering the whole connected experience there as well. Because exactly
Speaker 7:  to your point, no kitchen is is single brand
Speaker 4:  Except for next.
Speaker 7:  Except for next. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. So, you know, If, you want to,
Speaker 7:  you know, deliver a delightful cooking experience, you know, it needs
Speaker 7:  to be able to move from each brand to, to the next and, and, and
Speaker 7:  elegantly move across the, the, across the full kitchen. And you know, as
Speaker 7:  Nick touched on there, it's this, you know, dot connecting, you know, which
Speaker 7:  is sort of needed in the kitchen, you know, like this is what we see right
Speaker 7:  now that, you know, people are, they go to YouTube to figure out certain
Speaker 7:  tips, they then look on Google for substitutions. They then
Speaker 7:  go to their, sometimes have to, you know, figure out how, what's possible
Speaker 7:  on their Appliance manual that that's, or on their, on their interface,
Speaker 7:  you know, as Panasonic, one of our partners say is that like, you know, the
Speaker 7:  only thing that microwaves are used for in the states is to reheat food and
Speaker 7:  to make popcorn
Speaker 8:  Heat. Coffee and
Speaker 7:  Coffee. Yes, exactly. And coffee. But it's got unbelievable capabilities
Speaker 7:  inside of being able to, you know, perfectly defrost a pound of Turkey to
Speaker 7:  like, so If you can just, it's just making to Nick's point as well, making
Speaker 7:  these points accessible and just a, a tap of a button
Speaker 7:  available to you. So we've now got all of these pieces now represented
Speaker 7:  in, in data in our backend infrastructure that then allows us
Speaker 7:  armed with AI to just connect the Dots between these and actually deliver
Speaker 7:  a delightful consumer experience that's contextual right in the moment
Speaker 7:  to help you with exactly what you need at the, at the top of a bu. So like,
Speaker 3:  I could stick my Turkey in the Panasonic microwave,
Speaker 3:  defrost it, and then my Viking oven will know that I
Speaker 3:  am gonna be cooking the Turkey and can, and I can just press a button and
Speaker 3:  have all the settings go to the Viking oven. I mean, how, how is that gonna
Speaker 3:  work? Because one of the things I've noticed right now with Smart Kitchen
Speaker 3:  is we have all these individual smart appliances
Speaker 3:  and every time a new smart oven comes out, it's just its own
Speaker 3:  little ecosystem. And there's like the Therma mix, which David and I have
Speaker 3:  talked about in the past, and it's just a joy to use. It's a great smart
Speaker 3:  gadget, smart kitchen gadget, but it's siloed in its own
Speaker 3:  ecosystem. I mean, we, we have a big, we everyone has an oven in
Speaker 3:  their kitchen, most people have a stove top. you know, you've got all of
Speaker 3:  these parts and pieces already, why we shouldn't need to buy individual
Speaker 3:  smart appliances. What we have, I feel like could get
Speaker 3:  more intuitive to use and more integrated, but that's just
Speaker 3:  been a real roadblock to date, as is the whole smart home.
Speaker 3:  Interoperability in general just doesn't seem to be moving us
Speaker 3:  very far forward. And the kitchen feels like the biggest roadblock there.
Speaker 3:  And I know Ben, that's very much what you guys are doing and also Samsung
Speaker 3:  is doing with their interoperability through this home connectivity alliance
Speaker 3:  and matter being able to bring other appliances into the apps.
Speaker 3:  But then we're still having to use an app to control our kitchen. And I think
Speaker 3:  that's a friction point, right? No one really, if you're standing in the
Speaker 3:  kitchen, you don't wanna pull out your phone to press a button when you can
Speaker 3:  just press a button on, on the device. Is there a future where,
Speaker 3:  you know, I put the Turkey in the Panasonic microwave, it defrosts it,
Speaker 3:  and everything else happens automatically and I can just move things from
Speaker 3:  place to place, like move my Turkey around and without having to like, pull
Speaker 3:  out an app or use an interface or use voice. I mean, where is that
Speaker 3:  a, a realistic sort of future in the smart kitchen? Or are we, do we
Speaker 3:  need to still be there and press buttons?
Speaker 7:  I don't think we're that far away, you know, now, which is in incredibly
Speaker 7:  exciting and sort of where we are in the, in, in the journey. you know, I,
Speaker 7:  I I agree. I see a future where there's, you know, one screen in the middle
Speaker 7:  of your kitchen that you can use to orchestrate all of your appliances, and
Speaker 7:  that's where you get the, the feedback. but it's, it has to be multimodal.
Speaker 7:  So you can sort of look at your Apple watch and see, okay, it's like another
Speaker 7:  three minutes until your rice is, you know, ready, synced to the
Speaker 7:  finish of your chicken in the oven. So it all sort of starts to come together
Speaker 7:  at exactly the same time. And you can have this sort of automated process
Speaker 7:  to move to your point, from the defrosting in the Panasonic
Speaker 7:  oven to the, the quick transfer If you needed to over to
Speaker 7:  OOO over to another Appliance. We have standardized the
Speaker 7:  communication and the data format we believe needed for delivering
Speaker 7:  this delightful guided or cooking experience in creating a, a digital
Speaker 7:  representation of any recipe and digital
Speaker 7:  representation of, of any Appliance. So, you know, like really
Speaker 7:  trying to break down how to digitally represent an Appliance
Speaker 7:  in the, in the backend infrastructure to allow you, again, to connect the
Speaker 7:  Dots between all of these things and ultimately deliver this, this joyful
Speaker 7:  experience.
Speaker 3:  When you say digitally represent, can you break that down? Like what's, what's
Speaker 3:  it doing like, so like my cooking app, say my Samsung Food app or my
Speaker 3:  New York Times recipe app, it could know to like turn my oven
Speaker 3:  to broil or So I mean what, how's that sort of
Speaker 3:  actually working in the backend?
Speaker 7:  So we scoured thousands of Appliance manuals and
Speaker 7:  millions of recipes online. So we crawled them and sort of put them through
Speaker 7:  our sort of AI pipeline to start be able to process them. And we realized
Speaker 7:  initially this has now grown, but there's actually 77
Speaker 7:  cooking capabilities, you know, so bake, broil, steam,
Speaker 7:  soused
Speaker 3:  77, that's a lot. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Eight ways to describe them. So like time, temperature, speed, humidity,
Speaker 7:  power. So like suddenly once you have that sort of Rosetta stone,
Speaker 7:  that's sort of like how you can then map a recipe to an
Speaker 7:  Appliance and Appliance capability and control. We now patented some of this
Speaker 7:  experience as well, sort of how it's actually done, but allows us to then
Speaker 7:  search a recipe, see all the capabilities that are needed to be fulfilled
Speaker 7:  and then map them onto the Appliance you have in your kitchen. And
Speaker 7:  you know, it could say, you know, roast your chicken for, you know,
Speaker 7:  an hour at 180 degrees. I think the amazing thing is like, so this is
Speaker 7:  the way recipes have had to be written because all of our appliances are
Speaker 7:  a little different. All of our chickens are a little different If, you have
Speaker 7:  to give this generic one that's definitely gonna not poison people. So variably,
Speaker 7:  you know, it's always overcooked and dry. Whereas, you know, these
Speaker 7:  appliances now have unbelievable technology in them that, like
Speaker 7:  with a temperature probe and you know, heating maps can actually put,
Speaker 7:  you can, you've got chicken programs and the likes as well. But you know,
Speaker 7:  all, all of these appliances now are, are having all of these sort of great
Speaker 7:  programs, but nobody actually uses them because they're buried in
Speaker 7:  a menu that is, some of them look like a VCR from the nineties,
Speaker 7:  you know, you can't actually get get at them. So how do we again, surface
Speaker 7:  it, connect the Dots between these two pieces and what your Appliance can
Speaker 7:  actually do. So you tap a button and you, your, so your chicken ends up,
Speaker 7:  you know, moist on the inside, crispy on the inside, every single time and,
Speaker 7:  and across your full kitchen. So that, that's the, the real opportunity.
Speaker 3:  Doesn't there need to be like a much more basic common level
Speaker 3:  where our appliances communicate with each other? Or is that not even necessary
Speaker 3:  if we can just do it all in the cloud? And I, I guess that's the, the main
Speaker 3:  key here, right? It's people are concerned about buying smart
Speaker 3:  appliances because what is the benefit to me? And it's gonna be
Speaker 3:  obsolete? Is it in five or 10 years? Whereas I want my most
Speaker 3:  stoves, you know, you can have an aga that can last for 50 years.
Speaker 3:  Where, where is that benefit to me as a consumer of this
Speaker 3:  interconnected Appliance world? Is it coming or are we
Speaker 3:  just gonna be stuck with relying on cloud interfaces rather than
Speaker 3:  local interfaces? Well,
Speaker 8:  I think you've got things like Matter are meaningful when you've got Apple
Speaker 8:  Apps and Google, Samsung and others around the table, right? That that's
Speaker 8:  a, that's a Fresco and Fresco, yeah,
Speaker 3:  And Fresco number one. Number
Speaker 8:  One, exactly.
Speaker 8:  That, that is meaningful. Like, and of course we can't force everyone to
Speaker 8:  take part, right? Like there's gonna be, there's gonna be people that don't
Speaker 8:  take part in that. But over time, if it's popular with consumers and consumers
Speaker 8:  choose Matter devices because they want it all to work together, then people,
Speaker 8:  then the others will eventually join, right? And I think
Speaker 8:  ultimately driven by consumer demand, the software part becomes a little
Speaker 8:  bit less important about, because if, as long as it works with matter, it'll
Speaker 8:  then work with all the different, you know, the, the matter devices and you
Speaker 8:  can switch that out, right? If you want to, and you can choose the best one.
Speaker 8:  I think that's what's great about software. People can choose the best one
Speaker 8:  and the best ones win. And you can win really, really fast. You build something
Speaker 8:  new and that's not unique to this space. You can, that's happens with social
Speaker 8:  media companies that are huge and that's why some of them go out and buy
Speaker 8:  other social media companies because the, you know, preference has changed.
Speaker 8:  We have
Speaker 3:  The Federated kitchen. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  But actually one thing I would say is like, you know, I, I'm, I'm a startup
Speaker 8:  founder. I'm not, I'm not like a, a company executive, but I think in my
Speaker 8:  heart, but I'm still here at Samsung and, and why I think it's actually,
Speaker 8:  it's really exciting for me, my personal reason is we have so many
Speaker 8:  different appliances that are not just in the kitchen, just at Samsung, which
Speaker 8:  we have first party access to, right? TVs are one watches and
Speaker 8:  phones or another. And then of course we've got the kitchen. So what we can
Speaker 8:  now, what we're starting to do is connect all these different parts where
Speaker 8:  in, in, you know, if I, if I wasn't part of Samsung, I would basically need
Speaker 8:  to go and build partnerships with another, you know, Fitbit or, or
Speaker 8:  Apple Watch or whatever, to try and get that data in. At Samsung, we have
Speaker 8:  that data here. If a TVs, I forgot to a different TV company we have, it's
Speaker 8:  all first party. And first party gives you, you know, in today's security
Speaker 8:  and kind of privacy world also gives you some benefits. There is interconnectivity
Speaker 8:  that we can develop here. And then hopefully I, as a consumer, as
Speaker 8:  a user, I would love to be able to expand that across other companies too.
Speaker 8:  And I think Matter is definitely a positive for me as a, as a consumer, because
Speaker 8:  like you Jen, I, you know, I would love to have different, different parts
Speaker 8:  to my house. I'm never going to buy all my appliances from just one company.
Speaker 8:  you know, I know David joked that my whole kitchen is just Samsung. I have,
Speaker 8:  I do have a family hub and I do have a bunch of, you know, Samsung devices,
Speaker 8:  which I, which I love. But yes, I also have different appliances at my house.
Speaker 8:  Sure.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean that it's not just the kitchen, is it? There's the, you know,
Speaker 3:  the laundry room in Europe in particular, the laundry room's in the kitchen.
Speaker 3:  So there's so much more this, this can extend to within the smart
Speaker 3:  home. 'cause it does at the moment, again, feels like the smart kitchen's
Speaker 3:  kind of siloed. And I feel like there is so much more potential for the way
Speaker 3:  we can integrate our cooking into the whole home and not just
Speaker 3:  be, I mean, I think Nick, we talked about like, you'll be watching TV and
Speaker 3:  maybe watch an episode of Taste Made, which is like the only thing my husband
Speaker 3:  watches. And then you could snap a picture and your oven could be ready,
Speaker 3:  you know, your fridge can order you the food and your oven can get ready
Speaker 3:  for, but I keep using that analogy, you know, I want
Speaker 3:  my, I want my fridge to buy the food and I want my oven to be ready to cook
Speaker 3:  it. But there's so much more to the kitchen. And I guess just to kind of
Speaker 3:  as we wrap up, like where do you see the, the kind of future
Speaker 3:  integration of the Smart Kitchen beyond just remote control
Speaker 3:  of appliances? Like what is the kind of vision here where we can
Speaker 3:  feel like our kitchen is worth adding smart
Speaker 3:  technology into our kitchen? Where is the ultimate Smart Kitchen future for
Speaker 3:  both of you?
Speaker 7:  For me, it's back to what I mentioned earlier, it's the, like, it it becomes
Speaker 7:  your sous chef through the whole process. Yeah. To your point, you know,
Speaker 7:  you, you, we've got a feed from the what's in your fridge and what's in your
Speaker 7:  pantry. So it's like Ooh, you know, you've got this ine before it goes off.
Speaker 7:  Here's a couple of nice recipes for you, you know, then your oven's starting
Speaker 7:  to preheat. Here's all the other pieces that you, and it's just giving you
Speaker 7:  the right prompts. So, you know, also you can just like remove
Speaker 7:  that cognitive load so you're not worried sitting there sort of stirring
Speaker 7:  rice, sitting over the stove. you know, it's like, you know, it's gonna,
Speaker 7:  you're gonna get a ping when it's ready, you know, and, and all your food
Speaker 7:  will be ready at the same time. And, and you have the intrinsic pride at
Speaker 7:  the end of it that you've cooked it, you know, and then, so everyone's
Speaker 7:  delighted. So it's like, like that is absolutely what drives
Speaker 7:  me and the full team here at, at, at, at Fresco. And
Speaker 3:  Are we there now though? Or is that The future? Like, it sounds like you
Speaker 3:  sort of feel like we're already there.
Speaker 7:  No, no, no. Yeah, there's definitely work to do to, to, to get there.
Speaker 7:  But I think, yeah, that's where we can see is, you know, not too far
Speaker 7:  away now. And you know, I think, as I mentioned earlier, you know, it takes
Speaker 7:  time for hardware to be developed and and shipped. So we have, you know,
Speaker 7:  a, a view now as to sort of where the kitchen is gonna be in,
Speaker 7:  you know, 12, 24, 36 months. And I think, you know, one of the
Speaker 7:  inspiring things I would say that we can remind ourselves of is, you know,
Speaker 7:  everyone thinks the kitchen, you know, space moves slowly, but
Speaker 7:  I think just If, you look at air fryers, I think it's just such an amazing
Speaker 7:  example of, you know, they've gone from, you know, no one talking about them,
Speaker 7:  you know, four or five years ago to now being in everyone's kitchen
Speaker 7:  and everyone talking about the way we cook. you know? So that's something
Speaker 7:  that has like globally been transformed in a relatively short period of
Speaker 7:  time, and that can move faster with software. So, you know, I think that's
Speaker 7:  what we're excited about over the course of the next couple of years.
Speaker 8:  For me, I think it's the, all the different parts of your journey from inspiration
Speaker 8:  to meal on the table, whether that planning, shopping,
Speaker 8:  cooking, eating, all of those parts, and we have, we have different features
Speaker 8:  that we've already, you know, built in those, which we are gonna
Speaker 8:  incrementally keep improving upon. But ultimately it comes in down to like
Speaker 8:  sensors being able to predict and be, be making more
Speaker 8:  predictive experience for, for us, and then integrations into more devices
Speaker 8:  so it works more seamlessly with those devices. And those are all like, incremental
Speaker 8:  changes. And I think, you know, I, I think there's a fundamental kind of
Speaker 8:  like vision. I do think it's gonna change drastically there. I think those
Speaker 8:  are the real problems that we're in the kitchen that, that we are kinda already
Speaker 8:  working on solving, but we are gonna make them all work better. I think
Speaker 8:  the new part that I am more excited about now than I have
Speaker 8:  ever been is health because of what a big problem health
Speaker 8:  is for the, the world and for people in their lives. you know, obesity
Speaker 8:  and diabetes being the two bigger biggest ones, but there's lots and lots
Speaker 8:  of other ones too, which matter a lot. And I do think there's a, a
Speaker 8:  real role to play and, and it's not, I know it's not strictly in the kitchen
Speaker 8:  and people might think of health as being more of about watches or step
Speaker 8:  counting on your, on your phone, but actually what you eat has a huge
Speaker 8:  impact on your health, right? Especially in those two things, you know, diabetes
Speaker 8:  and people being overweight, So, I think like that opportunity to help people
Speaker 8:  is, is huge. And actually it also drives consumer choice, right? you know,
Speaker 8:  Ben mentions the air fryer. One of the reasons why people like an air
Speaker 8:  fryer is not because it's another thing to put in your kitchen counter, right?
Speaker 8:  And it, and it cooks stuff. It's because it cooks stuff healthily, right?
Speaker 8:  Without oil. So like, it drives behavior. People want to be healthy, like
Speaker 8:  it drives spending. For me, that's exciting because I'm trying to be healthy
Speaker 8:  and I know how hard it is. And I, I've seen how
Speaker 8:  good software experiences can help me be healthy. And I, I, I think there's
Speaker 8:  a lot of, it's a big problem in the world and I think we have a lot that
Speaker 8:  we can contribute to the world.
Speaker 4:  All right. Back in the studio, I really enjoyed that and I had been thinking
Speaker 4:  ever since we did it about the idea of joy
Speaker 4:  in the kitchen being a thing, right? Which kinda goes back to the same stuff
Speaker 4:  we were talking about. It's like what If you could do all the fun parts of
Speaker 4:  cooking and none of the like monotonous
Speaker 4:  nonsense, the like remembering to turn on the oven
Speaker 4:  and how to set timers and yelling at your voice assistant.
Speaker 4:  Like what if just the fun things was what you did in the kitchen?
Speaker 4:  And like, what a great vision that is. I love them.
Speaker 3:  It is, I know it, I, I, as I did point out, it is like, yeah,
Speaker 3:  I love this idea of joy of cooking, but it's
Speaker 3:  not as a mom of two with a full-time job and
Speaker 3:  a lot of extracurricular activities, joy of cooking maybe
Speaker 3:  on a Sunday afternoon, but not on a Monday
Speaker 3:  when I'm like desperately trying to get food on the table. So yeah,
Speaker 3:  I think the joy of cooking is great, but I think ultimately if we can,
Speaker 3:  and, and a lot of what both Ben and Nick said, really, I can
Speaker 3:  see, I'm mean, excited to sort of try and see how using
Speaker 3:  technology to make things streamlined and easier
Speaker 3:  in the kitchen will maybe make Monday evening dinner
Speaker 3:  joyful. Maybe. We'll see, I'm gonna try, I'm gonna test
Speaker 3:  all this out and see, hopefully there won't be too much swearing.
Speaker 3:  Am I allowed to swear on The Vergecast?
Speaker 4:  Oh, I mean this about, about your kids in dinner. Yes, absolutely.
Speaker 4:  That's, those are the rules. I I will say the solution that I have discovered
Speaker 4:  is to have a 14 month old who doesn't want to eat anything that isn't graham
Speaker 4:  crackers
Speaker 3:  Makes it easier to cook. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Well, and, and what I've discovered is most of parenting is just giving your
Speaker 4:  kid healthy food that they don't want to eat. And like, my diet has gotten
Speaker 4:  better because I'm eating all the veggies that I make for him. It's ridiculous.
Speaker 4:  But the thing that I'm struck by, and I'm curious how you feel before we
Speaker 4:  get into this crazy experiment we're about to run on on you, is
Speaker 4:  Ben and Nick are both really sort of optimistic about what the next couple
Speaker 4:  of years are gonna be. And I think of course they are, they're in this space.
Speaker 4:  They've founded companies like they're, they're startup guys, right? Like
Speaker 4:  of course they're optimistic about where this is going, but you've been in
Speaker 4:  the kind of mire and muck of trying to get all of this stuff working
Speaker 4:  for a long time as they talk about AI and as they talk about the platform
Speaker 4:  stuff. Are you optimistic that we're gonna get real
Speaker 4:  moves in, in this space over the next couple of years? Are we gonna start
Speaker 4:  to inch towards the stuff we've been talking about?
Speaker 3:  I think you know me, I'm very optimistic.
Speaker 4:  True.
Speaker 3:  And I do feel like, as we said at the beginning, that, you know, with
Speaker 3:  generative AI and some of the technologies that have, that we're
Speaker 3:  starting to see in the smart home Matter interoperability,
Speaker 3:  I feel optimistic, but I do think there is still a major
Speaker 3:  roadblock, which is that the smart kitchen is not an easy,
Speaker 3:  there's not easy turnover. Hmm. you know, people aren't going to go
Speaker 3:  and buy new, all new appliances. And so these, I still
Speaker 3:  think we're gonna see a lot of these individual appliances like air
Speaker 3:  fryers, we've talked about, everyone loves air fryers, but it's another
Speaker 3:  device and another gadget you go put in your kitchen. I, I feel like that
Speaker 3:  sort of beauty in the beast vision
Speaker 3:  of the, the kitchen where everything just has its purpose and all works
Speaker 3:  together and cleans everyone, everyone cleans themselves and cooks everything
Speaker 3:  for you. you know, I, I feel like we're still a long way off from that, but
Speaker 3:  I was really interested and as you picked up on the idea that really
Speaker 3:  we need to start from the food and not start from the
Speaker 3:  appliances. And I think that's where for individual
Speaker 3:  consumers, the smart kitchen gets much more interesting. I think the
Speaker 3:  larger Appliance side of the issue is something that the
Speaker 3:  manufacturers have to work out and that's gonna take a long time. As
Speaker 3:  much as they're all starting to work together, we all know how well that
Speaker 3:  works out.
Speaker 4:  Agreed. So before we get outta here, you have signed up
Speaker 4:  to Heroically, run a self experiment on yourself
Speaker 4:  for next week's episode. What is this experiment? Tell us what you're in
Speaker 4:  for before we get outta here.
Speaker 3:  So I am going to try to plan
Speaker 3:  my meals for a week for my family, using
Speaker 3:  Smart Kitchen Tech from apps to actual
Speaker 3:  appliances, to voice assistance, smart
Speaker 3:  displays, all the different tech that's in my kitchen, as well as a few pieces
Speaker 3:  that I've called in for the experiment. I'm gonna use Samsung
Speaker 3:  Food and the Fresco app to sort of test a little bit of what Nick and
Speaker 3:  Ben were telling us and see how, how it all works out. And I'm gonna
Speaker 3:  try and cook lots of ex foods that I've never cooked before
Speaker 3:  and see if my smart kitchen can make me a better chef.
Speaker 3:  And yeah, it's gonna be fun. It might get a bit messy.
Speaker 4:  Is your family prepared for what you're about to do to
Speaker 3:  Them? No. Okay,
Speaker 1:  Good.
Speaker 4:  Let's ride for the best. I'll
Speaker 3:  Just spring it on them and Who
Speaker 4:  Knows, maybe it'll go amazing. Maybe
Speaker 3:  There'll be lots of food to eat, so that should make them happy.
Speaker 3:  Cooking is hard though, so I'm probably gonna be quite tired and cranky after
Speaker 3:  all of this.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, we, we've asked you to, to keep a sort of running diary as you're doing
Speaker 4:  this, and I am extremely excited to hear unfiltered, just finished
Speaker 4:  dinner, Jen thoughts on the Smart Kitchen. I'm very, very excited
Speaker 4:  about it. But awesome. Thank you again for doing this. We're gonna be back
Speaker 4:  next Sunday with the Wild Results of Jen's experiment.
Speaker 4:  Until then, that is it for The Vergecast, thanks to Jen and Nick and Ben
Speaker 4:  for being on the show. And thank you as always for listening. This show's
Speaker 4:  Bruce by Andrew Marino, Liam James, and Will Poor Vergecast is a Verge
Speaker 4:  production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. We'll be back on Tuesday
Speaker 4:  and Friday with lots more Vergecast. And then next Sunday with the epic conclusion
Speaker 4:  of our Smart Home series. That's The Vergecast. See you next time. Rock and
Speaker 4:  roll.