# Transcript
ID: c10580b7-1638-4e5e-b8d4-e753b502485d
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/3931055994144455590/7960551584400941355/s93290-US-5753s-1734087880.mp3
Description: Nilay, David, and The Verge's Richard Lawler talk about a big week in AI news. First, they go over all the latest on Google's Gemini 2.0 launch, and try to figure out whether Project Astra and Project Mariner will ever turn into products people use. They also discuss OpenAI's release (and un-release) of Sora, the new Reddit Answers tool, and what's new in iOS 18.2. Finally, in the lightning round, there's talk of YouTube, Instagram, TikTok, Sonos, and Cruise. There also is and isn't talk of quantum computing. Because that's possible now.
Speaker 3:  Hello and welcome to Our Chest, the flagship podcast of the Agentic era.
Speaker 3:  That's where you just sent us requests and David has to do that,
Speaker 4:  But we say it's AI
Speaker 3:  Like every other AI company. I want to be clear that is how they all work.
Speaker 3:  Tesla's robotaxis, fleet of human operators waiting in just a guy, the background
Speaker 3:  guy. Yeah, to pounce. It's just how it works. There's a lot going on this
Speaker 3:  week. I'm your friend Neli. David Pierce is here. Hello. Waiting to take
Speaker 3:  your commands. David, memorize this list of names
Speaker 3:  and then make new names.
Speaker 4:  What I want to talk about, which is just your bad websites made
Speaker 4:  AI necessary. Yeah. This is what I've come to.
Speaker 3:  Richard Lawler is here.
Speaker 5:  I love ai. I'm a big AI guy now I've moved on from crypto.
Speaker 5:  It's all about AI now.
Speaker 3:  Richard
Speaker 4:  Big AI guy. That's what everybody says in ai.
Speaker 3:  I'm saying Richard, you have not had AI change that car behind you
Speaker 3:  from Mercedes to Ferrari, yet
Speaker 5:  There is no Mercedes, there is only Ferrari and but therefore
Speaker 5:  it is a Ferrari already.
Speaker 3:  That's a be wherever Hamilton goes, that's a Ferrari.
Speaker 3:  That is also in many ways how AI is being defined. Whatever this computer
Speaker 3:  does is ai. They should get, they should get Lewis
Speaker 3:  Hamilton to be this. You know what he is.
Speaker 5:  I love just remembering three commands to be able to tell my computer to
Speaker 5:  do one simple thing. It's just the best way to use it.
Speaker 3:  You know? Wait, there is a lot of like dumb crypto money in F1. Is there
Speaker 3:  a lot of dumb AI money in F1 yet?
Speaker 5:  Not yet. They've been kind of late on that. I don't know what's going on.
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 4:  True.
Speaker 3:  Well, the new season, it, A new season is coming, a new sponsorship opportunity
Speaker 3:  is await. I will say that Chrome sponsoring the McLaren and then
Speaker 3:  making the cart literally Chrome genius.
Speaker 4:  It's very good in terms of like just pure
Speaker 4:  actual like branding of the thing inside of the actual product, like
Speaker 4:  crushed it and McLaren, yes,
Speaker 5:  Chrome wheels are a great idea, especially when they're not Chrome, but they
Speaker 5:  look like Google Chrome. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  No, but they added actual Chrome to the car that was this year's vague innovation.
Speaker 3:  They, they put literal chrome on the car, which is not what you think about
Speaker 3:  when you think of the F1 car. Like what if this looked like a 1950s cab?
Speaker 3:  It's very good. That's all I'm saying. Alright. There's a lot of news, actual
Speaker 3:  AI news this week, not just Chrome in all senses of
Speaker 3:  the word. And a lot of it is Google and David, you wrote a,
Speaker 3:  a bunch of these little bits and Bobs Gemini 2.0 is out.
Speaker 3:  Google is making some mixed reality noises.
Speaker 3:  There's an Android mixed reality thing yet again. What?
Speaker 3:  Be honest about that. They've, they've tried this before. They're back again.
Speaker 3:  There's a new jus AI for code. What's, what's all going on here, David?
Speaker 4:  Okay, so let's, let's break all that into three pieces
Speaker 4:  and we, we should talk about all of them. And I, I think the three pieces
Speaker 4:  are Gemini 2.0, there's Astra and
Speaker 4:  Mariner, which are kind of like overlapping with Gemini 2.0 but are, are
Speaker 4:  like products and they're interesting and we should talk about them and then
Speaker 4:  we should talk about the XR stuff at the end. It's called Android XR.
Speaker 4:  I have many thoughts about the decision to use xr, but we, we should
Speaker 4:  talk about this, but let's, let's start with Gemini. So the, the big news
Speaker 4:  of this week was Google is starting to roll out Gemini 2.0, which
Speaker 4:  is the successor to 1.5, which I think it first launched
Speaker 4:  in February. So like nine months of
Speaker 4:  development later. This is the new thing. And what
Speaker 4:  de ve told me, who he runs Deep Mind at Google
Speaker 4:  and is in charge of all their AI stuff. And by the way, I talked to him earlier
Speaker 4:  this week while he was in Sweden accepting a Nobel Prize.
Speaker 4:  He like called me from his hotel room before the Nobel Gala,
Speaker 4:  which is like the worst power dynamic of an interview I've ever had
Speaker 4:  in my entire life.
Speaker 4:  It was really something, it's like, I don't know how to tell you you're wrong
Speaker 4:  on any of this because you're literally, you're going to get a Nobel Prize
Speaker 4:  tonight. But anyway, what he told me is that basically
Speaker 4:  what Gemini 2.0 flash is, is
Speaker 4:  roughly performance equivalent to what Gemini 1.5 Pro
Speaker 4:  is. Sure. So the way to think about it is he it's, it's like a full step
Speaker 4:  up in terms of like efficiency and speed and latency, which is
Speaker 4:  stuff that really, really matters with still the same amount of
Speaker 4:  performance as the pro level tier from last time.
Speaker 3:  Well, I mean just to unpack some Google product names here. Flashes the
Speaker 3:  little model that's supposed to run on phones. That's
Speaker 4:  Right. So they they call it the workhorse model. Okay. It's the one most
Speaker 4:  people encounter most of the time basically.
Speaker 3:  Got it. But so that's not the phones one. That's just the sort of like, here's
Speaker 3:  the one you get Flash.
Speaker 4:  There's one below Flash that I can't remember the name of, but it is, it
Speaker 4:  is like, it's the, it's the main one. Like when you use Gemini
Speaker 4:  now you're using 1.5 flash almost certainly. Okay.
Speaker 3:  But Nano is the one on the phone. Nano is on N is the one on the phone. Okay.
Speaker 3:  I just wanna be Google product names also. I just wanna point out they named
Speaker 3:  it Flash. Yeah. Like in the history of technology names to Reanimate,
Speaker 3:  they picked Flash. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's always cool. You didn't like
Speaker 3:  New grounds.
Speaker 3:  Look, Homestar runner was great, right? And if these, if these AI systems
Speaker 3:  can deliver me Homestar runner, that would be amazing
Speaker 4:  If Google made Homestar runner the official mascot of all of its AI
Speaker 4:  and like that was the voice and personality I was talking to, I would be
Speaker 4:  all in on ai honestly. Like done lock it down, get these
Speaker 3:  Woke eyes outta here, put strong that in. Let's make this happen. All right,
Speaker 3:  keep going. Exactly.
Speaker 4:  But so, so yeah, so it's, it's kind of a, a magnitude leap in power for
Speaker 4:  them. It's also like natively doing a bunch of things that
Speaker 4:  were separate in products before. So Gemini 2.0 can now do
Speaker 4:  images natively, which used to be a thing Google did with a separate model.
Speaker 4:  It can do audio natively, which is a thing it was doing in a separate model.
Speaker 4:  So there's just a lot of this like multimodal stuff coming
Speaker 4:  into Gemini, which is a big deal for Google in a bunch of ways.
Speaker 4:  But the main thing is like this is going to be the model that Google
Speaker 4:  tries to put everywhere. It's the one that they're gonna try to sell to cloud
Speaker 4:  customers who wanna do all this kind of stuff. It's the one they're gonna
Speaker 4:  put into AI overviews and search. It's the one they're gonna put into Gmail.
Speaker 4:  It's the one that's gonna be in Gemini. Like increasingly Google
Speaker 4:  is trying to do kind of the opposite of what open AI is doing. Open AI is
Speaker 4:  like we have a bunch of models for a bunch of different things and you can
Speaker 4:  use them all and they all kind of interoperate, but it is like different
Speaker 4:  models for different needs and Google is just like Gemini
Speaker 4:  and that is very much like how this company wants to approach ai.
Speaker 4:  And I get the real sense they see this as a big turn
Speaker 4:  in that direction.
Speaker 3:  Wait, lemme ask just a foundational question here. Yeah. There's a
Speaker 3:  big conversation in the AI industry about scaling laws and whether training
Speaker 3:  the next model will result in more capability. You
Speaker 3:  wrote very disparagingly about OpenAI trying to redefine a GI down.
Speaker 3:  I think you actually said we should just make fun of Sam Alman on this show
Speaker 3:  a couple weeks ago.
Speaker 4:  I did. I still believe that. Right.
Speaker 3:  So we're trying to drag the word a GI down to the ground and just be
Speaker 3:  like, anything this F1 car is a GI.
Speaker 3:  Sure. Then there's Google and it's their newest
Speaker 3:  model is the same capability but more efficient,
Speaker 3:  which seems important, but is kind of lost in the a GI
Speaker 3:  conversation. 'cause all of that is like, can we make a GI
Speaker 3:  out of a bunch of Nvidia chips that we have today?
Speaker 3:  If we throw more data at them, will they get smarter? And Google's like,
Speaker 3:  it's the same smart but more efficient.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So I, I actually talked a bunch about this with Des and I'm very glad
Speaker 4:  you brought this up because I've been thinking a lot about this in the context
Speaker 4:  of these announcements. And I think Google's stance seems to be
Speaker 4:  that there is more headroom to be had he, he kind of
Speaker 4:  allowed that it's slowing down that the idea of this stuff, just
Speaker 4:  like linearly getting better with every new model is probably not
Speaker 4:  true. But he did say he's like, there are still performance gains to be had.
Speaker 4:  There's new stuff we can learn how to do. And he also said that actually
Speaker 4:  what we need is, is the new technique. We don't need
Speaker 4:  more, we need new is kind of what he kept saying that like the, the way that
Speaker 4:  Transformers change the way we think about this stuff, like we need another
Speaker 4:  one of those if we're gonna unlock like the real next step change in ai.
Speaker 4:  And he seems to think those are out there and exist and they're working on
Speaker 4:  them and he has some theories he didn't want to tell me about them, but like
Speaker 4:  there is room upwards, but it is not just bigger
Speaker 4:  models. What's next? And I think what we're seeing right now, both with
Speaker 4:  what Google is doing and with what OpenAI is doing with this 12 days of
Speaker 4:  shipments thing, is everybody is trying to figure out now how to make these
Speaker 4:  things products. Like how do I get these things in front of
Speaker 4:  you in a way that is useful and valuable and worth paying
Speaker 4:  for, or at least using and in some like very meaningful way
Speaker 4:  pays off as a business for these companies that are just pouring money
Speaker 4:  down the toilet making these things work. So
Speaker 4:  for Google, one thing I liked about the way demos is framing it is
Speaker 4:  like Google works on all this stuff at sort of a technological
Speaker 4:  infrastructural level and then Google
Speaker 4:  is Google's biggest customer, right? So there's like, he was like, we we
Speaker 4:  think of this as, and this is like you're, you're making a face. This is
Speaker 4:  what everybody says about their stuff. Yeah. If
Speaker 3:  You're listening to this in your car just to match me rolling my eyes so
Speaker 3:  hard, your car crashed.
Speaker 4:  Everyone ever on decoder has said that about their companies. But like it's
Speaker 4:  true in a lot of cases, and I think it's true in this case too, that like
Speaker 4:  what Google needs is for
Speaker 4:  Gemini and Gmail to not run Google out of business because it's so
Speaker 4:  expensive to operate. Right? Right. And so, so the idea of making this stuff
Speaker 4:  faster and more efficient and lower latency becomes
Speaker 4:  really meaningful. Not only because Google is in this like incredible arms
Speaker 4:  race with every other cloud company to offer AI services and
Speaker 4:  this stuff is being really quickly commoditized. So being able to say we
Speaker 4:  are the cheapest and the fastest is becoming very powerful very quickly,
Speaker 4:  but also like it matters to Google's own
Speaker 4:  products in a pretty big way. So like he kept getting really excited about
Speaker 4:  efficiency and I realized he is like, oh no, like you're, you're serious.
Speaker 4:  Like this stuff, this means you can build this into products in a
Speaker 4:  way that is like, that works at scale without just
Speaker 4:  absolutely hemorrhaging cash the whole way.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But I mean we should talk about those products and and we will, but
Speaker 3:  I just, I just wanna say this very clearly and I'm the person who interviews
Speaker 3:  all the CEOs about their costs. I don't care. Right? Like
Speaker 3:  we made it cheaper to hallucinate is like a, I mean, honestly
Speaker 3:  there was a time in my life where that would've been a very compelling pitch,
Speaker 3:  but like, they're not better. Right? They're just cheaper to
Speaker 3:  run. And I, I I feel like I'm just stuck there. Like that's a big deal. I
Speaker 3:  I'm not discounting, it's a, it's not a big deal to put the thing more places
Speaker 3:  and see what kind of product you can build. And maybe all anybody wants is
Speaker 3:  to hallucinate some emails like great, but they're not more capable
Speaker 3:  yet. Like the big innovation here is that it, it got cheaper.
Speaker 5:  If Google wants to save some money on ai, they could just turn off the AI
Speaker 5:  overviews on my search results. Like I don't know how many pennies that would,
Speaker 5:  that would save them, but it's gotta be at least 5 cents considering the
Speaker 5:  amount of services I do.
Speaker 4:  It was really funny, Google, I think it was soon, wrote a blog post with
Speaker 4:  all these announcements that was like, you know, there are now more than
Speaker 4:  a billion people are experiencing AI overviews. And I was like, that's such
Speaker 4:  a different way of putting it than more than a billion people really are
Speaker 4:  excited to use AI
Speaker 3:  Overviews. We have foisted this upon a billion. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Exactly. It's like this is, this is one of the fastest growing search enhancements
Speaker 4:  ever. And I just kept thinking about U YouTube being like, this is our most
Speaker 4:  successful album ever because we shoved it onto everyone's iPhones. It's
Speaker 4:  like, I don't know that that's the flex you think it is guys.
Speaker 3:  Well so we should talk about the product. I just, that's the thing that really
Speaker 3:  leapt out to me is we have very quickly moved on from
Speaker 3:  talking about the models getting more capable and like we're worried that
Speaker 3:  these are gonna be super intelligence level extinction events for us
Speaker 3:  to maybe Sam Altman will just say it's a GI 'cause he wants to,
Speaker 3:  'cause that'll get him out of a Microsoft contract or something will happen
Speaker 3:  and it'll boost his stock price. And when they go public to we've made
Speaker 3:  it cheaper, we can put it more products and hopefully we can all start making
Speaker 3:  some money and that that's fine. Like
Speaker 3:  great, like very cool. The products still aren't there, they're not very
Speaker 3:  compelling yet. Maybe some, someone just has to figure it out
Speaker 3:  and then it, it just feels like I keep making the comparison to
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth. It's like they keep telling me Bluetooth is awesome. And I'm like,
Speaker 3:  but these headphones are bad. And we we're just stuck in that loop. So tell
Speaker 3:  me, I guess, tell me about the headphones. Are the headphones any good?
Speaker 4:  Well, okay, let me describe the headphones to you. Okay. Google launched
Speaker 4:  four new pairs of headphones.
Speaker 4:  One is Project Astra, which we've seen before. We've talked about
Speaker 4:  it a bunch on the show. It's, it's basically like the most sort of
Speaker 4:  all encompassing, ambitious version of Google's
Speaker 4:  AI idea. It's visual, it's listening, it has memory. It's,
Speaker 4:  it's the thing you like walk around your house with and then you're like,
Speaker 4:  where did I leave my glasses? And it tells you because the camera saw your
Speaker 4:  glasses. Like that's the idea. They're able to do some new stuff
Speaker 4:  on there. It's also now connected to things like Google Maps, which is cool.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So there's like, they're starting to be able to plug some of these
Speaker 4:  things in and that's where like again, having Gemini underneath all of this
Speaker 4:  stuff makes that doable in a way that's been much harder in the past.
Speaker 4:  So that's one thing. Number two is what's called Project Mariner.
Speaker 4:  And this is, it's a Chrome extension. Google calls it an experiment. They
Speaker 4:  have a million different terms that all mean some version of prototype.
Speaker 4:  We can
Speaker 3:  Kill this without you yelling at us,
Speaker 4:  Right? This is like the most prototype you prototype, but it is like
Speaker 4:  an agent in the way that we've been talking about agents for a while in that
Speaker 4:  it can like go and browse the web and do things for you.
Speaker 4:  Kylie Robinson and our team got some demos of this and her take
Speaker 4:  was basically, it works, it's really slow,
Speaker 4:  it's kind of wonky. I'm not sure this is meaningfully better than me just
Speaker 4:  like looking at some web pages myself. But one of the demos they give is
Speaker 4:  like, look at these webpage and find the contact emails for me and it will
Speaker 4:  actually go and literally click around the pages and try to find the
Speaker 4:  email for you. Can,
Speaker 5:  Can we talk about that one for a second? That was the one I was talking about
Speaker 5:  right at the beginning. Yeah, the request and, and you've gotta see the,
Speaker 5:  the video and we put a screenshot of it on the site, but the request is,
Speaker 5:  is absurd to me. It just starts off with memorize this list. What does
Speaker 5:  memorize mean to a bot? Like if I gave you a list, I assume that
Speaker 5:  you remember it now If you are a computer because that's what you do.
Speaker 3:  No, no, no, these computers are on drugs, Richard.
Speaker 5:  And now I have to tell the computer to memorize and then somewhere else in,
Speaker 5:  in the command it also said, remember again, so now I have to remind you
Speaker 5:  to remember this thing to go do a thing. And then in the context box it
Speaker 5:  tells you the results are unreliable, like right below it. So I'm telling
Speaker 5:  an unreliable party instructions that it can't follow. If I was
Speaker 5:  gonna have someone screw up a task, I would just do it myself. Like, like
Speaker 5:  what is AI doing from you? But
Speaker 3:  No, this lets you screw up higher value tasks,
Speaker 5:  Right? Oh, it
Speaker 3:  This fails to get a bunch of email addresses while you like, you know, crash
Speaker 3:  a bike like you're doing something
Speaker 4:  Else. There was a good one on there too in the, in the Project Astra
Speaker 4:  demo video. It, it starts and ends with a guy
Speaker 4:  trying to get into an apartment building and the first thing he does is he's
Speaker 4:  like, look in my email and find the, the code to this
Speaker 4:  front door and then remember it. And it's like I had the same reaction. It's
Speaker 4:  like, first of all, it's just in my email. Like it can just look in my email
Speaker 4:  every time who is remembering anything. And then at the end he's like, what
Speaker 4:  was that code? And it's like the code you asked me to remember and it's like,
Speaker 4:  no, it's still just the code in my email. Like what are we accomplishing?
Speaker 4:  You just, just look at the email again If you want to. It's fine. Like,
Speaker 5:  Now I have to remember the conversation I'm having with the computer about
Speaker 5:  the thing I'm trying to do.
Speaker 4:  Right? I have to tell you what I've told you so that you
Speaker 4:  can tell it to me again. And it's just like, what is, what is just, just
Speaker 4:  tell me the code. Just what is the code?
Speaker 5:  We, we fixed this, you let me pin notes on my phone screen and
Speaker 5:  then I had the code.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, there's, there's a lot of weird UI around this
Speaker 4:  stuff. And the question of like, what is this actually accomplishing that
Speaker 4:  is AI and is new,
Speaker 4:  hard to say. Again, I I like, I can't stop talking
Speaker 4:  about the fact that hacking your way into like pretending to use
Speaker 4:  a web browser on my behalf is not impressive and not interesting.
Speaker 4:  Like do other things. Well, so
Speaker 3:  Let's split these two up. Astro's interesting, right? Because we're
Speaker 3:  the same day that Google announced all this stuff. Apple announced iOS 18.2
Speaker 3:  released iOS 18.2 with Visual Intelligence. Yeah. And the, Hey look
Speaker 3:  at something and tell me about it. We, that's the world we live in now. This
Speaker 3:  is the new great AI feature which, you know, other companies have had,
Speaker 3:  but now it's built right into the iPhone and then Google is talking about
Speaker 3:  Astro with it. It seems like Astro is very much the future of Google lens,
Speaker 3:  right? You're just like, yes, looking at stuff, it's talking to you about
Speaker 3:  it, you're having a great time. But it is very much like I looked
Speaker 3:  at a picture, I scanned all the texts in the picture or I did some visual
Speaker 3:  recognition of what I'm looking at and here's some information you can have
Speaker 3:  a conversation with me about it that to whatever extent that is
Speaker 3:  super useful for people. I get it. I think there's
Speaker 3:  still just what I keep calling the US capital problem. Like
Speaker 3:  you ask Apple Visual Intelligence what happened at the Capitol building on
Speaker 3:  January 6th, like that answer is pretty dicey. Yeah. Right. And like there's
Speaker 3:  a, a universe of actors who would love to change what that answer is across
Speaker 3:  the political spectrum. And none of these companies have contended with it.
Speaker 3:  Astro's got the same problem, you know, everyone else has the same problem,
Speaker 3:  but they're headed that way. Well, and Google Lens has been headed that way
Speaker 3:  for a
Speaker 4:  Long time. Wait, do you think it's like a real mainstream use case that a
Speaker 4:  lot of people are gonna walk by the capitol and be like, what happened here
Speaker 4:  on January?
Speaker 3:  So I think it's a real mainstream use case that you're gonna be wearing a
Speaker 3:  pair of glasses in the future that purports to augment reality and everyone
Speaker 3:  lives in a weird custom political reality. Yeah, sure. Whether or not you're
Speaker 3:  looking at the Capitol or not,
Speaker 4:  Granted,
Speaker 3:  Right. I mean, and I'm not gonna go to it 'cause it's super dicey and
Speaker 3:  loaded and we should probably just do an entire episode on someday. But you
Speaker 3:  can just think of the infinite questions that come about when you look at
Speaker 3:  something that are ultra loaded and that someone will start a culture war
Speaker 3:  over, right? Yeah. Just e every in your house you can just look at stuff
Speaker 3:  and be like, you know, like, are the cowboys good? And
Speaker 3:  like there's just like a lot of questions underneath that that are like really
Speaker 3:  hard. Like, Hey is that Aaron Rogers? Tell me about his ideas. Like
Speaker 3:  If you just go for it, like just normal everyday things.
Speaker 3:  And that to me is, it's great that we're building technology for it and Astros
Speaker 3:  is very much the future of Google Lens, but there's this whole universe of
Speaker 3:  those problems that come with, I'm looking at stuff. Tell me about it.
Speaker 3:  Who will augment reality is like a great question.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think it's, I think there, there are sort of two separate
Speaker 4:  pieces of this kind of thing and I'm, I'm really bullish on one
Speaker 4:  and kind of bearish on the other. And I think the like how to
Speaker 4:  logistically get through your day thing. I think things like Astro are going
Speaker 4:  to be really useful for, right? Like there's a, there's a moment
Speaker 4:  in the demo video they just released where the guy holds up his phone and
Speaker 4:  he points it as at a bus that's just going by and he's like, well this bus
Speaker 4:  kept me to Chinatown. There are a lot of like complicated problems to solve
Speaker 4:  technologically there. But that's a really interesting UI problem
Speaker 4:  because that's a hard question to answer and if the AI assistant
Speaker 4:  can answer it, that's very cool. And the like stuff around
Speaker 4:  me and how I get places and like just like how to do your day,
Speaker 4:  this kind of thing can be really useful for it if it works.
Speaker 3:  Wait, but but I mean, can I just hold on the bus example? Sure. For one second.
Speaker 3:  One, ideally the will this bus get to me to where I'm going is not a culture
Speaker 3:  war problem, right? It's a question with an answer like, will this go there?
Speaker 3:  And it's an answer that Google already has in a million structured
Speaker 3:  databases with deterministic systems running them. Sure. So you can
Speaker 3:  just ask Google Maps this, Google has all kinds of public
Speaker 3:  transit infrastructure projects that have put sensors on buses and there's
Speaker 3:  open systems and you can build products and all that. And they've just built
Speaker 3:  that stuff to enable maps a decade ago. And so now you've got a
Speaker 3:  conversational layer that is a new interface for that where you're just like,
Speaker 3:  look at this, I'm asking about it, figure out what that is. And then it
Speaker 3:  parses that into a structured query for its existing Google Map systems
Speaker 3:  and delivers you the answer international language way. And so really what
Speaker 3:  you've just built a new interface for the existing good system that works.
Speaker 3:  And I think that's very power. I I
Speaker 4:  I all the good AI stuff is exactly that,
Speaker 3:  Right? And I just, that's like one, and when people talk about it, it's being
Speaker 3:  a platform shift. Like that's the one I see. Like we made a click wheel and
Speaker 3:  now we have iPods, we made Multitouch and now we have smartphones, we made
Speaker 3:  natural language UI that is pretty good and now we're gonna get a bunch of
Speaker 3:  other stuff and we made a UI that can listen
Speaker 3:  to a song and tell you about it. Yeah. Right. There's, there's like a lot
Speaker 3:  of that stuff that I think is cool. It's the next turn where
Speaker 3:  it's like, because it's a conversational natural language ui,
Speaker 3:  you expect to have conversations with you and like be a useful companion.
Speaker 3:  And that's where it just always seems to fall down. Yes. Because the systems
Speaker 3:  aren't actually intelligent and that, like that's to me is like, it,
Speaker 3:  it, we keep sliding from one to the other. Like, here's a
Speaker 3:  kick ass way to use Google Maps into this is your best friend that will,
Speaker 3:  you know, If you ask it nicely we'll try to have sex with you. You're just
Speaker 3:  like, well that's a pretty, that's a pretty long road actually.
Speaker 4:  Right? We assume because one thus inevitably the
Speaker 4:  other. Yeah. And I think, I think everyone needs to stop doing that. And
Speaker 4:  I think one thing that Apple is doing right to its credit is like,
Speaker 4:  it is, it is stuck on the idea that these are like features that
Speaker 4:  should be useful and not best friend companions
Speaker 4:  that you have. And I, I think like for the
Speaker 4:  foreseeable future that is, you should a pick one of the
Speaker 4:  two and not try to do both. And I think the one you should pick is like,
Speaker 4:  try to be helpful because we just keep seeing stories about
Speaker 4:  the friends being weird and problematic.
Speaker 3:  You just ran one of those stories from Josh like a long feature.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like it's, it's a mess and it's, that stuff is real. But
Speaker 4:  like, but in this case, like again, I think like
Speaker 4:  down every road lies a culture war. I I agree. Right? Like If you, If you,
Speaker 4:  If you follow it long enough, there's a culture war there somewhere. But
Speaker 4:  like there are things along the way that work and are
Speaker 4:  useful. And I think Google is starting to poke at some of that stuff in pretty
Speaker 3:  Interesting. But I, but I'm like, the culture war is like, not even, I'm
Speaker 3:  not even saying it's like politically dicey. I'm saying you're somewhere
Speaker 3:  and you're listening to that new choral version of like a prayer by Madonna
Speaker 3:  and you're like, is this song appropriate for church? And some people think
Speaker 3:  the answer is yes because they're performing it in churches in
Speaker 3:  America today. And it's like, well you just gotta, you gotta just,
Speaker 3:  the robots gotta unpack that box for you, right? Like, and I, I don't think
Speaker 3:  these companies are ready for that, which is what will truly make them useful
Speaker 3:  is by giving you an answer you might not like. And I, they're super not ready
Speaker 3:  for that in the, in the current political climate. And that's like, that's
Speaker 3:  when you make the turn. Like that's when it actually becomes a useful assistant
Speaker 3:  to you go find me misinformation. Even if I don't like it as
Speaker 5:  A slightly lower stakes version of that question. One of the demos I'm saying
Speaker 3:  Is like a prayer song about doing it is like not a high stakes problem.
Speaker 5:  It depends on where you are.
Speaker 3:  I suppose
Speaker 5:  One of the examples that they showed with Project Mariner was someone pulling
Speaker 5:  up a recipe in Google Docs and saying, add the veggies from this res recipe
Speaker 5:  to my Safeway cart. What if one of those things is a fruit and I
Speaker 5:  forgot that it was a fruit, not a vegetable, or I just disagree. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Now that's a high stakes. Yeah. Add these sandwiches to my cart. One of
Speaker 3:  'em is a hotdog and the thing just like a data center explodes somewhere
Speaker 3:  in America
Speaker 5:  This is is something that, that will happen to someone. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  All right. So that's, I just wanna like call that out like the, there's the
Speaker 3:  thing we want them to do, which is not just a
Speaker 3:  technology problem, like a straight up culture problem, like a society level
Speaker 3:  problem. And then there's like the really interesting part, which is build
Speaker 3:  a better interface for systems that already work. And then there's this weird
Speaker 3:  middle ground, which I think Mariner is, which you know, copilot is at Microsoft,
Speaker 3:  all these age agentic systems, which is what if we just use
Speaker 3:  the internet for you? And that's how we solve the problem of we
Speaker 3:  need something in the middle that works. Right. And David, I think this is
Speaker 3:  where you're getting to like what a stunning indictment of web design because
Speaker 3:  you're like, well the internet's pretty broken, so it would be better if
Speaker 3:  some unreliable ho robot used it for me. Right.
Speaker 4:  The the assumption is that you can't find anything, which is a very
Speaker 4:  funny thing for the company that made Google search to say. But yeah, we're,
Speaker 4:  we're at a moment where it is perceived to be easier
Speaker 4:  to ask this thing to go find a contact
Speaker 4:  email address than it is to just go find the contact email address. And
Speaker 4:  again, like I think a, a place we are landing
Speaker 4:  that is very funny is that all these companies are slowly
Speaker 4:  discovering that the most useful thing their tools do
Speaker 4:  are really boring and really like back of house accounting firm kind of
Speaker 4:  stuff. And that turns out to not be very
Speaker 4:  interesting to like a mainstream public that you need to get excited
Speaker 4:  about using your products. So they're stuck in this place of all these companies
Speaker 4:  are actually playing like a thoroughly B2B game and just
Speaker 4:  pretending that they're making like huge
Speaker 4:  strides toward mainstream consumer products.
Speaker 4:  That's all fine and good. And I think like Neil, I think you're really like,
Speaker 4:  you're right to be hung up on the fact that these things get some things
Speaker 4:  wrong, but also like people use 'em anyway. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like it, it like the, this thing will write my email for me
Speaker 4:  and it will make two weird mistakes, but then I can fix them and send it
Speaker 4:  and that's better than having to write the email from scratch
Speaker 3:  Or not fix them. Yeah. As we are learning every single day, the answer is
Speaker 3:  not fix them. Yeah. The answer to some extent is read them out loud on cable
Speaker 3:  news.
Speaker 4:  The answer is Hunter debuts will, will, will save us.
Speaker 4:  But yeah. And like
Speaker 4:  the Hunter deButts will like go down in history as like
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 3:  Refuse to explain and it's there you can look it up.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Ironically, If you Google Hunter deButts you'll get correct information
Speaker 4:  about what we're talking about. But, but anyway,
Speaker 4:  I just think we're, we're at a moment now where the question for all of this
Speaker 4:  AI stuff, just to bring it all the way back around is what is any of this
Speaker 4:  actually useful for? And I think the truth is the
Speaker 4:  models that we have now are better
Speaker 4:  than we need for a lot of things and vastly
Speaker 4:  like a million miles away from being good enough for what everybody keeps
Speaker 4:  talking about. Right? So now the question is, okay, we're not
Speaker 4:  gonna build the perfect thing for a long time, if ever, what can we do with
Speaker 4:  what we have now? And that's where things like efficiency come in because
Speaker 4:  at some point, like running a business costs money and you have to be able
Speaker 4:  to do these things and If you can make them cheaper, more people can use
Speaker 4:  them and find new things to do and like on and on and on. But the, the
Speaker 4:  question is like, okay, If you just take the technology we have right now
Speaker 4:  and you don't pretend it's God, what is it good for? And that is
Speaker 4:  like, that is the question Google is starting to try to answer. It's the
Speaker 4:  question OpenAI is starting to try to answer that is like the question of
Speaker 4:  2025 is like, what is any of this actually useful for? Because there are
Speaker 4:  answers, they're just not as, like, they're not God and
Speaker 4:  they're not fire and they're not the industrial revolution. So what are they?
Speaker 3:  It's like a tour guide and an extremely unreliable personal assistant,
Speaker 4:  Which to be fair is not nothing. Yeah. It's not nothing.
Speaker 3:  And I, I can see why they're compelling and I can see why. I mean, just the
Speaker 3:  demo, I mean Richard, you already brought it up like the Google demo of Mariner
Speaker 3:  where you're just like looking at a recipe in Google Docs and you just
Speaker 3:  ask it to go build you a shopping cart on a grocery site and it's just like,
Speaker 3:  does it for you neat. Like legitimately neat,
Speaker 3:  very slow, so slow that the Google PM
Speaker 3:  literally saw Kylie noticing how slow it was and said that's the elephant
Speaker 3:  in the room, that it's ponderously slow. Right?
Speaker 3:  But like, they know, they, they know it, they're not not hiding from it.
Speaker 3:  It's a research demo, but like I am, I'm stuck at
Speaker 3:  the systems are not themselves capable. So they are free riding on
Speaker 3:  other systems that can do the thing. The grocery site has
Speaker 3:  to exist and work and it needs to have a database of all the food
Speaker 3:  in the grocery store. And then you need to be able to put it in a cart and
Speaker 3:  like it, like all that has to work and be profitable
Speaker 3:  and sustainable. And then on top of it you're just like, and then this robot
Speaker 3:  will cost $20 a month and like do it for you. And eventually you're just
Speaker 3:  like, what if, what if this undercuts all of that? I keep
Speaker 3:  calling this a DoorDash problem where DoorDash has to
Speaker 3:  exist for a bunch of these services to get you a sandwich. And
Speaker 3:  If you just sort of delete door dash's business by cutting them out of the
Speaker 3:  equation and taking you the customer away from DoorDash, like
Speaker 3:  how is anyone gonna get a sandwich? Like you need this big
Speaker 3:  traditional deterministic logical computer
Speaker 3:  with a database that is reliable doing a bunch of work. So
Speaker 3:  your natural language interface can be useful. And I don't think anybody
Speaker 3:  has solved the problem of like, how do you keep DoorDash in business, including
Speaker 4:  DoorDash
Speaker 3:  And I'm not just speaking in DoorDash, whatever Uber, right? Like rabbits,
Speaker 3:  just like we're gonna click around Uber's website. All of these middle companies,
Speaker 3:  these like web two oh companies that digitize the interfaces for very
Speaker 3:  physical things. Like they're pretty, they were pretty
Speaker 3:  vulture in their times, right? Like Uber is the biggest taxi company in the
Speaker 3:  world, doesn't own a single taxi, Airbnb doesn't own a single hotel. Like
Speaker 3:  that's the joke about those businesses. And now they're under pressure
Speaker 3:  from AI systems that might use their interfaces
Speaker 3:  and never show them to a user. Right? And it's like where this has to
Speaker 3:  go somewhere that is actually useful for people. Well
Speaker 4:  It, it's a weird thing because you have all of the AI companies
Speaker 4:  would agree with you, but they see that as a strength and not a weakness.
Speaker 4:  Right? Where what they're saying is, okay, we are going to have an army of
Speaker 4:  service providers who just invisibly do the job on your behalf and you
Speaker 4:  don't have to worry about who they are. You don't have to go to the DoorDash
Speaker 4:  website every time you wanna order McDonald's, you just order
Speaker 4:  McDonald's and we'll get it done for you. And DoorDash or whoever will be
Speaker 4:  our provider of choice to do that. They would call that a victory, right?
Speaker 4:  Because I, as a consumer, I don't, I shouldn't have to interact at DoorDash
Speaker 4:  to get McDonald's. I shouldn't interact with McDonald's. But what what they've
Speaker 4:  actually done is a insert another step and B completely commoditize all of
Speaker 4:  these providers in such a way that they will eventually just
Speaker 4:  crash them all in an incredible race to the bottom to be one of these providers.
Speaker 4:  And so it's, it's like when all the carriers got really nervous
Speaker 4:  about being dumb pipes and so they bought content businesses, it's like
Speaker 4:  there there is a, there is another turn of that coming where
Speaker 4:  Uber is going to be terrified of being abstracted away by all of these AI
Speaker 4:  companies. And so it's going to do more to try and get you to use Uber and
Speaker 4:  it's just gonna get really weird as a result.
Speaker 3:  Or it's gonna just raise the price or
Speaker 4:  It's gonna raise the price. Yeah. Or
Speaker 3:  It'll raise the price for the AI systems. So an Uber
Speaker 3:  costs more If you book it through AI than If you book it yourself in the
Speaker 3:  app and look at an ad for Uber.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's just the next generation version of the app store tax
Speaker 3:  And you're we're, I think we're just gonna see a bunch of this stuff play
Speaker 3:  out. And every time everyone talks to me about these agents, and Google in
Speaker 3:  particular isn't a very privileged position because they run Chrome
Speaker 3:  and they run search and like one of their, their deep research preview that
Speaker 3:  they released in the same set of releases where it's like,
Speaker 3:  go research a topic for me and it comes with a research plan and then it
Speaker 3:  goes, searches the web for interesting results and then
Speaker 3:  delivers that research back to you. That's just perplexity, right?
Speaker 3:  It's just perplexity by another name and perplexity is in a bunch of trouble
Speaker 3:  'cause it's not paying any of the sources it's using Yep. To scour the web
Speaker 3:  in that way. And it's like at some point all of the people who make websites,
Speaker 3:  us included. And I feel like disclosure, the company has some sort of
Speaker 3:  meandering deal with open AI that hasn't really resulted in it as far as
Speaker 3:  I can tell. But like there it is.
Speaker 3:  Like all of these companies are gonna say, well we make the information,
Speaker 3:  we make the interface to book a taxi or whatever it is.
Speaker 3:  You, you have to pay us. 'cause If you just take the customers away
Speaker 3:  from us, we will go away and the bots will useless. And I think that just
Speaker 3:  that economic reality will result in some payments whether or not the,
Speaker 3:  you know, the lawsuits or whatever results in payments are blocking robots
Speaker 3:  at TXT. But it's come, it's, it has to be coming.
Speaker 3:  And I think the, I think it's gonna like follow the same pattern
Speaker 3:  everything else follows. Like Uber will be exclusive to copilot and DoorDash
Speaker 3:  will be exclusive to Gemini and like it's, that part's gonna suck for a long
Speaker 3:  time.
Speaker 4:  Yes. Or we're gonna, somebody is gonna figure out how to like
Speaker 4:  do the hack to make it work whether the companies want it to or not. And
Speaker 4:  then we're gonna have an entirely different kind of mess. And
Speaker 3:  Then a new generation of college students will we radicalize by Napster and
Speaker 3:  then that's how we will v for Vendetta my replacement. It'll be great. We
Speaker 3:  gotta take a quick break, but talk about this XR thing really quickly.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Okay. So you know, Android, how is Android?
Speaker 4:  Imagine if smart glasses were a thing and if if
Speaker 4:  Google just did Android again for those, that's what Android XR is. And
Speaker 4:  basically Google has been at this Smart glasses thing for like
Speaker 4:  15 years now, maybe has tried a bunch of
Speaker 4:  things. Do you remember Daydream? Daydream is one I had forgotten about that
Speaker 4:  I just randomly rediscovered today. Daydream existed. I wrote a whole thing
Speaker 4:  about it for Wired a million years ago. Completely forgot about that. But
Speaker 4:  anyway, so Google announced like a developer preview
Speaker 4:  of Android XR. It's basically what you think it's a, it's immersive versions
Speaker 4:  of some Google apps and some Gemini stuff. Basically the,
Speaker 4:  the underpinning of all of this is the assistant Gemini
Speaker 4:  stuff that you might wanna wear on your face. That's sort of the big theory.
Speaker 4:  They have a bunch of hardware partners. I've been hearing from like every
Speaker 4:  company that wants to sell you glasses over the last few weeks being like,
Speaker 4:  we're doing a thing with Google that we can't quite tell you about yet. That's
Speaker 4:  Android XR. So starting next year, I think we're gonna start to see
Speaker 4:  real development and hardware products. It sounds like Samsung
Speaker 4:  is gonna be the first outta the gate with like a real honest to god Android
Speaker 4:  pair of glasses. But it seems very clear that like Apple is trying
Speaker 4:  to be the apple of your face with the Vision Pro
Speaker 4:  and Google is very happy being the Android of your face. I think the question
Speaker 4:  of whether Google is going to make hardware is really interesting. Google's
Speaker 4:  made a bunch of prototypes and gave us some indication this week that it
Speaker 4:  is interested in them being more than prototypes. And If you want to do
Speaker 4:  all this Gemini stuff and Project Astral, like you gotta have glasses. Like
Speaker 4:  if, if this AI future that everybody's imagining
Speaker 4:  and trying to sell you on is going to come true, it's going to be glasses.
Speaker 4:  It just is. I I'm a hundred percent convinced.
Speaker 3:  I'm just saying it's a decade from now. There's an eighth grader,
Speaker 3:  one of our children will be in eighth grade at some point. They're on their
Speaker 3:  eighth grade ship to dc they're wearing their glasses. They look at the capitol
Speaker 3:  and say, what happened here? What's, what are some notable events in American
Speaker 3:  history? Does it say an insurrection or does it say it was a day of love?
Speaker 3:  And are the answers on two different eighth graders different? And these
Speaker 3:  companies are racing towards a future where they're going to have to answer
Speaker 3:  that question regardless of whether they make the hardware or not. Aren't
Speaker 3:  you just
Speaker 4:  Describing the internet though? Like
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. My feeling is that Bixby would say it's a day of love.
Speaker 3:  No, no further commentary. We should really
Speaker 4:  Do like a political alignment matrix of all of the different virtual
Speaker 4:  assistants.
Speaker 3:  Oh my God,
Speaker 4:  I feel like if I sat down and thought about it for five minutes, I would
Speaker 4:  end up with really strong opinions. Who did
Speaker 3:  T vote for? Yep. So my question is, do you wanna see the thing, know the
Speaker 3:  answer to that? Do you wanna go viral on X in this specific way? You're like,
Speaker 3:  we're gonna milk the last drop of traffic from this one dead platform
Speaker 3:  and it's up the political alignment chart of different ai.
Speaker 3:  No thank you. Alright. There's more AI
Speaker 3:  news, it's it, it's just a lot of things got released this week. Yeah, open.
Speaker 3:  I released SOA iOS 18.2 is out with Chad. GBD
Speaker 3:  integration, visual intelligence, which what, what, what, what do you wanna
Speaker 3:  start with?
Speaker 4:  Let's do iOS 18.2 first.
Speaker 3:  Okay. I mean we've, it, it's very familiar. I think we had a moment this
Speaker 3:  morning we're like, how much should we cover this? 'cause people have seen
Speaker 3:  it, they've used it. It's been in beta. The release candidate was last week,
Speaker 3:  but it's out now. If you have an iPhone 16 or up or even iPhone 15 Pro,
Speaker 3:  you get visual intelligence, you get Gen Moji chat. BT
Speaker 3:  integration is there. Joanna Stern wrote a very funny column where she's
Speaker 3:  like, you invoke chat GBT by saying like secret words. Like If you
Speaker 3:  ask Siri one way, you get a regular Siri answer. But If you ask Siri, like
Speaker 3:  write me a list, a ChatGPT is the list for you. Which is
Speaker 3:  very funny.
Speaker 3:  I've been, look, I've been using this stuff, David, I think you've been using
Speaker 3:  this stuff. What? What do you think
Speaker 4:  Richard famously uses Windows phone. So he, God only
Speaker 3:  Knows it's the only way to live.
Speaker 4:  I'll say two things. I think one, the single coolest thing about iOS
Speaker 4:  18.2 is the ability to change default apps for various things.
Speaker 4:  Like when you tap on a phone number, you can change which app it goes to.
Speaker 4:  Everyone should go examine all of those defaults because If you get that
Speaker 4:  kind of thing right, it makes your phone a lot better. This is the sort of
Speaker 4:  thing Android has been better at than iOS for forever and thank you
Speaker 4:  to occasionally confused EU regulators for making this
Speaker 4:  happen. The the chat GPT thing I think is
Speaker 4:  interesting. What I've found is that when I ask compound
Speaker 4:  questions, it punts to chat GPT more often than not,
Speaker 4:  right? Like if my question kind of has two parts or has
Speaker 4:  a a thing and then a modifier, like one I just did the other day was like
Speaker 4:  if I ask for a chocolate chip cookie recipe, Siri will just kind of
Speaker 4:  pull it and I'm gonna not say that word again because it's just
Speaker 4:  activated three devices.
Speaker 4:  But if I ask for a chocolate chip cookie recipe that
Speaker 4:  maybe will taste like I haven't tried before, then it punts to chat GBT
Speaker 4:  and then it's, it's a relatively consistent experience. Actually, one thing
Speaker 4:  that I've liked is that when it goes to chat GBT, the thing that it brings
Speaker 4:  down still looks like the normal
Speaker 4:  Siri response. So I think in that like the, my mental
Speaker 4:  construct of what's going on is very confused in a way that I don't like,
Speaker 4:  but the actual user experience of it I think is actually pretty good.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I mean in terms of like, this is a good way to get better
Speaker 3:  answers from a Siri and so you just get, I I
Speaker 3:  think that works to some extent.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like do I have feelings about the idea that my stuff is
Speaker 4:  going to chat GPT over and over and over again? Sure. But If you
Speaker 4:  don't, that friction should go away and there isn't actually as much
Speaker 4:  friction as I expected. So I think that's a probably on app,
Speaker 4:  on balance a good thing.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean, again, I've had the action button on my phone mapped to
Speaker 3:  the ChatGPT voice assistant forever. That's right. So this is just like
Speaker 3:  a slightly faster version of that for me with like more annoying
Speaker 3:  animation. Like I, I actually think the new sir animation
Speaker 3:  is, is so overwrought.
Speaker 4:  I agree. I missed the little swirling ball. The thing where it
Speaker 4:  like it now takes over my whole phone screen. I don't like it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's, it's very much like jazz hands. It's like get ready
Speaker 3:  for an experience. It's like, I don't need this tap. No, it's cool. But it
Speaker 3:  just means that it's gonna take a little bit longer to load. Right. And then
Speaker 3:  you talk, add a couple front, then talk, and then it does a thing where it
Speaker 3:  like fills out the words for you. There's, there's some amount of
Speaker 3:  like obfuscating how slow it was with the swirly ball. Yes.
Speaker 3:  Made it appear fast. You know, like how progress bars are.
Speaker 3:  They're, they're mostly designed to go really fast for the first part and
Speaker 3:  then they can be slow at the end. But you've already perceived it being fast.
Speaker 3:  That's very much what the old Siri was doing. And now it's just like
Speaker 3:  everything's glowing and you can see the world's and it's like, I don't need,
Speaker 3:  I don't need to see the mouse running the wheel guys just like let me know
Speaker 3:  when there's an answer.
Speaker 4:  I, I think that's right. I had actually not really ever thought
Speaker 4:  about Siri as a, as a spinning like max style
Speaker 4:  beach ball of loading things until it switched to this. And then it is like,
Speaker 4:  it is so desperate to make it seem like something is happening at all times
Speaker 4:  because it's slow. So it's just like, look at these beautiful pink and blue
Speaker 4:  swirlies until it finishes. Which it will do
Speaker 4:  eventually. It's
Speaker 3:  Like,
Speaker 4:  It's like alright, this is actually like pretty good design on top of a pretty
Speaker 4:  bad system. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I will say, I mean it's, it is again the natural language capabilities that
Speaker 3:  is what AI is best at. So it, I, it understands me a lot
Speaker 3:  better. And then chat G PD is familiar.
Speaker 3:  I don't know if it's hallucinating ny, but like it's, it's all happening
Speaker 3:  and there's some guardrails in there. It to me, the ones that I,
Speaker 3:  I don't think those are, the Apple intelligence is here features the, now
Speaker 3:  Siri can talk to Cha G pd. I think that is table stakes and it's kind of
Speaker 3:  weird that it wasn't there from the jump. The ones that I think are, are
Speaker 3:  big are image playground, gen, moji and visual intelligence,
Speaker 3:  right? Where the phone gets multimodal and it can now
Speaker 3:  talk in like both in and out. But I
Speaker 3:  like Gen Moji is just purely silly to me. Image playground is like
Speaker 3:  50 steps behind, although that's probably the safest way for it to be.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that seems to be deliberate
Speaker 3:  And visual intelligence is, you know, it's just the same thing we're talking
Speaker 3:  about. We're like, I look at is this a flower? And it's like, it sure is.
Speaker 3:  And like the next turn isn't quite there yet. And but like maybe
Speaker 3:  I'm just being a hater.
Speaker 4:  Well a, you're definitely just being a hater. That's certainly true.
Speaker 3:  I'm in a real little salty moods. I don't know why
Speaker 4:  You are. I can tell I'm enjoying this very much. You're like, what if everything
Speaker 4:  was awful and woke and I hated it?
Speaker 3:  Look, I know where the views are.
Speaker 4:  I don't know what, like the gen moji thing is one that I'm, I'm really
Speaker 4:  torn on because I feel like we've been covering apple's weird
Speaker 4:  ideas about emoji for like the whole life of The Verge.
Speaker 4:  And I don't think I have ever once earnestly sent
Speaker 4:  or received one of apple's weird emoji other than
Speaker 4:  like to goof on another tech reporter. I think if, like, if I just
Speaker 4:  made a Jen Moji and sent it to my wife, she would like call the police.
Speaker 4:  Like it would be so weird as, as a thing to just do
Speaker 3:  Has, wait, has your kid discovered the, you can hold on a face in a photo
Speaker 3:  and make a sticker of a face?
Speaker 4:  No, thank God, because
Speaker 3:  I have a camera roll full of those or wherever they are in the file system
Speaker 3:  on, I like just billions of stickers like left and right
Speaker 3:  and those are very funny to send around because they're horrifying.
Speaker 3:  But that's very much like we use the walkie-talkie feature on our Apple watches
Speaker 3:  and we're the only people use it with the walkie-talkie feature on Apple
Speaker 3:  watches.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, and I just feel like all of this stuff, image, playground, gen, Moji,
Speaker 4:  like, and this is true o of lots of other people's products too, is like,
Speaker 4:  I'm, I'm convinced that the, all of the AI
Speaker 4:  image generation stuff is more of a meme than a product at this
Speaker 4:  point. And I just don't, I don't know that there are I actual reasons
Speaker 4:  that they exist other than somebody made them like,
Speaker 4:  I don't know, Richard, am I crazy? Are you, are you just like sending Jen
Speaker 4:  Mos to all your pals every day?
Speaker 5:  I am not. I unfortunately do not have a device ready to run Apple
Speaker 5:  Intelligence in in my home. I probably never will because I
Speaker 5:  do not wanna send Jen Moji. I I don't wanna do this, but like
Speaker 4:  With Gemini 2.0, you're gonna be able to generate some weird stuff too. So
Speaker 4:  get ready when
Speaker 5:  You open up Instagram. I just wanna like search for an account and oh, now
Speaker 5:  I'm in the AI window. Thanks.
Speaker 4:  I really do hate that.
Speaker 5:  But I've, I I I, it's bizarre because I I I've never wanted
Speaker 5:  to generate an emoji. Not that I don't know if all of
Speaker 5:  the emojis that are in the phone exist and cover every feeling I've ever
Speaker 5:  had, but whatever feelings I have that aren't covered by those emoji,
Speaker 5:  I'm not in touch with you yet. I just haven't
Speaker 3:  Considered it. It's not,
Speaker 5:  It's not something that's, that's just dying to get out of me. That, that
Speaker 5:  I cannot, I I'm, I must, I must find the
Speaker 5:  zebra of many colors with, with, you know, anatomical
Speaker 5:  incorrectness that represents how I'm feeling right now. I just, I, I haven't
Speaker 5:  gotten it yet.
Speaker 3:  I think it's very important for everyone listening to this right now who
Speaker 3:  has access to Apple intelligence to pull over in their cars, send
Speaker 3:  in that prompt and then send us whatever it
Speaker 4:  Generates.
Speaker 3:  Like, I, I, I issue a lot of instructions on this show. Ask
Speaker 3:  your phone to make a zebra of many colors that's
Speaker 3:  anatomically incorrect. That is expresses a feeling that you don't know
Speaker 3:  you're having or whatever it is that Richard just said. And just let us know
Speaker 3:  what it gives you. I'm dying to know.
Speaker 4:  I feel good about that.
Speaker 3:  Look, I, I think ultimately Apple wants it to seem like the phone is very
Speaker 3:  capable and AI makes, whether or not it actually is capable
Speaker 3:  AI makes it seem like the phone can do more stuff than it could do yesterday.
Speaker 3:  Right now you can press camera control on your iPhone 16 and look at something
Speaker 3:  and it'll be like, here's a flower you, it can write for you in a way that
Speaker 3:  I think those ads are doing it a massive disservice to, 'cause it just seems
Speaker 3:  like everyone's a jerk at work.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Every one of those ads is like, Hey, dumb ass. Yeah. One seem like
Speaker 4:  not such a dumb ass happily
Speaker 5:  They have, they have a real problem with those ads because they have to find
Speaker 5:  something that is so important that you have to send the message, but also
Speaker 5:  not so important that you need to write it yourself. And what is that?
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 3:  How do you, how do you find that
Speaker 4:  You could conceivably be hired for, even though you're dumb as a rock,
Speaker 3:  The one where the guy rolls his chair out of the meeting to summarize whatever
Speaker 3:  and rolls back in the meeting. I get it. It's a very funny It is, it is,
Speaker 3:  it is attention getting, which is the purpose of advertising, but it's like,
Speaker 3:  oh that sucks. Like I would be like, get out of this meeting. Like I don't
Speaker 3:  need to waste my time. If you haven't done the reading, you can tell what
Speaker 3:  our reading's. Like, I I just think like they've made the phone slightly
Speaker 3:  more capable, but this big apple intelligence is here moment.
Speaker 3:  I don't know. It it, it's not the same as the chat GBT moment that
Speaker 3:  everyone talks about. Like no, your mind is not expanded because
Speaker 3:  the, the messages notifications are 8% better than they were in
Speaker 3:  iOS 18.1.
Speaker 4:  If if there's going to be that thing anytime soon, it's gonna
Speaker 4:  be agents. And even even Apple agrees with that, right? Like you talk about
Speaker 4:  the, the intense stuff that they're starting to build into iOS that's gonna
Speaker 4:  get Siri more access to apps so it can actually go and like
Speaker 4:  get information and do things inside of those apps. Like that's what everyone
Speaker 4:  is trying to build. And if somebody gets it right in a way that is useful
Speaker 4:  and doesn't cause a culture war Patel, that's gonna be
Speaker 4:  the next thing. Because those will be the moments where people are like,
Speaker 4:  oh, I, I, I now understand a thing I can ask this to do
Speaker 4:  that is useful and new.
Speaker 3:  The culture where I just wanna point out is in AR is in visual intelligence.
Speaker 4:  I see, okay.
Speaker 3:  App intense is money, right? Because Apple is
Speaker 3:  counting on a bunch of app developers to do what they say, which they usually
Speaker 3:  do. Yep. 'cause their customers are on the iPhone and they're in the app
Speaker 3:  store and to say you have to do app intent, just
Speaker 3:  like they said to a bunch of app developers, you have to do in-app purchases.
Speaker 3:  So we can take our 30% cut. That's how you get a Siri that can actually use
Speaker 3:  the apps. You have to build the features in a bunch of developers are gonna
Speaker 3:  say no, I don't know why DoorDash would say yes to that. The
Speaker 3:  answer has to be money and like no one has figured out that money yet. And
Speaker 3:  I I, I do just keep picking on DoorDash. If anyone from DoorDash wants to
Speaker 3:  come on and tell me that they're gonna happily let everyone disintermediate
Speaker 3:  their service, like that's great. But I just look at that per put
Speaker 3:  any company in that mix.
Speaker 5:  Well look at Netflix. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  You don't have to participate If you have your own audience
Speaker 5:  And what they've done with the Apple TV and Vision Pro. If you're big enough
Speaker 5:  you can just say no. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So I that I, I just see that coming but everyone wants to build these agents
Speaker 3:  and the the systems they want those agents to use do not have to play ball
Speaker 3:  and we just haven't sorted that out. Alright, so that's 18.2 people get it.
Speaker 3:  Let us know you think, send us your multicolor emotional zebra please.
Speaker 3:  Let's talk about soa. SOA is fascinating to me in that it doesn't
Speaker 3:  appear to be great but it's super good enough to be like
Speaker 3:  ultra interesting.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's about my read of it. I mean I think the
Speaker 4:  Sora is so bizarre because it
Speaker 4:  is another one on the list of things that OpenAI is like, this is too
Speaker 4:  good. We should barely even be allowed to launch this.
Speaker 4:  We're desperately afraid of all the things that this will visit upon the
Speaker 4:  world if we release it. And then there's just like here, it's a person
Speaker 4:  doing gymnastics whose body explodes in a thousand directions every time
Speaker 4:  they do a flip. And it's like, this is another one where I'm like, does this
Speaker 4:  exist for any reason other than so that people will post
Speaker 4:  about it on the internet? I, I sincerely don't know.
Speaker 5:  Also it's not exactly available. They very quickly
Speaker 5:  ran out of capacity and stopped accepting signups. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Wait, can you explain to me what happened here? I was away from the internet
Speaker 4:  for several hours and it went from SOA is available to SOA is not
Speaker 4:  available while I was gone. What
Speaker 5:  Happened? Yeah. That's pretty much what happened in in like it was like a
Speaker 5:  shoe release. Like oh it's out now it's not. And then Sam
Speaker 5:  was like ah, you know, we just underestimated the capacity and we'll be opening
Speaker 5:  it up at some point. So how much capacity do they actually have? How much
Speaker 5:  capacity can they support to run this thing? We don't know. You do have to
Speaker 5:  pay to use it. You have to have either the $20 or $200 plan. If you have
Speaker 5:  the $200 per month chat GPT Pro plan and you got access, then you
Speaker 5:  can make 10 80 p videos that are up to 20 seconds long. So I mean pretty
Speaker 5:  good deal. I think like 20 seconds of 10 80 p video
Speaker 5:  for just $200 a month. Wait two a month. Don't say everyone doesn't have
Speaker 5:  two accounts. $200 a month on the chat GPT Pro plan. I mean you can use
Speaker 5:  on the
Speaker 3:  That's one they just announced. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You can use the ChatGPT plus plan, but like that's a seven 20 p five seconds.
Speaker 5:  I mean, who's gonna do that? Like
Speaker 3:  That's nothing. You can't destabilize one country with five
Speaker 3:  seconds of seven 20 p video.
Speaker 3:  I mean look, I I watched Marquez Brown Lee's video about soa.
Speaker 3:  The most fascinating piece about it is when he asked it to make a, a tech
Speaker 3:  review video and then it had his plant in it. Yep. Because
Speaker 3:  it has clearly trained on his videos without any permission.
Speaker 3:  What are we doing guys like that? I I can't tell if
Speaker 3:  Google's gonna file that lawsuit or the YouTubers will file that lawsuit
Speaker 3:  but that lawsuit's coming just from that alone. That lawsuit's coming.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. I mean yeah, there, there, there, there is so much
Speaker 4:  obvious clear clean evidence that a lot of
Speaker 4:  open AI is just built on YouTube. It's pretty horrifying.
Speaker 4:  Also, Richard, I would point out you forgot one key difference between
Speaker 4:  the $20 and the $200 chat GPT subscription, which is that
Speaker 4:  If you pay more you can download the videos without any watermarks. Oh
Speaker 3:  Good.
Speaker 4:  So
Speaker 3:  That's, you can definitely destabilize the country If you pay more than that's,
Speaker 3:  that's,
Speaker 5:  That's worth $200.
Speaker 3:  Marque also said something really interesting in his video that I have just
Speaker 3:  been ruminating about ever since he said I had it make a bunch of
Speaker 3:  CCTV footage because it's so bad that people would
Speaker 3:  assume it's real. Like he intentionally generated footage that was
Speaker 3:  already low quality of like cars driving down the street but in like black
Speaker 3:  and white security camera footage. And that's like super interesting right?
Speaker 3:  Because they are 22nd clips with no sound
Speaker 3:  and people experience a lot of grainy low quality clips
Speaker 3:  with no sound that they take to be reality in a lot of contexts. Particularly,
Speaker 3:  Hey we found some security camera footage or we found some ring footage or
Speaker 3:  whatever it is. So you can pay to get rid of the visible watermark.
Speaker 3:  You pay $2 a month or you just crop it whatever. Are they doing C
Speaker 3:  two PA the the like the fancy embedded one?
Speaker 5:  Yes. OpenAI says that videos generated with, so we will have both visible
Speaker 5:  watermarks If you have the cheap version and C two P metadata to
Speaker 5:  indicate that they're made with ai. We, we hope that that works in in safe
Speaker 5:  civilization.
Speaker 3:  I'll say we've written a lot about C two PA, the content authenticity initiative.
Speaker 3:  Jess Weathered has done incredible work just trying to understand what it
Speaker 3:  is and how it will play out and whether it will actually mean anything to
Speaker 3:  anyone. And every time we read about it we get a bunch of angry notes from
Speaker 3:  readers who are, who have been deep in it, who are like, this is a
Speaker 3:  total fraud. Like this will never work the way you want it to for infinity
Speaker 3:  reasons. But it's the thing that we have and that's why
Speaker 3:  I keep writing about it. 'cause there's nothing else. There's, there's no
Speaker 3:  other choice. There's isn't like market competition to this metadata standard.
Speaker 3:  Like there's this one and Google has chosen to use it and it sounds like
Speaker 3:  open eyes using it, Adobe's using it. The platforms have to
Speaker 3:  start using it, right? The YouTubes and the Facebooks and the
Speaker 3:  tiktoks have to agree to display this metadata and they're
Speaker 3:  not uniformly agreeing to it and Apple hasn't chosen to
Speaker 3:  use it on the creation side. So we're just
Speaker 4:  Still, meanwhile all those platforms are furiously building AI tools
Speaker 4:  of their own and have exactly no incentive to point out when things
Speaker 4:  are made with ai. Like I just, I who benefits from doing
Speaker 4:  that other than regular people and thus why would they do it?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, we're just headed towards, I think what where we're gonna end up
Speaker 3:  with is a series of more closed platforms
Speaker 3:  that basically guarantee you stuff from like real people
Speaker 3:  and then open platforms where it's a free for all and maybe that's gonna
Speaker 3:  be good. Like honestly maybe it's good to be like on, if I open this app,
Speaker 3:  I know it's a bunch of like Hollywood movie directors who have actually made
Speaker 3:  the thing and if I open this app, who knows what random
Speaker 3:  AI generated slop I will get And like maybe that's fine. Maybe that's the
Speaker 3:  thing that breaks apart the internet in that way or like causes that fragmentation.
Speaker 3:  I just, I don't know. But it's, we're just at a point now where
Speaker 3:  all of the channels we're used to are gonna get completely
Speaker 3:  infused with AI generat content. I
Speaker 4:  Think the only problem with that outcome is I think the audience split between
Speaker 4:  those two different kinds of platforms would not be what you
Speaker 4:  hope it would be.
Speaker 3:  Oh I think it, yeah. One will be expensive. Yeah. One will have a small audience
Speaker 3:  and cost money like that that that seems correct. But I even now in TikTok
Speaker 3:  I see videos and it it just like silly stuff. It's like
Speaker 3:  here's a big wave crashing over a building and it's like pretty obviously
Speaker 3:  real and then all the comments are like this is ai.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 3:  And we've just destabilized that entire information economy. Yeah. LeBron
Speaker 3:  was never dunked on that. Was AI
Speaker 3:  a little more, there's more AI stuff, tragedy, we launched
Speaker 3:  Canvas view. What's going on there?
Speaker 4:  Canvas is basically the, the slightly more sort of interactive
Speaker 4:  thing that you can do where like If you have it write something for you,
Speaker 4:  it can display the thing that it's making next to the conversation you're
Speaker 4:  having about it and you can sort of edit the thing in real time with the
Speaker 4:  bot. This is the thing that Claude has been doing philanthropic spot
Speaker 4:  for a while and I think it's actually very clever, right? Like if, If you
Speaker 4:  allow for the possibility that maybe
Speaker 4:  generating several paragraphs of nah text is the best thing a chat
Speaker 4:  bot can do, this is actually a pretty good version of that
Speaker 4:  interaction where like you can have it to a thing and it, it generates it
Speaker 4:  in the right column and then you can, you can go back and forth with the
Speaker 4:  bot tuning it and changing it and you can make changes to it and it becomes
Speaker 4:  this sort of interactive thing rather than just
Speaker 4:  blocks of messages, which is what we've had before. This is like the big
Speaker 4:  trend here with all these chat bots is everyone has run up against
Speaker 4:  how much you can do inside of a back and forth messaging system. So they're
Speaker 4:  all trying to tack on little bits of UI and little bits of features that
Speaker 4:  don't feel like that but still work inside that kind of
Speaker 4:  basic construct. So I think in, in that case like Canvas is, is a
Speaker 4:  good idea whether you're, you know, writing stuff or writing code or whatever
Speaker 4:  it's been, it's been out, it's been tested for a while. I, I haven't heard
Speaker 4:  a ton about it but the people I've heard from seem to like it. So it seems
Speaker 4:  good. This
Speaker 3:  Thing you're saying about UI across all of these products is super interesting
Speaker 3:  to me. Like Chad CBD was the moment, right? Everyone
Speaker 3:  talks about it like my eyes were opened, I could see the world in color
Speaker 3:  and then like two years later we're like actually that interface
Speaker 3:  isn't like we have to build all these other kinds of products
Speaker 3:  to make this useful and the arms race of like what will
Speaker 3:  the chatbots themselves look like
Speaker 3:  Fundamentally, I think they're gonna get subsumed into operating systems
Speaker 3:  the way that Apple is subsuming them into Siri and then that they'll be more
Speaker 3:  specialized for other tasks. That's my guess. But it's interesting to see
Speaker 3:  them rev it.
Speaker 4:  I think that's probably right. I mean, and I think like the, the way that
Speaker 4:  I've come to frame, the way that I'm thinking about AI for next year
Speaker 4:  is the last two years have been like running towards
Speaker 4:  the point of diminishing returns for the actual underlying technology
Speaker 4:  and we're there, right? This stuff will keep getting better. There might
Speaker 4:  be some incredible physics miracle that changes
Speaker 4:  how all of this stuff works, but on the path that we're on this stuff
Speaker 4:  is going to keep getting better but much slower than it has before. And so
Speaker 4:  now the question is, is any of this useful for
Speaker 4:  anything? And we have not had to ask that question because we've been on
Speaker 4:  basically a two year run for all these companies of novelty
Speaker 4:  and they've made it a really long way just by finding
Speaker 4:  slightly new seeming things to do and just the fact that I could
Speaker 4:  take a picture and say, is this a flower? And I would say yes, it's a flower
Speaker 4:  was like novel and cool and exciting and we are at the end of
Speaker 4:  that moment and, and I think you're starting to see it like the disillusionment
Speaker 4:  with what all these things are attempting to do and whether they're
Speaker 4:  actually good is coming and it's here. And so the question now is like
Speaker 4:  let's assume the technology is not going to get several orders of
Speaker 4:  magnitude better next year. What else is there to do with the technology
Speaker 4:  that we have? Is the question,
Speaker 3:  Okay, so here's my answer. It's the last one of this section. The most useful
Speaker 3:  thing I've seen with AI yet Reddit built Reddit answers
Speaker 3:  which lets you just search Reddit without having to go through Google and
Speaker 3:  it has AI in it so it'll summarize a bunch of Reddit threads. So when you
Speaker 3:  search for whatever, it'll show you a bunch of Reddit answers but summarize
Speaker 3:  'em with ai. That might be the best thing yet.
Speaker 4:  This might be the best AI feature of all time. I
Speaker 4:  haven't used it. J Peter's used it a little bit and had I would say sort
Speaker 4:  of mixed experiences with it. But the
Speaker 4:  idea of being able to kind of poll all of Reddit with a question
Speaker 4:  that you have sounds amazing and it doesn't
Speaker 4:  work quite as well even in Google search, which
Speaker 4:  made this very expensive deal with Reddit to get the data because it just,
Speaker 4:  it just isn't compiling them the same way. But like if I
Speaker 4:  could just quickly be like, okay, what, what baby
Speaker 4:  gear does everybody on Reddit think you should buy? Like that that information
Speaker 4:  exists inside of Reddit and if it can go and
Speaker 4:  actually like compile all of that stuff in a way that works and makes sense,
Speaker 4:  kick ass dude I will use that all the time.
Speaker 3:  Okay, now that I've said that, I do agree this is very good there. Of course
Speaker 3:  the supplied examples are
Speaker 4:  What does Reddit think happened on January 6th?
Speaker 3:  The the, the one
Speaker 3:  Jay put in was tips for flying with the baby for the first time. Pretty
Speaker 3:  good like a perfect Reddit query, right? Like and
Speaker 3:  and honestly I what I want outta that Reddit experience is like give me 5,000
Speaker 3:  stories about this, right? Yeah. And so it summarized everyone's stories
Speaker 3:  and the answers
Speaker 3:  in first class helpful,
Speaker 4:  Solid.
Speaker 3:  Cool. I personally find my private shot very helpful with our baby
Speaker 3:  feed them during takeoff or landing classic advice by the way. And then bring
Speaker 3:  plenty of snacks and drinks to keep your baby occupied. And it's like, well
Speaker 3:  yeah, that's just stuff. Okay
Speaker 4:  Wait, this is very fun. I might just immediately take back everything I just
Speaker 4:  said because If you go down to the next screenshot, which is the Google searches,
Speaker 4:  the stuff
Speaker 4:  Don't board first. Good tips. Being strapped into the car seat is the safest
Speaker 4:  way for baby to fly. Good tip baby will need to be in a car seat. Baby will
Speaker 4:  also need to be held by you the entire flight. That seems confusing.
Speaker 3:  You're holding the car seat, holding the
Speaker 4:  Car seat.
Speaker 4:  Take some sanitizing wipes to clean the areas and plan your baby will be
Speaker 4:  touching. Have a light pad you can use for changing a plane. All of that
Speaker 4:  is more useful than this stuff that by the
Speaker 3:  Way, can I say none of that is the most useful tip that we found with with
Speaker 3:  Max, which is just bring five packs of differently colored post-it
Speaker 3:  notes and let her go crazy.
Speaker 4:  Ooh, that's good. Mine was just snacks. We bought I would say
Speaker 4:  40 different snacks on the channel. It's not
Speaker 3:  A parenting podcast, I'm just saying it's just funny, right? 'cause If you
Speaker 3:  take the world's body of information and Reddit, which is a lot of
Speaker 3:  personal experiences which are kind of useful and like for this kind of
Speaker 3:  thing where there's not an answer and then you try to shove it into the form
Speaker 3:  of this is the right answer you end up with put baby in chair.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's the problem that we've run into with Apple Intelligence. Like notification
Speaker 5:  summaries. Like notifications were already summarized. Like the people who
Speaker 5:  wrote the post already wrote them to be read by someone who wasn't really
Speaker 5:  paying attention and didn't have a lot of time and they, they laid it out
Speaker 5:  in a way they were upvoted because they were written well and they got you
Speaker 5:  the information they needed. You didn't need to summarize them and and extract
Speaker 5:  further value out of one particular line. You needed the whole thing
Speaker 4:  A
Speaker 5:  Hundred percent. We did it the wrong way. I
Speaker 4:  Mean this is, this is the the like ongoing, it's like,
Speaker 4:  it's not quite context collapse but it is, it is just
Speaker 4:  the pure like lowest common denominator of ai
Speaker 4:  which is that If you take everything and you try to shove it into two sentences,
Speaker 4:  you're going to get two incredibly uninteresting sentences. And
Speaker 4:  I think what we've seen from some others, like I think Notebook LM from Google
Speaker 4:  does a pretty good job of this, of basically it, it goes and
Speaker 4:  finds stuff and then just hands you a bunch of sources, right? Like what
Speaker 4:  I want from this Reddit thing is not Pat
Speaker 4:  answers in paragraphs. I want a bunch of links to like here are,
Speaker 4:  here are the 10, like you said Neli, here are the 10 most
Speaker 4:  loved and contentious and funny responses that we've ever gotten to this
Speaker 4:  question that everybody replied to. Oh my god, I tried this and it worked.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's how you do this, right? Not by saying here is the
Speaker 4:  rough summary of 12,000 Reddit posts and that's what too many of
Speaker 4:  these services are trying to do.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, that's it. I do think Reddit is, it's where I see the most opportunity.
Speaker 3:  'cause Reddit is vast, right? And like you can burn a lot of time hearing
Speaker 3:  every version of everything on Reddit and having a tool that helps you like
Speaker 3:  get through that better is kind of interesting. I'm just
Speaker 3:  it, you know, it's like that's one example. I'm sure there are other ones,
Speaker 3:  but the glory of Reddit is that it's a bunch of people
Speaker 3:  telling you what they experienced. It's very rarely that there's a right
Speaker 3:  answer, right? It's just like I'm gonna synthesize all this information from
Speaker 3:  all these people who are telling me about whatever, or just talking about
Speaker 3:  their fandom or whatever it is. And that makes me feel like part of a community.
Speaker 3:  It makes me feel,
Speaker 3:  it makes me feel like part of a community. It makes me feel validated that
Speaker 3:  like I might have some experiences too. Not I need to, I just shove in a
Speaker 3:  car seat.
Speaker 3:  Okay, we gotta take a break. We got we back with lightning round Boy this
Speaker 3:  is, this is gonna be, this is an action packed lightning round. We'll be
Speaker 3:  right back.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back with the lightning round. Liam, who is the Lightning
Speaker 3:  Round sponsor,
Speaker 1:  This week's lightning round is presented by Amazon Queue, the new
Speaker 1:  generative AI assistant from AWS
Speaker 3:  Oh, it's so good. Have we started adding the, the cash register sound effect?
Speaker 1:  I think we only did it on the first one since you asked for the effect, but
Speaker 1:  If you, If you want that to be a regular thing, we could,
Speaker 3:  I feel like we got in a lot of trouble with an episode recently by asking
Speaker 3:  for sound effects that we didn't deliver.
Speaker 4:  So also if you'd like to make a Jen Moji of Neli being showered in cash and
Speaker 4:  send it to me, I'm good with that. Right
Speaker 3:  Next to our, our emotional zebra. Alright, lightning round.
Speaker 3:  David, you wrote about this this week. YouTube is still growing fast on TVs
Speaker 3:  in the living room. What's going
Speaker 4:  On here? Yeah, so I would say statistically, If you are
Speaker 4:  absorbing this podcast right now, I don't even know what word to use anymore.
Speaker 4:  If you are experiencing this podcast, there is an
Speaker 4:  increasingly large chance you're watching us on your television in your living
Speaker 4:  room. If you are, hello?
Speaker 3:  Oh, it's only Love you if you're watching this on some janky side lid lcd,
Speaker 3:  I still love you. You should actually watch it. Watch it like several times
Speaker 3:  actually.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, watch it on all of your different TVs just to check the resolution
Speaker 4:  differences I would say. Yeah, but no, basically YouTube put out a bunch
Speaker 4:  of stats this week about how fast its living room stuff is growing.
Speaker 4:  400 million hours a month of podcast viewing is happening
Speaker 4:  on TVs, sports stuff is way up. They launched this new feature
Speaker 4:  that I think is kind of cool, it's called Watch with. And essentially
Speaker 4:  what they discovered is that a lot of people are watching a sporting
Speaker 4:  event with live commentary from somebody streaming and talking about it
Speaker 4:  and they're now smooshing those things together. So creators are gonna be
Speaker 4:  able to actually like do their own commentary over top of something that
Speaker 4:  they're watching and they're starting with sports but also made it pretty
Speaker 4:  clear that that's gonna come to other things. So like Kurt Wilms, the guy
Speaker 4:  I was talking to who runs product for YouTube's living room stuff
Speaker 4:  specifically mentioned like what about an Apple keynote where there are all
Speaker 4:  these creators who want to talk about it and comment on it. That's just a
Speaker 4:  thing we can offer that you can get all these different commentary streams.
Speaker 4:  I think that's very cool.
Speaker 3:  I'm sure Apple will have some, some very interesting thoughts about that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, what
Speaker 4:  Could possibly go wrong? Who's gonna be mad about new commentary on
Speaker 4:  every movie that exists in the world, but more broadly
Speaker 4:  like YouTube is now huge on TVs
Speaker 4:  and has gone undergone this shift. I think really in the last year, like
Speaker 4:  I follow this company pretty closely and they used to talk about the TVs
Speaker 4:  as just kind of another place. People watched YouTube and now they're like
Speaker 4:  really thinking about it as like a primary platform
Speaker 4:  for YouTube and they're building features for the TV kind of for the first
Speaker 4:  time. Like they have this shows thing where you can put up a bunch of videos
Speaker 4:  in seasons and episodes that makes it feel more like a streaming service,
Speaker 4:  that're doing the watch with stuff. They're doing a lot of work
Speaker 4:  to sync your phone with your tv. Like YouTube has
Speaker 4:  always kind of wanted to be Netflix in a certain way and I think
Speaker 4:  we're starting to see it push to be a little more premium, a little higher
Speaker 4:  end, a little more TV centric. They're convinced they can do this
Speaker 4:  without killing YouTube as a product elsewhere. But that,
Speaker 4:  that tension feels very real to me and I think it's really fascinating.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I will, can I say one thing on YouTube very quickly? We've like
Speaker 3:  talked about enough about a business in the past couple weeks. I don't wanna
Speaker 3:  overdo it, but I have a story on the website this week.
Speaker 3:  A lot of people complain that our YouTube videos on our website don't let
Speaker 3:  you click the title to go to YouTube and everyone thinks that's our fault.
Speaker 3:  'cause it makes sense that the publisher would want you to keep you on the
Speaker 3:  website. That it just, it makes sense that people
Speaker 4:  Well and because forever every YouTube video on the internet, you've been
Speaker 4:  able to, you, you hover over it, you click the title and it takes you
Speaker 3:  YouTube, YouTube, YouTube and in particular on phone. You wanna open the
Speaker 3:  YouTube app, there's all this stuff you wanna do, right? I, I hope people
Speaker 3:  know that The Verge is like very pro links. We have links everywhere, like
Speaker 3:  links on the homepage all the time that's on our fault. It is a YouTube decision
Speaker 3:  to disable those links and if we want to re-enable them, we
Speaker 3:  have to make less money in our YouTube videos you can read the whole story.
Speaker 3:  I was just very annoyed that I spent months being like, can you turn on these
Speaker 3:  links back on? And the answer at the end of the day was a hard no
Speaker 3:  unless we choose to either not use YouTube at all or make less money
Speaker 3:  and I'm not really part of the business side, made the business side make
Speaker 3:  a different decision. But I was like, that sucks. I'm just gonna tell everyone
Speaker 3:  about this. And all the YouTube people just made a very sad face at me.
Speaker 4:  If the internet goes back to every publisher having their own like
Speaker 4:  awful bespoke video player, again, I'm gonna be so angry,
Speaker 4:  like feel however you want about YouTube. It's a good video player. And the
Speaker 4:  internet was filled with bad video players for so long
Speaker 3:  By the way the links worked and we made the more money since 2016.
Speaker 3:  It was all fine. And then in the start of this year they
Speaker 3:  changed it to quote, remove their branding and they think the link
Speaker 3:  to YouTube counts as branding.
Speaker 4:  That's dumb
Speaker 3:  Dumb. Let me tell you how much of Brad I've been for the past
Speaker 3:  two and a half months and the answer was a hard no. I was like, I'm gonna
Speaker 3:  wrap. Is
Speaker 4:  Vimeo still around? Can Vimeo fix this? Sure.
Speaker 3:  Alright, here's a really weird one. I'm obsessed with this one.
Speaker 3:  Instagram is gonna let creators test reels
Speaker 3:  on people that don't follow them. So like, Adamis
Speaker 3:  Harry made this release, you go watch it. It's very interesting as a, as
Speaker 3:  a sociological document of how Adam thinks
Speaker 3:  Instagram creators think about Instagram. Like watch
Speaker 3:  this video through that lens. He's like, I know a lot of you are stressed
Speaker 3:  when you upload a reel that it won't perform. So now we're gonna let you
Speaker 3:  upload a reel. We won't show it to anyone who follows you. We'll show it
Speaker 3:  to people who don't follow you. So you can see how it'll do before
Speaker 3:  you publish it to everyone. And it's like, that's not how,
Speaker 3:  that's not how you should feel about your creative work, right?
Speaker 3:  Like I'm gonna focus group my video
Speaker 3:  before I show it to the people who follow me is a weird thing.
Speaker 3:  It is correct. I think if you're making like advertising, you run the pressure
Speaker 3:  washing business, you're like, is my pressure washing business gonna do better?
Speaker 3:  'cause they made, maybe that makes sense. But that's what I'm saying. Adam
Speaker 3:  thinks everyone is making commercial videos and they're trying to optimize
Speaker 3:  them for reach as opposed to making stuff on Instagram.
Speaker 4:  Richard, what do you make of this? This makes perfect sense to me.
Speaker 5:  I think it explains, like you said, it explains a lot about the way that
Speaker 5:  at Moser and Instagram kind of see the world, especially what we've seen
Speaker 5:  with threads. For example, the way that you could have a post that you, you
Speaker 5:  would put up and it would go viral with strangers but not be
Speaker 5:  seen by the people who follow you and in particular on threads go viral with
Speaker 5:  strangers who don't like what you said it, it was very, very,
Speaker 5:  very good at identifying people who do not like what you said and making
Speaker 5:  sure that they see your posts. But, but this is kind of
Speaker 5:  just the way that they see it. Okay, so you made something, you would love
Speaker 5:  to be seen by whoever, random
Speaker 5:  people, not your community because you would be de you'd be
Speaker 5:  deeming them in your channel If you wanted that.
Speaker 3:  No, but they're saying you don't wanna blow it with the people who follow
Speaker 3:  you so we'll like focus group it with people who don't
Speaker 3:  and then you can decide if that data makes you
Speaker 3:  confident to show the people that follow you and like maybe that that
Speaker 3:  I think that's interesting. I'm like, that is legitimately one of the most
Speaker 3:  novel features a social network has released in forever. Super
Speaker 3:  interesting.
Speaker 5:  I think the, the idea that you kind of can't trust the people who follow
Speaker 5:  you to judge whether or not your content is good is just a really weird way
Speaker 5:  to think about things.
Speaker 3:  And that might permanently down rank you in the algorithm. Like that's what
Speaker 3:  I mean like the, when I say watch this video from the perspective of how
Speaker 3:  does Adam think about creators thinking about Instagram, it's just purely
Speaker 3:  commercial. It's like what you want as a creator is to do
Speaker 3:  great in our algorithm. So here's some tools that will help you do great
Speaker 3:  in the algorithm. And it's like actually what I want as a creator is to
Speaker 3:  make art. Like those are different things,
Speaker 3:  like wildly different things.
Speaker 4:  This is gonna sound more cynical than I mean it, but I would, I would take
Speaker 4:  pretty strong bets on that. More people
Speaker 4:  are interested in making money than making art. Oh
Speaker 3:  Yeah, that, that, that's what I think those platforms just where we are,
Speaker 3:  I think creator platforms are commercialized in that specific way. People
Speaker 3:  wanna win them. And here's a feature and you know, he even says in that video,
Speaker 3:  we made this with creators. Like we've gotten a lot of feedback, they've
Speaker 3:  been working with creators, but there's just something very commercial about
Speaker 3:  everything that's happening there that is very far away from this was a photo
Speaker 3:  sharing website for like me to talk to my friends. Yeah, go watch a video.
Speaker 3:  There's
Speaker 4:  Something really specifically instagramy about this that I find really fascinating.
Speaker 4:  Like Richard, like you were saying. What this says to me is that you are
Speaker 4:  always on a knife's edge of losing everything
Speaker 4:  on Instagram in the way that like on TikTok, everything you make
Speaker 4:  is like a new pull at the slot machine, right? Like Instagram cares so much
Speaker 4:  more about who follows you and who you follow. Then TikTok does.
Speaker 4:  TikTok is just happy to shove stuff into the algorithm and see what works
Speaker 4:  and you'll randomly go viral and sometimes you won't. Instagram lets you
Speaker 4:  build something that is like much more sort of understandable by you
Speaker 4:  as the creator, but also If you make two videos in a row that your audience
Speaker 4:  doesn't like and respond, doesn't respond to, you're toast. Yeah. And that
Speaker 4:  this is like every creator's desperate fear is If you miss
Speaker 4:  once it can, it can kill the whole thing for you. And, and what this is,
Speaker 4:  is ary basically saying, yeah, that's true. So we're gonna give you more
Speaker 4:  tools to make sure you never do that.
Speaker 3:  It's weird. Yeah, it's weird. Speaking of it can all vanish an instant.
Speaker 3:  TikTok lost its court case, challenging the law
Speaker 3:  that would force it to either ban itself or be sold. Lauren
Speaker 3:  Feer wrote up the decision on that case complicated, but the court basically
Speaker 3:  said the Congress made a a national security decision. We're not gonna
Speaker 3:  override that many complicated First Amendment questions. We'll deal with
Speaker 3:  them probably in the quarter episode down the line. But Donald Trump, incoming
Speaker 3:  president of the United States asked about this by Kristen Weer on NBC news
Speaker 3:  and an hour and a half long interview. I'm just gonna read this quote because
Speaker 3:  it's a lot of words from Trump. I use TikTok very successfully in my campaign.
Speaker 3:  I have a man named TikTok Jack. He was very effective obviously because I
Speaker 3:  won the youth vote by 30%, which he did not do, but whatever. I just wanted
Speaker 3:  to say TikTok jack. Anyway, TikTok
Speaker 4:  Jack email us, I need to know everything about you.
Speaker 3:  And then he said, I use TikTok So I can't really, you know, I can't
Speaker 3:  totally hate it. It was very effective. But I will say this, If you do that
Speaker 3:  meaning ban it, something else will come along and take its place. And maybe
Speaker 3:  that's unfair. And what the judge actually said was, you can't have Chinese
Speaker 3:  companies, they have the right to ban it If you can prove that Chinese companies
Speaker 3:  own it. That's what the judge actually said. She has to follow up. She said,
Speaker 3:  well you protect TikTok. And he said, I'm gonna try and make it so that other
Speaker 3:  companies don't become an even bigger monopoly. It's specifically what he
Speaker 3:  means is Facebook. He has often complained that Facebook would just become
Speaker 3:  a bigger monopoly if TikTok is banned. And then during the campaign,
Speaker 3:  he obviously said to a bunch of young people, I'll protect TikTok, Biden
Speaker 3:  wants to ban TikTok, I'll protect it. This is in my mind a massive walk back.
Speaker 3:  Right? All he is saying is, I don't wanna face a monopoly, not I will protect
Speaker 3:  bite dance owning TikTok in America. And I am,
Speaker 3:  I'm just betting, I think we, we've done this a million times to David, like
Speaker 3:  who's gonna buy TikTok because that's the out, the out is
Speaker 3:  he negotiates a deal for Amazon or Walmart or
Speaker 3:  Subway to buy TikTok. There you go.
Speaker 3:  And he gets to say he saved it. I made a great deal to save TikTok.
Speaker 3:  Aren't you proud of me? I'm doing what I said I would do. And I am, I just,
Speaker 3:  you can watch the clip. We have it on the website. It feels very much like
Speaker 3:  that is the door he's opening
Speaker 4:  I think. I mean it's it's it's the escape hatch, right? It's, it's the closest
Speaker 4:  thing he's gonna find to a win-win at the end of this he gets a, he gets
Speaker 4:  an America first win. He gets TikTok to still be here.
Speaker 4:  He gets to like poke a knife at Mark Zuckerberg
Speaker 3:  Times running out though B goes into effect on January 19th, TikTok has
Speaker 3:  filed with the Supreme Court to appeal. We'll see what happens.
Speaker 3:  Notably January 19th is the day before January 20th,
Speaker 3:  which is when he takes office. So
Speaker 4:  Wait, Neela and I have have been on the record about what we think is gonna
Speaker 4:  happen many times. Richard, you have to make a prediction right now. What
Speaker 4:  happens on January 19th?
Speaker 5:  Oh,
Speaker 5:  TikTok actually turns into a new app called
Speaker 3:  Talk Tick
Speaker 5:  Something. It won't be, it won't be owned in China. Americans be owned in
Speaker 5:  like Malaysia or something like.
Speaker 5:  But you know by a very mysterious company that just happened to come into
Speaker 5:  a lot of money, who knows where it came
Speaker 3:  From. Next one. Chris Welch reviewed the Sonos Arc Ultra.
Speaker 3:  He says the hardware is great, particularly the new transducers from
Speaker 3:  mate that's a company in Sonos bought to make smaller transducers and make
Speaker 3:  more base loves those app is still
Speaker 3:  little, little something. Richard, what do you think?
Speaker 5:  I don't know. I mean it's, it's Sonos and they still have the problem of
Speaker 5:  the app that they messed up and made everyone mad. So how's
Speaker 5:  that going?
Speaker 3:  Medium? I, I would say the answer is medium
Speaker 3:  but I will say that as a soundbar seems very cool
Speaker 3:  If I, Chris was basically like this is worth upgrading. Which upgrading
Speaker 3:  from one expensive soundbar to another expensive soundbar is almost
Speaker 3:  not like no one has that thought. Like I'm a person who
Speaker 3:  likes to buy speakers and I'm never like I should upgrade soundbar like
Speaker 3:  and Chris thought it was worth upgrading, which is fascinating. So hopefully,
Speaker 3:  hopefully this is the beginning of the turnaround. This was big news this
Speaker 3:  week. GM shut down the cruise Robo taxii service laid
Speaker 3:  off a bunch of people. The former CEO of cruise just flat out
Speaker 3:  posted GM is a stupid company
Speaker 3:  which is great but it feels like
Speaker 4:  Think already used was dummies, which I like very much. Dummies is a, is
Speaker 4:  a surprisingly powerful. That's powerful mean thing to say to somebody. I
Speaker 3:  Know what David, there's just like a lot of action in this world and obviously
Speaker 3:  GM is like up and down. What do you, what do you think is going on here?
Speaker 4:  I think it, it just is starting to seem like
Speaker 4:  all of these car companies got out over their skis
Speaker 4:  on technological revolutions, right? There was the sense that
Speaker 4:  EVs and self-driving were gonna happen really fast
Speaker 4:  and that they were going to be immediately mainstream and they were gonna
Speaker 4:  be become a big business. And everybody got really excited about the
Speaker 4:  idea of robo taxis because then you have a really interesting like
Speaker 4:  diversified business from your own vehicles.
Speaker 4:  Like you can see how they get there,
Speaker 4:  but we're not there. And I and like unless you're Tesla and
Speaker 4:  people just keep giving you stock price money
Speaker 4:  with which to have weird ideas about where to go from here,
Speaker 4:  you're still fundamentally running a car business which is not getting higher
Speaker 4:  margin, it's not getting less complex. You
Speaker 4:  still have to make the things that people are buying now and it just feels
Speaker 4:  like one by one these car companies are starting to say, okay we,
Speaker 4:  we made these big giant future bets that just aren't coming true as quickly
Speaker 4:  as we thought and we just have to get out of it. I also think
Speaker 4:  a lot of people who cover this space more closely than I do think there is
Speaker 4:  something weird going on with this one in particular that the way
Speaker 4:  GM is handling this suggests that something else is going on inside of cruise.
Speaker 4:  That it basically just like pulled the plug all at once.
Speaker 4:  Which is a very odd thing to do when you're this kind of company that is
Speaker 4:  this invested in cruise. But the macro thing
Speaker 4:  actually kinda makes sense to me. It's just everybody made a bet
Speaker 4:  10 years ago now that they thought was gonna be true in five years and now
Speaker 4:  looks like it might be more like 25. I
Speaker 3:  Think it's just hard to lose money the way Google has chosen to lose money
Speaker 3:  on Waymo for this whole time. Yeah, right. I mean that's just Google's like,
Speaker 3:  we're just gonna lose money until this thing can make it through Phoenix.
Speaker 3:  Alright, we're gonna keep losing money until we can make it through Austin.
Speaker 3:  And it's just like,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, GM just doesn't, literally doesn't have that money. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  It's just not a thing. Richard, you're the one who put quantum computing
Speaker 3:  on this list. Google reveals quantum computing chip with breakthrough achievements.
Speaker 3:  Tell me, tell me why this one made Richard happy. 'cause most of the other
Speaker 3:  stuff did not.
Speaker 5:  I fully understand quantum computing. I understand everything about
Speaker 5:  it. Actually the quantum computing chip Richard is
Speaker 4:  Currently both here is called not here.
Speaker 5:  I, as I've said many times, my coin RJCC coin is quantum locked. It
Speaker 5:  is both launched and mint and premin at all times. That's how it works. That's
Speaker 5:  how quantum works. That's what we do here at RJCC coin. And we're gonna do
Speaker 5:  it on Willow because it can perform a task in five minutes that will take
Speaker 5:  a supercomputer 10 septillion years to complete, which may be
Speaker 5:  evidence that we live in a simulation or a multiverse
Speaker 5:  maybe, or maybe not. I don't really know what any of these words mean, but
Speaker 5:  it happened. They have a chip, they're doing a thing and now they're trying
Speaker 5:  to find a, basically, now that they've done this thing, they're trying to
Speaker 5:  find something to do with it that you will actually find the use for. So
Speaker 5:  they could prove how fast. It's because right now all the stuff they can
Speaker 5:  do is theoretical.
Speaker 3:  The answer is breaking crypto
Speaker 5:  RJCC coin.
Speaker 3:  That's what's gonna happen.
Speaker 5:  You're already in, its quantum you, you are already in it.
Speaker 3:  You already have
Speaker 4:  It. I have three very brief things to say about this whole thing. One, everybody
Speaker 4:  should read the research paper that Google did because even
Speaker 4:  Google's own researchers are basically like it, we, this thing we did is
Speaker 4:  cool, but I don't know what it is that we just did here.
Speaker 3:  They're like, that's all quantum computing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They're like, we did an amazing unprecedented
Speaker 4:  mathematical calculation that no one cares about and has no bearing on the
Speaker 4:  real world. Like they, they say that like, it's amazing that we
Speaker 4:  did it. We don't know why we did it or what it actually accomplishes. And
Speaker 4:  then they're like, the main thing that we've solved
Speaker 4:  here in our real breakthrough is that we've made it make fewer errors.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, like, like imagine if your computer was just like,
Speaker 4:  sometimes when you try to move a file, it just
Speaker 4:  explodes. But now our computer does that less. It still does it,
Speaker 3:  It's very good. It's less. I'm just saying the the main purpose of quantum
Speaker 3:  computing is gonna be to break cryptography in specific ways. Get
Speaker 3:  ready. Yeah, get ready.
Speaker 4:  But then the third thing is that they just very casually are like, this might
Speaker 4:  be evidence that we're living in a simulation and that's just like the end
Speaker 4:  of a, they just, they don't address that anymore. They just say it.
Speaker 3:  All right, here's the last one, which is pure evidence. We live in a simulation.
Speaker 3:  You can now buy Hyundai on Amazon.
Speaker 3:  It's very weird. You could, you like, it's very weird to go on
Speaker 3:  Amazon and see something listed for a price of $67,000,
Speaker 3:  but there's no one click buy. It's start the, the button is like start now
Speaker 3:  and then you get kicked to a dealer. And I feel like we're, we have to buy
Speaker 3:  a car to test out if the dealer actually plays ball.
Speaker 4:  Wait, that's less exciting. So I was really hoping there was gonna be like
Speaker 4:  an Amazon warehouse somewhere that's just full of cars.
Speaker 3:  That's Carvana, right? There's the, the vending machine.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, the car vending machine.
Speaker 3:  This is, they're, they're, I think they're just doing some pricing games
Speaker 3:  with Hyundai, right? Where Hyundai sets a price, Amazon sets a price and
Speaker 3:  the dealer just delivers a car and everyone gets a cut and is happy. But
Speaker 3:  there are still car dealers involved and I assure you at some
Speaker 3:  point they're gonna be like, and we've, we've marked this one up. We filled
Speaker 3:  the tires with nitrogen. So now that's an extra $6,000. Like that's car dealer
Speaker 3:  stuff, right? If anyone wants to buy a car on Amazon and tell us
Speaker 3:  how it goes. I'm dying to know If you just want to cut me a check for
Speaker 3:  $65,000 so we can buy on Amazon,
Speaker 3:  we'll accept that money as well. But I'm kind of dying to do this 'cause
Speaker 3:  I wanna see if the dealers play ball just,
Speaker 4:  This is so bizarre. It's weird man. Amazon will give you a $2,300 gift card
Speaker 4:  If you buy a car through Amazon.
Speaker 3:  It's the future man.
Speaker 4:  It's like kind of like a tax break, but it isn't,
Speaker 3:  The weird thing is the car only works
Speaker 3:  on Kindles in that,
Speaker 5:  But I want, I want them to link up to bring a trailer So I can just go on
Speaker 5:  Amazon like somebody's more sell XR four ti I is up there. I'm just like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, buy it now. And then it shows up at the house the next day and I have
Speaker 5:  to explain that that's what we need.
Speaker 3:  They just, they
Speaker 4:  Bring you the whole thing and then the delivery driver just hands you the
Speaker 4:  keys and walks away.
Speaker 3:  My cousin in New Jersey has absolutely impulse bought a car and bring a trailer
Speaker 3:  and had like a 1980s Mercedes roll up in his driveway
Speaker 3:  and his his wife is like, what's going on here?
Speaker 3:  But you can absolutely, I've been so pissed. Impulse by a car and bring a
Speaker 3:  trailer. That's a real thing that happens. All right, we gotta get outta
Speaker 3:  here. This is a great one, Richard. Thanks for being here. And I wanna call
Speaker 3:  out one story, which is maybe my favorite story of the month
Speaker 3:  so far. Christian Radkey, our creative director and Amelia Hall
Speaker 3:  kras, our photographer went to Pantone's launch of the Color of the Year,
Speaker 3:  which is called Mocha Moose, which is brown. So they went to a party for
Speaker 3:  the color brown. Christian was horrified 'cause she was accidentally wore
Speaker 3:  brown on that day, but then she got to the party, everyone else was wearing
Speaker 3:  brown. It's like a perfect VERGE story. Everything's great about it. Go read
Speaker 3:  that story. The photos are amazing. That's it. That's for cha. Rock and Roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and Vox Media podcast network. Our show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Liam James, will Poor and Eric Gomez. And that's it. We'll
Speaker 1:  see you next week.