# Transcript
ID: d755484f-2a3c-4318-8a86-88df205d087a
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5987074157053599148/-5831739028726032752/s93290-US-4452s-1716162640.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of tandem OLEDs:
The Verge’s David Pierce and Chris Welch discuss the new iPad Pros with an OLED screen, Sonos’ controversial new app, and Sonos’ leaked headphones.
Apple iPad Pro (2024) review: the best kind of overkill
The new Apple iPad Air is great — but it's not the one to get
The new Sonos app is missing a lot of features, and people aren’t happy
Sonos Ace headphones will have magnetic ear cushions and 30-hour battery life
The Verge’s Will Poor buys a bunch of broken iPhones on eBay, and pits the Apple Store against independent repair techs.
Jet City Device Repair
iFixit’s iPhone 8 charge port repair guide
Hugh Jeffreys’ iPhone 12 investigation
Apple’s plan to allow used parts in iPhone repairs
David answers a question from the Vergecast Hotline about why some people think the iPad should be a Macbook replacement.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (28 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Tandem Mo Lead. I'm your
Speaker 2:  friend David Pierce, and I am outdoors at a coffee shop
Speaker 2:  testing iPads. I try when I review devices to use them the
Speaker 2:  way that people use them. So that means like trying to do work, playing
Speaker 2:  games using the pencil, even though I'm a terrible artist. But I feel like
Speaker 2:  for me, when I think about the iPad, the single most like
Speaker 2:  charming, romantic iPad use case you hear for the iPad
Speaker 2:  is the people who just bring their iPad to a coffee shop, get a cup of
Speaker 2:  coffee, sit and do the Sunday crossword. I love it. That's what iPads are
Speaker 2:  for. So I am here, I have coffee, I have the iPad Pro, I have
Speaker 2:  the iPad Air, and I have a ham and cheese croissant and I'm gonna do the
Speaker 2:  crossword. I have a Monday crossword on the iPad Pro. I have a Sunday crossword
Speaker 2:  on the iPad air. I'm worried that I'm gonna kill the battery on the air before
Speaker 2:  I finish the crossword, not because the air's battery life is bad, but because
Speaker 2:  I'm very bad at Sunday crosswords, it's gonna be something. But anyway, we
Speaker 2:  have a lot coming up on the show today we're gonna talk to Chris Welch about
Speaker 2:  ole screens on the iPads. We're gonna talk about Sonos because there's a
Speaker 2:  lot of stuff going on with Sonos. We just have a lot to catch up on with
Speaker 2:  Chris. So we're gonna do that. We're also gonna talk about Right to Repair
Speaker 2:  Will Poor our producer, as you've heard a few times on this show, has been
Speaker 2:  deep in the right to repair world over the last few months. And this time
Speaker 2:  he has a really fun different kind of update on what it means
Speaker 2:  for us, the device owners and users when we can actually have
Speaker 2:  them repaired in new ways. Super fun story. Then we're gonna get to the hotline.
Speaker 2:  Like I said, lots to do in this episode. All that is coming up in just a
Speaker 2:  second. But seriously, I have a lot of cross wording to do and I only have
Speaker 2:  this one cup of coffee and not one croissant. So it's possible
Speaker 2:  it's not gonna happen, but I'm going for it. Wish me luck. This is The Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  See you in a sec.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. All right, I crushed the Monday crossword,
Speaker 2:  just crushed it top to bottom like eight minutes. Nailed it. Everything was
Speaker 2:  great. And then I did so badly on the Sunday crossword that I gave up.
Speaker 2:  Almost immediately, my mom can just sort of sit down with a pen and
Speaker 2:  do the Sunday crossword. And I think it's remarkable. It's like watching
Speaker 2:  somebody who's really good at Excel or PowerPoint or something, just sort
Speaker 2:  of use their tool. Like somebody who knows all the keyboard shortcuts for
Speaker 2:  Photoshop. I am not one of those people. I found a bunch of words I had never
Speaker 2:  heard before in the clues and was like, this isn't going to happen. So I
Speaker 2:  gave up, I came home. Here we are, let's get into the show. I don't know
Speaker 2:  If you noticed it yet, but it's kind of officially become gadget season
Speaker 2:  over the last couple of weeks. We had a quiet couple of months there, but
Speaker 2:  now it's developer conference time. Graduations are happening. So there's
Speaker 2:  deals everywhere. Back to school starts shockingly soon.
Speaker 2:  Everybody's got stuff they wanna sell you for Christmas that is somehow already
Speaker 2:  coming out, even though it's May, it's just gonna be a deluge
Speaker 2:  of gear for the next few months. And to be clear, that is awesome news.
Speaker 2:  But this week there are two particular gadgety topics that I'm especially
Speaker 2:  interested in. I wanna talk OLED screens now that I've reviewed the new iPad
Speaker 2:  Pro. And I wanna talk Sonos because a lot has been happening and
Speaker 2:  Sonos world the last couple of weeks. Some of it exciting and some of it
Speaker 2:  extremely not exciting. And there is no one better to talk about either of
Speaker 2:  those things with than the verges. Chris Welch. Hi Chris. Hello. We
Speaker 2:  haven't done this in a while. It's like, no, no. We have a lot to catch up
Speaker 2:  on. We haven't subjected anybody to terrible microphones in a while.
Speaker 5:  Oh yes, we're very overdue on that. Yeah, we
Speaker 2:  Are. We have a bunch to catch up on. Basically two big things I wanna talk
Speaker 2:  about while we're here. I wanna talk a little about iPads and then I wanna
Speaker 2:  talk a lot about Sonos. But let's start with the iPads and I wanna talk to
Speaker 2:  you in particular because you were very intrigued from the beginning
Speaker 2:  with the new iPad Pro. Tell me why.
Speaker 5:  I just use the iPad Pro quite a lot, honestly, for work,
Speaker 5:  for photo retouching, for lots of stuff, there's no device quite like it
Speaker 5:  among like all the gadgets that I have, say like the new 13 inch model has
Speaker 5:  definitely caught my interest. It looks kind of samey, but
Speaker 5:  also much nicer at the same time, which I can appreciate.
Speaker 2:  That's kind of the story of the iPad. Like exactly samey, but much nicer
Speaker 2:  in a way I can appreciate is like a perfect summation of the whole review
Speaker 2:  I wrote of the iPad Pro.
Speaker 5:  Hey, I mean you've held it, you've used it for a while now. What do you,
Speaker 5:  what are your, your thoughts? What's your takeaway?
Speaker 2:  I mean it's, it's exactly that at this point for me. Right? And I think part
Speaker 2:  of the reason I'm curious for your thoughts is I, you're more of an OLED
Speaker 2:  expert than I am, so I'm curious how you read it. But my takeaway so far
Speaker 2:  has been that in a certain way, this is like the platonic ideal of an
Speaker 2:  iPad. Like it's very powerful, it's very thin, it's very light. Like I
Speaker 2:  don't know how you'd spec this thing better than it is currently specked.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And yet I feel like that has increased my enjoyment of the iPad Pro
Speaker 2:  by like 1%. It's like the iPad's just really good and
Speaker 2:  it's been really good for a really long time. And now here we are. But you,
Speaker 2:  again, part of the reason I wanted to talk to you about this is when Apple
Speaker 2:  talks about like who uses the iPad? They like literally describe Chris
Speaker 2:  Welch, right? Yeah. Like do some work tasks, lot of photo retouching.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's like, it's a great sort of creative canvas and I feel like you
Speaker 2:  use it more fully than most people I know. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  this is again where the OLED comes in. Like for you as a photographer and
Speaker 2:  person who spends a lot of time with photos, what does this new screen
Speaker 2:  do for you?
Speaker 5:  I mean the brightness is pretty much the same as the prior one, but there's
Speaker 5:  no more blooming, which is nice. So you've got those, you know, perfect OLED
Speaker 5:  blacks and whatnot. I haven't seen it that much in person, but I'm,
Speaker 5:  I'm certain there are gonna be like a bunch of people who like obsess over
Speaker 5:  like, you know, like the uniformity of the screen. Like there are these forum
Speaker 5:  posts where people go into a dark room with their iPhone and like load up
Speaker 5:  like a gray screen and like see like how uniform it is. Like as one
Speaker 5:  side, like slightly warmer and like people like obsess over like the
Speaker 5:  smallest panel like issues. So that's gonna be like a whole new wave with
Speaker 5:  this one I'm sure once they actually get out to customers yet
Speaker 2:  There's just so much of it to look at now. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Two old panels that's kind of cool. But yeah, I, I don't get
Speaker 5:  the whole fitness thing. Like I wish they had like just put more battery.
Speaker 5:  They've, they've said 10 hours for years and years and years at this point.
Speaker 5:  Like that's true like when you use it as an iPad, but like once you like
Speaker 5:  do like laptop, laptop tasks with it, you're not getting 10 hours anymore.
Speaker 5:  So I wish they'd kept the same thickness as before but added more battery.
Speaker 5:  But we said that about their stuff all the time, so I know
Speaker 2:  It's been true for so many years at this point. Yeah. And I actually think
Speaker 2:  I have found that argument somewhat compelling over the years because
Speaker 2:  I think in most cases thinner, genuinely sort of is better in a lot of cases
Speaker 2:  and especially lighter is better for the iPad.
Speaker 5:  It's lighter especially. Yeah. But
Speaker 2:  I think at this point we might have tipped to, I would actually take slightly
Speaker 2:  heavier. It's so light and so thin, like it feels
Speaker 2:  amazing. Yeah. But then I pick up last year's pro and that
Speaker 2:  also felt great. I still have zero complaints about it even compared to this
Speaker 2:  new one. Yeah. So I'm like just if, if I were to hand back a little bit of
Speaker 2:  that thickness and weight and we can get rid of the camera bump and and
Speaker 2:  more battery. Yeah. I think I'd make that trade I had. But yeah, we've been
Speaker 2:  asking for that trade for years now. I don't think we're ever gonna get it.
Speaker 5:  How's the keyboard?
Speaker 2:  Oh dude, it's, it's so good.
Speaker 5:  They got rid of my favorite smart keyboard folio. I know. So I'm very upset
Speaker 5:  about that. I'm hoping it'll still work. Like I haven't tried it so maybe
Speaker 5:  it'll still work.
Speaker 2:  I have to confess, I have zero feelings about the smart keyboard folio. I
Speaker 2:  just, just none at all. Why? Why tell me all of your feelings.
Speaker 2:  Because it
Speaker 5:  Was like a perfect on the go keyboard. It was lightweight, so lightweight
Speaker 5:  and like the keyboard was like very mediocre. But like it was there when
Speaker 5:  you needed it and when it wasn't, you would just like flip it behind and
Speaker 5:  use the iPad for other stuff. Whereas with the magic keyboard, you're just
Speaker 5:  constantly like taking it off, putting it on, taking it off, putting it on.
Speaker 5:  There's no natural like secondary mode. And so I wish there was like
Speaker 5:  a, some kind of keyboard accessory that had that same kind of
Speaker 5:  versatility.
Speaker 2:  That is fair. I will give you that. The magic keyboard now, even though it's
Speaker 2:  lighter is still heavy. Yeah. And it like doubles the size of the iPad
Speaker 2:  essentially. And the thing I liked about the Folio, the folio was the one
Speaker 2:  you could actually pull the keyboard off and just have the case be a
Speaker 2:  kickstand, right? No. Oh that wasn't that one. See there's so many accessories.
Speaker 2:  How am I supposed to keep all of these straight?
Speaker 5:  But no, the Foley would just fold behind and so you'd like hold the iPad
Speaker 5:  and like the keys would be in your fingers, which was kind of strange. But
Speaker 5:  you know, I got used to all of it. It was quirky, it was made terribly. Like
Speaker 5:  that material they use, it just got awful. But like, you know, the keyboard
Speaker 5:  felt so nice and it was like waterproof and had a lot of benefits.
Speaker 5:  I mean, you know, it's not as nice as the magic keyboard by any means. But
Speaker 5:  $300 for a keyboard in any, any context as kind of silly.
Speaker 5:  Oh,
Speaker 2:  It's, it's lunacy. I mean, and, and I continue to be in a, a
Speaker 2:  hard position with all of this iPad stuff of like, if I recommend that
Speaker 2:  you buy an iPad, I'm basically saying you should buy an iPad Pro
Speaker 2:  plus a pencil Pro plus the new magic keyboard. And at this point I've just
Speaker 2:  recommended like $1,800 worth of gadgets to you.
Speaker 5:  What size iPad Pro
Speaker 2:  Though? I am personally forever a fan of the 11 inch, like the 13
Speaker 2:  feels great this year. It's, it's much more wield able than
Speaker 2:  it was. Yeah. But I still for my own uses
Speaker 2:  the 11 inches, it's the one, the keyword's a little smaller but I can hold
Speaker 2:  the thing a lot better. It's a little, just more manageable
Speaker 2:  for me personally. But I would imagine for you the 13 inch is is the only
Speaker 2:  one.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, just that bigger canvas. Like I love those removes of like a 15 inch
Speaker 5:  iPad and like a 16 inch iPad. Gimme that tomorrow. I'll absolutely get that.
Speaker 5:  So yeah, just make it bigger and bigger and I'm, I'm here for it. But yeah
Speaker 5:  I can see a case for the 11 especially now 'cause the screen is the same,
Speaker 5:  the OLED on the 13 inch. So yeah
Speaker 2:  The the one last thing on the OLED and then let's switch and talk about Sonos.
Speaker 2:  This whole tandem ole idea, you've been covering the TV world
Speaker 2:  for forever. There's been this sort of march of ole in those devices forever
Speaker 2:  ole in gigantic TVs. It's getting a little cheaper and a little better. Where
Speaker 2:  does what Apple's doing fit into kind of the overall ole
Speaker 2:  universe for you?
Speaker 5:  It seems pretty innovative. Like there aren't too many TVs that do that at
Speaker 5:  all. So I think like their thinking is that like two OLEDs can get brighter
Speaker 5:  and like stay safe longer. Whereas like If you push like a single ole panel
Speaker 5:  that hard for years and years. It might not kind of age as well. So it seems
Speaker 5:  like a smart way of going about it. I haven't seen it in person. I'm sure
Speaker 5:  people are gonna do like all, all sorts of like closeups and you know, like
Speaker 5:  deep dives on the tech there. But it's pretty cool. You know, it's a very
Speaker 5:  aptly thing to kind of put that in the iPad. So
Speaker 2:  Do you think if this is the sort of thing that works, we might start to see
Speaker 2:  at other places like a tandem o led television, is that a thing that makes
Speaker 2:  any sense over time?
Speaker 5:  I don't think it makes sense for the TVs 'cause they're already like pretty
Speaker 5:  bright like past like 2000 hits these days so they don't really need that
Speaker 5:  up of laptops. Maybe I could see it being a thing certainly. So we'll see
Speaker 5:  how it goes and see if it has like burn or any kind of like negative effects
Speaker 5:  over time. Yeah. But yeah for now it just looks very pretty so.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Yeah the, the timeline of all of this is gonna be interesting. Like
Speaker 2:  I've, I've had the iPads for six days now and you can do a lot
Speaker 2:  with an iPad in six days. Especially like we've used a lot of iPads for a
Speaker 2:  long time. But the two biggest questions I have are a, are there going to
Speaker 2:  be burn in issues on this screen because it's OLED and Apple's theory about
Speaker 2:  why that might not happen tracks at least sort of philosophically but
Speaker 2:  like we just don't know. And in six months it'll be really interesting to
Speaker 2:  see. And then the other one is, is literally just like breaking and bending.
Speaker 2:  Like every single morning I take this thing out of my backpack
Speaker 2:  or my suitcase as it was over the weekend or just like pick it off off my
Speaker 2:  desk and just look at it. I'm like, did it bend? Are we good? And so far
Speaker 2:  it's fine. So far it's fine. But like am I gonna be shocked? I saw
Speaker 5:  Some story that there's some kind of like new steel like rib inside there
Speaker 5:  for like added strength. So it's got some kinda like new component in there
Speaker 5:  to keep it from bending ideally. That's awesome. 'cause we started that whole
Speaker 5:  like news cycle back in like 2018 when they were shipping bent outta the
Speaker 5:  box, which was was pretty lousy.
Speaker 2:  I'm sure there are those, those pictures of the bent ones still. Yeah like
Speaker 2:  haunt the memories of people at Apple. It's good stuff. Yeah. Alright,
Speaker 2:  let's talk Sonos for a little bit. 'cause Sonos has been, I would say largely
Speaker 2:  because of you very in the news the last couple of weeks. Let, let's talk
Speaker 2:  about new products and then I wanna talk about the app and the kerfuffle
Speaker 2:  around the app.
Speaker 5:  Oh the app.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna get to that. But the, the big new thing that you have revealed
Speaker 2:  is coming and that has been kind of a semi-open secret for a while is coming
Speaker 2:  is the, the long awaited Sonos headphones. Tell me about the headphones.
Speaker 5:  They're called the Sonos Ace. There are photos on the site, they look very
Speaker 5:  nice. They seem pretty high-end. They're gonna cost around four
Speaker 5:  $50 I believe is the rumor. They're gonna have like noise cancellation,
Speaker 5:  all the usual high-end headphones stuff. They're gonna do tie-ins to your
Speaker 5:  home theater. So If, you own like a Sonos arc. You'll be able to hear TV
Speaker 5:  audio and do like spatial audio with head tracking for Atmos
Speaker 5:  content. And so yeah, Sonos wants this to be their next big hit 'cause they
Speaker 5:  kind of need a hit. They've had like a few soft quarters and people aren't
Speaker 5:  buying their speakers as much as they were during Covid Lockdowns and all
Speaker 5:  that. So they really need some kind of pick me up and they're really hoping
Speaker 5:  that this is gonna be that.
Speaker 2:  So I can imagine a world in which Sonos
Speaker 2:  basically just says we're very good at making audio products,
Speaker 2:  we've made home audio products, now we're making a different kind of audio
Speaker 2:  product. Is there more to the advantage of buying headphones from
Speaker 2:  Sonos other than just, they will probably be very good because Sonos is
Speaker 2:  making them. Like what, what in theory do you think people gain by buying
Speaker 2:  Sonos headphones as a Sonos thing?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think we'll see what they say once they actually like, you know,
Speaker 5:  actually announce them. But yeah, I think it's gonna be just a story of,
Speaker 5:  you know, we built our brand on audio. We know audio, but it's hard to compete
Speaker 5:  with like Bose in terms of like noise cancellations come out of the gate
Speaker 5:  and like challenge Bose in terms of a NC or Apple, you know, as the best
Speaker 5:  transparency mode on the market and like B and it sounds like Sonos thinks
Speaker 5:  that like they have the best everything. So we'll see how that actually
Speaker 5:  bears out in practice. But in terms of like what they'll offer some kind
Speaker 5:  of time in with home theater, I don't think they're gonna play like wifi
Speaker 5:  audio or anything like that. So it's gonna be somewhat limited
Speaker 5:  the tie into the Sonos ecosystem but, we'll, we'll see. I don't know. They
Speaker 5:  look cool and they had to put out this new app because of the headphones
Speaker 5:  so that's why there was a rush to get the new app
Speaker 5:  out and the Sonos community has not received it that
Speaker 5:  warmly.
Speaker 2:  Alright fine. You wanna talk about the app? Let's talk about the app. It's
Speaker 2:  fine. We waited long enough. Let's talk about the app. Yeah, so the story
Speaker 2:  as I understand it and I confess I am a Sonos user to the extent that I have
Speaker 2:  Sonos speakers and I play them through the Spotify app.
Speaker 2:  So I, I have almost no knowledge of the Sonos app except that it
Speaker 2:  is the thing I use to set up my Sonos speakers and then essentially ignore
Speaker 2:  because I just use Spotify, what has happened with this app? What is, what
Speaker 2:  is going on here?
Speaker 5:  So they redesigned the whole thing to make it faster and easier to get to
Speaker 5:  your speakers and just like change settings and search for music. So it's
Speaker 5:  got a whole new coat of paint but they've taken out like many, many
Speaker 5:  features like local music search is gone. You can't like edit
Speaker 5:  your queue like If, you make like a playlist. You can't do something that
Speaker 5:  basic until June they're saying that'll come back. So people are gonna have
Speaker 5:  to wait a month for some pretty basic,
Speaker 2:  The Q thing is is wild to me. Yeah, I think I, I wanna come back to the local
Speaker 2:  music thing because I, I have both questions and a lot of thoughts about
Speaker 2:  that but, but I honestly feel like one of the
Speaker 2:  core benefits of a Sonos system Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Is the way the queue works. Yeah. And it's a thing people love. It's a thing
Speaker 2:  they like to manage. It's a very good system and it is
Speaker 2:  o of all possible features to leave out for Sonos, I would put
Speaker 2:  that like mere last on the list. It's so wild to
Speaker 2:  me that that wasn't here.
Speaker 5:  Yeah it's a music app. Yeah and they took that out. They stuff like
Speaker 5:  sleep timers are gone until like May or June, late May or June. So it's just
Speaker 5:  stuff that's been taken out just so this app could be more, you know, somewhat
Speaker 5:  faster. I think Neli likes it quite a bit. So it depends like how you use
Speaker 5:  your own set. Like some people don't have like, you know, local music to
Speaker 5:  deal with or some people just use airplay to play stuff when there's snow
Speaker 5:  skier. So if they do that then I doubt they even care. But yeah, there are
Speaker 5:  a lot of like downgrades you could say like the accessibility has gotten
Speaker 5:  worse, which is terrible for people who like need those features. So that'll
Speaker 5:  be hopefully fixed by the end of this month. But stuff like that just has
Speaker 5:  people asking like, what the hell was the rush here? Like why didn't you
Speaker 5:  put this out as like a beta option and like have the old app still there
Speaker 5:  alongside it, you know, which are fair questions honestly versus just like
Speaker 5:  forcing everyone onto it right away.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. What is your sense of the backstory there? I think this does seem like
Speaker 2:  a somewhat surprising kind of own goal from Sonos on this
Speaker 2:  front. Like what, what, what is your sense of what's going on there? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I think it's all about the headphones really. That was just kind of strange
Speaker 5:  that they're like putting all this like pressure on a product that no one
Speaker 5:  owns yet. And so they're like making life less convenient for people who
Speaker 5:  have bought their stuff and their speakers just in the name of these ace
Speaker 5:  headphones once they're out.
Speaker 2:  So why do the headphones require this new app? Like the last time they did
Speaker 2:  a big update like this, it was to yeah basically change the whole infrastructure
Speaker 2:  of the system. Right. And that's, that's always gonna be challenging, right?
Speaker 2:  I get that. That is a thing you eventually have to do. It's gonna be messy.
Speaker 2:  I dunno that Sonos handled it perfectly but like I feel like that went fine.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And everybody hemmed and hawed and then kind of got on with their life.
Speaker 2:  This one seems like it just could have been
Speaker 2:  easier and Sonos kind of whiffed it. What is it about the
Speaker 2:  headphones that is forcing all of this?
Speaker 5:  I think they're trying to make it so you can like set them up easier out
Speaker 5:  of the house. You know like most Sonos gear you have to like be be home on
Speaker 5:  your wifi Sure. Before you set it up. Whereas like headphones you don't want
Speaker 5:  have to deal with that. So I guess that was part of the stack that they had
Speaker 5:  to change. But as far as like why a whole new app design was necessary or
Speaker 5:  like if these things just kind of like happen to coincide at some point.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, people are upset very, very mad If you go to the Sonos sub Reddit
Speaker 5:  or their forums they're saying we're listening and like they're like talking
Speaker 5:  to like their customers like on the forums and stuff and they're saying like
Speaker 5:  this is when this feature will come back, this is when this feature will
Speaker 5:  come back. But yeah, I don't know it just seems seems like a very big unforced
Speaker 5:  error that yeah. That they've made here and, and it's kind of shaken, you
Speaker 5:  know, trust in them again after the S one s two thing, which was overblown
Speaker 5:  like you said, like they never like killed any products. They left some
Speaker 5:  of their very oldest devices on the S one platform and like everything else
Speaker 5:  is still supported on S two so that was kind of ugly. But they did it and
Speaker 5:  it was fine. This is just different, it's like a change for the sake of change
Speaker 5:  and I think that's just not going over super well. But yeah, maybe the headphones
Speaker 5:  will come out and like they'll be mind blowing and you know all will be forgiven.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  We'll see, I mean I think part of the reason I'm so hung up on the local
Speaker 2:  music side of this is that it feels like a microcosm of
Speaker 2:  Sonos sort of losing its core audience, right? That like this
Speaker 2:  company has been the company for people who are willing to spend
Speaker 2:  some
Speaker 5:  Of their oldest customers especially
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And who are like willing to spend a lot of money to get really good
Speaker 2:  audio. There was just nothing like it for a really, really long time and
Speaker 2:  people spent a lot of money, they bought into these systems, they did a lot
Speaker 2:  of work to maintain these systems and then it feels like sometimes for good
Speaker 2:  reasons and sometimes for bad reasons and recently for very bad reasons,
Speaker 2:  Sonos has just kind of blown all of that up and it feels like it, it's like
Speaker 2:  when Apple forgets about the Mac Pro for like a decade at a time. It's just
Speaker 2:  like all you have to do is just sort of keep reminding these people that
Speaker 2:  you love them and all that means is just to keep supporting local music.
Speaker 2:  Like just let people upload their MP threes to your thing and there is a
Speaker 2:  set of people on earth who will love you forever.
Speaker 5:  I'm one of those people. Yeah. You
Speaker 2:  Know, and I can't tell if Sonos is like trying hard
Speaker 2:  to push away from those people in the name of like finding a much bigger
Speaker 2:  audience with things like headphones or if it's just screwing up
Speaker 2:  unintentionally. But I, it's, it's just a really odd move to me
Speaker 2:  to look at the people who have had your stuff for damn near 20 years at this
Speaker 2:  point and are like the people who care the most about their music. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And just say, oh we redesigned an app and we have nothing for you. That
Speaker 2:  seems nuts to me.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I don't think it was intentional. I think it was just like they had
Speaker 5:  their, they just like really mixed up their priorities as they were building
Speaker 5:  this app and now they're hearing about it. Obviously there are good parts
Speaker 5:  to this app, like don't get me wrong. So there's a web app now, which is
Speaker 5:  very cool. You can like access your system from like anywhere. And so that
Speaker 5:  wasn't a thing before so that's great. There are other odds and ends like
Speaker 5:  it's faster to like move around your system like access your speakers and
Speaker 5:  stuff like that. But it's just like lots of change all at once And
Speaker 5:  I think like people are fair when they say like you should have just done
Speaker 5:  a beta or had them, you know, side by side or you know, like a preview
Speaker 5:  app for a while just to kind of like ease people in versus like just
Speaker 5:  here's the new app, half the stuff is missing and it'll be back in like two
Speaker 5:  months. So you know, that's never gonna go over well and it hasn't but
Speaker 5:  I think they're learning again their second painful lesson after the S one
Speaker 5:  and S two fiasco and now we're here, so Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Let's hope we'll see where things wind up in like late June. Hopefully it'll
Speaker 5:  be at parody with the old app again. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I mean again I, it's, it's just been, I think I'm really sensitive to it
Speaker 2:  right now because we had Humane and Rabbit both
Speaker 2:  being like, oh don't worry, our products are awful now but they're gonna
Speaker 2:  be so good this summer. And then it was like for Sonos to basically come
Speaker 2:  out and say exactly the same thing, it's just like, oh no, like I've heard
Speaker 2:  this too many times now. Yeah I just don't believe you. And also
Speaker 2:  if that's true, why did you ship it now? Like just,
Speaker 5:  Just
Speaker 2:  Support everything for two months. It'll be fine.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  The other product that you, you scooped is a new Bluetooth speaker coming
Speaker 2:  from Sonos, which is I would say of all of the new Sonos stuff, maybe
Speaker 2:  the one I'm most excited about what's going on there.
Speaker 5:  The room two is coming soon as well. It looks just like the old one. So
Speaker 5:  not much has changed there. Still very small. I have
Speaker 5:  one, I like it fine. I think the move to is my favorite like Sonos overall
Speaker 5:  product that's bigger obviously can't quite travel with it the same way as
Speaker 5:  you can with The Roam. That's
Speaker 2:  The one with the big handle, right? Yeah that thing is a brick but boy it
Speaker 2:  sounds good.
Speaker 5:  Good. That's a brick. Yeah but the room was like a perfect shower speaker
Speaker 5:  like you were saying so that could be an option for you. But I think like,
Speaker 5:  you know, it's just pretty samey and there's a new button on the back so
Speaker 5:  you can like pair it easily. Whereas before again you had to like be on your
Speaker 5:  home wifi so you could set up a Bluetooth speaker. It's like what are we
Speaker 5:  doing here? So now there's a button you can just set it up right away and
Speaker 5:  that'll be simpler. So that's like the main change from the first gen model.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, there were some concerns with like the battery over long term so
Speaker 5:  hopefully they've fixed some of that stuff so it'll last longer. But yeah,
Speaker 5:  it's a tiny little thing. Sounds decent for its size. I think that'll be
Speaker 5:  out sometime this summer as well. So yeah tis the, tis the season for new
Speaker 5:  speakers.
Speaker 2:  I'm curious whether you think Sonos is
Speaker 2:  pushing more towards trying to be a company like Bose that
Speaker 2:  just kind of has a lineup of very good audio products or is gonna keep trying
Speaker 2:  to find a way to like build a whole system. 'cause like the thing that worked
Speaker 2:  for Sonos for so long I feel like was that it got better the more Sonos stuff
Speaker 2:  you used. But then I look at things like the headphones and
Speaker 2:  the Rome and again like any push that Sonos is gonna make
Speaker 2:  to sort of make a true like mainstream product. Yeah. Seems
Speaker 2:  like it pushes up against this idea of like building a beautiful little walled
Speaker 2:  garden system for people who love good audio. Do you think can Sonos
Speaker 2:  be both of those things or is it just going to have to lean
Speaker 2:  into like we just sell audio products the end? I
Speaker 5:  Don't know. I think they certainly can make a very, very good speaker. We've
Speaker 5:  learned that before. Can they like stand toe to toe on headphones with Bose
Speaker 5:  and Apple and Sony and whoever else that remains to be
Speaker 5:  seen. And like there are all these rumors of like a TV streaming device.
Speaker 5:  It's like how, how can Sonos really play in that world and stand out versus
Speaker 5:  Apple TV or Google tv. It's like, can you really like make a
Speaker 5:  statement there? I
Speaker 2:  Forgot about that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's kind of curious to me like what would a Sonos streamer look
Speaker 5:  like and why? So there's just a question of why as they go into the, these
Speaker 5:  new product categories, I'm sure they're gonna have like a great reason for
Speaker 5:  the headphones, you know. But as far as like a TV streamer, I don't really
Speaker 5:  understand like what Sonos could do to really, you know, stand out from the
Speaker 5:  pack. But we'll see. I mean they do wanna build out obviously. So it
Speaker 5:  should be a pretty fascinating next year for the company.
Speaker 2:  It and it does that strategically. I can see the idea of
Speaker 2:  just saying we make very good audio products. Yeah, we would like to make
Speaker 2:  audio products that are accessible to more people. That totally tracks for
Speaker 2:  me. But then I had, I honestly had totally forgotten about the TV streamer
Speaker 2:  thing and there was, but but this is like now all of this is pouring back
Speaker 2:  Sonos trying to be like, we are an operating system company. Like our main
Speaker 2:  thing is the platform, which I feel like is such a fundamental misread of
Speaker 2:  what people like about Sonos, that they've like tolerated crappy
Speaker 2:  apps for so long because the sound is great and now Sonos is being like,
Speaker 2:  forget the sound. It's all about the apps.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I don't know if people wanna tell us to become Roku, but we'll see.
Speaker 5:  We'll see what that looks like. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's a boy I don't want anybody to become Roku right now.
Speaker 2:  All right, so what, what's your sense of when are these headphones coming
Speaker 2:  out? Any, any news?
Speaker 5:  The rumor is June, so it should be pretty soon honestly. So hopefully
Speaker 5:  we'll get a pair and be able to do our tests and review and we'll see how
Speaker 5:  that microphone compares to competition. Yeah, I'm really curious to see
Speaker 5:  how they, like how the soundbar integration works and like the home theater
Speaker 5:  support people love like private audio from the Roku and stuff. And so
Speaker 5:  I think that would be a pretty compelling feature. So yeah, June
Speaker 5:  sometime is the belief and yeah, should know more than,
Speaker 5:  fair
Speaker 2:  Enough. They do look good. The pictures you got, they're like simple.
Speaker 2:  They, they had that sort of like almost a prototype look in a way that I
Speaker 2:  really like. They're sort of undesigned in a very designy way. I'm
Speaker 5:  Intense. Pretty not as heavy as the AirPods and Max thankfully because the
Speaker 5:  AirPods and Max are oof. They're heavy on your head
Speaker 5:  after a while. That's fair. So these will be less heavy than that but yeah
Speaker 5:  they look nice. So good how, how they'll sound we should know in a few weeks.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Alright, well when you get 'em, I'm thinking for the next mic test
Speaker 2:  we're gonna send you in like a cave somewhere and just do the most
Speaker 2:  echoy possible situation we can. Or we're gonna have you test a bunch of
Speaker 2:  mics. It's gonna be a lot of fun.
Speaker 5:  I'm
Speaker 2:  Here for it Until then, thank you Chris. Appreciate it as always.
Speaker 5:  Thank you.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and talk about
Speaker 2:  Right to Repair. We got a fun update for you on that front. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. We've been covering rate to repair a lot on this show
Speaker 2:  over really the last couple of years. And it turns out just in the last couple
Speaker 2:  of months a lot of stuff has been happening. Oregon just passed what is
Speaker 2:  probably the strongest rate to repair Bill we've seen yet, which includes
Speaker 2:  a ban on parts pairing Apple is slowly and somewhat
Speaker 2:  sketchily starting to change some of its repair practices, especially around
Speaker 2:  parked pairing. There's just a lot going on and the right to repair industry
Speaker 2:  is changing really fast. Will pour on. Our team has been looking into this
Speaker 2:  for a while and is now back, I think after breaking several phones
Speaker 2:  will pour. Welcome back.
Speaker 11:  Hi. Thank you. Yeah, I have a growing drawer full
Speaker 11:  of really brutalized iPhones after doing
Speaker 11:  the story and we will get into why, but I, I am now
Speaker 11:  going to be a used iPhone broker myself after all of this,
Speaker 11:  so we'll see how that goes.
Speaker 2:  So what have you been up to?
Speaker 11:  So I have been following all this legislation that you're talking about
Speaker 11:  and the company's changing policies, all this really high level stuff and
Speaker 11:  it was starting to just feel abstract to me. And so
Speaker 11:  as I have been following it all, wanted to just take a break and
Speaker 11:  get some stuff fixed to just see what these repair
Speaker 11:  practices actually look like in real life and see what repair issues
Speaker 11:  bubble up over the course of doing real repairs. So my
Speaker 11:  idea was to just collect a bunch of broken iPhones, take them to the Apple
Speaker 11:  store first for kind of an official diagnosis and then take
Speaker 11:  those same phones with the same problems to an independent repair shop and
Speaker 11:  see what repairs each store offered. How
Speaker 11:  knowledgeable the Apple store was in an independent store was how much the
Speaker 11:  repairs would cost. I just wanted to see what repair
Speaker 11:  advocates are fighting for specifically and why they're fighting so hard
Speaker 11:  for these independent shops. So that was the plan. And for the record, I
Speaker 11:  know a lot of the issues we're gonna talk about here are not unique to Apple,
Speaker 11:  but as we've talked about, apple products are just so ubiquitous that
Speaker 11:  so many of these repair shops literally live or die based on how
Speaker 11:  repairable Apple devices are. And the company has just fought against
Speaker 11:  Repairability so hard for so long that Apple is just the
Speaker 11:  center of this story. So lots of iPhones in this story. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's a good caveat. I forget who it was but somebody a while back said
Speaker 2:  to me, basically Apple is not the only company that
Speaker 2:  matters in right to repair, but none of the other companies cumulative
Speaker 2:  matter as much as Apple does. Yeah. So like it, it is the center of the
Speaker 2:  story feels like exactly the right way to describe it. It's not the whole
Speaker 2:  thing but it is the most thing.
Speaker 11:  Yes. And and every, you know, repair expert I talk to will say the exact
Speaker 11:  same thing and then all the examples they'll use are Apple.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So I love the first task of this, which is that you had to find a way
Speaker 2:  to have a bunch of broken phones. How does one acquire a bunch of broken
Speaker 2:  phones?
Speaker 11:  I try. I mean I like I started with the company Slack, I, I started
Speaker 11:  asking friends and family I, it was like a really weird thing to go looking
Speaker 11:  for. Turns out eBay. The, the answer is eBay. There are 1
Speaker 11:  million phones in that are broken in very specific ways on eBay.
Speaker 2:  What's the lineup that we ended up with?
Speaker 11:  So I saw a ton of broken screens and dead
Speaker 11:  batteries. I wanted to skip those because we know the Apple store will
Speaker 11:  repair those. They've got the prices listed, they have this DIY
Speaker 11:  repair program for those independent shops will do it. That is the most
Speaker 11:  common churn for repairs. So I went looking
Speaker 11:  for, I don't know, slightly more interesting repairs than that. The
Speaker 11:  things that I found, one, I bought a working iPhone eight with a
Speaker 11:  broken charging port. Okay. That I hear happens a lot.
Speaker 11:  We're just gonna call that one the charge port phone. The second one was
Speaker 11:  a, a second gen iPhone SE with a cracked screen that
Speaker 11:  also for some reason the listing said just rebooted itself every
Speaker 11:  few minutes. Oh weird. So that seemed interesting. I we're gonna call that
Speaker 11:  one the boot looper. Okay. And then one wild card that I
Speaker 11:  could not resist buying was a really nice looking iPhone
Speaker 11:  14 pro that the listing said was quote in salt water for a
Speaker 11:  while. I had to see what everyone would say about that one. We're gonna
Speaker 11:  call that one Rusty
Speaker 2:  In saltwater for a while. Feels like a euphemism for how terrible this
Speaker 2:  thing is that I'm now very worried about what's gonna happen to this phone.
Speaker 11:  This is the thing, it looked really nice. It just had this like kind of
Speaker 11:  artful corrosion along the metal rim of it. It actually like, it looked
Speaker 11:  really nice. I was really hoping that I could get it fixed,
Speaker 11:  just that I could use it myself. What,
Speaker 2:  What was the total budget for the broken phones here? What'd you end up spending
Speaker 2:  for these three phones?
Speaker 11:  Too much because I, I fell into the eBay trap. I like want, I like saw
Speaker 11:  these phones and I wanted them because I thought that they would be like
Speaker 11:  fun storytelling devices. The first two were
Speaker 11:  fairly cheap in the, I think I spent 40 bucks on
Speaker 11:  one and Oh okay. 60 on another or something. The 14 pro
Speaker 11:  I think I spent like $75 on. Oh that's
Speaker 2:  Not bad. I mean that's last year's phone. I almost expected it to be significantly
Speaker 2:  more than that actually. Yeah. Alright, so we're, we're a couple hundred
Speaker 2:  dollars in, you've got some deeply busted phones and
Speaker 2:  what step one was you, you said you were gonna take 'em to the Apple store,
Speaker 2:  right?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, step one was just walk into an Apple store. So I, I made an appointment,
Speaker 11:  I showed up at the store with these, these three phones in my bag. I
Speaker 11:  didn't even try to get permission to record at the Apple store 'cause I
Speaker 11:  didn't wanna be like, I'm a journalist doing an experiment. So I, I had
Speaker 11:  to just go in and go out and then just record some voice notes. But I
Speaker 11:  can tell you exactly what the Apple texts said about each one of these phones.
Speaker 11:  So first the iPhone eight with the bad charge port, just not
Speaker 11:  repairable by Apple, it's charge ports are not a thing that they
Speaker 11:  fix. Instead their best offer was
Speaker 11:  $350 for a refurbished iPhone eight if
Speaker 11:  I traded this one in, which didn't make a lot of sense. Walmart
Speaker 11:  sells the same model and the same configuration refurbished for like
Speaker 11:  $125. And then their other option was a
Speaker 11:  new SE for $430. So that's the charge port phone,
Speaker 11:  the rebooting SE two with the cracked screen. I explained what was going
Speaker 11:  on. They did try to run a diagnostic on it, but the phone kept
Speaker 11:  rebooting before the test could finish. So instead they poked around in
Speaker 11:  the settings and they saw that the phone had a third party battery in it.
Speaker 11:  And that was kind of it for them. They decided that must be the culprit.
Speaker 11:  They didn't say why a battery would cause a boot loop. They were just like,
Speaker 11:  ah, third party batteries cause problems. And that was the end of the conversation.
Speaker 11:  So they said that they could replace the battery for $89 but they also said
Speaker 11:  that the screen would shatter when they tried to remove it. So I'd
Speaker 11:  need to pay another 269 for a new display. So grand
Speaker 11:  total for that phone was $358 and
Speaker 11:  fingers crossed it, the battery was actually the problem and that it would
Speaker 11:  iFixit or again I could get a new se. They really, they kept on
Speaker 11:  trying to sell me a new se. So that was that one. And then the, and then
Speaker 11:  the iPhone 14 pro was just a full, nah,
Speaker 11:  the guy checking me in at the store told me that they just don't repair
Speaker 11:  anything with water damage. Which was a little surprising to me because
Speaker 11:  like water damage is a repair category on the Apple
Speaker 11:  repair website. So long story short, that was the Apple store. I was in
Speaker 11:  and out in 10 minutes with zero phones fixed.
Speaker 2:  So on the one hand I'm not shocked by that. On the other hand I'm starting
Speaker 2:  to think what does Apple fix? You know, you mentioned batteries and
Speaker 2:  screens, these are fairly straightforward. Is there a list sort of
Speaker 2:  official or unofficial of the repairs? Apple actually will do
Speaker 2:  at an Apple store.
Speaker 11:  You can't really tell from their website. Whenever I
Speaker 11:  ask an independent repair tech about this, they tell
Speaker 11:  me to just go to the schedule A genius bar visit page because
Speaker 11:  it has these big buttons for selecting the repair that you need. There's
Speaker 11:  a cracked screen button, a dead battery button, camera problems. And they
Speaker 11:  basically say if there isn't a button you can press, then they're not gonna
Speaker 11:  do the repair. So
Speaker 2:  This is a successful case potentially for why there should be other
Speaker 2:  people in the world repairing these things than the people at the Genius
Speaker 2:  Bar. And that's where you went next, right?
Speaker 11:  Yes. Yeah. I basically, I live here in Seattle. I poked around on Yelp.
Speaker 11:  I landed on a place called Jet City Device Repair. They've been around for
Speaker 11:  more than 15 years. They've got a couple locations and the area, they've
Speaker 11:  got good reviews. So I just, I made an appointment to bring my
Speaker 11:  phones in and chat with the owner.
Speaker 12:  Did somebody respond to Julia and let her know that if she's close enough
Speaker 12:  and can make it in by five, we can still take her in? If not, we have plenty
Speaker 12:  of time tomorrow.
Speaker 11:  So the shop was like the opposite of an Apple store. It was a little cramped,
Speaker 11:  a little messy, a little scrappy. There was this cushy front of house
Speaker 11:  where customers can hang out on a couch and wait for the repairs. And in
Speaker 11:  the back were three or so people working at desks
Speaker 11:  that had mats and lights and microscopes and some tools.
Speaker 11:  And then in the back there was a store room with like a million tiny little
Speaker 11:  bagged parts for every major cell phone that you could really name.
Speaker 11:  Jet City's owner Sava Popal brought me back to the store room
Speaker 11:  to check out my phones. So I brought a couple of things to look
Speaker 11:  at. I figure I can just show you what I brought and
Speaker 11:  tell you what the Apple Store said about each of them.
Speaker 12:  That's exciting.
Speaker 11:  So first the charge port phone, the Apple store said it was a non-starter
Speaker 11:  but Jet City fixes charging ports all the time in a lot of cases
Speaker 11:  because the Apple store won't OSH quoted me $90,
Speaker 11:  which is getting kind of close to a similar used phone
Speaker 11:  online, but I don't know, it'll keep one more phone outta the garbage dump.
Speaker 11:  So I, I said go for it. So OSH took the phone and used his
Speaker 11:  microscope to look at the tiny little pins inside the lightning port.
Speaker 11:  And what are you seeing?
Speaker 12:  I am seeing all the pins are damaged. They weren't great
Speaker 12:  to begin with though 'cause they have a little bit of corrosion on them.
Speaker 11:  From what Sava has seen, the Apple stores just aren't built
Speaker 11:  for a repair like this, even though it's a really common one. Instead he
Speaker 11:  says Apple has this wildly over-engineered process
Speaker 11:  for just a few select repairs like screens and batteries.
Speaker 12:  It's like extra with like extra Xs, you know, it's just
Speaker 12:  so much going on. What do you mean by that? They have like, they have this
Speaker 12:  one device that sort of holds the whole
Speaker 12:  phone together so it doesn't move around. There's another device that holds
Speaker 12:  the screen open for you while you're removing the screen. It's like
Speaker 12:  so much going on that you don't really need. And you see my kit is
Speaker 12:  this tiny little thing.
Speaker 11:  His toolbox is one of those pencil cases he used in grade school. I see
Speaker 11:  a toothbrush. I see an Exacto knife.
Speaker 12:  Yeah.
Speaker 11:  So for the repair Sava took two little screws out of the bottom of
Speaker 11:  the phone, then slid a little plastic tool around the edge of the screen
Speaker 11:  and popped it off to reveal the guts of the phone. And then he just starts
Speaker 11:  removing screw after screw from different components to get down to the
Speaker 11:  charging port. So why do you think a charging
Speaker 11:  port is something that is just outside of
Speaker 11:  apple's supported repairs?
Speaker 12:  It's complicated. There are a lot of screws.
Speaker 11:  God, those are tiny.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, they're, they're very small and you don't wanna mix them up because
Speaker 12:  most of the screws are different from each other.
Speaker 11:  Actually just combed through an iFixit repair guide for this model of iPhone.
Speaker 11:  And I counted 14 different sizes and kinds of
Speaker 11:  screws for this charge port repair.
Speaker 12:  You have to remove the entire motherboard to get access to the port. Then
Speaker 12:  the port itself has a bunch of screws.
Speaker 11:  Does it just feel like is just not worth the time
Speaker 11:  and effort if you're Apple?
Speaker 12:  I think they're incentivized to focus on selling rather
Speaker 12:  than repairing. So if they can say, Hey we provide repairs for
Speaker 12:  batteries and screens, then they can say we do provide
Speaker 12:  repairs. But if it's anything else you're just gonna have to buy a new device.
Speaker 12:  They're incentivized to do that because it's a sales
Speaker 12:  conversion.
Speaker 11:  I asked Apple about charge port repairs and Brian Nauman, who
Speaker 11:  is the VP of Apple's repair business, told me that the company does offer
Speaker 11:  them If. you have an iPhone 12 or newer and If, you mail the phone
Speaker 11:  directly into Apple. He didn't explain why they don't work with older phones.
Speaker 11:  Which is interesting because as we got deeper into the repair,
Speaker 11:  we ran into a hint that Apple might not want anyone fixing this part.
Speaker 12:  So this connector, when you remove it, there is
Speaker 12:  a tape. Tiny, tiny, tiny little piece of tape. Well the
Speaker 12:  neoprene actually hides a screw underneath this. So you don't
Speaker 12:  even realize that there's a screw down there. We didn't realize it until
Speaker 12:  like, we couldn't figure out why the board wasn't coming up. Yeah. And
Speaker 12:  these are delicate boards. So If, you don't have experience, you're gonna
Speaker 12:  apply a little bit too much pressure and it's gonna end up cracking.
Speaker 11:  Gotcha. And is there, can you think of a design
Speaker 11:  reason for that little piece of tape
Speaker 12:  There? No, because it's, it's not coming into contact with any metals. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  Or any like anything exposed. So the only reason
Speaker 12:  is to hide that screw
Speaker 11:  Brian Nauman from Apple disputed that the tape was meant to hide anything.
Speaker 11:  He said it was grounding tape there to quote, protect the electrical circuitry.
Speaker 11:  Anyway, OSH fished a new charge port out of his wall of bagged parts.
Speaker 11:  He connected to the phone, tested it, and put the whole thing back together
Speaker 11:  again.
Speaker 2:  So just like that we're we're, we're up and running again. What, 90 bucks
Speaker 2:  later And you have a working iPhone eight. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  Absolutely.
Speaker 2:  How long did this whole thing take?
Speaker 11:  It took us like an hour, but that was because I was literally like looking
Speaker 11:  over ASHA's shoulder and asking him questions every 30 seconds. He says
Speaker 11:  he can swap a charge ported out in like 20 minutes 'cause he's done a million
Speaker 11:  of them.
Speaker 2:  I'm sure he loved you during this whole process. He's like, leave me alone.
Speaker 2:  Let me do my job.
Speaker 11:  It's, I know it's a very zen process of keeping track of all of these screws
Speaker 11:  and I, I am not a zen person when I am. I just on the best of days, but
Speaker 11:  especially not when I'm interviewing. So I can't imagine that went well.
Speaker 11:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. Alright, well repair shop one Apple, store zero.
Speaker 2:  What's next?
Speaker 11:  Yes. So next is the boot looper. This is the, the phone that just
Speaker 11:  reset itself for no reason. I explained the problem to
Speaker 11:  Avav and I gave him the Apple store's diagnosis. Their best guess was
Speaker 11:  that it was a battery problem.
Speaker 12:  No, it's the charging port. It's either the charging port or the power volume
Speaker 12:  button.
Speaker 2:  Wait, will, is everything a charging port? Like is the, is the secret to
Speaker 2:  repairing your phone? Just that the charging port is always the problem.
Speaker 11:  I mean apparently this is, this is what happens when you like genuinely
Speaker 11:  buy broken phones and don't know what it'll take to fix them. Sometimes
Speaker 11:  you just end up with a bunch of broken charging ports. The deal here is
Speaker 11:  that it's not the charging port per se, it's the sensor that sits on
Speaker 11:  the charging port. The quote charging port is actually
Speaker 11:  a whole bunch of different components that are all bundled together. There's
Speaker 11:  the port, there's the sensor, there's some speakers, there's the vibration
Speaker 11:  motor. So that's all one part that you can swap in and out.
Speaker 2:  Got it. So it's basically like that sort of bottom stripe of your phone is
Speaker 2:  all one thing and whatever breaks the whole thing
Speaker 11:  Breaks. That's the replaceable thing. Okay. That's the thing that you can
Speaker 11:  buy replacement parts for. Got it. Anyway, as soon as I told
Speaker 11:  Avav that the phone was rebooting, quote every few minutes he
Speaker 11:  said, oh, it's every three minutes. This is a thing that he's seeing a lot.
Speaker 11:  And it usually means there's a bad temperature sensor somewhere.
Speaker 12:  What happens is when the device shuts off every three
Speaker 12:  minutes, yeah, there are temperature sensors around the device that
Speaker 12:  report what the temperature is. If one of those sensors fails
Speaker 12:  and it can't report, then the device as a safety precaution
Speaker 12:  will turn off, it'll turn back on and then the same thing happens.
Speaker 12:  Yes. And it checks every three minutes.
Speaker 11:  He booted up the phone and he found the device's analytics files,
Speaker 11:  which I had no idea existed. And for the record, the Apple Tech
Speaker 11:  did not do, the files are actually not that hard to find. They're in
Speaker 11:  the privacy and security setting screen. But you've gotta know what you're
Speaker 11:  looking for when you look at them. 'cause it's one of those walls of gibberish
Speaker 11:  text
Speaker 12:  And then you wanna find where it says panic. Oh,
Speaker 11:  Okay. That's the panic is the reset.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. And then when you go there in that first
Speaker 12:  big block of text, it'll say missing sensors.
Speaker 11:  The panic log told him that. Yep. The culprit is probably a sensor
Speaker 11:  on the charging port. So yes, we needed to replace this
Speaker 11:  phone's charging port too and just see if that stopped the reboot.
Speaker 11:  So same process as the last phone. Although one notable detail,
Speaker 11:  this is the phone with the crack screen that Apple said, oh, If, you open
Speaker 11:  it up, it'll totally shatter the screen. So you have to replace that too.
Speaker 11:  But I don't know, I watched AV pop the screen off without any problem
Speaker 11:  for whatever that's worth. Anyway, we plugged in the replacement part and
Speaker 11:  we turned on the phone to see if it would stay on this time.
Speaker 12:  We'll make it a five minute timer.
Speaker 11:  All right, so now we've got five minutes to figure out
Speaker 12:  If that
Speaker 11:  Is the culprit, but after exactly three minutes,
Speaker 11:  the phone reset.
Speaker 12:  Oh, a little phone.
Speaker 11:  We tried that meant that the problem might actually be
Speaker 11:  in the motherboard, which for a phone that's worth maybe a hundred dollars
Speaker 11:  is probably too much trouble to fix. But we wanted to rule everything
Speaker 11:  else out. So just in case the replacement part
Speaker 11:  also had a bad sensor. We tried a couple more identical parts from
Speaker 11:  Sasha's inventory. All of those failed to, we also verified that the
Speaker 11:  battery was fine since that was Apple's gas. It was fine. At
Speaker 11:  one point we actually lost track of the timer and we thought that we had
Speaker 11:  a working phone for a second. Oh,
Speaker 12:  We're it worked. Ah. Oh, there you go.
Speaker 11:  But it reset again.
Speaker 12:  Motherboard.
Speaker 11:  Motherboard. So that was it for the boot looper.
Speaker 2:  So we gave, we gave up on this one. It was, it was the end of the boot looper.
Speaker 11:  It was the end of the line for the boot looper. Okay. Yeah. Mother motherboard
Speaker 11:  problem is bad news. Right.
Speaker 2:  And in this case, I, I suspect it ends up just being a pretty straight
Speaker 2:  financial decision. Like yes, you could replace the whole thing and sort
Speaker 2:  of like ship a thesis your phone into a new phone, but at that point
Speaker 2:  it is probably a lot more expensive than just taking whatever deal Apple
Speaker 2:  would've given you. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  Exactly. Okay. Or even If, you don't take Apple's deal. There are cheaper
Speaker 11:  phones online. Just, just walk away.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, go, go buy a different broken one on eBay and just try thing
Speaker 11:  Again. Yeah, fix that one. Yeah, just go through it all again. Have better
Speaker 11:  luck.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Alright, so we're, we're at one to one. It's tiebreaker time.
Speaker 2:  Can we fix these phones? We have one that works. We, that is
Speaker 2:  broken forever. How are you feeling at this point in the process? I
Speaker 2:  feel like at the very least you've been given access to a lot more
Speaker 2:  information and process with the independent repair than
Speaker 2:  you were at the Apple store.
Speaker 11:  Totally. That is absolutely true. You know, walking out of
Speaker 11:  the store that day, I was like, well, I, I found a good stumper
Speaker 11:  on eBay. Yeah, I, I was, I was sort of hoping that we would go through this
Speaker 11:  process and triumph at the end, but the utter brokenness of the phone revealed
Speaker 11:  a lot more along the way. So yeah, on the one hand it was, it was funny
Speaker 11:  that the end result is the same. Both the Apple store and Jet City
Speaker 11:  were like, this is not a phone that's worth fixing. But as you're, as you
Speaker 11:  say, the journey to get there was was just totally different. Mm.
Speaker 11:  As soon as Apple saw that there was a third party part in their phone,
Speaker 11:  they were like case closed and that was the end of it. Whereas AV
Speaker 11:  found the log files, he opened the phone up, he tested like four different
Speaker 11:  parts. He really worked the problem, which was what I was looking to
Speaker 11:  see. And it drove home. You know, one big argument for independent
Speaker 11:  repair shops, which is that they'll repair things that manufacturers never
Speaker 11:  intended to be repaired in the first place. There's one really
Speaker 11:  wild case in point while I was there, while Sava and I were chatting
Speaker 11:  over his shoulder, I noticed this industrial looking device
Speaker 11:  next to his workbench that was shining a bunch of lights on an iPhone
Speaker 11:  that had a totally shattered back glass. And I asked Sava,
Speaker 11:  what is up with that? That's
Speaker 12:  The laser. Oh shit. What is that doing? It's lasering off the adhesive from
Speaker 12:  the backlash.
Speaker 11:  No kidding.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, that's the, you don't wanna stare too long into the white, I'll let
Speaker 12:  you wear this.
Speaker 11:  He handed me a pair of tinted glasses
Speaker 12:  And then you can stare at it while it's lasering.
Speaker 11:  So for most iPhone models, there's no official way to
Speaker 11:  fix that back glass. It's glued to the phone, but that's where indie
Speaker 11:  repair shops are like, okay, challenge accepted, you buy a laser
Speaker 11:  and you zap the phone to loosen the adhesive and then you manually scrape
Speaker 11:  the glass off and install a new plate. And that's just what it
Speaker 11:  takes to repair something in spite of the design of the thing.
Speaker 11:  Did you buy this laser specifically for this kind of repair or does it do
Speaker 11:  other things?
Speaker 12:  No, just for this,
Speaker 2:  First of all that rules, everyone should have a laser in their house that
Speaker 2:  just does one job. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  That's a single purpose laser. I have one for my cat and I I want
Speaker 11:  more now. Yeah. So that was really notable. The other notable thing
Speaker 11:  to me about the repairs that I brought in is that
Speaker 11:  as much as I was looking for stumps, they were actually pretty simple in
Speaker 11:  one regard, which is that the parts that we replaced were
Speaker 11:  not programmed by Apple to resist the doing of the
Speaker 11:  repair.
Speaker 2:  Oh. Is this the part where we get to talk about parts pairing? I've been
Speaker 2:  wanting to scream parts pairing ever since You said third party battery like
Speaker 2:  hours ago. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  Is this,
Speaker 2:  This is the parts pairing part of our program.
Speaker 11:  This is the parts pairing part of the story.
Speaker 2:  It's like when we talk about the smart home and we have to get really upset
Speaker 2:  about matter for 15 minutes, like this is the part of the right to repair
Speaker 2:  story where we have to talk about parts pairing.
Speaker 11:  Yes. And I like, I was very naive. I was like, okay, I
Speaker 11:  did a parts pairing story last time. This story isn't gonna be about parts
Speaker 11:  pairing, I'm gonna talk about other stuff. But I learned very quickly
Speaker 11:  that you just can't talk about iPhones without talking about
Speaker 11:  parts pairing any repair of just about any part of an iPhone will
Speaker 11:  eventually lead a repair tech to talk about parts pairing. So
Speaker 11:  without doing a whole other segment parts pairing in brief, your phone can
Speaker 11:  basically sabotage your repair. If it figures out that you didn't
Speaker 11:  use Apple parts installed by Apple text, so If you replace the
Speaker 11:  screen, it might lose the true tone feature. If you replace the battery,
Speaker 11:  it might not track its health over time anymore replaced touch ID
Speaker 11:  or face ID components, we'll just fully fail. Again, we've talked a lot
Speaker 11:  about this, but being in a repair shop made me
Speaker 11:  appreciate just how much parts pairing has undermined them over
Speaker 11:  the years. These bugs have been popping up in iPhones
Speaker 11:  generation after generation and it's not like Apple announces them to
Speaker 11:  everybody. They have to get discovered and shared and it happens when
Speaker 11:  repairs just start going haywire for no reason at all. So just to name
Speaker 11:  one example, a few years back a YouTuber named Hugh Jeffreys
Speaker 11:  noticed something really weird when he replaced the cameras in an iPhone
Speaker 11:  12
Speaker 13:  After changing the camera two functions are now completely unusable.
Speaker 13:  Portrait mode only works for the front camera with the back one only
Speaker 13:  flashing still images and a black screen. You can see panoramas
Speaker 13:  also don't work when using the 0.5 x zoom.
Speaker 11:  There was no warning about non-genuine parts. The new cameras were
Speaker 11:  just flaky, which is a thing Sava noticed. So
Speaker 12:  It mimicked a quality control issue rather than
Speaker 12:  an intentional interference with the functionality on Apple's part. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  And so your immediate gut instinct even as a technician is
Speaker 12:  going to be man, there's no reliable parts for them. With serialization
Speaker 12:  you can actually program failures that are in intermittent and
Speaker 12:  mess with people's heads. Wait,
Speaker 2:  Hang on. How did they know in this process that it wasn't some
Speaker 2:  sketchy part causing the problems here?
Speaker 11:  Well he knew because the YouTuber took the parts straight out of another
Speaker 11:  brand new iPhone 12.
Speaker 2:  Oh, that would do it. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  He actually took two phones right out of the box and swapped their components
Speaker 11:  and both the phones had these issues. So Apple eventually
Speaker 11:  fixed that specific bug with a software update, though they
Speaker 11:  added that non-genuine parts warning instead. Of course. And
Speaker 11:  actually just last month, apple did announce some
Speaker 11:  plans to relax some pairing restrictions on used
Speaker 11:  Apple parts. Though it's only on select models of iPhones and
Speaker 11:  there are just a lot of specifics that they haven't talked about. but it
Speaker 11:  does mean in the future you might be able to pull a screen off of
Speaker 11:  one iPhone and drop it in another without any problems. So we'll have to
Speaker 11:  see about that. But even if that happens after market parts
Speaker 11:  are probably still gonna cause problems. And this is the thing,
Speaker 11:  maybe some of those problems will be genuine aftermarket parts
Speaker 11:  don't always work perfectly with the original hardware and you can make
Speaker 11:  a mistake during a repair and that can cause a problem. But the repair
Speaker 11:  techs just feel so gaslit by Apple after this
Speaker 11:  history of bugs.
Speaker 12:  Now there's like this healthy paranoia. Yeah. Where you don't know if that
Speaker 12:  was something else or if it was intentional sabotage.
Speaker 11:  Over the years, the community has found some pretty clever workarounds.
Speaker 11:  There are ways to restore true tone if you're comfortable physically moving
Speaker 11:  microchips around. There are aftermarket home buttons that are explicitly
Speaker 11:  built to get around the phone security checks. OSH can even make
Speaker 11:  a third party battery play nice with an iPhone, but it is a process.
Speaker 12:  You see that tool right there? The
Speaker 11:  Red thing with the Yeah,
Speaker 12:  Yeah. That's a welder spot welder. Okay. And so you have to
Speaker 12:  cut the battery electronics from the old battery and
Speaker 12:  then you have a new battery without the electronics. Yeah. And
Speaker 12:  you spot weld those two points. Yeah. Back on and
Speaker 12:  then roll 'em like a cigar and then tape it up again and
Speaker 12:  then put it together.
Speaker 11:  The upshot is that chops constantly have this really tough choice
Speaker 11:  to make. Either they have to jump through all of these absurd
Speaker 11:  hoops to outsmart the devices that they're fixing or they have
Speaker 11:  to ask their customers to live with bugs and that
Speaker 11:  choice more than anything else. Infuriates
Speaker 11:  Ava,
Speaker 12:  We do better work than Apple. Jet. City. Device Repair does better work
Speaker 12:  than Apple. We've done better work than Apple for a very long time, but
Speaker 12:  because of these limitations sometimes appears as if we do
Speaker 12:  worse work.
Speaker 2:  All right. I feel Sasha's pain. I really do. But will you have led me up
Speaker 2:  to what I hope is now the grand finale here, which is our, our good
Speaker 2:  friend Rusty, the iPhone 14 that has spent, what was it, some amount of
Speaker 2:  time in saltwater?
Speaker 11:  I I actually reached out to the eBay seller after I bought it and it turns
Speaker 11:  out it, they just found it in a bay in Florida.
Speaker 11:  So some time is really putting it lightly.
Speaker 2:  I think somewhere between 10 minutes and two years in saltwater
Speaker 11:  Between 10 minutes and the release of the phone.
Speaker 2:  Love it. So Rusty, what happened with Rusty?
Speaker 11:  So I, you know, I I told you I had really high hopes for Rusty and
Speaker 11:  Ava again, to his credit, was totally happy to open it up and see,
Speaker 11:  but it's
Speaker 12:  Like leaking corrosion.
Speaker 11:  The guts of the phone were just totally coated in this toxic
Speaker 11:  looking white and brown gunk. It, it was disgusting.
Speaker 12:  Oh my god. I can
Speaker 11:  Hear, I mean I can hear the sound that it's making
Speaker 12:  Guys, you wanna see a record breaking that's like a coral reef in there.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. Corrosion phone. There's nothing we can do with it, but I got, I I
Speaker 12:  can share it with the, with the company. They're gonna have fun with it.
Speaker 11:  It was so bad that he posted a photo of it to the company Slack.
Speaker 12:  I was gonna say, can we fix this 14 pro mat?
Speaker 11:  So, so that was Rusty
Speaker 2:  Moment of silence for Rusty. I will say though, huge
Speaker 2:  success on your part in a certain sense that you managed to bring
Speaker 2:  this person a phone that they then shared with the rest
Speaker 2:  of the company. It was so broken, so spectacularly like. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  if the goal was to find interestingly broken phones, like, oh boy did you
Speaker 2:  do it?
Speaker 11:  I knew ensemble, you know, that's making me feel better for spending the
Speaker 11:  amount of money that I spent on a, a, a phone that was never gonna be fixed
Speaker 11:  guy. Yeah. Because I just, I knew that it was destined for something great.
Speaker 2:  It will live on, yeah, rusty lives on at the repair shop, it's probably,
Speaker 2:  he's probably in a, in a frame on a wall somewhere. Just oozing gross.
Speaker 11:  So foul.
Speaker 2:  So what, what do you feel like you learned from this experiment? You went
Speaker 2:  in trying to get kind of a real sort of tangible sense of what the right
Speaker 2:  to repair fight is Like what, what do you feel like you learned?
Speaker 11:  So I, I feel like I learned a couple of things. The first thing
Speaker 11:  is, is maybe obvious for people who have spent any time in this
Speaker 11:  world, but as a consumer and an Apple device
Speaker 11:  owner, it was new to me and it's just that Apple is not
Speaker 11:  the authority on its own phones in this context. It's people
Speaker 11:  like Sav who are, I've talked to a lot of independent
Speaker 11:  repair techs over the course of this reporting and they have all
Speaker 11:  just put in the time to get to know these devices
Speaker 11:  inside and out. And they literally have to, to understand them
Speaker 11:  better than the Apple geniuses if they wanna do all these repairs that
Speaker 11:  either Apple doesn't care about doing or actively doesn't want them to
Speaker 11:  do. That's the thing that, that sets them apart from
Speaker 11:  the Apple repair internal ecosystem. And that's what right to
Speaker 11:  repair. Advocates are trying so hard through these laws and all these other
Speaker 11:  things to protect. So that kind of turned my thinking around on the
Speaker 11:  sort of internal external repair ecosystem. The
Speaker 2:  Thing that keeps jumping out to me as you talk is there's such a different
Speaker 2:  incentive here, right? Like Apple, even If, you believe Apple
Speaker 2:  would like to fix the things that it sells. You also would like to sell you
Speaker 2:  new things. And so what you get, I think my sense of your Apple store trip
Speaker 2:  is very much that you sort of ran into a script and
Speaker 2:  when you said third party battery or they discovered third party battery
Speaker 2:  or it became obvious that it was water damage, it just immediately is like
Speaker 2:  jump to end, which means we can't repair it. Whereas If, you go to a repair
Speaker 2:  shop, the one and only thing they are there to do is repair
Speaker 2:  it. And so you just have set yourself up in a very different sort of
Speaker 2:  adventure from the very beginning just by the virtue of like who these folks
Speaker 2:  are regardless of their talent and resources and ability. Just
Speaker 2:  having this other thing where the only thing they are there to do is try
Speaker 2:  and fix your gadget totally changes the way that they're gonna work with
Speaker 2:  you.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. That's just their whole deal. The, the more people keep more older
Speaker 11:  gadgets going for longer, the more that they need to be repaired
Speaker 11:  and the more those repair shops are in business. So it's like, it's absolutely
Speaker 11:  a difference in incentive more than anything else. Totally. The other thing
Speaker 11:  that I just found funny and weird is just how
Speaker 11:  adversarial a relationship Apple has with these independent
Speaker 11:  repair shops, given what they're actually doing. Like you would think that
Speaker 11:  Apple was battling these super intense hackers who are trying to take the
Speaker 11:  company down based on the way that they're acting and all of these, these
Speaker 11:  bugs that they're putting into the phones and these repair techs are not,
Speaker 11:  not hackers. I mean you, you can look at what they're doing with these
Speaker 11:  batteries and their touch ID buttons to get around everything that Apple
Speaker 11:  is doing. Like they're, they're really scrappy people, but they're not trying
Speaker 11:  to destroy the company. They're just trying to fix the company's
Speaker 11:  products. They're literally just like, we're gonna fix your phones,
Speaker 11:  try to stop us. And I think that is a very
Speaker 11:  strange group of people to pick such an intense fight with.
Speaker 2:  15 Pro. We'd love to hear your thoughts since this has confused me for a
Speaker 2:  while. Unbelievable question. Love it very much. And this is actually, as
Speaker 2:  I've been reviewing the new iPads, kind of the main question I've been
Speaker 2:  thinking about the short version of both iPad reviews is that they're
Speaker 2:  excellent iPads, right? The iPad Pro is thin and
Speaker 2:  light and just lovely to hold in a way that it's been a long time since
Speaker 2:  an iPad has felt like that to me. The air is everything you would want
Speaker 2:  it to be. It's last year's pro in last year's air's body. The
Speaker 2:  screen's very good, the battery's very good, the processor is very good.
Speaker 2:  It gets the new pencil. It doesn't have a function row on the keyboard like
Speaker 2:  the new pro does, but it's a very good iPad. All of the iPads are very good
Speaker 2:  iPads, right? And so I think the question is really what is the
Speaker 2:  iPad for? And I think when you ask the question why do some people think
Speaker 2:  the iPad should be a Macbook replacement, I think it comes down to making
Speaker 2:  a device that is good for everything is really hard. It might be
Speaker 2:  impossible, but it's really, really, really hard. And if
Speaker 2:  you're Apple, I think one way to think about it is that Apple has had a bunch
Speaker 2:  of very versatile but also sort of focused devices
Speaker 2:  over time. Like the, the story of the Mac is easy, right? You can do lots
Speaker 2:  of things on the Mac, but it is fundamentally a device for doing work. And
Speaker 2:  you can define work as broadly as you want, but it is, it is a
Speaker 2:  productive creative device. It's a device for doing things.
Speaker 2:  The Apple Watch is a device that can do lots of things, but it has increasingly
Speaker 2:  over time become a device about fitness and health. AirPods headphones, that
Speaker 2:  one's easy, right? The iPhone is the exception. It is a
Speaker 2:  device that is fundamentally all things to all people.
Speaker 2:  And as a result, this is, I mean this is why smartphones have become so dominant,
Speaker 2:  right? They are all things to all people and thus they are the
Speaker 2:  most important device that almost everyone owns at this point. That's a very
Speaker 2:  hard thing to replicate if you're Apple or if you're anyone,
Speaker 2:  the smartphone won like it just did. And so trying to do something
Speaker 2:  that does all the same things a smartphone does that is as varied and
Speaker 2:  broad and able to accomplish so many different goals all in one package
Speaker 2:  just puts you in competition with the smartphone. It's a bad idea. Most people
Speaker 2:  don't do it. What we're seeing actually is that even things like
Speaker 2:  AI devices that try to do lots of things fail because they're worse than
Speaker 2:  your smartphone. And instead what's cool and what's working is devices
Speaker 2:  that take one feature of the iPhone and do it better. There's a
Speaker 2:  bit of a resurgence happening in dedicated cameras for instance, because
Speaker 2:  you get more control and you get better images. But if your camera was like
Speaker 2:  also trying to order you Ubers, that wouldn't make any sense. So what you're
Speaker 2:  seeing, I think in the best case here is companies that say, okay, we're
Speaker 2:  going to cleave off part of what the iPhone
Speaker 2:  does or a smartphone does in general and try to do it better, right? So
Speaker 2:  they're taking in many cases, smartphone chips, they can run smartphone apps,
Speaker 2:  they can do things that you do on a smartphone, on a touchscreen in similar
Speaker 2:  ways that you do them on a smartphone, but you can just do more and you can
Speaker 2:  do them dedicated. The iPad has always been the opposite.
Speaker 2:  It's trying to be incredibly versatile. It's trying to be
Speaker 2:  a jack of all trades. It's trying to be all things to all people. And I've
Speaker 2:  come to think of it like this over time. Apple basically sees
Speaker 2:  a core set of what you might call iPad things, right? And
Speaker 2:  that's playing games, that's watching TV and movies,
Speaker 2:  that's checking your email and browsing the web. This sort of basic
Speaker 2:  simple use case stuff that people have always done on their iPads, the
Speaker 2:  same kinds of things that even like Steve Jobs is talking about in the very
Speaker 2:  first iPad introduction, it's a device for sitting on the couch
Speaker 2:  casually using a computer. That's cool, that has been
Speaker 2:  very good on an iPad for a very long time. It's also true that most of those
Speaker 2:  things are almost as good and in some cases better on your
Speaker 2:  phone, which is device you already own. It's a device you have to buy before
Speaker 2:  you buy an iPad. And it's a device that is almost
Speaker 2:  in every case, more likely to be close to you than your iPad. So what
Speaker 2:  you have essentially is an iPad is now more work for slightly more benefit
Speaker 2:  because you have to go get it, you have to keep it charged, it has to be
Speaker 2:  updated, all this stuff. Whereas I think a lot of people just say, well,
Speaker 2:  would I do any of that? I have my phone and I already do all that stuff to
Speaker 2:  have my phone work. So what Apple has been doing over the last several years
Speaker 2:  is basically adding bits and pieces of functionality that you can't
Speaker 2:  do on the iPhone in the hopes that not all of them will appeal
Speaker 2:  to you specifically, but maybe one of them will, right? So this year
Speaker 2:  you have things like the Pencil Pro, which has a new gesture
Speaker 2:  called the barrel roll, which basically lets you preview the way that your
Speaker 2:  brush tip is gonna look on the screen as you move it around and it lets you
Speaker 2:  turn the brush as you're painting. This is the kind of thing that if you're
Speaker 2:  hearing that and it doesn't mean anything to you, that's fine, it's not for
Speaker 2:  you. But there are a lot of people for whom that gives them a level of control
Speaker 2:  doing artistic work that is really powerful and really important. That's
Speaker 2:  not how you get giant swaths of new people to use the iPad.
Speaker 2:  It's not a mainstream new use case, but it is a thing, right? And
Speaker 2:  Apple, I think believes that over time with enough power and enough work
Speaker 2:  and maybe enough AI stuff, which is what's coming at WW DC,
Speaker 2:  and I think we're gonna see Apple make some big swings at new
Speaker 2:  features that only work on these super powerful touch enabled, ultra portable
Speaker 2:  devices that make it more compelling. And so rather than have
Speaker 2:  one giant mainstream use case that appeals to everyone on earth, it wants
Speaker 2:  to have a million different little ones covering sort of every niche at a
Speaker 2:  time and hope that that adds up to
Speaker 2:  everybody. So how does this come back to the MacBook question? I think the
Speaker 2:  reason people talk about it as a laptop is because it is one obvious place
Speaker 2:  for the iPad to go, right? You look at it, it's a 13 inch screen, I
Speaker 2:  can drop it into my keyboard, it has a track pad, it runs a lot of the same
Speaker 2:  apps that are on my MacBook. So it's natural to say, well, okay, one thing
Speaker 2:  this could do that it doesn't is be more like my MacBook. I actually have
Speaker 2:  come to believe that that's the wrong answer, or at least it's the least
Speaker 2:  interesting answer. I think Apple's strategy of trying to find
Speaker 2:  a million small things that add up to one big thing is actually
Speaker 2:  more exciting and means ultimately that the iPad can be a device that isn't
Speaker 2:  just a touchscreen MacBook. I also think they should put a touchscreen on
Speaker 2:  the MacBook, but that's what the touchscreen MacBook should be. It should
Speaker 2:  be a MacBook with a touchscreen, not an iPad that runs Mac os. I just don't
Speaker 2:  think that's the right strategy. It's at least not the most interesting strategy,
Speaker 2:  but we're in this position now where if you're looking at the iPad and you're
Speaker 2:  saying, okay, this does a lot of stuff, but what? What would push it over
Speaker 2:  the edge? What would make it an essential important game
Speaker 2:  changing? Bring it with me everywhere, no matter what kind of device work
Speaker 2:  is one obvious answer to that. That's why you see for creative people, it
Speaker 2:  very much is that kind of tool. If, you need to draw on a screen. The iPad
Speaker 2:  is the best thing that exists. You can't replicate that on your phone, you
Speaker 2:  can't replicate that on your MacBook. You need an iPad for that. And we're
Speaker 2:  starting to see that for some filmmaking stuff that's happening. People are
Speaker 2:  doing interesting monitoring and editing work on their iPads. It's a cool
Speaker 2:  tool for photography, for editing photos, bits and pieces like
Speaker 2:  I'm saying. But If, you then throw in, you know, this capital W work
Speaker 2:  thing, whatever that means to people. Whether it's, I want to have
Speaker 2:  a desktop browser so that I can use all my browser extensions and Google
Speaker 2:  Docs will be better, or I want full bore, full power
Speaker 2:  Excel running on this thing so that I don't have to go back to my computer.
Speaker 2:  Or it means I want to use the accounting software that I haven't
Speaker 2:  updated in 10 years but desperately need in order to do my job.
Speaker 2:  If, you pull all of that stuff down to the iPad, I think it changes the iPad,
Speaker 2:  but it also makes it more essential to some people in a certain
Speaker 2:  way. And so I think that is why people have been pushing Apple to turn it
Speaker 2:  into like a laptop, is that it would make it something
Speaker 2:  everybody needs, which I actually don't think is right. Again, because laptops
Speaker 2:  exist and MacBooks in particular are very good laptops. And so
Speaker 2:  that is just a tricky thing for Apple to get right. Again, if
Speaker 2:  it wants to be this one all things to all people device,
Speaker 2:  it's gonna have to do a lot of that eventually. And I think Apple is sort
Speaker 2:  of hoping that work apps will get better before the
Speaker 2:  iPad has to worry about all of that old compatibility stuff. But I'm not
Speaker 2:  convinced that's gonna be true. So if I'm Apple, I'm saying right now
Speaker 2:  that the versatility of the iPad is the point and this is the thing that
Speaker 2:  you hear from people at Apple. It's a thing that I've heard from people at
Speaker 2:  Apple. The versatility is the point. They don't want this thing to be
Speaker 2:  a device for anything. They want it to be a device for everything that everyone
Speaker 2:  has a different subset of use cases for and that that is what makes it special.
Speaker 2:  That is an incredibly hard thing to do. I think the Apple Watch
Speaker 2:  is probably the most interesting comparison there by the way, because for
Speaker 2:  a time that was the pitch for the Apple Watch too, that it was, it was gonna
Speaker 2:  do all the things your iPhone did, but in a better, more accessible way.
Speaker 2:  The iPad is a pretty similar case and what we discovered with the watch is
Speaker 2:  that actually my phone's very good, but the watch does this subset of other
Speaker 2:  things very well that compliment that it does health and
Speaker 2:  fitness stuff really well. And it's a very simple controller and I can use
Speaker 2:  Siri. And so you're seeing Apple bet on those things more and more on the
Speaker 2:  watch over time, whereas on the iPad it's kind of still stuck
Speaker 2:  trying to be all things to all people. You can focus on the pencil and that's
Speaker 2:  great, but the pencil market I think is much smaller than the health and
Speaker 2:  fitness market. Same goes for some of the like ultra
Speaker 2:  performant apps that you're starting to see, whether it's like architects
Speaker 2:  or 3D games or augmented reality. I think all of that stuff on tablets is
Speaker 2:  fairly niche. So what Apple needs is either one big giant use
Speaker 2:  case and maybe it is laptop replacement or just
Speaker 2:  countless more of these little tiny niches that all eventually give
Speaker 2:  everybody a reason to need an iPad even though it's not the same one. That's
Speaker 2:  a hard, hard, hard game to play and it's a hard list
Speaker 2:  of tasks to finish, but I kind of hope that's what Apple keeps doing because
Speaker 2:  that to me is the most interesting possible future of the iPad. That said,
Speaker 2:  I do wish Google Docs work better, so just give me that and then I'll probably
Speaker 2:  need an iPad too.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that's it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everybody who's
Speaker 2:  on the show. Thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on everything
Speaker 2:  we talked about today, including my iPad reviews, all of Chris's
Speaker 2:  Sonos scoops and a whole bunch more on The Verge dot com. I'll put a bunch
Speaker 2:  of links in the show notes. If, you don't know, we've been doing much better
Speaker 2:  show notes posts on the site recently. They tend to go up about
Speaker 2:  nine o'clock in the morning on the days that we publish the show.
Speaker 2:  Go check it out there, leave us a comment, tell us what you think. We'd love
Speaker 2:  to hear from you and as always, If you have thoughts or feelings or questions
Speaker 2:  or just want to yell at me about iPads, you can always email us at
Speaker 2:  Vergecast at The Verge dot com or keep calling the hotline. 8 6 6 VERGE
Speaker 2:  one, one. we love hearing from you. Send us all of your thoughts and questions
Speaker 2:  and ideas. Google io is coming up, Microsoft build is coming up. WW DC is
Speaker 2:  coming up. I wanna know everything that you're thinking about and interested
Speaker 2:  in and want us to find out and want us to talk about. Keep it all coming.
Speaker 2:  This show is produced by Andrew Marino, Liam James, and Will Poor The. Vergecast
Speaker 2:  is VERGE production and part of the Vox Media podcast network, NELI, Alex,
Speaker 2:  and I'll be back on Friday to talk about whatever is about to happen at Google
Speaker 2:  io and a whole bunch more. We'll see you then. Rock and roll.