# Transcript
ID: 60cb42ed-20da-4dba-b0c2-7fbca3779c92
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/9042589769868344844/-6134862417323939636/s93290-US-6015s-1719186448.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and Alex Heath discuss Apple's Vision Pro team reportedly refocusing on a cheaper headset, Meta launching a new "Wearables" organization, a new AI company startup from former OpenAI chief scientist, and a whole lot more tech news.
Speaker 1:  I
Speaker 6:  And welcome to Vergecast the flagship podcast
Speaker 6:  but but happy to be here. David is off this week, but we've got Alex, which
Speaker 6:  is gonna be great. There's a lot of AI news. There's a bunch of VR news including
Speaker 6:  some, some Scoops outta meta in the reality labs division that
Speaker 6:  Alex is here to talk about and have some insight into. But we
Speaker 6:  should start with like the news, which is a weird bit
Speaker 6:  of news in that half of the news got delayed.
Speaker 6:  Weird. Microsoft's co-pilot plus PCs are now shipping.
Speaker 6:  They have Qualcomm Snapdragon X chips inside them.
Speaker 6:  This is the beginning of what might be the end of the Intel
Speaker 6:  dominance, the X 86 dominance for Windows machines.
Speaker 6:  But Microsoft had to delay recall, which was the flagship feature of the
Speaker 6:  copilot plus PC because of horrible security concerns.
Speaker 6:  Just a weird moment. Kranz, right? Like
Speaker 7:  Yeah, this
Speaker 6:  A weird stutter. Even the review units like didn't arrive on time 'cause
Speaker 6:  they were disabling recall. Yeah
Speaker 7:  Like this is wild. We were expecting to get these a week ago to start kind
Speaker 7:  of reviewing them before the embargo list and we got them the day of the
Speaker 7:  embargo. Tom's got both the Elite and
Speaker 7:  the Plus and is checking those out and, and a whole bunch of other people
Speaker 7:  on the team all have them and are just, we are all in this one room just
Speaker 7:  furiously benchmarking, constantly work. It's, they're having a lot of
Speaker 7:  fun doing it. But we've still got a lot of work to do so far. We figured
Speaker 7:  out that some stuff is working, some stuff isn't. There's
Speaker 7:  still a lot of weird like emulation bugs and stuff. I
Speaker 7:  think Adobe Premier was having a weird issue where it would
Speaker 7:  work with the elite processor but not necessarily with the plus
Speaker 7:  processor. Some games crashing. Some of this might be like
Speaker 7:  alleviated with more updates from everybody. But what was supposed
Speaker 7:  to be this big monumental moment for Microsoft and
Speaker 7:  Qualcomm and everybody instead was like, we did it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, here it is. We turned off half of it. Even in Best Buy, there's like
Speaker 6:  signs that say recall coming later on the demo units
Speaker 6:  because, so if you don't know if you, we weren't listening to the show in
Speaker 6:  the previous weeks. Microsoft announced these PCs and the flagship feature
Speaker 6:  was recall, which even if it was working in a totally secure
Speaker 6:  way is weird. The computer watches everything you do on
Speaker 6:  the computer like Windows watches. Everything you do takes screenshots of
Speaker 6:  it uses a local generative am I model to understand what's in those
Speaker 6:  screenshots. And then You can just be like, what? There was a website I thought
Speaker 6:  I liked. Did you remember what it and the computer will tell you? Or I was
Speaker 6:  working on this document, do you remember what it was? No, the comp You can
Speaker 6:  talk to the computer about what you've done with it, which some people
Speaker 6:  David Pierce very excited about because David would like to be
Speaker 6:  friends with the computer. It's, that's my understanding of First Sound.
Speaker 6:  Just
Speaker 7:  Friends.
Speaker 6:  Just, just friends. David is happily married and has a child. Other people
Speaker 6:  would like to be more than friends with the computer. As we have learned
Speaker 6:  time and time again as the AI industry has dominated the
Speaker 6:  headlines,
Speaker 6:  Microsoft was storing the screenshots in basically plain text.
Speaker 6:  So there's this like open database of everything you've done on your computer,
Speaker 6:  on your computer, huge security hole. Microsoft has had a history of security
Speaker 6:  problems. Recently Nadella sent out a memo to everyone being like, if you
Speaker 6:  have to choose between shipping fast and security, I want you to pick
Speaker 6:  security. And then they announced recall and everyone's like, this is a huge
Speaker 6:  security fault and they just delayed it. So they thought they could fix it
Speaker 6:  in time. They issued a blog post by fixing it in time and then they'd realize
Speaker 6:  they couldn't and they delayed it.
Speaker 6:  Kranz, does that feel like, I feel like that's only half of the story here,
Speaker 6:  right? That's just the background. That's part of the stutter step and
Speaker 6:  part of why it's not as flashy a launch like recall is a great
Speaker 6:  feature for what I think of as like the local news, right? Yeah. This is
Speaker 6:  a great demo for the local news and that is how you get a lot of mainstream
Speaker 6:  attention on new things. But the real thing here
Speaker 6:  on all of these tracking and PCs is performance in battery life where they
Speaker 6:  have not been competitive with M Series chips on MacBooks for a long time
Speaker 6:  and now they think they are.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. That is absolutely the big, the big moment here. And like the
Speaker 7:  other part was gonna be really cool and that was gonna be what got people
Speaker 7:  really excited to, to maybe upgrade. But for the rest of us it's
Speaker 7:  okay. Is this finally the moment where Arm on Windows
Speaker 7:  works? Because we've seen it so many times before and every time
Speaker 7:  it has fallen super short of the mark and
Speaker 7:  this time like from the early benchmarks, battery life
Speaker 7:  looking pretty good battery's in that like that, that,
Speaker 7:  that MIP range we're, we're still testing
Speaker 7:  so I don't wanna say which M chip, but it's in that like MIP range.
Speaker 7:  The the speed is looking pretty good. Gaming is like
Speaker 7:  possible. We've still got some work to do there to figure it out,
Speaker 7:  but the, it's, it's a surprise. It definitely doesn't seem like this is gonna
Speaker 7:  be a moment where just Qualcomm blows everybody away. Kind of like how Apple
Speaker 7:  did with the M1 chip where we were like, holy crap, apple actually did it
Speaker 7:  doesn't seem like we're gonna have that moment, but it's
Speaker 7:  still kind of too early to tell.
Speaker 6:  Well it's interesting 'cause Apple hasn't even had the incremental moments
Speaker 6:  after the M1. Yeah, like the M two to M1, it's
Speaker 6:  faster, but it wasn't the big step from Intel to arm,
Speaker 6:  right? M three to M two was faster, but it wasn't the same kind of revelatory
Speaker 6:  experience. So Qualcomm's coming in to just a very different set of
Speaker 6:  expectations. Yeah. Right. Like if You can match the M1 you've done
Speaker 6:  great, that's a big step forward over Intel. If You can beat the M three
Speaker 6:  or the M two, you're, it's the same incremental
Speaker 6:  progress as everyone else has made. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  I think that's kind of normal. We sometimes expect everybody to just blow
Speaker 7:  each other out of the water, but these like Windows is
Speaker 7:  hugely complicated to run. It is not an easy thing to run.
Speaker 7:  It has, there's so many like dependencies code for
Speaker 7:  old code that it has to work through and stuff. And then a lot of times
Speaker 7:  that's, that's stuff isn't built for Arm and so they're having to do all
Speaker 7:  this emulation more so than like an app a Mac would because
Speaker 7:  a Mac just, it's all built from Apple and so not all
Speaker 7:  of it, but most of it's built by Apple for Apple and it can kind of run and
Speaker 7:  knows what to do. That big like translation moment
Speaker 7:  hasn't quite happened for, for Windows machines.
Speaker 6:  They've been trying for a long time.
Speaker 7:  They've been trying and nobody's wanted to do it because it's like, well
Speaker 7:  you don't make, nobody makes good arm chips, so why should I build my, my
Speaker 7:  programs for Arm? And now it's like this could change that
Speaker 7:  this, this could change that. But it is so, so,
Speaker 7:  so early to tell. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  I get the chip story underneath this, but does Microsoft
Speaker 8:  actually think that anyone is gonna switch from Mac to Windows because
Speaker 8:  of this AI stuff? Yeah, because I look at this and it's like, you basically
Speaker 8:  need to tell me that I'd never have to actually understand or know how to
Speaker 8:  use Windows to actually switch to Windows. That's how I feel about Windows.
Speaker 8:  Like an AI needs to, it needs to be so dramatically different from what I
Speaker 8:  expect from a laptop as a lifelong Mac apple
Speaker 8:  lock-in blue bubble guy and like
Speaker 8:  this recall thing sounds cool but it's like I you, you would literally
Speaker 8:  have to say AI is running your laptop for you for me to consider switching.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. 'cause of the software lock in,
Speaker 6:  This
Speaker 7:  Is a pressure dressing, right? Like this is just for them to be like, no,
Speaker 7:  we can't lose anymore Windows people to Chrome or or
Speaker 7:  Max. Like we have to keep 'em here with cool features like that.
Speaker 7:  That's pretty, it's not like let's entice these people back. It's please
Speaker 7:  don't leave.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Help. Well no actually I wonder about that. You know, I,
Speaker 6:  or
Speaker 7:  At least that's how I feel about it.
Speaker 6:  I've heard a lot of CEOs, Alex I'm sure you have to describe
Speaker 6:  AI as a platform shift and I'm always
Speaker 6:  like from what to where, like what platform are you talking about
Speaker 6:  and what they want, what what they're trying to invoke is mobile, right?
Speaker 6:  This is a platform shift on the order of mobile. We went from laptops to
Speaker 6:  smartphones and that smartphones dominate computing and what they, what they're
Speaker 6:  trying to say is this is another platform shift on that scale.
Speaker 6:  And it's like, is it like
Speaker 6:  where like you still have to have a phone to use the
Speaker 6:  chat bot. Like is it that And I think part of this window stuff for
Speaker 6:  Microsoft is very much, okay we own this entire stack. We have this giant
Speaker 6:  investment in OpenAI, we've built copilot, we have all these ideas about
Speaker 6:  what a computer can be here. Like here's a new way to
Speaker 6:  use a computer that is meaningfully different than before. Also
Speaker 6:  you have to pre-install edge or whatever. Like we also, we'll push you towards
Speaker 6:  our browser. I don't know that Apple has different ideas. We, we, we talked
Speaker 6:  about it in the show after wwc, like Apple's ideas for what AI can do in
Speaker 6:  its operating system are basically the same as Microsoft's ideas. So the
Speaker 6:  idea that it's a platform shift I think is under some pressure. But
Speaker 6:  I know that's how these companies think about it. That this will entice you
Speaker 6:  to switch platforms
Speaker 8:  But it's just features right now. It's like I still have to look at the Windows
Speaker 8:  nav bar and figure that thing out, right? And it's like I'm just not gonna
Speaker 8:  do that. I'm sorry Tom Warren. Like I'm just not, so yes,
Speaker 8:  I think they think of it that way. But it shows, I think this
Speaker 8:  recall thing shows where the real platforms are and it's like
Speaker 8:  building two decades of software lock-in on top of
Speaker 8:  hardware, which is not ai, right? AI is software that
Speaker 8:  you're putting on existing hardware at least right now.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I'm, I'm curious, you know, people are listening if you have an
Speaker 6:  idea of where this platform shift is, I'm dying to know what people think,
Speaker 6:  but it is what it is. What Nadella has told me, it's what Sunar Pache has
Speaker 6:  told me. Like down the line the CEOs of the biggest
Speaker 6:  companies are like, this is a platform shift we cannot get left behind.
Speaker 6:  Like in particular with Microsoft, there's like a fear
Speaker 6:  that they got left behind in mobile and they can't get left behind this time.
Speaker 6:  And so you see them kind of, I mean they have been ahead of the curve at
Speaker 6:  every single step. You
Speaker 8:  Didn't hear Elon say it's gonna be trillions of dollars worth of Optimus
Speaker 8:  robots. That's, that's the platform shift.
Speaker 6:  I mean that's the true platform shift is kicking back with a brewski and
Speaker 6:  letting optimist do all your computing for you. Yeah, it'd be great if AI
Speaker 6:  express itself not as AI integrated into the operating system, but you have
Speaker 6:  an optimist robot that knows how to use Windows and that
Speaker 6:  that's actually what happens. I love that.
Speaker 7:  That would be Alex Heath. Yeah. And then like Tom Warren would get the one
Speaker 7:  that knows how to use Mac.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And Eli, you joke about how, you know, use would love to not have to
Speaker 8:  use software at work. You know, you just have an optimist use your software
Speaker 8:  for you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I need an op, I need a full fully complete optimist
Speaker 6:  robot that can use Okta And. if you can just get me there. I'll do it.
Speaker 6:  If You can fi if Optimist can file my expenses, oh my god,
Speaker 6:  those
Speaker 8:  Codes, they suck.
Speaker 6:  The CEOs of these companies will not come on decoder where I will just ask
Speaker 6:  them to look at their own software.
Speaker 6:  We'll see. We are gonna test out. I'll say that I, there, there, I have a
Speaker 6:  running list of my favorite Slack rooms at the company and it's the ones
Speaker 6:  where people have developed their own language. So my number one favorite
Speaker 6:  is we have a support room for our finance team where people just file tickets.
Speaker 6:  And some people have discovered and well some people come in there and they
Speaker 6:  ask very nice questions like, hello, I need help with da da da. And some
Speaker 6:  people have discovered that this room is staffed by a bot that just files
Speaker 6:  tickets and they just yell nouns. They're just like invoice
Speaker 6:  2 45. Like that's all they, they're just, and the other people are very,
Speaker 6:  and it's the greatest room in the entire company 'cause people have realized
Speaker 6:  they can just yell at a robot. The other one is The Verge benchmarks room
Speaker 6:  where it's just people communicating and increasingly arcane benchmarks.
Speaker 6:  Yep. And they've developed their own language about windows on arm
Speaker 6:  benchmarks and they're not, they're not using the normal rule.
Speaker 6:  Like no LLM can figure out what's going on in this room. Statistically this
Speaker 6:  language has never existed before. It's very good. I'm excited
Speaker 6:  for it. They're gonna come, we're gonna have all the reviews. I think David
Speaker 6:  is gonna do a full show with Tom and Nathan, our reviews editor
Speaker 6:  just running down all this stuff on, on Tuesday I believe, right Alex? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Okay, so we'll, we'll we'll come back around with that stuff. I'm,
Speaker 6:  Qualcomm has made a lot of promises here, right? They they, they bought that
Speaker 6:  company Nuvia, which was a bunch of X apple engineers on chip
Speaker 6:  team who were making server chips and they said no make
Speaker 6:  a consumer chip and set 'cause Apple didn't want to use its arm architecture
Speaker 6:  to make server chips. And they thought there was this big opportunity there
Speaker 6:  but then Qualcomm bought them and said no, make the next generation of Snapdragon.
Speaker 6:  So I shifted them, I dunno if you know there's some backstory here.
Speaker 6:  Arm decided that Qualcomm's license didn't cover this. And so
Speaker 6:  ARM is suing Qualcomm right now and Qualcomm's suing arm back
Speaker 6:  over these chips, which is bananas.
Speaker 6:  It's gonna come to some resolution. There's no way this actually like ends
Speaker 6:  up in anything but payments. But these chips are like
Speaker 6:  very, very controversial in their way 'cause it's a bunch of ex apple designers
Speaker 6:  who left and started a company and Qualcomm snap them up to go compete with
Speaker 6:  Apple's consumer chips. Can they deliver is a big
Speaker 6:  question. I'm excited to see our reviews and and see if that's true. Same
Speaker 6:  also this lawsuit is just the funniest lawsuit in the world. It's a good
Speaker 6:  lawsuit. Like if you're armed you're like screw it's Sue Qualcomm.
Speaker 7:  I feel like Qual Qu Kong gets sued a lot. Thank you. Like every time you
Speaker 7:  turn around somebody's like, no, I hate you Broadcom's. Like I'm suing you
Speaker 7:  Apple like I'm suing you mean? Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  This company is under fire and by the way we talk a lot about 5G on the show.
Speaker 6:  The, the level of interest in six G is at
Speaker 6:  least partially driven by people wanting to get away from Qualcomm's
Speaker 6:  5G patents. Like what if, what if there wasn't
Speaker 6:  a dominant player in wireless that we could get away from?
Speaker 6:  And so you, there's already talk about six G just to get away from Qualcomm.
Speaker 6:  Like Apple bought all of Intel's modem division and they still haven't produced
Speaker 6:  a radio that can compete with Qualcomm and its patents. Get ready for the
Speaker 6:  six G hype cycle. That's I'm, oh God is people love suing this company and
Speaker 6:  that's gonna drive the six G hype cycle. Some other stuff we should talk
Speaker 6:  about. This is kind of like a like a gadget rapid fire round.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Is that what we wanna call it? It's not quite a linear around. We've
Speaker 6:  learned some new stuff outta WWC about various Apple products.
Speaker 6:  Jen had a pretty good scoop. Apple is extending home
Speaker 6:  kit to use the ultra wideband ship in its phones to
Speaker 6:  automatically unlock doors, which is cool. So
Speaker 6:  a combination of ultra wideband and Bluetooth low energy. It can
Speaker 6:  sense when you are six feet away from your door on the outside and walking
Speaker 6:  towards it and automatically unlock the door, which
Speaker 7:  Is just sick
Speaker 6:  If
Speaker 8:  It
Speaker 7:  Worked.
Speaker 6:  But if you have a smart door lock, you need a new door lock to enable this.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. None
Speaker 7:  Of 'em work with it. This is,
Speaker 6:  It's a lot. Alex is he making face? I got two Alex's. Alex this is last
Speaker 6:  names only.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, last names only. This reminds me of the digital id, the driver's
Speaker 8:  license thing. Like it just seems like a bad idea. Like I get
Speaker 8:  that it sounds cool like you're in a product meeting and Cupertino and it's
Speaker 8:  like, oh we should digitize this but I don't really want my
Speaker 8:  device automatically unlocking my house.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah, yeah. You're well so the argument I felt
Speaker 6:  this way about
Speaker 6:  the feature where You can just point your phone at a door lock and it unlocks
Speaker 6:  like You can in express mode. But same way that if you use mass transit,
Speaker 6:  You can just like beep your phone at a trend style on the subway and it just
Speaker 6:  pays and like whatever. And I was like, I don't know, I, I definitely wanna
Speaker 6:  authenticate before. And I was like, no, if you steal my cow key,
Speaker 6:  you're in my house. Like the level of security is the same. And I think one
Speaker 6:  good question is like whether that is an acceptable level of security,
Speaker 6:  like it is I guess is the answer. Like if you have my phone,
Speaker 6:  can you, should you be able to get in my house? It's like a good question
Speaker 6:  everyone should ask and then You can adjust that setting however you want.
Speaker 6:  If you have my phone, you're six feet away from my house and you're walking
Speaker 6:  towards it, should the house automatically walk? It's, it's like earned it.
Speaker 6:  A different question like that. That's a new, I
Speaker 8:  Would like this feature if you could set it to where if face IID
Speaker 8:  hadn't been used in say an hour or two hours, then it doesn't work.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. But something like that, something where like the recency of me unlocking
Speaker 8:  the device means that it's definitely in my hand. You know?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. All right. Or you, you, your phone has been stolen and another iPhone
Speaker 6:  detects you shrieking into which void and your, your house locks down
Speaker 6:  like, like the bizarre use of the find My network.
Speaker 6:  It's interesting 'cause Apple has put a lot of chips and a lot of radios
Speaker 6:  and a lot of things recently and hasn't really done
Speaker 6:  a lot with them. So these ultra wideband chips have been in a lot of Apple
Speaker 6:  devices for quite a while now. And some of the uses are
Speaker 6:  cool, right? Like find my is a little bit more precise. If you have
Speaker 6:  the right selection of ultra wideband devices, You can
Speaker 6:  like point your phone at a home pod and send the music to it. Which is, you
Speaker 6:  know, supposedly like magic.
Speaker 7:  It it, it works half the time.
Speaker 6:  So I said supposedly like magic, like if you were a shit magician.
Speaker 6:  Yeah it works about that.
Speaker 7:  If I, if I did magic, that would be my magic trick. Like look
Speaker 6:  Yeah, you know what, you know those people are like I'm floating and they're
Speaker 6:  really just like standing on their tiptoes. That's me. That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 6:  But if you're always doing that, it's sort of the wrong angle and someone's
Speaker 6:  like you're just standing on your tiptoes. That's about how well the home
Speaker 6:  pod thing works.
Speaker 6:  Then they added thread radius gen, that was the other gen scoop from a couple
Speaker 6:  weeks ago. Like now they're adding other radios to these devices.
Speaker 6:  You see that they're like, okay wifi and Bluetooth can't do
Speaker 6:  all the things we want to do. They can't do it at the power level,
Speaker 6:  at the location, precision level, whatever. It's
Speaker 6:  that just can't do it. So we need to add more radius to this thing.
Speaker 6:  And then you see that animations for the new Siri
Speaker 6:  and you're like, oh they are super getting ready to take all the ports and
Speaker 6:  buttons. These Oh yeah, stop
Speaker 7:  You. You willing?
Speaker 6:  There's like, there's 45 different radios for every level of like
Speaker 6:  precision location and power that You can think of. None of
Speaker 6:  them aren't able to do much and then the buttons are gonna be capacitive
Speaker 6:  very soon. The
Speaker 8:  Arc of phones is that they just become panes of glass
Speaker 8:  that then start to curve that we then put in front of our eyes like
Speaker 8:  that is, that is the next 10 years of technology.
Speaker 6:  I wanna come back, I wanna come back to that. Lemme talk about that. And
Speaker 6:  the vision pro to some extent. So that's the UWB chip.
Speaker 6:  We're seeing Apple start to use it in more interesting ways, especially around
Speaker 6:  the home. I'm very curious if they ever acknowledge these thread radios.
Speaker 6:  We were kind of hoping they would at wwc. But it's interesting that
Speaker 6:  there's a bunch of thread radios in these devices you could do all kinds
Speaker 6:  of things with in a smart home. 'cause it used basically no power
Speaker 6:  compared to everything else. And then the other thing we found out, which
Speaker 6:  is really interesting speaking of apple and wireless is that the next generation
Speaker 6:  of CarPlay that no one has shipped yet will only be wireless.
Speaker 6:  Which is fascinating. So I, you know, I'm ob obviously obsessed with CarPlay
Speaker 6:  car cos are always on the coder. I'm always asking, they're gonna use it.
Speaker 6:  They're always like me. We'll see. So as you just
Speaker 6:  to set just to reset everyone's like understanding of CarPlay 'cause it's
Speaker 6:  very confusing right now. There's the CarPlay you have right now,
Speaker 6:  which is basically just like a second monitor for your phone. That's very
Speaker 6:  much what's going on. So you plug into your car, even a wireless CarPlay
Speaker 6:  your phone sends out another video stream and receives touch input from your
Speaker 6:  car and you've got a second monitor for a phone And. if you think about it,
Speaker 6:  almost everything that's happening on that screen is just phone stuff, right?
Speaker 6:  It's music, it's maps, but it's all just running on your phone and showing
Speaker 6:  up on this display. Not a lot of car stuff over there. Apple has
Speaker 6:  lightly extended this to be able to send a map to some instrument
Speaker 6:  clusters so they can send multiple video streams out from a phone. But it's
Speaker 6:  still phone stuff. Like everything's local on the phone without any
Speaker 6:  understanding of the data from the car. The next generation of CarPlay, which
Speaker 6:  they showed two years ago, I didn't even realize this was two years ago.
Speaker 6:  I thought this was last year, two years ago, WWC 2022, they showed
Speaker 6:  that mockup of like a giant screen and screen. Oh I remember.
Speaker 6:  And it's all CarPlay and there was like 45 clocks on it. 'cause no one looks
Speaker 6:  to do with all that screen the weather in 10 different cities, which you
Speaker 6:  definitely need when you're driving. And they're like, this is the next generation
Speaker 6:  of CarPlay. And then they showed a bunch of car maker logos. Do you remember
Speaker 6:  this? They showed a bunch of car maker logos and all those car makers like
Speaker 6:  what? That was basically what happened.
Speaker 6:  Porsche and Aspen Martin announced last year they would ship cars this year.
Speaker 6:  Haven't heard a word about those cars. No idea when they're coming out.
Speaker 6:  And that's it. So Apple had sessions at
Speaker 6:  this year's wwc and I ran around and talked to a bunch of people there just
Speaker 6:  about CarPlay and what's going on.
Speaker 6:  And I can't tell if this is a
Speaker 6:  change in strategy, if this has always been the approach
Speaker 6:  or if this is just Apple softening its language. But
Speaker 6:  Apple's basically saying to car makers, look
Speaker 6:  people have iPhones, they love CarPlay. What if you
Speaker 6:  used our design toolkit to redesign all of the stuff in your car. So it all
Speaker 6:  looked really good together and then you needed an iPhone.
Speaker 8:  Is it the context here that Apple just abandoned Project Titan? So
Speaker 8:  if they're not doing a fully integrated vehicle, wouldn't it make
Speaker 8:  sense for them to make this more of an open, this to me is like them going
Speaker 8:  the route of Apple TV plus and Airplay realizing that
Speaker 8:  we are not gonna make a TV and so therefore we want TV plus
Speaker 8:  everywhere. Is that not a fair analogy here?
Speaker 6:  I can't necessarily tell how much Titan played into it, right? Like
Speaker 6:  this is what I'm saying. I can't tell if this was always the approach and
Speaker 6:  now they're just softening the language. Like the technical approach
Speaker 6:  is that you have an iPhone, you connect to CarPlay, your iPhone will
Speaker 6:  go download a bunch of Apple car maker
Speaker 6:  co-branded assets. Like in the videos they have posted, they refer to this
Speaker 6:  as a co-branded experience. When have you ever heard Apple describe anything
Speaker 6:  as a co-branded experience? That's bananas Red.
Speaker 6:  Sure. Project Red
Speaker 8:  Windows on the Mac like at the very beginning.
Speaker 6:  That wasn't co-branded. So like there's some element of Apple designers and
Speaker 6:  car maker designers like working together to design
Speaker 6:  speedometers for CarPlay cars. Huh? Weird. And like
Speaker 6:  in the, this is public. I'm not, this isn't like some deep dark reporting.
Speaker 6:  I mean this is me saying You can go watch the videos. They're public and
Speaker 6:  they're calling it a co-branded experience where we're gonna work together
Speaker 6:  to express your car maker brand identity
Speaker 6:  inside of the Apple Design toolkit.
Speaker 7:  Weird. It makes sense in that all the cars
Speaker 7:  UIs are terrible.
Speaker 6:  It does. So the idea is you have an iPhone and you get this like upgrade
Speaker 6:  to your car ui. So everything looks like CarPlay. Yeah. Weird. How is Apple
Speaker 6:  gonna make any money doing this? No.
Speaker 7:  Like first of all, I think that's like a, I mean for a super wealthy company
Speaker 7:  like this, this is just like really good branding, right? I think it's about
Speaker 7:  You can go and, I mean show your, I mean You can show your, your dominance
Speaker 7:  in design and, and show these companies like
Speaker 6:  How you, so the, the specific way they're gonna show their dominance in design.
Speaker 6:  It's actually my favorite part of whole thing. Okay? The only font you're
Speaker 6:  allowed to use in next generation CarPlay is Apple San Francisco.
Speaker 6:  You can, You can change how wide it is. You can change how stretched it is.
Speaker 6:  You can italicize it. You can make it really thin. You know, like, and they're
Speaker 6:  like, look at all these different things You can do with this font. It's
Speaker 6:  a variable typeface. And it's like, yeah but it's only one like Porsche
Speaker 6:  and GM don't get to use different fonts.
Speaker 7:  Comic sands
Speaker 6:  Get get right? Like that's weird. Like so there's an element of control
Speaker 6:  where they're just, they're doing a very Apple thing. And then there's an
Speaker 6:  element of complete chaos, which I think is really fascinating, which they
Speaker 6:  have not talked about at all. Which is they will, when you
Speaker 6:  have like the next generation CarPlay interface up and you're like,
Speaker 6:  I want to control my massaging seats and my Aston Martin You
Speaker 6:  can push the button that says Control the Apple San Francisco
Speaker 6:  labeled button. And instead of showing you the next nice CarPlay
Speaker 6:  thing, it'll do a thing called punching through the automaker UI and it'll
Speaker 6:  just show you whatever garbage Aston Martin, no nevermind
Speaker 7:  Seats. Oh man, nevermind. I take it all back.
Speaker 6:  It's like, this is crazy. I can't, that's like, this is, this is the concession
Speaker 6:  to make it all. Okay, I can't because what car makers have been worried about
Speaker 6:  is they have to build everything three times. They have to build their own
Speaker 6:  native one. 'cause you need to have something you, you need to operate the
Speaker 6:  entire car without a phone. Right? A non-negotiable. If you buy a car,
Speaker 6:  then you need the next generation CarPlay version of everything and then
Speaker 6:  presumably Google will do something for Android, right? So what are you gonna
Speaker 6:  do? And they don't wanna build things three times. So Apple solution is like,
Speaker 6:  well build it once and then, you know, for some stuff we'll just let you
Speaker 6:  show the weird stuff. I, I can't
Speaker 8:  Wait for Siri powered by Chachi PT in my car to
Speaker 8:  just like open the doors like while I'm driving, when I request the massage
Speaker 8:  seat to turn on and it just hallucinates and you know, it just
Speaker 6:  Like freaking completely. Yeah, just goes in reverse.
Speaker 7:  Just ejects you.
Speaker 6:  And then to bring this around, apple wants this to only work
Speaker 6:  wirelessly because their goal is that CarPlay will be
Speaker 6:  connected, active in operating the interface of your car
Speaker 6:  by the time you open the door. And if not, by the time you open the door,
Speaker 6:  by the time the screen's light up, right? So you get in the car, you sit
Speaker 6:  down, the screens light up, it's CarPlay, it should not
Speaker 6:  be, you sit down in your car, turn it on and then like you have some like
Speaker 6:  loading process. And so You can only accomplish that over wireless. So CarPlay
Speaker 6:  is only gonna be wireless for whatever car makers adopt the next generation
Speaker 6:  CarPlay.
Speaker 7:  I'm hesitant to say this because I am very against this
Speaker 7:  move. But isn't that also just a precursor to them removing all the
Speaker 7:  ports? They're like, it's gotta be wireless because we're gonna,
Speaker 6:  It's not, not a precursor to them removing all the ports. And
Speaker 6:  it's funny because to make this work, apple also
Speaker 6:  has to give up some control of what runs where,
Speaker 6:  right? You don't want your speedometer running on the phone. So
Speaker 6:  Apple, your Apple designed speedometer or
Speaker 6:  delightful co-branded experience to be more accurate needs to run locally
Speaker 6:  on the car. So this is the first time I can think of that any Apple assets
Speaker 6:  are gonna get loaded onto somebody else's computer system in that way.
Speaker 6:  Outside of, to your point E, the Apple TV plus app, unlike
Speaker 6:  Rokus, right? Which is where apple ships an app and this is the, the,
Speaker 6:  the split is kinda the same. It's like okay you're gonna, we're gonna give
Speaker 6:  you an asset package of Apple things to run locally on the car
Speaker 6:  for things that we cannot risk if there's a disconnect.
Speaker 6:  The speedometer, the turn signals, da da da da, right? And there's some
Speaker 6:  differentiation in how that stuff works. Like the truly critical stuff cannot
Speaker 6:  be touched. They call that the overlay layer. That's your turn signals and
Speaker 6:  hazard indicators, the speedometer and stuff like the needles, that's those
Speaker 6:  assets can get refreshed over time. So those run in a different layer called
Speaker 6:  local UI. And then there's everything that runs on the phone.
Speaker 6:  And then in the middle there's like, I don't know, you wanna like mess with
Speaker 6:  your sports settings in the, in your fast car. Like that'll just be the weird
Speaker 6:  automaker UI shining through CarPlay and it's like, oh this kind of feels
Speaker 6:  like a mess. Right?
Speaker 6:  It's unclear who will take this and who will
Speaker 6:  use all of CarPlay like redesign the entire car to be CarPlay
Speaker 6:  to be Apple. And who will say okay, we took next generation CarPlay,
Speaker 6:  we fun, cool new speedometer. Every other part of the car controls
Speaker 6:  will be the existing ui. 'cause we can punch through CarPlay. And
Speaker 6:  honestly based on the feedback we get on the show, it's like some of our
Speaker 6:  audience will pick the car makers that use all CarPlay. Like they will
Speaker 6:  make an affirmative decision to be like, you know what that car maker Toyota
Speaker 6:  uses all of CarPlay, we're going with them over Honda. Which is like, here's
Speaker 6:  your weird heated seats. Well the
Speaker 8:  Third path is Rivian or Tesla, right? Where it's totally controlled by
Speaker 8:  the automaker. And like Rivian is a great example of, I think you and
Speaker 8:  I both test driven Rivian Eli. Like I think their interface is great.
Speaker 8:  It's very snappy. Obviously I miss some of the iPhone connection,
Speaker 8:  but I could also see more automakers going that
Speaker 8:  direction.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  But they have to make good user interfaces. Rivian is good. That is a big
Speaker 7:  difference between, yeah, no, that runs unreal. Like Rivian and Tesla
Speaker 7:  made good user interfaces for the most part. Tesla. Everybody else
Speaker 6:  For the most weirder, I would say for the most part
Speaker 8:  Tesla's like, you turn the car on, but everybody else talking like you wanna
Speaker 8:  like play a game on Netflix, you know, it's,
Speaker 6:  But it's a lovely experience. So Rivian just upgraded in the, the
Speaker 6:  rivian, the generation two R one trucks just came out.
Speaker 6:  They've changed some the, the ar the computing architecture of those is different.
Speaker 6:  But then they also updated the interface to be more self shaded. I mean they
Speaker 6:  have like unreal engine and the, they like using it. That said, I looked
Speaker 6:  to the parking lot at Apple Park when we were at WW c. A lot
Speaker 6:  of those people have riv. Oh yeah. Right. And there's all these rumors about
Speaker 6:  Apple and Rivian doing stuff together. Apple music just came to the Rivian
Speaker 6:  interface. If, if Tesla's never gonna break,
Speaker 6:  I feel confident about that one. Just a prediction I'll make based on nothing.
Speaker 6:  I don't,
Speaker 8:  The Tesla UI is gonna be x.com in a few years. That's the direction
Speaker 6:  S like it'll be Brock like fully just like telling dirty jokes. We try to
Speaker 6:  drive the car Rivian Yeah. Is still in the place
Speaker 6:  where they might try some other stuff to claw back some market share
Speaker 6:  to win some new buyers. And there are an awful lot of Rivian. Mm.
Speaker 6:  It's California people like people like trucks there. But it's something
Speaker 6:  I noticed. All right, moving on. See it's like a fast
Speaker 6:  round. Not quite lightning. We're just moving
Speaker 6:  Kranz. Tell me about this remote because you're very excited about a home
Speaker 6:  remote and I
Speaker 7:  About this you, you know I love a home remote. I'm still sad about Logitech.
Speaker 7:  I still have the like the fanciest of the Logitech remotes and it had soft
Speaker 7:  touch plastic. Oh my God. Which means it's starting to rot.
Speaker 6:  I have my, I have TiVo remote in the corner of this house. It's like not
Speaker 6:  a good, not
Speaker 7:  A good situation. It's so bad. Like the rot on that soft touch is so gross.
Speaker 7:  But there's a, there's a Kickstarter happening right now for the haptic
Speaker 7:  RS 90 and the RS 90 x and they promise all the stuff, all
Speaker 7:  the big universal remotes promise, which is like You can control stuff via
Speaker 7:  Bluetooth. You can control it via ir. You can control it via wifi.
Speaker 7:  Usually that requires some sort of hub that you have to plug in somewhere
Speaker 7:  in your house. This appears to require no hub and also
Speaker 7:  it's just got a big screen on it. So it's instantly the coolest remote You
Speaker 7:  can have in your house and it can, it's supposed to be able to control all
Speaker 7:  their smart homes and stuff. And like I said, Logitech did this. I've got
Speaker 7:  a control that does this, doesn't have the cool screen
Speaker 7:  and it required a hub. So this is instantly cooler
Speaker 7:  and this also is gonna come soon rather than discontinue.
Speaker 6:  Well it's a Kickstarter are actually gonna ship
Speaker 7:  Kickstarter. There's like the Kickstarter part of this is the really big
Speaker 7:  heavy caveat because there's a whole bunch of integrations that they're promising.
Speaker 8:  No,
Speaker 7:  Not there yet. There's no matter support, there's,
Speaker 7:  there's no support for some of the other smaller like radios and stuff like
Speaker 7:  that. So this is like cool
Speaker 7:  neat.
Speaker 6:  We're like two minutes away from Samsung being like Bixby
Speaker 6:  AI and your TV will not do everything for you. I
Speaker 7:  Don't want it. It's coming. We though coming. We are. It's coming. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like AI is probably, you know the reason Loge got out of this business was
Speaker 7:  because they said nobody wants these. No. And and me and four other people
Speaker 7:  were like, oh
Speaker 8:  I want my phone to be my universal home remote. That's it. I
Speaker 8:  don't want another remote. I want fewer remotes. Can we make that happen?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I just, I, that's how I use my phone.
Speaker 8:  But like I, I'm just getting like who is
Speaker 8:  this for I guess is the question For me.
Speaker 6:  It's me, me. What should I thought Alex?
Speaker 7:  It's, it's me and four other people. It's the four people who are still sad
Speaker 7:  that are Logitech remotes stack.
Speaker 6:  Whenever I see a screen like this, I just think about how slow it will be.
Speaker 6:  I knew I think about touching a button and nothing happening, right? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like yeah and I love it. I'm like yeah I want a screen like this. But you
Speaker 6:  know that thing you do with a touchscreen where you touch it and the button
Speaker 6:  looks like something happened but nothing happened. That's this product.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Almost like a guarantee that that is this product. It is. I will say
Speaker 6:  it is. I love that. It's called the Haptic RS 90. Great name.
Speaker 6:  Great name for a universal remote, fully good name. Name.
Speaker 6:  I just worry that actually people just use the apps in our
Speaker 6:  smart TV and what this thing is trying to solve is not,
Speaker 6:  I mean that's why Logitech got outta the business. So like we, we can't control
Speaker 6:  the apps in your tv. We can't see your tv.
Speaker 7:  Yep. Yeah. The will. So we'll see how this is
Speaker 7:  it. It's, it looks like it's gonna be funded. It looks like enough people
Speaker 7:  have invested in it. It's gonna be funded. This
Speaker 6:  Is like hot on the heels of that company. Brilliant going outta business.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Which Jen covered and they were like, we're gonna business but like
Speaker 6:  the thing we put in your wall will still work So brilliant.
Speaker 6:  And put like a touch screen in your wall that can control everything. Which
Speaker 6:  I was super hype on. 'cause the idea of having an in-wall sono
Speaker 6:  controller screen seems sick, right? You walk into a room and you're like,
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna pick a song a boop. I'm not using my phone like the whole thing.
Speaker 6:  And then they just like went outta business and it's like that is always
Speaker 6:  the worry I have with all of these things. Yeah. Speaking. Oh
Speaker 7:  Go ahead. This is gonna be like almost $400 probably. Perfect when it comes
Speaker 7:  out. That's too much.
Speaker 6:  All right, speaking. Oh let's do one more gadget and then I want to talk
Speaker 6:  about what's going on in AR and VR with Heath. We mentioned Risk V at the
Speaker 6:  top and we mentioned companies. I'm like Go Outta Business
Speaker 6:  framework is shipping the laptop 13. Which is
Speaker 6:  fascinating 'cause they're gonna have a risk V chip in it. This is the competitor
Speaker 6:  arm, right? This is the open source competitor arm that has the
Speaker 6:  performance per watt characteristics.
Speaker 6:  I'm kind of dying to try it out. I'm also, I have no idea what software I
Speaker 6:  could run.
Speaker 7:  Also I, I think one guy pointed out that it runs, it'll run
Speaker 7:  about as fast as a Raspberry PI four. Yes.
Speaker 6:  You gotta start somewhere. Baby steps. Baby
Speaker 7:  Steps, baby steps. Yeah. I have no idea what
Speaker 7:  can run this but I wanna like, this just is cool.
Speaker 7:  This is the kind of thing I just wanna have one.
Speaker 6:  I like how the, the actual line from the company
Speaker 6:  in the PR is the main board is extremely compelling. But we should be
Speaker 6:  clear that in this generation it is focused primarily on enabling
Speaker 6:  developers, tinkerers and hobbyists to start testing and creating and risky
Speaker 6:  like don't use this. The per the peripheral set and performance aren't yet
Speaker 6:  competitive with our Intel and a MD powered framework main. It's like,
Speaker 6:  yeah. Ooh. This is just to play with, I will say
Speaker 7:  EMC storage.
Speaker 6:  The risk, the nerds in our audience have been very excited at Risky
Speaker 6:  for a very long time. 'cause ARM is a like dominant
Speaker 6:  quasi monopolist now. Like the arm architecture license is the
Speaker 6:  thing and there hasn't been anything to compete with it. Which is why
Speaker 6:  everybody is moving to it, including Microsoft. 'cause
Speaker 6:  if you want performance for wat you end up on this architecture, which means
Speaker 6:  companies like Qualcomm and being able to dominate the market right next
Speaker 6:  to Apple. And you need an architecture license from ARM
Speaker 6:  to expand beyond it and ARM isn't giving this up anymore. Which
Speaker 6:  is part of the reason they're suing Qualcomm. 'cause Qualcomm is saying the
Speaker 6:  NUVIA chips fall under its architecture license and ARM says no. So
Speaker 6:  there's all this stuff that's wrapped up when you have one dominant architecture
Speaker 6:  that is owned by a company And Risk V is the thing.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  The open source source was it, was it
Speaker 6:  Nvidia? Not quite as fast as a Raspberry PI four. But it's the thing that
Speaker 6:  might break it.
Speaker 7:  Was it Nvidia that tried to buy Arm a couple years ago?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah, yeah. It was So ARM was, I mean the the finances are Arm are
Speaker 6:  hilarious, right? Like it was, it's a weird English company
Speaker 6:  that started licensing these designs. It got SoftBank bought it, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. and it was part of the vision fund. They, in the heady days
Speaker 6:  of the SoftBank Vision Fund where Maan was like, everything I touch will
Speaker 6:  be a monopoly. It didn't work out. You might recall it. WeWork
Speaker 6:  blew that entire business up. They tried to, they they started
Speaker 6:  divesting of assets. They were gonna sell Arm. Nvidia wanted to buy it. Basically
Speaker 6:  everyone yelled like everyone yelled, apple yelled qual like
Speaker 6:  all the architecture licenses were like you cannot let our competitor buy
Speaker 6:  this company. They said No Arm is now public instead. Which is a good
Speaker 6:  outcome or bad fun
Speaker 8:  Fact arm going public made up for all the losses the vision fund has had
Speaker 8:  for the last 10 years.
Speaker 6:  That's crazy.
Speaker 6:  Somewhere somewhere that WeWork people are like, God damn,
Speaker 7:  They're just launching a new product. Don't worry about
Speaker 6:  Mean it's like I could have changed the world.
Speaker 6:  It a lifestyle.
Speaker 6:  I watched one episode of We Crash and I was like I can't live this again.
Speaker 6:  Oh it's so bad. I hon I cannot be a part of this again. Yeah. Alright, let's
Speaker 6:  wrap up by talking about AR and VR Heath, you've got a Scoop meta just
Speaker 6:  reorganized Reality Labs. Talk about that. The Vision Pro team is trying
Speaker 6:  to make a cheaper headset. There's a lot of action here. What's going on?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, maybe we'll start with Vision Pro. The information had a good
Speaker 8:  story out confirming and putting more details on what Gerin
Speaker 8:  and others have reported that Apple is indeed working on a cheaper vision
Speaker 8:  pro. They hope to release it by the end of next year and they
Speaker 8:  have shelved a future iteration of V
Speaker 8:  two of the Vision Pro as it is today. So another high end, very
Speaker 8:  expensive one. They're trying to get this cheaper, one more into the ballpark
Speaker 8:  of a, you know, premium top of the line iPhone price. So we're talking
Speaker 8:  12 to $1,500. I had heard even before the
Speaker 8:  Vision Pro came out that Apple was already working on this cheaper version.
Speaker 8:  Apparently when Mark Zuckerberg was talking to me and others and basically
Speaker 8:  saying I'm going to scorch the earth with cheap headsets forever
Speaker 8:  and not really care about making a business, which we will get to in the
Speaker 8:  next story. Apple was like, oh okay we need to
Speaker 8:  like really work on a, on a cheap one and get it out. So
Speaker 8:  they've been working on it for already a couple years. I do expect we'll
Speaker 8:  see it next year whether it ships next year or TBD
Speaker 8:  And I think, you know, I've only used the Vision Pro once in that
Speaker 8:  initial demo that we all had at WDC last year, Eli, but I would
Speaker 8:  think that, you know, if it was in the ballpark of $1,500,
Speaker 8:  I would maybe pull the trigger even if the OS and the software hadn't
Speaker 8:  meaningfully gotten better just because of, you know, the
Speaker 8:  immersiveness of it. I kind of, it's just at 3000 it's just like it's,
Speaker 8:  it's out of touch for most people. Yeah. And it's still out of touch at
Speaker 8:  1500 but it's much more of a almost impulse buy for some people
Speaker 8:  at 1500. So yeah. and it will get
Speaker 8:  hopefully more developers interested but yeah, Apple's plugging away
Speaker 8:  on and I, and I think what we're, what the, the other part of this, the fact
Speaker 8:  that they are canceling the more expensive one or
Speaker 8:  shelving, it just goes to show that they packed so
Speaker 8:  much tech into this thing that it may not actually
Speaker 8:  be a good product and they may and
Speaker 6:  We
Speaker 8:  Kind of like have found that out already. Neli, you talk about how you don't
Speaker 8:  use the Vision Pro anymore. It's a great demo. Honestly
Speaker 8:  it was probably top three demos I've ever done of technology
Speaker 8:  and it's something that I consistently hear people do not use after the first
Speaker 8:  couple weeks. So
Speaker 7:  Would you say this was a Homer car?
Speaker 6:  No, I mean it's not like that ridiculous, right? Like yeah, okay. Like it
Speaker 6:  had some focus. They wanted it to be something I think about the fact that
Speaker 6:  it was a great demo. I so much of technology right now is like great demos
Speaker 6:  to fall apart as a product, right? Yeah. And that was the vision pro to a
Speaker 6:  t and I every AI demo so far has been
Speaker 6:  that from, unless you have some very narrow use case where AI can
Speaker 6:  solve a problem consistently for you, every other demo is like what? What?
Speaker 6:  I dunno if I would do that. The Vision Pro they have to make a big decision.
Speaker 6:  And here is the thing that I noticed at WWC that I've been thinking about
Speaker 6:  in that opening keynote video when they were like start when jumping off
Speaker 6:  the plane. Yeah. And they were like doing the introduction and everyone was
Speaker 6:  wearing their flight suits. Do you remember this vividly ridiculous bombastic
Speaker 6:  opening.
Speaker 6:  They had Mike Rockwell on the plane who's the, he's in charge of the Vision
Speaker 6:  Pro and he turns to the camera with the eyes on and they
Speaker 6:  played it for laughs. The eyes were a joke and it,
Speaker 8:  Those eyes, those eyes aren't shipping anymore. I can tell you that. That
Speaker 6:  That's what, this is what I'm saying the idea, if you remember the
Speaker 6:  initial Vision Pro stuff was like the eyes will place you in
Speaker 6:  the environment. They're very, they were so serious about the eyes.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so serious. Like dead serious about the eyes. I asked in
Speaker 6:  one of our briefings, 'cause you know the only question I asked anybody during
Speaker 6:  our Vision Pro briefings where have two of you ever
Speaker 6:  looked at each other with the eyes? Like have, have two people ever existed
Speaker 6:  in the same room wearing a Vision pro? And if when you looked at each other
Speaker 6:  with the eyes, did you laugh? And they were like, that's not funny.
Speaker 6:  'cause they were dead serious that this thing would bring you into the environment.
Speaker 6:  They meant it. They were very, yeah, it was sincere in that Apple
Speaker 6:  New age sincerity way. Like when you go to Apple Park and you walk
Speaker 6:  towards the theater, they play new age music at you and they're dead sincere
Speaker 6:  about it. Yes. And I'm like, this makes me feel like I'm in a cult. There's
Speaker 6:  a gap there between like how sincere Apple can be and then the world.
Speaker 6:  And they were super sincere that these eyes would be the thing that
Speaker 6:  enabled you to wear a headset all the time.
Speaker 8:  No, let's be real. They did the Eyes because they wanted to be able to not
Speaker 8:  call it a VR headset.
Speaker 6:  Right. Well so this is what I'm getting at. Yeah. This next version, this
Speaker 6:  cheaper version, they have to decide if this is a VR headset or an AR
Speaker 6:  headset. I will. And playing the Eyes for laughs was the thing
Speaker 6:  that signaled to me, okay, this is gonna be a view,
Speaker 8:  I will bet
Speaker 8:  strongly that there will not be the eyes in any Future Vision Pro
Speaker 8:  product. And I'll tell you why.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's just a bunch of costs for reason. Right. Well yes.
Speaker 7:  No one's taking you on that bet. We like our money.
Speaker 6:  I'll take that bet. The, I still, it was a Johnny
Speaker 8:  I thing, I know this from talking to people who worked on the, the Vision
Speaker 8:  Pro. It was Johnny Ive who insisted that the eyes ship,
Speaker 8:  I don't know the exact dollar amount, but it added an absurd amount of cost
Speaker 8:  and manufacturing complex complexity to the Vision Pro
Speaker 8:  because they
Speaker 7:  Had to do that curved glass.
Speaker 6:  Well the curved gra the curved glass was, or that
Speaker 7:  Curved glass in the display
Speaker 8:  Of the side. Right. It was the, the front facing O-L-E-D-I think it's an
Speaker 8:  O-O-L-E-D right. Anyway, with the, with the eyes.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it are very low eyes. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  It added an absurd amount of cost. No one wanted to ship it except Johnny
Speaker 8:  and his people and they've all left. And so, and they're making
Speaker 8:  a joke about it in keynote videos. So yeah, I don't think, I don't think
Speaker 8:  the eyes are long for this world,
Speaker 6:  But, so if you get rid of that and you're like, you're not now, you cannot
Speaker 6:  be perceived by other people in the world. The thing is a VR headset. Yep.
Speaker 6:  Right? And that to me is concession in one
Speaker 6:  way, right? Like they talked about this thing as ar ar ar, ar,
Speaker 6:  but if you can't wear it with other people like in VR headset and then everything
Speaker 6:  they've announced since is immersive, right?
Speaker 6:  New immersive videos, new experiences, new immersive games and it's like,
Speaker 6:  oh this is becoming a VR headset and a 1500 VR headset. Right now
Speaker 6:  the state of the state of the art, there is a pretty good product, right?
Speaker 6:  Like You can make something great for $1,500 in vr. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And I guess that maybe brings us to Meta, right? Should we, should
Speaker 8:  we go to that? Yeah. So yeah, meta obviously was first to this spot
Speaker 8:  Oculus a long time ago. They restructured Reality
Speaker 8:  Labs, the division that does all of their hardware and
Speaker 8:  horizon that cursed platform.
Speaker 8:  This week I had the scoop and command line. They're forming two new groups.
Speaker 8:  So Reality Labs is now Metaverse and Wearables. So
Speaker 8:  you'll notice there is no VR in those two phrases,
Speaker 8:  right? The the the Rift, I'm sorry, God, look how
Speaker 8:  the Rift, wow. The Quest is now under Metaverse
Speaker 8:  reporting to Vishal Shaw who used to run ads at Instagram and is a software
Speaker 8:  guy. So you basically have the, the thing that created this
Speaker 8:  whole org that the company really bet its future on is a
Speaker 8:  subdivision of a software org. Meanwhile, Wearables,
Speaker 8:  I'm told, is leaning heavily into the Ray bands. I
Speaker 8:  published this internal memo from Boz, the CTO, basically saying that
Speaker 8:  the Ray bands have been a much bigger hit than any of us anticipated.
Speaker 8:  Zuckerberg and others have been kind of alluding to this throughout the year.
Speaker 8:  I've heard that it's somewhere in the ballpark of a million-ish units
Speaker 8:  that they've sold, which is three to four x the first version of the Ray
Speaker 8:  bands. And they're seeing really good retention in the product. So people
Speaker 8:  are actually using it consistently. I have them,
Speaker 8:  I had, I have the AI turned on in them. I wrote in Command Line
Speaker 8:  a few weeks ago. I'm not trying to pat myself on the back, but I will just
Speaker 8:  saying that Meta is quietly winning the AI
Speaker 8:  wearable race here because the Raybans are something that
Speaker 8:  Meta has not done in a while. You could argue
Speaker 8:  maybe ever but shipped a really good consumer product.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, you're, you're a hundred percent right.
Speaker 8:  It's something that, that like normal people, like something that tech people
Speaker 8:  like because it's got the AI and yeah, the AI still hallucinates, but it's
Speaker 8:  very fast and it's right like maybe half the time,
Speaker 8:  right? So like I pointed at a tree in my backyard and I say, what is this
Speaker 8:  tree and how do I water it? It got it right. So like that's not, it's still
Speaker 8:  a demo, right? It's not like I'm, it's not gonna like change the world, but
Speaker 8:  in a couple years You can see where that's going and it's like, oh, if I
Speaker 8:  have reliable visual AI in Ray bands,
Speaker 8:  I may not UI may use my phone less. Which is the reason that is doing all
Speaker 8:  this by the way. So they are putting way more resources
Speaker 8:  behind the RayBan line and they also have these full
Speaker 8:  fledged AR glasses that they've been working on since 2018. Code
Speaker 8:  named Orion, which are insanely expensive. They cost thousands of dollars
Speaker 8:  to make, I have heard from people inside Meta
Speaker 8:  that it's a again, incredible demo. They really feel
Speaker 8:  like they've gotten there on the, on the hardware. They're not sure what
Speaker 8:  the software use cases will be yet. They're doing a lot of reviews of it
Speaker 8:  right now. I expect we'll get a tease of that later this year at Connect
Speaker 8:  their conference. So they have these two lines that
Speaker 8:  they're doing with glasses. They've got the AR glasses, which I leaked the
Speaker 8:  whole roadmap for Meta's Hardware a year or so ago.
Speaker 8:  So we know that the Ray bands are gonna be updated
Speaker 8:  next year with a little heads up display. So think more Google Glass,
Speaker 8:  less full AR Magic Leap. And they're gonna come with a
Speaker 8:  wristband that uses neural interface
Speaker 8:  technology from the startup Mebo called Control Labs
Speaker 8:  to control the display and to control some of the other inputs. 'cause You
Speaker 8:  can also like play podcasts through the, they have dis speakers in
Speaker 8:  the frames, right. That shipping next year that's gonna be
Speaker 8:  interesting. And then the AR glasses, the full fledged ones that are gonna
Speaker 8:  be more expensive and also have the band will be 2027. So
Speaker 8:  this is the path meta is on. They're going full on glasses
Speaker 8:  and really deprioritizing, they hate when I say this, but it
Speaker 8:  feels like that the Quest, because the Quest is still really struggling.
Speaker 8:  They're not really, they have some early product market fit with gaming,
Speaker 8:  but the retention is still not very good. I've heard. And the Quest
Speaker 8:  three, they, they got a lot of really good things about the mixed
Speaker 8:  reality, right? But it just, it's just not, I don't know why I wanna put
Speaker 8:  it on. Whereas the Ray bands, it's like, yeah, I get it. I have audio on
Speaker 8:  all the time. I can take calls, I can take photos and videos and I have AI
Speaker 8:  that is starting to work more and more. And by the way, they look like normal
Speaker 8:  glasses, right? Yeah. So it's just obvious that this is the
Speaker 8:  direction they should go. They seem to now be realizing that and they're
Speaker 8:  putting all their chips there and laying off some people as a result. So
Speaker 8:  that was the news outta meta this week.
Speaker 6:  So what's really interesting about Quest three is the rate of
Speaker 6:  innovation on the Quest three or improvement, I guess on the Quest three
Speaker 6:  skyrocketed after the vision broke came out. Yeah. They're like, oh, we should
Speaker 6:  ship a bunch of these features. Like I guess there's some competition. Like
Speaker 6:  here's, here's travel mode. We took it away, it's back. They
Speaker 6:  increase the fidelity of the pass through, right? Like just stuff that they
Speaker 6:  should have done, but they're still not, it's not winning. And even
Speaker 6:  Apple, if they come out with a 1500 version of the Vision Pro, they still
Speaker 6:  have to make the case for vr, right? Which, but Meta has been
Speaker 6:  trying for a long time. And now if Meta is saying, alright, it's these glass,
Speaker 6:  it's the thing that everyone always knew was the thing, right? It's
Speaker 6:  augmented reality glasses, we're actual light passes through to display
Speaker 6:  and you're looking at actual things instead of screens, and then we can put
Speaker 6:  some information near or around or over those real things.
Speaker 6:  Turns out that's the thing everybody has wanted the whole time. Look, why
Speaker 6:  would Apple continue to boondoggle its way towards the Vision Pro even at
Speaker 6:  $1,500?
Speaker 8:  Well, because they're on this path, right? Apple was working on
Speaker 8:  air glasses like Orion at Meta, and they basically
Speaker 8:  shelved it semi-recently in the last year or two for the headset
Speaker 8:  route. They think that if they can keep iterating on the headsets, they'll
Speaker 8:  figure out glasses eventually. Whereas Meta's like, no, we are going to have
Speaker 8:  glasses out in a few years and Apple's fine. They're always
Speaker 8:  late to this. Like, we all know that. So they'll come in late like they usually
Speaker 8:  do. I don't know if it'll be as late as they were with the Vision Pro, but
Speaker 8:  they're gonna be late and that's fine. But yeah, I think they're, they're
Speaker 8:  betting on productivity and being at home and coding and all these things
Speaker 8:  with Division Pro and Meta's like, no, we want you to lose
Speaker 8:  Meta's goal is to use your phone less because they hate being under Apple
Speaker 8:  and Google's thumb. Whereas Apple is like, let's just extend what we
Speaker 8:  do. And I think there's the big strategic difference.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. I'll say that. I have a a, a friend like from the Brooklyn
Speaker 6:  years who in the pandemic became one of those people who like doesn't live
Speaker 6:  anywhere. Like she just lives in beaches.
Speaker 7:  I I know one of those folks. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's, she's great. Like, does
Speaker 8:  She work, does she
Speaker 6:  Please,
Speaker 8:  Does she work at Nvidia or what?
Speaker 6:  She does not work in the va
Speaker 6:  and she was the first normal person adopter of the meta glasses
Speaker 6:  with the Ray bands. Like all of her Instagram pictures are a beach taken.
Speaker 6:  They're meta ray bands now. They're great. And You can, You can just see
Speaker 6:  it like, oh, this thing worked, like the thing worked. It looks like she's
Speaker 6:  wearing Wayfairs and all the pictures. Yeah, but they're, it's the meta glasses
Speaker 6:  and like, it, it wor it, it's like so much, there's no chance
Speaker 6:  that any of these people are wearing Vision Pros as they like Nomadically
Speaker 6:  Travel the world or the Quest three. But there's a hundred percent chance
Speaker 6:  that, hey, your camera is now in your sunglasses and you're looking at cool
Speaker 6:  stuff and you wanna share an Instagram is a loop that me can close. I
Speaker 8:  Was at a very fancy tech conference where I'm not even allowed to say the
Speaker 8:  name earlier this week, but it was a lot of tech CEOs and there were several
Speaker 8:  of them wearing the Ray bands, like walking around CEOs of
Speaker 8:  companies that it would be very funny for me to say who they were wearing
Speaker 8:  the Ray bands and you're not supposed to record anything here, but like,
Speaker 8:  they're, they're wearing them and it's like, oh, like, yeah, this is like
Speaker 8:  catching on. It's catching on with tech people, powerful people. And
Speaker 8:  it's catching on with normal people, which is like, that is a circle that
Speaker 8:  Meta has not been able to draw in its entirety of existence
Speaker 8:  as a hardware player.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  How, how good did Jensen look in the glasses? I,
Speaker 6:  I,
Speaker 8:  I can't comment.
Speaker 6:  I'm telling you, I think it VR is interesting. There's stuff in
Speaker 6:  vr like Supernatural, they keep promoting as a hit and there was actually
Speaker 6:  Supernatural just commissioned some study where they claim that waving bats
Speaker 6:  and VR as a strenuous is running.
Speaker 7:  It feels like it.
Speaker 6:  Sure. Like sure. Whatever man. Like
Speaker 7:  To me, yes, agree. If You can
Speaker 6:  You can claim that that fancy Peloton Beat Saber is the same as this
Speaker 6:  as like a, a swift run. Like more power to you. But that's the only thing
Speaker 6:  I have that's sticky. Right. And I, apple doesn't have anything that's sticky
Speaker 6:  yet except for the, the monitors. We'll see I just think Apple
Speaker 6:  moving away. The compromise of the Vision Pro was they built a VR
Speaker 6:  headset with all this pass through in the eyes and stuff to make it closer
Speaker 6:  to ar. And if what they're gonna do is drop the eyes and go head more towards
Speaker 6:  vr, that feels like a turn That is notable because
Speaker 6:  the real platform you wanna talk about the real platform shift has always
Speaker 6:  been ar Yeah, they've, everybody knows this. Tim Cook has talked about that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Is being the big platform shift and to go to, we just made a,
Speaker 6:  the best VR headset will be very different. Alright, we've been going, wait,
Speaker 6:  we're way too long. This is outta control. Does this show ever go long? Usually
Speaker 6:  David, I didn't think that ever happened. No. 30. I don't have tears
Speaker 6:  companies.
Speaker 8:  look to as like a demigod, right? And he has been totally quiet.
Speaker 8:  There's been this meme of like, where's Ilya for the last, you know, six,
Speaker 8:  eight months really since the November coup attempt. And
Speaker 8:  yeah, he's back with a company that they will not describe
Speaker 8:  anything about except that they're going to invent super safe a GI,
Speaker 8:  whatever the hell that means. His co-founder is Daniel Gross who used to
Speaker 8:  run AI at Apple, which is interesting and is now I would consider
Speaker 8:  one of, if not the most plugged in venture capitalists in AI who's been
Speaker 8:  raising a ton of money and and deploying it into startups.
Speaker 8:  And they are putting the call out for people to join. And
Speaker 8:  I'm sure we'll be rating ilya's former org OpenAI in
Speaker 8:  very due time. And the key thing here is
Speaker 8:  Ilya saying we are gonna be free from, I forget, I forget the exact
Speaker 8:  wording, but we are gonna be free from the products and management
Speaker 8:  day to day and only focus on long-term
Speaker 8:  aligned a GI research. And we will not release anything until we hit
Speaker 8:  a GI. So it's, this is a, this is a pure
Speaker 8:  research lab, which is what Ilya has been known for his entire career.
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna read this paragraph to you.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Read it.
Speaker 6:  Because anybody who has ever worked anywhere is, well, I think have the same
Speaker 6:  reaction to this paragraph. Our singular focus means
Speaker 6:  no distraction by management overhead or product cycles. And our business
Speaker 6:  model means safety, security, and progress are all insulated from
Speaker 6:  short-term commercial pressures. I,
Speaker 6:  sorry, I just like what?
Speaker 8:  Well, that the business model is, we just raised an
Speaker 8:  ungodly amount of money and we're gonna keep raising ungodly amounts of money.
Speaker 6:  So it, but that means you don't have a business model, right? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like that's how you get to do these things. Yes. Is like, you don't,
Speaker 6:  you don't have the pre you don't, like you don't have the pressure of a business.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 7:  Isn't that just all a really pointed jab at Sam
Speaker 7:  Altman?
Speaker 6:  But I, but yes. Or short,
Speaker 7:  Right? But obviously I figured it was more that than actual, like in this
Speaker 7:  case I was assuming that he was going less like I'm here to make money. 'cause
Speaker 7:  he's made it very clear he doesn't care about money. and more like I'm here
Speaker 7:  to like say I, I don't like what Sam Altman did, and so I
Speaker 7:  wanna make a company where we're
Speaker 6:  Stuff. All I'm saying is I watch Max and two of her 6-year-old friends from
Speaker 6:  kindergarten try to play lemonade stand and they are distracted by
Speaker 6:  management overhead and product cycles. And their business model means they
Speaker 6:  often compromise in safety, security and progress. Like
Speaker 6:  there's just like no way You can put any group of
Speaker 6:  people together and not have management overhead. So it is, it is
Speaker 6:  not possible, especially if you're trying to hire the
Speaker 6:  most highly paid, sought after talent that exists
Speaker 6:  in technology today is And that's what I mean, it's like I don't, I read
Speaker 6:  this paragraph, I'm like, this doesn't, you can't do this. This is the VC
Speaker 6:  promise. You can't keep
Speaker 8:  The VC math here is simple. We will give you whatever you want. And
Speaker 8:  when you invent a GI, it will change everything. It will be the new fire
Speaker 8:  and we'll figure it out. That's, I guarantee you that's the extent of the
Speaker 8:  diligence. I
Speaker 7:  Was, I was gonna ask like, where, where is the money coming from to recruit
Speaker 7:  all of these very highly paid people?
Speaker 8:  Well, they won't say where they've raised money from. So if you know, let
Speaker 8:  me know. But if you're listening to this, I wanna find out Daniel is, they're,
Speaker 8:  they're all super wealthy. Yeah. And they will have no trouble raising
Speaker 8:  whatever they want because when you co-founded OpenAI, You can raise
Speaker 8:  whatever you want.
Speaker 6:  And then in particular participated in the notable management overhead
Speaker 6:  of doing a huge coup Yes. Against the CEO. Yes.
Speaker 7:  A failed coup.
Speaker 6:  It's like your track record of not having management overhead is very bad.
Speaker 8:  Also, like a question I have is, what is safe A GII keep hearing
Speaker 8:  this and it's so
Speaker 6:  Intelligence, it's not a GI
Speaker 8:  Or super intelligence, which is actually now the new word for what comes
Speaker 8:  after a GI apparently is the thing I keep hearing. And so
Speaker 8:  we keep inventing new terms because they realize like the terms they had,
Speaker 8:  no one understands or they don't actually even understand what they are.
Speaker 8:  What is safe A JI what does this mean? Like Ilya's whole thing at OpenAI
Speaker 8:  was alignment, right? He set up this alignment group that was gonna get 20%
Speaker 8:  of open AI's compute budget. Apparently they never did. That led to
Speaker 8:  a lot of infighting and I think per, you know, helped him try to kick
Speaker 8:  Sam out. But I always hear this and I'm like
Speaker 8:  aligning for who and under what values are we aligning
Speaker 8:  and they don't seem to have an answer.
Speaker 7:  And then that's been like a consistent problem with ai, right? Is is that
Speaker 7:  they're always like, yeah, this is gonna be for everyone, but we
Speaker 7:  only trained it with these certain data sets. We only trained it using like
Speaker 7:  the pre-established knowledge of the certain people creating it. So
Speaker 7:  it's actually fairly insular and doesn't work for everyone. And there are
Speaker 7:  enormous edge cases every time we deploy it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And you know, as Neela and I uncovered when we were reporting on the coup
Speaker 8:  attempts, like this gets kind of portrayed in the media as this,
Speaker 8:  you know, acceleration versus deceleration almost like religious
Speaker 8:  faction war that's happening. And I do think there's part of that. I do think
Speaker 8:  IA is almost like religious and is like fervor here. But a lot of
Speaker 8:  this is just like boring company stuff. Business stuff. Yes.
Speaker 8:  It's like you wanted budget, you didn't get it, you got layered,
Speaker 8:  therefore you don't wanna work there anymore. OpenAI just hired a
Speaker 8:  CPO who used to run product at Instagram and a CFO who was the
Speaker 8:  CEO of Nextdoor a public company. It's very clear where OpenAI is going.
Speaker 8:  They're gonna, IPO they want build a massive business. They're going to get
Speaker 8:  rid of being a nonprofit. It's very clear. And some of your, I
Speaker 6:  Mean this week made some noises about not being a nonprofit, right?
Speaker 8:  And so if that's the direction they're going, you're ilia. It's like you
Speaker 8:  just want to do research, right? And that's where a lot of these researchers
Speaker 8:  still are is they just wanna do cutting edge frontier model development.
Speaker 8:  And this is him saying, come here, we'll do it. And
Speaker 8:  I, we should also note this is now the third offshoot of OpenAI that was,
Speaker 8:  has been created to create safer AI from
Speaker 8:  OpenAI whose mission is also to create safe ai.
Speaker 7:  It's not a great look.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So you have philanthropic for I would, I would actually put Xai in
Speaker 8:  this camp. Elon was the co-founder of an of OpenAI. Now you have
Speaker 8:  SSI, which is also, I feel like it's a medical term or something. What am
Speaker 8:  I Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 7:  I got this once. It was, it was, you take a pill for it. It's fine.
Speaker 6:  Sun, Neo ozempic. SSI. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I, look, I just, it's great that everybody thinks they can accomplish these
Speaker 6:  things. I actually think it's unclear at all
Speaker 6:  whether Transformers and LLMs can ever
Speaker 6:  do the things Yeah. That people want them to do. And in fact, over
Speaker 6:  time it has been more and more clear that perhaps they cannot Yeah. And so
Speaker 6:  what I'm dying to know is if SSI or any of the other companies that think
Speaker 6:  they can build a GI if they have another idea. Yeah. Because if the
Speaker 6:  only idea is we're gonna make a slightly better LLMI actually
Speaker 6:  don't I, there I'm not, you're not gonna make, you're not worried about whether
Speaker 6:  it'll be safe. 'cause it's not gonna be super intelligent.
Speaker 7:  I'm just why are people trying to build an a GI like these people are
Speaker 7:  nerds. They, they, they watch movies. Well,
Speaker 6:  That's why you just answered your own question. No, but they,
Speaker 7:  They watch the movies, they play the games. Like this man is setting out
Speaker 7:  to be the, the audio clips you hear when you're walking through
Speaker 7:  the ruins a thousand years later in a video game of the guy being like,
Speaker 7:  I don't know what's happening. Why is my AI going and killing the world?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Like that's what he's setting himself up for if he was
Speaker 7:  actually successful in his grand ambitions. And I'm just like, why?
Speaker 8:  Because the industry thinks that we, they have invented a new form of
Speaker 8:  intelligence and that hasn't happened before. Okay. And so it's,
Speaker 8:  I think the natural progression of this is that it's all smarter than us
Speaker 8:  and replaces us. and it seems inevitable to the people
Speaker 8:  building this stuff. What we see is like chat GPT can't get a math
Speaker 8:  equation. Right? Right. Yeah. That's like what we see, what they're seeing.
Speaker 8:  We gotta keep in mind like they gate this stuff like GPT-4 was in
Speaker 8:  existence for like over a year before OpenAI actually deployed it in the
Speaker 8:  world. So they're seeing things we're not, I'm not gonna like give them too
Speaker 8:  much of the credit there, but I do think there's, you know,
Speaker 8:  Jan Koon, who's the chief AI researcher at Meta has been saying
Speaker 8:  what you just said in Eli, that LLMs are not the path to a GI. So his group
Speaker 8:  is actually working on what comes after the transformer. What, what is the
Speaker 8:  architecture we need? Because these are parrots, right?
Speaker 8:  These LLMs are are fancy prediction engines. Right. And you, you don't
Speaker 8:  really unlock intelligence that way.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, no, I mean I, I, yesterday I assigned our futures team to write languages,
Speaker 6:  not intelligence. Like I, I feel like we just need to say some very
Speaker 6:  explicit declarative sentences that are true. Like, dogs are very
Speaker 6:  intelligent and cannot generate a PowerPoint the way that they like, you
Speaker 6:  know what I mean? Like, we're getting confused about what intelligence is.
Speaker 6:  At a very high level, I'm, I've been lately thinking a
Speaker 6:  lot about the, the Steve Jobs slide of technology and liberal arts.
Speaker 6:  You know, it's like, oh, you guys forgot about this whole street, this whole
Speaker 6:  street's missing from this conversation right now. and
Speaker 6:  it, there's just a piece of this puzzle where it You can bet on this stuff
Speaker 6:  to get better at an infinite rate. But like most curves level off.
Speaker 6:  and it is unclear to me what actually makes things intelligent that said,
Speaker 6:  well, you know, good luck. Good luck building your company with no management
Speaker 6:  overhead websites. Come on decoder. If you pull that off, boy do I
Speaker 6:  have a podcast for you? Right. I, I spent an hour talking about management
Speaker 6:  overhead every week with people. But like, it turns out, it always like three
Speaker 6:  6-year-old girls have management overhead. I, I promise you maybe more
Speaker 6:  than any company in America,
Speaker 6:  speaking of confounding decisions by AI companies,
Speaker 6:  perplexity started out so hot, man, they were
Speaker 6:  the ones, right? You can pick any model. You can ask these questions and
Speaker 6:  it was better searching Google. and it turns out, boy, have they been
Speaker 6:  awful shady along the way? What is going on here?
Speaker 8:  Well, yeah. So perplexity, for those who don't know, is trying to
Speaker 8:  unseat Google with an AI search engine. It's actually a
Speaker 8:  good product most of the time I would say that I like their AI
Speaker 8:  answers more than Google's on average. And
Speaker 8:  now we kind of know why it's 'cause they're stealing a bunch of content.
Speaker 8:  And
Speaker 8:  yeah, so Wired did some good reporting and found out that they
Speaker 8:  were going around their crawler blocker. I've
Speaker 8:  heard rumors that Perplexity has been doing this at an even grander scale
Speaker 8:  with even much larger corpuses of data.
Speaker 8:  And this is the, this is the OpenAI playbook on steroids a little bit, which
Speaker 8:  is just run fast and beg for forgiveness. And
Speaker 8:  that's what they're doing. They're basically going around people who have
Speaker 8:  said, no, you are not allowed to summarize this in doing it anyway.
Speaker 6:  And the way they're doing it is both shady and hilarious.
Speaker 6:  So they publish some IP ranges of their crawlers
Speaker 6:  and they publish the name of their crawler. So poor robots
Speaker 6:  txt a text file that should not bear the weight of all
Speaker 6:  intellectual property law on the internet, but which currently does You can
Speaker 6:  set it to disallow these crawlers. You can set it to disallow GPT bot,
Speaker 6:  which is Open Eyes. There's Google Bot plus I think. So there's Google Bot,
Speaker 6:  which is the regular search index. And there's the other one which is Google's
Speaker 6:  AI crawler. I feel like I need to disclose here. We used to
Speaker 6:  disclose GPT bot at Vox Media and then our company signed a deal
Speaker 6:  and now we don't. There you go. There's a disclosure
Speaker 6:  and you could just, you could disallow perplexity. And on top of that, they
Speaker 6:  did this thing where like, here are IP ranges. Like if you don't trust robots,
Speaker 6:  You can decide these ips. And then what Wired found, and then the folks at
Speaker 6:  Max Stories, which is a great indie Apple site, they found that
Speaker 6:  their content was showing up anyway in perplexity.
Speaker 6:  And then the investigations basically revealed these IP ranges were fake
Speaker 6:  and the crawler was fake. And they were setting up headless Windows 10
Speaker 6:  machines
Speaker 6:  to browse the web. Yes. Like, you know, those pictures of like the, the
Speaker 6:  streaming fraud farms where hot dogs are just swiping Android phones.
Speaker 6:  There's your VC money, I love it. Just swiping away
Speaker 6:  on a Windows 10 browser.
Speaker 8:  Just imagine if those Windows machines had a recall.
Speaker 6:  It's just like crazy. And you know, and the CEO for Plexus has talked a lot
Speaker 6:  of shit about Google. Like why are these results so bad? And like Google,
Speaker 6:  for better or worse is trying to play by the rules.
Speaker 6:  It's still pissing everybody off. But they're attempting to play by the rules.
Speaker 6:  The publishers are laid
Speaker 8:  Out. They have to, I mean, Google is under consent decrees. They're a massively
Speaker 8:  regulated mega cap tech company. So they can't do this kind of stuff.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And here's a startup being like, what if we lied? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  What We just didn't do any of that. And to be clear, I keep making this comparison.
Speaker 6:  You call it the opening AI playbook. This was the Google playbook 20 years
Speaker 6:  ago. Yep. Right. Google just allowed all of
Speaker 6:  Viacom's content to be on YouTube. Google indexed every book in the world
Speaker 6:  without permission. Google did image search, which it got sued over and it
Speaker 6:  won all those lawsuits because those products were new. So they
Speaker 6:  would show up in court and be like, judge YouTube. And the judge would be
Speaker 6:  like, YouTube's sick. And Viacom would be like, our marketing staffers are
Speaker 6:  using this anyway because it's sick. Google Image, image Church.
Speaker 6:  So useful. It's concoct in it's ne nothing like this has ever existed before.
Speaker 6:  Let's concoct some reasoning to allow Google to take all this stuff for free.
Speaker 6:  Because the theory is that you'll go buy the image
Speaker 6:  from Getty once you found it on Google. It's unclear what that theory really
Speaker 6:  came out to in the end. I
Speaker 7:  I never did that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Alex is not like I opened a Getty library the next day,
Speaker 6:  a Getty account the next day. But that, those are the theories back then.
Speaker 6:  Google Books that might have worked. Right? You can search all the books.
Speaker 6:  Maybe you'll actually buy the book in the end. Did it work out? Totally.
Speaker 6:  Well, I, I don't know. But those are the theories back then because the products
Speaker 6:  were so new, the experiences were so new. Perplexity is just like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  we stole a bunch of stuff and what we've delivered is an incremental improvement
Speaker 6:  on Google search. And I just, I don't think that's gonna win this time.
Speaker 8:  Maybe I, I am shocked at how little the people inside these
Speaker 8:  AI companies and their investors, again, I was just at a very fancy
Speaker 8:  tech conference with a lot of these people, how little they actually care
Speaker 8:  about this problem. How it is really just like, this is a, this is a bunch
Speaker 8:  of speed bumps that we'll go over to getting where we're gonna go.
Speaker 8:  And maybe it's because of the, the, the fact that Google is Google Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And they did all this 20 years ago and they're a trillion multi-trillion
Speaker 8:  dollar company. The,
Speaker 7:  I think's, I think to
Speaker 8:  Shows. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  I was gonna say, I think it's back to what Neli said about liberal arts education.
Speaker 7:  They just don't have any like historical context. So they're like, yeah,
Speaker 7:  this is gonna work.
Speaker 6:  They didn't take any history classes at Stanford.
Speaker 7:  I didn't, I don't need to know about Google. This is fine.
Speaker 8:  No, these are systems people. Yeah. They don't think in terms of
Speaker 8:  these, the values that we get mad about when it's like, Hey, I, I made
Speaker 8:  a thing, I charged people for it and you took it.
Speaker 8:  That's not okay with, with intellectual property,
Speaker 8:  with writing and stuff like that for some reason. It's just not a thing that
Speaker 8:  a lot of tech people that I know, it doesn't register for them.
Speaker 8:  I don't know why. Right.
Speaker 7:  Because they didn't take liberal arts s like,
Speaker 7:  they're like, what is an English class?
Speaker 6:  I want to spend more time. I don't have, I don't have a view of this. I I
Speaker 6:  haven't locked this into my brain yet. So people have thoughts. Send them
Speaker 6:  to me. 'cause I, I need the help, but I can feel this weird shift that
Speaker 6:  I've been calling the copyright apocalypse because some people
Speaker 6:  care about it a lot now more than ever before
Speaker 6:  the, this is mine. And you took it between influencers on
Speaker 6:  social media platforms rages out of control now,
Speaker 6:  right? Yeah. I'm a Taylor Schiff fan. And those three notes of a song
Speaker 6:  sound like three notes in Olivia Rodrigo fan. We have to do fandom war
Speaker 6:  now. Yeah. Until the music industry dos out. Writing credits
Speaker 6:  is a real thing that happens. Like at, at the
Speaker 6:  craziest level, this is a real thing that happens and that is copyright
Speaker 6:  maxism by really young people. And then over here you have nobody
Speaker 6:  owns anything. It's just something I should get it for free. And those things
Speaker 6:  are just in tension in a way that I, it feels unresolved
Speaker 6:  and un potentially unresolvable. Like you can't, you
Speaker 6:  can't have a bunch of YouTubers being like, I, I made this YouTube video
Speaker 6:  first. And anybody who even makes a video that looks like it is stealing
Speaker 6:  from me right next to everything in the internet should be free.
Speaker 8:  Maybe that's it. Maybe there's not a lot of love for media companies, as
Speaker 8:  we all know. And the fact that it's scraping wired or The Verge or whatever
Speaker 8:  is like whatever, they're fine. But when it's like your favorite influencer,
Speaker 8:  your favorite creator Yeah. And they're on their feed going, Hey, like this
Speaker 8:  model, don't use it because they trained on my stuff. I
Speaker 8:  do think you're right. I think people feel a lot more viscerally about that
Speaker 8:  than they do. Oh, like companies, right? I think it's when it becomes the
Speaker 8:  individual
Speaker 6:  And, and again, what Google was up against, what Napster was up against
Speaker 6:  was the big bad, right? Like the only face of the anti
Speaker 6:  Napster movement was Lars Ulrich for Metallica. And
Speaker 6:  you remember the flash that did not work for him. But really the face was
Speaker 6:  like Hollywood in the music industry. And no one ever feels
Speaker 6:  any sympathy towards Hollywood in the music industry. Like Hollywood could
Speaker 6:  be like, you wouldn't steal a cigarette. Like whatever they would say you
Speaker 6:  wouldn't, what was it? You wouldn't download a, you wouldn't,
Speaker 7:  You wouldn't download a car.
Speaker 6:  Right? So Hollywood can put up the banners and say you wouldn't download
Speaker 6:  a car. And everyone's like, screw you. I I'm super gonna download a movie.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And if I could download a car, I would, that'd be sick. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Rules. Like I've had this 3D printer for years not making cars,
Speaker 6:  but they were the big bats. Influencers are like people, like
Speaker 6:  influencers, like people, you know what I mean? Influencers are actual people
Speaker 6:  that you have pair social relationships with. Yeah. And like there's something
Speaker 6:  very emotional that is not resolved and it's gonna come to a head. 'cause
Speaker 6:  you know, the next story we have on our list here is a bunch
Speaker 6:  of social networks that want to introduce AI in various ways.
Speaker 6:  Alex, you played with one. And before we get to that, I just wanna call out,
Speaker 6:  TikTok is now letting people make AI
Speaker 6:  avatars of creators. Yeah. Right? And saying, this is your ad
Speaker 6:  creative and this is gonna come for every social platform. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  That's right.
Speaker 6:  Like in a massive way. Like if you are a creator and you feel the burnout
Speaker 6:  and You can make 50 more ads during your brand deal using it, you you
Speaker 6:  might do it.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. No, this is happening. So yeah, I wrote about this new app which was,
Speaker 8:  you know, I get a lot of test flights to try things and this is the first
Speaker 8:  test flight I've gotten in a while that made me feel something very strongly
Speaker 8:  where I was like, oh, when I opened it and it's, it is like
Speaker 8:  Instagram. It meets character AI where
Speaker 8:  basically it's a bunch of ais in a feed commenting and posting
Speaker 8:  together. And there's humans, but they don't need to be there. And like,
Speaker 8:  it's actually in some cases, not most, but in some cases hard to
Speaker 8:  tell who is human and who is not. And they just raised a bunch of money.
Speaker 8:  It's an ex snap, ex snap people. And the reason I wrote about
Speaker 8:  it is because meta is about to do the exact same thing Zuckerberg told me.
Speaker 8:  So last September, and I think later this year, we're gonna see them
Speaker 8:  start to roll this out where basically anyone can create their own ais,
Speaker 8:  send them into Instagram, send them into Facebook. And
Speaker 8:  same thing with businesses. And the idea is that if you are an influencer
Speaker 8:  and you feel overwhelmed by your dms, maybe an AI handles that for you.
Speaker 8:  Or maybe an AI actually posts on your behalf. Yeah. Zuckerberg is super
Speaker 8:  excited about this. I know. 'cause he's talked to me about it. It's very
Speaker 8:  freaky to imagine what this actually does to our social networks. It's coming
Speaker 8:  way faster than we think though.
Speaker 7:  Well it's interesting 'cause like in South Korea they've been doing
Speaker 7:  a little bit of something like this, right? With, with k-pop stars where
Speaker 7:  You can engage with k-pop stars on sites owned by the k-pop stars companies.
Speaker 7:  And it's not always, sometimes it's them. It's not always that.
Speaker 7:  Usually it's, it is a bot. It's, it's a, it's a person pretending to be them.
Speaker 7:  And so like that, that parasocial, how do we automate that? Parasocial stuff
Speaker 7:  has been happening in Korea for a long time. But I think the difference here
Speaker 7:  is that was gated too. Okay. You have to go download this app
Speaker 7:  Yeah. For this publisher and use it. Whereas this would be on meta
Speaker 7:  Instagram,
Speaker 8:  This would be like you open Instagram and it's like, oh, is that account
Speaker 8:  in ai? They may have three arms. Okay, maybe then.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, no, that's coming. So
Speaker 6:  There, then there's the other part which is you send agents out on your behalf
Speaker 6:  as an influencer or someone where you're like, someone wants to pay
Speaker 6:  money to subscribe. And one of the things I offer is like dms
Speaker 6:  with me. Yeah. And then my, my agent will just like do that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I won't do it. And that's infinitely scalable. Which if you are
Speaker 6:  an individual creator and all of these platforms are organized towards tearing
Speaker 6:  down collectives and enhancing individual creators. If
Speaker 6:  you're an individual creator, your ability to scale is limited by your
Speaker 6:  emotional capacity to do this work and your minutes in the day.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And so of course you're gonna let the robot talk to your fans.
Speaker 6:  Like it is the biggest no-brainer in the history of the world. Yeah, of course
Speaker 6:  you're gonna say, okay, you want to, you brand X wants to do an
Speaker 6:  integration with me, but they want to 50 different versions as creative,
Speaker 6:  I will make one and let the AI deep fake me into five more. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And that is already happening. Like at TikTok is
Speaker 6:  enabling the feature. Like it's it's happening now. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Well, Alex, to your question about why, like I was talking to Tran, the CEO
Speaker 8:  E of butterflies, this new app about this, the why. 'cause I showed this
Speaker 8:  app to my wife and she was like, just like, it was an immediate, just like,
Speaker 8:  ooh,
Speaker 6:  You know,
Speaker 8:  Like, I'm like, I, I think you're gonna meet a lot of people like that who
Speaker 8:  are like, why does this need to exist? Like why do we need to like fill our
Speaker 8:  time with just empty AI social media? And his point was
Speaker 8:  like, yes, it feels kind of broken right now. And I wrote about this, it
Speaker 8:  feels like when the hosts in Westworld break a little bit, it's not, not
Speaker 8:  there. But he was like, you know, I, I got into tech
Speaker 8:  by like making friends on forums, talking to people that I never met. I only
Speaker 8:  knew their username. He's like, we will get the models quickly to that quality.
Speaker 8:  And as someone who also came up and got into tech in a similar way, like
Speaker 8:  through like making friends on forums, like what happens when,
Speaker 8:  like I never met those people, right? I didn't know a lot of their names
Speaker 8:  ever. So if they were ai, would it have made a difference?
Speaker 8:  I mean we had a whole like philosophical conversation about this, but he
Speaker 8:  was like, you don't actually want to talk to people. There's traits of being
Speaker 8:  human that you like and AI will quickly copy all those traits.
Speaker 8:  And I'm like, disagree. Mind blown. And also, no, no,
Speaker 8:  thank you. But also it kind of, but is it inevitable? That's the question
Speaker 8:  it
Speaker 7:  Ignores like, and, and in in the eighties and nineties
Speaker 7:  there were the 900 numbers and you could like call like Yeah the
Speaker 7:  crypt keeper was one like Cory Ham and stuff like that. And Cory
Speaker 7:  Ham was not answering the phone to talk to a little 12-year-old girl who
Speaker 7:  had a crush on him. Right. Like that was a voice actor pretending to be him
Speaker 7:  and quickly
Speaker 6:  Wait out. So we just learned something very important about what you spent
Speaker 6:  your money on when you were a child. It
Speaker 7:  Was not me because if I had called a 900 number, I
Speaker 7:  would've not had a good time.
Speaker 6:  My dad super caught me calling you a 900 number once and he was like, you're
Speaker 6:  never using the phone again.
Speaker 7:  But that was like part of why, I mean, it was one that was the cost of 900
Speaker 7:  numbers, but that was the other part of it where it was like 900 numbers
Speaker 7:  were a little sketchy as a kid. You weren't really supposed to call them.
Speaker 7:  and it was because like yeah, it was a bunch of like, not con artists, but
Speaker 7:  basically licensed con artists pretending to be other people. And it's like,
Speaker 7:  that's that's gross.
Speaker 6:  But this is the, the, you hear this from tech people all the time. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  They're like, this is just the same as this other small problem that we had
Speaker 6:  in the past. They're like, but now you're doing it at scale. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like now you're doing it at scale. And that's like,
Speaker 6:  What if took, if we took a small problem and made it global, it's like, I
Speaker 6:  think maybe there's something different here. This thing by the way that
Speaker 6:  you just mentioned, it's come up several times now. It is this
Speaker 6:  unshakeable belief that these models are gonna get better. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And like on the rate of like, Moore's law will get better. Yeah. And I don't,
Speaker 6:  that metric doesn't exist. Like there isn't a Moore's law of LLM models
Speaker 6:  yet. You know, we've only really experienced 3.5 to four in the, in the public.
Speaker 6:  But I, and I understand that they've all got stuff looking at that we can't
Speaker 6:  see. Sure. But someone's gotta give me the number. Like gimme the rate of
Speaker 6:  change before I believe that this model will be able to simulate
Speaker 6:  whatever happened to me on forums when I was a child. Like, you know, like
Speaker 6:  you wouldn't last a minute in the asylum when they raised me. It's like,
Speaker 6:  I don't think so. Well,
Speaker 8:  So yeah, there's no Moore's law.
Speaker 6:  There's, that's
Speaker 7:  Incredible.
Speaker 6:  I
Speaker 8:  Mean there, there's no Moore's Law. There's scaling law. And the idea
Speaker 8:  is that as you continue to put more data, data and compute into these models,
Speaker 8:  they get exponentially better. That continues to hold true. If you compare
Speaker 8:  the output, the creative output of like GPT two or GP
Speaker 8:  3G, PT three to four, it's a massive difference. So, but
Speaker 7:  They're also running
Speaker 8:  Into
Speaker 6:  How, but you're saying that line is not linear. That's what I'm saying. Like
Speaker 8:  No, I'm saying everyone who works in AI believes that it is still linear.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  But it's not because we've just seen multiple stories about how they're all
Speaker 7:  desperate for data to the point that they're like, what if we make AI machines
Speaker 7:  to just create more content for us that can't go wrong.
Speaker 8:  Oh, the thing I'm hearing is it's gonna be synthetic data for training. So
Speaker 8:  literally you're, you're gonna have the ais get good enough that they start
Speaker 8:  talking and then the ais train on the ais. That's where we're going.
Speaker 6:  All right. We gotta create a very stupid this here. I can't, I can't sit
Speaker 6:  here. Sorry. Make, I'm just saying make real friends. Go to the forums while
Speaker 6:  You can. All right friends, get in there while the
Speaker 6:  getting's good. Get past the username, get their actual name because they
Speaker 6:  may be an AI in here. Request a driver's license immediately.
Speaker 6:  thing about this whole story to me is one, Nvidia has been
Speaker 6:  around for a million years. Video game fans
Speaker 6:  exist, right? Yep. Like people put Nvidia cards in their
Speaker 6:  PCs all over the place. It has been on this run for a long time,
Speaker 6:  right? Yeah. Like this is years now of Nvidia stock skyrocketing. And
Speaker 6:  the way CNN covered it, the headline in CNN was this company whose name you
Speaker 6:  can't pronounce, is now the world's most riches company. It's like, what?
Speaker 8:  It's actually pretty easy to pronounce, I feel like. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's not one, it's not that hard. That's what we
Speaker 8:  Care. It's easier than ss i
Speaker 7:  An editor and a writer together and they're both like, I don't know what
Speaker 7:  this is. Yeah. We got this.
Speaker 6:  It's just like at some point, like I, I understand we run a tech publication,
Speaker 6:  we're like swimming the water, but like they've even headed here for at least
Speaker 6:  two years. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. We, we had to hear about them like cryptocurrency, right? Nvidia
Speaker 7:  had this big, all these big stock jumps because of cryptocurrency, because
Speaker 7:  everybody was buying the GPUs because that was the best way to train.
Speaker 6:  Oh my God. This was completely outta my brain. I I This was gone, this information
Speaker 6:  had been deleted. Yeah, because
Speaker 7:  It was, it was 2020 just like crypto, we don't think about 2020.
Speaker 7:  And so that was happening to, to Nvidia. And so it was like steadily ticking
Speaker 7:  up and it was like, oh boy, a MD and Intel are, might be able to
Speaker 7:  beat it. And then it was like, we're gonna take all the crypto stuff out
Speaker 7:  of our, our GPUs and then everybody was like, Hey, AI's here.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Yeah. And, and others have been lost. Their
Speaker 7:  Minds.
Speaker 8:  The effect of this profession, the effect of this inside Nvidia is
Speaker 8:  fascinating. I've heard, and there's been some reporting and I wanna keep
Speaker 8:  doing more reporting on it. So if you have stories, if you're listening to
Speaker 8:  this and you have gotten fabulously wealthy at Nvidia, hit me up. We can
Speaker 8:  talk off the record. They have a retirement problem inside Nvidia. There's
Speaker 8:  a, there was a, a post I saw where it said if you join as a mid-level
Speaker 8:  software engineer five years ago and your total comp was 700,000, which is
Speaker 8:  a lot, right? But in tech, that's actually pretty middle of the road for
Speaker 8:  a good engineer. Your compensation yearly now is
Speaker 8:  $10 million. So that rules,
Speaker 8:  they actually have people just retiring like en mass.
Speaker 8:  And so like the, the question for Nvidia is like how,
Speaker 8:  what do you do to motivate people when people have gotten so
Speaker 8:  fabulously wealthy so fast and it's obvious there's gonna be a correction.
Speaker 8:  It's obvious Nvidia is not gonna stay the richest the most valuable company
Speaker 8:  in the world, right? So how does that collapse happen? Is it a
Speaker 8:  slow collapse? Is it a fast one? And what happens to the employee base is
Speaker 8:  fascinating. I think
Speaker 6:  It's, well you get rid of management overhead and product cycles. There you
Speaker 7:  Go. That's,
Speaker 6:  It's obvious what
Speaker 7:  You do merge with SSI like it's
Speaker 7:  gonna last a while, right? Because Yeah, they're the only ones making the
Speaker 7:  really good AI processors for server levels. Right?
Speaker 8:  Well they have software lock in too with Google.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, Google. That's, that's the thing. Google, Google Google's their main
Speaker 7:  primary competitor, right? Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Well yeah. Arm A-A-M-D-I would say a MD is like an arms dealer
Speaker 8:  is probably the biggest one. Google doesn't sell TPUs really as much. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  But
Speaker 7:  NVIDIA's got a big headstart. This is one of the things that like has kept
Speaker 7:  Intel propped up for years was because Intel had this huge head start
Speaker 7:  in the server space. 99% of, of the server space. So
Speaker 7:  you know, they can bomb a couple of years against
Speaker 7:  Qualcomm and be fine because they got the servers. And I think NVIDIA's kind
Speaker 7:  of feels like not quite as cushy a position, but
Speaker 7:  similarly cushy.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean they have Cuda, like what they have is a software layer that
Speaker 6:  makes their GPUs more valuable. Yeah. Which
Speaker 6:  AMD does not. But if you run Azure, I mean we've had all these people in
Speaker 6:  the show and Alex talks 'em all, if you run Azure or AWS or Google Cloud
Speaker 6:  or whatever, you do not want to be beholden
Speaker 6:  Tokuda and Nvidia. Yeah, no, you, you, you want all kinds of things to happen.
Speaker 6:  So that's
Speaker 7:  Why Apple and Nvidia don't look at each other anymore.
Speaker 6:  It is very funny that Apple and I video hate each other. It is, it used to
Speaker 6:  be just like a little funny because Apple would insist that bad graphics
Speaker 6:  cards were good graphics cards
Speaker 6:  and that was just funny. Like in its way now it's deeply funny.
Speaker 7:  It's extremely good.
Speaker 6:  'cause all that OpenAI integration is happening in H one hundreds that Apple
Speaker 6:  does not want to talk about at all. Yeah. And,
Speaker 8:  And and doesn't wanna pay for. And that's the thing. Yeah. Market forces
Speaker 8:  will ensure that Nvidia does not stay the top GPU supplier in the world because
Speaker 8:  they are too expensive and it that no one wants Jensen being the, the
Speaker 8:  king of GPUs. Right? Everyone wants to have options. And so NVIDIA's challenge
Speaker 8:  to justify this valuation and to keep growing is to build lock-in. and
Speaker 8:  it is like, it would make a lot of sense for them to start competing directly
Speaker 8:  with Google Cloud and Azure to become a one-stop shop because otherwise
Speaker 8:  people will out chip them. That's just going to happen and may take time.
Speaker 7:  And we've been seen that for years with them. And, and and they like, like
Speaker 7:  on the gaming side, they got really, really good at the lock-in. They got
Speaker 7:  really good at being like, you can't use these a MD processors because we
Speaker 7:  went out to every single game developer and made sure they were using our
Speaker 7:  tools. So you had to use our like we get the better stuff. So
Speaker 7:  they're, it is gonna be really interesting over the next couple of years
Speaker 7:  is as they just like absolutely Duke it out with some of these other companies.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And I think a lot of people are gonna be surprised at how vicious they
Speaker 7:  get.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. But it's like one step down from that, right Alex? Yeah. Keith was
Speaker 6:  saying these things are free, like Apple's not paying for it if there's no
Speaker 6:  business model. One step down from, we paid all of the money in the world
Speaker 6:  for H one hundreds. The price, the H 100 rule just fall. Like
Speaker 6:  if the demand is there right now. 'cause everyone thinks they're gonna monopolize
Speaker 6:  something. Yeah. What it is is remains to be seen.
Speaker 6:  But that's why, that's why the price is high. We'll see. All right, I'm gonna
Speaker 6:  go next 'cause I want Heath to end the lightning round with this.
Speaker 6:  We just continue to track tech litigation. The
Speaker 6:  United States Department of Justice has sued Adobe for
Speaker 6:  deceiving subscription pricing in Creative Cloud. And
Speaker 6:  it's, it actually is deceiving. It is deceiving in one specific way, which
Speaker 6:  is when you sign up for Creative Cloud, You can pick annually, build
Speaker 6:  annually, build monthly or monthly. Annually. Billed
Speaker 6:  monthly is the default choice. So that means you pay for a year but they
Speaker 6:  charge you per month and you've signed a one year contract. And, if you try
Speaker 6:  to cancel early, they just charge you the rest, rest of the year. Or You
Speaker 6:  can sign up for monthly or You can just cancel after every month because
Speaker 6:  it's the default because it's the cheapest. People pick it and they think
Speaker 6:  it's a monthly subscription and there's no fine print. It doesn't actually
Speaker 6:  disclose that this will happen. They try to cancel, they get stuck with the
Speaker 6:  rest of the bill. This is bad. This is straightforwardly bad for
Speaker 6:  a company with basically a monopoly market share in these
Speaker 6:  tools.
Speaker 6:  It is also just beyond the pill. Like this is piddly shit. What are you doing?
Speaker 6:  Like people are gonna buy Photoshop man. Like that's
Speaker 7:  A local gym move on their part.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I really think about, I've been thinking about this a lot with Adobe.
Speaker 6:  I, I've basically insisted The, Verge, overc Adobe over the past
Speaker 6:  few years. 'cause I, they're such a central player in everything that's going
Speaker 6:  on. Like influencer media
Speaker 6:  depends on the existence of Adobe. That's weird, right? Like Premier
Speaker 6:  runs YouTube. Like YouTube never built creative tools, which is
Speaker 6:  one of the weirdest things about YouTube. They had that one app on the phone
Speaker 6:  once, but they've never built a video editor. The success of
Speaker 6:  TikTok is they made a video editor that's really good and they made all those
Speaker 6:  templates and they made it easy to do all this stuff. YouTube never did that.
Speaker 6:  They're like uploads some videos and then people built the entire creator's
Speaker 6:  ecosystem on the back of Premier largely
Speaker 6:  a little bit of final cut 'cause there's so many creators to use Max, but
Speaker 6:  mostly Premier and you like Google never built that stuff.
Speaker 6:  So you just like look at this industry like Adobe's the center of everything.
Speaker 6:  They're at the center of all these, all these AI creativity battles, right?
Speaker 6:  'cause they have Adobe stock and people use Photoshop and General fill and
Speaker 6:  the more you cover Adobe, the more you realize there's a massive
Speaker 6:  difference in how the company perceives itself and what it does and the tools
Speaker 6:  it makes and how everyone else perceives Adobe. It's
Speaker 6:  yawning gap. I've said this before, we had Hanta ion on
Speaker 6:  decoder. He never talks to anyone really. He shows up on C-N-B-C-F or earnings
Speaker 6:  reports. It never gives wide ranging interviews. I was so excited for that
Speaker 6:  interview that this guy never talks. We asked him all the questions. Some
Speaker 6:  of the questions were pretty harsh. The audience was mad at me just for paying
Speaker 6:  attention to Adobe. They're like, why would you platform Adobe? Which
Speaker 6:  is an incredible question because it's Adobe. I don't
Speaker 6:  think I've seen a company burn that this much Goodwill ever.
Speaker 6:  Right? And then on top of it, they had their terms of service
Speaker 6:  debacle where it, we've covered terms of service
Speaker 6:  changes like this so many times. Like I could barely even pay attention to
Speaker 6:  it. Where they changed their terms of service to let them do content
Speaker 6:  moderation on their cloud services. So if you have, if you run a
Speaker 6:  cloud service, people will put bad things on your cloud service.
Speaker 6:  That is just as true effective nature as there is. Like horrific
Speaker 6:  shit will end up on your cloud storage system if you have a scaled cloud
Speaker 6:  storage system. And what you don't wanna do is give a bunch of contractors
Speaker 6:  PTSD, which is a real thing that has happened that we have covered
Speaker 6:  by making them look through stuff on cloud services or look through reports.
Speaker 6:  So you build automated systems to go through cloud services and find the
Speaker 6:  child abuse material. Like that's what you do. So Adobe changes its terms
Speaker 6:  to let people know it's gonna do this in creative Cloud. People assume that
Speaker 6:  they're gonna train on AI and they freak out at Adobe. And that
Speaker 6:  Adobe has so little goodwill that even as they tried to explain this, people
Speaker 6:  are like, we don't believe you. And so now they've updated their terms of
Speaker 6:  service again and you just connect that directly to, oh
Speaker 6:  you're getting sued by the government because annual paid monthly was not
Speaker 6:  clear to people and you charge them the rest of the money when they canceled.
Speaker 6:  It's just like to, it's crazy to me that this company is so
Speaker 6:  important but does not realize that it needs to maintain the goodwill of
Speaker 6:  the, the people that depend on it. Well you
Speaker 7:  Don't have to when you're a monopoly. You can just be a monopoly.
Speaker 6:  It's But does this make you look, I I've met all their executives. They're
Speaker 6:  not dumb,
Speaker 8:  You know? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's like baffling to me.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But they're, you know, they can do what they want. They're monopoly.
Speaker 7:  Whatcha are you gonna do go to go to Da Vinci?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, maybe. Yeah. Maybe a photo get out there.
Speaker 6:  Them not acquiring Figma I think will go down. We're gonna come back on the
Speaker 6:  failed Figma deal One because Figma will turn into a different company
Speaker 6:  and we'll see if they can go compete with Adobe. But that was driven as
Speaker 6:  much by some of this burn goodwill as anything. And I think we're gonna see
Speaker 6:  the creative tools industry bifurcate on that moment over the course of history.
Speaker 6:  'cause if they had acquired Figma, a lot of, a lot of things would've been
Speaker 6:  a lot different I think. Yeah. Alright, last lightning round one. We gotta
Speaker 6:  end here. Heath, this is like the best story in history.
Speaker 8:  Okay. Yeah. The San Francisco standard has a fun story where techies
Speaker 8:  are increasingly paying up to 1200 an hour for fashion
Speaker 8:  consultants because of CEOs like Mark Zuckerberg deciding to wear
Speaker 8:  chains. And I just encourage everyone
Speaker 8:  to read this story. There is a side-by-side photo of a guy who's gone through
Speaker 8:  one of these fashion consultants. I would argue he looked better
Speaker 8:  before. I'm not gonna like, I'm not gonna judge like, you know, I'll whatever
Speaker 8:  they, or at least the same, it's just like, as my grandfather would say,
Speaker 8:  you know, money doesn't buy sense and like reading this like,
Speaker 8:  like techies, like just be who you are. You don't need to like try to
Speaker 8:  look cool and you don't need to pay 1200 an hour to try to
Speaker 8:  look cool. Like the internet is there. Like you could just
Speaker 8:  research on
Speaker 6:  Your own. This side by side photo is brutal.
Speaker 8:  It's brutal. It's not, it's not brutal because he looks
Speaker 6:  Better or worse. He looks the same.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, the same. And then it's like both of them
Speaker 7:  Are kind of just baggy outfits.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And then like it, it's perfect because at the end, like the story,
Speaker 8:  they're like interviewing a founder who's done this and then he is like,
Speaker 8:  I'm making an AI app that will do this for people for $20
Speaker 8:  a month. And it's like the circle just completes
Speaker 6:  Itself.
Speaker 8:  That's
Speaker 6:  Amazing. You know Amazon tried to do that with their weird camera. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Super. Didn't work. Yeah. I
Speaker 8:  Just would say
Speaker 6:  If you're paying someone this much money to take you to Bloomingdale's, You
Speaker 6:  can do better than this photo.
Speaker 8:  That's what I'm saying. Like it's
Speaker 7:  Money doesn't buy. Oh, don't think he went to Bloomingdale's. He does
Speaker 8:  It. No, it does. That's the couch. Does it? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  This is, he's in the, he's in the dressing room at Bloomie's.
Speaker 7:  Oh my gosh. Get out, leave. It's not great. Leave the store,
Speaker 7:  sir. No, that's a bad look if that's what you're pulling outta Bloomingdale's.
Speaker 7:  That's like You can that at Dillard's.
Speaker 6:  That's brutal. All right, we gotta end it here Before we, before we do more
Speaker 6:  shaming,
Speaker 7:  Sorry. Sorry for your fashion.
Speaker 6:  scores.
Speaker 9:  The. Vergecast is the production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network.
Speaker 9:  Our show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll
Speaker 9:  see you next week.