# Transcript
ID: b02a6223-f010-47df-a818-f978b9bd1cc9
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6207463092334866776/388469998858561165/s93290-US-5914s-1732879773.mp3
Description: 2024 is almost over, somehow. So we gathered a bunch of our Verge colleagues and told them each to tell us three things from the year: the biggest story, their favorite new tech thing, and their favorite new non-tech thing. We got a collection of big stories, cool gadgets, great movies, and more good stuff from the year that was.
We're also planning a special episode for Tuesday, December 10th, all about The Verge and The Vergecast. So if you have questions about how we work, what we cover, why we talk about copyright law so much, or what Nilay is actually like to work with every day, tell us! Call 866-VERGE11, or email vergecast@theverge.com, and we'll answer as many as we can on the 10th. Thanks in advance!
Speaker 1:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Cozy Games.
Speaker 1:  I'm your friend David Pierce and I just bought a bunch of pens. So we've
Speaker 1:  been talking a lot about notebooks and stuff on this show over the last few
Speaker 1:  weeks. We're actually gonna talk a little bit more about it on this show.
Speaker 1:  But a thing that I should admit that I don't talk about a lot here
Speaker 1:  on The Vergecast or in life is that on the side of
Speaker 1:  being like a digital note taking lunatic, I'm also
Speaker 1:  kind of a notebook lunatic. I go through these phases every
Speaker 1:  once in a while where I'm like, okay, I'm gonna become a notebook guy. I
Speaker 1:  spend too much time on my phone. My phone is really useful, but what I need
Speaker 1:  is just when I'm gonna write things down, I'm gonna do it on pen and paper.
Speaker 1:  It's gonna be great. Love it. I always forget that the real problem is that
Speaker 1:  my handwriting is awful and that my hand hurts when I write too much. So,
Speaker 1:  I just buy a bunch of notebooks. I'm like, this will fix it. So, I have like
Speaker 1:  old, like five starts school notebooks. I have,
Speaker 1:  I have a bunch of like mole skin knockoffs. I have an actual
Speaker 1:  mole skin. I have this thing called the tote book from a company called Studio
Speaker 1:  Neat that I really like. I have one that I bought at Staples.
Speaker 1:  This one is my journal from high school in which I wrote
Speaker 1:  a bunch of poetry to my girlfriend that no one is ever allowed to read.
Speaker 1:  But the thing that I've realized most is that A, I need a notebook that is
Speaker 1:  with me most of the time. So what I usually end up doing is getting like
Speaker 1:  a little field notes thing that can just sort of live in my pocket. But the
Speaker 1:  main thing is I need pens, like a million pens and I don't wanna spend any
Speaker 1:  money on pens. So I'm gonna an Amazon and I bought these, they're called
Speaker 1:  the pilot Precise V five rt. I think I found them
Speaker 1:  from a Wirecutter review that was like, these are good pens that you don't
Speaker 1:  have to press super hard on. So. I bought 12 of them and my
Speaker 1:  plan is just to put them everywhere. Like one in the car, one in my backpack,
Speaker 1:  one at my desk, one upstairs, one next to the bed, and then the goal is just
Speaker 1:  to like always have a pen within reach. I try to carry
Speaker 1:  a pen around, but I find I'm pretty good at having my notebook with me, but
Speaker 1:  terrible at having my pen with me. So I'm going with like an infinite pens
Speaker 1:  situation. It's gonna be great. And I'm going to write in notebooks more
Speaker 1:  often. Anyway, that is not what we're here to talk about today. It's
Speaker 1:  a holiday week, at least here in the US it's Thanksgiving. So instead of
Speaker 1:  normal newsy vergecast on a week where there's not really any news, we figured
Speaker 1:  we'd do something slightly different. So what we're gonna do today is we're
Speaker 1:  gonna talk to a bunch of different folks on our staff about some of the biggest
Speaker 1:  stories of the year, the most important things that they worked on,
Speaker 1:  the most important things that we covered, their favorite new thing that
Speaker 1:  happened this year that had nothing to do with any of the stuff that we covered.
Speaker 1:  It's just fun to talk to our staff and get to know them and what they're
Speaker 1:  into and what they're interested in. And we've done this before on the show
Speaker 1:  and I had a great time doing it and y'all seem to like it too. So we invited
Speaker 1:  a bunch of people back and talk to them about some of their favorite and
Speaker 1:  some of the biggest things from 2024. All that is coming up in just
Speaker 1:  a second. We got a bunch of people to get to lots of stuff. If you're
Speaker 1:  on like a long drive this weekend, lots of stuff for you to
Speaker 1:  listen to. Lots of fun verse to have to hang out with. All that's coming
Speaker 1:  up, But. first I really, I have to go distribute this mountain
Speaker 1:  of pens all over my house and then
Speaker 1:  systematically lose them one by one until I have to buy 12 more pens. This
Speaker 1:  is the first Vergecast, we'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  thoughts on what we should be doing but aren't. I wanna hear those too. Send
Speaker 1:  them all our way. You can either call the hotline eight six six VERGE one
Speaker 1:  one or email vergecast at The Verge dot com. It send us all your questions.
Speaker 1:  December 10th, we're gonna do that episode. It's gonna be really fun. Alright,
Speaker 1:  let's get into it. So we gave a bunch of folks on our staff,
Speaker 1:  very small bits of homework, basically come with what you
Speaker 1:  think is the Story of the year, your favorite tech thing of the year, and
Speaker 1:  your favorite new non-tech thing of the year. All these things are very broad
Speaker 1:  deliberately 'cause we figured people would interpret them differently and
Speaker 1:  come with different ideas about what makes for a Story of the year
Speaker 1:  and what constitutes new tech thing of the year.
Speaker 1:  Everybody came, came with delightfully different and interesting answers,
Speaker 1:  and I think we're gonna get a swath of basically all the things The
Speaker 1:  Verge cares about, kind of all in one place, plus just a sense
Speaker 1:  of some of our favorite new stuff. All right, we have eight people to go
Speaker 1:  through. Let's do this. First up, Jay Peters news editor on our
Speaker 1:  team, Jay Peters. Hello.
Speaker 4:  Hi, David. How are you?
Speaker 1:  I'm good. We are not going to talk about this for too long, but you're
Speaker 1:  here on Wired EarPods that you just bought, and this is
Speaker 1:  not going to factor into our discussion, but I just wanna say congratulations
Speaker 1:  on your wired EarPods. Thank you. The best headphones on earth for $20.
Speaker 4:  Yes, thank you. I am plugging them directly into my MacBook Air.
Speaker 4:  Someday I'll upgrade from my iPhone 12 mini, and guess what? They'll plug
Speaker 4:  straight into those two. It'll be fantastic. I can't wait,
Speaker 1:  Honestly, like all the cool kids wear wired headphones again, and I
Speaker 1:  get it. It's like I was on a train the other day and I accidentally
Speaker 1:  spent 20 minutes trying to connect my Mac to someone else's
Speaker 1:  Bose headphones instead of my Bose headphones. And I was like, oh, I have
Speaker 1:  the cable. And I plugged it in and it was fine. It's just this, it's life
Speaker 1:  is better this way. Yeah. All right. So we gave you some homework. Let's
Speaker 1:  start with Story of the year. What was your Story of the year?
Speaker 4:  The Story of the year to me. Is Google being ruled a
Speaker 4:  monopolist? Mm. I think this is huge
Speaker 4:  because depending on what happens as a result of that
Speaker 4:  ruling, including a potential breakup of the company,
Speaker 4:  different pieces like it could fundamentally transform the way we use
Speaker 4:  the internet, how we search for things
Speaker 4:  and like what the defaults on our phones are. I think this could
Speaker 4:  be really, really, really massive in ways that we just don't even understand
Speaker 4:  yet because we don't know what the end result's gonna be.
Speaker 1:  I like this one. And I also feel like the fun thing about this story
Speaker 1:  is it, you might be correct this year
Speaker 1:  and next year and the year after that, and the year after that, and the year
Speaker 1:  after that. And then it might be nothing. Which is why this story is so much
Speaker 1:  fun. Because it is, it is either, I think you're right, these
Speaker 1:  like single most consequential thing happening in tech or it is going to
Speaker 1:  be a awful lot of hand wringing and nonsense and lawyer fees and
Speaker 1:  ultimately amount to nothing.
Speaker 4:  Yep.
Speaker 1:  What If you? If, you were a betting man. Which one would you pick of those
Speaker 1:  two outcomes?
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna say a little bit closer to the big deal end versus
Speaker 4:  the nothing end. Okay. Because to me it seems like kind of
Speaker 4:  likely that the government's gonna say Google can't make the
Speaker 4:  default deals, especially like the one on the iPhone that has made it,
Speaker 4:  you know, the pervasive mobile search on iPhone. And so like, I think
Speaker 4:  that it's just gonna have an absolutely massive change down the line.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I tend to agree, and I think I was reading something the other day
Speaker 1:  about the, all the ways in which this trial and the
Speaker 1:  Microsoft trial from 25 years ago are just scarily
Speaker 1:  similar in the way that they're going. Oh, interesting. Yeah. And, and that
Speaker 1:  one's a really fun case because what ultimately happened
Speaker 1:  was not that much, but while Microsoft was so focused on it, the internet
Speaker 1:  happened and this company called Google, like did a bunch of
Speaker 1:  smart things that Microsoft didn't have time or energy or attention to do.
Speaker 1:  And just the existence of that crazy thing
Speaker 1:  screwed up Microsoft and changed the internet.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I think If you if, especially if you're a believer that AI is as
Speaker 1:  big a deal as people say, we're sitting in the middle of that again.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It, it seems like the AI companies,
Speaker 4:  I don't see like a direct like, oh this is obviously the next Google type
Speaker 4:  thing, but like, it seems like there, there's something in that
Speaker 4:  everybody is starting to realize that maybe Google isn't the only option
Speaker 4:  and that could have very large ramifications in how we use
Speaker 4:  tech every single day.
Speaker 1:  I, I'm, I'm with you. Are you using any of the AI search engines by the way?
Speaker 4:  No, I so far have not been a huge fan of them,
Speaker 4:  but I think it's also time for me to explore them
Speaker 4:  a little bit more.
Speaker 1:  I feel the same way. There's something in the muscle memory of it that
Speaker 1:  has just been much harder for me to change than I expected. And
Speaker 4:  That might just be because of my like day-to-day work of like
Speaker 4:  writing news as fast as possible all the time. Like yeah,
Speaker 1:  We like Google stuff for a living. Yeah. Like it's a real way.
Speaker 4:  I have like really specific ways that I find this information that I know
Speaker 4:  that it works 95% of the time that like other search
Speaker 4:  engines may not be strictly built for my use case, but that might also
Speaker 4:  not be true. Or there might be ways that I can use those things that I haven't
Speaker 4:  tried yet.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. All right. What's your New thing of the year? Presumably it's not a
Speaker 1:  search engine. What's your new thing
Speaker 4:  I would say? My favorite new thing is a game I played this year. It was
Speaker 4:  Final Fantasy seven Rebirth. I say this as a huge fan of the original
Speaker 4:  PlayStation game. I loved the remake and So I had the really high
Speaker 4:  expectations going into this one and it totally exceeded them. It's like
Speaker 4:  this just giant RPG, you're hanging out with your friends, these characters
Speaker 4:  that like, you know, I've followed and, you know, fallen in love with in
Speaker 4:  various, you know, for various reasons playing the games forever.
Speaker 4:  And I thought Square Inc's just totally deliberate on this really incredible,
Speaker 4:  huge ambitious RPG. I also have a very special memory in that
Speaker 4:  I played so much of it in the middle of the night while my new child was
Speaker 4:  sleeping on me. So like I have this like kind of really cool attachment with
Speaker 4:  like what that game represented in addition to the time of my life
Speaker 4:  that I'm in right now.
Speaker 1:  The genre of video games you can play with a sleeping child on top of
Speaker 1:  you is a, is a special, special thing. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I have never had the occasion to do this with somebody on this podcast,
Speaker 1:  and I'm gonna make you do this right now. Okay. I have never played one second
Speaker 1:  of Final Fantasy in my entire life. Okay. Not for any good reason. It's just
Speaker 1:  never happened. Yeah. So can you, can you give me like the,
Speaker 1:  the 62nd case for someone who has never played Final Fantasy to get
Speaker 1:  into specifically Final Fantasy? VII Rebirth?
Speaker 4:  Well, I wouldn't start with Rebirth Okay. Specifically 'cause it's part two
Speaker 4:  of a three part giant story. You should start with, oh,
Speaker 1:  See now I'm just tired already, Jay. I know, but you should, I know this
Speaker 4:  Is the problem with these games. I've already spent so much time in it that
Speaker 4:  I have to see it all the way through. All right, fair enough. If you're gonna
Speaker 4:  start, start with remake, which I think
Speaker 4:  it captures everything that people loved about the
Speaker 4:  original, on the original PlayStation brings it up to, what would you call,
Speaker 4:  you know, modern graphics and modern gay play standards. And
Speaker 4:  they, they clearly know the source material very well and they know that
Speaker 4:  people really, they really love it and they really treat it with
Speaker 4:  like care and, and expanding it in ways that are very interesting and
Speaker 4:  still feel very true to the source material, but also
Speaker 4:  have some kind of new interesting spins on the story that everybody's very
Speaker 4:  familiar with from your original game into this new stuff. So like, it's
Speaker 4:  long, you know, as a parent, I don't know, If, you're able to find 50 free
Speaker 4:  hours to dig into that, but like If, you really want something to like settle
Speaker 4:  into and, and just dig into. It's, it's awesome and it's really fun
Speaker 4:  to play too. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Is it the kind of game you can play in long stints
Speaker 1:  or short stints? Can you play 20 minutes of Final Fantasy at a
Speaker 1:  time?
Speaker 4:  Yes, I would. I would argue so if only because that's
Speaker 4:  a muscle I've had to develop since having a kid just in general is like understanding
Speaker 4:  that not every session is gonna be like two hours on the couch at the end
Speaker 4:  of a workday. It's like 20 minutes here, 20 minutes there. And I think you
Speaker 4:  can do it in that there's always like either like little quests to be doing
Speaker 4:  or you can, you know, advance farther along along
Speaker 4:  whatever main story path that you're doing and you can play it on Steam deck,
Speaker 4:  which I dunno, If you have a steam deck, but I love my steam deck. It's fantastic
Speaker 4:  thing for If. you have a kid and you just need to play a game somewhere around
Speaker 4:  the house where you have time. I think you can do it.
Speaker 1:  All right. I love it. All right, last thing. Favorite non-text of the year?
Speaker 4:  Well, the Sentimental Choice is my new child, obviously, but if I, no, that
Speaker 4:  doesn't count. That's not true. If I have to pick, if I pick
Speaker 4:  something else, I got a pack of field
Speaker 4:  notes notebooks from attending the xo XO conference in the
Speaker 4:  final one in Portland this year. This is like a special brand that they made
Speaker 4:  just for the show. And normally I've not ever cared about Field
Speaker 4:  Notes, but I actually started like using them a bunch and I think
Speaker 4:  they're awesome. They're very pocketable.
Speaker 4:  I like the little grid on the ones that I got here. Just very nice for
Speaker 4:  sketching random stuff. And I find that, like, I'm finding that
Speaker 4:  writing to-do lists or, or outlining stories
Speaker 4:  just with pen and paper and no computer has been like a really
Speaker 4:  great thing for my brain to process stuff. And it's something
Speaker 4:  I've done just way more than I ever expected. Like I thought as
Speaker 4:  a new parent I'd be like, okay, super locked in all my tech stuff. I gotta
Speaker 4:  be super zeroed in on that. But sometimes just sketching in an notebook at
Speaker 4:  the end of the day has been a really, really good way to get a handle on
Speaker 4:  things.
Speaker 1:  I love that. I think field notes I have always struggled with because like
Speaker 1:  you said, they're the exact right size. Like as a, as notebooks
Speaker 1:  go, it is the thing I want, but I
Speaker 1:  have never figured out how to like, hold it in my hand
Speaker 1:  correctly to write in it. Let's
Speaker 4:  See. Because it's
Speaker 1:  Just, it's just not quite rigid enough. Yes. And and there's something I
Speaker 1:  I end up fascinating between these like giant super
Speaker 1:  sturdy notebooks that are like really easy to write on in any circumstance.
Speaker 1:  And these like teeny tiny ones that fit in my pocket. And I
Speaker 1:  love a field notes, they make great stuff. But there is, there is something
Speaker 1:  about it that is like, I just occasionally find it annoying to write in and
Speaker 1:  it drives me crazy.
Speaker 4:  What I think I found is I do like the, your hand is the, is
Speaker 4:  the back. Like it's the, the support for everything. But I'm also not
Speaker 4:  doing a ton of extensive journaling. It's like, oh, I'll dash
Speaker 4:  off a sentence here, or I'll write some bullets here. And that I think
Speaker 4:  makes it so, like, if I had to sit down and write, if I was sketching out
Speaker 4:  a novel on this, this would not be my favorite place to do it. Fair. But
Speaker 4:  for, for taking notes or thinking through ideas and, you know, I'll write
Speaker 4:  a sentence. I'll sit on something and think about it, write another sentence.
Speaker 4:  It's been really perfect for me. So I would recommend it for, for that. That's
Speaker 4:  really good use case.
Speaker 1:  I love that. Yeah. Field notes for the win. There's like an entire corner
Speaker 1:  of old head bloggers who just got very excited hearing you said
Speaker 4:  That, I'm sure. Yes.
Speaker 1:  So awesome Jay, thank you as always. Appreciate
Speaker 4:  It. Thanks David.
Speaker 1:  Okay, moving on. Next up, Jake Kastrenakes, the versus
Speaker 1:  executive editor. Jake. Hello.
Speaker 5:  Thanks for having me.
Speaker 1:  I, the sweater game with you is always very strong. Most people, it's all
Speaker 1:  moody. People will not be able to see this, but the, the sweater game is
Speaker 1:  very strong with Jake all the time.
Speaker 5:  Can I tell you, Thomas Ricker, when he came from the Netherlands, oh my
Speaker 1:  God. Spectacular.
Speaker 5:  That's the Europeans know what they're doing.
Speaker 1:  Thomas at one point was wearing a sweater that I thought was very good, and
Speaker 1:  then he put a scarf on over the sweater and I was like, God, it's even better.
Speaker 1:  And then he put a jacket on over the scarf in the sweater that was even better
Speaker 1:  and tie the whole thing. It was the most incredible thing I've ever experienced.
Speaker 5:  We're hopeless in comparison.
Speaker 1:  Truly, truly. All right, Jake, we gave you some homework. What's your Story
Speaker 1:  of the
Speaker 5:  Year? Okay. I hate to be that guy. I I really do.
Speaker 5:  I really do. But I have to tell you, it's ai.
Speaker 1:  Okay, listen. I
Speaker 5:  Mean Sure. Listen, it's okay. It's the obvious one. It's the obvious one.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But look, we came from a year where AI is
Speaker 5:  the most
Speaker 5:  hopelessly overhyped technology
Speaker 5:  all year nonstop. And I hate to be the person, but I think AI
Speaker 5:  is actually good, not
Speaker 5:  necessarily for humanity. Okay. I, I don't wanna say that, but, but
Speaker 5:  just fundamentally on a product level, I can punch a button on my phone
Speaker 5:  and have a conversation with, I don't, I don't know
Speaker 5:  what it is.
Speaker 1:  It's, it's best not to think
Speaker 5:  About it. I can diagnose the problem with my air conditioning system,
Speaker 5:  right? Yeah. I I I don't know how to do that myself.
Speaker 1:  Can I, can I tell you my own story just from the other day? Yeah. So it's
Speaker 1:  open enrollment time at Vox Media. We're all doing our benefits. I
Speaker 1:  had to decide whether we wanted to do my health insurance that we get
Speaker 1:  or my wife's health insurance through her job. And I looked at the
Speaker 1:  summary of benefits document for like, I swear to God hours and
Speaker 1:  my eyes glaze over. I couldn't remember which was which the, the words.
Speaker 1:  I uploaded the two documents to Notebook lm and was
Speaker 1:  just like, which one's better given what I think is coming for the next year?
Speaker 1:  And laid out a couple of things and it told me the answer and it was correct.
Speaker 1:  It was the most incredible thing I've ever seen in a minute and a half. It
Speaker 1:  was just like, it was like, here's all the information you need about which
Speaker 1:  insurance to pick. And I was like, oh, I had the same thought you did. I
Speaker 1:  was like, oh, AI is good. Now I I take it back.
Speaker 5:  There's the thing e everybody has that moment eventually, and it's like,
Speaker 5:  I don't know that this is going to completely revolutionize the world, at
Speaker 5:  least as it is right now, but there are these small moments where it's like,
Speaker 5:  that just saved me 10 minutes of Googling. Right? It's not a hundred percent
Speaker 5:  correct, but like, it got me in the ballpark and, and yeah, that's actually
Speaker 5:  what I need right now.
Speaker 1:  I totally agree. I had somebody a while ago tell me that If, you just look
Speaker 1:  at AI as the world's most powerful summarization
Speaker 1:  machine that is both a much smaller vision
Speaker 1:  for it and also really cool and full of neat things that it can do. And I
Speaker 1:  like, I've been thinking about that ever since. And it's like that there
Speaker 1:  is a lot you can do there. And that's actually a thing it's good at.
Speaker 5:  I I think we have these maybe impossibly high standards for
Speaker 5:  AI and look like I, it's our job to hold these
Speaker 5:  companies to those high standards. That's fine. I'm going to keep demanding
Speaker 5:  that they make these things better. But If you told me, you know,
Speaker 5:  a year or two ago that I can on hand
Speaker 5:  have somebody who will, you know, gimme a ballpark correct answer
Speaker 5:  or do math for me or, or you know, write something
Speaker 5:  for me and it'll be like reasonably good. That would seem impossible.
Speaker 5:  And I think reasonably good is still pretty
Speaker 5:  impressive. Again, problems abound. I will be the first to
Speaker 5:  admit that, right? But these things exploded.
Speaker 5:  They are suddenly in everything. I do not know if people are
Speaker 5:  actually using them in most of these places, but I
Speaker 5:  have a suspicion that a lot of these very minor small use
Speaker 5:  cases, just writing stuff better summarizing stuff is going to
Speaker 5:  become second nature for people very quickly.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, totally. And I think 2025 is, I hope the
Speaker 1:  year where the like high-minded rhetoric
Speaker 1:  gets a little closer to the actual reality. Like the tech
Speaker 1:  is gonna get a little better, but also everybody just needs to calm down
Speaker 1:  about it for a minute.
Speaker 5:  Everybody needs to calm down a bit and Nvidia is worth like
Speaker 5:  $500 trillion or something. I I don't,
Speaker 5:  don't quote me on that one Exactly. But
Speaker 1:  It's not investment advice. Some
Speaker 5:  Something feels a little off there. Like it's cool technology, but like
Speaker 5:  yeah, people need to chill out a little bit.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's not God just yet. Yeah. But maybe, you know, we'll do this
Speaker 1:  again in 12 months. Who knows? All right. What's your next one? Your your
Speaker 1:  favorite New thing of the year?
Speaker 5:  Favorite New thing of the year? I'm shooting a little bit 'cause this is
Speaker 5:  from end of last year. I bought it this year. But I wanna hype up
Speaker 5:  the Weam amp.
Speaker 5:  This is If. you are a psycho like
Speaker 5:  me who has a bookshelf speaker
Speaker 5:  system, right? You don't have an all-in-one, right? No soundbar.
Speaker 5:  You didn't just buy some powered speakers. You have speakers that
Speaker 5:  need to be powered by an amp that need different input sources
Speaker 5:  fed into them. You've probably gone through the absolute
Speaker 5:  madness and chaos of having a bunch of different parts and pieces.
Speaker 5:  You need the amp, you need the streamer, you need the phono amp, you need
Speaker 5:  all these different things. The we Amp says, Hey,
Speaker 5:  I know it's all, it sounds better If. you get 500 different things
Speaker 5:  and, and come and and stack them all together. What if we just skip all that
Speaker 5:  isn't gonna, is it gonna put everything in one, $300? It
Speaker 5:  sounds reasonably good and it does all the things
Speaker 5:  that I I hate that all these fancy sound
Speaker 5:  system parts do not do. It automatically turns on and off.
Speaker 5:  It doesn't get flaming hot in my cabinet.
Speaker 5:  It streams things, it switches inputs automatically.
Speaker 5:  My TV can control it. It's great. I love it.
Speaker 1:  I cannot describe to you how convincing a pitch that just was.
Speaker 1:  I think about my parents all the time who bought this like as tall
Speaker 1:  as me set of speakers when I was a kid. Yeah. And they still
Speaker 1:  have it. And all the other parts of their system that they had the, you know,
Speaker 1:  the CD player and the FM radio, all that stuff is a million years old and
Speaker 1:  long dead. But the speakers still sound amazing and they have spent all this
Speaker 1:  time trying to figure out, the speakers are just sitting in the basement
Speaker 1:  and they're like, well, what do we do with these? Because again, like you
Speaker 1:  said, it's, do I rebuild a room full of stuff? I'm
Speaker 1:  gonna literally, I'm going to buy this for my parents for Christmas and it's
Speaker 1:  going to blow their minds.
Speaker 5:  I'm telling you. It is, it is. As somebody who has done it over and over
Speaker 5:  again, it is not worth rebuilding. Like all these
Speaker 5:  separate items and stringing 'em together. It is such a hassle. The
Speaker 5:  sound is not that much better. Don't come for me.
Speaker 5:  You know, just, just give into the simplicity. You know, your speakers are
Speaker 5:  still gonna sound great. And this has basically nearly everything
Speaker 5:  a sound system needs with the one exception of a a funnel input. It doesn't
Speaker 5:  have that, that's a bummer. So you do need a separate amp for that, but otherwise
Speaker 5:  it can stream Chromecast, it can stream airplay.
Speaker 5:  I don't know a can hook up to your tv. It's great.
Speaker 1:  I love it. All right. Well last thing. Favorite non-tech thing of the year?
Speaker 5:  Favorite non-tech thing of the year? This is a, again, not from
Speaker 5:  this year I'm cheating, but for me personally Yeah. New to you.
Speaker 1:  It counts.
Speaker 5:  This, this is a new to me thing. I found a card game
Speaker 5:  that has been a, a hit of all of the board game
Speaker 5:  nights I have been to. It is super simple. I think as I've gotten
Speaker 5:  older, I have strayed from the games where they take like two and a half
Speaker 5:  hours to play Yeah. And need to read an instruction manual for an hour beforehand.
Speaker 5:  The game is called Chronoloy. It is super simple. I love it. And basically
Speaker 5:  it's a deck of cards and each card has an event and a
Speaker 5:  year on it. And everybody starts out with one ear. Right.
Speaker 5:  And somebody's gonna read you another one. And so in front of you,
Speaker 5:  you might have something that says Apple Computers is
Speaker 5:  founded and it says 1976. That's what happened. Right. Okay. So
Speaker 5:  now's your turn David, and I'm gonna read you the next card. And it says,
Speaker 5:  LBJ becomes president after JFK's assassination.
Speaker 5:  And you have to say, did this happen before or after?
Speaker 1:  Before.
Speaker 5:  Before Easy. Okay. Not too bad. But now you've got two cards down, right?
Speaker 5:  You've got 1976. 1963 So I say The Beatles
Speaker 5:  appear on Ed Sullivan. What was that? Before, after, or in between?
Speaker 5:  Now it gets complicated. Ooh. Because you're like, Hmm. 60.
Speaker 5:  It
Speaker 1:  Was in between,
Speaker 5:  It was in between, it was 6 4, 12. Right. And it is fun. It's really, that
Speaker 5:  is very fun. It's really super easy to learn, super fast party game.
Speaker 5:  And it's fun because you get to, you know, rib your friends about not knowing
Speaker 5:  history. I don't know anything.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I feel like I'd be, I'd be good until about the dates that you
Speaker 1:  said and then it would all fall apart for me. It's like the things where
Speaker 1:  people talk about something that happened in like the Roman Empire and I'm
Speaker 1:  like, oh, that was like the 1450s. Right? And they're like, that was 16
Speaker 1:  bc I'm always like, all right, cool.
Speaker 5:  The amount of time it took me to think on, I, I got
Speaker 5:  a Pompei card and I'm like, Jesus. I'm pretty sure that was,
Speaker 5:  that was far back. But I don't know
Speaker 1:  How there's a thousand years
Speaker 5:  I would say it was, it was pretty, yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. A lot of people made funny for that one. Turns out it was a really
Speaker 5:  long time ago. That
Speaker 1:  Should be enough. Like you should get a half point for just being like, it
Speaker 1:  was, it was before The Beatles. That's
Speaker 5:  All that's, I knew it was, I knew it was before you get the point. I knew
Speaker 5:  it was before The Beatles. That was all I needed to know.
Speaker 1:  That's pretty good. Game's called Chronoloy.
Speaker 5:  Chronoloy. All right. Highly recommended for Chill, fun
Speaker 5:  board game night.
Speaker 1:  I like it. All right, Jake, thank you as always.
Speaker 5:  Cool. Talk to you later.
Speaker 1:  Next up on the list, Justine Calma, our senior science reporter,
Speaker 1:  Justine. Hello.
Speaker 6:  Hello.
Speaker 1:  Coming to us from the control room of one of our podcast studios.
Speaker 1:  Yes. I love this. All right, so we gave you some homework. The first thing
Speaker 1:  you had to do was come with your Story of the year. What was the Story of
Speaker 1:  the year?
Speaker 6:  Well, that for me was a no brainer. It was definitely the
Speaker 6:  US presidential election. Sure. Well, the outcome of the elections,
Speaker 6:  this is, you know, this is what I'm losing sleep over leading up
Speaker 6:  to next year. I mean, it just changes. It, it affects everything. Right.
Speaker 6:  For me on the science desk, I'm an environmental reporter and so there
Speaker 6:  are literally studies out there around how much more
Speaker 6:  pollution we can expect with this next administration, how much more that's
Speaker 6:  gonna warm the planet. We cover a life in the future. And so, you know,
Speaker 6:  we're looking at a hotter future,
Speaker 6:  all kinds of fallout. And, you know, across all of
Speaker 6:  the desks that we cover, I do a lot of work with the policy team. Over
Speaker 6:  the past year we were covering some major Supreme Court decisions.
Speaker 6:  The Supreme Court ha has been absolutely made over with
Speaker 6:  Trump's previous appointees. That's made it more difficult. Some of those
Speaker 6:  Supreme Court decisions have made it more difficult to regulate industry.
Speaker 6:  So, you know, that has wide reaching effects and
Speaker 6:  So I, that for me is a, the Story of the year
Speaker 6:  going into next year.
Speaker 1:  Is there anything on your mind on that front right now, other than
Speaker 1:  just sort of sheer abject screaming and
Speaker 1:  rage all the time? I feel like we're, we're in a moment now where, where
Speaker 1:  like we as reporters and also just like we as people are going to have to
Speaker 1:  figure out like how to talk about this stuff other than just
Speaker 1:  what sometimes feels like directionless screaming all
Speaker 1:  the time. Like what, what's on your mind as you're thinking about kind of
Speaker 1:  the, the stories inside of this that you're thinking about over the next
Speaker 1:  year or so?
Speaker 6:  One thing that's gonna be really interesting to watch is what happens at
Speaker 6:  the state and local level. You know, in the past that
Speaker 6:  that has been where people have counteracted
Speaker 6:  what's going on at the federal level, made progress when there's been an
Speaker 6:  action at the national level. And so it'll be really interesting to see
Speaker 6:  what comes out of that sort of local
Speaker 6:  organizing moving forward. And then another
Speaker 6:  interesting place to watch, which is like
Speaker 6:  very divisive in the environmental community, but surprisingly
Speaker 6:  super bipartisan is gonna be nuclear
Speaker 6:  energy. And So I was gonna ask you about this.
Speaker 1:  Okay.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, exactly. So I mean. If you're looking at just
Speaker 6:  my beat on The Verge, I think one of the biggest stories has been this,
Speaker 6:  is it too soon to say nuclear renaissance? It's probably too soon. But there's
Speaker 6:  anything Renaissance is like overkill, right? But yeah, but there's been
Speaker 6:  a whole lot of interest in nuclear energy, particularly from
Speaker 6:  tech companies looking for electricity,
Speaker 6:  for energy hungry data centers. You know, this is a growing issue with
Speaker 6:  ai. We saw a slew of nuclear energy deals
Speaker 6:  from Amazon, Google,
Speaker 6:  Microsoft.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Three Mile Island is coming back. Like what a, what a weird
Speaker 1:  version of the timeline here.
Speaker 6:  So they say we'll have to watch and see. Fair. But,
Speaker 6:  but yes, but you know, Trump has been supportive of nuclear energy in the
Speaker 6:  past. It's gotten bipartisan support. If, you look at
Speaker 6:  Trump's pick to lead the Department of Energy, Chris Wright, he is
Speaker 6:  a fossil fuel executive, CEO of a fracking company, but also
Speaker 6:  sits on the board of a nuclear energy company with
Speaker 6:  Sam Altman. So that'll be really interesting to see that company is developing
Speaker 6:  advanced nuclear reactors. I don't know. We'll, we'll have to see what happens.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I feel like with, with a lot of that stuff, I always get
Speaker 1:  tripped up trying to figure out how long these things take. Because on the
Speaker 1:  one hand we have these like super pressing issues and the,
Speaker 1:  there were the three Mile Island guy was basically saying like, we're ready.
Speaker 1:  Let's spin this back up and go back to work. Everything's gonna be terrific.
Speaker 1:  And then you hear about all these projects that are, you know, we're, we're
Speaker 1:  talking about like 20, 40 deadlines for things. And like, God only knows
Speaker 1:  where we'll be by 2040. Yeah. Is this stuff gonna start to
Speaker 1:  become sort of meaningfully real next year, do you think?
Speaker 6:  No. Okay. Okay. I think we, I think we may see more deals,
Speaker 6:  but the earliest projections that I've seen for the first advanced
Speaker 6:  nuclear reactors coming online are gonna be
Speaker 6:  probably the early 2030s. And so it's gonna be a while
Speaker 6:  before we see these, these new technologies. And to be clear,
Speaker 6:  those are next generation nuclear reactors that have not
Speaker 6:  been deployed in the US yet. You know, they still need to get all of the
Speaker 6:  regulatory approvals and everything. Not to mention
Speaker 6:  the costs, because Sure. Both tradition, like old school
Speaker 6:  nuclear reactors, the, the big plants that we, we
Speaker 6:  have today, they're really expensive to build this, these next
Speaker 6:  generation technologies are supposed to be smaller and cheaper, but
Speaker 6:  projects have also run into rising costs too. So yeah. So
Speaker 6:  that's why a lot of this stuff is still up in the air. You have all of the
Speaker 6:  regulatory and permitting delays, and then you have everything that's going
Speaker 6:  on when it comes to making this actually an
Speaker 6:  affordable source of energy.
Speaker 1:  Got it. Okay. And I would say, it doesn't seem like the regulatory state
Speaker 1:  is going to get more efficient and effective in, in the very near future.
Speaker 1:  So I would not say My hopes are super high, but hey, we'll, we'll take it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. We'll see what this efficiency task fork does. I mean, it could
Speaker 6:  just be like, go ahead, do whatever you want.
Speaker 1:  I mean, fair. That would be, it would go faster than short. Yeah, it would
Speaker 1:  go faster. All right. What was your favorite
Speaker 1:  New thing of the year?
Speaker 6:  Year? Okay. So I have to plug, I, I'm a really big documentary fan.
Speaker 6:  I just, I love nonfiction. But I had to plug
Speaker 6:  this documentary that is still in theaters
Speaker 6:  called Nurse Unseen. It's about Filipino nurses. I,
Speaker 6:  I'm Filipino, my mom is a nurse. And you know, at the Emmy's this year,
Speaker 6:  you saw the host talk about how er went like 15
Speaker 6:  seasons without ever having a Filipino nurse If. you go into
Speaker 6:  almost any hospital medical establishment, you're bound to find
Speaker 6:  a lot of Filipino nurses. And so this documentary goes into the whole history
Speaker 6:  of that, why there's been a pipeline of nurses coming to the US from the
Speaker 6:  Philippines since really World War ii, the Philippines was a US territory.
Speaker 6:  But it also just talks about, it really focuses on
Speaker 6:  how these nurses were on the front lines during the pandemic and So
Speaker 6:  I just think it really gives voice to a community that's been overlooked
Speaker 6:  and has just done a lot for our healthcare system.
Speaker 6:  So that was one of my favorite documentaries of, of the year. That's
Speaker 6:  a really good one. And hoping that it's streaming soon. I
Speaker 1:  Was just about to ask, it's still, it's still in theaters right now.
Speaker 6:  It's still in theaters. Okay. I have heard that they're, well, I don't know,
Speaker 6:  I don't wanna give anything away. I'm hoping that it's streaming soon. Fair
Speaker 6:  enough.
Speaker 1:  Fair enough. We'll, we'll, we'll track it down in a theater. I love a documentary
Speaker 1:  on the big screen, by the way. It's like, it's sort of an unusual thing.
Speaker 1:  It feels like this is gonna sound less like a compliment
Speaker 1:  than, I mean it, but it's, it feels like school in like the best possible
Speaker 1:  way to sit in a, in a, especially in like a little tiny like art
Speaker 1:  house thing. I went to a jazz documentary, like, frankly, I don't care about
Speaker 1:  jazz, but like, I just sat in a room with a bunch of people who are like,
Speaker 1:  I wanna spend two hours learning about jazz. And it was delightful. And I
Speaker 1:  like, I'm like, I give me more of those moments of like sitting in a lecture
Speaker 1:  hall watching something really interesting together. Like, I kind of miss
Speaker 1:  those days. It's good stuff.
Speaker 6:  Well, okay, I'll say my guilty pleasure this year's. I did go to a cat film
Speaker 6:  festival in New York City, A
Speaker 1:  Cat film festival.
Speaker 6:  Alright. Yeah. Which is exactly how it sounds. It's like basically your
Speaker 6:  Instagram or TikTok reel full of cat videos, but on a big screen.
Speaker 6:  But you don't go for the videos, you go for the community and all of the
Speaker 6:  people
Speaker 6:  who love cats as much as you do, and like all of the like, cute
Speaker 6:  kids that are having a great time. And it's just, I don't know. Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 6:  You, you go to documentaries and
Speaker 6:  Yeah, those kinds of screenings to just be with your people.
Speaker 1:  That's fantastic. It's like a, it's like a fake or it's like a backwards
Speaker 1:  way of having a cat convention. I love that very much. Yeah, yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1:  They're like, we're gonna pretend this is a movie, but it's just so a bunch
Speaker 1:  of cat people can hang out with each other. It's gonna be fun, I
Speaker 6:  Think. Yeah. I think that film festival is on tour as well.
Speaker 1:  Idea Unbeliev wants to watch it idea. I have, I have no notes on that. All
Speaker 1:  right. Did you have one more pick for us? What, what else is on your list?
Speaker 6:  Okay, well, okay. I did pick one other documentary that,
Speaker 6:  that I also saw in theaters, but it's also streaming on Disney Plus and Hulu.
Speaker 6:  It's called Sugarcane. It premiered at the 2024
Speaker 6:  Sundance Film Festival this year. It's a really important watch. It's a,
Speaker 6:  it's a tough one as well. It, it's about an, an investigation
Speaker 6:  into abuse at an Indian
Speaker 6:  residential school run by the Catholic church in Canada after they found
Speaker 6:  unmarked graves. It was created
Speaker 6:  by an advocate who is actually a source that I've interviewed
Speaker 6:  in the past. He's an environmental justice advocate,
Speaker 6:  but he, his dad went to the school and it's a really
Speaker 6:  powerful story too, about healing and his
Speaker 6:  relationship with his dad and how they move forward.
Speaker 6:  So that was another, another pick for me.
Speaker 1:  That's a really good one. Yeah. I feel like we're in this funny moment
Speaker 1:  of like, there are so many great documentaries out
Speaker 1:  there and my list of ones to watch now is so
Speaker 1:  infuriatingly long that I just, I have to like, I
Speaker 1:  need to cancel all of my streaming services except for the documentary ones
Speaker 1:  for like six months and just catch up on documentaries and it's gonna be
Speaker 1:  great. Very excited about it. Yeah. Yeah. Awesome. All right,
Speaker 1:  Justine, thank you so much. Appreciate you doing this.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, thanks. Oh, sorry. The other thing for the non-tech thing I forgot
Speaker 6:  was our, our 2004 package was incredible
Speaker 6:  this year. Like just, it just brought me back to high school. And even
Speaker 6:  just our talking about making that happen
Speaker 6:  was just so much fun. Like all of us on The Verge staff liked combing
Speaker 6:  through our pictures, trying to find them from 2004 and discovering that
Speaker 6:  they've all vanished and then seeing the story that came out of that was,
Speaker 6:  was awesome.
Speaker 1:  The first run of people's pictures from 2004 was pretty spectacular.
Speaker 1:  Everybody seemed to have like one photo from that year, and
Speaker 1:  it's always incredibly embarrassing and it
Speaker 1:  just Terrific. Loved it. Very much
Speaker 6:  Love.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. All love it. All of my 2004 photos are just like me wearing two popped
Speaker 1:  collars and like a pukka shell necklace. It was not, yes. Not like a cool
Speaker 1:  time in my history. I wouldn't say.
Speaker 6:  Oh my God. Yeah, I can see that so clearly.
Speaker 1:  Well, that's the meanest thing you've ever said to me. Ine hurts my feelings.
Speaker 6:  No, no, that was, I mean, who didn't have a pook shell necklace? Right.
Speaker 1:  Listen, I got out of it. That's all I can say. It's, there you go. It took
Speaker 1:  too long to get out of it. Is
Speaker 6:  It back yet? I'm like, all that stuff is coming back. Right? I'm just waiting
Speaker 6:  till I see the high school students rocking it again.
Speaker 1:  I assume So. My I have two nephews in high school right now, and neither
Speaker 1:  of them are wearing puka, but like frosted tips I think are starting to come
Speaker 1:  back. So like, it's, it's coming. Yeah. The, the pukas are coming. It's,
Speaker 1:  it's a terrifying thought.
Speaker 1:  our supervising producer on our video team. Veen. Hello.
Speaker 7:  Hello.
Speaker 1:  You told us before we started recording that you didn't prepare at all, so
Speaker 1:  this is gonna go really great or really terribly. Yeah, either way. I'm very
Speaker 1:  excited. It's,
Speaker 7:  It's gonna go great.
Speaker 1:  I, I feel good about it.
Speaker 7:  I'm always under-prepared for everything that we do. So it's
Speaker 1:  Under promise and overdeliver. That's the, the VE end story.
Speaker 7:  It usually ends up pretty good. So, you know, let's let,
Speaker 7:  let's try it out.
Speaker 1:  I'm into it. So thing number one was the Story of the year. What's your Story
Speaker 1:  of the year? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I'm immediately coming with a curve ball here. I'm gonna pick
Speaker 7:  a video of the year. I am a supervising producer at The Verge So I. Feel
Speaker 7:  like, I feel like I can pick a video. Is that okay? Can I break the rules
Speaker 7:  here?
Speaker 1:  You, yeah, you can pick whatever you want. Okay.
Speaker 7:  For video of the year, I have to go with the Vision
Speaker 7:  Pro Review because it was just like one of those like classic
Speaker 7:  VERGE reviews that was just like way overproduced
Speaker 7:  in a short period of time. It was a whole team just
Speaker 7:  working together. Like late into the night. The script
Speaker 7:  that Neli delivered came in incredibly late
Speaker 7:  and was incredibly good. It was just like one read and it was like,
Speaker 7:  this is amazing. The only problem is it's currently 35 minutes long,
Speaker 7:  we're gonna have to cut like a third of it out, which we did. But
Speaker 7:  it was such a strong script, it was really good. And then just, you know,
Speaker 7:  it was a new, new product category for Apple. A lot
Speaker 7:  of eyes on it. Yeah. It just felt like, I, I love
Speaker 7:  the hustle, I love the time crunch, I love embargoes, I love all that stuff.
Speaker 7:  It is exhausting, but it was very exciting time
Speaker 7:  of the year and it was like very much at the beginning of 2024. And it feels
Speaker 7:  like, I don't know, it feels like it was either like two days ago or
Speaker 7:  like seven years ago. I can decide. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I hear that. I feel like if, if we had been talking
Speaker 1:  in February, like what are gonna be the, you know, technology
Speaker 1:  stories of the year for 2024, I feel like we all would've picked the Vision
Speaker 1:  Pro to be one of them. And
Speaker 1:  our video was very good. The Vision Pro less
Speaker 1:  good. And I think the, what we've seen in the 10 months
Speaker 1:  since that thing came out at this point is it kind of feels like it just
Speaker 1:  died. I don't know, like do you, does anyone you know, talk about or care
Speaker 1:  about the Vision Pro anymore?
Speaker 7:  No. There's always like a moment on threads. Maybe
Speaker 7:  when somebody who has the Vision Pro is like, Hey, this cool thing came
Speaker 7:  out, you should look at it. And I see a screen recording, I'm like, oh, that's
Speaker 7:  great. Move on. But
Speaker 7:  like, like two weeks ago. Yeah, the Ultra Wide Monitor support came out.
Speaker 7:  People
Speaker 1:  Are excited about this. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Looks pretty sick. Like pairing it with a Mac Mini and having that, like,
Speaker 7:  that work space incredibly amazing. You'll still need a
Speaker 7:  monitor. It's, it's not like you can just live in Vision Pro
Speaker 7:  and like fully beat yourself into it. I did
Speaker 7:  use it, you know, during our testing period
Speaker 7:  and, and everything. And that was the thing that I actually enjoyed the most.
Speaker 7:  Just external monitor, using it as just like an
Speaker 7:  extra monitor, like leaning into a
Speaker 7:  Lightroom photo, right? Or like just
Speaker 7:  getting closer to it and doing some like brushes and
Speaker 7:  coloring and everything did actually feel incredibly fun.
Speaker 7:  Like I thoroughly enjoyed that. I don't know if I can do it for hours and
Speaker 7:  hours and hours. But being in the Vision Pro, like virtual
Speaker 7:  monitor, using it, that was like, that was for me the, the
Speaker 7:  best use case for it. I do wish,
Speaker 7:  like Apple Pencil gets some kind of support there.
Speaker 7:  'cause it does, it takes you away when you have to like go back to keyboard
Speaker 7:  and mouse sort of thing. You know, like it's just, it's like, oh, okay.
Speaker 7:  I'm still using kind of a similar input here. Even though the,
Speaker 7:  like the feature is good. So I, I wish there was like more there to do,
Speaker 7:  even just like zooming in or like doing more stuff with it. So
Speaker 7:  that was like a good use case. So, I do, do understand why people are very
Speaker 7:  excited about the ultra wide monitor. But yeah, the price is just
Speaker 7:  too extreme for anyone to like buy this and,
Speaker 7:  and use it. But, you know, it's, it's impressive and
Speaker 7:  it's just too expensive.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I, I could not agree more. And the improvement
Speaker 1:  is increasingly far away. It seems like, like the, the
Speaker 1:  solutions to this problem seem like they keep slipping out, but let's move
Speaker 1:  on. No thing number two, your favorite New thing of the
Speaker 1:  year.
Speaker 7:  It's Division Pro. No, I'm kidding.
Speaker 7:  How
Speaker 1:  Do this Good twist.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, by the way. All right. I struggle with this one
Speaker 7:  a little bit because there are like two things. One also came
Speaker 7:  out a long time ago, or at least it was announced a long time ago. It's the
Speaker 7:  Fuji X 106. Yep.
Speaker 1:  I figured that might be your answer.
Speaker 7:  I, I, I know, I'm, I'm so predictable.
Speaker 7:  The thing about it is that, you know, I've had the X 100, I
Speaker 7:  don't know, second or third generation long time ago and
Speaker 7:  decided to get rid of it. And I've been missing it ever since.
Speaker 7:  So when this one came out, I was still a little hesitant, like,
Speaker 7:  oh, do I really to spend money on yet another camera? And I did it,
Speaker 7:  it took eight months for it to get delivered. So I just got it like last
Speaker 7:  month, right? It was like eight months. Oh wow. Yeah. I order, I ordered
Speaker 7:  on like the day that it came out. Think, yeah,
Speaker 1:  We talked about it on this show, how you, you were like in the middle of
Speaker 1:  talking yourself into buying it.
Speaker 7:  Oh my God, that is very true. I forgot I for look at this. What a, what a
Speaker 7:  beautiful first circle. So I've only been using it for a little bit and I've
Speaker 7:  had a couple of trips, couple of work trips, and it's just like, oh yeah,
Speaker 7:  the, this is, this is my favorite thing. Like I just love this
Speaker 7:  camera so much. I've been also reviewing some bigger cameras and
Speaker 7:  they like that difference between like, hey, a tiny little 35 millimeter
Speaker 7:  camera and a big full frame camera. It's like,
Speaker 7:  I still love this little tiny camera so much. So that
Speaker 7:  was pr, that, that's probably my pick. I'm also like incredibly like
Speaker 7:  indecisive person. So.
Speaker 1:  Okay. What was your other one? Just gimme, gimme 10 seconds on the, on your
Speaker 1:  Honorable Mention here.
Speaker 7:  Keynote app.
Speaker 1:  Ooh, the Hali video one, right? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Okay. Like, you know, I did the iPhone review in tandem with
Speaker 7:  Neli this year, and it was kind of the first time
Speaker 7:  a little bit disclaimer. I, my first, my, my, my personal phone was like
Speaker 7:  a 13 Pro. It didn't have any of the fancy recording features.
Speaker 7:  So it was like, oh, now I have pros, now I have Apple Log. Wow. Pro
Speaker 7:  is is like so huge. I can't work with this. So Keynote was
Speaker 7:  the option that had the, you know, HEVC files
Speaker 7:  use that. The LUTs that they have built in are really good.
Speaker 7:  I like Tyler Salman's lut the most. It's just
Speaker 7:  really nice. I've been using it a lot more. So finally I have an action button.
Speaker 7:  It is programmed to open Keynote. I use an
Speaker 7:  iPhone as a camera a lot more this year than ever before.
Speaker 1:  That's a good one. I like that. All right, last thing. Your favorite non-tech
Speaker 1:  thing of the year. This can be any, anything you want. It just can't be tech.
Speaker 7:  This was tough. Liam was helping me out 'cause because I did ask him like
Speaker 7:  ahead of time, we just walked away from a meeting and I was like, do you
Speaker 7:  know what I should do? He's like, I don't know. It can be anything. Like
Speaker 7:  maybe you got good at making coffee. In fact, yes, I did get a coffee machine.
Speaker 7:  Did you? Yeah. So that's one of the things. The other one is,
Speaker 7:  yeah, it's good to step away from our tech bubble. We're all in our tech
Speaker 7:  bubble and the way that I do it recently is this
Speaker 7:  magazine called Mounting Gazette. It is absolutely massive.
Speaker 7:  And I do mean like physically it's just like a, a big magazine. Oh wow.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Sure.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, it's all about outdoorsy stuff. It's all about like ski, well it
Speaker 7:  depends on the season, but skiing, snowboarding, just being
Speaker 7:  outdoors. It is, it used to be a magazine
Speaker 7:  long, long time ago and someone who lives up in
Speaker 7:  Tahoe area, he decided to buy the brand back and now he's
Speaker 7:  making this really beautifully crafted magazine
Speaker 7:  and I feel like, I don't know, I'm, I am a print
Speaker 7:  person. So, I do like print products and it
Speaker 7:  just feels nice to kick back, open it up, look at some
Speaker 7:  beautiful photography and read about
Speaker 7:  stuff that I really like, which is skiing and snowboarding. So,
Speaker 1:  I. Love that. You know what I was thinking about the other day? I
Speaker 1:  haven't bought a coffee table book in a million years make, because it just
Speaker 1:  feels like those don't exist anymore. A we should make one. I agree. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  we should. But b like magazine as coffee table
Speaker 1:  book is kind of an incredible idea. Just like, give me a big, giant thing
Speaker 1:  I can bring into my house.
Speaker 7:  I think that would be it. I don't, I don't know. I don't know. I don't, I,
Speaker 7:  I don't know. I got into That's good.
Speaker 1:  These are good answers. What's the, what coffee machine did you buy? Tell
Speaker 1:  me that and then I'll let you go.
Speaker 7:  It is a, it's one of the Breville ones that has a grinder
Speaker 7:  on top and a milk thing onto the side.
Speaker 1:  Oh, the whole, you got the whole pipeline going now. Yes. Yes. Once you,
Speaker 1:  once a milk frother becomes part of your coffee experience. There's just
Speaker 1:  no going back. Yeah. It life is better and it will never go
Speaker 1:  back.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it is very nice. But I did struggle at first, like, it took a while
Speaker 7:  to like figure out like, all right, what do you want me to do here? I like
Speaker 7:  went through many like bags, like beans and bags of coffee and I'm
Speaker 7:  like, great. I spent like $16 in these beans and I've got like
Speaker 7:  three cups of coffee. This is bullshit. I'm gonna go back to my
Speaker 7:  Nespresso pots. No, but I finally figured it out
Speaker 7:  and I, there's a lot of coffee shops in the neighborhood that I really like,
Speaker 7:  and every time I like to visit in New York, I go to a few of them as well.
Speaker 7:  I'm like, I need those beans. So yeah, I really became a little bit of a
Speaker 7:  snob, but not, not an annoying snob,
Speaker 1:  But welcome because again, there is no going
Speaker 1:  back. It costs a fortune and it takes forever, but
Speaker 1:  it is, it is worth
Speaker 7:  It. I still think it costs less than buying coffee anywhere else.
Speaker 7:  So
Speaker 1:  Veer, thank you as always. Appreciate it.
Speaker 7:  See ya.
Speaker 1:  Next up on my list, Kylie Robinson, our senior AI reporter.
Speaker 1:  Kylie. Hello. Hello. How you feeling? You sound like you
Speaker 1:  got a a, a winter cold thing going on. How you holding
Speaker 7:  Up? I sound like shit. That's okay. You can say it. Yeah. I have a little
Speaker 7:  bit of a cold, but I'm happy to
Speaker 1:  Be here. Good. All right. Well, we won't keep you long. Let's just, let's
Speaker 1:  just blast through this. Cool. So I'm just gonna preface this
Speaker 1:  with, someone else already picked AI as the Story of the year,
Speaker 1:  so you can pick it If you want to, but just know that you'll be copying
Speaker 1:  Jake. All that said, what's your Story of the year?
Speaker 8:  It's gonna be just a common theme of Billionaire. crybabies.
Speaker 8:  Sorry. Sorry guys. But that's true. Like the common theme of the year. All
Speaker 8:  I'm thinking about is Jeff Bezos stomping his feet. Elon stomping his
Speaker 8:  feet, Sam stomping his feet. Sam Altman,
Speaker 8:  lots of billionaires stomping their feet over issues and
Speaker 8:  wanting their way and less regulation. That's the common theme of the year
Speaker 8:  for sure. Whether it's AI or, you know, energy or,
Speaker 8:  you know, what have you. Hardware
Speaker 1:  Or American politics, American politic, like it really is American politics.
Speaker 1:  There are like several childish billionaires
Speaker 1:  who seem to just be everywhere doing everything all the time. They're making
Speaker 1:  popular podcasts now. Yes. It's like, just leave us, let us have this one.
Speaker 1:  Yeah,
Speaker 8:  You put a tariff on straight men with podcasts,
Speaker 8:  put under mics, put a tariff. 200%. That's a good idea.
Speaker 8:  But yeah, I think that's probably something we're gonna continue seeing.
Speaker 8:  I feel like with the incoming Trump administration, that's something
Speaker 8:  that's only gonna strengthen is billionaires
Speaker 8:  saying, you know, let's, let's be chill. Be chill with my products, my company
Speaker 8:  please you like, you like iPhones. Right. Come on man. So that was the
Speaker 8:  theme of this year, and I think we're just gonna continue seeing that.
Speaker 1:  Do you think it's gonna be that, or do you think the billionaires are now
Speaker 1:  gonna be like, we've won, let's go
Speaker 1:  away.
Speaker 8:  Like, like hide. Like be it, not
Speaker 1:  Even hide, but like it some point it's like they did it right, like they
Speaker 1:  got everything they wanted and now go enjoy
Speaker 1:  all of your money in yachts or whatever.
Speaker 8:  Hmm. Interesting. I think they're still gonna have to argue with Trump again.
Speaker 8:  These tariffs are so weird and Elon has his ear. And that's something I'm
Speaker 8:  thinking a a lot about because I was reading the OpenAI
Speaker 8:  Elon lawsuit and to me it reads like, you know, I
Speaker 8:  have the incoming president's ear and look, they're being
Speaker 8:  anti-competitive and you know, So I think these people, if
Speaker 8:  Elon's on Trump's side, these people are still gonna have to like, you know,
Speaker 8:  kiss up, if that makes sense.
Speaker 1:  True. Or in the, on the flip side, they get to start pointing
Speaker 1:  at their enemies from right inside of the White House and Exactly. Picking
Speaker 1:  fights that way. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  Exactly.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Well that's not the most uplifting one I've heard, but yeah, unfortunately,
Speaker 1:  I think you can, you can describe a lot of what's happening in the world
Speaker 1:  to that small group of people.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I'm sort of delirious on Sudafed and that is of course the first thing
Speaker 8:  that came to mind. It's just, it, it's what?
Speaker 1:  It's Love it. All right. What was your favorite new tech thing of the year?
Speaker 8:  It, it was Stardew Valley.
Speaker 1:  Woo. Okay.
Speaker 8:  It's very, like, whenever I say that, they're like, people are like, oh,
Speaker 8:  I played that in Covid. Like, why are you playing it now? The new update
Speaker 8:  just came out for the switch, which means I get different colored cats
Speaker 8:  and all sorts of new ways to explore
Speaker 8:  the town. But yeah, that cozy comfort games.
Speaker 8:  I have a very cozy comfort house. I just love Stardy
Speaker 8:  Valley. It's,
Speaker 1:  Can you just explain Stardy Valley to me? I've never played it. Of course.
Speaker 1:  And I feel like everyone describes it in a way that almost
Speaker 1:  never makes any sense. Wow. Everybody says very nice things like you
Speaker 1:  just said, but the the, you just were like, now I have different colored
Speaker 1:  cats. Yeah. And that's like the explanation for why this game is better.
Speaker 1:  Explain this to me. Teach me about Stary Valley.
Speaker 8:  Do you know what animal crossing is? I do animal crossing with combat.
Speaker 1:  Oh, that is very compelling. Yeah, it's really fun. That's a, that's a good
Speaker 1:  case.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, you get to like, beat up monsters and caves and you know, like
Speaker 8:  you have to grind really hard for resources, almost like a Minecraft
Speaker 8:  situation. You have to grant for these resources and then you get to make
Speaker 8:  like your cool little farm. You get to marry someone in the game.
Speaker 8:  I just did an interview with somebody for The Verge that is yet to come out,
Speaker 8:  but they said that they were really into Star Du and the first thing we ask
Speaker 8:  each other is, who did you marry? Mine is Harvey. He's the doctor at the
Speaker 8:  town's doctor. Nice.
Speaker 1:  Good for you.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, actually V asked me that when I first started at The Verge. She said,
Speaker 8:  who did you marry and star you? I can't remember.
Speaker 1:  This is like a personality test, do you think? Like, can you tell a lot about
Speaker 1:  somebody? Exactly. Based on who they marry and star you. Okay, interesting.
Speaker 8:  But yeah, there was a new update. You can sink ungodly
Speaker 8:  amounts of hours into it 'cause it is so fun and chill and yeah.
Speaker 8:  Cozy comfort games.
Speaker 1:  I really have developed an affinity for games that are
Speaker 1:  like pointless in the best way. Yes. Like for, for forever.
Speaker 1:  All the games I liked were like games where you work up to the big boss and
Speaker 1:  then you beat the big boss and then the game is over. Right. Hell yeah. Like
Speaker 1:  that was what I always played. And I would
Speaker 1:  encounter games like Star do, or even like Animal Crossing or Minecraft in
Speaker 1:  these games. And I would just be like, what's the point of this game? And
Speaker 1:  it took me so long to wrap my head around the idea that the point of the
Speaker 1:  game is just to play the game. Yes. And it's like, it's fun to play the game
Speaker 1:  and that's actually enough. And there's a real, like, it's the friends
Speaker 1:  we made along the way kind of vibe to these games that I have like really
Speaker 1:  come to appreciate in the last couple of years. Totally.
Speaker 8:  Animal Crossing was a bit too pointless for me. Like I was getting too figety
Speaker 8:  with that one. But Star do has like, you know, stuff to work towards
Speaker 8:  like goals and quests, which I really appreciate. I restarted
Speaker 8:  Skyrim this year too, which is like another pointless time sink
Speaker 8:  from 2011. But you, you gotta love it.
Speaker 1:  I, yeah, I agree. I've also recently gone back all in on the switch.
Speaker 8:  Nice.
Speaker 1:  And it's gonna be Stardy time. Good
Speaker 8:  Choice. Hell
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I have this old yellow original switch. Wow. The
Speaker 1:  battery is trash. Wow. But the games are awesome. I don't care. It's amazing.
Speaker 8:  I love it. I, I hear we might be getting another switch next year, but they've
Speaker 8:  said that every year for many years.
Speaker 1:  Honestly, it's getting to the point now where like every one of these Nintendo
Speaker 1:  head fakes is a, a little funnier than the last because it's a very,
Speaker 1:  very funny thing that Nintendo is doing where everybody wants a switch and
Speaker 1:  they're like, just kidding. We did a museum and an alarm clock and a music
Speaker 1:  app. Fucking a like, very funny, but also just release the
Speaker 1:  damn switch. Please gimme the switch. Yeah, I do. I would like to have it
Speaker 1:  in my house. Like, give me one Exactly. And then keep doing these funny jokes
Speaker 1:  and I'm ready.
Speaker 8:  Right, exactly.
Speaker 1:  That's fine.
Speaker 8:  As long as I'm in on it. Yeah, just
Speaker 1:  Give just you and me just the two of us. Right. Perfect. Not Andrew Webster
Speaker 1:  because he, he doesn't want one at all and doesn't spend all his time
Speaker 1:  thinking about this.
Speaker 8:  Perfect.
Speaker 1:  All right, last thing. Your favorite non-tech thing of the year.
Speaker 8:  My favorite non-tech thing has been, oh, it's gonna sound so
Speaker 8:  lame. 'cause I wrote it down and now it sounds more lame on a podcast.
Speaker 8:  Curated playlists in fresh flowers. Okay.
Speaker 8:  That's all you need in life is a nice little playlist. I made one for November
Speaker 8:  because I've been traveling so much. I was in New York seeing you guys.
Speaker 8:  I went on another reporting trip out of the state and I'm going to Texas
Speaker 8:  for Thanksgiving break. And you need a playlist for
Speaker 8:  that. And then getting to share that with everyone you like is a good time.
Speaker 8:  So a little playlist to get you through and validation from your friends
Speaker 8:  about it. What's
Speaker 1:  Your playlisting process? Do you like spend hours? Oh no. Okay.
Speaker 8:  No, no. Purely vibes based. The, the one that I have right now
Speaker 8:  is called Nonstop November, and it's mostly
Speaker 8:  like indeed, you know who Suki Waterhouse is?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Lots of Suki Waterhouse, you know, sad,
Speaker 8:  fun Autumn vibes. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Nonstop November. Just, just what I'm looping, basically. Like I am
Speaker 8:  addicted to these songs and I need them in a playlist. And here is of, you
Speaker 8:  know, a hundred songs. They're just like, that one is sort of my playlist
Speaker 8:  vibe and fresh flowers. They're cheap. They make you happy.
Speaker 8:  I have a vase next to my front door and then
Speaker 8:  one on my desk. So I get to flex it and my
Speaker 8:  What's on your desk series? But yeah, they're, they're simple. They make
Speaker 8:  you happy. That's all you need is music and fresh flowers.
Speaker 1:  Do you have a favorite kind of flower or is it just whatever, whatever they're
Speaker 1:  selling at the bodega.
Speaker 8:  Oh wow. The bodega. The bodega. Okay.
Speaker 1:  You're gonna move to New York. You have to learn the word bodega Kylie. That's
Speaker 8:  True. That's
Speaker 1:  True. We're just starting this now.
Speaker 8:  VERGE casters If. you have a sublet with fresh tulips.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, it's, it's tulips. I think that they're really pretty. Okay. And then
Speaker 8:  they open slowly and yeah.
Speaker 1:  I love this for you.
Speaker 8:  Thank you.
Speaker 1:  It's just a cozy fall full of fresh flowers. This sounds so nice.
Speaker 8:  I know. It is. And it's pouring rain here and I have a slight cold and
Speaker 8:  that's okay. And I'll play my cozy games. I'll write my, you know,
Speaker 8:  weird AI stories about billionaires. It's a good time.
Speaker 1:  You're like one oversized thing of soup away from being
Speaker 1:  like a rom-com character right
Speaker 8:  Now.
Speaker 1:  Oh my God. Wow. And that's, that's what we should all aspire to, I think.
Speaker 1:  Wow. Okay. You're like, you're at the beginning of a Christmas movie is what's
Speaker 1:  happening right now. It's gonna be amazing.
Speaker 8:  I would hope that, you know, in the Christmas movies, you don't have the
Speaker 8:  winter cold. They, they leave that out for some reason. This
Speaker 1:  Is true. Once you come out of that and then, then everything's better,
Speaker 8:  Obviously.
Speaker 1:  Awesome. Kylie, feel better. Thank you. Thank
Speaker 8:  You.
Speaker 1:  All right, moving on. Barbara Krasnoff reviews editor. Here we go.
Speaker 1:  Barbara. Hello.
Speaker 9:  Hey there.
Speaker 1:  Okay, we gave you some homework. Let's do your Story of the year first. Let's
Speaker 1:  start there. What was your Story of the year?
Speaker 9:  Well, actually it's two or more stories of the year. It's the election
Speaker 9:  coverage that we had. Hmm. I was especially
Speaker 9:  impressed by Addie's, the pragmatist guy to the 2024
Speaker 9:  presidential election. I mean, I read that about five times.
Speaker 9:  It gave more information about what the
Speaker 9:  candidates had done in the past and what they were saying now about various
Speaker 9:  important issues. I I just wanted to sort of print it out and mail it to
Speaker 9:  everybody I knew. And that of course, Neely's
Speaker 9:  essay vote for Donald Trump is a vote for school shootings and measles. I
Speaker 9:  mean, you, you gotta mention that. I mean, that, that was just amazing.
Speaker 1:  Probably the best headline we ran this year. I don't know how you topped
Speaker 1:  that as a headline.
Speaker 9:  I, I, I honestly don't. I certainly couldn't and I wouldn't have had, I wouldn't
Speaker 9:  have had the gut suit to put it up E either. So I'm very
Speaker 9:  glad that our editor in chief did. So those were my favorites for the
Speaker 9:  year.
Speaker 1:  The, those are good ones. I, I agree with all of those. What was your tech
Speaker 1:  thing of the year? I found this of all three pieces of homework we all had
Speaker 1:  to do. I found this to be by far the hardest. What was, what was yours?
Speaker 9:  Well, I bought myself a little steam deck. Hmm. It's, it's
Speaker 9:  not brand new. Here. I'll show it to you. I forgot it unplugged right now
Speaker 9:  'cause I was playing with some stuff, but, you know, there it is.
Speaker 1:  I love it. The stream deck has, I think everyone at The Verge I think has
Speaker 1:  had a stream deck at one point or another. I, I think it's very good. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  And I, I love playing with it.
Speaker 1:  What are you doing with it? What's, what's on the, what's on the board right
Speaker 1:  now?
Speaker 9:  Well, nothing because it's unplugged, but
Speaker 1:  Not a great sign for the stream deck. I have to tell you the fact that it's
Speaker 1:  unplugged
Speaker 9:  Not a great sign. Well that's 'cause I was moving it from computer
Speaker 9:  to computer, but I basically use it for
Speaker 9:  very quick answers to things,
Speaker 9:  so that's cool. And just to get places from one to the other. Hmm. My
Speaker 9:  problem is I do not have a smart home. So I can't use it for
Speaker 9:  the really sexy things that Jen uses it for, for example.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. But also I just like playing with it. I, I
Speaker 9:  like playing with different things and I'm gonna play with it some more.
Speaker 1:  What, what fun stuff have you discovered? Even things that haven't stuck?
Speaker 1:  I feel like I, I'm with you just in the sense that having a bunch of
Speaker 1:  buttons in front of me is just endlessly fun. And I will find a bunch
Speaker 1:  of wildly unproductive things to do with them just because it's fun to press
Speaker 1:  buttons. Well,
Speaker 9:  I've been trying to attach it to my Chromecast.
Speaker 1:  Ooh, that's good.
Speaker 9:  I haven't done it yet, but that's my next project because
Speaker 9:  at home, well we have just the one TV and
Speaker 9:  what we tend to do is we run these
Speaker 9:  constantly, this background stuff on birds in various
Speaker 9:  interesting places or cute kittens because it gets the,
Speaker 9:  the blood pressure down. And what I wanna do is to be able to just press
Speaker 9:  a button and have the cute kittens pop up up on the tv. So
Speaker 9:  that's, that's my next project.
Speaker 1:  That is an extremely good idea. I have been
Speaker 1:  spending all year trying to figure out how to more quickly
Speaker 1:  play a specific set of YouTube videos. My problem is I have a toddler who
Speaker 1:  between three and 12,000 times a day
Speaker 1:  just stares at me and demands Moana. And I've like
Speaker 1:  mapped the shortcut button on the Roku remote to get there.
Speaker 1:  I've done a bunch of stuff. I've tried to figure out like, you know, all
Speaker 1:  these macros that will do it. I love the idea of just having a button that
Speaker 1:  is just like, play the happy video and it's, and then he can do it himself.
Speaker 1:  Just play the video.
Speaker 9:  And also because we are, we are unfortunately a Google
Speaker 9:  Voice household and sometimes that just does
Speaker 9:  not work. And I'd much rather just press a button
Speaker 9:  and have Netflix or whatever come up than have to try to
Speaker 9:  say it or have to do it the really old fashioned way and do it on
Speaker 9:  the remote. So that's where I am right now.
Speaker 1:  I like that a lot. Can I give you one other tip as a, as a person I know,
Speaker 1:  oh, please. Who has to also use slack all day? Using the stream deck
Speaker 1:  to change my Slack status has been wonderful and also has
Speaker 1:  made me a better coworker because I now reliably change my Slack status.
Speaker 1:  So just to have a thing that's like, I have one that's like a BRB with the
Speaker 1:  little hanging BRB sign. Yeah. And I just have a button on it that I can
Speaker 1:  press on the stream deck and it puts me up at BRB for 60 minutes. Oh, that's
Speaker 9:  Perfect.
Speaker 1:  Game changer. That
Speaker 9:  Is perfect. Thank you. I will definitely take that into
Speaker 9:  consideration.
Speaker 1:  Happy to help. All right. What's your other thing? Non-tech thing.
Speaker 9:  Totally. Non-tech thing is Googly eyes
Speaker 9:  see this.
Speaker 1:  That's so good.
Speaker 9:  And the reason is basically when we had our meeting,
Speaker 9:  I had been to the office for like a year and so when we had
Speaker 9:  our meeting, I was sitting around at one of the stations and
Speaker 9:  one of our colleagues basically said, I have this bag full of
Speaker 9:  Googly eyes. Does anyone want any? And I said, sure, I'll take a couple.
Speaker 9:  And I stuck it to the back of my phone and it's
Speaker 9:  the most relaxing thing that I, anytime
Speaker 9:  I get like tense or upset or whatever, I just look at these,
Speaker 9:  these really wide sympathetic Googly eyes
Speaker 9:  and I go, oh, things aren't too bad. So that's my totally favorite
Speaker 9:  non tech thing for right now. It does
Speaker 1:  Make your phone feel much nicer. Like, I feel like I like your phone
Speaker 1:  more than I like most phones now. Well,
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Look, I mean, look at this poor, cute little thing. I, I basically,
Speaker 9:  for those who, who aren't looking, I've got a dark blue
Speaker 9:  backing on my Pixel six
Speaker 9:  and they're two little lies against the dark blue backing it just, just
Speaker 9:  looking at you wide, almost like kit and eyes, you know, and
Speaker 9:  saying, hi, I love you, you are nice.
Speaker 1:  It's adorable. And they're like almost perfectly aligned, but just slightly.
Speaker 1:  It's great. Great. I'm, I'm a big fan. There's a real Googly eyes thing
Speaker 1:  happening in our newsroom now that I love very much v
Speaker 1:  song on our team. I know instead of getting the new Mac mini just put Googly
Speaker 1:  eyes on her old Mac mini to make herself feel better about it. And that seems
Speaker 1:  to have worked very well for her.
Speaker 9:  V is the one who gave me these, so there you
Speaker 1:  Go. She's starting a trend here. Googly eyes, all the things. Do you now
Speaker 1:  look around your house being like, what else can I Googly eyes? I feel like
Speaker 1:  a, a bag of Googly eyes makes someone very dangerous.
Speaker 9:  Oh, oh yeah. Well, yeah, absolutely. In fact, you know, I'm, I'm looking
Speaker 9:  on Amazon or someplace I'm gonna get a bag of those so, so that I can not
Speaker 9:  only use them on things here, but So I can carry them with me. So if I meet
Speaker 9:  somebody who's like, not in a good way, I'll just hand them a couple of Googly
Speaker 9:  eyes. That's
Speaker 1:  So good. Just just hand them to Googly eyes and walk away with no explanation.
Speaker 1:  I feel like people would instantly understand what you meant. I love it.
Speaker 9:  I think so. That's
Speaker 1:  Really good. All right, Barbara, thank you very much. Alright,
Speaker 9:  Very good.
Speaker 1:  All right, we gotta take one more break and then we have a couple more people
Speaker 1:  to talk to about all the favorite and biggest stuff from the air. We'll be
Speaker 1:  right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back up next. Alex Heath, deputy editor at The Verge
Speaker 1:  and the author of the very good Command Line newsletter. Alex Heath.
Speaker 1:  Hello.
Speaker 12:  Hi.
Speaker 1:  You have an AI background and you just alerted us to the
Speaker 1:  Riverside Mac app and this is the greatest day of my life. So I. Just all
Speaker 1:  of my answers before have changed. My thing of the year is that Riverside,
Speaker 1:  which we use to record this podcast now has a desktop app and everything
Speaker 1:  will be wonderful.
Speaker 12:  Happy Thanksgiving, David.
Speaker 1:  Seriously, this is what we do here. All right, so we gave you some homework.
Speaker 1:  What was your Story of the year?
Speaker 12:  It's a theme and I'm calling it The AI rat race,
Speaker 12:  which is just this idea that all of the big tech companies
Speaker 12:  and OpenAI anthropic have just been
Speaker 12:  trying to one up each other all year long with all of these
Speaker 12:  announcements to a kind of petty, hilarious degree.
Speaker 12:  And I expect that to only continue next year, but this year
Speaker 12:  really felt like it ratcheted up quite a bit. And apologies
Speaker 12:  if others have said something along these lines, but that's, I I just, I
Speaker 12:  don't think you can like seriously say there was a bigger
Speaker 12:  story in tech this year than that.
Speaker 1:  I agree. And I, I actually think I, I like that way of thinking about it
Speaker 1:  too, that what we've had is this like incredibly high stakes,
Speaker 1:  expensive game of like teeny tiny one-upsmanship all year. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Like everybody's just doing 5% better than everybody else
Speaker 1:  every three weeks all year and spending ungodly amounts of
Speaker 1:  money.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. And it's, and it all blurs together and you reflect back on the year
Speaker 12:  and it's like, I guess Chad CPT is a
Speaker 12:  little better to use, Claude is better. Like all of these
Speaker 12:  things feel better. But I haven't felt
Speaker 12:  the kind of aha, early iPhone moment
Speaker 12:  this year. It's just felt very kind of constantly iterative.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. We, we like skipped straight to the iPhone 14 era of
Speaker 1:  Yeah. ai. So you, you said you think it's gonna
Speaker 1:  continue next year? Yeah. Do you, you think so like there, there's another
Speaker 1:  case to be made that like we're, we're hitting sort of a slowdown with these
Speaker 1:  models. Maybe there's like a bubble that's gonna burst. Maybe everybody's
Speaker 1:  going to finally like take a deep breath and start to ask real
Speaker 1:  questions about ai. You don't think any of that's coming?
Speaker 12:  Oh, David, it's like you were reading my newsletter before it even comes
Speaker 12:  out. It will have come out by this time. There you go. No,
Speaker 12:  that is actually an interesting point. There is this concept in AI called
Speaker 12:  the Scaling Wall that seems to be hitting everyone in the
Speaker 12:  face, which is just this idea that everyone thought that
Speaker 12:  new models would get dramatically smarter the more
Speaker 12:  compute and money you threw into training them. And that's turning
Speaker 12:  out now to not be the case. So I and others have reported that Google and
Speaker 12:  others are seeing diminishing returns from training their
Speaker 12:  next kind of frontier models. And the
Speaker 12:  consensus seems to be that that's okay because
Speaker 12:  there's a lot of work that needs to be done with just building good experiences
Speaker 12:  around the models that exist today. Yeah. And agents
Speaker 12:  are a thing I think we're gonna be hearing a lot more about next year, which
Speaker 12:  are basically LLMs that do things on your behalf that can chain together
Speaker 12:  multiple actions, take over a desktop interface
Speaker 12:  or a phone or something like that. And you can achieve
Speaker 12:  agents with the models that exist today. It's all
Speaker 12:  the magic is done in post training and what happens after you've trained
Speaker 12:  one of these large models. And the scaling wall seems to be
Speaker 12:  applying to, to training new models, but not necessarily
Speaker 12:  improving the ones that exist today.
Speaker 1:  That's fair. Do you think the leaderboard has changed this year? Like as
Speaker 1:  we look at who is winning this race, it, it's been
Speaker 1:  a wild game of kind of leapfrog, but looking back, do you
Speaker 1:  feel like we're in a different spot than we were 12 months ago?
Speaker 12:  I think it's hard to say with a straight face that anyone other than
Speaker 12:  open AI is the winner right now. I would say
Speaker 12:  OpenAI, especially with its oh one reasoning model release is
Speaker 12:  still kind of ahead of where the puck is going. Everyone
Speaker 12:  is gonna be doing, I say reasoning with air quotes, reasoning models
Speaker 12:  next year, I will say it does feel like Meta has significantly
Speaker 12:  moved up the leaderboard this year with, with Llama and
Speaker 12:  the excitement around it and the adoption of it. Gemini seems to be doing
Speaker 12:  okay. I think Google's happy with it, but wishes
Speaker 12:  that more businesses were using it, anthropic is killing it
Speaker 12:  on the business side on, you know, just being accessible through every cloud
Speaker 12:  provider. And OpenAI is the big consumer bet. You know, that that
Speaker 12:  chat GPT is gonna be the next Google or the next Facebook. It kind of has
Speaker 12:  to be to justify open AI's insane valuation.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. So it's a lot of the same players. They all kind of
Speaker 12:  constantly move up and down. That's why I call it a rat race. But going
Speaker 12:  into the new year, going into December, and I caveat all this
Speaker 12:  with saying a year ago my Thanksgiving was ruined because Sam
Speaker 12:  Elman got suddenly fired from Open AI
Speaker 1:  Fair. I guess in that sense, an awful lot has changed in 12 months.
Speaker 12:  And I, and Neli was at, I think Disneyland and we were just constantly
Speaker 12:  calling each other while he was in between rides, trying to confirm reporting
Speaker 12:  that we had all week long on The Verge. So, you know, who knows what could
Speaker 12:  happen. The AI industry moves very fast, but as of right now, feels like
Speaker 12:  OpenAI still has a little bit of an edge, but that edge is rapidly
Speaker 12:  dulling, which is interesting.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, yeah. I agree. All right, next thing on the list, your favorite tech
Speaker 1:  thing of the year.
Speaker 12:  This is not, it's not Riverside for Mac though. I am also very happy about
Speaker 12:  this. It's another app that, you know,
Speaker 12:  I just think a lot of AI apps aren't very good. But there's this one I've
Speaker 12:  found that I use on my Mac all day long called Granola.
Speaker 12:  And it's a Granola meeting note taking app. It
Speaker 12:  gets around wiretapping laws by not actually recording your calls, but what
Speaker 12:  it does is it runs a hyper miniaturized LLM
Speaker 12:  live while you're on a Google meet, a Zoom, whatever, FaceTime
Speaker 12:  call and transcribes it in real time so it doesn't
Speaker 12:  save the audio file or let you listen to it after, but it gives you a transcript.
Speaker 12:  And then it has been kind of post trained to really focus on
Speaker 12:  summarizing, summarizing in an actionable way how
Speaker 12:  you would want to see notes from a meeting. Almost like
Speaker 12:  you've got a personal assistant that's like in the meeting with you. I've
Speaker 12:  been using it for like, our editor calls for interviews
Speaker 12:  and it's got, you know, a pretty nice interface and it's fairly
Speaker 12:  well integrated into, into Mac os. So that's
Speaker 12:  my pick. It's like a simple, actually useful application of AI
Speaker 12:  in a work kind of setting. Does
Speaker 1:  The action items thing actually work? I feel like yeah, the, we've gotten
Speaker 1:  to the point where the transcription stuff on a lot of these services is
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Is very fast and very good. But I'm, I'm so skeptical of the thing
Speaker 1:  where it's like, we're gonna tell you the three most important things that
Speaker 1:  happen in this meeting. Pretty is does Granola actually do pretty well? Good.
Speaker 1:  Yeah,
Speaker 12:  It's pretty good. And it recognizes voices and it knows how to make distinctions
Speaker 12:  and, you know, it gives me like next steps after a meeting based
Speaker 12:  on how we talked about it. You know, like for example, like really long
Speaker 12:  ones where a lot is said, it's actually pretty helpful at breaking all of
Speaker 12:  that down. You know, it's not perfect, but it's definitely the best I've
Speaker 12:  used in this context. And then it's got a bunch of like, integrations with
Speaker 12:  other apps. Like you can drop a summary straight into Slack or
Speaker 12:  your email app or something like that. So they're, they're, they're continuing
Speaker 12:  to build on it. And I'm, I'm pretty bullish on it as a product, honestly,
Speaker 12:  just because it's, it's a very good niche application
Speaker 12:  of, of ai.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. That's, that's, that's pretty cool actually. What about non-tech things?
Speaker 12:  I went to Japan Yeah. This summer
Speaker 12:  slash fall, and I'm just gonna pick alcohol, you know, that kind of
Speaker 12:  sums up my, my year anyway.
Speaker 1:  I thought you were gonna just pick Japan, but I like just picking alcohol
Speaker 1:  just as much. That's pretty good. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. I mean, Japan is awesome, but I, I fell in love with Shochu in Japan,
Speaker 12:  which is like, it's not sake, it's not soju,
Speaker 12:  it's like a higher a BV almost like whiskey
Speaker 12:  clear, very easy to drink, earthy, smoky
Speaker 12:  Japanese spirit. And I want to find more of it in the States.
Speaker 12:  But yeah, anytime I see Shochu now, I, I ordered immediately.
Speaker 1:  How easy is it to find in the States?
Speaker 12:  You know, I thought it would be easier. It's, it's, I'm in LA and it's,
Speaker 12:  so, it's a little bit easier here. We, we just, we have a lot of Japanese
Speaker 12:  people in really good restaurants that are Japanese in la but
Speaker 12:  it's harder to find when I travel, but Yeah.
Speaker 12:  Showed you it's, it's good. All right. And
Speaker 1:  Strong. I'm gonna have to try this. I, yeah, very briefly, a couple of years
Speaker 1:  ago during the pandemic was like, I'm gonna get into Japanese whiskey, and
Speaker 1:  I, it's so good, man. It, it was, it's so good. But it was, it's such
Speaker 1:  a different world Yeah. Of booze that I just, I eventually was
Speaker 1:  like, I'm gonna go back to learning about like Kentucky Bourbon, because
Speaker 1:  that's, that's as much as I can handle right now.
Speaker 12:  Well, I'm from Kentucky. I can, we can have a whole convo about
Speaker 1:  Bourbon at some point. We'll have to do that sometime. I like it. All right,
Speaker 1:  Alex, thank you as always. Appreciate it.
Speaker 12:  Thanks man.
Speaker 1:  All right. Last but certainly not least, Ash, Parrish, The
Speaker 1:  Verge video games reporter. Here we go. Ash. Hello.
Speaker 1:  Hi. It's been a minute. We haven't done this in a while. You need to come
Speaker 1:  on the show more often.
Speaker 13:  I think the last time I was on, I was talking about tears of the Kingdom
Speaker 1:  Maybe. I think that's right. We also talked about GTA six like a hundred
Speaker 1:  years ago. We did.
Speaker 13:  I don't remember that one I
Speaker 1:  Like very much because there was like that weird leak that happened forever
Speaker 1:  ago.
Speaker 13:  Okay. I do remember that. But I don't remember being on The Vergecast about
Speaker 13:  it.
Speaker 1:  You were, it was great. We had a terrific time. I believe I enjoyed every
Speaker 1:  second of it. So we gave you some homework. What was the
Speaker 1:  Story of the year for you?
Speaker 13:  So the Story of the year for me, I'm gonna do something a little bit different
Speaker 13:  and I'm gonna choose a story from my beat, which is video games, which
Speaker 13:  isn't necessarily like the biggest story for The Verge overall because No,
Speaker 13:  I love it. It's like a tech website and there are a lot more important things
Speaker 13:  happening in the tech world than what's going on in the world of video games.
Speaker 13:  But I have like two buckets for biggest Story of the
Speaker 13:  year on my beat. I've got like the actual factual,
Speaker 13:  this is objectively the biggest story and then the biggest story, like to
Speaker 13:  me personally, okay, so the biggest story Objectual, actual factual, is
Speaker 13:  the switch to N GT six. They are these like almost
Speaker 13:  oppressive figures looming in the distance that
Speaker 13:  is like slowly coming towards the video game industry. And
Speaker 13:  when it hits, it's gonna be this like massive
Speaker 13:  event. And both of those things are supposed to happen
Speaker 13:  next year. Like Nintendo is not, you know, they're being
Speaker 13:  coy about exactly when, but they're saying we are definitely,
Speaker 13:  definitely going to announce the switch successor sometime before
Speaker 13:  the end of Q1 2025. And that's, and it's just been like a
Speaker 13:  constant, like, not deluge, but like Nintendo
Speaker 13:  feels like with everything that they're doing now, it's like we're clearing
Speaker 13:  the books. We are getting everything off of our plate
Speaker 13:  just clearing the runway for when this massive story hits. And so that's
Speaker 13:  on the hardware side and on the software side you have GTA six,
Speaker 13:  which is probably going to be the biggest video game
Speaker 13:  release in our lifetimes. I
Speaker 13:  don't know how else to explain it. It's
Speaker 13:  just this GTS six is just this massive, crazy, insanely
Speaker 13:  popular thing that has been hyped
Speaker 13:  up possibly too much. Hopefully Rockstar
Speaker 13:  can deliver on not their promises, but at
Speaker 13:  least the idea or that people have in their head for what
Speaker 13:  this video game is supposed to be. Well,
Speaker 1:  So let me, let me actually pause on that because Yeah, this is a, a thing
Speaker 1:  that I have been wondering about a lot recently, which is
Speaker 1:  a, it's sort of wild that the two biggest things in video games right now
Speaker 1:  are things that don't exist yet. And I think you're absolutely right that
Speaker 1:  they have like, been the stories of the year all year despite not
Speaker 1:  existing. And there's like a lot of existential questions you could ask about
Speaker 1:  games as a result. But I do wonder after all of
Speaker 1:  this, is it even possible for these two things to live
Speaker 1:  up to the hype? Like, yes, you think
Speaker 13:  I do? Okay, good. Nintendo is Nintendo.
Speaker 13:  Yes, they've had some stinkers like with the OU and, and things like that
Speaker 13:  in the past. But I think no matter what
Speaker 13:  it is, no matter what it does, it will be big because it's
Speaker 13:  Nintendo. Like Nintendo had that alarm o thing out. Like it's,
Speaker 13:  which was just like little, you know, chintzy
Speaker 13:  alarm clock that was just like nothing. And it's sold out within seconds.
Speaker 13:  Okay. And that's true. And it's just an alarm clock that plays like Nintendo
Speaker 13:  beeps and boobs. People want it because of who
Speaker 13:  makes it. And that's exactly the case for both of those things.
Speaker 13:  It's a rockstar game. It's a Nintendo system, no matter what the
Speaker 13:  kind of quality it is, it's still gonna sell like gangbusters may not perform
Speaker 13:  the way that the bookkeepers want them to perform if they are lower quality.
Speaker 13:  But it's still gonna be like the massive, massive million
Speaker 13:  dollar, million copy thing selling thing.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I just like, I don't know, I feel like we, we've been
Speaker 1:  burned especially on the, on the game side by
Speaker 1:  these huge things that just turned out to be even
Speaker 1:  slightly worse than we expected. And it, it becomes this whole giant catastrophe.
Speaker 1:  And it's like, if, if GT six does what, like cyberpunk 2077 did,
Speaker 1:  the world will collapse in on itself. Yeah. And I'm,
Speaker 1:  I think maybe I'm just hardening myself against that possibility as somebody
Speaker 1:  who's very excited about this game.
Speaker 13:  I understand that I, you know, we haven't
Speaker 13:  seen very much of GTA six outside of a trailer and leaked
Speaker 13:  materials Rockstar hasn't really told us all that much
Speaker 13:  about what the game is. We haven't really seen official gameplay
Speaker 13:  yet. So we, we actually have no idea what to expect from
Speaker 13:  them. And I think that's probably smart on there end to kind
Speaker 13:  of like manage expectations. Like, you can't get mad at us for something
Speaker 13:  about this because we never actually told you what this thing was. We just
Speaker 13:  said it was GTA six, we gave you the trailer, we put, put it out there.
Speaker 13:  We didn't tell you to expect this, this, this, this or this. We just, you
Speaker 13:  know, did our thing and put it out there. But, you know, I don't know
Speaker 13:  it, you're right in that there have been these big huge releases that have
Speaker 13:  been kind of underwhelming. But I don't know,
Speaker 13:  like I said, doesn't matter what kind of quality it is because it's rockstar,
Speaker 13:  because it says GTA six on the box, it's gonna sell 10 billion copies.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, fair enough. Alright. I I I believe you. Okay, so those are the big
Speaker 1:  stories. What's the, what's the one nearest and dearest to your heart? So
Speaker 13:  The thing that is important to me that I think is, like
Speaker 13:  my personal big story for the year is the story of the video
Speaker 13:  game industry layoffs and the rise of Gamergate 2.0, as it
Speaker 13:  were. We are in the second year
Speaker 13:  of this like trend of studios being shut down
Speaker 13:  of massive, massive, massive amounts of people being laid off.
Speaker 13:  We're really gonna start feeling it. I believe in 2025, there was
Speaker 13:  Embracer group put out, went there with their earning statement
Speaker 13:  maybe a couple weeks ago stating that, you know, we've got this
Speaker 13:  dried up release pipeline without really qualifying that
Speaker 13:  with the fact that we closed like six different studios and laid off
Speaker 13:  over a thousand of our employees. And like If, you don't have people working
Speaker 13:  for you anymore because you close everything down and fire everybody. Yeah,
Speaker 13:  of course. Your, your, your production pipeline is gonna suffer and you're
Speaker 13:  not gonna have games out that are gonna make the money that you need to
Speaker 13:  appease your shareholders. Like, we're starting to see the, the, the
Speaker 13:  knock on effects of this, like this layoff last two years,
Speaker 13:  like really starting to hurt and pinch these big corporations because now
Speaker 13:  they have nothing to show for it. They laid off everybody, they closed these
Speaker 13:  studios and now they have no product anymore because there's nobody around
Speaker 13:  to make it. Right. On the other end of that, you've got this
Speaker 13:  rising culture war thing within video games where
Speaker 13:  people are trying to attribute the problems of
Speaker 13:  the video game industry with the layoffs and the closures and all, and
Speaker 13:  like, you know, games failing with the idea that it's minorities and people
Speaker 13:  of color's fault, which is absolutely patently absurd. Yeah. Because, you
Speaker 1:  Know, we're just doing this again somehow.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. Pretty much. We're, we're doing this again. Ugh. And these people,
Speaker 13:  you know, they have nothing interesting to say. They're not really paying
Speaker 13:  attention to facts. They're just really upset that the culture
Speaker 13:  of storytelling in video games, both like on the screen and in the
Speaker 13:  development room, is shifting away from trying to
Speaker 13:  appeal to, I'm going to use extremely heavy quotes
Speaker 13:  because it's not true. Traditional gamers, which have always been straight
Speaker 13:  cis heterosexual white men, and into this more diverse
Speaker 13:  tapestry where we're making stories that appeal to people of color,
Speaker 13:  L-G-B-T-Q people, disabled folks. And we're
Speaker 13:  starting to see development rooms also reflect that diversity as well.
Speaker 13:  And, you know, people can't handle change like that and they get really
Speaker 13:  mad and they start getting mad at people for the wrong reasons. And
Speaker 13:  it's important to me that these stories get covered so we
Speaker 13:  can understand why they're happening and why it is not true.
Speaker 13:  We can counteract their narratives that like, oh, this game failed because
Speaker 13:  it was woke, you know, which is ridiculous. And then this woke game that
Speaker 13:  was really, really good succeeded because actually it wasn't woke that,
Speaker 13:  which is very funny. Another like the other side of that argument,
Speaker 1:  Right? The democrat secretly Republican. Exactly. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Somehow it just like, do you ever look at this industry and you're like,
Speaker 1:  oh, we're, it just is all the same. Like how many times in history
Speaker 1:  is it like Grand Theft Auto Nintendo is doing a thing and
Speaker 1:  everybody is losing their minds and mad and we're kind of doing
Speaker 1:  Gamergate. Like, it just, this is just the cycle. We're just doing it all
Speaker 1:  over again.
Speaker 13:  I think the, the problem with that is specific
Speaker 13:  to the video game industry is that we do not have the kind of
Speaker 13:  like institutional memory that other industries have
Speaker 13:  because of the way that the industry is currently working in terms of journalism
Speaker 13:  and in terms of like, you know, having a dedicated group
Speaker 13:  of people that are covering these kinds of issues, but we fire them all
Speaker 13:  the next day. Like, it's really, really hard to keep a job in
Speaker 13:  video games journalism right now. And that, and because of that,
Speaker 13:  because it is so hard to, you know, maintain a steady job
Speaker 13:  and because the, these kinds of reportings doesn't necessarily move the
Speaker 13:  needle like top 10 ways you can get the most out of your switch or, you
Speaker 13:  know, that kind of shit. Right. We don't have the institutional memory say
Speaker 13:  the way, I don't know, movies do or any other kind of
Speaker 13:  like, cultural thing because everybody's gone.
Speaker 13:  They have to move on and go somewhere else so they can make money and pay
Speaker 13:  their bills and not, you know, be destitute.
Speaker 1:  Totally. All right, well these are good things and again,
Speaker 1:  we, we need, you need to come on the show more often. This is all, you know,
Speaker 1:  where
Speaker 13:  I, you know, where I metaphorically live my desk
Speaker 1:  Is why I do. Now we were talking about this before. I do now. This is great
Speaker 1:  news. All right, let's, let's keep going through this. So the next thing
Speaker 1:  was your favorite New thing of the year. And for most people, we've been
Speaker 1:  making them say tech, but If, you wanna do like, you know, games or
Speaker 1:  tech enough. So If, you wanna do games, we can do games, tech, whatever you
Speaker 1:  want.
Speaker 13:  The tech thing, it's not necessarily this year, but it came out
Speaker 13:  late enough last year where I think it counts kind of like that window where
Speaker 13:  this movie came out in 2024, but it's not eligible for the Oscars
Speaker 13:  until the next year. It's that it's The, Playstation Portal. Oh
Speaker 1:  My god. Yeah. You're The Playstation Portal fan. The one that's out there.
Speaker 13:  I am the one PlayStation portal fan. Now this is so exciting because of
Speaker 13:  the recent news that PlayStation portal will now let you stream games
Speaker 13:  from the cloud. Mm. Before that, like, I already
Speaker 13:  appreciated the device because it allowed me to play my
Speaker 13:  PlayStation games on the couch and still be in the same room with my husband
Speaker 13:  and we can like watch TV or do whatever. And I appreciate that. Like, I,
Speaker 13:  like, I don't like being sequestered or taking away like the living room
Speaker 13:  television from him. So like, you know, because I have to do this thing
Speaker 13:  because I am literally working, you know, he can't watch, you know, whatever
Speaker 13:  silly thing that he wants to watch. Right. And so that kind of, that makes
Speaker 13:  it easier for me. But the big thing is that that kind of like breaks
Speaker 13:  open this device and now makes it kind of like a must own for like anybody
Speaker 13:  who has a PlayStation five is the idea that now you can stream games
Speaker 13:  without the need of being tethered to a PlayStation five
Speaker 13:  because it's gonna let you stream cloud games, If, you've got a PlayStation
Speaker 13:  premium plus membership. I don't remember exactly how that works,
Speaker 13:  but yeah. That, that makes it like, okay, now this is on the
Speaker 13:  level of the steam deck. Maybe not the same technical heavy lifting specs
Speaker 13:  as a steam deck may have, but definitely the utility that I think is gonna
Speaker 13:  make it like, okay, this is, this is something that I need to, that I need
Speaker 13:  to own now.
Speaker 1:  That's really good. That's fair. And I, I have to say I'm also personally
Speaker 1:  very excited about this because the portal is such a like, lovely little
Speaker 1:  thing. Like they made a nice object and they just
Speaker 1:  hamstrung it in such a stupid way. Yeah. So it's like, it's nice to see it
Speaker 1:  actually start to do the thing. It should have been doing all along. Correct.
Speaker 13:  Correct. Now if we can make it such that, you know, it doesn't drop the
Speaker 13:  connection because I can't wire my PlayStation where it is. Mm.
Speaker 13:  Like where I have it, like, so we can like beef up the way that it,
Speaker 13:  you know, streams from the PlayStation and So I don't have to like
Speaker 13:  reconnect every, you know, couple minutes, then we'll we'll be like cooking
Speaker 13:  with gas, but until then, you know what, I can live with this.
Speaker 1:  All right. I'll buy it. I love it. All right. And then last thing, your,
Speaker 1:  your non-tech thing of the year.
Speaker 13:  I think you might already know what the answer to that question is. It's
Speaker 13:  my new Corgi puppy boo. His,
Speaker 13:  his real name is Syphilis because I named him after my favorite
Speaker 13:  historical horse, Alexander the greats horse syphilis. But we call him
Speaker 13:  Boo for short.
Speaker 1:  Do you call him Phyliss when you're mad at him? Like, is that when you're
Speaker 1:  like, you know, sternly talking to him? You
Speaker 13:  Know, I haven't yet, but I think that might be a thing that happens.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Because I feel like that's a, like if I heard someone yelling that
Speaker 1:  at the dog park, like who, that's serious stuff. Then
Speaker 13:  When you hear someone yelling at, at the dog park, you're like, that is
Speaker 13:  the biggest nerd that I've ever
Speaker 1:  Seen. Also, my mice also that also that,
Speaker 13:  But yeah, he's a, he's a three month old Corgi who
Speaker 13:  loves chewing on feet and he's trying to chew on mine now because he's
Speaker 13:  teething and he is absolutely shit monster. But I love him to death. So
Speaker 13:  that is my favorite non-tech thing of the year.
Speaker 1:  I love it. So three months. He's just a terror. He's just,
Speaker 1:  he is just a destroyer. He's,
Speaker 13:  He is a, he's a toe chewing terror. Okay. That's for sure.
Speaker 1:  But then he like sleeps on top of your head and you're like, all right, we're
Speaker 1:  cool. Everything's fine.
Speaker 13:  Pretty much. Yeah. I love this. Then yeah, then he makes his little noise
Speaker 13:  when he's like yawning or something like that, and it's so, so
Speaker 13:  dang cute.
Speaker 1:  He is very cute. There are a bunch of dog dedicated Slack
Speaker 1:  channels at The, Verge and Vox Media in general. And like,
Speaker 1:  it's not so much that you've like won those channels with Boo,
Speaker 1:  but like, you, you, you did it. It's like pretty hard to compete with with
Speaker 1:  Boo's situation right now.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. That, you know, that's the goal.
Speaker 1:  He's doing good work. All right, Ash, thank you as always. It was great to
Speaker 1:  have you come back soon. We have, I think a lot of stuff to talk about in
Speaker 1:  2025. So
Speaker 13:  We will definitely have a lot of stuff to talk about in 2025 for
Speaker 13:  sure.
Speaker 1:  Okay. All right, we'll see you then. Thanks. Alright, that is it
Speaker 1:  for The Vergecast today. Thank you to all of The Verge staff who came on
Speaker 1:  the show for coming on the show, for doing your homework, for talking us
Speaker 1:  through all your favorite stuff. There is lots more on all this stuff,
Speaker 1:  all the stories of the year, all of our favorite things, lots of it at The
Speaker 1:  Verge dot com. I'll put as much as I can in the show notes, but I trust that
Speaker 1:  you'll tell me all of the things that I forgot to put in the show notes.
Speaker 1:  As always, If, you have thoughts, questions, feelings, and again,
Speaker 1:  particularly If, you have questions that you want us to talk about on
Speaker 1:  The Vergecast, about The Vergecast, and about The Verge and about the future
Speaker 1:  of media. You can always email us at vergecast at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 1:  Call the hotline eight six six VERGE one one. I wanna hear all your
Speaker 1:  thoughts, all your questions, all your ideas, everything. Lots of fun stuff
Speaker 1:  to come in the next couple of weeks, including big thoughts about the future
Speaker 1:  of media. It's gonna be great. This show is produced by Liam James, Wil Poor
Speaker 1:  and Eric Gomez. The Vergecast is The Verge production, and part of the Vox
Speaker 1:  Media Podcast network. We'll be back on Tuesday to talk
Speaker 1:  about some fun Van Lifey things and some microphones. Then we'll be
Speaker 1:  back on Friday to talk about the news. It all just keeps happening. Friends,
Speaker 1:  we are winding towards the holidays, so we're gonna get into some year end
Speaker 1:  stuff here pretty soon. But Lord knows the AI news
Speaker 1:  isn't gonna stop just because it's Thanksgiving. If you're in the us, I hope
Speaker 1:  you had a wonderful Thanksgiving. I hope you have an awesome weekend. We
Speaker 1:  will see you on Tuesday. Rock and roll