# Transcript
ID: f90c4cb2-6f0e-478e-a557-9d0308e39935
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7867437718327820157/1869656059317631369/s93290-US-5690s-1716767986.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss announcements from Microsoft Build, the OpenAI's trouble with Scarlett Johansson, new Sonos headphones, and more.
Speaker 2:  no matter what. It's
Speaker 2:  and then we're gonna get your products
Speaker 2:  and the truth is gonna come out. Right? Like that's the cycle that we're
Speaker 2:  in is it's great. It's a we are super great video. I'm glad you
Speaker 2:  paid all the influencers.
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna put your face computer on my face man. And then we're gonna know.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I'm gonna hold your, I'm gonna hold your teenage engineering box
Speaker 2:  and then we're gonna know
Speaker 5:  I like it. 'cause it's one timeline darker than the, is this
Speaker 5:  anything timeline? Yeah. And I feel like we were in the, is this anything
Speaker 5:  timeline for a while and now it's, it's getting slightly Bleecker.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's probably broken and I don't believe you. Yeah. We're gonna put
Speaker 2:  AI in Google search and Google search is gonna tell you to put glue in your
Speaker 2:  pizza, which is a real headline. Yeah. By the time you are listening to this,
Speaker 2:  I think Kylie will have that headline up, which is AI previews and Google
Speaker 2:  search are overwhelmingly stupid.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Mostly 'cause they're reading Reddit and Reddit is full of jokes
Speaker 2:  and people are, are now like willfully
Speaker 2:  trying to like Google bombing is back. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Because you ask Google like what mammal has the most
Speaker 2:  bones, which is the real thing people are doing. And it goes and finds a
Speaker 2:  Reddit joke from five years ago that's like, it's snakes.
Speaker 5:  And it makes you realize like the the running joke on the internet is that
Speaker 5:  sarcasm and jokes are very hard to understand. It turns out that like people
Speaker 5:  still better at it than Google, which is real, real bad at it.
Speaker 2:  It's probably broken and I don't believe you again, the theme of the week,
Speaker 2:  there's some exciting news this week, like legitimately cool news this week.
Speaker 2:  David, you talk to Tom about everything that happened at Microsoft Build
Speaker 2:  and the Surface event. Legitimately cool news if that stuff works, the
Speaker 2:  Mac versus PC race is fully back on. Yep. The processor
Speaker 2:  wars are back on with a new metric. Right? Like they have, Microsoft
Speaker 2:  has NPUs now with the Qualcomm chips doing ai. Apple has neural engines.
Speaker 2:  That's all really exciting.
Speaker 2:  Boy, do I want that stuff to work, right? Like it's
Speaker 2:  just a we do you not feel like Open Eye week, we're gonna talk about Open
Speaker 2:  Eye and Carl Johansen and it's like, yeah, I don't believe you.
Speaker 2:  Like what a weird place to be.
Speaker 5:  It is. And it also, you end up in this place of like questioning
Speaker 5:  everybody's intentions all the time too. Like with, with Microsoft it's like,
Speaker 5:  oh, windows on arm. You did it. That's so exciting. Do you remember all the
Speaker 5:  other times that you told me that you did it? That that's really interesting.
Speaker 5:  And then with all this OpenAI is stuff, the, the timelines are weird.
Speaker 5:  Everybody is saying things that don't all make sense simultaneously
Speaker 5:  and it's just, you get to the point where it's like, does anyone know what
Speaker 5:  they're talking about?
Speaker 5:  And it's, it's just very strange. But I, I agree with you on the Microsoft
Speaker 5:  stuff in particular I thought was both
Speaker 5:  substantially nerdier and substantially more exciting than I expected it
Speaker 5:  to be. Like it was a wonky build in like the best way.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Let's start there. We we are gonna talk about OpenAI and scrolls your sen
Speaker 2:  later. We're gonna have a lightning round unsponsored
Speaker 2:  for now. We gotta start a shoe company that's called Unsponsored and then
Speaker 2:  have the Lightning Round sponsored by Unsponsored.
Speaker 5:  That's pretty good. If, you're
Speaker 2:  A shoe investor. Call me. Is it
Speaker 5:  All the logos or is it No logos. No logo on the shoe. I think it might be
Speaker 5:  all the logos. Oh,
Speaker 2:  Oh right. You like bring it all the way back around. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's every shoe logo on it. And it's called Unsponsored Please. Like
Speaker 5:  somebody at mischief is building that right now. They just heard me. You
Speaker 5:  can have that mischief. Enjoy
Speaker 2:  If. you sponsor logo If,
Speaker 5:  You sponsor the around.
Speaker 2:  Look, I'm not saying we're a bunch of IP experts on this show. I'm just saying
Speaker 2:  If, you give us cash, we'll give you that idea. Okay. We,
Speaker 2:  let's start with Build. 'cause it, it was an nerdy build and I think you
Speaker 2:  guys only really scratched the surface with Tom who was there. Great job
Speaker 2:  covering it. The big news is obviously the, the co-pilot PCs, right. Co-pilot
Speaker 2:  plus PCs, which have the NPU, which are running on
Speaker 2:  the new Snapdragon X processors. It should be noted that
Speaker 2:  the team that built those processors at Qualcomm is
Speaker 2:  from a company called Nuvia, which Qualcomm acquired. Nuvia
Speaker 2:  is a bunch of ex Apple chip designers. You can see how they caught up.
Speaker 2:  Yep. It's a pretty straight line. Right? You you, you're losing the apple.
Speaker 2:  The Apple chip designers leave, you buy them. So you're competitive with
Speaker 2:  Apple. Again, we gotta run the benchmarks, we gotta get the
Speaker 2:  things. But Kranz, I mean you're, you're a chip nerd. Do you, do you buy
Speaker 2:  it right now?
Speaker 6:  I mean I I think it's the nuvia part of it that makes me kind of cautiously
Speaker 6:  optimistic. And also the fact that laptop makers actually want us
Speaker 6:  to try the laptops, generally
Speaker 2:  Speaking. Oh yeah. That's a big one.
Speaker 6:  They do not when it sucks. They're like, you, you, are you sure you want
Speaker 6:  this? and they slow roll you, right? Yeah. Like they, they wait a while to
Speaker 6:  get it to you and then you end up having to buy it and review it yourself.
Speaker 6:  And this time they're like, when do you want it? We'll get it to you next
Speaker 6:  week. They're, they're really eager about it. And, and in a way that like
Speaker 6:  surprised me. I took a few briefings on the laptops and I was like, oh, you
Speaker 6:  guys are like pumped. I'm not used to that. And it reminds me a lot of when
Speaker 6:  a MD was like coming back when it was making its big comeback what, in like
Speaker 6:  2017 where suddenly people were like, do you care about a MD? Like get
Speaker 6:  excited. And I was like, oh, oh you, this is weird. But
Speaker 6:  yeah, the the, the NPUs is the big, is the big deal here. I think
Speaker 6:  like Microsoft said, If, you wanna take
Speaker 6:  advantage of the, the most stuff that's gonna be in Windows now you
Speaker 6:  probably want an NPU in that computer. And NPUs have been around for a while.
Speaker 6:  Like Intel's had them. They're, they're called neural processing units. Everybody's
Speaker 6:  been doing it. You know, apple calls it a neural engine, whatever. But
Speaker 6:  they've all been doing it and it's basically just another processor to offload
Speaker 6:  those like tasks that generally you would've put on your GPU
Speaker 6:  or like made your CPU kind of brute force. And now it's like, okay,
Speaker 6:  just for this. And it's like
Speaker 6:  when Intel introduced it a couple of years ago, it was one of those things
Speaker 6:  where you're like, okay, do I care about this? Like I'm not an AI researcher,
Speaker 6:  why should I care about this? And that's still kind of the
Speaker 6:  question unless now I think the big change is that like
Speaker 6:  Adobe's gonna be using it and a lot of these like film processing companies
Speaker 6:  and stuff are doing it. So it's like, okay, I guess it makes a little more
Speaker 6:  sense now than it did, you know, six years ago. What do you guys feel about
Speaker 6:  that?
Speaker 2:  Well, I'm curious. I mean a lot of what they announced in
Speaker 2:  Windows is Yeah, fairly interesting. Some of it
Speaker 2:  I think people have had a really strong reaction to like recall, but some
Speaker 2:  of it is just straightforwardly cool. Right? Like you can draw stick figures
Speaker 2:  in Microsoft Paint and it will generate more
Speaker 2:  photorealistic images as you draw. That's cool. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That's neat. And that's one of the first examples of like
Speaker 2:  a cool local AI workload beyond the light rooms
Speaker 2:  and premieres of the world that I can think of
Speaker 2:  because most of the other AI workloads like happen in the cloud. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 2:  You like, you talk to a chat bot and they happen in the cloud or you're coding
Speaker 2:  and GitHub and co-pilot and GitHub is happening in the cloud and now you've
Speaker 2:  got some cool stuff that's happening locally. We should talk about recall,
Speaker 2:  which is the other big thing that's happening on the NPU. But they're not
Speaker 2:  more of those that, I mean like on like they're not more of those.
Speaker 2:  There's the other stuff that's like you're playing Minecraft and the computers
Speaker 2:  watching with you and talking you through how to play Minecraft,
Speaker 2:  but I suspect there's a little bit of hybrid local
Speaker 2:  cloud happening there. I know it's happening with paint because
Speaker 2:  there are things paint won't let you generate because Microsoft's
Speaker 2:  commitment to AI safety. Yeah. Which is weird. 'cause If, you turn off the
Speaker 2:  ai you can draw any kind of dongs you want and paint.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. So there there is like a little bit of push and pull
Speaker 2:  between the cloud and local, right? Yeah. In in just in terms of safety,
Speaker 2:  which is really interesting to think about. Like Google Docs is a cloud application.
Speaker 2:  You can type anything you want in Google Docs. Microsoft Word 365 can
Speaker 2:  be expressed as a cloud application. You can type anything you want in
Speaker 2:  Microsoft Word 365, you turn on AI features in Microsoft
Speaker 2:  Paint. It's like you can't draw some stuff weird. That's just weird.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. You know, and like I suspect we're gonna have a a long conversation
Speaker 2:  about those kinds of lines for years to come. But that part, just
Speaker 2:  the other part of it where it's like, where's the AI happening? Is it in
Speaker 2:  the cloud or is it here on the machine? It's kind of interesting that Microsoft's
Speaker 2:  answer is very much like both. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Well, and I think that's the right answer, right? A again, the the where
Speaker 5:  one ends and the other begins is I think forever going to be
Speaker 5:  complicated, but everyone I talk to says that the place we have to
Speaker 5:  get to is both because the stuff that you do on device is
Speaker 5:  private and fast in a way that anything that happens off
Speaker 5:  device just can't be. And I think about like the, the translation stuff
Speaker 5:  Microsoft is trying to do. Like there's a chunk of that that If, you don't
Speaker 5:  do it locally, it's going to suck because real time
Speaker 5:  translation that has to go to the cloud is by definition not real time
Speaker 5:  translation. It just breaks. And so the thing that they launched where like
Speaker 5:  it you can be in edge and it can translate a
Speaker 5:  YouTube video while you're watching the YouTube video. Very
Speaker 5:  cool. In theory. Awful with a half second delay.
Speaker 5:  Like it's the sort of thing that I think is is that tuning that they're gonna
Speaker 5:  have to do to get those two pieces right, is actually like the whole ball
Speaker 5:  game. Yeah. But I think it's very cool that Microsoft is is deep in this
Speaker 5:  idea of we're going to start on your device. And I think that's
Speaker 5:  smart and right.
Speaker 2:  And I think the other interesting part there is obviously we're, you know,
Speaker 2:  we're barreling towards wwc where we expect Apple to announce many, many
Speaker 2:  similar kinds of things, or at least a similar kind of focus
Speaker 2:  on ai. Microsoft has the big AI
Speaker 2:  part, they've got Azure and the big OpenAI didn
Speaker 2:  relationship and they are integrating all this stuff and they have their
Speaker 2:  own models that they're running at all sorts of scales. And so they're, I
Speaker 2:  think they're able to just like take more shots across Windows and
Speaker 2:  devices and, and their suite of applications that runs everywhere. And that
Speaker 2:  to me, that to me is like the interesting part. Like there isn't another
Speaker 2:  company that kind of has all the pieces,
Speaker 2:  whether Microsoft can execute, whether it can deliver finished
Speaker 2:  applications that people like to use, whether it can make people interested
Speaker 2:  in Windows, like consumers interested in Windows outside of a gaming context.
Speaker 2:  Again,
Speaker 2:  I think it's broken and I don't believe you like, that's that's where I'm
Speaker 2:  at. You know, it's like you gotta, we have to get the machines. It's interesting
Speaker 2:  Alex that you're saying that the companies are excited, but there's a lot
Speaker 2:  of investment in like Intel chips in the world, the next 86 applications.
Speaker 2:  And that transition's gonna be slow, not fast. I I think they did say they
Speaker 2:  did say stuff about emulation, right?
Speaker 6:  Intel chips have had NPU in them for a very long time. They, they introduced
Speaker 6:  a couple of years ago. So the big difference is now co-pilot
Speaker 6:  has like kind of a minimum amount of what your NPU should be able to process.
Speaker 6:  So the deal is that before, you know, an NPU would do
Speaker 6:  it, like what, 18 tops or something, which is
Speaker 6:  like trillion operations per second. So, so it would do like 18 and now they're
Speaker 6:  saying, okay, it has to be 40, it has to be 45. And and that was one of the
Speaker 6:  things like Apple was bringing up tops in their M four presentation
Speaker 6:  back with the iPad where they were like, we can do 30, 38
Speaker 6:  tops. And you're like, cool, what does that mean? This is great. And, and
Speaker 6:  then Microsoft was just like, you gotta do 40. And we're like,
Speaker 2:  I. love it. Cool.
Speaker 5:  Tom used to do megapixels in my favorite possible way. Yes. This rule.
Speaker 2:  Yes. We're back to like the megahertz war or whatever.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's gonna be super goofy, but they're like
Speaker 2:  Polar are here on
Speaker 6:  The top. They're really leaning on that. 'cause I guess you'd need, they,
Speaker 6:  like they're saying, you know, a lot of the stuff that's that's coming to
Speaker 6:  Windows will work Okay. On older Windows
Speaker 6:  PCs, but like you're really gonna need those, the the neuro processors. Well,
Speaker 6:  but also and really good
Speaker 5:  Ones. Importantly also your computer will be good, right.
Speaker 5:  Which is not a small thing. Right. The idea of all
Speaker 5:  of these things, like Alex, you said this before, like if you're an AI researcher,
Speaker 5:  it's a, it's a nice to have, but it is going to in other ways
Speaker 5:  make your computer worse. And the promise that Microsoft came out with,
Speaker 5:  with the copilot plus PCs is these computers are going to be fast. They're
Speaker 5:  going to do AI stuff, they're going to have long battery life and they're
Speaker 5:  going to be good computers. And that is not a small thing in
Speaker 5:  the Windows world right now, in which you've kind of had to choose one or
Speaker 5:  two of those three things for a really long time. And especially
Speaker 5:  with this Qualcomm stuff, if they can get the battery life there to the
Speaker 5:  point where AI is not like, you don't have to buy an AI computer the
Speaker 5:  way you buy a gaming computer and you like make a bunch of sacrifices in
Speaker 5:  exchange for this one thing. You want to work really well if they can actually
Speaker 5:  have solved these three things together. That to me is where the
Speaker 5:  stuff gets really powerful. And then when, and then you get the whole scale
Speaker 5:  of Microsoft and the fact that it has the app store and the browser
Speaker 5:  and the os and the models and the cloud service. Like that's
Speaker 5:  when that becomes really powerful. If and only if the devices don't suck
Speaker 5:  and maybe possibly the devices don't suck.
Speaker 6:  Well if they don't suck and they're, they're affordable enough, right? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like most people are spending $700 on a laptop and most of these laptops
Speaker 6:  are in the $1,200 range, which is intentional. They're, they're meant to
Speaker 6:  go after the MacBook Air because MacBook airs sell a lot better
Speaker 6:  than everybody else's laptops.
Speaker 2:  Right? Right. And what's interesting is, you know, Sasha and CEO of Microsoft
Speaker 2:  talked to Joanna Stern at the Wall Street Journal, notable for expat, Joanna
Speaker 2:  Stern I might add,
Speaker 2:  and basically was like, yeah, we're gonna beat the MacBook Air, Yusef Medi,
Speaker 2:  who's executive vice president of Microsoft basically is
Speaker 2:  like a MacBook error with an M three. These computers will beat those by
Speaker 2:  50% on cbe. So they're making huge performance claims
Speaker 2:  on these PCs. Right. They're also thin and light. There's some question I
Speaker 2:  think John Gruber raised about whether they have fans as though people care,
Speaker 2:  but
Speaker 6:  They do have, some of them have fans,
Speaker 2:  Some of them are gonna have fans. Yeah, fine. But MacBooks have thermal
Speaker 2:  throttling issues, particularly the error. Right. They slow, they do slow
Speaker 2:  down. So If, you wanna run these computers really hard with AI
Speaker 2:  workloads, which are essentially on a GPU like piece of the processor.
Speaker 2:  They make it hot, but we're expecting good battery life.
Speaker 2:  I, and then the list of
Speaker 2:  the list of manufacturers here is Dell, Lenovo, Samsung, hp, ASER as
Speaker 2:  it's everybody. Microsoft obviously has a surface pro and the surface that
Speaker 2:  that's the suite, right? Yeah. There isn't
Speaker 2:  how Alex you taken the briefings. How are they differentiating these is just
Speaker 2:  like, are you a doll fan boy or a Seuss fan boy and they still the same
Speaker 2:  concern.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Kind of like everybody's, everybody's bringing up their own thing.
Speaker 6:  I took an HP briefing and they rebranded their whole thing. Right?
Speaker 6:  'cause you had like the HP Specter and the HP Pavilion and the
Speaker 6:  HP something you've never heard of. Like, like it was just a mess. and they
Speaker 6:  redid their whole portfolio into the elite book and the, the
Speaker 6:  pro book for, for corporates or corporate stuff.
Speaker 6:  And then the omni book, which is for the rest of us. And the omni book is
Speaker 6:  like, I, I got to play around with one. It was really nice. Didn't get to
Speaker 6:  benchmark or anything like that. So again, we're gonna have to wait and see,
Speaker 6:  but it was like, it was a nice laptop. It felt like
Speaker 6:  exciting and good in a way. It felt kind of like my iPad Pro with the,
Speaker 6:  the thing on it, the the the magic keyboard only
Speaker 6:  lighter and better.
Speaker 2:  Oh, the the surface keyboard looks awesome. Right? 'cause it's totally wireless.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like that's always kind of the way, right? Like Microsoft has done this before
Speaker 6:  where they go and they say, all your OEMs, you're gonna have to like swarm
Speaker 6:  around this. It's gonna be the netbook or, or touch computers or whatever.
Speaker 6:  But you're gonna have to start making these touch computers. They're just
Speaker 6:  like, yeah, you gotta, you gotta touch the screen. Right? And, and, and this
Speaker 6:  case, this is the swarm around the dumbest name alive.
Speaker 6:  But, but they recognize apple's coming for us. You know,
Speaker 6:  everybody to your, your point Neela, you say this all the time, the computer
Speaker 6:  is no longer about the rest of the computer. It's about the, the browser.
Speaker 6:  And, and Microsoft has to compete with that. Like that is a very, that
Speaker 6:  is an existential crisis for Microsoft, right? If everybody just says, okay,
Speaker 6:  I just need a Chromebook or whatever my phone, that's bad for them. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So that, that, that's why they've put all this AI in. That's why they're
Speaker 6:  really like glomming onto this trend at the moment.
Speaker 6:  And I don't know the, these things will be really interesting. I'm really
Speaker 6:  curious to see how fast they are because Qualcomm's made these
Speaker 6:  promises before, but this time they've got like this whole new team behind
Speaker 6:  it, which like, HP was like, well, you know, 'cause I was like, what's different
Speaker 6:  this time you guys have released some real dog shit?
Speaker 2:  Like it's probably broken and I don't believe you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And HP was like, well it's a new team over there. Yeah. So like, we're
Speaker 6:  feeling confident. And I was like, okay, well that's, that's different. I
Speaker 6:  mean, but we'll see. Right. You just kind of have to, to hold your breath
Speaker 6:  and
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Look, this is the thing about tech coverage and I, I feel like we have
Speaker 2:  said this many, many times, but this is like a new era and we
Speaker 2:  just need to repeat ourselves. Eventually the products ship
Speaker 2:  and then there's no hiding and there's only two kinds of
Speaker 2:  coverage in the world where the truth just outs it's sports
Speaker 2:  where one team wins and another team loses. And
Speaker 2:  it's tech where you can hold the thing in your hand and it's,
Speaker 2:  it works or it doesn't. Yep. And like a lot
Speaker 2:  of things have not worked recently.
Speaker 2:  We are on an all time run of things not working. Yes. And a lot of the reason
Speaker 2:  that things don't work is the underlying AI models are not
Speaker 2:  reliable, which is something Alex you have been pointing out now for a couple
Speaker 2:  weeks. It, you we're making these huge bets and like,
Speaker 2:  it's like betting on a toddler. Like, like, are you gonna,
Speaker 2:  are you gonna stand up for a long time? Are you just gonna tip over like
Speaker 2:  let's build a business around you?
Speaker 6:  What was interesting was like some of the AI stuff that Microsoft was doing
Speaker 6:  is stuff that we've already seen before, right? Like, like HP and a lot of
Speaker 6:  these PE companies said, okay, you're gonna buy one of these IPCs,
Speaker 6:  what the hell does that actually mean practically? And in
Speaker 6:  HP's case, they were like, we've slapped it, we've like thrown in the chat
Speaker 6:  GPT prompt window so you can talk to chat GPT-3 0.5
Speaker 6:  on an HP computer. And I was like, cool, I don't, I don't care
Speaker 5:  About that. That's not the answer. That's the answer. It is definitively
Speaker 5:  the, not
Speaker 6:  The answer. But then the other thing they were doing was they were like,
Speaker 6:  okay, well you can also, like we, we can learn more about the computer to
Speaker 6:  better optimize it. And that's something that we've seen from NVIDIA's been
Speaker 6:  doing that for years now with DLSS. And so it's like, okay, well that's actually
Speaker 6:  useful and like a use of AI that I've seen
Speaker 6:  in practice and seen at work. Yeah. So I could almost get excited about that.
Speaker 5:  I also think that's where recall comes in Yeah. And is actually really important
Speaker 5:  to this whole thing because what I think Microsoft did well,
Speaker 5:  both at the surface event on Monday and at Build on Tuesday, is
Speaker 5:  give people examples of what AI can do on their computer.
Speaker 5:  Yes. And, and the answer is not a chat bot that you
Speaker 5:  could find at a website like that isn't, that's nothing. You have accomplished
Speaker 5:  nothing if that's what you've done. But what Microsoft said is they, and
Speaker 5:  it was a lot of little things in spots, right? Where they're like AI copy
Speaker 5:  and paste, copy in one language, paste in another. Like it's you, you kind
Speaker 5:  of have to do a million of those in order to make this case. But I think
Speaker 5:  recall was the big swing where it was like, okay, here is one genuinely
Speaker 5:  new thing you can do on an AI PC that you couldn't before. That is better
Speaker 5:  because of ai. Yes. And like in the whole AI world,
Speaker 5:  we are severely lacking in that type of thing. Yes.
Speaker 5:  And I feel like the, whether recall is any good, whether people want it,
Speaker 5:  what we do with the privacy implications, all that aside, just the fact that
Speaker 5:  Microsoft is like, we, we found a new thing we can do now because of this
Speaker 5:  felt really good to me that I was like, okay, you understand what this is
Speaker 5:  actually for? Which is things like it's it's for doing things.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's not for talking to a chatbot I can talk to in a web browser.
Speaker 5:  It's not for a bunch of random nonsense that doesn't help
Speaker 5:  anybody. Like it's it's for things.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think Ryan Broderick, who writes the Garbage Day newsletter has been
Speaker 2:  consistently pointing out that the AI industry has to talk
Speaker 2:  about a GI in destroying the world to make their
Speaker 2:  extremely boring demos have stakes.
Speaker 2:  That's
Speaker 5:  Very true. Yeah. Like
Speaker 2:  You, you have to be like, it can see an orange, this will lead to the end
Speaker 2:  of the world. Like you just fine. You know?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But you're right that Microsoft laid out a particular vision
Speaker 2:  of computing, which is you're using a computer all day.
Speaker 2:  What If you could then interact with a computer in a way that
Speaker 2:  remembered all of the things you were doing and that became your
Speaker 2:  companion. And we should get into the reaction and the reality of that
Speaker 2:  and how it might work and the privacy implications. I think all those things
Speaker 2:  are really important. I just wanna st spend one second on Nadela saying this
Speaker 2:  is one of the two dreams people have had for a long time in the keynote.
Speaker 2:  Mm. Because he is not wrong. Right. The idea that you live your
Speaker 2:  life on the computer and all the things you do on your computer
Speaker 2:  comprise your experiences and it would be cool
Speaker 2:  if the computer could help you sort those out is in fact a dream.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  And it requires like one bit of a philosophical shift, which is I think
Speaker 2:  most people think about that dream in terms of just like walking around the
Speaker 2:  world. Like what If you had an ambient computer or the ar ar glasses
Speaker 2:  and you were just like asking questions and your, your sort of IRL experiences
Speaker 2:  were that thing. And Microsoft has been like, all right, we're
Speaker 2:  like, we HoloLens aside, like actually you live your life on the screen
Speaker 2:  so we can just build a thing on this, on the screen and then we'll get to
Speaker 2:  your eyes later. You know, we'll put the computer on your face at a later
Speaker 2:  time. What about the computer that's in front of your face? What if we made
Speaker 2:  that do the thing that everyone wants? And that is a leap.
Speaker 2:  I I, it's actually kind of an interesting leap that Microsoft took first
Speaker 2:  in this way that where whereas everyone else has been chasing these classes
Speaker 2:  and I, I just like, it should be, I I think noting that he called it
Speaker 2:  one of the two dreams everyone had and I think people were like, is that
Speaker 2:  the dream? And it's like, oh actually we've been talking to air glasses for
Speaker 2:  like a decade and this is just that, but just
Speaker 2:  digitally instead
Speaker 5:  Of how Yeah. Once Microsoft is the company that actually like lives in the
Speaker 5:  real world unlike everybody else.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. They're not just showing some weird concept videos of like the Microsoft
Speaker 2:  kin, like
Speaker 5:  Exactly
Speaker 2:  Whatever that is or the, the, what was it, the papyrus, what was that thing
Speaker 2:  called? The Courier? Oh,
Speaker 5:  The Coru. Coer. RIP The Courier. They probably made a thing called the
Speaker 5:  Papyrus at one point.
Speaker 2:  I'm sure
Speaker 6:  They will send if
Speaker 2:  They haven't. Can I tell you a, an early a story about Neo Patels
Speaker 2:  experiences of copyright infringement? You don't, nobody remembers the kin.
Speaker 2:  This is like a thing that happened to a small number of us on the internet.
Speaker 2:  But Microsoft in the early iPhone days, instead of releasing a smartphone
Speaker 2:  released a teen focused feature phone called the Microsoft Kin. This is real.
Speaker 2:  There was a kin one and a kin two. They were bonnet like, I dunno
Speaker 2:  why they did this. and they were not smartphones, they were
Speaker 2:  legitimately feature phones that could like send MSN messages.
Speaker 2:  And their marketing campaign was like beautiful young people in hip art
Speaker 2:  districts of cities like skateboarding talking on their feature phones. And
Speaker 2:  I remixed their ads to the song Two Drunk to Fuck
Speaker 2:  by the Dead Kennedys
Speaker 2:  and Microsoft immediately had YouTube take them down. Amazing.
Speaker 2:  And I'm like, I'm like, that would just be a great TikTok now. Like no one
Speaker 2:  would even ask this question. Now anyone, if you're out there, do your thing.
Speaker 2:  TikTok the Kin, by the way, we gave them horrible reviews before they
Speaker 2:  even came out. Microsoft canceled them. This is a real victory of the eng
Speaker 2:  Gadget days. Well, I dunno what we're talking about anyway. No, the products
Speaker 2:  are real. That's what we're talking about. Not the Microsoft can, the products
Speaker 2:  are real. You can like use it and then the reaction to them is,
Speaker 2:  I don't trust this at all. It's probably broken. I don't, I don't believe
Speaker 2:  you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. The reaction to recall in
Speaker 6:  particular was surprising to me because like I I edited our story on it and
Speaker 6:  I was like, this is cool. I'm really excited about this. Like, didn't think
Speaker 6:  of the privacy stuff at all. 'cause I operate under the assumption if someone
Speaker 6:  physically has your computer, then you're boned. Like,
Speaker 6:  like you're screwed if someone has your computer, you're done.
Speaker 2:  That's the same word.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They're the same. Just in case people didn't understand what
Speaker 6:  bone, what means. I, I wanna make sure our entire audience understands,
Speaker 6:  but I, I just didn't ca I was like, okay, cool. This is, this is really neat
Speaker 6:  and and I'm excited for my computer to be a better archive of things because
Speaker 6:  that's what I use a computer for. Yeah. And then a friend was like, have
Speaker 6:  you heard about how pissed people are about recall? And I was like, why?
Speaker 6:  And they're like, because it records everything you do. And I was like, that's
Speaker 6:  literally what a computer does. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's like the point of
Speaker 2:  Them. Middle of the history tab of your browser. I
Speaker 5:  Was just about to say, this is one of my favorite things to do to people
Speaker 5:  is like, people don't understand the extent to which this
Speaker 5:  stuff is already being recorded. Like go look at the cash files on
Speaker 5:  your computer for what happens in all the apps on your computer. Like they,
Speaker 5:  they already know. But I think Kranz to your point, the,
Speaker 5:  the thing about privacy, there are real interesting privacy implications
Speaker 5:  here about like, what happens if somebody gets hold of this? What if there
Speaker 5:  are there gonna be new kinds of malware that can get onto my computer and
Speaker 5:  chase this stuff down? Like the stakes that go up slightly. But I, I do think
Speaker 5:  part of the reaction was just reminding
Speaker 5:  people of how much these devices already know.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And the the just the thing where it's like I am,
Speaker 5:  I'm doing all of this stuff on here. Like this is in a very real
Speaker 5:  way my life. And just the fact that that's being
Speaker 5:  collected somewhere feels gross to be reminded of. Like
Speaker 5:  even though sort of intellectually I understand that that's already the case.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's like when you realize that your ISP has access
Speaker 5:  to every website that you go to on your phone, even if you're on like in
Speaker 5:  incognito, like no, like Verizon still knows hi Verizon. It's still there.
Speaker 5:  Like it just, people hate being reminded of that and it is just such
Speaker 5:  an unavoidable fact of being alive right now that it is how it is that I
Speaker 5:  think it every time it comes up again, you're made to feel sort of powerless
Speaker 5:  and helpless against this like, incredible tide of all these
Speaker 5:  electronics that know too much about me. Well I think
Speaker 6:  It's also the fact that it's got, it's, it's using ai, right? Like, like
Speaker 6:  that's a big part of it. And people are having this weird moment,
Speaker 6:  especially this week and we're gonna talk about it more with like what's
Speaker 6:  going on with Scarlet Johansson later. But people are just having this sudden
Speaker 6:  visceral reaction to ai. And so this thing was, she was like, yes,
Speaker 6:  computers archive all your data. They have done that since the beginning
Speaker 6:  of time. This is just more efficient at it. They were like,
Speaker 6:  that might have gone over a little easier if they hadn't also said, and we're
Speaker 6:  gonna use AI to do it all. 'cause even though the ai, everything is happening
Speaker 6:  according to Microsoft, you know, security researchers will do their thing.
Speaker 6:  Everything is happening on the computer. It is not going into the cloud.
Speaker 6:  None of this is being shared anywhere. The, it's using the NPU to like
Speaker 6:  process this stuff. All of it's happening there. So theoretically it is no
Speaker 6:  different than just using your computer as normal. Only now if a
Speaker 6:  bad person gets ahold of your computer, they're gonna have a little easier
Speaker 6:  time recovering everything you do. That's it. But
Speaker 6:  that you put AI in there and people are like, burn it to the ground. Well
Speaker 5:  The whole road of that is so fascinating to me. 'cause I was talking to Dan
Speaker 5:  Roker, the CEO of this company called Rewind, which has been doing a third
Speaker 5:  party version of this on max for the last, I think year or so now.
Speaker 5:  It's another one that it uses basically like screen recording and your
Speaker 5:  device audio to pull out a lot of this same information. and
Speaker 5:  they actually just launched a new version that sinks in the cloud
Speaker 5:  because the overwhelming feedback from people was either
Speaker 5:  hell no, or hell yes, the hell no people you're never gonna get, and what
Speaker 5:  the hell yes people wanted was for all of this to be available to them
Speaker 5:  in more places. And so it's like we're actually in this bonkers
Speaker 5:  divide where there's a set of people who like as soon as you present them
Speaker 5:  the beginning of the road are like absolutely not. And just like, nope. Their
Speaker 5:  way out of this whole technological transition. And then there are a bunch
Speaker 5:  of people for whom the privacy stuff is actually going
Speaker 5:  to be a hindrance. Yeah. More than anything else. And there are gonna be
Speaker 5:  people who are like, well why can't I access everything that I did on my
Speaker 5:  other computer from my work computer? And then Microsoft is gonna be in this
Speaker 5:  horrible position of being like, well, we have to do the less private thing
Speaker 5:  because it's actually what our users want. And it is just, it just
Speaker 5:  like exacerbates that divide further and further and it just, I, I
Speaker 5:  don't know, it just feels crazy to me. Like the rewind folks were like, I
Speaker 5:  I don't know what you want from us. We tried to do it as private as we could
Speaker 5:  and the people who used it didn't want that anymore.
Speaker 2:  So there, there's two things about that that I think are fascinating and
Speaker 2:  they are expressed sort of in very tangible ways than
Speaker 2:  I think in very esoteric ways. So the very tangible way I did
Speaker 2:  the thing when I interviewed Sundar, where I handed him my phone to look
Speaker 2:  at Google search results and we ran that clip. The clip is like doing bonkers
Speaker 2:  on TikTok. And
Speaker 2:  in the clip as a joke, I say to Sundar, phai,
Speaker 2:  don't dig through my phone. Like of all the things you were ever gonna say
Speaker 2:  to a CEO e like a billionaire, CEO of one of the largest, you just pull it
Speaker 2:  up kicks and Max don't literally like, who am I? Of course I said like, I
Speaker 2:  couldn't resist it, you know, but it was just a joke. It's just like a
Speaker 2:  way to be human when you hand someone your phone and the
Speaker 2:  people in the comments are like, he already knows everything.
Speaker 2:  Like why would you tell him not to dig through your phone? Like he's, he's
Speaker 2:  the CEO of Google, like If you want, he can just, he can already dig through
Speaker 2:  your phone. And I think that's nihilism, right? Like
Speaker 2:  there's an element of nihilism there, which is like, it's already over. Like
Speaker 2:  you might as well embrace it and be excited about it. And then there's an
Speaker 2:  element of nihilism that's like, well I can't stop it. I'm gonna live off
Speaker 2:  the grid for the rest of my life. And that's one thing, the, the more esoteric
Speaker 2:  thing that I think about all the time is as more and more of these
Speaker 2:  companies get more and more into AI content generation,
Speaker 2:  the thing that they are promising, the people who pay the money, which is
Speaker 2:  in large part advertisers, is that they will make autogenerated
Speaker 2:  ads on their platforms. Yeah. So like Google will make autogenerated
Speaker 2:  AI created ads on YouTube. Meta will do it on Instagram. TikTok
Speaker 2:  will do it on TikTok. TikTok actually announced AI generated ads this week
Speaker 2:  and Mia Sato is writing with them.
Speaker 2:  You're gonna get to a place where you get extremely well targeted custom
Speaker 2:  content and the people who are like Facebook is listening to me are
Speaker 2:  gonna lose their minds.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  Right? Like the idea that you have privacy then is like out
Speaker 2:  the window. Like right now people think Facebook is listening to them because
Speaker 2:  it can target you based on your wifi networks, which is
Speaker 2:  the simplest thing. It just like knows what IP address you're on. It knows
Speaker 2:  that your friends have been on that IP address and it was like serve some
Speaker 2:  ads across based on interest targeting. It's not smart, it's
Speaker 2:  not stupid, it's like somewhere in the middle, you know? Yeah. Like it's
Speaker 2:  a pretty blunt instrument, but people are convinced that
Speaker 2:  Facebook is listening to them. You're gonna get to a place where it knows
Speaker 2:  a whole lot about you and then it knows that you're on the same wifi network
Speaker 2:  as your friend that you talked to about vacations in Mexico and then it delivers
Speaker 2:  you a video of you in Mexico.
Speaker 2:  What? Yeah. Like people are lose their minds and then
Speaker 2:  I think that, well I don't have any privacy anyway. I might as well just
Speaker 2:  give the cloud provider of recall or rewind
Speaker 2:  everything. I think that might actually change in a dramatic way very quickly
Speaker 2:  at that point.
Speaker 5:  Maybe it like, it really does seem like either, either the
Speaker 5:  pendulum is going to swing aggressively at some point soon or the pendulum
Speaker 5:  is just going to like burst through the side. No,
Speaker 6:  No. You know what's gonna happen
Speaker 2:  Explodes.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like Charlie in the chocolate factory style, just like launch through
Speaker 5:  the ceiling and be gone.
Speaker 2:  One thing
Speaker 2:  like, like what, what's gonna happen to the privacy pendulum? They, it's
Speaker 2:  go into space.
Speaker 2:  One thing I'll note you mentioned that the ISPs can see everything. Like
Speaker 2:  you would think that there would be a federal privacy bill. I'm, there is
Speaker 2:  not one of the first things that the Republican congress in
Speaker 2:  Trump's first term did. Literally one of the first things was
Speaker 2:  they threw out privacy bill that would've kept your data private from
Speaker 2:  ISPs. Yep. It was just like one of, Hey, we're here. What should we do? We
Speaker 2:  should make it so at and t can read all your shit. Like immediate.
Speaker 2:  It was an outrage. Yeah. And we, we have just not fixed that
Speaker 2:  in years.
Speaker 6:  I I I tend to feel like that that tension is only gonna be resolved
Speaker 6:  when congress actually knows what a computer is, how
Speaker 6:  it works, how to like use it like when they finally, well
Speaker 2:  Here's what a computer is. Yeah, it is. Its an AI powered
Speaker 2:  device. But If you say the right words, we'll bang you. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And I think Congress will react to that idea. Very powerful.
Speaker 6:  But it'll also If you say the wrong words, share all the photos of you
Speaker 6:  banging it to
Speaker 2:  Look If. you wanna get something done in United that'll get united that'll
Speaker 2:  states congress, it's blackmail and booty. those are your choices.
Speaker 5:  That's real. That's
Speaker 6:  So honestly, this is a great thing, right? Like yeah. Like I think this tension
Speaker 6:  has been there for a very long time and, and I think you are right that we
Speaker 6:  are coming to a point where like something's gonna have to give
Speaker 6:  these companies like Microsoft are really pushing for,
Speaker 6:  for stuff that is just completely counter to what we understand of privacy
Speaker 6:  and security and what we want. And the only way that's gonna change is if
Speaker 6:  someone else says, Hey, you can't do that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I look, I think the recall stuff is really interesting. I think it's,
Speaker 2:  to your point, David, it can't see what you're doing on your phone, right?
Speaker 2:  So this promise that you have this companion and this sort of living your
Speaker 2:  digital life with you except for what you do on your phone,
Speaker 2:  that's weird, right? And then you get into, should this be a cloud service?
Speaker 2:  Are you're running a background app on an Android? Like Apple's not gonna
Speaker 2:  let them do it, right? No. Maybe Apple does it on its own in iOS in a couple
Speaker 2:  weeks. Like we're, they're gonna have to bridge that gap I think for
Speaker 2:  this to be truly successful. But then there's the piece where
Speaker 2:  yeah, we're gonna have to hold them accountable to this thing being totally
Speaker 2:  local and a bunch of other AI stuff on this device is hybridized, right?
Speaker 2:  Like the paint example is hybridized. Like, I don't know. And that's why
Speaker 2:  I don't wanna seem overly skeptical. I I I really, I can see the jump
Speaker 2:  that Microsoft made from ar glasses are too hard. We have a bunch of
Speaker 2:  ai, we can basically do ar ar on windows. Like
Speaker 2:  ar is not the right word, but like this sort of augmented experience
Speaker 2:  in Windows for your digital life.
Speaker 6:  Multimodal you mean? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's, it's, there's something there. Co-pilot's like almost exactly
Speaker 2:  the right word, right? Like you're just doing stuff on a
Speaker 2:  computer and you're asking questions about the experiences you're having.
Speaker 2:  A lot of people have thought that would happen first in glasses on your face
Speaker 2:  and Microsoft is like, what if it happens on the screen in front of you?
Speaker 2:  Like, great, I
Speaker 6:  Like this. I just wanna point out, you said co-pilot is the right word. Where
Speaker 6:  do you stand on copilot plus PCs?
Speaker 5:  Awful. Awful,
Speaker 2:  Awful. Awful. I
Speaker 5:  Know what that is. Awful. Even, even Microsoft
Speaker 5:  has trouble saying the phrase copilot plus PCs. Like If,
Speaker 5:  you go back and watch, there are a bunch of people who clearly practiced
Speaker 5:  very hard who still occasionally struggle to say the phrase copilot plus
Speaker 5:  PCs. It's terrible. Yeah. Cool product. Bad name.
Speaker 2:  They, I just wanna figure out, figure how we're gonna get it right.
Speaker 6:  Why didn't they just call 'em AI PCs? Like did h HP just, just
Speaker 5:  'em copilot PCs their first, the hell is the plus doing there Copilot.
Speaker 5:  It's not a streaming service.
Speaker 5:  What are we doing here?
Speaker 2:  Do you have these features on Windows have a monthly fee?
Speaker 6:  No, I don't think so yet.
Speaker 5:  Not as far as we know. I don't think some of it requires an
Speaker 5:  OpenAI API key, which you have to pay for
Speaker 5:  like some of the, some of the copy and paste stuff. You can only do If. you
Speaker 5:  have the, I think the like GPT-4 key or something. But ah,
Speaker 5:  most of this stuff seems like it's gonna come baked into Windows, which itself
Speaker 5:  is rapidly becoming a subscription service. So I think that's where you end
Speaker 5:  up getting charged for it is like as a Microsoft's 365 thing rather
Speaker 5:  than a specific AI thing over time. I
Speaker 2:  Do love the mental image of like three to five years from now the extremely
Speaker 2:  cheap Acce R PC in a Walmart with like the dented cardboard sign that's like
Speaker 2:  copy and paste in multiple languages and it's just like
Speaker 2:  sitting in Racine, Wisconsin. You know, like everyone's like, why?
Speaker 2:  And that costs a monthly fee and they're like, why aren't these computers
Speaker 2:  selling? Like, that's gonna be great for everybody. We take a break.
Speaker 2:  That's just build, there's more,
Speaker 2:  there's like yet more behind use this week. Yeah, we'll come back. We'll
Speaker 2:  talk about Scarlet Show Hansen. It's really what we're gonna do here on The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  out in, in the scheme of
Speaker 2:  many of the traditional PC companies announced copilot plus
Speaker 2:  PCs including Samsung and If. you have been tracking
Speaker 2:  Samsung, you will know that Samsung recently instituted
Speaker 2:  six day work weeks for its executives to quote, inject a sense of
Speaker 2:  crisis into the company. They did not
Speaker 2:  institute six day work weeks for their engineers or products for the executives.
Speaker 2:  You get a bunch of executives working on Saturdays, you
Speaker 2:  get crazy ideas,
Speaker 2:  which I have taken to calling Saturday Samsung.
Speaker 2:  So Samsung's copilot pc, this is a real thing. So If, you buy
Speaker 2:  the new Galaxy Book four Edge, by the way, there's no space between book
Speaker 2:  and four, but a space between four and Edge. All right.
Speaker 5:  Marketing you is that the name of that is the Samsung Galaxy
Speaker 5:  Book four Edge copilot plus pc. Yeah, that makes me wanna throw things.
Speaker 2:  I'm saying you had the extra day on Saturday, you could have gotten rid of
Speaker 2:  a couple words. Alright.
Speaker 2:  But the, the people hooked Samsung in their quest to
Speaker 2:  inject a sense of crisis into the company have decided that their,
Speaker 2:  their single best idea is to just give away
Speaker 2:  TVs. Yeah. So the previous one of these we
Speaker 2:  covered the previous iteration of Saturday Samsung was that If, you bought
Speaker 2:  A Frame tv, you got another tv, which is perfect
Speaker 2:  If. you buy a Galaxy Book four Edge, again, there's no space between
Speaker 2:  book and four, but a space between four and Edge. A Galaxy Book four Edge
Speaker 2:  copilot plus vc. You do receive a 50 inch crystal
Speaker 2:  UHD 4K tv
Speaker 5:  Sick.
Speaker 2:  This is, this is the plan. I know. What's the SRP on that? It's
Speaker 2:  $379. They're, they're, they're just throwing you a $380 tv.
Speaker 2:  I'm sure it looks like absolute trash. I'm sure it's the same panel as a
Speaker 2:  frame tv. I gonna say just a single LED backlight
Speaker 2:  just shining gray in the dark.
Speaker 2:  But I just love that Samsung, they, they've got all the executives that are
Speaker 2:  on Saturday. Just how are we gonna, it's a crisis you guys.
Speaker 2:  How are we gonna, how are we gonna bring the stock price back up? And they're
Speaker 2:  like, here's what we're gonna do. Everybody gets a 50 inch tv. No.
Speaker 5:  Well you know that before that somebody was like, what if we made
Speaker 5:  them cheaper? Someone was like, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 6:  Just, just get rid of them. We're
Speaker 5:  Gonna go more, we're gonna go the other way. Yeah, but you also get a television.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna find the $380 of margin in every other product.
Speaker 2:  And you know what everybody loves is a free garbage 50 inch
Speaker 2:  TV If. you buy a tv, you get another tv, you buy
Speaker 2:  Chromebook, you get a tv, you buy and you buy our brand new
Speaker 2:  state-of-the-art copilot plus laptop free tv. That's,
Speaker 2:  that'll do it. So you're considering a surface. Does a surface come with
Speaker 2:  a free tv?
Speaker 2:  This I'm, it's great. I cannot, this year of Saturdays is gonna be amazing.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Sorry, I just literally, I said to David and Alex before we
Speaker 2:  started the show, the only thing I wanted to talk about was Saturday Samsung
Speaker 2:  and we forgot it's my fault. Just excited.
Speaker 2:  I it's, I could keep going another hour on Saturday. Samsung. Alright. Right.
Speaker 2:  We should talk about OpenAI is who I would say did not
Speaker 2:  have as successful of a week in AI as Microsoft
Speaker 2:  is. That's fair. Right? Fair. Even though Microsoft Fair, even big partner
Speaker 2:  Sam Altman was on stage at build. But I, I would,
Speaker 2:  I would characterize OpenAI didn as weak as definite.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Own goal was a phrase I heard used a lot.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it really is like a record week for
Speaker 5:  don't tweet as advice to give on the internet.
Speaker 5:  Really one of the all time what If you just didn't tweet moments
Speaker 5:  from Sam Waltman this week.
Speaker 2:  All right, let's run through it. It's, it's not a complicated story. It is
Speaker 2:  getting more and more complicated as more more people talk, which is bad.
Speaker 2:  That is a bad sign. If a seemingly simple story
Speaker 2:  starts to get more and more complicated, lawyers are gonna get
Speaker 2:  money. I will remind you what, what my
Speaker 2:  contracts professor in law school used to say, Stuart McCauley, why did this
Speaker 2:  case get filed? And we'd all say some idealistic first year law school
Speaker 2:  bullshit. And he would say no, the lawyers wanted A BMW.
Speaker 2:  A lot of lawyers are getting BMWs at the end of this rainbow.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Charlotte Johansen's lawyer is gonna be driving.
Speaker 2:  He already bought, he's like, I'm good. He bought
Speaker 6:  It from Disney.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. He like pre he's getting another one to bmw. He like, he's in a rivian
Speaker 2:  this time. He is like, just put a standing tab at the BM BMW
Speaker 2:  dealership. Just whatever m is coming out next. Just
Speaker 2:  gimme one of those. Although I've heard the XM is not great. Anyway. Okay,
Speaker 2:  so here's the, the basic rundown. They announced GPT-4
Speaker 2:  Oh, which in classic, I think it's broken. I don't believe you
Speaker 2:  appears to hallucinate more than GPT-4. Great.
Speaker 2:  But the, the headline feature of 4.0 is, it's
Speaker 2:  multimodal. O is for Omni. It can look at stuff, it can talk to you, you
Speaker 2:  can talk to it. And it has these, because it's multimodal.
Speaker 2:  A lot of the demos are people chatting to it. And then
Speaker 2:  open. I had these voices, they already had them.
Speaker 2:  One of them was called Sky, which was a, a woman.
Speaker 2:  But because of these demos, which were very voice heavy and
Speaker 2:  very personality driven, because that's the other big feature of 4.0,
Speaker 2:  a lot of people noticed that the Sky voice sounded a lot like Scarlet
Speaker 2:  Hansen. And that sky in particular made a lot of people
Speaker 2:  feel flirtatious. Right. Alex. I, I would say that's like the, I I
Speaker 6:  Think, I think that's an accurate assessment of things people got a little
Speaker 6:  horny for for Sky there. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  A lot of people thought they could bang an iPad last week. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It was uncomfortable for
Speaker 2:  Everyone. That's just, I mean I, I I don't know how else to characterize
Speaker 2:  the way people feel about AI right now except an awful horny, awful lot of
Speaker 2:  people wanna bang an iPad. It's fine. You know,
Speaker 2:  it's like some people wanna give all their privacy away to a cloud. Other
Speaker 2:  people, they have a particular dream. Okay, that's fine. You can, that
Speaker 5:  Was the other dream. Satya Anella was talking about
Speaker 2:  It's dream number two. Yeah. What If you could tag an iPad.
Speaker 2:  Alright, so there's a lot of conversation about
Speaker 2:  this voice, whether it sounds like Farhan or
Speaker 2:  not. And there's like a reasonable debate. Some people are like, absolutely
Speaker 2:  not. Some people are like, it does, people have asked
Speaker 2:  open eye executives very directly. Our own Kylie Robinson asked Mira
Speaker 2:  directly and she said, no, it was not our intention. No thought of this whatsoever.
Speaker 2:  And then Sam Altman tweets the word her, which
Speaker 2:  is the movie from Spike Jones at SARS Scarlet Hansen, which
Speaker 6:  He says is one of his favorite movies of all time in an inspiration.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Great. So now he's undone his poor
Speaker 2:  executive who was saying this was not the point. And then a very strange
Speaker 2:  thing happens, opening eyes sort of out of nowhere publishes a blog post.
Speaker 2:  It's like, here's how we selected our voices.
Speaker 2:  That's a weird time to do it. and they, it's just a very odine corporate
Speaker 2:  blog post. It's like we had a process. We did casting directors, blah, blah,
Speaker 2:  blah blah. Then they had our Mia David, our AI reporter, Mia David
Speaker 2:  talk to one of their executives to go through it. They would not
Speaker 2:  say that. No. They pulled it first.
Speaker 5:  They pulled it before they explained it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Okay. So it's like a very normal corporate and I
Speaker 2:  blog post, then they pull the voice
Speaker 2:  like almost immediately after that they pull the voice sky. Sky, yeah. And
Speaker 2:  say, based on concerns we've heard, we're pulling this
Speaker 2:  voice. Which is interesting 'cause there's only one person's concern
Speaker 2:  that matters. and she is a very powerful actress in Hollywood
Speaker 2:  who was married to the head writer Saturday Night Life.
Speaker 5:  So can I, can I, can I just pause you on that moment? I, I, I'm curious If,
Speaker 5:  you guys had the same reaction that I did in that moment, which is
Speaker 5:  obviously Scarlett Johansen is mad. Yep. Yeah, right there. I just couldn't
Speaker 5:  think of any other, 'cause this happened on Sunday night or like overnight
Speaker 5:  into Monday morning. I, I could not imagine a world in
Speaker 5:  which they pulled this voice and put up this long blog
Speaker 5:  post, which essentially amounted to one of those. Like my, we didn't
Speaker 5:  copy Scarlet Johansen t-shirt is raising a lot of questions answered by my,
Speaker 5:  we didn't copy Scarlet Johansen t-shirt, one of those moments. And we
Speaker 5:  were, we were covering this thing like, okay, they were, they say they're
Speaker 5:  just trying to allay confusion. Like, I couldn't think of another plausible
Speaker 5:  reason other than Scarlet is yelling Yes.
Speaker 5:  Right? Like, was that your reaction?
Speaker 2:  It's the only thing be happening here. Yeah. Okay. Then they called
Speaker 2:  me a David, one of our reporters and said, we have an interview with our
Speaker 2:  executive. They would not tell Mia the timeline.
Speaker 2:  The only question is, did Scarlet call you? And then you pulled the voice,
Speaker 2:  right? Legitimately the only question here. And they're like, we heard these
Speaker 2:  concerns, we want to get out. We pulled the voice and they just like, wouldn't
Speaker 2:  say the timeline weird. So we run this story, they said, here's a
Speaker 2:  headline.
Speaker 2:  Our headline is like, pretty anodyne, right? It's also just like more OpenAI
Speaker 2:  is talking. We pulled this voice out of concerns. Here's,
Speaker 2:  here's some more color on that, except they won't say what the timeline is.
Speaker 2:  Hours later, Scarlet Hansen has a statement out first to Bobby Allen at NPR
Speaker 2:  and then Wily to everyone that says basically like, Sam
Speaker 2:  Altman called me to be the voice of chat, GBT. And I
Speaker 2:  said, no. And then, you know, several weeks later
Speaker 2:  I'm listening to these demos and it sounds like my voice, I lo I lawyered
Speaker 2:  up and I want to know exactly how this happened.
Speaker 6:  Well, he called her like two days before the launch. Like he, he
Speaker 6:  called her initially his, her timeline that she outlines is like, they talk,
Speaker 6:  they chatted a while ago about it and she thought about it and then she said,
Speaker 6:  no, I don't wanna do the voice. And he's like, cool. Didn't hear from him
Speaker 6:  for a while. Two days before the demo, Sam Altman calls her
Speaker 6:  and is like, Hey, you reconsidered. And she's like, no, I don't wanna do
Speaker 6:  it. And he's like, cool.
Speaker 2:  And then she hears a voice That sounds like her. Yep.
Speaker 5:  That was a perfect Sam Altman impression by the way. Alex, like I know you
Speaker 5:  were working on that. I worked really hard, worked well was really good.
Speaker 5:  Thank you.
Speaker 2:  It sounded like it was an all lowercase.
Speaker 2:  Then there's just one last piece of reporting from Natasha Teko, another
Speaker 2:  former version reporter at the Washington Post. She has talked to the agent
Speaker 2:  of the voice actress that OpenAI cast for the Sky Voice. Both the actress
Speaker 2:  and the agent wished to remain anonymous. I have a lot of feelings about
Speaker 2:  that, but they wish to remain anonymous. And she's seen some documents that
Speaker 2:  lay out a version of the timeline that says OpenAI actually recorded all
Speaker 2:  this and never said to this actress, sound like Sol Jansen. So maybe
Speaker 2:  there's some blurriness here. There's some old case law in the mix
Speaker 2:  here. We, you know, we did a story, we talked to some lawyers. There's a
Speaker 2:  very famous case with Tom Waits who has a very distinctive voice.
Speaker 2:  By the way, Heath led was basically doing Tom Wait's impression in the dark
Speaker 2:  night, which is very funny. But that's the voice like If. you think about
Speaker 2:  Heath Ledger in the dark night, like Tom Waits has this very distinctive
Speaker 2:  voice. There's a very famous commercial where they asked the singer to sound
Speaker 2:  like Tom Waits, Tom Waits sued one. There are other tastes
Speaker 2:  like this where people's likeness get used without their permission. My my
Speaker 2:  favorite one of this is a Vana White v Samsung,
Speaker 2:  yes. Maybe the best of these cases that exists. Samsung ran
Speaker 2:  a commercial that looked like Wheel of Fortune where a robot was turning
Speaker 2:  the letters and Vanna White said, that robot is me
Speaker 2:  and one. Wow.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it seems very good. She felt like a monopoly.
Speaker 2:  It is. I, with all of the cases I ever read in law school, I was like, this
Speaker 2:  is why I came here. Vanna White v Sam Electronics.
Speaker 2:  So there's like a lot of these weird cases, like you are not allowed to trade,
Speaker 2:  in particular in New York and California, which is where most of the celebrities
Speaker 2:  are. The state law does not allow you to trade on the license of celebrities
Speaker 2:  to sell your products. That's just a thing we have not gotten
Speaker 2:  to. We cloned a voice using another actress and everyone
Speaker 2:  got confused. That's new. That's a new problem for our court system that
Speaker 2:  I'm very much looking forward to seeing litigated. But, but we're
Speaker 2:  in this place where we've expanded the boundary of what you can take.
Speaker 2:  Right. And the AI companies are really just taking a lot of stuff without
Speaker 2:  asking for a lot of permission. And I think this one with Scarlet
Speaker 2:  Jen Hansen and Sam Altman in this completely insane timeline that is getting
Speaker 2:  complicated, the more anyone talks is, I think really,
Speaker 2:  you know, we talked about it in the earlier segment. People have really,
Speaker 2:  really an like, antagonistic feelings towards AI because it feels like
Speaker 2:  it's taking stuff from us. And a famous actress
Speaker 2:  who was in a bunch of Marvel movies, she's not the
Speaker 2:  right adversary for Opening Eyes.
Speaker 6:  Who sued Disney,
Speaker 2:  Who sued Disney, right? Like, I don't know, man,
Speaker 6:  That's not the person you wanna like mess with. Yeah. I, it was just
Speaker 6:  kind of gobsmacked by this because, you know, I think
Speaker 6:  like Lake Bell plays does a, a really good scar, Scarlet
Speaker 6:  Johansson impression on an animated show where she's playing Black Widow
Speaker 6:  and, and she sounds a lot like her. It's great. But also she's playing Black
Speaker 6:  Widow and, and, and there's, there's a whole, there's like agreements in
Speaker 6:  place and that's why it's allowed this is she, this
Speaker 6:  person sounded a lot like Scarlett Johanssen and then Sam
Speaker 6:  Altman tweeted her clearly referencing this.
Speaker 6:  He's talked about how much affection he has for that voice, for that
Speaker 6:  concept. It's just like, oh, you really just kept walking into
Speaker 6:  rakes on this one dude. Like, just, just stop, stay
Speaker 6:  stand still for a moment because yeah, they probably did hire this
Speaker 6:  woman and she probably didn't know that she sounded a lot like
Speaker 6:  Scarlet Johansson or that that's why they hired her, right? Like
Speaker 5:  There are so many weird twists and turns of all of this, right? 'cause then
Speaker 5:  there's the question of was this voice
Speaker 5:  made to sound like Samantha from her or does it sound like
Speaker 5:  Scarlett Johansen? And is there a distinction between those two things and
Speaker 5:  is that meaningful? And how much do people associate the voice of Samantha
Speaker 5:  and the role of Samantha with Scarlett Johanssen? That's just like, all of
Speaker 5:  this is unprecedented in such bizarre ways. But the thing that keeps jumping
Speaker 5:  out to me is that the immediate
Speaker 5:  response was that of course OpenAI is,
Speaker 5:  is wrong. Yes. 'cause of course OpenAI would've just gone
Speaker 5:  and ingested the movie and used that. I mean, we've seen
Speaker 5:  the technology now that you can use five minutes of somebody's voice and
Speaker 5:  spit out a pretty passable version of that voice. Like
Speaker 5:  just the immediate assumption that that's what OpenAI didn was. Either
Speaker 5:  find a person and tell them to do a Scarlet Johansen impression or screw
Speaker 5:  all that. Just train your model on Samantha and her
Speaker 5:  and call it a day that like this company has so aggressively lost the benefit
Speaker 5:  of the doubt. It made me think of the, the iPad Crush commercial in the same
Speaker 5:  way. Yeah. Yeah. That it's just like this is a company that people do not
Speaker 5:  trust and people think the worst of now and
Speaker 5:  believe that their intentions are bad. And I think the, the thing with
Speaker 5:  the OpenAI thing is, I think the answer is probably some weird
Speaker 5:  middle sketchy thing. And it seems like the OpenAI version of the story is
Speaker 5:  that OpenAI didn ran a pretty normal process. And then Sam Altman, who is
Speaker 5:  the CEO of OpenAI, just like weird, went rogue and started calling
Speaker 5:  Scarlett Johansen. And now there are all these things out there about how
Speaker 5:  Sam just desperately wants to be famous and it's making him make mistakes.
Speaker 5:  And like we've gone in all of these weird directions. Wait,
Speaker 2:  Hold on. Can I just say I hate it when companies pretend
Speaker 2:  they're CEOs are idiots? I hate
Speaker 5:  Totally fair.
Speaker 2:  Sam Alman is a billionaire. He is the founder of
Speaker 2:  OpenAI. He is so much in charge of OpenAI is that when the board of
Speaker 2:  OpenAI fired him for being reckless and manipulative, the
Speaker 2:  employees all staged a reverse coup and brought him back. That's
Speaker 2:  real. And it's like, yeah, that's a, a real thing that happened just a little
Speaker 2:  bit ago. Yeah. A couple months ago because the board of directors was like,
Speaker 2:  we don't trust Sam Altman and fired him and he
Speaker 2:  got his way back in the company. He has a new board of directors and now
Speaker 2:  a bunch of employees are quitting. 'cause opening eye is generally abandoning
Speaker 2:  It's like safety culture. Yeah. And he's doing this reckless stuff and I
Speaker 2:  just don't buy it that the company is like, yeah, we are running responsibly.
Speaker 2:  There's just this hot head that we reverse cooed back into the CEO role
Speaker 2:  that we can't control. Like you,
Speaker 6:  You can't like, like it's just a full like lie on their part
Speaker 6:  to be like, we have no control over him. It's like, well he runs the company.
Speaker 6:  So
Speaker 5:  Like I agree with that, that, and yet I also find it
Speaker 5:  absolutely plausible that the billionaire CEO who is kind of
Speaker 5:  feeling himself would call Scarlett Johansen on the side
Speaker 2:  And try to get it true. Oh, that's, but yeah, no, if I had a billion dollars
Speaker 2:  and I was like, my robot can plausibly make Kevin Roos think that it's in
Speaker 2:  love with him. Like I would call Scarlett Janssen. you
Speaker 5:  Don see what would happen. You don't tell these people who are doing the
Speaker 5:  casting process who then you are happy to throw to the wolves after the
Speaker 5:  fact. But like the, the bones of that
Speaker 5:  version of the story do not seem implausible to me at all.
Speaker 5:  But it also doesn't matter. He's the CEO of the company. It doesn't matter.
Speaker 2:  Right. The part where they ultimately shipped the voice that sounded like
Speaker 2:  her in every sense of that word. And he knew
Speaker 2:  about it and those were the demos. And I'm confident that he watched every
Speaker 2:  second of those demos. He was
Speaker 5:  In the, and he tweeted
Speaker 2:  In the audience the word her. Yeah. Those are his choices. Yeah. He
Speaker 2:  knew,
Speaker 5:  He
Speaker 2:  Tweeted the word her.
Speaker 5:  He knew the whole thing. It's
Speaker 2:  Hard to undo that thing. By the way, your question about whether it's the
Speaker 2:  movie Her or Raja Hansen, I will offer you the
Speaker 2:  1995 case Metro Goldwin Meyer, the American Honda
Speaker 2:  Company where Honda made an ad for the Civic del Soul that
Speaker 2:  looked a little bit too much like a James Bond movie and lost
Speaker 2:  to MGM. Yes. Really? It was, it was not James James Bond. They
Speaker 2:  made too good a commercial. It was a guy in a suit jumping out the, you know,
Speaker 2:  the, I don't remember the civic tell soul. That's not a
Speaker 2:  high watermark and civic design, but it was a civic with a, a top that you
Speaker 2:  could like take off. And so the ad was like
Speaker 2:  he's driving James A. James Bond like character is driving a Honda
Speaker 2:  Civic, very plausible. And he blows the top off and jumps outta the car and
Speaker 2:  does some James Bond stuff. And MGM said that that is James Bond. You made
Speaker 2:  James Bond. Wow. You can't have it. and they
Speaker 2:  won. Yes. That's so dumb. I'm excited for us to go
Speaker 2:  to court against OpenAI and say, your robot, the
Speaker 2:  precedent by which we are suing you is MGM versus American. Have
Speaker 2:  you seen the Civic del Soul judge? MGM by the way, also
Speaker 2:  now owned by Amazon. Just one of those
Speaker 2:  things. Just a weird moment in time
Speaker 2:  because again, most of these cases took place in New York and
Speaker 2:  California ages ago. Most of them are about pretty
Speaker 2:  normal ads, right? Like that's why you appropriate a celebrity's likeness
Speaker 2:  to try to sell something. Those days are over. Like TikTok is
Speaker 2:  full of weird, deep fake celebrities and just like
Speaker 2:  pure copyright infringement. The number of companies right now If, you run
Speaker 2:  a regular company and you wanna buy a regular ad and you're like, I'd like
Speaker 2:  to use Taylor Swift to sell my towels. You can't. But that's
Speaker 2:  too expensive. If you're a super shady distributor of
Speaker 2:  Alibaba towels and you're on TikTok, it's all Taylor Swift all
Speaker 2:  day long deep fakes baby. It's crazy. And like there's a
Speaker 2:  gap here that's happening where the law has absolutely not caught up to reality.
Speaker 2:  'cause most of these cases are about big ad agencies and big companies with
Speaker 2:  big budgets running ads. Right? I don't know
Speaker 2:  that you we're just gonna, we're just in for a moment of chaos
Speaker 2:  because the reality of what's happening on the ground is people do not care
Speaker 2:  about the law as particularly IP law and the big companies
Speaker 2:  Google OpenAI, they are the next generation of their
Speaker 2:  technology is just founded on taking stuff,
Speaker 2:  which is why OpenAI does not have the benefit of the doubt. Everyone believes
Speaker 2:  they took whatever they want and if they wanted to, they, they would
Speaker 2:  just make a clone of Scarlet Hanson's voice. Whether or not they cast an
Speaker 2:  actress who sounded just like her. It doesn't matter. Because if the technology
Speaker 2:  exists for them to just do it and no one thinks they have the control to
Speaker 2:  not do it. Weird. Yeah. A weird moment for them.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And I, at least from what I've heard so far the last couple of days, I'm
Speaker 5:  curious if y'all have heard anything different, is that this, there's
Speaker 5:  no indication so far that Scarlett Johanssen is
Speaker 5:  actually going to like, take real legal action here. She put out that one
Speaker 5:  statement and we don't know what's gonna happen next, but that if she
Speaker 5:  did this would have a real chance of
Speaker 5:  going somewhere and being pretty important and precedent setting
Speaker 5:  in terms of like, it just feels like in so many ways we're itching for like
Speaker 5:  the one weird AI lawsuit and like, maybe it's the New
Speaker 5:  York Times one, but it would be frankly a lot like Wilder
Speaker 5:  and weirder and more fun if it was Scarlett Johanssen.
Speaker 6:  Well, I think they're probably kind of different cases. Like they're, they're
Speaker 6:  targeting different things, but they get the same thrust of things, which
Speaker 6:  is can you just take shit?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like what are you allowed to do in the name of That's very
Speaker 2:  Nice.
Speaker 6:  Ultimately it's can you just do stuff?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. Right. I mean like, if, if I do it with a computer, it's fine.
Speaker 2:  Right? It's like that's the answer. And there look, there are very meaningful
Speaker 2:  differences between what you can do at a computer. I can do it real life.
Speaker 2:  Like for example, Alex, if I came to your house and took one of your Blu-rays
Speaker 2:  away, I that would be a crime. Yeah. For many reasons. One, I
Speaker 2:  just a crime against our friendship, you know? Right. I'd very obsessed,
Speaker 2:  but importantly you would not have the Blu-ray anymore. Whereas if I came
Speaker 2:  to your house and copied a file off your PL server and left, I think you'd
Speaker 2:  be like, well, and our friendship has strengthened. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And
Speaker 2:  You would also have the original copy, your very legal copy
Speaker 2:  of whatever content. Yeah, totally.
Speaker 6:  I would have the Blu-ray still in my closet. Yes, that's correct.
Speaker 2:  Th this is like a meaningful thing in copyright law. Whereas, you know, it
Speaker 2:  was all, it's all founded on physical scarcity. It has not translated to
Speaker 2:  the world of like digital very well. On the other hand,
Speaker 2:  I can just do whatever I want. 'cause it's a computer is not a workable
Speaker 2:  strategy either. Right. You know, like there's some middle ground here that
Speaker 2:  no one has ever really thought through. And I think that AI conversations,
Speaker 2:  you know, this is a conversation I had with Sundar, like, do you feel great
Speaker 2:  about OpenAI training on YouTube? Okay. The web doesn't feel that way about
Speaker 2:  you. And he was like, that's weird. You know, like everyone has to wrestle
Speaker 2:  with those two ideas at the same time while we're saying, Hey,
Speaker 2:  some of this technology is like really cool. Like, you want some of this
Speaker 2:  technology, some of this stuff is really great for people who have, who are
Speaker 2:  differently abled. Right? Like who, how are we gonna solve these problems?
Speaker 2:  And I Alex I think you're definitely right that like the training law, the
Speaker 2:  training lawsuit is a copyright lawsuit. And this other
Speaker 2:  stuff is like a likeness lawsuit, a right of publicity lawsuit. They're different
Speaker 2:  bodies of law that are very hard to distinguish for normal people.
Speaker 2:  Normal people can't tell you the difference between a copyright and a trademark
Speaker 2:  and a patent. Right. Like this is even more esoteric than that.
Speaker 2:  And on top of it, sort of the inherent nature of it is that these are celebrities.
Speaker 2:  Like you can't, you don't have a right of publicity. You don't have publicity.
Speaker 2:  Right. And like all of the law is built around celebrity. And so
Speaker 2:  you're just gonna get a sequence of people, of plaintiffs
Speaker 2:  who are just the most sympathetic because they are gonna be celebrities.
Speaker 2:  Yep. And at some point, you know, like we did an
Speaker 2:  episode, Sarah John and I did an episode of Decoder where we talked about
Speaker 2:  the copyright law. And like that feels like a time bomb waiting to go off.
Speaker 2:  Something's gonna happen with copyright law and training data. It, it is
Speaker 2:  inevitable that one of those cases goes the wrong way. 'cause there's so
Speaker 2:  many of them now. It feels inevitable that particularly is
Speaker 2:  these companies wanna trade on famous voices even
Speaker 2:  if it's not this case that, I don't know man, like Kevin
Speaker 2:  Hart is gonna be like, that sounds too much like me, just like sue Amazon.
Speaker 2:  Like it's like one of those kinds of things is gonna happen. I mean
Speaker 5:  It's this, it's the music thing, right? Yeah. Like this, it's, it's all of
Speaker 5:  the, the like copyright trolls coming after anyone who writes
Speaker 5:  a song with power chords in guitars now. Yeah. Like, we're, we're gonna do
Speaker 5:  that again at a crazy scale. I
Speaker 6:  Feel it's a little almost simpler than that because it, it,
Speaker 6:  it's kind of straightforward that if Amazon had gone and released an
Speaker 6:  Alexa voice that was Kevin Hart and it wasn't actually Kevin Hart, he would've
Speaker 6:  sued, but Amazon went and said, Hey Kevin Hart or Samuel Hall Jackson or
Speaker 6:  whoever, do you wanna be a voice? No. Do you wanna, but
Speaker 2:  They have done that Bunch Money Jackson is a voice on on
Speaker 6:  Alexa. Yeah. They paid him. Yeah. And, and so like, like I think in this
Speaker 6:  case there's a lot of precedent of like everybody else knew how to do this
Speaker 6:  business and OpenAI is like
Speaker 6:  Yolo.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. By the way, I dunno what's wrong with me. That I had to immediately
Speaker 2:  think of it. That I had to quickly think of a very distinctive voice and
Speaker 2:  my mind went immediately to Kevin Hart.
Speaker 6:  I wasn't gonna comment on it, but that's just what I
Speaker 2:  Had
Speaker 6:  Comment on it to you later in Slack.
Speaker 2:  It's a very distinctive voice. I just don't, I just dunno.
Speaker 5:  I often think of you as the Kevin Hart of The Vergecast so that
Speaker 2:  It's time to take a break David.
Speaker 2:  And we'll see if you're back when we come back for the lightning round.
Speaker 2:  Weird time. It's kind of broken and I dunno if I believe you, we'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 5:  It's beautiful.
Speaker 2:  Dreams. Dreams do come true. Alright, lightning
Speaker 2:  round. We gotta start with this one. It's maybe the most important lightning
Speaker 2:  round item. The United States government, the Department of Justice has
Speaker 2:  sued Ticketmaster Live Nation. I'm shown Ticketmaster. They want to break
Speaker 2:  it up. This has been a long time coming. I would
Speaker 2:  say this is Taylor Swift lawsuit. It feels fully like Taylor Swift lawsuit.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. It really is. And this has been I
Speaker 5:  think kind of in the wind ever since the merger
Speaker 5:  happened. I mean in 2010 right? Was when the merger was, and even
Speaker 5:  then, if I remember right, there was real, this should not be allowed
Speaker 5:  energy.
Speaker 2:  Oh this was fully If. you wanna ever make the case that Brock Obama was kinda
Speaker 2:  like a bad president? His competition policy where he just like,
Speaker 2:  let this stuff slide like his DOJ and his FTC just let this stuff slide
Speaker 2:  all over the place. Like full Reagan. Like this is the
Speaker 2:  core of that argument. Yeah. Like when, when people make it like Obama
Speaker 2:  presided over the great recession and all this other stuff in recovery. Part
Speaker 2:  of it was we are just gonna let these mergers slide to bring the
Speaker 2:  economy back. And now we're on the other side of it. You can also blame Ronald
Speaker 2:  Reagan. I I prefer to blame Ronald Reagan when we made an entire decoder
Speaker 2:  video blaming Ronald Reagan for Ticketmaster. You can watch
Speaker 2:  that video. But basically the heart of the argument is Ticketmaster
Speaker 2:  Live Nation owns ticket sales, obviously promotion artist management. They
Speaker 2:  own all the venues. They own 60 of the top 100 venues in the United States.
Speaker 2:  And so you just have this vertically integrated monopoly and if an
Speaker 2:  artist tries to screw with it, ticket master crushes them, which means
Speaker 2:  prices go up. 'cause there's no competition.
Speaker 5:  It's actually, in a very funny way, it is sort of perfect
Speaker 5:  textbook monopoly stuff. Like the allegations are so simple
Speaker 5:  to understand. I actually encourage people to go read the lawsuit because
Speaker 5:  it really is like If, you want to understand what a monopoly looks like.
Speaker 5:  It is what these allegations say Live Nation and Ticketmaster
Speaker 5:  does, which is own everything and just use that to beat
Speaker 5:  the hell out of anybody who tries to own anything and come at you. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And like the, the threats that they are alleged to make against
Speaker 5:  artists and venues who don't work with them, the ways that they like raise
Speaker 5:  fees to keep everybody out and like self deal to each other. Like it's, it
Speaker 5:  is pure monopoly stuff. If all of these allegations are true, it's,
Speaker 2:  And at the end of it, at the very bottom of it, yep. Prices are high, but
Speaker 2:  service quality is low. Right. Like they don't have to invest in the ticketing
Speaker 2:  platform or the app or the website because who cares. Right.
Speaker 5:  Which, which is why Ticketmaster broke.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Which is why there's a crush of demand for Taylor Swift tickets. Even
Speaker 2:  after she told them there will be a crush of demand, can you handle it? And
Speaker 2:  it still crashed and they didn't have to do anything. 'cause there's where,
Speaker 2:  where are you gonna go Taylor? And I think once the United States government
Speaker 2:  is like, where, where are you gonna go Taylor? She doesn't have choices.
Speaker 5:  If Taylor Swift doesn't have options, there's a monopoly happening here.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Then, then maybe we'll do something But. anyway, you can go read the lawsuit
Speaker 2:  and like I said, we'll, we'll drop the link. We made a long decoder about
Speaker 2:  the whole buildup of this with a lot of great interviews in this. One of
Speaker 2:  our, when it was a, it was a pi you know, we do two episodes now. It was
Speaker 2:  a pilot of our explainer episode. So it was a fun one. All that was my, I
Speaker 2:  we gotta say that one. Alex, what's your lightning round?
Speaker 6:  Salt Spoon?
Speaker 2:  Totally different move. Sorry.
Speaker 5:  What?
Speaker 6:  Totally, totally different. I actually have two. Yeah. And I feel this one
Speaker 6:  is almost more important. That's not true.
Speaker 5:  Salt Spoon is the new Mad Max movie, right? Yeah. Is that, that's what that's
Speaker 5:  called. Okay.
Speaker 6:  That it's exactly what it's called. But I I know we, we've done, we've talked
Speaker 6:  before on The Vergecast about how you can like use
Speaker 6:  electricity to make people taste things a little differently. Andrew Marino
Speaker 6:  did a really good podcast, Vergecast on it.
Speaker 6:  Somebody else was like, what if we put those electrodes into a spoon and
Speaker 6:  so we could take things that aren't salty and make them more salty. And as
Speaker 6:  someone who grew up low sodium because of their mom, hell yes.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I am so excited for this. I didn't know what salt tasted like until I was
Speaker 6:  like 16. Like, this is incredible. I'm so excited. But
Speaker 6:  they're only, they're only selling like 200 of 'em
Speaker 6:  and it doesn't work. If, you have like heart problems, which
Speaker 6:  If you most people on low sodium diets. That's why they're on them. It doesn't
Speaker 6:  work if you're like pregnant. So a lot of the people who might
Speaker 6:  wanna be on low sodium diets this won't actually work for, but
Speaker 6:  it's a salt spoon and that's cool.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. When I read this, I thought it was a spoon that just dumped salt.
Speaker 6:  No, that's, I've got one of those in my, my kitchen right now
Speaker 5:  That's just called a spoon. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. No, but that's just a real CES local news gadget, you know? Yeah. Like
Speaker 2:  it's spoon that precisely delivers that. No, this one just shocks you into
Speaker 2:  believing there's salt. A different approach.
Speaker 6:  I love that for them. And it's from the people who do like soy sauce, it's
Speaker 6:  Kiran. Oh,
Speaker 2:  Nice.
Speaker 6:  So very good. They they know salt.
Speaker 2:  They should make a sriracha spoon.
Speaker 6:  Oh my God.
Speaker 2:  I want, they should just continue electrocuting my brain into, into flavor.
Speaker 6:  Just trick my brain constantly. Please. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  All right, David. Like
Speaker 5:  I, we have to talk about humane, right? Oh gosh. Everyone's everyone's
Speaker 5:  favorite startup. There was a Bloomberg report this week that Humane
Speaker 5:  is now looking for a buyer. And I believe the price it's looking for is somewhere
Speaker 5:  between 750 million. And a billion dollars
Speaker 5:  also was in that story that the company has raised
Speaker 5:  $230 million. So
Speaker 2:  It wants a four x valuation Yeah. At the top end. Okay. And
Speaker 5:  I would remind you that it is, it's, it's that humane. It is. It's
Speaker 5:  the one, it's the one we've talked about. It's not a different, like B2B
Speaker 5:  Humane that is very successful,
Speaker 5:  truly bold strategy to come out and say, I'm not surprised this company's
Speaker 5:  looking for a buyer. Right. Like, I think the, the thing you hope for with
Speaker 5:  your first product is that it gets you money to get to the second product.
Speaker 5:  And then the second product is the one where you start to win. And that's
Speaker 5:  where you go, like, that's the strategy. But If, you flop on the first one
Speaker 5:  and holy God, does it look like they flopped on the first one?
Speaker 5:  It's very hard to get out of that. So I'm not shocked that Humane is looking
Speaker 5:  for a way out. I think a, it's going to have a lot of trouble
Speaker 5:  finding a buyer because this company is not full of people who are like beloved
Speaker 5:  in the tech industry, I would say.
Speaker 2:  And at the top,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, at the top. Like Imran Chari in particular, I would say
Speaker 5:  left Apple not beloved by people still
Speaker 5:  at Apple. That's about as much as I can report
Speaker 5:  on that. But that I, I feel pretty good saying that
Speaker 2:  The
Speaker 5:  Rest of it is just, it is truly
Speaker 5:  wild for this company to come out and say, we think we should get four x
Speaker 5:  what we phrased.
Speaker 2:  And everyone who works
Speaker 5:  Here should get rich because of this terrible product that we've made.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So two things. One, it's probably broken. And I
Speaker 2:  don't believe you
Speaker 2:  real theme, I'm just telling you.
Speaker 5:  Well, that one's definitely broken. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  We know that it's super broken and I don't believe, like I'm just saying,
Speaker 2:  we caught a lot of heat for being mean at the TED Talk.
Speaker 2:  Here we are. Second, let's go through the list. Right. So Apple
Speaker 2:  is out. I don't, they're not gonna pay them the money. No. Nope. And I, I,
Speaker 2:  I concur with your reporting and that is also about as much as I can say.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But like, if you're out in the mix, it's just out there.
Speaker 2:  That's just information. Yeah. Apple's not gonna buy this company especially
Speaker 2:  'cause they're entire pitch was, we're gonna obsolete the iPhone. Right.
Speaker 2:  Doesn't seem like the sort of thing Apple's gonna invest in. No. Apple has
Speaker 2:  the Apple Watch, they're gonna be fine. They have
Speaker 2:  Siri, which is a little shaky, but they got the Apple watch
Speaker 2:  Google. No. Right. That feels like a no. They're, they're still struggling
Speaker 2:  to integrate Fitbit and don't need Google has predict projector, more
Speaker 5:  Hardware, both like more hardware chops and more hardware issues
Speaker 5:  than it can deal with already.
Speaker 2:  Right. Google for example, I'll just do this. They just merged Android and
Speaker 2:  the Pixel team under Rick Oslow who formerly ran the Pixel team
Speaker 2:  and all of hardware. And now he runs all the platforms too. So Rick has to
Speaker 2:  like keep Samsung happy, right? Like
Speaker 2:  he's, he now manages the whole ecosystem, which is really interesting. Right?
Speaker 2:  But can you, and, and he is gotta figure out the rest of Fitbit, which
Speaker 2:  is still messy from what I understand from V You can't just like throw a
Speaker 2:  bunch of X apple designer to not their right. Running
Speaker 2:  not your AI platform.
Speaker 5:  Right. And a big part of what Humane, I suspect is trying to sell
Speaker 5:  is the operating system. Right? Like they've always said, we
Speaker 5:  are not just about the AI pin. Like they're, they wanna be a platform. And
Speaker 5:  this is a pitch you hear from everybody, but I, I suspect If, you're gonna
Speaker 5:  pay anything like the price that they want. You think you're buying what
Speaker 5:  has the potential to be a winning platform? Not a bunch of hardware engineers.
Speaker 5:  Like Google doesn't actually need more hardware engineers at this moment
Speaker 5:  in time.
Speaker 6:  No. Is it not just them trying to be like, everybody's really hot
Speaker 6:  for AI right now. We shipped an AI thing
Speaker 6:  by our AI thing,
Speaker 2:  But their AI thing is OpenAI.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But Samsung's got Saturdays
Speaker 2:  If they
Speaker 5:  Wanted to do that, they should have sold four months ago. Right. Like
Speaker 5:  if you're just trying to capitalize, you sell before you ship and not after.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Well,
Speaker 6:  Unless you're greedy and you think you actually like,
Speaker 2:  Or they thought they were gonna win. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. and they thought they were gonna win. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Which is fine. Companies are allowed to work harder. Like sure. There's,
Speaker 2:  how do I put this? There's no lack of sincerity in the humane
Speaker 2:  ecosystem, right? Like no, that's, it might be some confusion,
Speaker 2:  some delusion, but not But they're not
Speaker 5:  Kidding.
Speaker 2:  They're not insincere. Right? Yeah. Right. Okay. So Google's
Speaker 2:  out, right? I think Google's out just 'cause the, the stuff runs on OpenAI
Speaker 2:  stack and Google doesn't run that and they don't need more complication.
Speaker 2:  Google, if anything is trying to streamlined, right? Yeah. Microsoft is interesting.
Speaker 2:  Microsoft runs a bunch of OpenAI didn stuff. They don't have mobile. Right.
Speaker 2:  There's lots of rumors. I think Saachi Nadella is smarter
Speaker 2:  than this. That's frankly just my, my belief
Speaker 2:  there. I don't think he, I don't think he's like, yeah, we'll take a flyer
Speaker 2:  in this nonsense. He's they're winning. He's like,
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna take on the MacBook Air.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That I would put if of all the possibles Microsoft at the top. I just
Speaker 2:  think Nadella is smarter than this distraction. Samsung
Speaker 2:  loves bad unfocused ideas. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  They're, they're in the mix. Love goofy hardware. A bunch of
Speaker 2:  executives sitting around on Saturdays with nothing to do except do have
Speaker 2:  a deals.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They're, they're gonna see that, that, that story on Saturday and be
Speaker 6:  like,
Speaker 2:  Got it. Yep.
Speaker 5:  Can you imagine the humane team just being given Bali?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Right. Bali. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Go figure
Speaker 2:  Out Bali. Yeah. Just this now the laser projector rolls around.
Speaker 2:  Is that, is that something
Speaker 5:  I could actually see it and I, and Samsung, like smart things is always an
Speaker 5:  interesting version of that. Samsung actually a lot
Speaker 2:  Is the Humane band running smart things is like a
Speaker 2:  pure nightmare. Just no, it's gonna run absolute nightmare.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Agreed. But Samsung is,
Speaker 5:  has a history of
Speaker 5:  actually following through on pretty big acquisitions in a way that I think
Speaker 5:  could be interesting. I suspect the humane team would not be psyched
Speaker 5:  about working for Samsung. I don't, but that is the funniest possible
Speaker 5:  outcome.
Speaker 2:  Don't, don't, I'm stuck on Samsung as a history of following through app.
Speaker 2:  Have you used smart things, sir?
Speaker 5:  It's it's still there. That's that's
Speaker 2:  True. It's there. It's,
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 2:  Around, I would say for as much, as much as I talk about the Frame tv, the,
Speaker 2:  the people who run the frame, the services are the boxy people. 'cause Samsung
Speaker 2:  bought them a while back. Oh yeah.
Speaker 5:  Oh, boxy.
Speaker 2:  I'm not saying this is great.
Speaker 2:  I'm just saying it's, it's true that Samsung buys things and then the people
Speaker 2:  continue working there. Yeah. All right. So Sam, LG I think is the
Speaker 2:  same, right? If, if LG gets with, but they're not doing
Speaker 6:  Saturdays.
Speaker 2:  Right. But yeah, Samsung's ahead. 'cause they're in the office on Saturday.
Speaker 2:  But if LG gets a whiff that Samsung might do it, LG might buy it. LG famously
Speaker 2:  bought Web os So a history of betting on doomed
Speaker 2:  platforms and then turning them into television operating systems.
Speaker 2:  You could see the Humane
Speaker 6:  Cosmos.
Speaker 2:  What if your TV had a laser projector in it that projected under your hand
Speaker 2:  Pretty good. Amazon feels like a hard no.
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. That company is is bringing it's,
Speaker 2:  it's like getting smaller, not bigger.
Speaker 6:  Panos is running all of hardware now.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Oh yeah, yeah. Panos is there. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Panos is there. Like
Speaker 2:  Panos Pane is now Yeah. In charge of Amazon devices and services.
Speaker 6:  He, he's not gonna go and be like, yeah, let's, let's buy that and
Speaker 6:  integrate that into Amazon's tech stack.
Speaker 5:  If your question was, which of these companies is most likely to
Speaker 5:  ship something that resembles the AI pin in the next three years? I think
Speaker 5:  it might be Amazon. I would
Speaker 6:  Agree.
Speaker 5:  But I don't think Amazon would get to that point by
Speaker 5:  acquiring Humane.
Speaker 2:  No, my question is, who will spend a billion dollars on
Speaker 2:  Humane?
Speaker 5:  The answer to that is like Steve Mnuchin or something like
Speaker 2:  Some social now runs the ai. Exactly. I'm just saying
Speaker 2:  my list is Samsung, lg. If Samsung,
Speaker 2:  if they get a whiff of Saturday Samsung and then like
Speaker 2:  distant 5,000 place third
Speaker 2:  Microsoft. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I think that's probably right.
Speaker 2:  Agree. Who else has a billion dollars? Costco. It's Walmart.
Speaker 2:  I'm just thinking like the people that work at Oracle, who, who, who thought
Speaker 2:  about buying TikTok but would buy Humane instead.
Speaker 5:  It'll it'll end up being like Verizon or Comcast who's just like really
Speaker 5:  excited about a new they're they're gonna be like, this is your TV
Speaker 5:  remote. Yeah, yeah. On, on your lapel. And everybody's gonna be like, no,
Speaker 5:  thank
Speaker 2:  You. We're gonna, the idea of the humane design team
Speaker 2:  bringing that energy to launching like the next Fios remote.
Speaker 5:  It's beautiful.
Speaker 2:  It's very good. That's compelling. Just like, it's like on stage at
Speaker 2:  Ted being like, you can turn the volume up and down. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I do wanna know though, by the way, if, if you're listening and you have
Speaker 5:  an idea of a company that either might or should buy Humane,
Speaker 5:  tell us
Speaker 2:  Exxon
Speaker 5:  Vergecast at The Verge dot com. Call the hotline. Eight six six Virgin
Speaker 5:  one one. I genuinely wanna know. 'cause I bet there is an interesting
Speaker 5:  match or two that we're not thinking of, and I'd love to know what they are.
Speaker 5:  Ford. Ford. There you go. Drive your car with your
Speaker 5:  Oh no, it's gonna be, it's gonna be Elon Musk and it's gonna be Grok and
Speaker 5:  it's just gonna be the
Speaker 2:  Brock Hardware. Don't,
Speaker 6:  Don't summon that
Speaker 2:  Rough. All right. Rock bush. We'll see what happens. And
Speaker 2:  again, it's just a Bloomberg report. Humane itself has not said anything,
Speaker 2:  but I strongly suspect they need to get out the game. I also suspect Rabbit's
Speaker 2:  gonna end up in the same spot very soon.
Speaker 6:  All right. I I, I gotta do one more. I gotta do one more. Okay.
Speaker 6:  Apple,
Speaker 6:  you sometimes you get photos on your phone and you're like, that's that's
Speaker 6:  a terrible photo. You delete it or you're like, Ooh, that's too spicy to
Speaker 6:  keep here in case my mom sees my photos and you delete it. And there was
Speaker 6:  an unfortunate bug where those photos just popped back up
Speaker 6:  into people's things, into their phones and Apple said
Speaker 6:  nothing. But they corrected it just with the latest
Speaker 6:  os update. So you should no longer have reappearing nudes or
Speaker 6:  whatever else. And Apple has said nothing about that too.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's weird to confirm a bug like this by
Speaker 2:  issuing an iOS update and then saying nothing else. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. and they were like old. The, the, my understanding
Speaker 6:  is it's like not just, oh, a photo you deleted last night. It's like,
Speaker 5:  So people are getting like years old photos, right? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So, so that's, that's terrifying. But at the same time
Speaker 6:  with recall, I would've loved that. So I, I don't know where I stand on this,
Speaker 6:  but I do stand on like yeah, if I delete something, I generally want it
Speaker 6:  deleted. Do
Speaker 2:  You believe it's deleted, right? Yeah. Is it,
Speaker 6:  Is it actually gone? Yeah. Don't believe it's deleted. I want to know where
Speaker 6:  that data goes when I make a choice about it. And I think that's the difference
Speaker 6:  between recall and this. Like, recall, you will know where the da theoretically
Speaker 6:  where the data goes once the security researchers actually figure that out.
Speaker 6:  This we don't
Speaker 2:  Know. Big caveat.
Speaker 6:  Big caveat.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. This is weird. I I, I think, you know, we, we are part of our job
Speaker 2:  is holding big companies accountable and it is truly
Speaker 2:  irresponsible for Apple to not say why this happened and what they did
Speaker 2:  to fix it. There's a bunch of people on Reddit who love to argue with me
Speaker 2:  on threads who are like, we figured it out and you're overhyping this and
Speaker 2:  it doesn't matter because we didn't cause the bug. We didn't fix the
Speaker 2:  bug. It's great that you have a theory about why it happened. The
Speaker 2:  theory send wonderfully plausible I love it. I don't know what happened.
Speaker 2:  Right? There's, there's one party that knows what happened and they, they
Speaker 2:  should be accountable for their mistake. 'cause this is a big mistake and
Speaker 2:  it's weird that we give them a pass. Yep. And so, you know, we
Speaker 2:  can't force them to, all we can do is send emails. That's, that's the
Speaker 2:  sheriff Neli has got Mime Stream and he pushes that button
Speaker 2:  every day. Yep. That's all we can do. And we just can tell
Speaker 2:  you they have not responded to any of our emails or any of our phone calls
Speaker 2:  about this. And I think that's fundamentally irresponsible. Yeah. Because
Speaker 2:  you're, you're, you're playing with people's, like some of the most personally
Speaker 2:  that exists
Speaker 2:  anyway. Hopefully they say something soon and if not, I'll just keep sending
Speaker 2:  emails. What else is there to do? Yeah. In my
Speaker 2:  administration they would go straight to jail. Vote for tell.
Speaker 2:  Last one. I'm actually excited about this. Sonos, ACE headphones are out.
Speaker 2:  A shout out to Chris Welch who covers every square inch of the
Speaker 2:  Sonos beat to the point where I think Sonos like the Sonos,
Speaker 2:  Reddit like waits for Chris to come around and then like, Sonos itself is
Speaker 2:  just like, oh no, Chris is here. It's great. He's, he scooped the
Speaker 2:  headphones, obviously they look great. They're like a cross between
Speaker 2:  like the Sony vibe and an AirPods Max vibe. The four
Speaker 2:  $50 is expensive. The headline feature is, if you're watching TV
Speaker 2:  on a sono soundbar, you can push a button in the audio, come to your headphones.
Speaker 2:  I, I want this to be compelling to me. And I just, it's not my use case
Speaker 2:  for these things.
Speaker 6:  I think that's a really compelling If. you are married and you live in a
Speaker 6:  small home and you wanna stay up late playing video
Speaker 6:  games or you wanna stay up late watching tv.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Neli in his cavernous mansion wouldn't,
Speaker 6:  Wouldn't understand. Yeah. Neli, your house is just too big to fully appreciate
Speaker 6:  that
Speaker 2:  In his home theater. How often? No, it's not. It's the real time switching
Speaker 2:  that. I understand that sometimes you wanna watch TV and listen to headphones.
Speaker 2:  I, I got you. Yeah. But the part where you're like, well, I started with
Speaker 2:  the soundbar
Speaker 6:  Because they walk out of the room, they say, I'm going to bed and now you're
Speaker 6:  just like, boop. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Ah, yeah, I can see it. But that's a headline feature by the way. That feature
Speaker 2:  oddly is iOS only right now, soon coming to Android. Weird
Speaker 2:  special audio. A PTX If. you have Android as well?
Speaker 2:  No high res anywhere else? No. Why? It's Bluetooth
Speaker 2:  everywhere. Except if you're doing the weird TV
Speaker 2:  thing, probably for battery life. And then obviously
Speaker 2:  this all comes on the heels of the disastrous app launch,
Speaker 2:  which Sonos won't come out and say, but it feels very
Speaker 2:  obvious that they set the timing of the headphone launch. They needed the
Speaker 2:  app for the headphones. And so then the app came out before it was ready.
Speaker 2:  If any other sequence of events occurred to make the app come out before
Speaker 2:  it was ready, I would be shocked. I wish Sonos would just say it like Pat
Speaker 2:  Chris talked to Patrick Spence, CEO, Sonos, and he was like, well, the app
Speaker 2:  was just ready. And it's like, why don't you just say we put out the app
Speaker 2:  because the headphones are coming out. That would be fine. Or give people
Speaker 2:  a choice. Don't update the app yet,
Speaker 5:  Right? Yeah. Ship it as If, you buy the headphones, here's the new version
Speaker 5:  of our app. It's going to be rolled out to everybody before long. Like that's,
Speaker 5:  it's not a hard sequence of events to do. But
Speaker 5:  instead Sonos was like, oh, this doesn't have Q Management, which is what
Speaker 5:  everyone wants. Let's ship it Anyway.
Speaker 2:  So I don't actually, I have no problems with this app. I'm the only person
Speaker 2:  in America who has no problems with this app because we don't use the queue.
Speaker 2:  We use playlists. Our playlists are in Spotify and Apple Music.
Speaker 2:  And so like, whatever.
Speaker 5:  I just don't use the Sonos app. Same.
Speaker 2:  That's what I mean. Like Becky just uses Airplay Yeah. For our
Speaker 2:  Sonos. But it's fine. It is a little bit faster. I know
Speaker 2:  other people have wild problems. Like Casey Newton is like, I can't even
Speaker 2:  set the volume on my speakers anymore.
Speaker 5:  It's really bad. If, you have a local music collection that you care about
Speaker 5:  a lot too, which is like, and, and Chris and I talked about this a couple
Speaker 5:  weeks ago that like, those are the core Sonos people and have
Speaker 5:  been for two decades. Yeah. And Sonos just continues to try to
Speaker 5:  drive them away in very strange ways. Yeah. Headphones look sick though,
Speaker 5:  because
Speaker 6:  There's six of them.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, right. This is the classic story. The company is chasing the bigger
Speaker 2:  consumer market where the money is and the growth is. And then you've got
Speaker 2:  these like very passionate users who are like, my entire life is one
Speaker 2:  button an app from 2004 and we are the people in the red.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well, like you, you, there's, there's a dynamic there that I am
Speaker 2:  as a person who surprised, designed our website. I'm aware of the people
Speaker 2:  who were mad. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They've
Speaker 6:  Released apps before. Concurrently. They had, they had the two versions of
Speaker 6:  the
Speaker 2:  Lass of Death. No, that was a disaster.
Speaker 6:  It was horrible. But they had two.
Speaker 2:  No, that's a disa like Sonos. It's all bad now. Sonos is just bad. Well,
Speaker 2:  Patrick has been on the show a bunch of times. We've talked to him about
Speaker 2:  a lot of things. Everything from spatial audio and like how
Speaker 2:  they design speakers all the way to like antitrust. Like,
Speaker 2:  like he's been on the show. They have mismanaged in particular
Speaker 2:  these apps and what the apps do and how the apps work. Like the S
Speaker 2:  one to S two transition disaster. The Sonos, like,
Speaker 2:  we're gonna trade in your old speakers ever. And then like, we're gonna break
Speaker 2:  the old ones and they undid it. That was bad. Like there's this thing
Speaker 2:  that they're in particular not good at, which is wild. 'cause that's, and
Speaker 2:  they should get better at it.
Speaker 6:  The magic of Sonos is, is how it works with all your stuff. And
Speaker 6:  it just talks to each other. It's supposed to be super smart. And yet the
Speaker 6:  app continues to be kind of dumb.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And the, the, again, I I, I have not had I, because I don't
Speaker 2:  use some of these features, like, what was it, timers and alarm clocks are
Speaker 2:  broken in this app. And the idea that I would set my alarm clock using the
Speaker 2:  Sonos app is just what, but like If, you are the person who, but
Speaker 5:  A lot of people do. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. If you're the person whose alarm clock broke, like you are mad. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's a problem. Right? Like, you should find a way
Speaker 2:  to be like, okay, these core features, there's some of these core features
Speaker 2:  where people just like build their lives. Like alarm clocks are, people build
Speaker 2:  their lives around it. You, you have to respect it. And like in
Speaker 2:  this case, I think Sonos says they've gotten more and more consumer,
Speaker 2:  they've sort of like gotten away from it and they should just recalibrate
Speaker 2:  that a little bit. That said, I have like 9,000 Sonos speakers. Like I'm
Speaker 2:  trapped in this ecosystem. What you can do, it's fine.
Speaker 2:  All right. I think that's it. That's it. David, do you have another one?
Speaker 5:  Nope, that's it. We're done.
Speaker 2:  All right. We gotta
Speaker 5:  Wrap this thing. Spotify has a font,
Speaker 2:  Spotify has a font.
Speaker 5:  That's all that's I have. I have, that's all the information I have for you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  They might, Amazon might make you pay for Alexa once they add AI too. It's
Speaker 2:  like, that's kinda stuff. Yeah. The big thing is that I'm gonna go try to
Speaker 2:  call Scarlet Johanson now and see if she will voice
Speaker 2:  verges ai. Yeah. As revenge.
Speaker 6:  Do like AI calling Jos to call her.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I will say a friend of mine was like, Google should just
Speaker 2:  take this voice now. They should just pay her whatever amount of money she
Speaker 2:  wants now. Yeah. If there's like an arms race for
Speaker 2:  celebrity AI voices, I would be, that would be very entertaining. Alright,
Speaker 2:  that's it. Also, my voice is available for cheaper than Scarlett Johansen's.
Speaker 2:  In case you're wondering, it's hard to
Speaker 5:  Reproduce. It's the most expensive. Like who do you, is it, is it like, I
Speaker 5:  feel like it's either like Scarlett Johansen or Ryan Reynolds. This is whole
Speaker 5:  Jones. We could do no way in terms of like, no, James Earl Jones.
Speaker 6:  James Earl Jones, Mufasa, and Darcy.
Speaker 5:  It's important to everyone that I remind you that Alex Kranz is 66 years
Speaker 5:  old.
Speaker 5:  And if you've never heard of any of those words that she just said, don't
Speaker 5:  worry. They all
Speaker 6:  Know who that is.
Speaker 2:  I mean, aren't there, there's like Amazon, isn't Amazon set the mark? I guess
Speaker 2:  the rates are gone higher, but yeah, this is a thing that exists. You can
Speaker 2:  just buy other voices from Amazon, right?
Speaker 6:  Yep. You can.
Speaker 2:  Alright. Send us your notes with who you think the most expensive voice would
Speaker 2:  be. I don't want to, I don't. We will read. We will read your ideas.
Speaker 6:  Everyone's gonna agree with me. It's fine.
Speaker 2:  It's David at The Verge dot com everybody. All right. That's it. That's The
Speaker 2:  Verge test, rock and roll.
Speaker 3:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 3:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one. One. The Vergecast
Speaker 3:  is the production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is
Speaker 3:  produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.