# Transcript
ID: cea84c36-f2fb-43be-8520-72e6a03775bc
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/513336866313696731/-4064009453844022791/s93290-US-4534s-1732491713.mp3
Description: Richard Lawler joins the show to chat about the Tyson / Paul fight, and more importantly the fact that Netflix didn't seem to be able to keep up. As live sports — and TV in general — move toward streaming, are even the biggest names in tech ready for what's coming? After that, Roland Allen, the author of The Notebook: A History of Thinking on Paper, tells us about the history of the notebook, and why we've been writing things down about our lives for centuries. Even in a digital world, Allen argues, you just can't beat the notebook. Finally, a question from the Vergecast Hotline sends producer Will Poor down a TikTok Shop rabbit hole.
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the Bullet Journal Method.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend David Pierce, and I am sitting here on a
Speaker 2:  weekday buying candy on TikTok. Like, I
Speaker 2:  don't know how this happened, but suddenly my algorithm is just absolutely
Speaker 2:  overrun by freeze dried Skittles, which are a
Speaker 2:  thing you can buy. And there's like a sour coated
Speaker 2:  gushers thing that everybody's really excited about. But the biggest thing
Speaker 2:  that's happening all over TikTok is Swedish candy. There are these things
Speaker 2:  called bubs. They're little like skulls that are
Speaker 2:  massively popular. People are so excited about them, they sell out like crazy.
Speaker 2:  There's this company called Bon Bon that has absolutely blown up
Speaker 2:  on TikTok. There's something happening inside of Candy Talk
Speaker 2:  and I can't figure out what it is. I can't figure out how it works where
Speaker 2:  all these companies and people are getting this candy from and repackaging
Speaker 2:  it and selling it to people. But I'm now deep down this rabbit hole.
Speaker 2:  I bought candy on a TikTok live stream last night while I was
Speaker 2:  walking my dog. It's a real thing that happened and I bought it on the stream
Speaker 2:  and the guy was like, oh, oh David, thanks for your order. I'm gonna give
Speaker 2:  you extra sour powder because you ordered on the live stream. And I was
Speaker 2:  like really excited for a long time that this was a thing that
Speaker 2:  had happened to me. It's coming in two to four days, apparently.
Speaker 2:  Is it anything? Is it food? Did I order it from an actual
Speaker 2:  company? I literally have no idea. That's the TikTok shop, but it's
Speaker 2:  possible there is going to be an alarming amount of candy coming to my
Speaker 2:  house very soon. And frankly, that's great news. Anyway,
Speaker 2:  we are not here to talk about Kand. I have a feeling I will be talking more
Speaker 2:  about Kand over time, but not today. Today we're gonna do two things. First,
Speaker 2:  we're gonna talk about the Jake Paul, Mike Tyson fight on Netflix.
Speaker 2:  I don't really care about the fight, but I care a lot about what it means
Speaker 2:  that Netflix had this massively popular event
Speaker 2:  and it didn't go great. And Netflix has some more massively popular events
Speaker 2:  about to happen. And we're also just at a really interesting moment in the
Speaker 2:  sports streaming world where if Netflix can't do it, can anyone,
Speaker 2:  we're gonna talk about it. Also, I'm gonna talk to Roland Allen who
Speaker 2:  wrote a book about the history of notebooks. And actually
Speaker 2:  what he wrote is a history of civilization told through The
Speaker 2:  Notebook. He makes a really fun case for why pen and paper has been
Speaker 2:  so important in history, why it's so important now, and why even in
Speaker 2:  an increasingly digital world, writing things down in a notebook is not going
Speaker 2:  away. Super fun. We also have a hotline question that we're gonna get into
Speaker 2:  that sent our producer will pour down kind of a wild rabbit hole
Speaker 2:  of, again, the TikTok shop. It's a weird world out there. All that is coming
Speaker 2:  up in just a second. But first. I've now been staring at these freeze dried
Speaker 2:  Skittles for too long and I'm gonna buy them.
Speaker 2:  Wish me luck. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. All right, so Friday night,
Speaker 2:  Jake Paul, Mike Tyson. It both was and
Speaker 2:  was not the fight of the year. I don't know
Speaker 2:  anything or particularly care about boxing if I'm completely honest with
Speaker 2:  you. But the thing I heard from everybody is that actually the undercard,
Speaker 2:  all the fights that were before the main fight was great. Lots of good fights.
Speaker 2:  But then Jake Paul versus Mike Tyson, eh, I mean, it was
Speaker 2:  like a YouTuber versus a man in his late fifties. I don't really know
Speaker 2:  what anybody expected, but that is the fight that we got. Anyway,
Speaker 2:  I think the more interesting story here has less to do with that fight
Speaker 2:  itself and more to do with how things went on Netflix
Speaker 2:  and what it says about what Netflix is ready for as it tries to take
Speaker 2:  over live TV and what the whole streaming industry is ready for.
Speaker 2:  Lots to talk about. There's lots of this stuff left to come. The tests keep
Speaker 2:  coming for these companies. So figured it was a good time to check in and
Speaker 2:  nobody better to do it with than Richard Lawler. Richard, hello.
Speaker 4:  Hey,
Speaker 2:  I just saw you the other day. This was very exciting.
Speaker 4:  We were in person and you understood that I exist outside this room.
Speaker 2:  I did. It's useful to be reminded of that every once in a while, but not
Speaker 2:  like for too long. I think we got about the right amount of time near each
Speaker 2:  other. This this is, this is good. Yep. All right. So
Speaker 2:  first question, did you watch the fight on Friday?
Speaker 4:  I did not watch the fight because doing anything else was a better choice.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean I, I would say, as it turns out, that is largely correct.
Speaker 2:  It is a real bummer that this whole thing was not about a sport. I enjoy
Speaker 2:  more than boxing between YouTubers and old men. But
Speaker 2:  I last here we are
Speaker 4:  As, as I said on social media, if I wanted to see a YouTuber fight an old
Speaker 4:  man, I would just go punch a YouTuber.
Speaker 4:  I can put that fight on myself right now.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's a beautiful thing. If, you walk outside, I'm sure someone is filming
Speaker 2:  a TikTok and you can just punch them in the face and, and here we are and
Speaker 2:  apparently 60 million people will watch it. If. you do. But I think the,
Speaker 2:  the reason I wanted to talk to you about this is we've talked a lot over
Speaker 2:  the last couple of years about basically the question is
Speaker 2:  streaming ready for sports? And it's been, it's been
Speaker 2:  coming, it's been happening. Amazon is kind of making it work with
Speaker 2:  football, but like the NFL is is the thing, right? And every streaming
Speaker 2:  platform wants the NFL. A bunch of them have gotten it. Netflix is gonna
Speaker 2:  have it on Christmas day. And I think to me, the
Speaker 2:  single most surprising thing that happened this weekend was that Netflix
Speaker 2:  was not ready for this fight.
Speaker 4:  You'd think they would've been, right? They have the data, they know how
Speaker 4:  many customers they have. They know how many people were interested in this
Speaker 4:  fight. They know how heavily they promoted it. They know that there wasn't
Speaker 4:  really anything else to do on Friday night, it felt like. And still
Speaker 4:  they were surprised somehow. They just weren't ready for the moment.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. A and am I crazy for thinking that if anyone should be able to
Speaker 2:  do this just from a pure technical deliver, the
Speaker 2:  bits in high quality to people perspective, it ought to be Netflix.
Speaker 4:  You'd think so, but delivering things live is very different. And I think
Speaker 4:  that's what we found basically. Every time there's a massive event and every
Speaker 4:  time we've had these Super Bowls streaming now for years that they've, they've
Speaker 4:  been available on the internet each and every time. It's just a little bit
Speaker 4:  glitchier than you'd expect. Yeah. Even though they know how many people
Speaker 4:  are going to tune in. Because it's hard because delivering these things with
Speaker 4:  milliseconds and just fractions of a second of delay is
Speaker 4:  difficult. Like, like you can cache the streams and videos and If, you
Speaker 4:  have a new series, you can put your little devices in every, every, everyone's
Speaker 4:  nearby ISP and you could put it very close to them and have it preloaded.
Speaker 4:  You can't do that with live. It just doesn't work.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And it, it's starting to make me wonder if it is
Speaker 2:  technically speaking right now, just an unsolvable problem. 'cause like you
Speaker 2:  said, I think If, you go rewind away, like Game of Thrones
Speaker 2:  had streaming issues and there were a bunch of ways that these companies
Speaker 2:  could and did solve them, right? And like you don't hear that
Speaker 2:  anymore from these sort of big event HBO
Speaker 2:  style shows anymore. Like the, everybody logged onto HBO at
Speaker 2:  nine o'clock on a Sunday night and couldn't watch their show. I have not
Speaker 2:  heard that in years. We just fixed that. But
Speaker 2:  there is something about trying to do this live and just literally like the
Speaker 2:  physical infrastructure of making all of that happen that we're
Speaker 2:  very good at with linear television and they've been doing it for decades
Speaker 2:  and they have trucks and it's a whole thing. And I, I'm starting to wonder
Speaker 2:  if we just haven't developed the over the
Speaker 2:  internet pieces of this in such a way that it's gonna work.
Speaker 4:  I think the main issue is just that the internet wasn't made to work like
Speaker 4:  that. And we're kind of tacking things on and we're make, creating these
Speaker 4:  solutions to work around a problem that the internet was never designed to
Speaker 4:  solve. Something that we talked about last year, but that still hasn't really
Speaker 4:  arisen is L four s, which was supposed to help the latency issue so that
Speaker 4:  when you send a packet and it really needs to get to, to someone on time,
Speaker 4:  that is the first one to get there. And there's so many other strategies
Speaker 4:  that I think these companies have done to try and make sure that when people
Speaker 4:  are streaming, it's not getting bogged down. It's not getting clogged at
Speaker 4:  the various choke points, but it still does. You've got how many
Speaker 4:  different devices you've got, how many different bit rates you've got, how
Speaker 4:  many different encodings and DRM protection and all of these other things
Speaker 4:  that you're putting on top of this that make it that much harder to stream
Speaker 4:  a live event. And it's just not a problem that we solved yet. And I guess
Speaker 4:  on Christmas day, we're going to get another opportunity to see how close
Speaker 4:  Netflix is.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well I think I, I've been making fun of Netflix
Speaker 2:  for like 48 hours now because they put out that statement on Saturday
Speaker 2:  that was basically like, we think we did a great job
Speaker 2:  after a whole evening and day of people online
Speaker 2:  being like, this looks awful. I can't see anything.
Speaker 2:  This is just like a 1980s pixelated
Speaker 2:  monstrosity of a picture. Yeah. And then Netflix is like, you know what?
Speaker 2:  We did it. And I've kind of come around for all the reasons that you're saying.
Speaker 2:  I'm like, honestly, maybe this is literally the best Netflix could have done.
Speaker 2:  And to some extent that might be more alarming as we think about where we're
Speaker 2:  going. But maybe Netflix is not out of its
Speaker 2:  mind to think it actually did this about as well as it could have.
Speaker 4:  I I can definitely see why they would have that perspective. What's
Speaker 4:  interesting is like I'm hearing from people over, you know, I was watching
Speaker 4:  a stream of someone pointing their phone at the TV on TikTok
Speaker 4:  and live streaming it. 'cause the Netflix stream was 45 minutes behind, right?
Speaker 4:  And so it's like, it can be done, you can get live video
Speaker 4:  that people actually watch as long as, you know, 60 million people aren't
Speaker 4:  tuning into this particular stream at the moment.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. There is a, there is a magic number at which it all kind of falls apart.
Speaker 2:  And I'm very curious, this is part of the reason I'm, I'm interested in
Speaker 2:  these Christmas football games because Netflix has these two games on Christmas
Speaker 2:  for the first time. They're both actually gonna be really good games. As
Speaker 2:  it turns out, they're, they're like some of the best teams in the
Speaker 2:  NFL. It's gonna be very exciting. It's Christmas day. Lots of people are
Speaker 2:  gonna watch, it seems unlikely that it's gonna be 60 million people
Speaker 2:  on either game. But like, let's say it's, let's say it's 30,
Speaker 2:  we're gonna get such an interesting test case of at what
Speaker 2:  point have we just hit the capacity of all of this infrastructure.
Speaker 2:  And there's also just not that much time. Like Netflix can't fix the internet
Speaker 2:  between now and Christmas Day. So to some extent, I assume there
Speaker 2:  will be lots of things it can learn, but it's not like it can rebuild its
Speaker 2:  whole data delivery system between now and Christmas in order
Speaker 2:  to get these football games. Right. So, I feel like we're gonna get a totally
Speaker 2:  different but very similar test.
Speaker 4:  And I, I think that's a big part of, it's just that you aren't dealing with
Speaker 4:  just one problem or just one problem in just one place. You have many people
Speaker 4:  in diff many different places. You have different issues. You have,
Speaker 4:  oh, the network's bad here or we don't have the, the backend
Speaker 4:  node connecting close enough to this many people who are all trying to stream
Speaker 4:  it. You have different kinds of demand in different places. What if it's
Speaker 4:  good in most places, but it's not good in Baltimore. Like, Baltimore's playing
Speaker 4:  away at this Texans game. And if it's just bad in one city,
Speaker 4:  that is millions of people who are going to be very upset with Netflix.
Speaker 4:  Beyonce fans not always ready,
Speaker 4:  ready If you are going to cause problems for them to watch. Their favorite
Speaker 4:  could be an issue. We're gonna, we're gonna find out what happens. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So speaking of Beyonce, let's talk about this. 'cause the, the news on Monday
Speaker 2:  was that Beyonce is going to be doing the halftime show at, at one of
Speaker 2:  these games. Is that
Speaker 4:  Right? Yes. It's the second game between the, the Ravens and the Texans.
Speaker 4:  Okay. 'cause it's in Houston, she's from Houston. Natural synergy.
Speaker 2:  That makes sense. But like, it's Beyonce, right? Like I would I would say
Speaker 2:  in terms of like who you could announce as your halftime performer, that's
Speaker 2:  about as big as it gets, right? Like that's, it's Beyonce. And so
Speaker 2:  to me it's like, if you've ever wondered how serious Netflix is about doing
Speaker 2:  this, Beyonce is the answer, right? Like this,
Speaker 2:  this company is not kidding. And I think Jake Paul and Mike Tyson, you can
Speaker 2:  be like, oh, this is like slightly interesting, but also like
Speaker 2:  slightly silliness. Two football games is like cool, but whatever. But
Speaker 2:  like, it's, it's Beyonce, Richard, they got Beyonce.
Speaker 4:  There are millions of people who will not miss that. Exactly. This is gonna
Speaker 4:  be probably their first time to be able to see the songs off of her new album.
Speaker 4:  It it just, there are a lot of things that are lining up. They are going
Speaker 4:  to be ready, they're going to be prepared for this and Netflix has to deliver.
Speaker 2:  What do you make of this from Netflix? Netflix is clearly like all in now
Speaker 2:  on sports after you and I have spent years on this show talking about how
Speaker 2:  Netflix was very happy to not be in live sports. They did the Drive to
Speaker 2:  Survive thing. They were like, we're gonna make the sort of ancillary content
Speaker 2:  around games. We don't need to compete in this. Netflix has been saying this,
Speaker 2:  it feels like this company has done a total 180 and is now like we have to
Speaker 2:  figure out how to do live and that means sports. Does this make sense to
Speaker 2:  you?
Speaker 4:  The thing I'm not sure about is how far they'll go into live, because I think
Speaker 4:  that at least in one way it kind of serves them. How do we keep people from
Speaker 4:  not canceling Netflix? And one of the answers is we have a huge event every
Speaker 4:  few months. So that every time you start thinking, man, you know what? I
Speaker 4:  haven't watching Netflix in a while. Do I still need this subscription? Then
Speaker 4:  Beyonce's on there and you're like, yep. Can't cancel yet. Fair.
Speaker 2:  That gives me Yeah, that's true. Like you need to basically have one of those
Speaker 2:  at least announced every month so that I'm like, okay, well
Speaker 2:  I'll keep it until then. And then like the day after Christmas, they're gonna
Speaker 2:  announce the next thing for February or whatever. And then that'll, that'll
Speaker 2:  be that. We,
Speaker 4:  We grew up with HBO and Showtime playing this game with boxing, with
Speaker 4:  music, with all of these things our entire lives growing up in the
Speaker 4:  nineties, it's the same playbook.
Speaker 2:  You know, what you just made me realize is they're definitely going to announce
Speaker 2:  the Stranger Things debut of some kind the
Speaker 2:  day after Christmas. And that's gonna, that's, that's how we get there for
Speaker 2:  sure. Yeah. It,
Speaker 4:  It it just rolls in and on itself. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Exactly. Do you think Netflix has moves in sports here? Like is this, are
Speaker 2:  you at all as a sports fan interested in what's coming here?
Speaker 4:  Not really. I, I just, I, I wonder what,
Speaker 4:  what they can do, but they have enough money that it kind of doesn't matter
Speaker 4:  because they can get enough events. If they can sign up, say the NBA Cup
Speaker 4:  or whoever, if if they have enough money, people will create events for them
Speaker 4:  to host Jake Paul versus Mike Tyson. They said, how can we get
Speaker 4:  Generation Z, generation X and millennials all to watch the same thing at
Speaker 4:  the same time? Got it. And they'll just, they'll just find something else.
Speaker 4:  They will, they will create something. They tried the hotdog competition.
Speaker 4:  I don't think that really attracts all that much in attention. That seemed
Speaker 4:  to go off pretty well without Glitches. Their reality show was the first
Speaker 4:  one that had huge problems. And I think they did the comedy thing that didn't
Speaker 4:  work all that well. But you know, it's been kind of up and down. So it's
Speaker 4:  hard to have these hits, but they're just gonna keep looking. They're gonna
Speaker 4:  keep digging. They're, they've got the checkbook ready to spend
Speaker 2:  Clearly. And I think the thing I've been trying to figure out is
Speaker 2:  whether I want one of these streaming services to really
Speaker 2:  try and reinvent the wheel. Because I think, like you look at
Speaker 2:  Amazon, which has been doing Thursday night football for a couple of years
Speaker 2:  now. It just is football. Amazon has
Speaker 2:  like a couple of interesting stats ideas, but they're even
Speaker 2:  like doing that in a sponsored way on other networks. Like that's just a
Speaker 2:  whole separate thing. But it's like, it's, it's Al Michaels, it is like the
Speaker 2:  most straightforward down the middle old school kind of
Speaker 2:  football game. and we haven't seen a Netflix football game, but
Speaker 2:  I would assume it's gonna be very much the same thing. Peacock is now
Speaker 2:  streaming Sunday night football, but it's just taking a tv streaming and
Speaker 2:  turning it into streaming. So part of me is like, somebody needs to take
Speaker 2:  this and like blow up the whole concept of what it might be
Speaker 2:  and give us new ways of looking at stuff and change the cameras and make
Speaker 2:  it more interactive and whatever else. YouTube with Sunday ticket. Another
Speaker 2:  example, like YouTube Sunday ticket is just Sunday ticket. It's just Sunday
Speaker 2:  ticket. It's just Sunday ticket. And that's fine, but it's part of me is
Speaker 2:  like, what's the next thing? And then the other part of me is like, well
Speaker 2:  maybe let's spend our time making sure the thing works and then give it a
Speaker 2:  few years and we will worry about actually putting this out there.
Speaker 4:  I think that that is the, the big question here. Because what I think what
Speaker 4:  people want is not personalization. It is the same thing but better because
Speaker 4:  that's one thing that, that has been pushed out there. Oh, you'll be able
Speaker 4:  to get your personalized stream. You'll be able to get exactly what you want.
Speaker 4:  Maybe you'll be able to tune into whatever camera you want. But what works
Speaker 4:  better is when we're all watching the same thing at the same time. Like Paul
Speaker 4:  versus Tyson, which creates a spectacle which creates a, I can't miss this
Speaker 4:  and it's not personal, it's together and that is better. And you
Speaker 4:  don't need like a fake auditorium of people. You just need an event that
Speaker 4:  people want to watch. You don't need avatars, you don't need 3D you don't
Speaker 4:  need any of those things. You don't even need a good fight.
Speaker 2:  What you're saying is If, you had picked the other camera, you wouldn't have
Speaker 2:  seen Mike Tyson's bare ass and that would've been a problem for you. It
Speaker 4:  Would If you could've all avoided that. It just, it would've been a choice
Speaker 4:  if, if we had all been able to avoid that. But apparently that wasn't what
Speaker 4:  the people voted for. 60 million people went the other way. So listen,
Speaker 4:  we are wrong.
Speaker 2:  Netflix knows what people want. Richard, like let's be honest with each other.
Speaker 2:  That was not, they
Speaker 4:  Have the analytics,
Speaker 2:  My conspiracy theory says that was completely deliberate. And and it is,
Speaker 2:  it is just to juice views. You gotta get 'em how you can. Every we, this
Speaker 2:  is the world we live in, Richard. It's fine.
Speaker 4:  Next Virgin Cast is gonna be very interesting.
Speaker 2:  Listen, it's, it's Q4. I'll do what I gotta do.
Speaker 2:  So how are you feeling as a, as a streaming sports fan right now? This is
Speaker 2:  like, this is a fun time to do this. 'cause we're, we're in the middle of
Speaker 2:  the NBA season. We're in the middle of the NFL season. The NNHL has started.
Speaker 2:  College basketball is going college football is peaking. It's like, this
Speaker 2:  is the best part of the year. If all you wanna watch is sports,
Speaker 2:  and yet I feel like my sports watching life is
Speaker 2:  more chaotic and more expensive than ever. I tried to watch the Bill's
Speaker 2:  chiefs game on Sunday night and literally couldn't. I went through 10 services
Speaker 2:  and I was like, oh, I just don't have this game somehow. And I feel like
Speaker 2:  you feel my pain on this. As somebody who also likes to watch esoteric sports
Speaker 2:  that you're not allowed to watch, that
Speaker 4:  Is the greatest thing. Like, oh, oh, your, your team is playing. You pay
Speaker 4:  for maybe three packages already to watch this particular
Speaker 4:  sport. And you find out, wait, I don't have the one that has this game still
Speaker 4:  somehow I'm maybe better than last year because the local
Speaker 4:  monopoly that controls Pistons streaming, they're still bad.
Speaker 4:  Still a monopoly. They're named after a different gambling company now. Sure.
Speaker 4:  But at least it works. So when I give them my money to watch the Pistons,
Speaker 4:  I can actually watch the game sometimes. And then I'm paying for League Pass
Speaker 4:  So, I'm, and I'm paying for my local team subscription. But then if the game
Speaker 4:  is on national TV, on ESPN, if, if I'm not paying for, you know, a, a
Speaker 4:  cable package, can't get it or I can't get the good TNT
Speaker 4:  stream, I can get the league past TNT stream, which, you know, with no announcers
Speaker 4:  and whatnot. And it's just like, wait, how is this better than cable? Because
Speaker 4:  I used to just have cable and it was like, okay, So I pay this much and I
Speaker 4:  know that I'll be able to see the game. Maybe it'll be on a different channel
Speaker 4:  or whatever, but I will be able to turn on my TV and the game will come in
Speaker 4:  and I don't have to log in and log out and have glitches and have the same
Speaker 4:  ad three times a row.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I remember years ago having sort of the, the mental
Speaker 2:  rubric of like, okay, if it's a good game, it's gonna be on this channel.
Speaker 2:  If it's a nah game, it's gonna be on this channel. And if literally no one
Speaker 2:  cares because both teams are trash, they'll just put it over here. And I
Speaker 2:  knew the number of all of those channels and So I could find the game in
Speaker 2:  30 seconds no matter what. And now it's literally like I went on, I went,
Speaker 2:  I was on sling watching Red Zone because Sling still has Red Zone for reasons
Speaker 2:  I don't completely understand. I sling doesn't have CBS. So
Speaker 2:  when RedZone only got down to one game, I didn't have it there anymore. I
Speaker 2:  went to,
Speaker 2:  I went to YouTube tv, which had it, but my
Speaker 2:  access had turned off because I forgot to pay it. That that one's probably
Speaker 2:  on me. But then I went over to
Speaker 2:  every streaming service I could think of being like, which one has CBS. And
Speaker 2:  by the time I realized it was Paramount Plus, which sure, that's the one
Speaker 2:  with CBSI had, it was over and I had
Speaker 2:  to go in and find my Paramount plus password because who uses Paramount Plus
Speaker 2:  and it was just a hold and I was like, I will pay you just to watch the last
Speaker 2:  five minutes of this game. I couldn't do it, wouldn't, wouldn't let me devastating.
Speaker 4:  And, and as I said, back in the day, I just knew three channel numbers. That
Speaker 4:  was all I needed to know. I didn't have to figure a whole bunch of things
Speaker 4:  out. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Do you have any sense of whether this is gonna get better? You and I haven't
Speaker 2:  talked about venue sports in a while. This supposed like
Speaker 2:  smushing together of all these different companies rights.
Speaker 4:  Well that depends on what happens on the, the courts if they ever actually
Speaker 4:  get to launch or whatever they do or, and if it would be any good, if it
Speaker 4:  actually did exist, which will we ever find out?
Speaker 4:  We do not know.
Speaker 4:  Also, I think there's some interesting things going on because Amazon, for
Speaker 4:  example, like with the NBAI think in 2025 could be very interesting because
Speaker 4:  Amazon is gonna have a lot of NBA games directly. They also own
Speaker 4:  a share of the, whatever it's called now, FanDuel Sports
Speaker 4:  Networks that have some of these local broadcast rights. And in my area,
Speaker 4:  oh, I didn't know that has the local broadcast rights. So maybe they can
Speaker 4:  package it together. So, I can just use one app to watch most of
Speaker 4:  the games. Unfortunately, the Pistons might be good and then they'll be on
Speaker 4:  national TV and I'll have to pay even more to watch more games. So just problems
Speaker 4:  on top of problems.
Speaker 2:  Well, at that point then you have to pay for ESPN's
Speaker 2:  multitude of streaming services. It's part of venue. It has ESPN plus is
Speaker 2:  the, what's it called? Flagship, right? That's the thing that's supposed
Speaker 2:  to just be ES, ESPN on the internet that's supposedly launching next year.
Speaker 2:  Like in a funny way, we were having conversations
Speaker 2:  a few years ago about how a bunch of really old
Speaker 2:  rights deals were slowing everything down, right? 'cause they had all been
Speaker 2:  signed a decade ago. They were, they were really focused on
Speaker 2:  broadcast TV in particular. And so the idea that this stuff could be
Speaker 2:  streamed and available widely didn't really exist. Now it feels like basically
Speaker 2:  all of those deals have turned over. I think the NBA is probably the last
Speaker 2:  one to turn over. Yeah. And that starts next year. Big streaming
Speaker 2:  shift. Like you said, Amazon's a big player now a lot of stuff is moving
Speaker 2:  to ESPN, which is doing a lot of streaming stuff. And now it feels like the
Speaker 2:  holdup is the platforms which can't figure out how to launch. They
Speaker 2:  can't figure out what they're supposed to charge. They can't figure out how
Speaker 2:  to serve this stuff to this many people. Like we should be in a moment
Speaker 2:  where some streamer is like, we are going to exclusively stream the
Speaker 2:  Super Bowl and it's gonna be fine. Netflix should be able to do that. There
Speaker 2:  are more people in America who have Netflix than anything else.
Speaker 2:  Like this should be possible. And yet it isn't. And everyone knows
Speaker 2:  it's not possible. So we're in a, we're in a weird moment now where the problem
Speaker 2:  we used to have is no longer the problem. And it's making very obvious this
Speaker 2:  new problem that we have, which is that none of the platforms are ready for
Speaker 2:  this.
Speaker 4:  It turns out that the problem is money and certain companies have lots of
Speaker 4:  it and they're willing to spend it. So the leagues are gonna chase it in
Speaker 4:  however they, they can. And what the leagues have found is that playing the
Speaker 4:  networks off of each other or now the platforms off of each other and the
Speaker 4:  networks and the various intermingling of those is the way to
Speaker 4:  get the highest bids to make the most money. And so now we're in
Speaker 4:  for another 10 years or so of, of switching and swapping between
Speaker 4:  apps.
Speaker 2:  I really hate how aggressively I'm starting to root for Amazon
Speaker 2:  because I, I think you're right that Amazon has this big idea of being
Speaker 2:  like the one that puts it all together. And
Speaker 2:  I think in theory, ESPN wants to be that and is doing
Speaker 2:  some interesting stuff along those lines, but Disney just doesn't have the
Speaker 2:  money to do that. But basically like the companies that could just
Speaker 2:  buy all the sports rights, it's just kind of Amazon and Apple. And
Speaker 2:  Apple, I don't think is, is interested in playing that particular sports
Speaker 2:  game, but Amazon like
Speaker 2:  it, it could get as much as it wants, right? Like it can afford all of of
Speaker 2:  it. And so they have
Speaker 4:  The scale, they also have the scale to deliver. Yeah. As bad as their apps
Speaker 4:  tend to be, they can actually deliver a live stream. And AWS does exist.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Thursday night football works. It's not as big as these. Like I would be
Speaker 2:  interested to see 60 million people try to watch Prime video, right? Like,
Speaker 2:  again, it's, there is a, there is a matter of scale that we just haven't
Speaker 2:  seen on streaming work anywhere yet. But,
Speaker 2:  but yeah, I feel like if if someone were going to give us the dream
Speaker 2:  back, it's probably gonna be Amazon, which I makes, I hate saying
Speaker 2:  that out loud. Even just that, that felt bad, that I'm like, gosh, I hope
Speaker 2:  Amazon wins TV because that would be terrific.
Speaker 3:  But it kind of feels like it.
Speaker 4:  That's how dark the future has gotten. We're looking at Amazon and saying,
Speaker 4:  save us.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Andy Jasi, it's all up to you.
Speaker 2:  Oh, brother. So what, what have you seen this year that gives you hope?
Speaker 2:  Let's end on a high note here. I wanna just say, we haven't talked about
Speaker 2:  this on the show in a long time. I thought peacock crushed the Olympics when
Speaker 2:  it comes to sports streaming. The thing that I was like, okay, internet sports
Speaker 2:  TV is gonna be cool, was Peacock in the Olympics,
Speaker 2:  all the sports, all the different ways to navigate. They had the gold zone
Speaker 2:  thing, they had the primetime thing. Like that was great. And I
Speaker 2:  don't know how replicable that is for other sports, but like, I, that to
Speaker 2:  me was when it was like, okay, the streaming era of sports might be great.
Speaker 4:  It was there, it worked. The streams were consistent, the quality was high.
Speaker 4:  I didn't feel like I was way behind. I didn't have to feel, I didn't feel
Speaker 4:  like I, I had to watch a bunch of things that I didn't want to. It it,
Speaker 4:  I, I, I got a lot that I wanted there. There were some things that could've
Speaker 4:  been better. I felt like, you know, when you were navigating through like
Speaker 4:  archive defense, when you wanted to watch something that already aired, it
Speaker 4:  was harder than it needed to be. Yes. But I felt like they also made some
Speaker 4:  concessions perhaps to, to make the viewing experience a little bit better.
Speaker 4:  Like If, you If you jumped out of something and you jumped back in all. Okay,
Speaker 4:  so the ad doesn't play just again, the way that we've seen in previous years
Speaker 4:  and on other platforms. Yeah, and I
Speaker 4:  think there's some push and pull because I understand, hey, this platform
Speaker 4:  needs to make money from this event. Got it. But I just want
Speaker 4:  to watch it. I paid for it. Yeah, I would like to watch it. Give me that.
Speaker 4:  And, and they kind of, they kind of crossed that bar and that's where
Speaker 4:  everyone else should be aiming at. At the minimum,
Speaker 2:  You're a simple man with simple needs. Richard, just show me the thing that
Speaker 2:  I have clicked on, please.
Speaker 3:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. All right, Richard, thank you as always.
Speaker 4:  Thank you.
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and we're
Speaker 2:  gonna talk about notebooks. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So a few weeks ago I started reading this book called The
Speaker 2:  Notebook A History of Thinking on Paper by a guy named Roland Allen. And
Speaker 2:  it traces like a thousand years of history
Speaker 2:  of how people write on paper. He makes this
Speaker 2:  big case, that paper is this incredibly
Speaker 2:  critical invention in the history of the world. And that actually
Speaker 2:  without paper, without notebooks, we wouldn't have modern capitalism.
Speaker 2:  We wouldn't know nearly as much about history as we do that actually
Speaker 2:  a lot of the world that we live in is defined by
Speaker 2:  the way that people wrote stuff down and what they wrote stuff down on. He
Speaker 2:  tells a whole history of notebooks all the way through the
Speaker 2:  Renaissance and all the way up to now. And even in the future,
Speaker 2:  If, you listen to the show, you know that I love note taking apps. I love
Speaker 2:  thinking about how people write stuff down. I think the systems for all this
Speaker 2:  are fascinating. And this book was like catnip for me. So I asked Roland
Speaker 2:  to come on the show and talk through some of the big ideas in his book, and
Speaker 2:  also why notebooks continue to survive in
Speaker 2:  this increasingly digital world. It's a super fun conversation. I
Speaker 2:  really enjoyed talking to him. And yes, there is more
Speaker 2:  12 century history in this episode than most, but we're
Speaker 2:  gonna go with it. So to start with Roland, I asked him to quickly
Speaker 2:  recap the case that he makes that paper
Speaker 2:  is a hugely important invention in the history of the world. And that
Speaker 2:  without paper we might not have any of this. Here's what he said
Speaker 2:  to that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, permanence is really why
Speaker 5:  for thousands of years we've had different ways of writing things down as
Speaker 5:  human beings. So you go back to, you can, you can carve on stone, you can
Speaker 5:  make little dents in clay tablets, which you then fire and dry out and they're
Speaker 5:  permanent, but they are clay tablets, so they're not super portable or practical
Speaker 5:  or robust. Then you have papyrus, papyrus,
Speaker 5:  the reed product, which grows in Egypt.
Speaker 5:  And you can write on that, you can draw on that. But papyrus, it turns
Speaker 5:  out, unless it's actually an in an Egyptian tomb, completely
Speaker 5:  dry with no movement and nothing to disturb it, it will just
Speaker 5:  automatically fall apart. It it, it can't cope with any kind of damp or
Speaker 5:  it can't really cope with being handled. So papyrus is handy, but
Speaker 5:  it's not permanent. And then you have wax tablets and
Speaker 5:  these are beautiful things. They're amazing. Completely died out in Europe.
Speaker 5:  But for about 2000 years, this is how Europeans
Speaker 5:  retained information, took notes, wrote poems,
Speaker 5:  agreed contracts, bills of sale, whatever, with a layer of wax
Speaker 5:  on wood, which you would then scrape into with a little stylus.
Speaker 5:  Now obviously that's not permanent, so it's very useful for
Speaker 5:  being in a poet's notebook, for instance, because you can wipe it over at
Speaker 5:  the end of the day when you're finished writing your poem. But for a business
Speaker 5:  record, it's no good at all because you know, you, you have to
Speaker 5:  know what you agreed, what you contracted. Then you have
Speaker 5:  parchment, and parchment comes along a little bit later during the period
Speaker 5:  of the Roman Empire probably. And that's a really good writing
Speaker 5:  material. It's very tough, it's completely indestructible and
Speaker 5:  you can write on it beautifully. And you can also paint on it If you like.
Speaker 5:  So the illuminated manuscripts, which we see the book of Kas and so on,
Speaker 5:  these are all on parchment and they're very beautiful. But the problem is
Speaker 5:  when you write on parchment with a pen, the ink
Speaker 5:  sits on the surface and dries, which means you can scrape it off.
Speaker 5:  Which means that, again, it's not permanent, you can change it, you can affect
Speaker 5:  the record. So it's no good for business. Paper turns up in Europe around
Speaker 5:  the year 12 40, 12 50. And very quickly a
Speaker 5:  few people realize it's a game changer because anything which is
Speaker 5:  written on paper, stay with ink stays there. So
Speaker 5:  you can have a contract, you can keep a business record, you can
Speaker 5:  do anything legal, you can have a deed, for instance, and you don't have
Speaker 5:  to worry about it being forged. Yeah. And that's
Speaker 5:  important. So paper is really important because it's permanent and that leads
Speaker 5:  to its very, very rapid adoption in
Speaker 5:  the business community in particular.
Speaker 2:  Was that where it started? I was, I was trying to match some of the timelines
Speaker 2:  and going back through, it seems like I,
Speaker 2:  if I have the timeline correct, there were, there were two
Speaker 2:  threads. There was kind of the people who use it for business and people
Speaker 2:  who use it for recording things in their own personal lives. But
Speaker 2:  it does seem like business became a real use case for
Speaker 2:  notebooks first.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, absolutely. A hundred percent. And the analogy, which you can
Speaker 5:  very easily draw is with the modern computer. Mm. You know, that
Speaker 5:  comes from IBM and it's businesses and governments which
Speaker 5:  have it to begin with for the first how long? 30 years, maybe 40 years.
Speaker 5:  And then you get people using it creatively. And then you get people like
Speaker 5:  jobs thinking, oh, you can have some fun with this thing. You know, you can
Speaker 5:  play games on it, but you can also be seriously creative. So now you have
Speaker 5:  Pixar, for instance. And I don't think anyone at IBM in the 1940s was
Speaker 5:  thinking that Pixar was gonna happen. Right? Looking back, it seems inevitable
Speaker 5:  that people would do something like that. And it's exactly the same kind
Speaker 5:  of relationship with notebooks. You have
Speaker 5:  businesses come to rely on notebooks, utterly, they use them for everything.
Speaker 5:  And therefore
Speaker 5:  notebooks get into everyone's hands, particularly in a culture like Italy,
Speaker 5:  which at the time Italy's the richest part of Europe. But it's also where
Speaker 5:  they invent banking, where they invent companies, where they invent
Speaker 5:  accountancy, double entry, bookkeeping, limited liability, partnerships,
Speaker 5:  futures, markets, all of these things which we know and love.
Speaker 2:  And, and a lot of that you talk about happens,
Speaker 2:  not sort of, it, it, that doesn't happen. And then they put it down in notebooks,
Speaker 2:  like the existence of those things and notebooks and this new
Speaker 2:  writing, permanent technology go hand in hand.
Speaker 5:  Absolutely. You can't do one without the other. But then of course, so
Speaker 5:  they have to have these notebooks, and once they have to have them in the
Speaker 5:  evening, they take 'em home and then, then they do the fun stuff with them.
Speaker 5:  And that's entirely accidental, I think. But,
Speaker 5:  you know, thank God from our point of view, it's given us all of this interesting
Speaker 5:  literature and art and poetry.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So, I confess. I'm particularly interested in the fun stuff. So
Speaker 2:  let, let's start there. I think the, the first thing I had written down in
Speaker 2:  my notes was like, let's go back to Florence and, and there's
Speaker 2:  a word that starts with a Z that I can't pronounce. And it was, it
Speaker 2:  was, it, my, my gut tells me it's pronounced zibo, but I could be wrong.
Speaker 2:  I
Speaker 5:  You are dead, right? Yeah. Yes. I I you just have to imagine yourself ordering
Speaker 5:  a zzi baldon an Italian restaurant and you'll be fine. Right.
Speaker 2:  A, a type of notebook and also a beautiful croissant like thing
Speaker 2:  that I will like very much. Tell me what those were. Talk a little bit about,
Speaker 2:  well, kind of how that spread.
Speaker 5:  Okay, back to the restaurant Z baldon seems to have been a word for salad
Speaker 5:  and that's exactly what it is. So it's a collection of lots of
Speaker 5:  different things jumbled together. Now, this is a time
Speaker 5:  before print, we're talking about about 1300 and it's Florence
Speaker 5:  and it's a time before print. So If, you wanted to have any book or literature
Speaker 5:  or poetry in your house. You had to basically write it
Speaker 5:  down yourself. Yeah. And therefore,
Speaker 5:  Florence is a very business-like community. They're very entrepreneurial.
Speaker 5:  Everyone's got their own little business, therefore everyone's got their
Speaker 5:  business notebooks. They take 'em home in the evening and if they hear
Speaker 5:  a poem which they like, or if they hear is one of ESOP's fables
Speaker 5:  is very popular, or a bit of ovid or a prayer, which is particularly
Speaker 5:  resonant to them, or a recipe, very often they're writing down medic
Speaker 5:  medicinal cures. Anything you wanna keep written down in your house, you
Speaker 5:  just write it down in your al And it's a very personal notebook, but it's
Speaker 5:  completely unsorted. So it's like a salad in this jumbled up way.
Speaker 5:  And they're brilliant because they're these windows
Speaker 5:  into what Florentine people loved. Yeah. So we
Speaker 5:  know the poetry, they like to read, we know the prayers that they wanted
Speaker 5:  to remember. We know the stories that they liked to tell and we know what
Speaker 5:  they liked to eat when they had a headache. You know, all of this kind of
Speaker 5:  information because everyone in Florence at this time who could read or
Speaker 5:  write, which was most of them unusually, they kept a al
Speaker 5:  and it was a really strange local thing. But it was so fun.
Speaker 2:  I also get the sense that folks back then were reckoning with the same thing
Speaker 2:  people reckon with now, which is like, what do I do with any of this? And
Speaker 2:  this is sort of the eternal question of notebooks, right? Is you, you
Speaker 2:  write a bunch of stuff down, you collect all this stuff. And as a historical
Speaker 2:  artifact, especially in aggregate, it's very cool, right? You, you get a
Speaker 2:  sense of what people were doing in a, in a community. But if
Speaker 2:  I'm a person in Florence in the 13 hundreds keeping one of these,
Speaker 2:  what do, what am I doing with it day to day? What's gonna happen to these
Speaker 2:  notebooks? Are they thinking about like the grand sweep of history and their
Speaker 2:  responsibility to write this stuff down? Like what were the, what was the
Speaker 2:  point of these notebooks?
Speaker 5:  So the ziel only the, the only point was fun. They weren't thinking about
Speaker 5:  the grand sweep of history, but they knew that they were a bit precious because
Speaker 5:  they would leave them in their wills. So this is how we know, one of the
Speaker 5:  ways we know how many people had them, because the wills often survive.
Speaker 5:  And also you see these little dedications in the, someone will start
Speaker 5:  their zil donni, then they'll leave it to their son and then the son will
Speaker 5:  have an argument on the pages of the Zil donni with his brother saying, oh
Speaker 5:  no, he dad left it to me actually. You know? So you have these little
Speaker 5:  bickerings and you can see that sometimes they pass down three generations
Speaker 5:  and that people maintain them 'cause the handwriting changes.
Speaker 5:  So that's one thing. So Zi donia, they're always for fun, but
Speaker 5:  people definitely keep know that they have a value.
Speaker 5:  The other thing that they also start doing is viewing their family as
Speaker 5:  a kind of business and then keeping what they would call a libre de familia.
Speaker 5:  Oh, well za is the other word for it. Where they keep a family
Speaker 5:  record, which is essentially births, deaths, marriages,
Speaker 5:  investments, you know, we bought this house, I invested in this company,
Speaker 5:  my daughter got married, my son died, my grandson was born, he was
Speaker 5:  baptized, et cetera. And they're very businesslike. You wouldn't
Speaker 5:  call them diaries because there's no emotion in there. There's no
Speaker 5:  happiness or sadness. But they just record the central
Speaker 5:  of most important events of a family's life. And then that would get passed
Speaker 5:  down through the generations as well. And that, but that's more viewing your
Speaker 5:  family in a kind of quite serious business-like way If, you are a
Speaker 5:  grammar school in the, say 15
Speaker 5:  hundreds. 16 hundreds in Europe. You were expected to
Speaker 5:  keep a commonplace book in a very rigorous way. And that was a very formal
Speaker 5:  kind of thing. But that was educational, you know, that wasn't, no one ever
Speaker 5:  really did that for fun. 'cause it's such hard work. Yeah. It's a, it's a
Speaker 5:  real effort and it's study. But I think that outside of school
Speaker 5:  you have people like Leonardo who would just draw all over the
Speaker 5:  place. You have people who doodle. You have people who write very intimate
Speaker 5:  personal diaries, people who write very formal ones, people who write about
Speaker 5:  their relationship with God. You know, there's no hard and fast
Speaker 5:  rules.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And that feels like the, the thing that
Speaker 2:  lingers most over time is that everybody is perpetually finding new ways
Speaker 2:  to fill up a notebook. Yeah. Kind of more chaotic
Speaker 2:  over time too. Everybody gets weirder and weirder about notebooks.
Speaker 2:  Da Vinci is an interesting one. You, you mentioned him and obviously I would
Speaker 2:  say, you've obviously done more research on this than I have, but I would
Speaker 2:  say Leonardo da Vinci's notebooks probably history's most famous
Speaker 2:  notebooks, fair to say.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I would say so. Okay. Yeah. Yeah. Those are the ones when I was telling
Speaker 5:  people that I was writing history of Notebook and they were looking baffled,
Speaker 5:  I would go, you know, Leonardo. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 2:  Well, one thing I thought was really interesting in, in your telling of his
Speaker 2:  story was that he
Speaker 2:  did not seem to imagine that his notebooks would eventually become wildly
Speaker 2:  famous. And the idea that these were for public consumption
Speaker 2:  was kind of a thing that happened much later. The notebooks were very personal
Speaker 5:  Much
Speaker 2:  Later and very individual. How did that change come about? Like
Speaker 2:  at what point did people start writing notebooks? Even in some of the
Speaker 2:  styles that you're talking about, thinking about other people?
Speaker 5:  Very, very late in the day, I would say. I think what's interesting,
Speaker 5:  Leonardo's notebooks are fascinating for two reasons, I think very far
Speaker 5:  apart in time. Firstly, because they're an amazing record of his thoughts,
Speaker 5:  his researchers, his explorations and his personality up to a
Speaker 5:  point so that that period around the year 1500,
Speaker 5:  wow. You know, there was something really incredible going on there. And
Speaker 5:  then basically they just vanish into
Speaker 5:  aristocrats libraries, you know, and no one reads them,
Speaker 5:  no one, they probably pull 'em off the shelf and just look at them as a curiosity.
Speaker 5:  No one studies them at all until the 1890s
Speaker 5:  when a German guy called Richter goes around Europe. He looks at
Speaker 5:  them all, he transcribes them, he researches, he writes about them. And then
Speaker 5:  for the first time, 400 years nearly after Leonardo
Speaker 5:  dies, people actually realize, oh, he wasn't just
Speaker 5:  a good painter, he was also all of these other kinds of genius as well, because
Speaker 5:  he was just known as a painter up to that point. And then,
Speaker 5:  and I think it is a direct result of the publication
Speaker 5:  of Leonardo's notebooks and people understanding that there's this
Speaker 5:  process behind his genius, then everyone else
Speaker 5:  starts taking their notebooks much more seriously. So Picasso, for instance,
Speaker 5:  he starts painting in the 1890s at exactly the same time or learns how to
Speaker 5:  paint. He's a boy. And he, for instance, took his
Speaker 5:  sketchbooks incredibly seriously. He never gave them away, he never lost
Speaker 5:  them. He kept them filed away in boxes in his house in the south of France,
Speaker 5:  and they were numbered, cataloged, ordered. He knew that his
Speaker 5:  sketchbooks were really important, whereas painters a hundred
Speaker 5:  years before him,
Speaker 5:  it seems to have been a very casual relationship. You know, or rather they,
Speaker 5:  they themselves use their notebooks, but they had no sense that anyone else
Speaker 5:  would ever find him interesting. So
Speaker 5:  yeah, I think there's definitely a change. And I think that Leonardo sort
Speaker 5:  of accidentally 400 years after his death prompts it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And, and to the extent, you know, if any kind of, well-known writer
Speaker 5:  now will sell their papers to the University of
Speaker 5:  the University of Austin, for instance. Right. You know, collects writer's
Speaker 5:  notebooks and it will pay good money for them a hundred, 150 years
Speaker 5:  ago, you know, universities were not doing that, they would, wouldn't have
Speaker 5:  seen the value.
Speaker 2:  Do you think that changes the way we look at those notebooks now? I mean,
Speaker 2:  I I think about even go back to Florence, like you, you, you think about
Speaker 2:  those as an important record of real life
Speaker 2:  in a way that as soon as people become self-conscious that someone else might
Speaker 2:  see their notebooks, it sort of ceases to be a record
Speaker 2:  of real life. It, it becomes an Instagram version of real life
Speaker 2:  where everything is maybe subtly
Speaker 2:  self-consciously changed to be for public consumption
Speaker 2:  in a way that, I don't know, like I, we we think about notebooks as these
Speaker 2:  intensely private things, but as soon as you understand that someone else
Speaker 2:  might see it. I wonder if it changes what that thing is.
Speaker 5:  Oh, well, certainly when it comes to diary writing in particular, so the,
Speaker 5:  any number of published diaries you can tell were written with publication
Speaker 5:  in mind. Mm. I write a diary every day and I don't
Speaker 5:  expect that anyone else will ever read it. And it's
Speaker 5:  certainly never gonna be published. And it's, I think you're right. It's
Speaker 5:  more intimate and it's, you know, that it's pretty uncensored
Speaker 5:  unfiltered. But then you have the Tony Blairs of this world
Speaker 5:  whose diaries are published, I think. Sure. And that's a
Speaker 5:  completely different kettle of fish.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I guess that's okay. Both of those things can exist, but they are
Speaker 2:  very different things.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. Very, very definitely. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I am really curious about how you as a person in,
Speaker 2:  in a digital world came to think about notebooks. Because
Speaker 2:  again, there is such a, there's so much about
Speaker 2:  that history that a feels very modern. Like we're, we're talking about
Speaker 2:  the same kinds of things now and like you said, using computers for the same
Speaker 2:  kinds of things that people were using notebooks for 800 years ago.
Speaker 2:  But I wonder if you're going through and you have to spend time thinking
Speaker 2:  about the thing itself and, and like you said,
Speaker 2:  paper is this crucially important invention, and
Speaker 2:  if we had invented computers in 1200 instead of inventing
Speaker 2:  paper, would it have gone roughly the same way? Or is there something
Speaker 2:  about that thing and that time and that invention
Speaker 2:  that made it different from even everything that came after?
Speaker 5:  I think up to a point, the invention makes the time. You know,
Speaker 5:  you said to me very confidently that we live in a digital world, you know,
Speaker 5:  and, and of course you are, right? Yeah. We do definitely live in a digital
Speaker 5:  world. We're speaking to each other, you know, via a digital link
Speaker 5:  up and surrounded by amazing technology. I would
Speaker 5:  also, if I was being contrarian, say to you, you are living in a notebook
Speaker 5:  world. Hmm. Because capitalism, which gives us all of
Speaker 5:  we, what we see around us, that for 600
Speaker 5:  years was entirely based in notebooks.
Speaker 5:  We would call them ledgers or account books, but it was an entirely
Speaker 5:  notebook based system until the first IBM machines. So,
Speaker 5:  and that was invented at the same time as, or roughly speaking the same
Speaker 5:  time as The Notebook arrives in, in Europe, in sort of in that place in
Speaker 5:  Italy around the year 1300. They invent all of the mechanisms of
Speaker 5:  capitalism. So really we are in that world as much as we're in the
Speaker 5:  digital world.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, and I, there is definitely a sense of you have an invention
Speaker 5:  and then it shapes the world that you live in. But in unexpected,
Speaker 5:  surprising, fun, hopefully ways no one saw
Speaker 5:  that Twitter was coming 10 years before Twitter arrived. Sure. But, and then
Speaker 5:  suddenly it's everywhere, and then suddenly it's nowhere again. You know?
Speaker 5:  So who knows?
Speaker 2:  So, okay, let's, let's fast forward a bunch in history to,
Speaker 2:  not now, but close to now. And I wanna talk about the bullet journal.
Speaker 2:  And the reason I wanted to start with the Zi is that I feel like you can
Speaker 2:  draw a straight line from that thing in Florence
Speaker 2:  800 years ago to the bullet journal phenomenon of
Speaker 2:  today, like, like a dead straight line through
Speaker 2:  almost a millennium of time.
Speaker 2:  How, how is that possible? Like, why do you think this, this thing,
Speaker 2:  this idea of how we want to record our lives in a physical
Speaker 2:  notebook has been So I consistently
Speaker 2:  persistent over so many centuries.
Speaker 5:  It's a really great, simple, minimal tool. I think like
Speaker 5:  with, with any kind of technology, there's a, there's a, or any kind of invention,
Speaker 5:  there's a real virtue to simplicity. You know, so your, your
Speaker 5:  knife and fork or your chopsticks, chopsticks are great because they're minimal.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You can't, once you've pictured them, you've invented them once. You
Speaker 5:  cannot improve on them. And a notebook I think is a lot like that. It
Speaker 5:  came to a kind of, very quickly, it became kind of perfect
Speaker 5:  in terms of its how practical it was, how cheap it was, how available it
Speaker 5:  was to everyone. And you can't really improve on that as a bit of
Speaker 5:  technology, you know, because, and then people will use it in different
Speaker 5:  ways over history. And bullet journals are, I think, a really good example
Speaker 5:  of how you can take this really simple thing and just use it in a slightly
Speaker 5:  new way. And suddenly it opens possibilities for people which they never
Speaker 5:  appreciated before. Like, there are a lot of people
Speaker 5:  whose genuinely, there are a surprising number of people whose lives have
Speaker 5:  really been improved by doing bullet points to
Speaker 5:  organize their life. And it kind of helps them to rationalize things and
Speaker 5:  make proper decisions and act more intentionally and therefore, thereby live
Speaker 5:  happier lives. I think I, I find it constantly incredible
Speaker 5:  how this really simple thing can be reinvented so regularly. But
Speaker 5:  you're right, there is a continuous line all the way through. I think it's
Speaker 5:  just 'cause it's incredibly simple and it doesn't require batteries, it doesn't
Speaker 5:  require system updates. It's, you know, If, you drop it, it doesn't break.
Speaker 2:  What was it that was interesting to you about the bullet journal and, and
Speaker 2:  its history? Like why, why did that jump out to you as a, as a thing worth
Speaker 2:  adding to this history?
Speaker 5:  It was important to me because,
Speaker 5:  firstly, because it was a, it was a real thing. It was a real trend, you
Speaker 5:  know, when I was starting to think about the book. And it gave me sort of
Speaker 5:  confidence that there was gonna be an appetite of people who were interested
Speaker 5:  in this stuff, which is very key in terms of building
Speaker 5:  my confidence. And then what was interesting was, I never,
Speaker 5:  I've never bullet journaled myself. I've never done the writer Carroll method,
Speaker 5:  but I got his book and then I spoke to him, interviewed him, and
Speaker 5:  he's really thought about it quite deeply. And he's thought about
Speaker 5:  the implications of writing stuff down and of organizing your thoughts on
Speaker 5:  the page and having this notebook, which you carry everywhere, and which
Speaker 5:  you write everything down on. And that kind of encouraged me to
Speaker 5:  think deeply about it too. Mm. You know, he's taken it very seriously for
Speaker 5:  a long time and he's thought about it in a particular way and I'm, I've got
Speaker 5:  a more historical angle and I think about it in different ways, but they're
Speaker 5:  completely compatible. But the, just the fact that he had taken
Speaker 5:  it seriously, I found really interesting and, and hence
Speaker 5:  giving him a chapter, I think was, you know, kind of fair because
Speaker 5:  he was really about the only person who had written a book about notebooking,
Speaker 5:  you know? Yeah. Before I did so. And he also
Speaker 5:  had some really interesting things to say about notebooks, which aren't bullet
Speaker 5:  journals. He was really inspired for instance, by kind of artists
Speaker 5:  scrapbooks and, and sort of collages and
Speaker 5:  sketchbooks, which were sort of more than sketchbooks, which had elements
Speaker 5:  of diary in them. So not pure bullet journal stuff, but stuff, which is
Speaker 5:  a really interesting expression of your experience. And, and
Speaker 5:  Ryder definitely put me onto those things.
Speaker 2:  Why do you think that way of thinking about
Speaker 2:  notebooking and journaling and keeping track of your life lagged so
Speaker 2:  much? The business side of things, which as you
Speaker 2:  chart in the book, got really systematized and really
Speaker 2:  specific. And like we, we built capitalism on top of these things, right?
Speaker 2:  Like double entry accounting became a worldwide phenomenon and people
Speaker 2:  understood how to do it. And there were kind of accepted rules
Speaker 2:  on how to keep these kinds of notebooks. But in people doing
Speaker 2:  it in their own lives, like you said, there have been bits and pieces of
Speaker 2:  this over time, but
Speaker 2:  somebody like Ryder Carroll comes along hundreds of years later and
Speaker 2:  really thinks like, okay, how can I break this thing down into sort of
Speaker 2:  understandable, repeatable pieces that just happened much later? Why do you
Speaker 2:  think that is?
Speaker 5:  Honestly, I have no idea. There, there are que there are
Speaker 5:  questions you can't answer. I mean, the, the another big question, which
Speaker 5:  I just have no idea, is why did people start writing diaries?
Speaker 5:  Or, or rather, why did they start writing diaries in England
Speaker 5:  in around the year 1570 when they'd never
Speaker 5:  done them anywhere else in the world before? I've looked really hard at trying
Speaker 5:  to find out what was so special about England at that time, which made people
Speaker 5:  start to keep a diary like you would you an emotional diary of how
Speaker 5:  they felt about the day's events. I, I, sorry, not very good podcast
Speaker 5:  material. I'm making a baffled expression. Listen to picture that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I have no idea. And I think your, my answer to your question is, it's
Speaker 5:  a good question. I have no idea.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's, I, I have, I have a theory and it's based on nothing,
Speaker 2:  but it's a theory and I'm gonna, I'm gonna give you my theory as a way of
Speaker 2:  asking you another question, which I also have about this. I'm here for it.
Speaker 2:  I think as, especially as
Speaker 2:  we became more enmeshed with digital tools,
Speaker 2:  life took on like a new level of informational chaos.
Speaker 2:  There is just more stuff coming at us now than there ever has been.
Speaker 2:  And that's true in our professional lives, but it's also
Speaker 2:  true in our personal lives. I think in a, in a new way
Speaker 2:  in the last, I don't know, several decades, that there's just more
Speaker 2:  happening around you and to you all the time. And
Speaker 2:  we're, we're still reckoning with that as people, right? This question of
Speaker 2:  like, we understand what is going on in the world in a way that we are
Speaker 2:  like evolutionarily not equipped to do, and what do we do with that? All
Speaker 2:  these really interesting questions. But I think one thing that I see all
Speaker 2:  the time is people crave systems. There there is this idea that
Speaker 2:  if I can just find a way to make this make sense,
Speaker 2:  everything will be better, right? And I think, and you, you mentioned the,
Speaker 2:  the getting things done method in, in the book also. And I think that
Speaker 2:  speaks to the same thing where it's like, yeah, there's this swirling mass
Speaker 2:  of stuff in my life and If you can just tell me where
Speaker 2:  to put it and how my brain will get quieter. And I think
Speaker 2:  that's meaningful to people. And, and again, i I, there there is
Speaker 2:  a definite sort of, we are people of our time and technology
Speaker 2:  thing that is all kind of swirling together there. But I feel like when I
Speaker 2:  see people who like really love bullet journal what it, what it says is like,
Speaker 2:  the world is insane and messy, but I have made this thing
Speaker 2:  that is like my world and it is beautiful and looks like me and it
Speaker 2:  just feels good. And it's why like, people get mad at all the bullet journalists
Speaker 2:  who are like spending all of their time organizing their pages and not time
Speaker 2:  getting stuff done. And it's like, no, the the organizing the pages is actually
Speaker 2:  the point of the thing. Yeah. As much as anything else, it's taking control,
Speaker 2:  right? Like making The Notebook is the point. And I, I feel like that was
Speaker 2:  one of the things that just keeps coming up throughout history in your book
Speaker 2:  is like the act of making the thing is as much the point as anything else.
Speaker 2:  Going back and reviewing it is fine. Doing stuff with what you put in it
Speaker 2:  is fine, but the act of making The Notebook in the first place is
Speaker 2:  maybe the most important part of the whole process. And I feel like there's
Speaker 2:  so much of that happening right now that yeah, we need structure around
Speaker 2:  that more than ever. Yeah, that's just a theory.
Speaker 5:  That's it. And my answers to that is yes,
Speaker 5:  that's the short answer. Slightly, slightly more involved example, or to
Speaker 5:  sort of back up what you said. So I have a day job and
Speaker 5:  I do this, I write books and talk to people
Speaker 5:  about it. And so the level of inputs
Speaker 5:  into my life in terms of communication and things flying at me from different
Speaker 5:  directions. I've got two email addresses. I've got the Instagram,
Speaker 5:  I've got the Twitter, which I'm switching off shortly, but I've got the,
Speaker 5:  the Facebook, I've got WhatsApp on the phone,
Speaker 5:  et cetera, et cetera. It just goes on. And that's before I'm in a room
Speaker 5:  with anyone actually talking to them face to face. And my way of dealing
Speaker 5:  with this is to write a diary. Yeah. So at the end of the day,
Speaker 5:  I will put it all down in here and, and it's,
Speaker 5:  it's under control as you say. And I've turned this
Speaker 5:  ephemeral nonstop flow of craziness,
Speaker 5:  most of which is completely trivial, but has to be managed somehow.
Speaker 5:  And I've just turned it into a calm thing on the page.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I completely agree. And as to how that makes me feel, the
Speaker 5:  analogy I use is it's
Speaker 5:  like having a shower. Yeah. Showers are lovely. Yeah. Just great.
Speaker 5:  I like to have a shower every day, but if I can't, if I have to go a day
Speaker 5:  without, that's fine. No one really minds two days
Speaker 5:  without it's, you know, mentally I start to smell.
Speaker 5:  So, and that's what I'm like with the diary. That's really good. Now If,
Speaker 5:  you miss a day. Yeah, I can't miss two days. I start to smell mentally and,
Speaker 5:  and it really cleans me out. Sort of that process of just dumping it on the
Speaker 5:  page really, really is refreshing and cleansing in that sense.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I like that a lot. Why do you think we haven't found a way to do
Speaker 2:  that digitally in the way that is satisfying and
Speaker 2:  valuable in the same way that we have in notebooks? Because
Speaker 2:  like, we pretty much do business on computers now there, there's
Speaker 2:  not a lot of paper notebooks out there responsible for
Speaker 2:  how capitalism runs anymore. Yeah. But I think I, I am someone
Speaker 2:  who has tried every note taking app on planet Earth.
Speaker 2:  I I obsessively use them. I build these systems and
Speaker 2:  overwhelmingly the ones that feel the best. And as I talk to people, the
Speaker 2:  answer is you try them all and you eventually just get a nice notebook and
Speaker 2:  a pen and you start filling it. Yeah. And there is, there is something about
Speaker 2:  that that we have not replaced. And I'm curious, If you have thoughts on
Speaker 2:  why it has been so hard to replace?
Speaker 5:  I have lots of thoughts. I'm gonna give you the deepest one because please.
Speaker 5:  I think this is, I think your listener can cope with a, a sort of high level
Speaker 5:  bit of neurobiology. So when you write on a
Speaker 5:  notebook page, and they've done this with MRI scans and the very clever
Speaker 5:  way of using multiple men mineral I scan called voxel based morpho.
Speaker 5:  When you can look at multiple brains at once, when you write in a notebook,
Speaker 5:  you use different parts of the brain to when you type
Speaker 5:  or when you write something on your phone or your tablet. And one of the
Speaker 5:  different parts you use is the hippocampus. Now this is right in the
Speaker 5:  bottom of the brain and it's your mental map. So when you
Speaker 5:  drive to your place of work, you are using your
Speaker 5:  hippocampus. When you know where the coffee
Speaker 5:  cups are in your kitchen, you are using the hippocampus. Taxi drivers, cab
Speaker 5:  drivers have amazingly well developed hippo campi,
Speaker 5:  an early case study in brain plasticity actually. Right.
Speaker 5:  So this is very interesting. Why do you engage your hippocampus when you're
Speaker 5:  writing in a notebook? And it's because your notebook is a place,
Speaker 5:  right? And it has its own geography. So when you write things on the pages
Speaker 5:  of a notebook, you remember, or I certainly tend to remember, oh, that was
Speaker 5:  on the left hand side at the top. Oh, that was I, I wrote that in blue somewhere.
Speaker 5:  Now that was at the back of The Notebook that was at the front. And I'm
Speaker 5:  thinking about The Notebook in quite a different way to how I think about
Speaker 5:  a digital note and what they think the people who research this
Speaker 5:  is that when you scroll or you carry on writing and what
Speaker 5:  you've written on a screen just scrolls up up top of the page and
Speaker 5:  vanishes off the top of your screen.
Speaker 5:  It just vanishes. It has no place in the geography of your lived
Speaker 5:  experience, unlike stuff which you write down in a notebook page. So I've
Speaker 5:  got my yellow notebook and I know that if I open it halfway through, roughly
Speaker 5:  speaking, I'm gonna find what happened in July. And I can't do that
Speaker 5:  with notes I've made on an iPad, but just because my
Speaker 5:  brain hasn't thought about them in that geographic way. So that's one reason
Speaker 5:  why you feel more comfortable and you navigate those notes more
Speaker 5:  happily than you do when they're digital.
Speaker 5:  Other reasons are to do with I think the sort of the sensory experience of
Speaker 5:  writing fingers on the page, the pen in your hand being a slightly richer
Speaker 5:  experience. It's more difficult as well, it's very easy to type.
Speaker 5:  You can type, you could roughly speaking type everything I
Speaker 5:  said to you right now, you'd get it all pretty much down. You
Speaker 5:  can't do that with the pen and ink. You have to filter, you have to pause
Speaker 5:  the ideas, you have to process them and paraphrase. And that
Speaker 5:  gives you a much richer, deeper understanding of what you
Speaker 5:  are actually listening to. You can type whatever
Speaker 5:  I say without actually listening to what I'm saying at all, but to write
Speaker 5:  it down, you have to paraphrase it and therefore you have to actually interact
Speaker 5:  with the ideas. So this is why teachers and academics much
Speaker 5:  prefer their students to, to write notes rather than to type them.
Speaker 5:  So there's a couple of answers.
Speaker 2:  Do you think there's a marriage there that we can make work? I mean, I keep
Speaker 2:  thinking about you, you start the book with moleskin, which is probably
Speaker 2:  the first notebook most people think of when they think of notebooks. And
Speaker 2:  moleskin for years has been building digital tools
Speaker 2:  and they have, they have a really beautiful calendar app. They have a really
Speaker 2:  interesting journaling system. Like it, it's all very good. Nobody
Speaker 2:  cares about it the way that they care about physical moleskin notebooks.
Speaker 2:  No. And you know, there, there was this phase for a long time of
Speaker 2:  like, maybe we're gonna do smart pens where I'll write
Speaker 2:  in a notebook, but it will transcribe it digitally. And now there are things
Speaker 2:  where like, okay, you can write with a pen, but it's on your iPad and it
Speaker 2:  will recognize the text and make something out of it. And it feels like we're,
Speaker 2:  we're poking at this thing where the, the act that you're describing, I think
Speaker 2:  is absolutely the best one. But having a
Speaker 2:  notebook that is a bunch of words on a page that
Speaker 2:  sits on my bookshelf waiting for me to do something
Speaker 2:  with it feels like it's missing something. Like there is a best of
Speaker 2:  both worlds here that I think I desperately want to exist. And I don't
Speaker 2:  know, maybe, maybe it just doesn't and can't and won't. But I am curious,
Speaker 2:  like, do you, do you think we can marry those two things?
Speaker 5:  I'm not gonna say never. Okay. But I've not seen it done yet in a way which
Speaker 5:  I think some people that sort of the moleskin magic paper, the
Speaker 5:  dotted paper, whatever, they, they make it work for them and, and good luck
Speaker 5:  and that's great. And some people also managed to make those
Speaker 5:  kind of posh tablets, the, the remarkable tablets work
Speaker 5:  in in a similar way. And again, go you
Speaker 5:  personally, I haven't ever managed to.
Speaker 2:  Okay, last thing and then I will truly let you go. Tell me just
Speaker 2:  briefly about moleskin and why you, you start the book with
Speaker 2:  moleskin. I wanna end our podcast with moleskin. Why is moleskin
Speaker 2:  so ascendant? What, what is it about this company and this thing
Speaker 2:  that has made Moleskin the brand? The Notebook the thing
Speaker 2:  in our sort of modern world,
Speaker 5:  It's the complete refinement she took,
Speaker 5:  and I I say she, Maria Seg Bondi, who was the woman who
Speaker 5:  conceived the, the moleskin notebook, who took the very simple basic
Speaker 5:  notebook that we knew she added to it. She added this little elastic
Speaker 5:  strap, the pocket in the back that it'll page at the front saying, If, you
Speaker 5:  find this notebook, please return it to, she added all of these things
Speaker 5:  to a very minimal product and she somehow made it seem even more
Speaker 5:  minimal. Right? So, and the
Speaker 5:  analogy I make, she made, she made it minimal and she made it black. And
Speaker 5:  that was the most Italian thing you could do is like pair old sunglasses,
Speaker 5:  Prada, little black dress, espresso. You know, that's what they do.
Speaker 5:  They make it minimal and black. And she did that and somehow
Speaker 5:  she just, she tricked us. If you like, she fooled us. And
Speaker 5:  thank God that she did, I wouldn't have written this book if it wasn't for
Speaker 5:  Moleskins. I think because she made us look again at this simple notebook
Speaker 5:  and think of it as something which had some material value, that had some
Speaker 5:  material beauty and was, could be therefore inspiring in
Speaker 5:  a way that your school exercise book couldn't be. Hmm. So she's, from that
Speaker 5:  point of view, she's my heroine creatively, she's also
Speaker 5:  for me a figure of awe because If, you look at Moleskin's numbers, the company's
Speaker 5:  numbers through history, that company's profit margin
Speaker 5:  is ridiculous. It's like 43% profit every year, gross
Speaker 5:  profit. And it's a manufacturing company. No company does that,
Speaker 5:  you know, how did they do it? So I take my hat off to her and
Speaker 5:  I can forget quite easily about all of the ridiculous collaborations
Speaker 5:  with Evernote and Adobe and things like that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, listen, you gotta do some weird stuff because
Speaker 5:  The, the key product is amazing. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well, and to that point, actually, one of the things you, you say kind
Speaker 2:  of as an aside in the book is that there are
Speaker 2:  a million other notebooks that are like, they, they give you ideas and prompts
Speaker 2:  and they put stuff inside and they're like, this one's for your recipes,
Speaker 2:  this one is for your travels. And what actually turns out to be the case
Speaker 2:  is nobody wants that. They want the blank one. Yeah. And I think that is
Speaker 2:  like as a, as a perfect metaphor for all of this that just carries with
Speaker 2:  me through the whole thing that like you can, you can make it whatever you
Speaker 2:  want, you can guss it up and people will want the blank one because then
Speaker 2:  they can do what they want with it. And there's something very powerful in
Speaker 2:  that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Freedom.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean that's the story of The Notebook, right? It is permanence and
Speaker 2:  it's freedom in, in very real ways. Lovely.
Speaker 5:  Yes. I'll take that. Can I, can I, can I have that? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I'll, I'll take that.
Speaker 3:  All right, we
Speaker 2:  Gotta take one more break and then we're gonna come back and take a question
Speaker 2:  from The Vergecast hotline. We'll be right
Speaker 3:  Back.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we're back. Let's get to the hotline as always. The number is 8 6 6
Speaker 2:  VERGE one one. The email is vergecast at The Verge dot com. Please send us
Speaker 2:  all of your questions. We have a couple of specific hotline things we're
Speaker 2:  gonna do in the next couple of months before the end of the year. So keep
Speaker 2:  an eye on our socials, we'll mention it on this show, but all of your questions,
Speaker 2:  send 'em to the hotline. We love it this week. Like I mentioned, we have
Speaker 2:  something slightly different. We got a question that sent our producer will
Speaker 2:  pour down a pretty wild rabbit hole inside the TikTok
Speaker 2:  shop. So here, let me just play you the question and then Will's gonna take
Speaker 2:  it away. Here we go
Speaker 6:  Everyone. This is Sean from Ohio. I know that
Speaker 6:  Neli specifically hates CarPlay, but one
Speaker 6:  thing I've been seeing pop up on TikTok a bunch lately is
Speaker 6:  these CarPlay adaptable screens that
Speaker 6:  they plug into your car somehow. And it's kind of like a
Speaker 6:  retrofit for old vehicles to use CarPlay
Speaker 6:  or Android Auto. I've been seeing 'em all over TikTok lately. I don't
Speaker 6:  know if this is vaporware, if this is real. Until the other day I saw one
Speaker 6:  out in the wild in a car next to me and I wanted to wave 'em down and ask
Speaker 6:  them if it's good or not. So wondering, If, you guys think they're good?
Speaker 6:  Is this just a crazy technology or whatever?
Speaker 6:  Anyways, love to hear your opinion. Thanks, bye
Speaker 7:  So I am the proud owner of a 2006 Toyota Prius,
Speaker 7:  and I would love to have CarPlay. So as soon as I heard this
Speaker 7:  hotline question, I went on TikTok and I just searched for
Speaker 7:  CarPlay screen and I found exactly what our listener
Speaker 7:  Sean was looking at.
Speaker 8:  If you're like me and you have a much older car that you want to feel more
Speaker 8:  expensive, you need this portable Apple CarPlay.
Speaker 9:  Once you connect it to the CarPlay, it has your phone, your messages, all
Speaker 9:  your different apps on there as well. And
Speaker 10:  It's a great price. Don't sleep on this shop at the
Speaker 10:  link below. You could save yourself hundreds of dollars.
Speaker 7:  There are at least a couple of different models for sale on the
Speaker 7:  shop. The one I saw the most was made by he Ha hi ha,
Speaker 7:  H-I-E-H-A. It's a seven inch color
Speaker 7:  touchscreen. It comes with a couple of different mounting options for your
Speaker 7:  car and they throw in a backup camera. And all of
Speaker 7:  that is $37, allegedly marked down from
Speaker 7:  120, which is a very suspicious markdown.
Speaker 7:  I also found a lot of really similar listings for similar
Speaker 7:  products, similar prices, similar markdowns.
Speaker 7:  I've never bought anything on TikTok. It was all really overwhelming
Speaker 7:  and all a little bit sketchy feeling. So Sean, I
Speaker 7:  completely understand your feeling of, is this real? Is this not
Speaker 7:  real? You know, it all kind of reminded me of
Speaker 7:  the, you know, page seven of an Amazon search result
Speaker 7:  page for a gadget, but it's $37. That is
Speaker 7:  an amount of money that The Verge can put on the line on your behalf. So
Speaker 7:  I ordered it.
Speaker 11:  Okay, I got my CarPlay screen in the mail.
Speaker 11:  The brand on the box is Uni Uni, but it
Speaker 11:  says from TikTok Incorporated. It came very
Speaker 11:  quickly.
Speaker 12:  Let's open it up.
Speaker 7:  My first impressions of it, seven inches is actually a pretty big screen.
Speaker 7:  It kind of has an iPad mini vibe to it. It seems solid
Speaker 7:  enough. It comes with a power cable that goes out to a cigarette
Speaker 7:  lighter or it's A-U-S-B-C If. you happen to have that.
Speaker 7:  There's an ox cable that it comes with. It's got the backup camera
Speaker 7:  and the wiring and two different suction or adhesive
Speaker 7:  mounting options for your dashboard. The screen itself is
Speaker 7:  kind of heavy and the mounts are pretty cheap. Plastic. So I was a
Speaker 7:  little bit worried about how well it was gonna mount stably to the
Speaker 7:  dashboard, but I gave it a shot.
Speaker 12:  Let's figure out where to put this thing.
Speaker 7:  One tricky thing for me was just figuring out where to put it.
Speaker 7:  Like my Prius has a screen and I need that for
Speaker 7:  the existing backup camera and for AC and for
Speaker 7:  other stuff that I don't have physical buttons for. So it needs to be
Speaker 7:  a second screen that I put on the dash somewhere that is not gonna
Speaker 7:  block my view of the road or my view of the speedometer, et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 7:  Mounting itself turned out to be fine. The suction and the
Speaker 7:  adhesive worked out well, and once I turned the car
Speaker 7:  on the screen worked fine.
Speaker 12:  Okay, it's turning on.
Speaker 12:  I've got options for CarPlay Android Auto phone link and audio
Speaker 12:  output
Speaker 7:  Setup was really easy. It was reasonably bright
Speaker 7:  and responsive. I don't know, it was a little laggy, a little bit washed
Speaker 7:  out. But again, $37. And for what it's
Speaker 7:  worth, it is a ton better than my existing Prius screen
Speaker 13:  Head south on 30th Avenue, Southwest towards Southwest Cambridge
Speaker 7:  Street. I drove around with it for a while and I don't know, it
Speaker 7:  did all the CarPlay things. Google Maps is amazing on a much
Speaker 7:  larger screen. If you're used to a phone that's in a holster on your dashboard,
Speaker 7:  it was easy to see texts when I was parked. There's a lot of little perks
Speaker 7:  to it. Audio was a little bit more complicated.
Speaker 7:  It comes with a bunch of options to send audio. One,
Speaker 7:  there's a standard ox jack, which for me means a long
Speaker 7:  awkward snaking cable to the port in my car. You can use
Speaker 7:  Bluetooth, which is just horrible on my Prius. So that's a no.
Speaker 7:  You can send audio to FM radio, which I kind of love
Speaker 7:  and is an amazing throwback. Or it does have an internal
Speaker 7:  speaker, which is crappy, but it's actually fine for
Speaker 7:  directions if that's the only thing you need the audio for. And the
Speaker 13:  Light turn right onto 26th Avenue Southwest.
Speaker 7:  And by the way, If, you ever wanted to know what The Vergecast would sound
Speaker 7:  like on FM radio? Here you go.
Speaker 15:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Quantified REM
Speaker 15:  cycles.
Speaker 7:  So like I said, I drove around for an afternoon with it and
Speaker 7:  there were things I struggled with, but they don't actually have much to
Speaker 7:  do with the device itself. The screen is cheap, but it's
Speaker 7:  functional. But a couple things stood out. The first thing is to get the
Speaker 7:  most out of it, I would need to install it on my dashboard.
Speaker 7:  And then I'd need to snake the power to the cigarette lighter in
Speaker 7:  one part of the car, and then snake the audio cable to the UX port
Speaker 7:  in another part of the car. And if I wanted the backup camera, I'd have to
Speaker 7:  wire that to the brake light and to the screen. It's all
Speaker 7:  just a lot of cable management. Like you're putting a
Speaker 7:  screen in the car where there wasn't one, or in my case, finding a place
Speaker 7:  for a second screen, which is all doable, but it's not
Speaker 7:  something that tiktoks show you. 'cause you know they're all trying to sell
Speaker 7:  you this thing. Like if I did a TikTok review,
Speaker 7:  100% of it would just be really awkward cable management.
Speaker 7:  And then the other thing that I realized all at once as I was driving
Speaker 7:  down the street is that, oh wait, I live in a neighborhood
Speaker 7:  where car break-ins happen kind of a lot. And I
Speaker 7:  now have what looks like an iPad mini just sitting on my dashboard at all
Speaker 7:  times. Like this thing 100% is gonna get stolen at some point,
Speaker 7:  which again, is not a knock on the screen itself and it might not be a
Speaker 7:  concern for you where you live, but it's kind of a deal breaker for
Speaker 7:  me 'cause there's no way this thing is worth a broken window. So
Speaker 7:  Sean, what are we to make of this thing? Well,
Speaker 7:  at a really basic level, it does what it claims to do.
Speaker 7:  I don't know how long it will last. It's certainly really cheap, but
Speaker 7:  it all works. It gives you CarPlay in your car, If, you didn't have it before
Speaker 7:  and the rest of it is just up to you to make work with your car.
Speaker 7:  For me, I've always been jealous of people with CarPlay,
Speaker 7:  but now I'm faced with this question, is this actually better
Speaker 7:  than just putting my phone in a holster on the dashboard? And I
Speaker 7:  think my answer is no, honestly, but your answer
Speaker 7:  might be different.
Speaker 2:  Alright, right. That is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everyone
Speaker 2:  who was on the show, and thank you as always for listening. There's lots
Speaker 2:  more on everything we talked about from all the Jake Paul, Mike Tyson, Netflix
Speaker 2:  stuff to Roland Allen's book, to all the stuff about the
Speaker 2:  TikTok shop on The Verge dot com. I'll put a lot of links in the show notes.
Speaker 2:  There are a lot of links this week. But as always, read The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  It's a good website. And If you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or other
Speaker 2:  good ideas of notebooks that I should buy. You can always email us at Vergecast
Speaker 2:  at the birge.com or call the hotline eight six six VERGE one one. Again,
Speaker 2:  we have some fun stuff coming for the hotline in the next few weeks, so keep
Speaker 2:  an eye on our socials. Keep it locked here. We'll keep you posted. This show
Speaker 2:  is produced by Liam James, Wil Poor and Eric Gomez. The Vergecast is The
Speaker 2:  Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Nila and I will
Speaker 2:  be back on Friday to talk about all the news happening this week. All the
Speaker 2:  new gadgets, all the wild stuff with the FCC. And
Speaker 2:  maybe we will have named show and tell by then, but frankly, I wouldn't bet
Speaker 2:  on it. We'll see you then. Rock and roll