# Transcript
ID: a986c843-e7e9-45aa-962d-21722311a736
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-1180063519714313466/-8108472469955947969/s93290-US-5045s-1723233236.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, Alex Heath, and Lauren Feiner discuss a federal judge ruling that Google violated US antitrust law, X suing a group of major advertisers over an “illegal boycott”, and the rest of this week's wild tech news.
Speaker 5:  sue you because I I want money. And you said no. So
Speaker 5:  to court
Speaker 4:  It's a lot. It's a lot. We have an additional Alex Alex
Speaker 4:  Heath is here. Hi.
Speaker 6:  I am, I'm also not using Bing. You couldn't pay me to use it either.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah, we could have, I want to be clear. We could have also been the flagship
Speaker 4:  podcast if you can't pay me to use Bing. Another thing we're gonna
Speaker 4:  spend a lot of time on today, it, it's a big week. Lauren Finer is
Speaker 4:  also here. Hey Lauren. Hello. There's a lot of news this week.
Speaker 4:  I thought it was gonna be a quiet week. We, we really thought it was
Speaker 4:  gonna be a quiet week. And then on Monday the court
Speaker 4:  released a gigantic ruling in the Google search antitrust case. Finding
Speaker 4:  the Google search is a monopoly. We gotta talk all about that. The assistant
Speaker 4:  attorney general for antitrust, Jonathan Cantor was on decoder. We had just
Speaker 4:  a lot to say about that case. Lot to say about Apple in relation to that
Speaker 4:  case. Google was paying Apple for default placements. So we gotta spend time
Speaker 4:  in that. Then we're like, huh, all right, we know what's gonna happen this
Speaker 4:  week. Then Elon Musk filed an x, filed a
Speaker 4:  lawsuit against advertisers claiming antitrust
Speaker 4:  violations because they refuse to advertise an XI would
Speaker 4:  say not is clear cut a victory for that case as maybe
Speaker 4:  in the Google search case. We gotta talk about that. We have a
Speaker 4:  lightning round. There's a bunch of stuff in light around talk about actually,
Speaker 4:  and then of course, Disney Plus is raising prices. A real, a real bird chest.
Speaker 4:  Oh, and I judged a TV competition, which I thought I was gonna get a chance
Speaker 4:  to write about, but didn't because everyone's suing each other. I read so
Speaker 4:  many PDFs this week.
Speaker 6:  Wait, you judged a TV competition?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, like the, the, the the 20th annual TV shootout.
Speaker 4:  What? Yellow?
Speaker 5:  What was the actual TVs?
Speaker 4:  The actual TVs? We, they put, they put a bunch of OLEDs and micro LED TVs
Speaker 4:  in a room.
Speaker 4:  And I went into that room with a bunch of like, like high-end
Speaker 4:  Hollywood colorists and compression engineers.
Speaker 4:  and it was, it was like all of them. And then me as the judge and
Speaker 4:  we, and we looked at the TVs. We had long worksheets to fill out as we watched
Speaker 4:  different, like scenes of movies. And then we like rated and I was gonna
Speaker 4:  write it. I was like, this was my week to finally let go of
Speaker 4:  talking about the government and talk about what I love instead, which is
Speaker 4:  how TVs look. And I didn't get to do a lick of it.
Speaker 4:  Wow. What did the frame TV rank? The frame TV was not, it did not make
Speaker 4:  it to the competition. What
Speaker 5:  Immediately like booted
Speaker 4:  It, it, it wasn't even in the mix. Like it didn't even get into the,
Speaker 4:  there were six TVs in the, in the finals and the, the frame was not among
Speaker 4:  them.
Speaker 4:  They're not really finals. They just picked the six effects TVs in the market.
Speaker 4:  And then I will tell you the two brands, we'll talk about it, but the two
Speaker 4:  brands specifically said, do not include us in this competition.
Speaker 4:  Just looking to thank you.
Speaker 4:  We'll get to it and I'll talk about it and I promise I'll write about it
Speaker 4:  for next week. But that's what I thought I was gonna do this week. Like really
Speaker 4:  and truly, I thought I was gonna argue with people about whether micro led
Speaker 4:  ETS can compete with OLEDs. And I didn't do that because
Speaker 4:  our, our, the, the sheer number of PDFs generated by
Speaker 4:  the judicial branch of our government was out of control.
Speaker 4:  Like talk about a good time to buy a B Palmer. Just PS
Speaker 4:  days. Just forever. Alright, let's start with the Google searching.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. This case has been going on since what, 2020. It was filed under the
Speaker 4:  Trump administration in this sort of like classic Trump administration.
Speaker 4:  Like I dunno, let's sue Google. Like we're mad at them. But that
Speaker 5:  Was actually Biden, right? That that took it home.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And then obviously the Biden administration with, with Le Kahn and,
Speaker 4:  and specifically Jonathan Canter at the Department of Justice who runs the
Speaker 4:  antitrust division. You know, Le Kahn is the chair of the FTC
Speaker 4:  Cantor runs the antitrust division at the d oj. They've been sort of like
Speaker 4:  debating, AR arguing even who gets to take which antitrust
Speaker 4:  enforcement action and Google ended up at the doj. Lauren, you have some
Speaker 4:  color. Like even watching that, how do they decide who gets to do what?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, so generally how it breaks down is it's
Speaker 7:  somewhat based on just like the expertise of each agency. Like I think there's
Speaker 7:  certain industries that DOJ tends to take in certain
Speaker 7:  industries that FTC take tends to take. and it also,
Speaker 7:  maybe they'll consider like is this something where we might bring in the
Speaker 7:  FTC act, which obviously the FTC would use.
Speaker 7:  And maybe that feeds into the determination. But I think
Speaker 7:  generally it's just based on is this an industry that typically is A
Speaker 7:  DOJ or an FTC industry?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So the DOJ had this one again started under the Trump administration.
Speaker 4:  The Biden, DOJ carried on with it. There was a trial, we covered
Speaker 4:  the hell outta the trial. Eddie Q was on the stand. Tim Cook was on the stand.
Speaker 4:  Nadella was on the stand talking about whether being could compete with Google.
Speaker 5:  Was this the trial where they like just wouldn't let us see a lot of it.
Speaker 5:  It was a lot of it was closed
Speaker 7:  Off. Yes. Yeah, that's right. Yeah. There was a period where the
Speaker 7:  judge, I, I think it was a result of some of
Speaker 7:  the third parties in the cases that didn't want, you know, their business
Speaker 7:  information just aired out in front of the press and the public
Speaker 7:  kind of pushed for, you know, more behind closed
Speaker 7:  doors, elements of the trial. And the judge conceded to a lot of
Speaker 7:  that in the beginning. And then there was a lot of pushback from the press
Speaker 7:  and it became a bit more open. So yes, that was this trial.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, and it like the judge was like, well I believe Google when they say
Speaker 4:  these are trade secrets. And there was a lot of criticism. Lauren, from what
Speaker 4:  I understand, the judge took the criticism to heart. Like he was pretty stung
Speaker 4:  by it. And then he opened up and we got to cover more of it. We did, we did
Speaker 4:  cover the trial in an ongoing basis and then it was pretty quiet while he
Speaker 4:  was writing this opinion, which is 286 pages long.
Speaker 4:  He was writing a
Speaker 5:  Book.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it it is a, it is a book about search.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it was interesting 'cause I was just looking back at my stories from
Speaker 7:  the days of the closing arguments in May and I remember walking
Speaker 7:  away from that thinking like, you know, he kind of was holding his
Speaker 7:  cards close to the chest but you know, made a few
Speaker 7:  comments that seemed to dig at Google. But reading it back now having
Speaker 7:  seen the opinion, I can see like, oh he really was
Speaker 7:  kind of probably already drafting this and thinking about a lot of these
Speaker 7:  sections of the opinion even back then.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, so the, the, the ruling in the case 286
Speaker 4:  pages yesterday, I said to Sarah JI thought it was readable. And she was
Speaker 4:  like, you don't, you don't know what readable means. That's clear lawyer
Speaker 4:  You can read it. It's not like at one point
Speaker 4:  there he's talking about how ad auctions work and there's literally like
Speaker 4:  mathematical formula in it. It's there, there's a lot in
Speaker 4:  286 pages. But the main holdings are Google
Speaker 4:  search is a monopoly and he found that there's a market for general
Speaker 4:  search engines. Alex, you and I have talked about this,
Speaker 4:  whenever there's antitrust cases, the tech companies try to argue that markets
Speaker 4:  don't exist. Like Facebook is basically held off in antitrust action
Speaker 4:  by insisting that there's no such thing as a market for social networks and
Speaker 4:  Facebook is not in it. Even if there was, and that has worked until kind
Speaker 4:  of now when the judge found, okay, general search engines are a thing, people
Speaker 4:  understand what they are is distinct from TikTok search or whatever. So he
Speaker 4:  found general search as a market and Google is the only competitor and there's
Speaker 4:  a line in there. He is like, these are Fortune 500 companies, apple and whoever
Speaker 4:  else, and they can only turn to Google. There's nowhere else for 'em to go.
Speaker 6:  I really like the way that he defined that. It seemed like it was actually
Speaker 6:  the clearer way to say it, which is just a general search
Speaker 6:  engine encompasses a lot of the web. It's not a silo like TikTok,
Speaker 6:  TikTok, You can, I mean I've used TikTok for search to find
Speaker 6:  things that I'm looking at, but it's only TikTok content. And I thought the
Speaker 6:  way he just kind of clearly defined general search as being an
Speaker 6:  aggregation of a lot of different sources of content was helpful. Even like
Speaker 6:  following the trial, not as in the weeds as Lauren, but like I, the
Speaker 6:  definition stuff was always pretty wonky to me how they were defining different
Speaker 6:  corners of search. And I thought he actually did a pretty good job in the
Speaker 6:  opinion, the final ruling here laying it out. Oh
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I, that was something that during the closing arguments, I remember
Speaker 7:  the judge, I think Google was trying to make the case that, you know,
Speaker 7:  Amazon is a potential competitor and all these other things. And I remember
Speaker 7:  the judge saying something along the lines of like, well, you know, Amazon
Speaker 7:  doesn't like index the web. Like it is a different thing. So I think that's
Speaker 7:  something that he really took to heart.
Speaker 4:  He points out that he had expert witnesses in the case
Speaker 4:  who testified that the biggest advertisers on Google
Speaker 4:  and Bing are vertical search engines. So like
Speaker 4:  flight search engines or travel search engines or whatever. They advertise
Speaker 4:  a lot on Google 'cause that's where the audience for their searches are.
Speaker 4:  And he is like, well this is, they're obviously not substitutes. Like if
Speaker 4:  you're, if you're trying to acquire audience for your vertical search engine
Speaker 4:  and travel or whatever on Google, Google is obviously not substituted for
Speaker 4:  that. So he, he lays out this case and you know, if you want to get into
Speaker 4:  the nitty gritty legal analysis of it, you should just listen to to coder
Speaker 4:  with cantor 'cause we got into it and part of it is
Speaker 4:  understanding how the government is getting better at
Speaker 4:  defining these markets. 'cause this is where they have gotten tripped up
Speaker 4:  and where the tech companies have really won and pushed off a lot of this
Speaker 4:  enforcement for years by just, by just
Speaker 4:  tying these like deep philosophical knots of like what is it Even the market
Speaker 4:  that Google is in, even in this case, this is one of the funniest
Speaker 4:  counter arguments that Google made. They said that Google is not in the market
Speaker 4:  for search engines, it's in the market for answering queries.
Speaker 4:  Sure. Just like broadly, just like if you have a question, that's
Speaker 4:  the thing that Google does. Yeah. And like they're like every place you might
Speaker 4:  answer a question is a place that competes with Google. And the judge was
Speaker 4:  like, no. Like that's not true. If you search Amazon, you only get products,
Speaker 4:  you don't get answers to questions. Google is this like very general search
Speaker 4:  engine. So the government went there, they said a search engine and they
Speaker 4:  said that they're anti-competitive protecting the monopoly in search that
Speaker 4:  they have with the deals with Apple, which we should talk about at length.
Speaker 4:  So Apple pays Google $20 billion a year on the order of
Speaker 4:  $20 billion a year to be the default search provider on iOS and
Speaker 4:  the Mac and other Apple products. There are some conditions which are
Speaker 4:  the thing that make those deals anti-competitive. It's not just the money.
Speaker 4:  We should talk about those. And then they found that there's a monopoly for
Speaker 4:  search text ads, which is just the text ads in search,
Speaker 4:  not general search ads because there you do have competition from
Speaker 4:  TikTok and Amazon and all this other stuff, but search text ads, the ones
Speaker 4:  that show up on the search engine results page, the judge said, Hey, there's
Speaker 4:  a monopoly here and Google has acted anti competitively and this is I think
Speaker 4:  the shadiest part of the whole trial.
Speaker 4:  Google just slowly raises the prices of those ads
Speaker 4:  without considering what competitors might do or arrivals might go and
Speaker 4:  they hide those price increases in the auctions. Well
Speaker 4:  that was
Speaker 5:  What the judge said, like that was why he found that to be a monopoly, right?
Speaker 5:  Was because they just didn't have to care about anyone else and they could
Speaker 5:  just raise prices whenever. And he said, yeah, that's just the monopoly guys.
Speaker 5:  I don't know what to tell you.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, he did this in, in in both in the advertising part and in the search
Speaker 4:  engine part where he pointed out Google does stuff and it doesn't care that
Speaker 4:  people might leave. Which is, as we have noted on the
Speaker 4:  show many times, like the most essential truth of
Speaker 4:  the Google experience right now is like, boy you just blow stuff up,
Speaker 4:  you cancel stuff, you shut it down, you make it worse and there's nowhere
Speaker 4:  else to go and Google doesn't seem to care. And the judge pointed
Speaker 4:  out, he was like, this is only a firm with monopoly power can get away with
Speaker 4:  some of the stuff that they do, including raising prices by making it
Speaker 4:  appear that the auctions, you know when you buy an ad on Google search, like
Speaker 4:  buy a keyword, you buy like airline flights or whatever, keyword hotels.
Speaker 4:  Yeah these are like hotly contested keywords. You wanna put advertising around
Speaker 4:  those keywords in search. And so Google is raising the prices of those
Speaker 4:  auctions making it appear as though it's like noisy, like there's a
Speaker 4:  more demand or it's fluctuating but really over time it's just raising the
Speaker 4:  price. And that the judge found was that that was evidence of monopoly behavior
Speaker 4:  and also just like wrong, right? So this, this is a huge decision.
Speaker 4:  There's stuff where they didn't, the government didn't win. There's no monopoly
Speaker 4:  in like, there's no monopoly in general search advertising.
Speaker 4:  The Google didn't get sanctioned for the way it treats. Its like ad tech
Speaker 4:  stack, which you probably know is called double click and now has another
Speaker 4:  name and then Google deleted a lot of its chat history and the government
Speaker 4:  wanted sanctions for that and then Google deleted a lot of internal records
Speaker 4:  and the government wanted sanctions for that. I didn't get that. So that's
Speaker 4:  all cast aside. But the main ones, the important ones are Google search and
Speaker 4:  Monopoly. Google's acting anti competitively. Google text ads are a monopoly.
Speaker 4:  Google is raising the prices anti competitively. That's, it just feels
Speaker 4:  like a huge deal. Cantor told me this case goes on the Mount Rushmore
Speaker 4:  of antitrust decisions, which, well you, you, which implies there's a Mount
Speaker 4:  Rushmore of antitrust decisions.
Speaker 5:  Like I wanna talk about a lot of the Apple stuff here. But you talked at
Speaker 5:  Cantor, did he explain what they're gonna do next? Did he,
Speaker 5:  did he say Oh yeah we're gonna get 'em for this.
Speaker 4:  Oh so this is, yeah this is important to note. Lauren, I'm, I'm curious if
Speaker 4:  you've heard anything here but the, the trial is what's called a bifurcated
Speaker 4:  trial. So there's this part which is did you do it and is it wrong?
Speaker 4:  Yes, Google search monopoly. Then there's what's called the remedies phase
Speaker 4:  where the court lays out a process for how it will basically hold a second
Speaker 4:  trial where they'll figure out what the punishment is and how they will fix
Speaker 4:  it. And that could be anything the government could ask for anything. The
Speaker 4:  court could impose anything. It could be fines, it could be structural
Speaker 4:  that's breaking up Google, it could be behavioral. In other cases the, you
Speaker 4:  know, there's like oversight of a company's behavior to make sure it doesn't
Speaker 4:  do the bad thing. Again all they're all kind of all on the table and Cantor
Speaker 4:  just, I mean like he's a government lawyer. I was like answer the question.
Speaker 4:  He is like, I'm not gonna answer your question. Like very directly, very
Speaker 4:  charmingly. It was like, I'm super not answering your question but You can,
Speaker 4:  You can look back to history. You know the Microsoft case comes up over
Speaker 4:  and over again in this and that was like a lengthy remedies phase, also
Speaker 4:  bifurcated trial. They negotiated a settlement then there was a second trial
Speaker 4:  to see if the settlement was fair and then Microsoft was under the microscope
Speaker 4:  with oversight for a long time to make sure it didn't do a bunch of Microsoft
Speaker 4:  stuff. You can, You can see that potentially happening in here.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Lauren, did you get any sense from like, I guess they're in DC of
Speaker 5:  people at how they're, how they're gonna react to it, what kind of punishments
Speaker 5:  they might wanna do. Seeing his cantor was like refusing to give neli any
Speaker 5:  of the good stuff. He was just like, nah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I mean I think that I, I know that a lot of the
Speaker 7:  rivals to Google who have been, you know, really cheering
Speaker 7:  on this case from the DOJ side, they, you know, I think
Speaker 7:  they're really cheering this decision but at the same time are holding
Speaker 7:  back a little bit because they know that what really matters here is
Speaker 7:  what Google is made to do to respond to the
Speaker 7:  finding of liability. So I think, you know, there is a little
Speaker 7:  bit of hesitance that, you know, maybe there's gonna be some
Speaker 7:  sort of remedy that doesn't fully fix the problems. You know, maybe something
Speaker 7:  like a search screen that we've seen in Europe that like doesn't really seem
Speaker 7:  to do too much. So I think there's just a feeling of
Speaker 7:  like, alright we're really happy about this but also we know it's not done
Speaker 7:  yet. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  We should know. Google has already said it's gonna appeal. The ruling, the
Speaker 4:  statement from president of Global Affairs Kent Walker is,
Speaker 4:  it's actually pretty funny. It says this decision recognizes that Google
Speaker 4:  offers the best search engine but concludes we shouldn't be allowed to make
Speaker 4:  it easily available. It's, he's basically saying that this is nonsensical.
Speaker 4:  I don't know if that is what the decision actually says. It is true.
Speaker 4:  The decision says over and over again Google is the best search engine but
Speaker 4:  then is like, it's also the only one. Like
Speaker 7:  I think it's also that, you know, I think the judge bought
Speaker 7:  into this argument that the DOJ was making that like there's kind of
Speaker 7:  this flywheel effect where like we, you know, it gets
Speaker 7:  all these defaults like gets all these people to use its platform
Speaker 7:  and you know, make all these queries and then it has all this really good
Speaker 7:  data and then it uses that data to
Speaker 7:  just make the search engine better and monetize that.
Speaker 7:  And so I think, you know, he's saying yeah it is a really good
Speaker 7:  product but that's also because of these
Speaker 7:  exclusive contracts that have gotten it to that place. Which
Speaker 5:  Like the, I think maybe you pointed this out Neli or maybe it was Sarah J
Speaker 5:  online that Apple is gonna have to like,
Speaker 5:  like Apple could have taken that $20 billion it gives Google every time and
Speaker 5:  gone and made its own competitive search engine for
Speaker 5:  less than that. And that kind of like factored into the judge's
Speaker 5:  reasoning.
Speaker 4:  Yeah we should really, we should generally talk about Apple but yeah let's
Speaker 4:  talk about Apple. Yeah know Google pays Apple $20 billion a year and Google
Speaker 4:  has also internally estimated that for Apple to build a search engine
Speaker 4:  will cost Apple $20 billion, right? Hmm. So there's only
Speaker 4:  so many companies that can compete with Google. One of them is
Speaker 4:  Apple, one of them. And, and you know, and there's like lots of reasons and
Speaker 4:  there's lots of reasons for that. One of them, the most important one
Speaker 4:  is that Apple can set the default on an iPhone so it can collect all of this
Speaker 4:  data and like a huge percentage
Speaker 4:  of Google's queries for search come
Speaker 4:  from default placements, right? It's like 50% of all Google search
Speaker 4:  queries come from default placements on mobile or desktop, whether it's Android
Speaker 4:  phones or iPhones or whatever. So Apple has a massive share of those
Speaker 4:  default placements, particularly on mobile. And so it could build a search
Speaker 4:  engine, it can compete 'cause it has all of that and Google pays the money
Speaker 4:  to keep them from doing it. And inside of that
Speaker 4:  services agreement it also puts in conditions that
Speaker 4:  Apple agrees not to make things that look like search
Speaker 4:  better at search. So Siri can't get better
Speaker 4:  like the, I think the agreement says it can't get better than it is today
Speaker 4:  or it can't be meaningful improved password to today Spotlight search can't
Speaker 4:  get better. There's some documents that are, you know, as part of the exhibits,
Speaker 4:  apple considered putting some advertising into Spotlight search
Speaker 4:  on the iPhone and they just like, well we gotta talk to Google about that
Speaker 4:  but we don't wanna renegotiate this Google deal. I guess we won't do that
Speaker 4:  and You can just see them. They're just held back by the existence of this
Speaker 4:  deal and its conditions with Google. Like we've asked a million times, why
Speaker 4:  doesn't Apple just build a search engine? And the answer is $20 billion a
Speaker 4:  year. Yep. That's just fully the answer. And that's actually the thing
Speaker 4:  that's anti-competitive, not the default placement, right? Not
Speaker 4:  buying the default. It's the conditions that say You can, you also cannot
Speaker 4:  compete with us but
Speaker 5:  Apple doesn't want to. Right? Like, like they said, no we don't
Speaker 5:  wanna use Bing, we don't wanna put something else
Speaker 4:  In. So one of the absolute funniest conditions of
Speaker 4:  the agreement with Google is that Apple is required to defend
Speaker 4:  the deal against regulatory actions. So like yeah,
Speaker 4:  apple said a bunch of stuff that trial but they're legally
Speaker 4:  obligated because of their contract with Google to cod defend the
Speaker 4:  deal in the face of regulatory efforts.
Speaker 5:  That's not shady. That's that's totally normal way it's pretty to do business.
Speaker 5:  That's fine.
Speaker 4:  So yeah, I mean it's true that Apple says they don't want to, they don't
Speaker 4:  need to. Apple repeatedly said that Google is the best. There are some incredible
Speaker 4:  quotes here. Eddie Q testified, they said
Speaker 4:  would you ever use Bing? And he said there's no price Microsoft could pay
Speaker 4:  to make us set Bing as the default. And then he said they could give us the
Speaker 4:  whole thing for free. They could give us the company and we
Speaker 4:  wouldn't use Bing like Microsoft, you could just have Microsoft. And he is
Speaker 4:  like, no, Google is the best. And it's like maybe you believe that
Speaker 4:  but maybe you have a contract that says you have to say it like I don't know.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like if, if you rolled up to Tim Cook and you're like here's what we
Speaker 4:  get Microsoft like I feel like he'd be like we should talk about this.
Speaker 5:  I mean Bing is
Speaker 5:  notoriously awful. Maybe just like Eddie was trying to like find some good
Speaker 5:  flight deals.
Speaker 6:  Obviously he has to say that I think it's interesting that this contract
Speaker 6:  was also done in 2016. So Apple and
Speaker 6:  the the most recent search contract between Apple and Google, which means
Speaker 6:  that they knew in 2016 that this deal
Speaker 6:  looked bad and they put a clause in saying they both needed to defend
Speaker 6:  themselves against regulators. That's just a massive red flag. I
Speaker 6:  don't know about you guys, I always felt like Google was gonna lose this
Speaker 6:  case just because of how mafia like this
Speaker 6:  arrangement has been. And the problem with Google's
Speaker 6:  core argument at a very high level is this inherent
Speaker 6:  contradiction of their argument was we're winning 'cause we're the
Speaker 6:  best, we're the best search engine, right? That was their at the highest
Speaker 6:  level legal argument, but then also paying a
Speaker 6:  lot of money to win. Yeah. So what is it? Is it actually because you're
Speaker 6:  the best or because you're paying money? And Google was never able to address
Speaker 6:  that contradiction because I think they know that this contract is anti-competitive.
Speaker 6:  I think all sides know this and I don't think it's started that way. Like
Speaker 6:  I don't think it's an over exaggeration either to say that this contract
Speaker 6:  has shaped Silicon Valley, maybe more than any other
Speaker 6:  contract between two companies in the sense of how Google and Apple
Speaker 6:  grew together and have been kind of weirdly joined at the hip
Speaker 6:  since, you know, I the iPhone with Steve Jobs and
Speaker 6:  Eric Schmidt coming on stage together and
Speaker 6:  they've kind of let each other grow and not,
Speaker 6:  you know, there hasn't been a turf war because of this very lucrative deal.
Speaker 6:  So you've got things like Apple uses Google Cloud a lot.
Speaker 6:  We found out that Apple intelligence was trained exclusively on
Speaker 6:  Google's TPUs instead of Nvidia hardware. Google helps
Speaker 6:  serve advertising through Apple's
Speaker 6:  integrated iOS placements that's been happening for years.
Speaker 6:  They've just like become very enjoined in a way that yeah,
Speaker 6:  Eddie could say, you know, we we're not gonna like do
Speaker 6:  this for the whole company. But it's also like that's that's
Speaker 6:  because they kind of already are doing this with, with Google.
Speaker 6:  Like they,
Speaker 5:  So they really did just kind of carve out and say like, okay, you get this
Speaker 5:  set. I mean, not on paper, but they really did just kind of carve
Speaker 5:  things out and say, okay, you get search, we're gonna take phones.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Well I I don't I think there's like teams inside of Google who, who do not
Speaker 4:  know that anyone
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like pixel teams.
Speaker 4:  Like what? But you know, it's, it's fascinating. The, the phone piece
Speaker 4:  is really interesting, right? Because obviously Android, Android exists and
Speaker 4:  I agree with you Alex, I think the contract that Google has shaped a lot
Speaker 4:  of thing that I agree with the ox. I think that the Apple Google contract
Speaker 4:  in particular has shaped a lot of things and it's like a black
Speaker 4:  hole. It's like dis distorted the fabric of tech space time around it for
Speaker 4:  a long time. But Google has these same deals with tons of other
Speaker 4:  companies. It has these deals with carriers, it has T-Mobile and
Speaker 4:  at t and Verizon all have similar default placement deals
Speaker 4:  because you know, the carriers provision apps and services on the phones
Speaker 4:  they sell and Google knows that's like a very powerful mechanism of
Speaker 4:  distribution. And if they didn't pay Microsoft would and then Microsoft
Speaker 4:  would've slightly more distribution. There's a study in the case the
Speaker 4:  the judge cites from inside of Google. It's very small. I'm gonna warn you
Speaker 4:  now the sample size is tiny, it's like 26 people. But Google that a study
Speaker 4:  of 26 people and they found that half of them did not
Speaker 4:  know when Google was switched out for Bing on their iPhones. They just like
Speaker 4:  didn't notice because no one notices. That
Speaker 5:  Seems real,
Speaker 4:  Right? And like these defaults are super powerful. The government cantor
Speaker 4:  told me he is like the, the, the thing we did for the first time in any antitrust
Speaker 4:  case is we put a behavioral scientist on the stand to point out that
Speaker 4:  no one changes the defaults and habits are powerful And that, and the judge
Speaker 4:  bought it. Like he comes back to the testimony from this behavioral scientist
Speaker 4:  several times at one point, I think this is like the most Vergecast thing
Speaker 4:  ever. You might recall that Verizon owned Yahoo. They they did,
Speaker 4:  they did. That was a surreal thing that happened inside of a company called
Speaker 4:  Oath that they made that combined Yahoo with a OL.
Speaker 4:  This isn't important except to say like The Verge was born out of
Speaker 4:  AOL's bullshit. So like it's very personal to me that Verizon made oath
Speaker 4:  at one point but Verizon owned Yahoo and it wanted to
Speaker 4:  preload Yahoo search on its phones and they looked at
Speaker 4:  the opportunity cost of doing that and how much it would work, how much it
Speaker 4:  would cost and what it would take. And they looked at the check from Google
Speaker 4:  and they picked the check from Google, right? They took their
Speaker 4:  own product that they had bought and they're like, we could make this good
Speaker 4:  by putting it in front of more people and getting that clickstream data and
Speaker 4:  making the search engine better. Or we could just take Google's money
Speaker 4:  and Google's like, what if it was more money and then Verizon caved and they
Speaker 4:  flipped Yahoo and you're like whoa, why? Why didn't anyone ever try with
Speaker 4:  Yahoo? It's because Google just made sure it couldn't get the
Speaker 4:  distribution. Also very, VIR has one of my favorite parts of this whole decision.
Speaker 4:  There's a lengthy conversation about bloatware and Android phones
Speaker 4:  and I don't know if I believe this, but there's all this evidence
Speaker 4:  that people won't accept three browsers on their phones
Speaker 4:  or three search widgets, but they will take two because Samsung
Speaker 4:  has two, right? So like there's like internal Google emails and evidence
Speaker 4:  and like meeting notes where they're like we're not so worried
Speaker 4:  that our deal with Samsung for distribution where there's
Speaker 4:  our browser and Samsung's browser is under threat from
Speaker 4:  Microsoft. 'cause no one would ever accept three browsers. And it's like,
Speaker 4:  I don't know man, I feel like Samsung's like one minute away from doing three
Speaker 4:  browsers. Samsung
Speaker 5:  Is a hundred percent, is it Samsung gonna do like four different
Speaker 4:  Browsers? Yeah. It's like we're very close and like no one, they're like
Speaker 4:  absolutely not two search widgets on the home screen, heaven
Speaker 4:  forbid. And it's like, I don't know, have you met these carriers? Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  if not for your exclusivity contracts. Like they would put two search
Speaker 4:  widgets on the home screen. Like I think they just, they're minutes away
Speaker 4:  from doing this. They
Speaker 5:  Just forgot Bloatware. They just like forgot how bloated phones were before
Speaker 4:  Apple. It's a, there's a lengthy discussion of bloatware in this decision
Speaker 4:  and how Google sort of like used the threat of bloatware
Speaker 4:  to, to make sure they were an exclusive provider of search on on these devices.
Speaker 4:  And you just see it up and down the stack. They, they find their angles
Speaker 4:  to make sure there isn't competition and they press their advantage on those
Speaker 4:  angles. And I, to me it's well that's why we don't have other search
Speaker 4:  engines. Like there's Bing and Bing just isn't good enough
Speaker 4:  and like the judge basically says Bing isn't good enough. Apple maybe asked
Speaker 4:  required to say it says Bing isn't good enough. Google's out there running
Speaker 4:  benchmarks saying Bing isn't good enough and then sort of knowingly making
Speaker 4:  their product worse and it's fine. What
Speaker 5:  Was the number? There was one number in the, in the decision that was like
Speaker 5:  it would take Bing 17 years to get the same
Speaker 5:  amount of click data that Google gets in a day or something.
Speaker 7:  So basically in this opinion the judge says that
Speaker 7:  13 months of user data acquired by Google is equivalent to over 17
Speaker 7:  years of data on Bing,
Speaker 4:  Right? And that's like the amount of amount of use Google gets in 13
Speaker 4:  months is it would take being 17 years
Speaker 4:  and all of that feeds back into the ranking model. It's like a really interesting
Speaker 4:  thing in this opinion is the stuff
Speaker 4:  he dismisses, right? He says TikTok is not a competitor Google search. And
Speaker 4:  then he's like, I know you all want me to talk about AI and how AI might
Speaker 4:  like dero Google search but we're not there yet. It hasn't happened yet.
Speaker 4:  I don't see it and I've got all this evidence and testimony from Google's
Speaker 4:  on people saying they need the user data even when they try
Speaker 4:  the AI tools, even when Google puts its AI models up to make the search results,
Speaker 4:  it's the click data that actually helps them refine the search.
Speaker 6:  They need the feedback loop, right? Yeah. And this is what I
Speaker 6:  hear talking to like Meta and other companies. Like they
Speaker 6:  really think that the people who win at large scale network effects businesses
Speaker 6:  like this just have the feedback loop and AI
Speaker 6:  search. If it just gives you the answer you're not
Speaker 6:  learning a lot about is the answer good, how can we improve it?
Speaker 6:  Because you don't have an interface where people are browsing clicking the
Speaker 6:  links going from pages and yeah it's smart of Google. I,
Speaker 6:  you know, they recognized early that search was a network
Speaker 6:  effects business and aggregator business and
Speaker 6:  they went out and bought all kinds of distribution. They did
Speaker 6:  Android purely to get Google search out there on phones. They
Speaker 6:  realized they didn't own a phone so they made an, they bought an OS and scaled
Speaker 6:  it and did all these like funny business, you know, deals
Speaker 6:  to basically bundle. And this is like, this is a tale as old
Speaker 6:  as ti as time. I mean Microsoft, we'll get into this I'm sure Microsoft
Speaker 6:  20 years ago got its hand slapped by the DOJ for doing almost the
Speaker 6:  exact same thing. And the characters that come up in this case
Speaker 6:  have a fascinating background in that case. Like Kent Walker
Speaker 6:  who's running legal at Google was the general counsel for Netscape during
Speaker 6:  the Microsoft antitrust trial. Like he, he understands like
Speaker 6:  he understands bundling and what it does to the smaller players. You can't
Speaker 6:  see this if you're listening to this, but I'm wearing a Microsoft logo shirt
Speaker 4:  From the early two 2000 from the trials and
Speaker 6:  Of this beautiful. So yeah, I just find it interesting that like
Speaker 6:  if you look back at the last time a case like this was brought was Microsoft
Speaker 6:  and Microsoft was so dominant, so ascended and the question was will
Speaker 6:  Microsoft control the consumer and point to the internet, right?
Speaker 6:  And now 20 years later as a result of that decision, Microsoft didn't get
Speaker 6:  broken up but it changed a lot as a result. We've got Eddie
Speaker 6:  Q in court saying you couldn't give me all of Microsoft to use bank. Right?
Speaker 6:  And it's like what does that mean for Google in 20 years? Yeah. Like that's
Speaker 6:  what these cases do and this is why it's such a big deal long term.
Speaker 4:  So this is what Cantor has said to me on decoder, again, I won't get too
Speaker 4:  into the weeds and legal stuff, but his takeaway, his big consumery
Speaker 4:  takeaway was this case is a continuation of the Microsoft
Speaker 4:  case. The opinion itself, the judge makes endless references to the Microsoft
Speaker 4:  opinion. He says I'm using the same analytical framework as the Microsoft
Speaker 4:  case. And Cantor's point to me was that case was about
Speaker 4:  the application model moving from Windows to the web, which it
Speaker 4:  definitely did. Now whether or not you want to ascribe that to antitrust
Speaker 4:  action or not, a lot of people have a lot of arguments. But a thing that
Speaker 4:  really happened is we run apps and web browsers now and not natively
Speaker 4:  on Intel processors on Windows. Like we just run web apps. We're making this
Speaker 4:  podcast in a web app right now. A very cranky web app I would add that only
Speaker 4:  runs in Chrome. There's your antitrust problems.
Speaker 4:  But the application model moved to the web, it allowed a company like
Speaker 4:  Google to exist because Microsoft wasn't able to bundle Internet Explorer
Speaker 4:  and force out other browsers. So you had browser competition, which meant
Speaker 4:  you had application model competition on and on and on. And now you get to
Speaker 4:  Google and now the government has cases against not only Google but also
Speaker 4:  Apple basically alleging the same thing and cantor's like we have to
Speaker 4:  make sure the next generation of applications is allowed to exist. And it's
Speaker 4:  these moments when everyone can see the change that the incumbents
Speaker 4:  try to crush the, in the insurgent models. And he, his
Speaker 4:  point is Google is trying to do that potentially with AI search. They see
Speaker 4:  it coming. So they're trying to lock down their advantage and make sure no
Speaker 4:  one else gets distribution, right? And they can capture that market and he
Speaker 4:  thinks Apple is trying to do that on the iPhone too. I dunno if they're gonna
Speaker 4:  win the Apple case, but that's the sort of his theory of the situation is
Speaker 4:  a direct continuation from Microsoft. The Microsoft case is generally interesting
Speaker 4:  because you know it's been 20, they, they started that investigation in 1990
Speaker 4:  and they reached resolution in what, 2001? Yeah. So that took a long time
Speaker 4:  and you know, bill Gates is out there being like, yeah that distracted me
Speaker 4:  so I didn't do smartphones. and it's like, yeah, like that's one way of thinking
Speaker 4:  about it. But you also made Windows foam, which was bad.
Speaker 5:  That's what he likes to say. Like he's just like, it distracted me. It's
Speaker 5:  like, no, it didn't distract you that much 'cause you made a phone, you just
Speaker 5:  made a crummy phone and you don't want people to know talk about it.
Speaker 4:  Well
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it, it makes these companies, especially at this scale just
Speaker 6:  super skittish, right? And you're, and I do think there is an argument that
Speaker 6:  Microsoft missed the mobile wave and didn't do it right because
Speaker 6:  it was skittish because it was on, it was on its back foot, it was
Speaker 6:  subsumed by litigation and regulatory response internally.
Speaker 6:  And it's hard to not see that maybe playing out with Google
Speaker 6:  here and You can see Google already reacting this way in that like
Speaker 6:  they're, the way that they fake bought at character AI last
Speaker 6:  week for example, which is totally wild. It came out after
Speaker 6:  The Vergecast last week, I'll just quickly recap it. They basically bought
Speaker 6:  this AI company without doing it and they paid all the investors
Speaker 6:  and the employees as if they bought the company, but they only took the AI
Speaker 6:  people and are leaving the husk, the flaming husk of what they left
Speaker 6:  behind And saying good luck but
Speaker 6:  not a, not a m and a event because they didn't buy equity.
Speaker 6:  But they're doing deals like this because they already feel this
Speaker 6:  antitrust scrutiny and they're not able to take the kind of big swings that
Speaker 6:  they took to get to where they are now, which is buying YouTube, buying
Speaker 6:  double click, buying these things that fortified their monopoly.
Speaker 6:  And there's a really strong argument to be made that in the same way this
Speaker 6:  kept Microsoft from being able to be so aggressive in the early two
Speaker 6:  thousands that could happen again with Google here. Okay,
Speaker 4:  But here's the counter argument to that. Microsoft was distracted and
Speaker 4:  lost in compliance efforts and I dunno, bill Gate was drinking tequila and
Speaker 4:  screaming at the moon about the Department of Justice or whatever he was
Speaker 4:  doing instead of inventing the iPhone
Speaker 5:  Jumping over chairs.
Speaker 4:  I do believe that fine, maybe you believe that's a hundred percent true.
Speaker 4:  Google exists. Apple was allowed to be resurgent
Speaker 4:  because they put out the iMac with a web browser on it.
Speaker 4:  Like the, the iMac running OS nine when it came out was
Speaker 4:  not like there's a suite of great OS nine
Speaker 4:  applications for the Mac. It was, this is the computer
Speaker 4:  that's easiest to get on the web with. That's how they marketed it because
Speaker 4:  the web was the application environment, it was the thing everybody wanted.
Speaker 4:  It wasn't a bunch of weird intel CD rom Windows
Speaker 4:  applications or whatever was happening before. And Carta was not the thing,
Speaker 4:  right? It was the web and that worked
Speaker 4:  like I, here we are in 2024 and we're like Apple and Google are dominant
Speaker 4:  companies because Microsoft was forced
Speaker 4:  or coerced or distracted away from foreclosing that competition.
Speaker 4:  And it's pretty hard. Like You can look at that in hindsight and
Speaker 4:  I promise you a bunch of old head VCs and investors will like,
Speaker 4:  and x Microsoft executives in particular will litigate and
Speaker 4:  re-litigate whether that actually happened or whether Apple was just better
Speaker 4:  or whatever. But it is true that Microsoft was turned away and the web was
Speaker 4:  allowed to be dominant and the dominance of the web is what enabled the iMac
Speaker 4:  to be successful. And now we're here with the iPhone, right? Like that's
Speaker 4:  the line.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think that's what a lot of advocates for antitrust
Speaker 7:  enforcement would say is just like, yeah maybe, you know, with
Speaker 7:  Microsoft, we saw Microsoft bogged down and it's legal
Speaker 7:  woes for a while, but you know what would've been a bad
Speaker 7:  outcome was like never getting the rise of Apple and Google in the first
Speaker 7:  place. Never getting those products. Not that Microsoft wasn't the one to
Speaker 7:  invent those.
Speaker 5:  Well, and also Microsoft is doing just
Speaker 4:  They figured it out.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, right. Like, like it forced 'em to be competitive. It forced 'em to
Speaker 5:  think that's why they, they they invested in Azure and, and they built up
Speaker 5:  this, this huge cloud computing business. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Microsoft is literal, Nadel is like, I wanna make a dance. Like yeah, like
Speaker 4:  having a good time of his life.
Speaker 5:  Like competition is in fact good. And when these companies get so big that
Speaker 5:  they don't compete, we do see things like this and I'm, I'm not just saying
Speaker 5:  that because I just bought a car with Google inside and it's hot garbage
Speaker 5:  and I can really feel how their, their monopoly is
Speaker 5:  affecting me personally. But you do feel it like everything. Oh, you
Speaker 6:  Feel it. Oh you feel it. Google's stock price in the last five years is up
Speaker 6:  177%. Do we feel like search has gotten
Speaker 6:  177% better in the last
Speaker 5:  Five years? Worse. It's actually theyve
Speaker 4:  Gone opposite direct. No, they've canceled 177% of their products.
Speaker 4:  That's all they've done. They've just, they've just end of life
Speaker 4:  177% of the things they invented. But
Speaker 4:  I think this is the part that's really hard and I, you know, you couldn't
Speaker 4:  have guaranteed in 2001 that Apple would be resurgent or that Google
Speaker 4:  would come to be dominant on the web. That they, they're dominant and I think
Speaker 4:  it's really hard to sit here in 2024 and predict that OpenAI won
Speaker 4:  will now have a chance to become the next Google OpenAI won. Which I
Speaker 4:  will remind everyone, Microsoft owns 51% You can
Speaker 4:  49 You can't predict. You can't predict that it's 49. You can't
Speaker 4:  predict that Microsoft will, or you can't predict that TikTok
Speaker 4:  will actually turn into a search engine because it has some designs on like
Speaker 4:  larger search applications who might get banned. Like
Speaker 4:  there might be some startup that, you know next year is
Speaker 4:  gonna take off and grow at the scale. It's really hard to make the
Speaker 4:  forward-looking argument, especially when we don't know what the remedy is
Speaker 4:  gonna be. Right? If the government shows up and says break up Google and
Speaker 4:  the only way to fix this is to, I break up YouTube and Google and the
Speaker 4:  first thing YouTube is gonna do is build a general search engine. 'cause
Speaker 4:  it's obvious that that's what they should do. And the first thing newly broken
Speaker 4:  up Google will do is build a video platform. 'cause like sure, but is what
Speaker 4:  they're gonna ask for. We don't know Lauren, I just gonna ask Lauren, I
Speaker 6:  I was gonna ask Lauren this, do we think the DOJ actually wants to break
Speaker 6:  up Google? I think they actually just want Google to not be able to
Speaker 6:  spend 30 billion a year buying their distribution.
Speaker 7:  I mean I would, I think the strongest signal we have is just the
Speaker 7:  statements from Cantor himself about how he thinks about
Speaker 7:  remedies generally, and that's that he prefers structural remedies,
Speaker 7:  AKA breakups. And so I think how, how sweeping
Speaker 7:  will that structural remedy be that they ask for? I don't know, but,
Speaker 7:  and you know, will they, is there a chance that they decide it's better to
Speaker 7:  go with a behavioral remedy, AKA like ask them to stop doing
Speaker 7:  something, ask them to stop putting certain terms in their contracts? Maybe
Speaker 7:  they think that's more appropriate in this case, but I think
Speaker 7:  we have to seriously consider that, you know, this
Speaker 7:  structural remedies are something that Jonathan Cantor tends to
Speaker 7:  like.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, well sure. My guess my point is like negotiating 1 0 1 is you always
Speaker 6:  ask for more than you know you're gonna get. I think they will
Speaker 4:  Gimme the whole company. Yeah, give me all of Microsoft.
Speaker 6:  They will obviously ask to break up Google. I think in Cantor's heart of
Speaker 6:  hearts, he would actually be okay if all that came out of this case
Speaker 6:  was what happened in the Microsoft case, which is the government went for
Speaker 6:  a breakup, they didn't get it, but Microsoft was foreclosed from doing these
Speaker 6:  bundling anti-competitive contracts for distribution. I have
Speaker 6:  to think the DOJ would be happy with that and that would be just as I think
Speaker 6:  impactful on all of tech if
Speaker 6:  Google just can't buy out its distribution.
Speaker 5:  But but would would it?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think
Speaker 5:  So because I, I think like how, if you think of, okay, how do they do
Speaker 5:  that? How do they change that? Well then first thing, how do you change it
Speaker 5:  on the iPhone? How do you change what that default is because there's always
Speaker 5:  a default.
Speaker 4:  Well, so I, one of inside of that question I think is a very
Speaker 4:  weird thing, which, so inside of that
Speaker 4:  question I think is a, a, a hard problem to grapple with, which is right
Speaker 4:  now Apple collects $20 billion here from Google. If it can no longer collect
Speaker 4:  that money, will it spend money to make its own search
Speaker 4:  product? I that weird, it's not spending on
Speaker 5:  Bing,
Speaker 4:  Right? It's yeah, it's not gonna take the money from Bing as we know at EQ
Speaker 4:  won't, there's no sum. He's unviable integrity is unimpeachable
Speaker 4:  by Bing specifically. But you know, Cantor told
Speaker 4:  me that he thinks that AI turn is a big inflection point
Speaker 4:  and he wants the remedy to be forward looking, right? He's not like, he's
Speaker 4:  like, I can't fix 15 years of anti-competitive behavior. I need to make it
Speaker 4:  so the future has competition in it. So if you prevent the money, if you
Speaker 4:  prevent the 20 billion from an Apple, does Apple invest more in Apple intelligence?
Speaker 4:  Does it start answering more questions directly? Does it make, you
Speaker 4:  know, right now it's OpenAI won is the, the sort of general search product
Speaker 4:  built into Apple intelligence, but we know they're gonna make a deal with
Speaker 4:  Google too. Maybe there's more choices there, right? And like
Speaker 4:  Apple's going to to to more providers and You can see like maybe
Speaker 4:  that creates a different outcome.
Speaker 5:  Like for me it's like, is it gonna make Siri better?
Speaker 6:  I think we're underestimating the power of money and the power of
Speaker 6:  when you're, so yes, 20, it's 20 billion, but it's actually more than that.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's a meaningful percent of Apple's profit margin because the Google
Speaker 6:  check is a hundred percent margin. So when you subtract the Google
Speaker 6:  money Apple services business, which is the narrative for the future
Speaker 6:  growth of the stock that Tim Cook has been spending for 10 years collapsed
Speaker 6:  by a quarter, it's significant. And I think we're
Speaker 6:  underestimating the just capitalistic inherent
Speaker 6:  drivers here of when you are not getting a check to not do
Speaker 6:  something anymore, you may go do that thing.
Speaker 6:  And for the last, you know, 10 years, Apple's been getting paid an
Speaker 6:  ungodly amount of money to just like, don't look over there.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Hey Liam, just to end on this, we've talked a lot about the, the decision
Speaker 4:  and the mechanics of Apple and what might happen next. Heath, you're, you
Speaker 4:  know, you're sourced inside all these companies. What's the vibe inside of
Speaker 4:  Google right now? Are they afraid? Are they worried? Are they watching their
Speaker 4:  stock price? Like what, what's happening?
Speaker 6:  They're always watching the stock price. I think that
Speaker 6:  what will really start to change things is when we get closer
Speaker 6:  into this remedy phase and there's an actual sense of
Speaker 6:  is it a breakup? Is it Apple can no longer, you know,
Speaker 6:  just be our default. Do we have to like make this a fair playing field?
Speaker 6:  We have to open up our distribution lanes. We can't bundle
Speaker 6:  Android and search when that stuff starts becoming more
Speaker 6:  concretely explained, which Lauren, correct me if I'm wrong, but it
Speaker 6:  sounds like will be this fall, this is happening pretty soon, right? So
Speaker 6:  I would say by this fall, what will happen if the Microsoft case is any
Speaker 6:  indication is there will be a ton of scrambling inside Google, there'll be
Speaker 6:  a whole division spun up to address this. Whatever structural changes they
Speaker 6:  need to make, should they lose this on appeal.
Speaker 6:  And it's going to be messy because it's, it's
Speaker 6:  hard to, I've been thinking about this like who does this hurt more in the
Speaker 6:  short term Apple or Google? Because Apple
Speaker 6:  gets the money, which will hurt its stock price, but
Speaker 6:  Google's not gonna have its distribution, which will also
Speaker 6:  hurt its stock price. I have to think that Apple already
Speaker 6:  has the scenarios mapped out of what it will do, should it lose this
Speaker 6:  case. The vibe I've gotten inside Google is that they've actually been
Speaker 6:  kind of gritting their teeth and just praying that this won't
Speaker 6:  happen, which is the Microsoft approach. 20 years ago,
Speaker 4:  Microsoft had other businesses though. I just wanna point
Speaker 6:  This out. No, Google does too. Like Google Cloud is huge like Google and
Speaker 6:  YouTube,
Speaker 4:  But not huge compared to search.
Speaker 6:  I think YouTube and Google Cloud together are as big
Speaker 6:  as search if not bigger.
Speaker 5:  Nila, you don't think the pixel is gonna come around?
Speaker 5:  XR is about to like blow us all away.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying Google has all of its eggs are in this basket. Well
Speaker 6:  All of its eggs are in Gemini. Yeah. And I think, you know, we saw this this
Speaker 6:  week with like Gemini in the new Nest lineup, right? They're putting Gemini
Speaker 6:  everywhere. I thought it was really interesting how we were at IO and
Speaker 6:  Gemini was such a big part of the Pixel Android experience
Speaker 6:  and it's only gonna be on Pixel. I think they really are betting on Gemini
Speaker 6:  being the thing that kind of makes them something that consumers willingly
Speaker 6:  pick again because they didn't have to worry about this for the last 10
Speaker 6:  years, was search and Gemini for them
Speaker 6:  has to work as a thing that makes people interested in Google as an actual
Speaker 6:  innovator again. And I think that is their big bet to survive this
Speaker 6:  change. Should they lose the Apple deal?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. All right, we'll see. Again, we're not at the remedies phase yet.
Speaker 4:  If you want to read all 286 pages of the opinion, it's it,
Speaker 4:  we'll put a link in the show notes. And, if you want a deep dive onto like
Speaker 4:  the legal mechanics of it. We'll link to that episode of Dakota where Cantor,
Speaker 4:  'cause he, we got very nerdy and at one point I think he was like, what are
Speaker 4:  you doing? Stop it.
Speaker 4:  But we'll link all that in the show notes. We gotta take a break. We are,
Speaker 4:  we're, we're well on our way to going over already. We'll be right back.
Speaker 6:  50% year over year. And I think there's a lot of pressure on
Speaker 6:  Linda ya carino the CEO ish of
Speaker 6:  X to find revenue and Elon
Speaker 6:  hates this trade group and probably said
Speaker 6:  we just need to sue them like you did with OpenAI won, et cetera.
Speaker 6:  And it's a trade group, so you know, it's not the companies that
Speaker 6:  make that spend the money. It's a, it's a thing that, it's an entity
Speaker 6:  that is a middleman that helps them decide how to spend the money. But the
Speaker 6:  idea that any trade group has the ability to keep
Speaker 6:  Unilever from
Speaker 6:  spending on a platform is, shows a fundamental
Speaker 6:  misunderstanding of the advertising ecosystem. Well isn't
Speaker 5:  Yeah, X also a member
Speaker 6:  Of the trade and they're a member and they tweeted that they were proud
Speaker 6:  to be a member last month. So
Speaker 6:  yeah, I Linda ya Carino posted a very,
Speaker 6:  I'm just gonna say a
Speaker 5:  Hostage video
Speaker 6:  Hostage. She not hostage.
Speaker 4:  She's not hostage. No, no, she's not host that. True. She's just bad at making
Speaker 4:  videos. Well,
Speaker 6:  It could have been ai I don't know. The, the necklace saying, mama and then
Speaker 6:  free speech makes me think it wasn't ai. No.
Speaker 4:  These are all choices she made in her dumb bubble where people think that
Speaker 4:  shit's cool speech. There's nothing about her that's a hostage or unwitting
Speaker 4:  like we have. I she was at code last year, we saw her. She like, she's
Speaker 6:  Real. She's
Speaker 4:  Doing this 'cause she wants to Yes,
Speaker 6:  I think so. I think there's a big part of where people
Speaker 6:  at x this is just from like my sources and Kylie's, like
Speaker 6:  really feel the fading of their relevance as a company.
Speaker 6:  It was really funny, like Linda held an all hands after filing this lawsuit
Speaker 6:  that our Kylie Robinson was, was getting info from, from
Speaker 6:  a source. And
Speaker 6:  when journalists started like posting what was happening to us all hands,
Speaker 6:  she sat in the all hands like, look, this shows that we're important. Which
Speaker 6:  I think is just like a sign of the vibe,
Speaker 6:  which is like X is thrashing around trying to be
Speaker 6:  important. And I think litigation is a very classic
Speaker 6:  Elon way of feeling important. And this is also has, like,
Speaker 6:  it has Jim Jordan wrapped up in it. Lauren, I I I just,
Speaker 6:  I this makes me just want to like roll my eyes.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, because he was upset, right? Like he he did a thing last year. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Lauren, can you explain the, the Republican Congress,
Speaker 6:  Jim Jordan aspect of this? Because it's, it's, it's like brain worms,
Speaker 6:  but it, we, it's probably important to explain they are
Speaker 4:  Important brain worms. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Oh well, oh yeah. I forgot that Jim Jordan
Speaker 7:  did send this letter to companies in this group
Speaker 7:  asking about this boycott and you know, this is like
Speaker 7:  the kind of thing that Jim Jordan likes to get involved in.
Speaker 7:  You know, he did a whole thing around the, you know, what he
Speaker 7:  has termed like censorship or collusion between the Biden administration
Speaker 7:  and and tech companies.
Speaker 7:  So I think this is, you know, right in that sweet
Speaker 7:  spot of like
Speaker 7:  x being this like free speech platform in his eyes
Speaker 7:  that's being harmed by, you know, this group of other
Speaker 7:  corporate entities. So I think like this is
Speaker 7:  just like right in that kinda wheelhouse.
Speaker 4:  And I think I just wanna say something very clearly and look, I know I went
Speaker 4:  to law school. I'm not saying I'm an expert on every aspect of the law. I
Speaker 4:  just know this one thing. Wait, you went to
Speaker 6:  Law school.
Speaker 4:  There's no constitutional duty to spend money
Speaker 4:  on advertising. You don't have to do it.
Speaker 4:  And in fact, most of our speech law,
Speaker 4:  like depends on the functioning of a market, right? We're
Speaker 4:  like actual, like, you know, there's a cliche phrases like the
Speaker 4:  cure for bad speech is a more speech that we use. We're like, oh
Speaker 4:  we'll just like shovel more into the market and people will make their own
Speaker 4:  choices. And one way You can make choices by spending money. Famously, our
Speaker 4:  Supreme Court has held the money in speech disclosure is the holding in Citizens
Speaker 4:  United disclosure,
Speaker 6:  The Verge makes money through advertising,
Speaker 4:  Right? I'm confident we're a part of whatever adver like
Speaker 4:  GM initiative. So like big platform
Speaker 4:  companies, it's hard to hold them to account. So the adver, it's
Speaker 4:  like crazy that Unilever can't roll up to meta and
Speaker 4:  be like, don't put our ads next to racism. And meta's like, yeah, I don't
Speaker 4:  know, we'll take it. We'll we'll like have another meeting. So they form
Speaker 4:  these trade organizations to be like, Hey, together we
Speaker 4:  have enough power in the market to make you build the
Speaker 4:  tools for ads. Don't show up next to racism. That's like, that
Speaker 4:  is the thing that is happening here. And underlying all of this is this,
Speaker 4:  and I'll just say it, it's like the Jim Jordan committee
Speaker 4:  and the Elon Musk and the Linac Arena. They're like, we should be able to
Speaker 4:  do racism and like You can, you should put the money near the
Speaker 4:  racism. Well, no,
Speaker 6:  They're
Speaker 4:  Mad that you don't, they're mad that these companies won't do it. No,
Speaker 6:  There's they, yes they wanna do that, but they also think
Speaker 6:  they deserve money for it. And what you're drawing the distinction on is
Speaker 6:  X has every right to operate its platform in the same way that GM has
Speaker 6:  every right to tell its clients. This is what we think and
Speaker 6:  these are the platforms you think we should, we think you should spend
Speaker 4:  On, et cetera. Right? Until we got to this extremely weird
Speaker 4:  point in American history where people are like, what if, what if racism?
Speaker 4:  Like what if, what if we did some more racism? This is a, it's a weird moment.
Speaker 4:  Up until recently, a thing like GM that was like, we know
Speaker 4:  these platforms are open and anyone can post whatever they want, but we want
Speaker 4:  the adver, like we, they're very relevant for the advertisers. So we want
Speaker 4:  all the platforms, the advertisers to come together in a committee and have
Speaker 4:  boring meetings and talk about brand safety guidelines and then
Speaker 4:  we'll all make money together. Like that is, I dunno if anyone,
Speaker 4:  like probably a lot of our listeners have been to like marketing conventions.
Speaker 4:  Like I've been, I've talked to a lot of advertisers in my time. Like they're
Speaker 4:  the money, they're very boring and safe. Like
Speaker 4:  advertisers do not want to be near a bunch of Nazi stuff. So
Speaker 4:  they're like, we're gonna go work with the platforms and we're gonna build
Speaker 4:  these guidelines. And Twitter was in it. And what you're finding out
Speaker 4:  now is like Twitter doesn't want to offer those controls.
Speaker 4:  The owner keeps tweeting weird racist stuff,
Speaker 4:  which makes the platform seem not safe. And then boosting his own reach.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like you don't have to spend money next to that. And it's,
Speaker 4:  you know, they filed it in this in Texas where they're gonna get a favorable
Speaker 4:  judge. I'm sure they're gonna get some weird favor ruling, but eventually
Speaker 4:  you're gonna have to contend with the idea that not spending money
Speaker 4:  somehow harms the free speech of racist on Twitter.
Speaker 4:  And like, I don't think You can get that far. I think You can force a lot
Speaker 4:  of people to spend a lot of money defending that action. I think You can
Speaker 4:  scare a lot of advertisers. The way that people have scared Bud Light,
Speaker 4:  right? You can scare the World Federation of Advertisers, the trade
Speaker 4:  organization into dissolving gm, which is two people in
Speaker 4:  a conference room and they just, they're, they're done with it now for a
Speaker 5:  While. Their Slack room is closed.
Speaker 4:  You can do a bunch of weird threatening stuff, but at the end of the day,
Speaker 4:  the thing you are arguing for is platforms should have racism on them
Speaker 4:  and advertisers should be okay putting their ads next to that racism And.
Speaker 4:  if you don't offer those controls, you still have to spend the money And.
Speaker 4:  if you don't, it's like a problem, right? Under this, I would say
Speaker 4:  under this, notably Rumble also filed an antitrust lawsuit
Speaker 4:  alleging that Gar
Speaker 5:  Co polluted. Yeah. They're trying to get other people to do it and the only
Speaker 5:  ones who wanna do it are the ones who wanna do racism and are mad that nobody
Speaker 5:  will fund their racism.
Speaker 4:  I would just point out that Twitter before all of this was not like
Speaker 4:  Disneyland. Yeah, it was,
Speaker 5:  There was some racism.
Speaker 4:  YouTube makes a lot of money. There's a lot of weird shit on YouTube.
Speaker 4:  Meta notable provider of Facebook to old people.
Speaker 4:  Weird Trump, Jesus all over, all over Facebook today.
Speaker 4:  Right? Like they're, the money's still flowing in because they're playing
Speaker 4:  the game in the market. And Mark Zuckerberg is like, you
Speaker 4:  know, he, he might be cozying up to Peter Thiel and saying Donald Trump is
Speaker 4:  a badass, but his public persona is like, I grew up my hair and I'm drinking
Speaker 4:  a beer on a surfboard. We should all make money together. And that's more
Speaker 4:  or less all you need to do. Not Elon Musk sit at the deal book
Speaker 4:  conference with Andrew os Sorkin and tell Bob Iger to go fuck himself and
Speaker 4:  say, you can't bribe me with money. And now he's like, wait, you're not spending
Speaker 4:  the money, I'm gonna sue you.
Speaker 6:  Exactly. And that's what, that's what this is totally about is it's a denial
Speaker 6:  on Elon's part that he has been self-destructive.
Speaker 6:  He has been destructive to X's business and he wants to blame everyone but
Speaker 6:  himself. I think that's ultimately what this comes down
Speaker 5:  To. He's just a litigious bully. He's just like, how can I bully people
Speaker 5:  legally? He's done it plenty of times before. This isn't the first time he's
Speaker 5:  done it. This is probably just one of the stupidest times he's done it.
Speaker 5:  Like,
Speaker 4:  You know. Okay, so that's like on the, on the top level. Yeah, it's done
Speaker 4:  right. You, you don't have a constitutional duty to spend money. You
Speaker 4:  just don't. So stupid. Then there's the lawsuit itself.
Speaker 4:  And I don't like, I don't wanna pull it's, it's dumb. They, he didn't even
Speaker 4:  get his usual lawyers to file it. He had to go get other lawyers. Like Quin
Speaker 4:  Emanuel, his usual law firm is not
Speaker 6:  This. Oh they aren't Uhuh.
Speaker 5:  That's good. Yeah. Yeah. This is like a real rando. He
Speaker 4:  Had to get someone else to do it. In classic Elon Musk fashion, this
Speaker 4:  complaint centers around a contract that doesn't exist.
Speaker 4:  We love that. He just loves to find contracts that don't exist. So you'll
Speaker 4:  recall when he sued OpenAI won, it was for a contract
Speaker 4:  that didn't exist. He has withdrawn that lawsuit. He refiled it in federal
Speaker 4:  court recently and now he's claiming it's fraud. There's, he took out the
Speaker 4:  contract claims 'cause he realized you can't sue our contract doesn't exist
Speaker 4:  in this case. He's saying there's antitrust, there's collusion.
Speaker 4:  And the way he finds it is by inventing an enforceable
Speaker 4:  contract with this ad trade organization
Speaker 4:  and he has to go find it somewhere. He has to say that it's a contract and
Speaker 4:  it's enforceable and it doesn't exist. Like there's no penalty. Unilever
Speaker 4:  spends the money, like they might get an angry call from someone, but like
Speaker 4:  there's no penalty 'cause there's no contract. So he says the agreement
Speaker 4:  by among Gars advertiser advertising agency members to enforce brand safety
Speaker 4:  standards is memorialized in a number of places other than the
Speaker 4:  FAQ and the charter. So if you're like, this contract is in
Speaker 4:  an FAQ, you're already on your bed, you're, you're wrong and you're like
Speaker 4:  looking at other places. And then it says, for example, in new member applications,
Speaker 4:  Gar m explains that members must agree to work with industry partners in
Speaker 4:  category peers in a collaborative, non-competitive way. That's the
Speaker 4:  application.
Speaker 4:  There's no contract. So you have this like big collusion and
Speaker 4:  underlying it is nothing. and it, I'm telling you this is just there to
Speaker 4:  threaten people. And then there's a devastating what can only be described
Speaker 4:  as a devastating cell phone.
Speaker 4:  The advertising boycott of Twitter now X is contrary to the economic
Speaker 4:  self-interest of the boycotting advertisers. Due to the boycott of
Speaker 4:  Twitter. Prices charged for advertising declined substantially in
Speaker 4:  November, 2022 and remain well below those charged by Xs
Speaker 4:  closest competitors in social media. By refraining from
Speaker 4:  purchasing advertising on x boycotting advertisers are foregoing
Speaker 4:  a valuable opportunity to purchase low priced advertising.
Speaker 4:  This
Speaker 7:  Just sounds like an ad for
Speaker 4:  X advertising. Well
Speaker 6:  Also that's hilarious. It's also hilarious that Linda posted this video on
Speaker 6:  X where the advertisers she's trying to talk to are not
Speaker 6:  there. They're purposely not there.
Speaker 4:  Well she was,
Speaker 5:  She was there saying it's your voices, right? Yeah. Like he was calling on
Speaker 5:  the the users to effectively attack. Yeah, yeah. All of
Speaker 5:  these folks. So there's like,
Speaker 4:  That's and that's like the Bud Light moment, right? Yeah. Like we're mad
Speaker 4:  at Unilever. Go weirdos. Yeah. And like, I
Speaker 4:  I, I personally think there's a lot on the other side of this lawsuit is
Speaker 4:  a lot of powerful advertising money. And they're gonna say, actually,
Speaker 4:  we don't think your platform is brand safe. and it is our money is our speech
Speaker 4:  and we can do whatever we want. And there's, there's no contract here saying
Speaker 4:  we can't do these things. There's a trade organization
Speaker 4:  that we rely on so that we all act in a collective way to prevent
Speaker 4:  the monetization of racism. And that's fine. And I, it's
Speaker 4:  really hard to gin up a lot of outreach over.
Speaker 7:  It's a really strange concept that, you know, it's like Linda is
Speaker 7:  asking users to be mad that they're not getting
Speaker 7:  advertisements from specific companies. Like, I don't think anyone's ever
Speaker 7:  been mad to not get that.
Speaker 5:  You need to be furious. The charm and bear is not in your feed right now.
Speaker 5:  Got it. Is what she's saying. It's just goofy.
Speaker 4:  It's also funny that they've gone X premium, they're now
Speaker 4:  advertising. It has no ads.
Speaker 4:  'cause you don't, it's 'cause you don't have any ads.
Speaker 4:  Alex, how longer, how much longer do you think this iteration of access to
Speaker 4:  go, like, to be clear, it is popping off during the election
Speaker 4:  night because in election year there's a lot of activity. Yeah. On the platform.
Speaker 4:  There's a lot of people coming to threads because Elon keeps posting insane
Speaker 4:  nonsense. But it's, it's still vibrant in its way.
Speaker 4:  Is it gonna be able to sustain itself over time?
Speaker 6:  I think it's very hard for a platform with this level of
Speaker 6:  scale and network effects in social media to just die quickly.
Speaker 6:  I think it's like we're talking like, or Elon pulls the plug,
Speaker 6:  right? Elon could have a episode and decide to fully pull the plug
Speaker 6:  or sell it for parts. But barring that, I think it continues to
Speaker 6:  live on it. Dwindles and influence, if I had to guess
Speaker 6:  their percentage of users who are regular regularly posting has gone way
Speaker 6:  down based on just scanning it. Like my,
Speaker 6:  the my Feed is just a lot of the same accounts now. It's just less,
Speaker 6:  less interesting, less varied, but it still has
Speaker 6:  that twitchiness. It's still, and for oddly like in the tech community, the
Speaker 6:  AI world especially, it's just still where everyone is is and hanging
Speaker 6:  out and like the OpenAI won. The OpenAI won. People are like, they're just
Speaker 6:  feeding training data to rock every day. It kind of blows my
Speaker 6:  mind, but, so yeah.
Speaker 6:  Threads doesn't quite have that kind of real time
Speaker 6:  juice and
Speaker 6:  s like Yeah. It just, it's missing that still. Well it's
Speaker 5:  Gonna tell us about the last suit next week. Don't worry.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, exactly. Yeah, we'll find out about it last week or next week.
Speaker 6:  I think, you know, he's betting big on payments. I think we're gonna see
Speaker 6:  that relatively soon, this whole banking play where You can
Speaker 6:  exchange value with other Nazi supporters on the
Speaker 6:  platform. I mean, I don't, I don't know what that's, you know, he's, I think
Speaker 6:  they're building that stack from scratch. I would hope so because I could
Speaker 6:  imagine Stripe turning that off after a while when you realize like what's
Speaker 6:  happening with that. But yeah, it's kind of just turning into this like,
Speaker 6:  it's a reflection of Elon. It's a reflection of his psyche.
Speaker 6:  It reminds me a lot of like Rupert Murdoch and Fox
Speaker 6:  and especially how he's using it in this election cycle. It's in stark
Speaker 6:  contrast to Meta and Zuckerberg. Yes, you've got
Speaker 6:  Zuckerberg on the edges with the Trump stuff, but Meta is like, we're out
Speaker 6:  of politics. We're, we're not, I think we're not recommending it even, right?
Speaker 6:  And so it's very different. Prince
Speaker 5:  Is, Murdoch is successful with
Speaker 4:  Fox.
Speaker 5:  Fox is like the most successful news network. Yeah. And, and he, he's really
Speaker 5:  good at it. But Elon's not. He's, he's,
Speaker 6:  Well I think X will start to look more like that. I think it becomes his
Speaker 6:  media empire.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's, it's, I mean it's already become that, right? Right. It's already
Speaker 5:  become his place where he can go and spout the most transphobic, racist
Speaker 5:  stuff imaginable and not get yelled at and then
Speaker 5:  sue people because they don't wanna advertise next to that transphobic racist
Speaker 5:  too. It's just
Speaker 4:  Very, he's a free speech. Absolutely. Well, yeah.
Speaker 6:  Wanna be very clear about this. And that's, that's the thing, like he said,
Speaker 6:  we need the, the internet needs its digital town square and that's what X
Speaker 6:  was gonna be. and it turns out like no one wants to be hanging out
Speaker 6:  with a bunch of people yelling crazy, insulting, vile stuff.
Speaker 6:  It
Speaker 5:  Turns out digital Times Square
Speaker 4:  Sucks.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Times Square is like, you never want to be there unless you're a
Speaker 6:  tourist and you got conned into a, a guide thing there. So like yeah,
Speaker 6:  I I I feel like it's just reflecting him more and more
Speaker 6:  and that's going to make it smaller. But it will, it will live on,
Speaker 6:  I think it stokes his ego and I think he likes having a platform
Speaker 6:  that has a media element to it that also feeds his other businesses,
Speaker 4:  Which
Speaker 5:  Gets acquired by the other one first. True social or
Speaker 5:  XI just summed that. I'm sorry.
Speaker 4:  I feel like after we gotta wrap this up, we are way over. We got a whole
Speaker 4:  lightning round. But I feel like that that is like a
Speaker 4:  supernova of garbage
Speaker 4:  that after this election we will see, right? Yeah. Those things will
Speaker 4:  collide into each other after this election. But yeah, there's just
Speaker 4:  a, there's a moment happening here where it feels like whatever
Speaker 4:  platform, we've talked about this so much in the show, whatever platform
Speaker 4:  era we are in with big search in Google with Twitter
Speaker 4:  dominating public discourse with Instagram being where all the influencers
Speaker 4:  are, like all of that is just sort of winding down. Like people are tired
Speaker 4:  of a lot of it. And like, we'll see what happens next. But You can, You can
Speaker 4:  feel it like, oh, a bunch of stuff that we took for granted is changing.
Speaker 4:  And one of them in particular is the dominance of Twitter and the
Speaker 4:  conversation because he's
Speaker 5:  as popular. By adding in like a b, C news is now gonna be live.
Speaker 5:  You'll be able to watch ABC Oh sure. Just on Disney Plus. And I'm like, that's
Speaker 5:  really smart. I'm really excited about that as someone who doesn't pay for
Speaker 5:  cable. But yeah, Disney's just jacking
Speaker 5:  the prices up and it's gonna keep happening. I'm sorry folks. I I wish And
Speaker 4:  They're gonna do, they're cracking down a password sharing in September.
Speaker 4:  I I So they've just figured it out. They're like, we're gonna charge everyone
Speaker 4:  a lot of money. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They're like, like everybody knows exactly what to do, which is make
Speaker 5:  everybody pay you a lot of money for things, which is what they were all
Speaker 5:  doing before streaming. And they're just like, oh my God, what if we did
Speaker 5:  what we did with cable, but
Speaker 4:  Now we can, it turns out there is a constitutional duty to pay a lot of money
Speaker 4:  for Disney. Yeah. That's, and that, that's just baked into the fabric
Speaker 4:  of America.
Speaker 5:  There. There's, I I I still wait with bated breath for the,
Speaker 5:  the, the lawsuit or the antitrust suit against Disney
Speaker 5:  for just buying all of pop culture and owning all
Speaker 5:  of it. Except for like Taylor Swift.
Speaker 4:  Hey, I'm gonna go see the Wolverine movie tomorrow. Don't, it's all, we're
Speaker 4:  close to spoilers already.
Speaker 5:  I don't wanna spoil it. I don't wanna spoil it, but it is the entire Disney
Speaker 5:  RA is like in that movie.
Speaker 4:  All right. So that's, that's Disney.
Speaker 4:  Lauren, what's your line around?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, so I've got Microsoft and Delta
Speaker 7:  just going at each other for, you know, who, who was the issue
Speaker 7:  with Delta having to cancel a bunch of flights after the
Speaker 7:  CrowdStrike issue. And this whole story is basically the Spider-Man meme.
Speaker 7:  They're just pointing at each other and it seems like maybe
Speaker 7:  Delta, Delta CEO missed an email from Satya Nadella
Speaker 7:  offering help. And so it's very good.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  It's just a lot of really mundane things like missing emails except that
Speaker 6:  Well Delta wifi does suck, so I'm not
Speaker 4:  Surprised. It's really bad.
Speaker 6:  I'm not surprised that he missed an email. He's probably on one of his planes.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Delta wifi is horrible lately. Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Actually it seemed like maybe the CEO was like flying to the
Speaker 7:  Olympics. Oh my god. So yeah, it, it definitely could be. Could be
Speaker 7:  the Delta wifi.
Speaker 4:  So CrowdStrike went down, Delta went down catastrophically
Speaker 4:  and then Ed Basian, who's the CEO of Delta, was on TN bbc. And he said, when
Speaker 4:  was the last time you heard of the big out at Apple? Which apparently just
Speaker 4:  made everyone mad. Like everyone got except for Apple. I think Apple is
Speaker 4:  thrilled to hear that. And so Microsoft sent this letter and
Speaker 4:  they're like, our software didn't cause your problem.
Speaker 4:  CrowdStrike did. And CrowdStrike is kinda like,
Speaker 4:  don't we're, can you guys fight? Yeah. It's all very good.
Speaker 4:  And they keep saying they've been offering to help Delta. Delta apparently
Speaker 4:  had it worse. Like other airlines came back faster.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, Delta was like days later they were
Speaker 5:  canceling. Like they just canceled their
Speaker 5:  unaccompanied minor program during all of this. They were like,
Speaker 5:  yeah minors you just don't travel anymore. And so kids were like stranded
Speaker 5:  in random airports and stuff. They shit the bed
Speaker 5:  and and are looking for someone to blame.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So Microsoft is saying Delta has apparently not modernized its
Speaker 4:  IT infrastructure. And that said is rapidly becoming apparent that Delta
Speaker 4:  likely refused Microsoft help because the IT system is having most trouble
Speaker 4:  storing crew tracking and scheduling was being serviced by other providers
Speaker 4:  such as IBMs. and it is like I've never seen
Speaker 4:  an IT vendor look at a client and be like, no it's
Speaker 4:  you. Absolutely not. This
Speaker 6:  Is your fault. Well didn't South, was it Southwest not impacted because they
Speaker 6:  were still running on like such an old version of
Speaker 4:  Windows? No, that's a meme that's right up there with JD Vance on the couch.
Speaker 4:  It's like, it's so good you don't wanna check it. You know. Wait,
Speaker 6:  JD Vance on the couch isn't reel
Speaker 4:  Damnit? It's like it's, it's like there's a long list of two good to check
Speaker 4:  and Southwest wasn't affected 'cause it's running. Unlike Windows three is
Speaker 4:  like right up there.
Speaker 6:  You just ruined my
Speaker 4:  Week. I'm sorry. That's fine. Southwest is great. Alright Alex,
Speaker 4:  what's yours? Heath, what's your lightning around?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so mine is a great scoop that Kylie had on the site about Humane,
Speaker 6:  a company that we obviously have been obsessively chronicling since the
Speaker 6:  dirt disastrous debut of its AI pin. She found out
Speaker 6:  based on some internal sales data that she got that more pins are
Speaker 6:  being returned than sold. That's
Speaker 4:  Very good. Which
Speaker 6:  I'm not running a hardware business, but I think that's bad.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And the piece is great. She's got a lot of color.
Speaker 6:  I just wanna call out Humane spokesperson,
Speaker 6:  Zoe's Zos K's statement to us
Speaker 6:  where she said we do not comment on financial data but we'll
Speaker 6:  refer it to our legal counsel. Okay. And
Speaker 6:  it's just ridiculous. It's a ridiculous response to a story like this. But
Speaker 6:  Humane is very much on the defensive. There's
Speaker 6:  talks, rumors of them, you know, trying to sell themselves to hp.
Speaker 6:  They raised over $200 million and sold 9 million worth of product ish.
Speaker 6:  So not good for them. And
Speaker 4:  Wait, if you do the math at $9 million at whatever that the pin was 700 bucks.
Speaker 4:  So they sold like 12,000 units.
Speaker 6:  They wanted to sell a hundred thousand in the first year.
Speaker 4:  Right. So he sold like 12,000 and I think Harley has it. There's only 7,000
Speaker 4:  left in the wild. Yeah, yeah. That's bad. That's just generally bad if you
Speaker 6:  Those have one, you should save it and put it in a box. It's gonna be a great,
Speaker 6:  honestly it'll be a great collector's item
Speaker 5:  If you have one and have it returned it and actually use it. Just, just hit
Speaker 5:  me up. I wanna know everything about you. I wanna understand
Speaker 5:  your world
Speaker 4:  Somewhere right now and can't be, Sam is touching their pin and being like,
Speaker 4:  email Alex. Alex email Alex.
Speaker 5:  Nope. No the pin's on fire.
Speaker 4:  Oh that was the other thing Holly. This piece, which I think is one of
Speaker 4:  the worst pieces of the puzzle. They haven't figured out how to
Speaker 4:  refurbish the pins. Yeah. Because some limitation with T-Mobile, which I'm
Speaker 4:  guessing is related to repro provisioning the eim inside the
Speaker 4:  pin. So they're just stuck with this and they hope they can figure it out.
Speaker 4:  We just bad all around. I will say to to Heath's point,
Speaker 4:  once you tell, once you start waving lawyers at me, I've learned something
Speaker 4:  about you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 4:  I'm not gonna say
Speaker 6:  It's the ultimate tell.
Speaker 4:  It's the ultimate tell. Yeah. It's just like, it's like, oh, oh I, I know
Speaker 4:  something. And we, we do this a lot people, a lot of lawyers have
Speaker 4:  emailed me The Verge still exists. That's all I'm gonna say.
Speaker 4:  We're, we're better at it than you might think. Alright, I'm
Speaker 4:  gonna talk. Can I, can I quickly talk about the TV competition?
Speaker 5:  Tell us
Speaker 4:  Everything. A story that I didn't write a thing that no one knows that I
Speaker 4:  did. There's a very famous TV store
Speaker 4:  in Westchester, New York called Value Electronics. They've been doing it
Speaker 4:  forever. They sell a million TVs Robert's on the guy who owns it,
Speaker 4:  he runs it with his family. It's just a little mom and pop and they sell
Speaker 4:  more high-end TVs than anyone like Sony allocates, high-end
Speaker 4:  TVs to this one store. And so every year they run and he's a
Speaker 4:  former broadcast engineer. So every year they run this thing called the TV
Speaker 4:  shootout. They've been doing it for 20 years and like literally like
Speaker 4:  com, the CEO of compression houses and like
Speaker 4:  the head colorist for movie studios, like a Warner Brothers discovery
Speaker 4:  and coding person is like, they're the judges. They have
Speaker 4:  master calibrators come and calibrate all these TVs. Beautiful. And then
Speaker 4:  there was me, 'cause I'm a consumer reviewer, which is great. So I was like
Speaker 4:  honored to do this. I felt completely outta my depth. I think my scores were
Speaker 4:  in line with everyone else. And I will write this up over the weekend, but
Speaker 4:  I will say one my my tv, the one I bought, the Sony 8 95,
Speaker 4:  it won.
Speaker 5:  Yay. Congratulations.
Speaker 4:  One, I was the winner. And then the mini L led D TVs, I think
Speaker 4:  I said micro LED earlier. But the mini LED D TVs, the new Bravia nine,
Speaker 4:  there was a Samsung one, there's an LG one, they're not even in the running
Speaker 4:  yet. You can just obviously tell like they're gonna get there.
Speaker 4:  But there's so much more to go on the mini LED side before they
Speaker 4:  compete with the OLEDs. The OLEDs were just like, it was like a, a sigh of
Speaker 4:  relief going and looking at the eds after the mini LEDs that, so I'll write
Speaker 4:  all this up. But it was fascinating to be a judge in a
Speaker 4:  TV picture quality con like first of all, I was in heaven, like
Speaker 4:  pure heaven, just joy for two days I did nothing but look at
Speaker 4:  TVs with other TV nerds and talk about things like posturization
Speaker 4:  in like fields of color.
Speaker 5:  Did people who, who, who brought the like color perimeter? Did anybody bus
Speaker 5:  it out?
Speaker 4:  The, so the, we were, I gotta write about this, but
Speaker 4:  we were judging the tv. It wasn't a subjective
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  Evaluation. They had $40,000 Sony reference
Speaker 4:  monitors. Yes. By each bank of three TVs. Oh my gosh. And
Speaker 4:  the, the judging was how much the TVs were
Speaker 4:  deviation. How big of a deviation from the reference monitor those TVs were.
Speaker 5:  Oh, so of course the Sony won,
Speaker 4:  Right? 'cause it was a Sony reference. I was, does the Sony look like it's
Speaker 4:  own Sony reference monitor? But the, the reference monitors were like, this
Speaker 4:  is what the mastering people wanted the movie
Speaker 4:  to look like or wanted the content to look like. And then if you calibrate
Speaker 4:  the TVs, how closely can you calibrate the TV to the reference,
Speaker 5:  This is what I want.
Speaker 4:  So it's not like a what looks better totally subjective thing. It was how
Speaker 4:  close is this to the reference, which made it like a very
Speaker 4:  different kind of exercise. And then obviously everyone's like a huge nerd.
Speaker 4:  Like people were up there like staring at pixels and like
Speaker 4:  intently and we had to be reminded. The judges were like, you can't collude.
Speaker 4:  I was like purely in heaven. No antitrust here for two
Speaker 4:  days over a weekend.
Speaker 5:  How many times did you have to watch Harry Potter
Speaker 4:  Or Avatar? Oh man. So we watched a movie called Dr.
Speaker 4:  Sleep several times, which is insane. So you had to find things like we
Speaker 4:  were judging things like low light performance, right? Or fast
Speaker 4:  SDR motion or like bright high HDR sports. So they had to
Speaker 4:  find clips to play. All of the clips were being
Speaker 4:  run off an oppo Blu-ray player. I'm
Speaker 5:  So happy
Speaker 4:  Out of you. Or off or off. A Kaleido escape, which is really high bit rate.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Streaming. So all the, there were all these like specific
Speaker 4:  clips that were there to show like specific things
Speaker 4:  that we were to judge. And I had like
Speaker 4:  60 numbers per sheet and there were like four sheets
Speaker 4:  of scores and it was, it was a 10 point scale and I was like,
Speaker 4:  world of no sevens, like the whole thing. It was great.
Speaker 4:  The Sony You can go look at the press release. You can see the scores. The
Speaker 4:  Sony won, the LG G four came in second more or less
Speaker 4:  and the Samsung came in third in the Eds and then the, the mini Sony Mini,
Speaker 4:  they came in first in mini these. So the scores are public. I'm not revealing
Speaker 4:  anything. You can just go look at that press release. I will write up the
Speaker 4:  whole thing 'cause there's more to say. But I have to say like, I thought
Speaker 4:  I was gonna spend this week arguing about TV stuff with people and I super
Speaker 4:  did it. I was very much distracted by other stuff, but I had the time in
Speaker 4:  my life. It was really fun to be a judge. I hope I get to do it again next
Speaker 4:  year. And yeah, I'm like, I
Speaker 4:  I and I, the interesting thing is the, the
Speaker 4:  head room for those many ladies to get as good as OLEDs is obvious, but it's,
Speaker 4:  it's nowhere close. Like yeah. Not even in the same ballpark.
Speaker 5:  Was it the brightness and just like that, that that difference in the
Speaker 4:  Range? No, it's like, it's called, I mean they're LCD TVs. Yeah. So they're
Speaker 4:  still, they're, they're like washed out. The colors are all wrong. Like the
Speaker 4:  LCDs are all pinker than the OLEDs. It's, it's like bananas.
Speaker 4:  I will post up my scores, like my, my score sheets. There's lots.
Speaker 5:  I'm like, Mila, I just want you to file this story. I just really wanna read
Speaker 5:  that story.
Speaker 4:  That's what I thought I was gonna do this weekend. I had to read PDFs all
Speaker 4:  day long.
Speaker 5:  Please no one else release a major lawsuit.
Speaker 4:  I started in this whole career to not be a lawyer and to look at TVs all
Speaker 4:  day long. No
Speaker 5:  More lawsuits we're done for the week. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Also Justice for the Frame tv. I'm really stunned. The Frame TV was not even
Speaker 4:  in the picture. Like I brought up the frame TV with a bunch of people. Oh,
Speaker 4:  the manufacturers all had representatives there. So I met a bunch of very
Speaker 4:  nice like Sony engineers and product managers and all the companies were
Speaker 4:  there. And I kept asking like, do you think the Frame TV is a harbinger of
Speaker 4:  doom? And they'd be like, no, no comment. I don't Who are you? You a professional
Speaker 4:  color? Calibrator.
Speaker 5:  Well there we got more of 'em now
Speaker 4:  We yeah, there's, there's a competition for the Frame TV from who is it?
Speaker 4:  Is it
Speaker 5:  Sense? It's tcl, L and Hisense. So like, like race
Speaker 5:  to the bottom on tv. Quality there real,
Speaker 5:  no disrespects
Speaker 4:  A real, it's a real something. TCL and a high sense by the way opted out
Speaker 4:  of the competition. They declined to participate, which is pretty good.
Speaker 4:  All right, Kranz, what's your lightning round?
Speaker 5:  All right, so my, my lightning round is Chromecast is dead but Chromecast
Speaker 5:  is not dead. Just the dongle is dead. I, I saw there was
Speaker 5:  some confusion out there in the world. Chromecast is like the protocol that
Speaker 5:  You can go and like cast things to your TV or whatever that still lives.
Speaker 5:  The little dongles are gone. They're done.
Speaker 4:  It's all over. It's they're all over. It's the picture we have in our Chromecast
Speaker 4:  has gone is a picture I took of the first generation Chromecast in
Speaker 4:  2013 plugged into my pioneer crow. And in the background
Speaker 4:  You can see my three component cables plugged into it because it was 10 years
Speaker 4:  ago component.
Speaker 5:  Pretty
Speaker 4:  Rule. Pretty sure my cable box was plugged in with RCA cables by a component.
Speaker 4:  It's very good. It's
Speaker 5:  Very good.
Speaker 4:  It's kind of it, you know the Google's whole idea with the Chromecast
Speaker 4:  was you, you're just gonna use your phone to watch video and send it to a
Speaker 4:  TV.
Speaker 5:  And we all realized that sucked.
Speaker 4:  Yeah it didn't work. And then the TVs all have the software in it and the
Speaker 4:  new streamer box. Alex, I'm very curious for your
Speaker 4:  perspective on this. They told Chris Welch that their North Star, what they
Speaker 4:  were competing with is the Nvidia Shield.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, look, we love to rip on the Nvidia Shield. I
Speaker 5:  personally still use the Apple TV myself, but the
Speaker 5:  Nvidia Shield is the most powerful step top box. It is the highest quality.
Speaker 5:  It is the one that like if they had been using a streaming box at the
Speaker 5:  shootout Neil I went to, that's what they would've been using. They use Apple
Speaker 5:  tv.
Speaker 4:  I just wanna be
Speaker 5:  Very clear about. But Apple TV is, that's the one that installers all like
Speaker 5:  to use because that's what the clients board prefer. Yes. So those are two,
Speaker 5:  like the two. So like chasing the Nvidia Shield is
Speaker 5:  awesome. The Nvidia Shield could probably do to chase itself a little. 'cause
Speaker 5:  I don't think it's had an update in like two years, but it's like, it also
Speaker 4:  Is like, I think Nvidia has different priorities
Speaker 5:  Now. Yeah, right now they're like, we're just gonna like generate buckets
Speaker 5:  of money with ai. We don't care about these little, if
Speaker 4:  We ever, I Jensen Wang decoder, I'm gonna be like Jensen
Speaker 4:  Wong. If we ever new Jensen Wong a decoder, I'm be like, AI, whatever.
Speaker 4:  Tell me about your plans for the Nvidia shoot. And then we're gonna see if
Speaker 4:  he even knows it exists.
Speaker 5:  He's just gonna be like pocket sand, throw it at you and like disappear out
Speaker 5:  of frame. Just absolutely not
Speaker 4:  Run away. Oh Alex, I gotta tell you, one of the tests we did
Speaker 4:  at the TV shootout was an A TSC 3.0 Yes. We watched the
Speaker 4:  Olympics broadcast from NBC New York in 10 80
Speaker 4:  PHDR to something called the Zapper Box. Like a tuner
Speaker 4:  box with Atmos audio. It was like ba bare, like barely compressed 'cause
Speaker 4:  it was just full quality broadcast. It looked incredible. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I was like, I gotta get an antenna. And I was like, no, I don't, you
Speaker 5:  Don't need money.
Speaker 4:  I truly do not have to get antenna.
Speaker 5:  That's the only station and, and you won't get, you won't get any joy out
Speaker 5:  of it once the Olympics are over.
Speaker 4:  There was a very funny mis like miscommunication moment where I was like,
Speaker 4:  where is this coming from? And someone very earnestly was like, it's in
Speaker 4:  Paris. I was like, no, that's not what I meant at all.
Speaker 4:  Bon sure. I was like, no, I at what station? It's bro fine. Whatever
Speaker 4:  it was very good. Alright, we are way over. I'm sorry that we talked
Speaker 4:  about Elon Musk, but he's not good at knowing what a contract
Speaker 8:  Network. Our show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James.
Speaker 8:  That's it. We'll see you next week.