# Transcript
ID: 67e45cac-6a61-4f82-8883-cea5a299067e
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5778845663659071045/-7788965998295249416/s93290-US-4151s-1707093939.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss Nilay's review of the Apple Vision Pro, and then answer questions from our listeners.
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Variable
Speaker 2:  Immersion. I'm your friend, David Pierce, and I am sitting here updating
Speaker 2:  a bunch of apps on my Meta Quest. Three So I tend to
Speaker 2:  go kind of in and out with VR stuff. I had a long run of doing
Speaker 2:  workouts and Supernatural So I was using the thing almost every day. And
Speaker 2:  then, you know, it was winter, I got Lazy So I didn't do that for a while.
Speaker 2:  And then recently I got really into the Assassin's Creed game, Assassin's
Speaker 2:  Creed Nexus vr, it's super cool. But then I had one of those moments of being
Speaker 2:  like, okay, I'm spending too much time with this game. Time to stop. But
Speaker 2:  recently I've been picking this thing back up because I'm gonna be honest
Speaker 2:  with you, I've been having some fomo. So this week is the week
Speaker 2:  Apple's Vision Pro comes out. We've been waiting for apple's, ar, vr,
Speaker 2:  mixed reality, whatever you wanna call it, $3,500 headset to come
Speaker 2:  out. And it's coming out this week on Friday, February 2nd. I've been hearing
Speaker 2:  from people who pre-ordered one. I've been hearing lots of ideas about apps
Speaker 2:  that are gonna come out. It all seems very exciting and it's just making
Speaker 2:  me feel bad 'cause I don't have one. But you know who does have one is NELI
Speaker 2:  Patel, the Verges editor in chief and my Vergecast co-host. So we figured
Speaker 2:  for this episode, we would just grill NELI about the Vision Pro. He spent
Speaker 2:  the last few days writing about it, testing it, trying to figure out
Speaker 2:  what this thing means in the world and whether it's worth your
Speaker 2:  $3,500. So we got lots of questions from you. We have lots of questions for
Speaker 2:  Eli Alex and I are gonna spend, I mean potentially like
Speaker 2:  many, many, many hours asking Eli all of our questions about the Vision
Speaker 2:  Pro to figure out not only if it's better than this thing, the
Speaker 2:  Quest three that I'm in right now, but if it's the future, is this. The
Speaker 2:  next thing is this where we're headed. So that's what we're gonna do for
Speaker 2:  the whole rest of this episode. It's All Vision Pro all the time, all week,
Speaker 2:  because it's headset week. All that is coming up in just a second.
Speaker 2:  But first I feel like I just guilted myself into doing a workout. So I'm
Speaker 2:  gonna pop into Supernatural for a little bit, do some boxing, and then we're
Speaker 2:  gonna get to it. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Alright, it is 9:10 AM on Tuesday,
Speaker 2:  January 30th, which means 10 minutes ago was when the embargo
Speaker 2:  for Vision Pro reviews lifted. There's a bunch of 'em out there. Our friend
Speaker 2:  Mark has, Brownley has one. Our friend Joanna Stern has one a scene that
Speaker 2:  has a video. I was watching, I, Justine has a fun video that I was just poking
Speaker 2:  through. There's a bunch of good stuff out there. But before the review
Speaker 2:  publishes is actually one of my favorite moments, especially being sort of
Speaker 2:  inside the process because you go through all this testing and you have to
Speaker 2:  decide what to make of this thing. Not just is it good not, is
Speaker 2:  it cool? Does it have some neat features? But is this a good package?
Speaker 2:  Is this worth buying? Is it worth the price? And I think the challenge
Speaker 2:  for us and from watching some of these reviews for a lot of other folks is
Speaker 2:  to figure out what to make of this thing. Everybody seems to agree that the
Speaker 2:  tech is amazing. There's just no question that Apple did a
Speaker 2:  lot of the things it was trying to do very well. But to what end?
Speaker 2:  What is this for? What is this thing about? What are you supposed to do with
Speaker 2:  it? Why does it exist? These are the big like existential questions
Speaker 2:  that both as a reviewer and as a person thinking about buying a product like
Speaker 2:  this, you have to think more about with a first generation
Speaker 2:  device like this, it seems like the Vision Pro really is the first of something,
Speaker 2:  but exactly what that is and where it's going and whether we want it is
Speaker 2:  hard to know. So about 24 hours ago as I'm
Speaker 2:  recording this, we sat down with Eli, we dragged him into the studio in this
Speaker 2:  like haze of doing all of the review stuff and
Speaker 2:  tried to go through that before the review publishes, before he'd seen anything
Speaker 2:  else before we'd gotten comments and everything, I just wanted us to sort
Speaker 2:  of pick his brain about the review. So for the whole rest of
Speaker 2:  the show, it's gonna be just me, Alex Cranz and NELI
Speaker 2:  Patel. And we are going to go deep on the Vision Pro
Speaker 2:  Eli's review how he felt, what it was like to use this thing and a whole
Speaker 2:  bunch more. Let's get into it. NELI Patel, welcome.
Speaker 2:  Hello, Alex Krantz. Hello. Hello. NELI, we have talk about
Speaker 2:  your life status. We've all reviewed gadgets, all three of us. And I know
Speaker 2:  that this is the point of the process where it can either be going very
Speaker 2:  well or you can be ruining a lot of things you've decided about your life
Speaker 2:  and decisions you've made in the past that have led you to this moment. How
Speaker 2:  you feeling?
Speaker 5:  I want the audience to know that David has chosen to record this podcast
Speaker 5:  with me at the most vulnerable time for any reviewer.
Speaker 2:  This was very much on purpose. Yes, it's, it's right now it is
Speaker 2:  27 hours before embargo time. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Which is when everything about everything you've ever done in your life is
Speaker 2:  suddenly up in the air. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So I'll just, just to give people the context. I've had the Vision Pro for
Speaker 5:  a little less than a week. It'll be six days when you hear this. Apple
Speaker 5:  Security arrived at my house, the Vision Pro last week. It was pretty intense
Speaker 5:  and we've had it, we've been using it. This is the moment in the review process
Speaker 5:  where the video is shot, it's being edited, the written
Speaker 5:  review is mostly written, it's in edits. And I'm just sitting
Speaker 5:  around waiting to see if I'm right, which again is the most
Speaker 5:  vulnerable part of any review. Like I've done, I've said what I think, here's
Speaker 5:  what I think. And then tomorrow it'll get published and everyone will yell
Speaker 5:  at me or not yell, Who knows. But, so David is like, this is when I want
Speaker 5:  to talk to you, which is mean and unfair. That's the perfect
Speaker 2:  Time. Yeah. I feel, I feel really good about it
Speaker 5:  And you can hear it. We've been pulling basically Allnighters for a week.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And you can hear it in my voice. I think
Speaker 2:  It's been a lot. So in an effort to make this easy on you, basically what
Speaker 2:  is going to happen here is we have a long series of questions, some of them
Speaker 2:  from us and some of them from listeners. We ask for
Speaker 2:  questions on the hotline and in the email and on threads. And we got like
Speaker 2:  a billion of them. Some of them are very weird. But basically
Speaker 2:  we're sort of at the top here. We're gonna go through your review, like beat
Speaker 2:  by beat. I just, we have a bunch of questions and we're gonna talk about
Speaker 2:  them because this thing is weird and complicated and we're gonna sort of
Speaker 2:  wind towards your big feelings about this at the end. And then we're gonna
Speaker 2:  get into a bunch of questions we got from people. Does that make sense? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So the whole first section of this is called
Speaker 2:  Is It Good? And we're just gonna name a bunch of things and we're gonna
Speaker 2:  ask about if it's good. And Alex, you should obviously ask all the questions.
Speaker 2:  I'm missing lots of stuff going on here, but okay. We have, we have a bunch
Speaker 2:  of these, but the first one is, is wearing the thing, is it good?
Speaker 5:  Medium. Okay. Medium. It's heavy. It is not,
Speaker 5:  not heavy. Everything about this product is a
Speaker 5:  fight between what Apple wants it to be and what it is. As
Speaker 5:  I've been using the thing, there's a very clear gap between Apple's
Speaker 5:  ambitions and dreams. And the product that they can make and the product
Speaker 5:  they can make today is the best version of this thing that anyone has ever
Speaker 5:  made. I, I'd wanna be very clear about that. The headset you
Speaker 5:  put on your face where you look through lenses at a screen,
Speaker 5:  no one's ever done it like this. It is very good. It is obviously not the
Speaker 5:  thing that they want. And so their ambition is just like way out ahead of
Speaker 5:  the reality of this product. And the reality of this product is that it's
Speaker 5:  heavy. It weighs more than an 11 inch iPad Pro. 11 inch iPad Pro is four
Speaker 5:  70 grams. This one is somewhere between six and six 50 depending on its
Speaker 5:  configuration. Then there's the headband situation
Speaker 5:  where the really cool one, that one you want to use the solo band with the
Speaker 5:  ridges in the back and the wheel, the one they like designed the full
Speaker 2:  Ski goggles look. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's like, and that's one I've been using. It's, it's fine, but there's,
Speaker 5:  there's like not a lot of affordances in it. So you know, like the back of
Speaker 5:  your head, there's like a, a ridge, you know, to your neck. Like those are
Speaker 5:  in different spots, in different people's heads, but there's no like hinge
Speaker 5:  point. So if you just get what you get, like the thing just compresses around
Speaker 5:  your head and wherever the back of your head lines up with your eyes,
Speaker 5:  that's what you get. You know, it's, it's like there's just that, there's
Speaker 5:  the, the fact of the thing is there's not a lot of
Speaker 5:  affordances to wearing it. And then when you're wearing it, it's hot. Like
Speaker 5:  it gets hot after a while and maybe that's, you get hot after a while.
Speaker 5:  Maybe it's, it gets hot after a while, but you're like, I'm wearing a big
Speaker 5:  heavy thing on my face. And then you just take it off and then when you take
Speaker 5:  it off, you're no longer looking at screens, you're just back in the world
Speaker 5:  and you're like, oh, this is very nice.
Speaker 2:  The thing that I remember, especially with a lot of the early
Speaker 2:  Oculus and Quest stuff was there was that feeling where you would
Speaker 2:  take it off and you would kind of like scrunch and stretch your face because
Speaker 2:  you would realize like your, your forehead and the sort of bridge of your
Speaker 2:  nose had gotten just tons of pressure. Yep. As you're wearing the thing.
Speaker 2:  Is that the feeling? Like is it, is it sort of the same thing?
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. Especially on my forehead. Okay. I feel like after a long while
Speaker 5:  you feel like your eyebrows are just working. Like you just, you just start
Speaker 5:  doing the thing with your eyebrows. You're like, I'm just gonna lift it with
Speaker 5:  my face a little bit more. And then you, and then you monkey with the fit.
Speaker 5:  It's not the worst. Like make, take the decision to take the battery out
Speaker 5:  of it to reduce weight. I understand why they made that decision and it,
Speaker 5:  it's fine because the thing is such a stationary product, like in its way
Speaker 5:  that the battery just goes on the table and you're fine. but it is like they
Speaker 5:  had to do it. If they'd add the batter is that's 383 grams or
Speaker 5:  something. If they'd added another 383 grams a weight to this, it would be
Speaker 5:  a, A disaster. Yeah. So it's as close as they can get it
Speaker 5:  to being comfortable, but for a long duration of time
Speaker 5:  it is not.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 6:  Can you expand on it being stationary? Does it mean you're just like,
Speaker 6:  everything you do in it, you're just sitting still?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like you and I talk about the quest all the time. Yeah. The Quest wants
Speaker 5:  you to get up and move and play Beat Saber and
Speaker 5:  Supernatural. And there's a games on the Quest are like virtual reality games.
Speaker 5:  So like I'm gonna run around in virtual reality, right. I'm gonna do stuff.
Speaker 5:  This thing is like, I'm gonna sit down and I'm gonna look at Windows. Mm.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Like in that those windows could be everywhere, but like mostly
Speaker 5:  it's sit down and look at stuff. There are surprisingly few
Speaker 5:  games for this thing that feel like you need to move around. The only one
Speaker 5:  I've seen is Superfruit Ninja, which was in a demo,
Speaker 5:  which is not even out yet. So I haven't even gotten a chance to play Superfruit
Speaker 5:  Ninja, which is very funny. And I haven't seen a single VR game yet. There
Speaker 5:  are some coming, right? The thing supports Unity. I'm told that
Speaker 5:  Unity developers across the industry are working very hard on bringing games.
Speaker 5:  We'll see, that's to be seen. But all the games right now are
Speaker 5:  mixed reality games where just like a game board is floating in space.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So it seems like it is big and heavy in the way you would sort of
Speaker 2:  expect it to be big and heavy, but not like worse than a lot of other things.
Speaker 2:  Like it's just a headset. I feel like so much of this, and it goes back to
Speaker 2:  that thing you were saying at the beginning, like Apple would love for this
Speaker 2:  not to be a headset, but it's a headset.
Speaker 5:  It is super, A headset. Yeah. You're going to ask all these questions about
Speaker 5:  is it good? And the frame for that, all of them is like, is this
Speaker 5:  the best headset ever made? Right. And the answer is almost always yes.
Speaker 5:  But it's a headset.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So just add parentheses for a headset to all of the questions we're
Speaker 2:  about to get to. Yeah. The next one is the displays. Are they good? This
Speaker 2:  seems very important.
Speaker 5:  They are displays this, this is what I mean. You cannot, the displays are
Speaker 5:  incredible. They are a triumph of engineering that you can't see
Speaker 5:  pixels. The pixels are smaller than red blood cells, right? They're
Speaker 5:  7.5 microns. They're about the size one
Speaker 2:  Of those very cool and totally meaningless right?
Speaker 5:  Compared, but it like, they're like itty bitty, like, and then each of those
Speaker 5:  pixels has three RGB subpixels. This isn't like a PenTile
Speaker 5:  pattern, it's like straight apple calls it S stripe. You can go look at a
Speaker 5:  photo, it's RGB for each sub Pixel, each of which can be individually
Speaker 5:  controlled, like the engineering of this little display panel,
Speaker 5:  or two of them in each device. That works when you're moving your head around
Speaker 5:  like I am beyond impressed. But then you're looking at them through
Speaker 5:  lenses and there's just the reality of a
Speaker 5:  display in a lens system. So the lenses have specular
Speaker 5:  highlights or what looks like specular highlight. When you look at something
Speaker 5:  bright, the lenses have color fringing, like green
Speaker 5:  pink color fringing around the edges that if you look for
Speaker 5:  it in certain conditions, it's just gonna be there. The lenses are slightly
Speaker 5:  vignette. The lenses are slightly distorted at the edges. I asked
Speaker 5:  Apple about this and this is, they know like they, they're like, we're doing
Speaker 5:  a bunch of hardware and software to minimize these effects. But as you, they
Speaker 5:  were, they said something to me like, as you, you're well aware of displays
Speaker 5:  and lenses. You are obviously familiar with these problems. I was like, yeah,
Speaker 5:  yeah, here they are. Here's a thing that I, I keep
Speaker 5:  thinking about and I actually really want your feedback on whether this is
Speaker 5:  important or not. Apple spec for the display is 92% of the
Speaker 5:  DCIP three color gamut, which is an incredible thing to put on a
Speaker 5:  webpage. That sounds really good.
Speaker 2:  That's NELI bait right there.
Speaker 5:  DCIP three is like, you know, high-end color gamut for cinema people,
Speaker 5:  but it itself only represents like 53 or
Speaker 5:  54% of the colors your eyes can see. So 92%
Speaker 5:  of DCIP three means the displays can only show you
Speaker 5:  49% of the colors your eyes can see. I'm like a display, you know,
Speaker 5:  I'm a display nerd and I don't care on a laptop or a phone. Like
Speaker 5:  this is stuff I, I think about and I like, I like reading about if you're
Speaker 5:  like asking me to look through it all the time, I'm like, well, you just
Speaker 5:  threw away 50% of the color information in the world. I don't know how to
Speaker 5:  like, I emotionally do not know how to like comprehend that, right? Because
Speaker 5:  in every other context, I just don't care because I can just look around.
Speaker 5:  So displays are incredible. Like I don't want to overdo it. The displays
Speaker 5:  are incredible. They are a triumph. No one has ever engineered or shipped
Speaker 5:  displays like this at scale. They're so just think about how tiny
Speaker 5:  those pixels are and then you're like, oh, they are still displays, right?
Speaker 6:  Like you never forget,
Speaker 5:  Right? You never forget. You are looking at screens like
Speaker 5:  the most screens and then on, you know, the reality pass through is camera
Speaker 5:  based. So there's just like motion blur. Even a bright room when
Speaker 5:  you like look around, there's motion blur on the displays. You can't, you
Speaker 5:  just can't overcome the inherent nature of cameras and displays.
Speaker 5:  So the question is like, is are the displays good? Is really a question about
Speaker 5:  like, how is the product designed to be used and can
Speaker 5:  the displays do all the things that you think they should be able to do?
Speaker 5:  And the answer is they're the most incredible displays ever. They're triumph
Speaker 5:  of engineering. You are still looking at screens and being asked to perceive
Speaker 5:  reality through screens is a is a tall ask.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's a weird one. I feel like for this first run
Speaker 2:  of this, when this technology is new to most people and
Speaker 2:  new to like existence, that feels like a somewhat acceptable
Speaker 2:  trade off, right? Like we're, we're gonna hit a point where especially with
Speaker 2:  something like this, if I am looking at my room and then I put on a headset
Speaker 2:  and suddenly my room, which it's still showing me is
Speaker 2:  different, that feels bad in a way that like I turn on my TV
Speaker 2:  and trees don't look the same color, they do out my window, but they're like
Speaker 2:  different trees in a different place and my brain understands that that's
Speaker 2:  a screen. Like your brain is not supposed to understand that this is a screen,
Speaker 2:  right? Like that's what success looks like is that you forget you're looking
Speaker 2:  at screens and for now at least it feels like
Speaker 2:  I'm looking at screens and they're very good. Like just the fact that you
Speaker 2:  didn't even mention how it feels to like read text on a
Speaker 2:  webpage feels like a victory to me because it means it was fine. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  that is, to me, at least for this first one that's the bar is like, can
Speaker 2:  I look at stuff? And, and it seems like we're there,
Speaker 5:  You can read texts on a webpage that refresh rates, it can go up to a hundred
Speaker 5:  hertz. I mean, again, incredible technical achievement
Speaker 5:  with these displays. Yeah. I I not even a hint of,
Speaker 5:  boy, I can imagine how these displays could be better, like incredible technical
Speaker 5:  achievement with these displays and when digital information,
Speaker 5:  right? Windows, videos, Mac mirror, like all that
Speaker 5:  stuff looks good. But again, the displays are being
Speaker 5:  asked to pass through reality and your eyes
Speaker 5:  are better than screens and cameras. And that is a historic problem.
Speaker 5:  Like, don don't know that we can overcome that problem.
Speaker 6:  Well I was gonna ask, is it, you know, when you think of AR the two kind
Speaker 6:  of most successful, I'm using big scare quotes here. Most
Speaker 6:  successful ones have been what? Magic Leap and HoloLens.
Speaker 2:  That's a bleak, I use the scare
Speaker 6:  Quotes guys, I use the scare quotes. Is the experience just that, that
Speaker 6:  that interaction with the real world through this headset, is that better
Speaker 6:  in this than in those systems?
Speaker 5:  What's fascinating about both of those is one, they failed two,
Speaker 5:  there's like no AR happening in this thing. None. Oh,
Speaker 5:  there are exactly three ar things that I have seen so far.
Speaker 5:  And by ar I mean digital information layered over the real world
Speaker 5:  where the real world and the virtual world interact. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Right. So virtual reality, you're just in a virtual, a virtual world, you're
Speaker 5:  doing stuff in the virtual world, the real world doesn't matter. Mixed reality
Speaker 5:  is what most people have experienced. It's what most of this is where you're
Speaker 5:  in the real world and you just like put up virtual stuff, but there's no
Speaker 5:  connection between the real world and the virtual world. Right? Right. So
Speaker 5:  I've got windows, safari windows are open all around me. It's not like
Speaker 5:  I'm, they're sticking to the walls. Like they're just like floating all around
Speaker 5:  me and then that bubble can move through the pass through. That's, it's weird,
Speaker 5:  but it, you know, like yeah, that's mixed reality and that's what most people
Speaker 5:  are familiar with and that's a lot of this, the three AR features
Speaker 5:  I've seen so far in the vision pro, two of which I think are historically
Speaker 5:  important, like should go down as footnotes in the history of AR one. When
Speaker 5:  you open a Mac laptop and you look at it and it's your laptop and your
Speaker 5:  iCloud, a button floats above the screen that says connect.
Speaker 2:  Oh that's awesome. Oh that's
Speaker 5:  Cool. And you can, you can just reach out and push it and then your MAC display
Speaker 5:  mirrors into the Vision Pro. Incredible. That rules
Speaker 2:  Two,
Speaker 5:  When you are typing on a Bluetooth keyboard and you look down, it knows where
Speaker 5:  the keyboard is and it puts a text preview window above it so you can look
Speaker 5:  at your fingers typing on the keys and see what's being typed.
Speaker 2:  Oh. So instead of having the text box like way up here while you're looking
Speaker 2:  down at the keyboard, it brings the text box down to the keyboard. Right.
Speaker 5:  I've got a big Google doc up there, I'm typing away and I look down at the
Speaker 5:  keyboard and I can see what I'm typing. So I don't have to like move my head
Speaker 5:  around. Clever. And it, it positions that box correctly near the keyboard
Speaker 5:  and it shows you what you're typing. That is a true AR feature, right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  There's a connection between what I'm doing in the real world and a connection
Speaker 5:  in the virtual world and they've made, and that is amazing. Again, I think
Speaker 5:  these are like the first mainstream AR features to ever ship
Speaker 5:  historic. The third one that I've seen is the loading screen for Super
Speaker 5:  Fruit Ninja where you can throw a strawberry at a pig that's running around
Speaker 5:  your floor that is not even shipping yet. I only saw that in a demo
Speaker 5:  that Apple gave me. It, it feels less historic. I'm just gonna say don don't
Speaker 5:  think that is quite as historic.
Speaker 2:  I feel like this is true erasure of the thing where I can put an IKEA couch
Speaker 2:  in my living room through my iPad,
Speaker 5:  But that's what Apple has been demoing forever. Right?
Speaker 2:  I know. It's the only feature idea anyone has ever had until
Speaker 2:  this thing
Speaker 5:  And it's, it's just not here. And I asked and you know, they're like, game
Speaker 5:  developers are working on this. Like, you know, the most charitable read
Speaker 5:  of this thing is this is a developer kit. Yeah. And so they're gonna build
Speaker 5:  all these and they're, and they're yet to come and, and I think that you,
Speaker 5:  if you wanna be really fair to this thing, that's how you think about it.
Speaker 5:  But Apple's positioning everything, the thing they're asking it to do, the
Speaker 5:  ad they put out is like people wearing it while they're just like hanging
Speaker 5:  out doing laundry and a call comes in and you're like, what is the value
Speaker 5:  of wearing this if it's not doing anything for you? And the value should
Speaker 5:  be a bunch of AR stuff, not, I'm waiting for the phone to ring and I, there's
Speaker 5:  again, there's a real tension between the ambition of the product and how
Speaker 5:  it's being communicated and the reality of the product.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Okay. That's good. So, and I think this is related and we've kind of
Speaker 2:  halfway answered it, but the next one I had written down here is the pass
Speaker 2:  through. Is it good?
Speaker 5:  It is as good as any pass through can ever be and I think pass through is
Speaker 5:  a dead end.
Speaker 2:  Okay. That's essentially what I wanted you to say. And this is where, this
Speaker 2:  is where we get into questions about like optical AR and the question of
Speaker 2:  like what are these things supposed to look like in the future? And one of
Speaker 2:  your hobby horses, which you've talked about a lot on this podcast, is like
Speaker 2:  a VR headset might be the wrong direction for this because eventually if
Speaker 2:  it's gonna be glasses you're gonna have things like peripheral vision and
Speaker 2:  light is gonna be able to get in from the outside. So like even the best
Speaker 2:  possible version of this thing we're trying to do is not the thing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And and it doesn't seem like using this has changed your mind on that
Speaker 2:  at all.
Speaker 5:  It's displays and cameras. Yeah. So you've got a thing over your head and
Speaker 5:  then there's a camera looking at the world for you and it's showing it on
Speaker 5:  display and that just, you already, if you are a Vergecast listener,
Speaker 5:  you already know a bunch of stuff about cameras in displays just by osmosis
Speaker 5:  from being around the show story. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  We're so
Speaker 5:  Sorry. In low light, what does a camera have to do? It has to increase the
Speaker 5:  ISO or increase the shutter speed. They can increase the shutter speed because
Speaker 5:  they need the latency to be so low. So you can tell what it's doing is really
Speaker 5:  ramping ISO and then doing a bunch of noise reduction. So in low light things
Speaker 5:  just get, the world is less sharp. I walked into my bathroom wearing
Speaker 5:  the sue day and turned around and I couldn't find the light switch.
Speaker 2:  Oh wow.
Speaker 5:  Right. Wow. It was just like too dark in there for me to see the light switch.
Speaker 5:  I took the thing off and I was like, well there's lights, you know, it's
Speaker 5:  like, so there's a thing that happens there. It is incredible. Pastor again,
Speaker 5:  it is the best that has ever been done on a consumer device. It is the best
Speaker 5:  that most people ever experienced. Alex don don't know about the, the Varrio
Speaker 5:  headset that you've talked about, but Addie is familiar with it. She was
Speaker 5:  my editor on this. She's like, you know, it's an enterprise product. It's
Speaker 5:  way more expensive. Like so for a consumer headset, this is definitely the,
Speaker 5:  the best pass through it has ever shipped. It might be better than the varrio,
Speaker 5:  you know, probably, but the VA is like aimed it enterprise application. It's
Speaker 5:  just like a different thing for a consumer product. This thing is the best
Speaker 5:  you will get and it can do things that no other
Speaker 5:  password I've ever seen can do. I can just use my phone with no blooming.
Speaker 5:  Like apple's HDR video processing capabilities are incredible
Speaker 5:  and they're doing it in real time at 12 milliseconds of latency. So
Speaker 5:  stunning technical achievement. You're asking it to replace reality.
Speaker 5:  You've set the bar so high that like, I don't know that it can be
Speaker 5:  crossed. I can't sit here and imagine how you could make cameras and screens
Speaker 5:  overcome their limitations. It like a real way. Like maybe noise
Speaker 5:  reduction can get even better but you have to make it 50 times better
Speaker 5:  for this to substitute for reality. Yeah. And So I, there's just, when I
Speaker 5:  say it's a dead end, it's like this is as good as anyone has ever done it
Speaker 5:  and it feels like optical AR is still the thing you want where light
Speaker 5:  is just passing through some glasses, some lenses and they're, the screens
Speaker 5:  are being put over it And that's really hard. And I think there's a reason
Speaker 5:  Apple shipped this 'cause no one has gotten there yet.
Speaker 2:  There was some technology not that long ago, I think it might've been self-driving
Speaker 2:  cars that somebody described as like really amazing and three physics
Speaker 2:  miracles away from being possible. And I feel like there's some of that in
Speaker 2:  here too that it's like the things that we're doing here are incredible and
Speaker 2:  we fundamentally have to change the laws of the universe in order to get
Speaker 2:  to the next thing after this. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That, that feels, that feels correct with this device. It's
Speaker 2:  Kinda like
Speaker 7:  Robotics, right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, totally. Where you're
Speaker 6:  Always expecting the, the robot to walk like a human. But actually
Speaker 6:  humans are really well made
Speaker 5:  For that thing. Humans are not well made for mounting hardware on like a
Speaker 5:  VR headset on your face.
Speaker 2:  I have found myself wondering, in talking to you about this thing many times
Speaker 2:  who the like platonic ideal of the vision pro wearer is and like
Speaker 2:  what the measurements of their face are. 'cause you know there is like, there
Speaker 2:  is a head in there that is like just crushing it with the vision Pro
Speaker 5:  Apple, you know, apple like measures everyone ears to make the AirPods. I
Speaker 5:  asked if there was a maximum head size. Okay and I was told
Speaker 5:  we have not considered that, but there is a maximum hair size.
Speaker 6:  Wow.
Speaker 2:  It's Craig. If you have bigger hair than Craig,
Speaker 5:  It is like very, it's not like a small, it is very large, but there is some
Speaker 5:  sort of maximum hair size.
Speaker 2:  We have to find the maximum hair size. This is now the first cat's main
Speaker 2:  goal. All right, let's keep going Audio, which I think is a sneakily
Speaker 2:  important and kind of underused feature of all of these headsets.
Speaker 2:  Is it good?
Speaker 5:  It's great. No, no complaints. It is very loud. The spacial stuff is
Speaker 5:  really cool when you push the window. I watched the NFC championship game
Speaker 5:  on YouTube TV and the browser on the, on the thing last night and as I pushed
Speaker 5:  the browser window away, the Detroit lions got farther and farther away from
Speaker 5:  me. You know, like that's cool. It is very loud. Everyone around you
Speaker 5:  can hear what you're doing. So if you are in a public place, you should wear
Speaker 5:  the air. You should in particular, you should wear second generation AirPods
Speaker 5:  Pro. You can use any Bluetooth headphones you want. But the second generation
Speaker 5:  AirPods Pro get all of the features so they get spatial audio, they get lower
Speaker 5:  latency, they get 48 kilohertz. Like you just want to use those also
Speaker 2:  Feels like the right, you don't want big headphones with these like you don't
Speaker 2:  need more weight on your head as you're wearing grow. Yeah. Okay. But in
Speaker 2:  but no, no notes. You're a guy who cares deeply about this stuff. You're,
Speaker 2:  you're good with spatial audio, you're happy about this?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean I, I'm sure if I had more time in sleep I
Speaker 5:  would have notes on the audio but no, no notes.
Speaker 2:  Everyone has just been sneaking up on you for several days now.
Speaker 5:  But again, there's not, again because there's not a lot of AR experiences
Speaker 5:  or even VR experiences, that thing hasn't happened. It's just windows
Speaker 5:  are playing audio at you. I was on a FaceTime call with Joanna and Marquez
Speaker 5:  so we could look at personas and
Speaker 5:  boy and they, their PS three characters sounded like
Speaker 5:  they were talking to me from where they were, which is cool.
Speaker 6:  Part of that is really cool.
Speaker 2:  Alright, one more and then we're gonna take a break and then we're gonna
Speaker 2:  get into some of the like how you use this thing stuff. Battery life, is
Speaker 2:  it good?
Speaker 5:  Irrelevant. That's my answer. It's why it's fine.
Speaker 5:  It's two and a half hours. Okay. We haven't had a chance to like do a battery
Speaker 5:  rundown. I'm not even sure that I would wanna subject anyone to do a battery
Speaker 5:  rundown. And that's what I mean it by, it's irrelevant if you are in this
Speaker 5:  thing for two and a half hours, boy are you gonna feel it? I can't. I just,
Speaker 5:  I personally cannot imagine a situation where you want to be in it for that
Speaker 5:  long. I know Joanna wore it for like 20 hours straight
Speaker 5:  or whatever. She did some enormous, the don don't know what the actual number
Speaker 5:  is 'cause I, as we are recording this, I have not read her review, but when
Speaker 5:  I had talked to her on that FaceTime call, she'd been wearing it for five
Speaker 5:  hours. Oh boy. Wow. And I'm very worried. I love her to pieces. She's one
Speaker 5:  of the very closest friends. I'm so worried about her. I just can't imagine
Speaker 5:  a situation where you want to hit the battery life and
Speaker 5:  then because it is so stationary you're, it feels like it'll be close to
Speaker 5:  power. Now the one situation where you, I could see it being a problem is
Speaker 5:  a plane. Hmm. But then you're sitting so you can just like plug in a battery
Speaker 5:  like you'll be fine.
Speaker 2:  Can you hot swap the batteries? That's a question. We've gotten a bunch.
Speaker 5:  You cannot hot swap the batteries. The batteries are, it's a mechanical
Speaker 5:  twist connector. It's very satisfying. It's like a big cyber decky
Speaker 5:  twist connector, you know, and it lights up. The battery is a motion sensor
Speaker 5:  so when you pick it up, the light glows green or orange. It's a very apple.
Speaker 5:  There's no button to tell you the battery status. It has a motion sensor.
Speaker 5:  Sure at 34 99 you can do anything. So
Speaker 5:  it just picks up and glows. But you can't hot swap it from the headset itself.
Speaker 5:  You can just plug another battery into it over USBC.
Speaker 2:  Alright, let's take a quick break and then we're gonna come back and talk
Speaker 2:  about the bunch of ways you actually use this thing. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Next one on my list. I think we should get into the
Speaker 2:  like life inside of the headset thing. And I, I feel like there are two big
Speaker 2:  parts of the how you use this thing that really
Speaker 2:  sort of define whether this thing is gonna work or not. I guess the, the
Speaker 2:  first one is, is the eye tracking. So eye tracking is it good?
Speaker 5:  It's as good as anyone has ever shipped. Eye tracking.
Speaker 2:  I'm just gonna start playing that for myself. At the beginning of every one
Speaker 2:  of these answers, which
Speaker 6:  Version of Toby does it really like perfectly replicate.
Speaker 2:  That's Toby with two eyes.
Speaker 5:  It is the best eye tracking that anyone has ever shipped. Yeah, I It's not
Speaker 5:  good enough Ooh. This is, I like, I'm just gonna keep coming back to this
Speaker 5:  and it's gonna be frustrating until you use it.
Speaker 5:  It's the best, the first time you use it until you use it. It's hard to even
Speaker 5:  for me to explain what I'm talking about. Yeah. The
Speaker 5:  first time you put it on and we, you know, so many of us have had that demo,
Speaker 5:  it's magic. You look at stuff, it highlights,
Speaker 5:  you click your fingers together. If you get it wrong, you're like, oh, you
Speaker 5:  just have to get used to it. Right? Like that's the experience that you have
Speaker 5:  in that first demo. The idea
Speaker 2:  Is basically like where your eyes focus is a
Speaker 2:  cursor is sort of the way to think about it, right? And you're sort of moving
Speaker 2:  that cursor around with your gaze and you look
Speaker 2:  at a button in order to be able to click on that button, right? Is that like,
Speaker 2:  is that a reasonable way to think about the metaphor there? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You know how the iPad cursor kind of snaps it's that.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Right. So you just sort of like if buttons are big and you look in
Speaker 5:  a general error, they will highlight.
Speaker 2:  Oh, I see. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Fascinating thing about this is one, I think Vision OS
Speaker 5:  is designed for eye tracking that is slightly more precise than it actually
Speaker 5:  is. Like that's how it feels. Ooh it probably isn't. It's probably designed
Speaker 5:  to be exactly as it's apple, right? Meaning
Speaker 2:  Like the buttons are like a little too small and a little too close
Speaker 5:  Together. Yeah. I'll just give you one super dumb example. The keyboard
Speaker 5:  is like ridiculous. Like it's just a fully rid, like they needed
Speaker 5:  to have a keyboard and it's there, but there's no way they want you to use
Speaker 5:  that keyboard for any serious text input. The keys are too close together.
Speaker 5:  So you're like sitting there trying to look from one letter to another and
Speaker 5:  you're just like, I hate, I hate this. And then you just give up and you
Speaker 5:  like dictate to Siri or you connect a regular keyboard and you use that keyboard.
Speaker 5:  There's no way you should use that keyboard. And part of it is that it is
Speaker 5:  just funda. It's fundamentally ridiculous. Part of it is like the, the buttons
Speaker 5:  are close, too close together and you will sit there trying to look from
Speaker 5:  the E to the R and the system just like won't let you. And
Speaker 5:  I've never looked at a letter as hard as I've tried to look at a letter
Speaker 5:  and be like, I'm looking at it man. Brain
Speaker 2:  Is saying like RRR.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And the sometimes the easiest thing to do is to look completely away
Speaker 5:  and try again. Right? And maybe the thing is like, you know, I can't
Speaker 5:  quantify it. Maybe it's 99% accurate, but
Speaker 5:  that 1% just like ends it, but it
Speaker 6:  Doesn't like wiggle. Like Toby would sometimes kind of wiggle.
Speaker 6:  It wouldn't quite register your eye.
Speaker 5:  It's the best eye tracking that has ever been shipped. This is what I'm saying.
Speaker 5:  This is the best anyone has ever done it. Yeah. Without question. It's the
Speaker 5:  best anyone's ever done it. And you know, a keyboard on a computer is a
Speaker 5:  hundred percent precise, right? Right. You push a button, that
Speaker 5:  button is pushed every single time. Multitouch iPhone is actually not
Speaker 5:  a hundred percent precise. There's a lot of algorithmic work happening to
Speaker 5:  make a touchscreen appear to be a hundred percent precise. Like a lot
Speaker 5:  of work has happened over the past decade to make those touchscreens feel
Speaker 5:  even more precise. But they appear to you to be a hundred percent precise.
Speaker 5:  And when they are not, like when autocorrect fails, which is an experience
Speaker 5:  everyone has, you are utterly frustrated, right? When when a touchscreen
Speaker 5:  goes dead and you're jabbing at a button, it doesn't do anything. Whew. That's
Speaker 5:  awful. Right? That's the worst. That's the worst. But most of the time a
Speaker 5:  touchscreen appears to be a hundred percent like direct input control. Your
Speaker 5:  eyes are bad that like you are just constantly
Speaker 5:  looking at stuff that you don't wanna look at, right? Yeah. Or like you're
Speaker 5:  looking at the biggest thing instead of, well the play button is the biggest
Speaker 5:  thing in a video player. And I constantly wanna push the plus 10 seconds,
Speaker 5:  but my eyes are like, look at how big that play button is. And so I'm just
Speaker 5:  looking at the wrong thing. And that is, it's the best anyone's ever done
Speaker 5:  it. And it went Addie's line was It works until it
Speaker 5:  doesn't. Mm. Right. And my version of that is it feels like magic until it
Speaker 5:  is not. Yeah. And there's, it's just a binary So I
Speaker 5:  this connects to hand tracking, which I think is your next question probably.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The hand tracking is exactly the same way. It's magic until it is not.
Speaker 5:  And particularly where it's not is when it can't see your hands,
Speaker 5:  which, like, I'm just sitting at a table right now. If I just had my hands
Speaker 5:  in my, my lap, it couldn't see my hands. This is a ridiculous complaint.
Speaker 5:  The hand tracking system needs to see your hands. No other computer stops
Speaker 5:  working if it can't see your hands.
Speaker 5:  Like, like if you want this to be a primary computing device like your hand,
Speaker 5:  it has to be able to see your hands. If I, if you're just standing up and
Speaker 5:  your hands are by your sides and if you're like me, they kind of like fall
Speaker 5:  behind you, it stops working. And so like it's the
Speaker 5:  best it's ever been shipped without question. It is the best it's ever been
Speaker 5:  shipped it. It just hits the wall of reality, which is the thing
Speaker 5:  is not actually your eyes and your hands are not actually controlling this
Speaker 5:  device. Cameras are watching your hands in your eyes
Speaker 5:  interpreting them and turning that into input. And that interpretation
Speaker 5:  has real limits.
Speaker 6:  So like to keep it fully functional at all times, you have to kinda like
Speaker 6:  keep your hands up at all
Speaker 5:  Times. No, it's a pretty big bubble around you. Okay. So like, if you are,
Speaker 5:  it's basically like if you slice your body in half, it's the plane of the
Speaker 5:  body in front of you, like all the way around. So if you're sitting
Speaker 5:  on a couch and you got a hand over the side of the couch, it mostly works
Speaker 5:  If you are anywhere, anywhere, I can see your hands basically. Okay.
Speaker 5:  But if you, if it's really dark and you are lying down
Speaker 5:  and the IR flood lights in the front can't sort of like reach down and see
Speaker 5:  your hands and light them up, the cameras can't see your hands. So then you
Speaker 5:  can't use it. It's like you're, you're just gonna find all of these places
Speaker 5:  where like if you are meant to wear this thing all the time, the, they will
Speaker 5:  come up more than you think. But in most uses it feels like magic.
Speaker 5:  Right? It's this line of it is absolutely magic until it is not. Oh, and
Speaker 5:  then the other thing that's funny is that it is always using your hands as
Speaker 5:  input. This is
Speaker 2:  What I was about to ask about, like, have you had to train yourself to be
Speaker 2:  aware of your eyes and hands in ways that you wouldn't be? Yes. Otherwise.
Speaker 2:  Like you, anyone who has ever watched The Vergecast on YouTube knows
Speaker 2:  NELI, never ever, ever stops moving his hands. You touch the mics, you're
Speaker 2:  moving around, you're gesturing at stuff, you're pointing at Yes. Things
Speaker 2:  you're, you're like, are you like aware of these parts of your body
Speaker 2:  in new ways after using these devices?
Speaker 5:  Yes. In particular, you have to sit still. When I write scripts for a decoder
Speaker 5:  or for video reviews like this, I talk as I write to make sure I
Speaker 5:  can read what I'm writing and it sounds good and flows. And I move my hands
Speaker 5:  when I talk. And I was just scrolling all over the place by accident, just
Speaker 5:  whipping windows around for no reason, just clicking on stuff. And I was
Speaker 5:  like, oh I gotta, I gotta keep my hands still. Some people do not secret
Speaker 5:  their hands. This is a very personalized complaint. But if you do, you're
Speaker 5:  gonna notice you have to sit still unless you want to do something. And then
Speaker 5:  the other thing is that you have to get used to the
Speaker 5:  control being linked to your eyes. And that is not how you use a
Speaker 5:  computer. How many times have you looked at something on screen and just
Speaker 5:  banged around the arrow keys to get around without looking at the arrow keys
Speaker 5:  constantly all the time on the Vision Pro you have to go
Speaker 5:  look right. Right. That, and that's just like the simplest example on a phone
Speaker 5:  where you know there's a little bit more collapse between what you're looking
Speaker 5:  at in the controls. How many times do I opened Lightroom and like move to
Speaker 5:  slider back and forth while looking at the photo to see how the brightness
Speaker 5:  is changing or whatever. On the Vision Pro, you gotta look at that brightness
Speaker 5:  slider. Weird. Weird.
Speaker 6:  Does it feel like that friction could ever go away for you? Like at
Speaker 6:  some point you could see yourself doing it more naturally and it's just you've
Speaker 6:  had five days with it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I've had five days with it. You know, I've asked Apple about this particular
Speaker 5:  thing. This is a big philosophical needy design. Yeah. Question, right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like should the control of the thing be directly linked to what you're looking
Speaker 5:  at? Or should those things be disconnected? And so, you know, obviously
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm asking this, I'm just wandering the streets being like, what is
Speaker 5:  the essential nature of input? This is what I love. I love it. I love talking
Speaker 5:  about this stuff. And they're like, you get one, you get used to it and two,
Speaker 5:  that it's not the only input on the system, right? You can connect a Bluetooth
Speaker 5:  keyboard and trackpad, you can use Siri to do all this stuff. Like we want
Speaker 5:  to expand the range of computing inputs beyond the mouse and the keyboard.
Speaker 5:  And after five days or six days, I'm kind of like, well the mouse and keyboard
Speaker 5:  are historically undefeated. So yeah, good luck. You know,
Speaker 5:  like,
Speaker 2:  I, I agree with that. The one that's missing there is like, I think there's
Speaker 2:  a way of looking at the Vision Pro that is sort of an amalgamation of all
Speaker 2:  of the technology Apple has ever built to do anything all in one device.
Speaker 2:  And the one that it feels like it's missing is multitouch. Like it's, it's
Speaker 2:  surprising to me. Yeah. Given all of the stuff in here that there isn't a
Speaker 2:  way to reach out and touch the buttons on the keyboard to type.
Speaker 5:  You can, you can punch one finger at a time. Oh
Speaker 2:  You can. Oh okay.
Speaker 5:  That makes me feel you can't multitouch. Okay. Right. So it can register
Speaker 5:  big movements of the hands. I want to like, big is the wrong
Speaker 5:  word.
Speaker 2:  So you can type on it like a typewriter kind of.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, you can, you can hand pack on a, on a and you look silly and it's
Speaker 5:  slow and it's not a hundred percent accurate. Sure. And like I said that,
Speaker 5:  but you can do that, right? Like we don't have Optic Id
Speaker 5:  set up on ours because other people, like the video team is constantly using
Speaker 5:  it, light it up and all this stuff and so everyone puts it on and they punch
Speaker 5:  the code into Oh,
Speaker 2:  Interesting. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Right. Instead of doing the thing. 'cause it's just, it's just a big phone
Speaker 5:  key badge or what looks like a phone keypad shows up in front of you and
Speaker 5:  you're like boop boop boop boop. And it's like very funny to watch everyone
Speaker 5:  do this every time they put it on.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So that is a fallback option. At least makes me feel a little bit better
Speaker 2:  about this. I do think there is a thing that the, the eye tracking, it just
Speaker 2:  adds another step to everything you want to do. Yep. The the
Speaker 2:  example I always give to people is like, your muscle memory knows where all
Speaker 2:  the app icons are on your phone. So like if you, if you had to think about
Speaker 2:  looking at an app every single time you wanted to open it, it would be annoying.
Speaker 2:  And it's just your, your fingers learn where things are in a way that is
Speaker 2:  useless to you on the Vision Pro.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You have to be looking at things. I'll give you another example actually.
Speaker 5:  The Multi-touch example is a really good one. So a quest where you have
Speaker 5:  controllers and every VR company loves being like, you're
Speaker 5:  a DJ now. They just love it. Didn't, you know, in my twenties I was
Speaker 5:  like, I'm gonna be a DJ feels right if we all, we all go through this period.
Speaker 5:  We all
Speaker 6:  Had that moment and
Speaker 2:  In all subsequent decades, Bila has said those things.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I'm still a dj, I'm playing tonight at Soundbar. So in the Quest you
Speaker 5:  have controllers in your hands and you like look at Tribe xr, which is the
Speaker 5:  DJ app on the Quest and it's floating in space and you like reach out
Speaker 5:  and it shows your hands, it doesn't show the the controllers and you push
Speaker 5:  the button and it looks like you're grabbing the fader and then after a while
Speaker 5:  your brain kind of remaps, you're like, oh I'm actually grabbing this fader.
Speaker 5:  I'm actually twisting this knob. And your hands are doing some controller
Speaker 5:  stuff, right? They're just like gripping or pushing the button, the trigger
Speaker 5:  button. but it after your brain just kinda like remaps to that
Speaker 5:  thing. Vision Pro doesn't have that. It's got taps. So you
Speaker 5:  look at a knob and you tap your fingers and drag it the
Speaker 5:  same way you do anything else and it's like, oh I'm not, there's no connection
Speaker 5:  between me physically interacting with this floating deck in dj,
Speaker 5:  which is the Vision Pro version of this. The way that in Tribe xr, it's like
Speaker 5:  I've got a controller, I'm pushing buttons on the controller and because
Speaker 5:  something tactile is happening to my hands that looks like something tactile
Speaker 5:  is happening over here. Like my brain is just like rewiring to be
Speaker 5:  convinced that that is actually happening now. Interesting. Now can I DJ
Speaker 5:  in any of these apps? No,
Speaker 5:  Absolutely not. But the Vision Pro is like because you're just tapping your
Speaker 5:  fingers together. It's like you're clicking. The difference is very much
Speaker 5:  between, I would give you the difference is feels very much like the difference
Speaker 5:  between a touchscreen and a mouse. Right? Where a touchscreen feels like
Speaker 5:  you're directly controlling some pixels and a mouse is like I'm clicking
Speaker 5:  on stuff. Okay. So
Speaker 6:  Sort of like when you're on a screen and you're trying to play an old, like
Speaker 6:  a Nintendo game on your phone it feels like garbage. But then younger people
Speaker 6:  are just used to phone screens and so it, they don't hate it as much. They,
Speaker 6:  they can play Fortnite and stuff.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I watch Max plays Minecraft on her iPad. I'm like how are you doing
Speaker 5:  this? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So she'll have a great time. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So may maybe the younger people are gonna live fully in headsets and they're
Speaker 5:  gonna be fun. But it's that, it's that control dynamic is
Speaker 5:  you, you will feel it in a way that, again, I keep saying it is the best
Speaker 5:  it has ever been done. Is it good enough? Like I don Dunno, I I don Dunno.
Speaker 5:  I don Dunno if it can ever be, it has to be 50 times better. By the way,
Speaker 5:  can I say this thing please? Because I haven't given this a score yet. So
Speaker 5:  we're gonna spend all night debating the score. I think shipping a
Speaker 5:  $3,500 computer whose default input method is not a hundred
Speaker 5:  percent consistent. That's a full point. Yes. That's a full
Speaker 5:  point, right? A hundred
Speaker 2:  Percent. And one out of every a hundred times you hit a key. It just made
Speaker 2:  up a different key to do. Yeah. You would not like that keyboard.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Right. And there's all these other affordances and whatever, but like
Speaker 5:  that feels like a full point.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Anytime I review an E Ink device, I have to like knock
Speaker 6:  off a point 'cause it's not gonna work all the time.
Speaker 5:  That's brutal.
Speaker 2:  You type three letters and then four seconds later it types two of them and
Speaker 2:  then something else. Okay. Let's get to the, the two main use cases
Speaker 2:  that I think we and others have identified for this thing so far. And you
Speaker 2:  should, you should add to this list if there are any obvious big
Speaker 2:  ones that I'm missing. But the first one is using it essentially as a
Speaker 2:  monitor for your computer as a a thing to attach to a Mac
Speaker 2:  and do stuff with. Is it good?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's really good. Caveats it. One, it's really good. You put, especially
Speaker 5:  if you have a a laptop, you push the button. The thing that I really enjoyed
Speaker 5:  doing was putting the, the virtual display over where my Mac display
Speaker 5:  had been. My MacBook display had been and then making it really big. So then
Speaker 5:  you're like, I have a 50 inch MacBook Pro, I'm gonna use Lightroom. It's
Speaker 5:  cool. Like that is just cool.
Speaker 2:  So it's like you have your Mac on your desk and then a giant ass like TV
Speaker 2:  sized monitor in front of you. Right?
Speaker 5:  But like where the MacBook display is, oh
Speaker 2:  Can you do the thing from your Mac where you have like a
Speaker 2:  bunch of windows spread around the room or whatever. Can I put Mac apps in
Speaker 2:  all those places? Or is that just Vision Pro apps
Speaker 5:  You get one single Mac display, you can't have multiple Mac displays, which
Speaker 5:  know a lot of people wanna do, which you can do to much less good effect
Speaker 5:  with Quest headsets, right? Like there are apps in the Quest that just will
Speaker 5:  let you have multiple monitors. Yeah, I assume there will be those apps for
Speaker 5:  Vision Pro, but by default and with all of the cool iCloud stuff that
Speaker 5:  you want, which is really important. It's one display. And by the way, the
Speaker 5:  cool iCloud stuff, magic, you know, this is like an iPad on your face. Like
Speaker 5:  it's a very easy way to understand what's happening here and the cool iPad
Speaker 5:  stuff that Continuity can do is amazing in this context. So you're
Speaker 5:  using a Mac in this window and then you just scroll the mouse on the Mac
Speaker 5:  Track pad over and it turns into a Vision Pro Cursor. You copy from the Mac
Speaker 5:  in this window and you paste it in the Vision Pro app over here and it just
Speaker 5:  works. That's cool. Very cool.
Speaker 2:  All right, so that's that one. And then the other one is basically using
Speaker 2:  it as a TV entertainment system. This is the one I think Alex and I are both
Speaker 2:  the most theoretically excited about. That feels like it could be the most
Speaker 2:  immediately useful for people. Is it a good tv?
Speaker 5:  Super good. Okay, very good. I watched way more of Top Gun Maverick than
Speaker 5:  I wanted to. And by the way, I watched it on the treadmill at 2.7
Speaker 5:  miles an hour, just walking up a hill very slowly. Okay. I did not try to
Speaker 5:  run, I was like, I'm not, yeah, I don Dunno about this, but I was like, can
Speaker 5:  I take a slow walk watching a movie on the best TV I can get in near a
Speaker 5:  treadmill? And the answer was unequivocally yes. Very cool. It does
Speaker 5:  this really cool thing when you put it in environments where the light from
Speaker 5:  the TV reflects, unlike the mountain, it's, it's just all very cool. The
Speaker 5:  caveat I will give you is it supports 3D,
Speaker 5:  it supports high frame rate. It's the only consumer device that supports
Speaker 5:  high frame rate 3D. So you can watch Avatar wave water at 48 frames
Speaker 5:  per second and three DI don't know if that's good. It's just like, that's
Speaker 5:  what James Cameron wants. Like you can, you can, you can live that life.
Speaker 5:  I watched five minutes that and I was sick. Oh wow. And I, you know, like
Speaker 5:  I'm pretty good at vr like I do, I I play grand. My vr right. VR motion
Speaker 5:  does not drive me too crazy. This was like too much and I had to take it
Speaker 5:  off immediately. So I would just be careful and there are no guardrails anywhere
Speaker 5:  in Vision Os to tell you, be careful. The, the one that I've seen
Speaker 5:  is if you take a spatial, like a a first person video and
Speaker 5:  there's a lot of motion in it, it will detect that there's a lot of motion
Speaker 5:  in it and be like, be careful watching this one. It does not say be careful
Speaker 5:  watching Avatar wave
Speaker 2:  Water. Interesting.
Speaker 5:  But if be your own video, it'll sometimes say be careful.
Speaker 2:  You should always be careful watching the way of water, no matter the circumstances.
Speaker 2:  You should always be careful. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, the TV stuff is good. The thing that I will two caveats there.
Speaker 5:  One, you're alone, there's no you even if like three of you have a vision
Speaker 5:  pro together, you can't sync 'em up. So you can't look at the same thing
Speaker 5:  at the same time. I mean you can manually sync them up, which is sad if
Speaker 5:  you find yourself with like three people wearing a vision pro counting to
Speaker 5:  three to hit the play button on Avatar. Like just buy a tv.
Speaker 2:  It's like the thing on a plane where you, you try and hit play on on both
Speaker 2:  screens at the same time. It's good stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So like there, but there's no in in os sinking of that stuff.
Speaker 5:  So you Yeah. I'll watch the same thing, which is weird Right. Movie or someone
Speaker 5:  social experiences and then two, you can't screen record what you're seeing
Speaker 5:  like Disney will just DRM that shit out. Yeah. And I was like, this sucks.
Speaker 5:  Like that's me being like, oh this sucks. Like a huge part
Speaker 5:  of the experience of watching shows right now is like sharing clips of social
Speaker 5:  media or whatever and you can't Weird it's, and then, and then it's your
Speaker 5:  eyes, right? You're like, I'm seeing this. Look at how cool the light on
Speaker 5:  the mountains is. I can't show it to you because of copyright restrictions.
Speaker 5:  Weird. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I'm sorry for laughing. That is weird.
Speaker 5:  It's weird. It's weird to be like, oh, like Bob Iger has DRM
Speaker 5:  to my eyes, I don't like that
Speaker 6:  Very black mirror feeling. Yeah. Like I just keep thinking that the episode
Speaker 6:  where she like gets her her husband outta the way or boyfriend or whatever.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And it just feels like these, this headset's really equipped for that
Speaker 6:  but not in a pleasant way.
Speaker 5:  It's weird man. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 2:  Weird. Are there any like big picture use cases other than those two?
Speaker 2:  Those are the two people seem to mostly ask us about and also being have
Speaker 2:  been kind of imagining since this thing first launched. Is there anything
Speaker 2:  that like leaps out to you as equally big to those two things?
Speaker 5:  No. To be perfectly blunt, I mean I think the Mac thing is,
Speaker 5:  I want to see how people actually react to it. Yeah. Like it's cool and it
Speaker 5:  was really cool, but 25 60 by 1440 is not enough. Yep. Like my
Speaker 5:  16 inch practical pro is more a solution than that. Right. So it's cool to
Speaker 5:  have a big like editing and Lightroom huge is great, but then the sort of
Speaker 5:  reality of the resolution is actually you're gonna find yourself fighting
Speaker 5:  it. And then you know, TV is tv. Like some of that stuff is really cool.
Speaker 5:  But I was, again, I was watching the playoffs last night. There's no Fox
Speaker 5:  Sports app to scream in 4K and I was watching YouTube TV
Speaker 5:  seven 20 P Fox at huge stuff. It's like you
Speaker 5:  yeah, you
Speaker 2:  Fair.
Speaker 5:  There's a part of me and I'm just a shameless plug for the TV that I'm
Speaker 5:  convincing myself was not an extraordinarily splurged purchase. You
Speaker 5:  can go buy an is o lead for far less money and then you'll have a
Speaker 5:  really nice TV that you can take pictures of if you wanna share something.
Speaker 2:  But then Bob Iger will come to your house and
Speaker 5:  Throw, then Bob, he is like, look, I'm not busy enough. I need you to stop
Speaker 5:  doing that.
Speaker 6:  Just cuts the cord
Speaker 2:  Off. Alright, one more before we take a break and then we're gonna do some
Speaker 2:  listener questions. Then we're gonna get outta here. The Vision Pro. Is it
Speaker 2:  good?
Speaker 5:  The Vision Pro is the best version of this thing that anyone has ever made.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 2:  Which to to Apple's credit has basically been what it has been
Speaker 2:  saying about this all along. Right? Like the answer to why is this thing
Speaker 2:  $3,500 is because it is the best one of these we can make.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Without question, it is the best version of this headset that anyone
Speaker 5:  has ever made. It is unquestionably still a VR headset. It is a
Speaker 5:  primary computing device. I do not think VR headsets are it. Maybe
Speaker 5:  this thing just proves that point to a lot of people. Right. It is weird
Speaker 5:  to be alone using a computer the way that this thing makes you alone. Hmm.
Speaker 5:  We haven't even talked about the front display. Right. The, you know, the
Speaker 5:  big thing about this that is supposed to make you not feel alone is the front
Speaker 5:  display showing your eyes to other people. Right? Well, you can't see 'em
Speaker 5:  most of the time they're sup. It's super dim and that glass is really reflective
Speaker 5:  and mostly people are like, am I supposed to be seeing something? And you're
Speaker 5:  like, it's my eyes. And they're like, ah.
Speaker 6:  I was like, is that actually maybe a good thing that you can't see it? Most
Speaker 6:  of the time
Speaker 5:  They don't look good. They look like they totally look like CGI. It's a super
Speaker 5:  low re display in there. Like I, I've seen the part, you know, in a briefing
Speaker 5:  it's, you can just like, it's just a grid of pixels, like a sports stadium
Speaker 5:  screen or something. Or the sphere. God bless the sphere.
Speaker 5:  Here's a question. Would you rather live in the vision pro or live in the
Speaker 5:  sphere? And the answer is the sphere.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Sphere's a little more expensive but you know, it's okay,
Speaker 5:  But it's really dim. You can't really see the eyes. You're never making anything
Speaker 5:  that actually looks like eye contact. Like it just, that's not happening.
Speaker 5:  So it's like you're just alone in there and like the stuff that I think is
Speaker 5:  really cool, like yesterday I was walking around the, the cafe of our office,
Speaker 5:  which is huge and I just had windows all over the place in there, just
Speaker 5:  windows for days just like over tables floating in space. And I was just
Speaker 5:  walking around looking at stuff and I was like, this rules.
Speaker 5:  And no one else could experience that with me. Like other people just saw
Speaker 5:  me looking around, pointing it up.
Speaker 5:  I just think there's something lonely about that. Like really
Speaker 5:  intensely lonely and I would rather not have that
Speaker 5:  experience. And So I think VR is great. I like, I'm a VR headset user. I
Speaker 5:  love playing Grand. My own vr, I love Supernatural. Like there's single use
Speaker 5:  applications, mostly gaming that make a lot of sense to like
Speaker 5:  have a focused lonely experience for using an iPad. don
Speaker 5:  don't know, I like half the time I'm like, look at this on my screen to someone
Speaker 5:  else. And that is really hard to do. Yeah. So I. It is the best version of
Speaker 5:  this that has ever been made. But I went through and looked at every Tim
Speaker 5:  Cook quote about VR and AR for the past decade and his complaint
Speaker 5:  about it always has been VR is isolating and like I'm here at
Speaker 5:  the end with holding the thing and I'm like, yep, VR is pretty isolating.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean that the, the like, big question I think we're gonna
Speaker 2:  spend a lot of time talking about and covering over the next few years really
Speaker 2:  is, is the vision pro like the end of that arc
Speaker 2:  in which we realize that's not where we're headed? Or is it sort of overlapping
Speaker 2:  the end of that arc, but it is actually the beginning of the next thing.
Speaker 2:  And I think Apple wants you to believe it's the beginning of the next thing,
Speaker 2:  but what it built looks more like the end of the VR arc and So
Speaker 2:  I think, which it turns out to be is gonna be really interesting over time.
Speaker 5:  We can end here. There's a real danger reviewing a first generation Apple
Speaker 5:  product.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Yep.
Speaker 5:  I I feel it. Right? Like nobody looks back on a first generation like
Speaker 5:  Quest review and is like they got it wrong. Like a first generation Apple
Speaker 5:  product. Especially when you're in a tiny group of reviewers. People look
Speaker 5:  back on it and they're like, you got it wrong. And I know this is a risk
Speaker 5:  to say, but I'm gonna say this, this feels like it will convince a lot of
Speaker 5:  people that some of these technologies are dead ends. Mm. Right. Like you,
Speaker 5:  if you, you can try as hard as you want. You can be one of the richest companies
Speaker 5:  in the world. You can put all of that capability in and there's a lot of
Speaker 5:  this thing that feels like Apple made it because only Apple can make it.
Speaker 5:  Right. Like the Giant's just looking for a fight and found one
Speaker 5:  great. I think that's so cool. Like I, I have no qualms with that. Go
Speaker 5:  get it. But that means if you look at this device, you're like, oh, pass
Speaker 5:  through VR does not actually substitute for the goal, which is optical
Speaker 5:  ar where you're just looking through a pair of glasses and the computer's
Speaker 5:  putting stuff over reality. Like that's the goal. You gotta get there. And
Speaker 5:  this thing, there's no, there's no path from here to there. And I don don't
Speaker 5:  know, like that's my big take from this thing is like, it feels like Apple
Speaker 5:  needed to build a simulator of the computing experiences it wanted to build.
Speaker 5:  And if it talked about it that way, I might be a little, a little more charitable,
Speaker 5:  but they're like show their ad is like people are just like doing laundry
Speaker 5:  in it. It's like, no that this, this is not that thing.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Alright. Well by the time you're hearing this, Eli's review is live.
Speaker 2:  The video's live. Go watch it. Go read it. We're gonna take a break and then
Speaker 2:  we're gonna come back and we're gonna do five minutes of quick questions.
Speaker 2:  Then we're gonna get outta here. Be
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. So. I have a big list of questions thanks to everybody
Speaker 2:  who called and emailed and posted with questions. We've answered a bunch
Speaker 2:  of them already, which is great. So we're just gonna blow through a bunch
Speaker 2:  of the ones we didn't do already. The first one is a hotline question from
Speaker 2:  Joe.
Speaker 13:  Hi, my name's Joe and about the Apple Vision Pro.
Speaker 13:  What does the thing smell like while you're wearing it?
Speaker 2:  Nila, we got this question so many times I cannot tell you. How does it smell?
Speaker 2:  I need to know.
Speaker 5:  I don't know why people ask me this question. Here's my solution. AirPods
Speaker 5:  Max outta the box had a smell because they were like manufactured in
Speaker 5:  China and then shipped over here and like they, whatever particular process
Speaker 5:  on the fabric I think has a smell. So there's like a tiny whiff of that smell
Speaker 5:  immediately went away. Will they smell after you sweat in them for a while,
Speaker 5:  don? Don't dunno yet. Okay. Dunno. Yet. I do know I had a little Z
Speaker 5:  in my face with a video review and I wore a little bit of concealer and it
Speaker 5:  got on the headband and I asked Joanne about this and she's like, that's
Speaker 5:  covered in my review too. Interesting. But here's a big question. Do you
Speaker 5:  wanna wear a computer that messes up your hair every time? Use it wrong.
Speaker 5:  No. Do you wanna wear a computer that messes up your makeup every time you
Speaker 5:  use it? Is it a different bigger question? Ooh and that
Speaker 5:  stuff might smell, you know? Yes. Like once you cake this thing full
Speaker 5:  of sweat and makeup Ooh.
Speaker 2:  Okay. All right. That's a good one. Next, a question from Matt and we talked
Speaker 2:  about this a little bit but I I, and it seems like the answer so far is we'll
Speaker 2:  see, but he asks, is there any gaming use case beyond playing on a virtual
Speaker 2:  screen with an Xcl controller that it seems like you can just do now, right?
Speaker 2:  Like you can play games kind of from a Mac or in theory from Game Pass
Speaker 2:  through Safari or whatever, but have you, is there any other gaming stuff
Speaker 2:  you've seen seen that sparks something in you?
Speaker 5:  No, I mean the, the games are all like iPad games in three DI played we to
Speaker 5:  golf, which is really fun. Nice. But it's still like it's in 3D, right? Those
Speaker 5:  are, it's a 3D game inherently you're just looking at on 2D thing. And so
Speaker 5:  like they just built it so it's virtual and you like pull back and let go.
Speaker 5:  There's nothing like NFL Pro era or like any of these big VR
Speaker 5:  games. They are to come. I'm told they are to come, but nothing yet.
Speaker 2:  And that's actually a good segue to another question that we got from Kyle
Speaker 2:  who says, I wanna know what iPad ports are like and if there's any jankis
Speaker 2:  with them both in how they work and the general UI basically like apps that
Speaker 2:  are just iPad apps that they check the checkbox to say put it on the Vision
Speaker 2:  Pro. What have you seen so far?
Speaker 5:  I think it is very telling that Apple shipped a bunch of its own apps as
Speaker 5:  iPad apps. Fascinating. iPad apps are designed for your fingers. And so
Speaker 5:  the eye tracking is even more frustrating than iPad apps. Mm. 'cause all
Speaker 5:  the targets are even smaller. They work, they there's no, there's no not
Speaker 5:  working. Right. They they work but you will inha you will realize like, oh,
Speaker 5:  the same way that putting a mouse and keyboard experience on a touch screen
Speaker 5:  can be frustrating.
Speaker 2:  I was just gonna say like, have you ever attached a mouse or one of the keyboard
Speaker 2:  attachments on the iPad with the track pad? It's like it feels cool and also
Speaker 2:  like it was clearly not designed for that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And you can, you know, if you have a, they sent me a magic keyboard,
Speaker 5:  a magic track pad. I had those connected a lot. You can just like, that all
Speaker 5:  looks like iPad os it's all the same stuff. So yeah, they're totally usable.
Speaker 5:  There's no particular weirdness there except if you're using hand and
Speaker 5:  eye tracking you'll quickly discover that that apps are designed for
Speaker 5:  not that And sometimes that shows up. I think it's totally, it's like barely
Speaker 5:  criticism. Like it's just obvious what's happening.
Speaker 6:  It's better than like when all the iPhone apps came to iPad and it was very
Speaker 6:  clearly like just the iPhone app big.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah, that's a good comparison. It's
Speaker 5:  Way, way, way better than that. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Okay good. Alright, I have another hotline question. Another one. Believe
Speaker 2:  it or not that we got multiple times from Ray.
Speaker 14:  Hey this is Ray and this is a question about the Vision Pro. I wonder
Speaker 14:  what happens if you look in a mirror with the Vision Pro
Speaker 14:  on, would it phase you in like it does with other people or would it
Speaker 14:  recognize that you're wearing the Vision Pro and not do it? And what happens
Speaker 14:  if you turn on the fake eyes but it consider you a person that can fade
Speaker 14:  into thanks.
Speaker 5:  This is one of the first things I tried. Why do you think I was in the bathroom?
Speaker 5:  You look crazy. You you? Because I was like trying to see my own eyes, right?
Speaker 5:  So yeah, it does show you your own eyes, but I can't tell if it is because
Speaker 5:  it thinks you're another person or if it knows that you're looking at yourself,
Speaker 5:  which is like a weird Mm. Does a computer know I'm looking at myself is like,
Speaker 5:  that's another two hours. Yeah, we
Speaker 2:  Don't have time for that today.
Speaker 2:  but it it like nothing horrible happened. Like, you're still here. No, you
Speaker 2:  looked in the mirror, you're
Speaker 5:  Still here. I was like, man, these eyes kind of suck. Walked away.
Speaker 2:  Okay, cool. We got a question from Andy. Basically asking about
Speaker 2:  multiple user support questions about OS and software
Speaker 2:  adjustments for the hardware. Like is, is this a device you can
Speaker 2:  functionally share with other people?
Speaker 5:  No, absolutely not. The only affordance is something called guest
Speaker 5:  mode where you say put this in guest mode and
Speaker 5:  then it lets you limit what apps, whoever wears a headset can put can use
Speaker 5:  next. And then it lets you limit whatever apps whoever's running a headset
Speaker 5:  can use. And that's it. That's what you get. And then, and then you're supposed
Speaker 5:  to give it to someone else. They do a tiny little bit of setup just to align
Speaker 5:  the displays. They don't even do the hand tracking setup and that's it. And
Speaker 5:  then so they then it's like you can only use Safari and they give it back
Speaker 5:  to you and you log in and you're good to go. But there's no multiple user
Speaker 5:  accounts. Nothing. It's, it is this thing is an iPad. Okay. But the same
Speaker 5:  way that iPad doesn't have multiple user support, this doesn't have it.
Speaker 6:  Did that feel like it heightened that lonely experience for you?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, this is my computer. Like you give it to someone else here you can
Speaker 5:  just use my computer now. It's weird. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 5:  By the way, a particularly weird thing about that is, you know, there's optic
Speaker 5:  id so someone else should not be able to unlock your computer. But 'cause
Speaker 5:  again, because other people are using it for capture and all this stuff to
Speaker 5:  make our video, other people can just be my persona.
Speaker 5:  Like they can make FaceTime calls with my head. It's like, it's not at all
Speaker 5:  how it's designed, it's just the reality of how we are using it today, which
Speaker 5:  is
Speaker 2:  Wild. Yeah. Talk about the personas for a sec. 'cause that was something
Speaker 2:  we got a couple of questions about too. This idea that if I make a FaceTime
Speaker 2:  call or I go on Google meet or whatever wearing this, that it's not
Speaker 2:  showing a camera version of me, it's showing like my
Speaker 2:  avatar. Yeah. What's the verdict on personas?
Speaker 5:  I will say what Marque said when we did our FaceTime call for the video.
Speaker 5:  This is very impressive And also bad. They're bad. They're in
Speaker 5:  like if I showed up in a meeting with a persona, I, I personally feel like
Speaker 5:  that would be insulting. So the persona just replaces the front facing camera.
Speaker 5:  Right? That's how you should think about it. Apps don't know it's happening.
Speaker 5:  They don't see it. They call for the front camera and they get
Speaker 5:  your persona.
Speaker 2:  Oh, so the Vision Pro just reports to whatever app you're doing? Yeah. This
Speaker 2:  is what the webcam is
Speaker 5:  Seeing. This is what the webcam is seeing. Oh. Which is fascinating. A great
Speaker 5:  hack. Like brilliant, right? Yeah. And then you know, you do the scan and
Speaker 5:  see your face, they look like PS three characters. Like we, I was talking
Speaker 5:  to Marquez and and Joanna on that call and I was like, Marquez, this looks
Speaker 5:  like you're about to give me an item that will help me fight the boss. Like
Speaker 5:  that's how it looks, you know, like Welcome To my store. Like in any
Speaker 5:  game that you might play, they're ba they're uncanny. It's weird that they
Speaker 5:  have decided that everyone has the same tongue. Like You don't scan your
Speaker 5:  tongue, but you stick your tongue out. You have a tongue weird. Just weird.
Speaker 5:  Like someone at Apple is like do a tongue model. We'll just use it for everybody.
Speaker 5:  Do a tongue, like someone had that job, right?
Speaker 6:  Just the Gene Simmons tongue for everyone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's like you can't get different tongues. You, you're always wearing
Speaker 5:  the same clothes. It looks like you've just had the worst Botox ever.
Speaker 5:  Like I took a call with our creative director, will Joel to look at some
Speaker 5:  design stuff and he is like, I'm so used to looking at your face on these
Speaker 5:  calls because you're looking at something and you know, like your face
Speaker 5:  portrays more than you ever seen. And he is like, it's just, I can't, this
Speaker 5:  is, I, this is not useful for me. So yeah, I Apple, it's in beta.
Speaker 5:  There's a reason it's in beta. There's a reason they haven't shown it to
Speaker 5:  anyone. Like it's not good. Yeah. Like there's a long way to go. Well
Speaker 5:  and it's like, you know for, I keep saying it has to be 50% better. I can
Speaker 5:  see how this can get 50% better. It's very offense.
Speaker 2:  Okay, fair enough. Alright, two more then. We'll then we're outta here from
Speaker 2:  Jesse. What is it like looking at real world displays through pass through
Speaker 2:  TVs, PCs, phones, smartwatches, et cetera?
Speaker 5:  Fine, but blurry. Okay. Yeah, that it fine, but blurry. Fair enough. Like
Speaker 5:  I, I can just use my phone, but it's blurry.
Speaker 2:  And last one from our Raj who asks, is the digital crown
Speaker 2:  really useful to gradually transition between VR and ar? I don't see any
Speaker 2:  point where a person has to be in between the two modes. They could have
Speaker 2:  just switched back and forth.
Speaker 5:  So using it, you'll quickly discover there's a lot of times you wanna be
Speaker 5:  in between the two modes because if you put windows out in space and they're
Speaker 5:  like going through walls or things, it screws their
Speaker 5:  brain. So you're like, here's a portal into depth.
Speaker 5:  Like here's a portal into a big desert landscape. And so instead of
Speaker 5:  walls in front of me, there's like depth and now I can put windows into that
Speaker 5:  depth while I still have the room around me and I can look around. So
Speaker 5:  that is very useful. It is an inherent right? It is a big compromise
Speaker 5:  over like, should this be ar right? That's like I'm creating a virtual environment
Speaker 5:  to solve the problem of AR in this moment. And then you want to, you know,
Speaker 5:  you have Fuller on the moon, but like that halfway setting you, I
Speaker 5:  ended up using a lot more just to create that depth for the os.
Speaker 2:  All right, NELI, you have to go. You have now 26
Speaker 2:  hours to change your mind about everything. Chop
Speaker 5:  Chop. Send more questions. We'll, we'll do more of these. I, I know people
Speaker 5:  are gonna have infinite questions.
Speaker 2:  Oh for sure. And we, yeah, we're gonna, we're gonna cover this a bunch. We'll
Speaker 2:  talk about it more on Friday show. We'll, we'll we have a lot to do and I
Speaker 2:  think especially as we start to see more apps, we're gonna talk a lot about
Speaker 2:  this. So Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I think we have a lot developers have to basically make this product work.
Speaker 2:  For sure. Yeah, so call the hotline. Eight six six version one one. Email
Speaker 2:  us Vergecast Verge dot com. We'll put Eli's review in the video in the show
Speaker 2:  notes. NELI and Alex. Thank you both. Thank
Speaker 5:  You. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Alright,
Speaker 2:  That is it for The Vergecast today. Thanks to NELI and Alex for being here.
Speaker 2:  Thanks to NELI for braving all of these days and his deep
Speaker 2:  vulnerable state and coming on and talking about the vision Pro. It's the
Speaker 2:  sacrifices we make everybody. Also, thanks to everybody who sent in questions
Speaker 2:  via the hotline or email or on Fred's, they were all great. And please, like
Speaker 2:  NELI said, keep them coming. We're gonna keep talking about this thing for
Speaker 2:  a while. We'll also put links to Eli's review and the video in the show notes.
Speaker 2:  But we are covering the Vision Pro in every way we can think of.
Speaker 2:  So keep it locked on The Verge dot com Lots coming this week. This show is
Speaker 2:  produced by Andrew Moreno, Liam James, and Will pour The. Vergecast is Verge
Speaker 2:  production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. NELI Alex. And I'll
Speaker 2:  be back on Friday to talk about new web browsers, much more vision,
Speaker 2:  pro stuff, and everything else happening in tech. We'll see you then. Rock
Speaker 2:  and roll.
Speaker 4:  When you surround yourself with the best tech, that's an instant level up.
Speaker 4:  So shouldn't you level up in every room of your house.