# Transcript
ID: c981ef2a-8f03-4631-9ee8-c9c7d8b8d692
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-101348595237699856/5548262620178074015/s93290-US-2929s-1709629215.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of region locked phones:
The Verge’s Allison Johnson and Jon Porter report back on all the tech we saw at Mobile World Congress this past week.
MWC 2024: all the phones, wearables, and gadgets announced in Barcelona
Peering through Lenovo’s transparent laptop into a sci-fi future
What if phones actually bent to our needs?
The Phone 2A makes a guest appearance at Nothing’s MWC event.
The Humane AI Pin worked better than I expected — until it didn’t
Samsung has big ambitions for the Galaxy Ring
A short gif of Infinix’s color-changing charging E Ink phone concept.
Now there’s a 28,000mAh battery with a phone in it
Xiaomi’s new Watch S3 has a bezel you can swap as easily as a strap.
Honor’s Magic 6 Pro launches internationally with AI-powered eye tracking on the way
HMD is making a Barbie flip phone alongside a smartphone for tinkerers
Later, David answers a question from the Vergecast Hotline about web crawlers and AI.
With the rise of AI, web crawlers are suddenly controversial
The Vergecast and Decoder are live at SXSW this weekend, March 8th and 9th. SXSW attendees can see both shows live on the official Vox Media Podcast Stage at the JW Marriott, presented by Atlassian. Learn more at voxmedia.com/live.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (8 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Region Locked Phones.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend David Pierce and I am standing outside of the Alamo Draft
Speaker 2:  house where I just saw Dune part two. Now I don't know if I'm like the expert
Speaker 2:  on whether Dune movies are any good. I saw part one just the other day
Speaker 2:  on an iPad, on a train. I haven't read the books. Love the first
Speaker 2:  movie. Loved the second movie. It's really long. It's really intense. It's
Speaker 2:  really loud. I had a great time. Everybody should go see it. Ideally on
Speaker 2:  the biggest screen you can possibly find, but Dune is not what we are here
Speaker 2:  to talk about on The Vergecast today. Today we're talking about Mobile World
Speaker 2:  Congress MWC is one of those trade shows that some years is
Speaker 2:  kind of boring. It's just a bunch of companies being like, look on Android
Speaker 2:  phone. And some years is really interesting. And this year was one of those
Speaker 2:  interesting years. So we are gonna have John Porter and Allison Johnson,
Speaker 2:  two Verge reporters who were at the show in Barcelona over the past week
Speaker 2:  and they're gonna tell us about all the interesting gadgets they saw and
Speaker 2:  maybe whether we got a hint of what The future of gadgets
Speaker 2:  really looks like. All that's coming up in just a sec, but first
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna go home and sleep for a bit because it's really late because that
Speaker 2:  is a three hour long movie. Then we'll get to it. This is The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast. See you in a sec.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. I got some sleep. I'm now deep in the dune
Speaker 2:  behind the scenes YouTube rabbit hole. I've learned a lot of fun facts about
Speaker 2:  Austin Butler's hair. Let's get into the show. So Mobile World
Speaker 2:  Congress is, I would say typically the second most interesting trade show
Speaker 2:  of the year, at least most years. CES is the big one in Las Vegas
Speaker 2:  for the whole electronics and tech industry. But MWC has for
Speaker 2:  years had kind of a special niche as a place that is all
Speaker 2:  about one thing and that one thing is obviously mobile. Often
Speaker 2:  that just means lots and lots of phones and this year it meant that too.
Speaker 2:  But the thing about mobile right now is that the definition of
Speaker 2:  that word is starting to change. So thanks to ai
Speaker 2:  we're getting new kinds of devices altogether and because Apple and
Speaker 2:  Google have so thoroughly dominated the smartphone era, there are lots
Speaker 2:  of companies that are looking to figure out what's next. Even in the smartphone
Speaker 2:  world, the idea that your phone should just be a slab of glass that
Speaker 2:  runs a bunch of apps that come from an app store that's run by either Apple
Speaker 2:  or Google, there are so many good reasons for companies and for people
Speaker 2:  frankly to try and get past that idea. And so not only are we getting lots
Speaker 2:  of new phones, we're getting lots of new ideas about what a phone or a
Speaker 2:  mobile device in general should look like and how it can work and what
Speaker 2:  it should mean in our lives. This is my kind of stuff to talk about so we're
Speaker 2:  gonna talk about it. The rgs, Allison Johnson and John Porter were both at
Speaker 2:  MWC last week. They played with all the devices and they tried to figure
Speaker 2:  out what they all say about The future of mobile and somewhat
Speaker 2:  miraculously they both made it home safe and not sick and they're here to
Speaker 2:  help me dig into all of it. Allison Johnson. Hello. Hello, John
Speaker 2:  Porter Welcome back to The Vergecast.
Speaker 6:  Hello.
Speaker 2:  So you guys survived. Yes. Tell us a little bit about what MWC is like. I
Speaker 2:  confess, it's been a bunch of years since I went and it's like in Barcelona.
Speaker 2:  So it seems very romantic and lovely in a way that like going to
Speaker 2:  Vegas for CES does not seem romantic and lovely. But like
Speaker 2:  give me the the 2024 vibe check of MWC this year.
Speaker 6:  So I read a lovely comment that referred to MWC as
Speaker 6:  a very nice overseas trip for this journalist And I, I read
Speaker 6:  that comment whilst sitting in a dingy hotel room with
Speaker 6:  a bathroom ceiling that was leaking at approximately
Speaker 6:  11:30 PM on a Saturday evening while I was just
Speaker 6:  writing my third embargo of the weekend. So I think that,
Speaker 6:  I think that kind of sums up maybe how glamorous, how glamorous MWC is,
Speaker 6:  but I mean like a lot of trade shows I think a lot of companies want to kind
Speaker 6:  of get out ahead of the show itself. So it means the weekend is
Speaker 6:  kind of filled with with these press events and you you kind of
Speaker 6:  end up kind of rushing from from one to the other to the other kinda
Speaker 6:  like barely keeping track of of what's happening because every single company's
Speaker 6:  just trying to jostle and not step on each other's toes too much but
Speaker 6:  maybe step on them a little bit and then the show kicks off on on Monday
Speaker 6:  in earnest and then it's just this frantic rush to to see the kind of the
Speaker 6:  smaller players that aren't able to hold a big press conference over the
Speaker 6:  course of the weekend and actually kind of get hands on time with with the
Speaker 6:  gadgets themselves.
Speaker 2:  Allison, what was your read? Was this your, this wasn't your first MWC was
Speaker 2:  it?
Speaker 7:  This was my first MWC. Oh it lived up to the hype I guess.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I was surprised by how busy, yeah the weekend was. It was
Speaker 7:  just like darting around Barcelona just to see different
Speaker 7:  stuff and just that added like difficulty level of like I don't
Speaker 7:  understand any of these street names but I'm gonna find this place where
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna look at a phone that bends. but it was great. It was, you can't
Speaker 7:  beat eating some meat and cheese in your hotel room at 1130
Speaker 7:  writing embargoes
Speaker 2:  Glamorous job we do. It really is, it really is. It did seem like
Speaker 2:  watching from afar not only kind of an unusually newsy show
Speaker 2:  but an unusually cool show in the sense that there was like
Speaker 2:  not just kind of the giant slew of all the phones that are kind of
Speaker 2:  the same as the other phones that MWC falls into every once in a while
Speaker 2:  where it's just like every company shows you their version of the same phone
Speaker 2:  that everybody else is making and there's 60,000 of them and that's MWC
Speaker 2:  this year it felt like there were some some big weird
Speaker 2:  swings in a way that I don't remember seeing in a while.
Speaker 2:  Is that, did it feel like that on the ground? Like was it cooler and more
Speaker 2:  exciting than, than maybe some of these we've had in recent years?
Speaker 7:  That was my impression. It was kind of a lot of running around to
Speaker 7:  see like weird little things like the Samsung Galaxy
Speaker 7:  ring was kind of out on display for the first time so we
Speaker 7:  got to go see that the Humane AI Pin was kind
Speaker 7:  of an unannounced guest appearance, so we got to see that
Speaker 7:  in action. I think the Deutsche Telecom booth, which
Speaker 7:  in the US is like T-Mobile, it's a very like T-Mobile
Speaker 7:  vibe of like everything was magenta, there were like blinking lights and
Speaker 7:  stadium seating and kind of like carnival ish. I was
Speaker 7:  like wow, this, this is really wild. So we
Speaker 7:  saw some cool stuff. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I made a list of kind of the coolest gadgets that I
Speaker 2:  read about you guys seeing and I just wanna sort of run down your experiences
Speaker 2:  with a bunch of them and it seems to me that If, you were gonna pick one
Speaker 2:  that was kind of like the, the star of the show that everybody was talking
Speaker 2:  about. It feels to me like it's Lenovo's transparent laptop.
Speaker 2:  Do you think that's right? Is that the right answer?
Speaker 6:  I love Lenovo's transparent laptop. I can't articulate what I would
Speaker 6:  ever use it for. It filled me with joy hearing
Speaker 6:  Lenovo themselves trying to articulate why you would, what you would use
Speaker 6:  it for. But then that feels like a kind of part of the process with unveiling
Speaker 6:  a concept laptop like that you show this thing off to the world and a bunch
Speaker 6:  of people see it and a lot of people go, I don't know really what this
Speaker 6:  achieves, but then maybe like one person right in the back raises their hand
Speaker 6:  and goes like, what about and then you can take it back to your lab and kind
Speaker 6:  of like optimize it for that kind of like idea that that that just came up.
Speaker 6:  I will say Lenovo's big idea for this laptop, which If you haven't seen Firstly
Speaker 6:  go see it, it's a transparent micro LED display gets as bright as like
Speaker 6:  a thousand nets but it doesn't have a kind of a contrast layer. So that thing
Speaker 6:  is just transparent in a way that you can't control
Speaker 6:  when all the pixels are lit up, like when it's bright white. So If you say
Speaker 6:  had like a notepad open or something you can't see through that. But
Speaker 6:  kind of other than making the whole screen white, you kind of don't have,
Speaker 6:  don't have control over this thing.
Speaker 2:  So it doesn't have like the, there's that LG TV at CES that could sort of
Speaker 2:  roll up the thing behind it so that it would have something to, to contrast
Speaker 2:  against. This doesn't have that. It is just see through all the way,
Speaker 6:  It doesn't have that. A thing Lenovo told me when I asked was like, oh yeah,
Speaker 6:  we'll definitely try and include something like that if we this were ever
Speaker 6:  to make it to to production. But their idea for why you might want
Speaker 6:  this was they kind of had this artistic
Speaker 6:  idea for it that, oh, maybe you are an artist and you're sitting there and
Speaker 6:  you're sketching and you can see things behind it. So maybe you,
Speaker 6:  you put some sunflowers behind, behind the screen and then your
Speaker 6:  then, which then brings me onto the, the lower half of the tablet, which
Speaker 6:  is this kind of drawing tablet where when you bring a sty close to it,
Speaker 6:  the keyboard, the illuminated keyboard disappears and suddenly it's kind
Speaker 6:  of like a, a wack on surface type thing and then you can kind of sketch what's
Speaker 6:  behind the laptop, which I think would make sense if this thing
Speaker 6:  was the size of a TV like Lenovos thing. But when you're talking about I,
Speaker 6:  I forget exactly how big the screen is, I think it's maybe like 14, 15 inches.
Speaker 6:  You can just look around it. Like I, I don't know anyone out there that's
Speaker 6:  like hard oh are the unknowable joys of
Speaker 6:  what could be behind my laptop.
Speaker 6:  So Mike, my theory for who would buy this
Speaker 6:  thing if it did ever make it into production and like to be clear, they're
Speaker 6:  not making any promises about being into production. They were kind of confident
Speaker 6:  that the technology would maybe appear in a future product. But my guess
Speaker 6:  would be that this would be a thing for kind of really high end
Speaker 6:  front desks in like banks to buy and like the kind of place you, you
Speaker 6:  walk into and maybe nowadays they have an iMac 'cause they want, 'cause they
Speaker 6:  wanna project that air of high tech sophistication and maybe in The future
Speaker 6:  they go, Hey, check it out. We all look like we're minority report. Don't
Speaker 6:  you want to, you know, spend a bunch of money at at at this business? 'cause
Speaker 6:  it's a real, it's like a, it's a showy thing but I don't know
Speaker 6:  like where the practical element of of this thing
Speaker 6:  comes in. But I hope that, like I hope it starts the conversation the way
Speaker 6:  they hoped. And I hope that someone at the back is kind of now
Speaker 6:  thinking Ooh actually I have this perfect use case for, for a transparent
Speaker 6:  laptop display. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I I appreciate that. With the whole transparent display
Speaker 2:  technology happening right now, nobody knows what to do with it except to
Speaker 2:  put it in fancy waiting rooms, which is so funny there and it's like there
Speaker 2:  the LGTV they were like, it could be, it could be a virtual fish tank at
Speaker 2:  your dentist's office and it's like, all right, like sure I'm down, let's
Speaker 2:  do it. I have, I have no issue with that. I also will never ever buy one
Speaker 2:  for my house. But I, I'm just honestly glad that
Speaker 2:  anyone is doing weird laptops. The world is better when there are weird
Speaker 2:  laptops and I appreciate Lenovo for not just making ThinkPads
Speaker 2:  but for also making weird laptops.
Speaker 6:  We should also point out that they're very sensible business laptops are
Speaker 6:  probably actually the more impactful announcement from the show. 'cause they,
Speaker 6:  they've kind of done a bunch of work with I Fixit to kind of make these things
Speaker 6:  more repairable. So I went through this cool demonstration with a couple
Speaker 6:  of I fixit guys who were kinda like pointing out all the kind of like the
Speaker 6:  little things they've done. So I think for starters, loads of components
Speaker 6:  can be removed with just a Phillips head screw and then they've got little
Speaker 6:  ly icons kind printed into the shay to kind of go, okay, If, you wanted to
Speaker 6:  remove the battery, you want remove these three screws
Speaker 6:  and then they've got little QR codes in there that you can scan and it takes
Speaker 6:  you to a page on Lenovo's website where it shows you a what part you need
Speaker 6:  and BA little like video showing you how to, how to replace this thing. And
Speaker 6:  like that's, it's like the transparent laptop kind of gets you in
Speaker 6:  Lenovo's door and then when they're there they're like, okay, but this is
Speaker 6:  the less lesson attention grabby Sure thing that's actually
Speaker 6:  gonna have like a, a huge impact on like the thousands and
Speaker 6:  thousands of businesses that buy those ThinkPad laptops.
Speaker 2:  No, I, I remember years ago somebody, I think it was at Lenovo told
Speaker 2:  me that they make really cool colored laptops to
Speaker 2:  bring you over to the shelf so that you'll buy their black laptop. And I,
Speaker 2:  I have thought about that ever since that they're like, everybody loves this
Speaker 2:  like rad orange thing that we made and absolutely nobody buys it
Speaker 2:  but it is literally marketing for our other colors and it's just like, you
Speaker 2:  know what? If that's what we do with this new stuff, I can live with that
Speaker 2:  for a while. Yeah, Allison speaking of truly insane things that will probably
Speaker 2:  never come to a real product but I love to pieces. Anyway, you saw a thing
Speaker 2:  that I believe you have named Bendy the bendy phone.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, bendy phone.
Speaker 2:  Tell us about this.
Speaker 7:  It's a phone that bends. No, this was a, a similar
Speaker 7:  thing. Motorola, you know, owned by Lenovo. Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah, we're just doing a whole Lenovo thing here. I didn't even mean to do
Speaker 2:  that. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Okay. Yeah that's, that's always saw the show was Motorola
Speaker 2:  Phones
Speaker 7:  Apparently. No they have this con it's a concept phone so similar,
Speaker 7:  they're just kind of like, we're trying this out, it's just to see if we
Speaker 7:  can do it. They showed it off I think late last year or earlier this
Speaker 7:  year. But it's a actual phone. Like they showed me it
Speaker 7:  runs apps and all that stuff, but it just
Speaker 7:  bends backwards. You sort of get to that point of like, okay,
Speaker 7:  so why and the, the couple things they had worked out
Speaker 7:  was like there was a little metal bracelet you could put on and then it would,
Speaker 7:  the case that the, that bendy phone was in would just kind of
Speaker 7:  clamp onto it and then you have this like massive chunky
Speaker 7:  bracelet or watch on your arm and it's like, okay,
Speaker 2:  Probably not though. Yeah
Speaker 7:  I don't think I'm gonna wear that but like, okay that's a thing you can do.
Speaker 7:  And then, and it and it sort of like, it doesn't just kind of bendy one
Speaker 7:  way you can sort of like curve the top part of the screen a
Speaker 7:  little more and they had it so it would kind of run
Speaker 7:  a little launcher on like half of the screen just pretty much
Speaker 7:  the way the flip razor phones like cover screen
Speaker 7:  works so you get like little widgets and you can run
Speaker 7:  a full app If you want but it's weird. Yeah it would just, just kind of a
Speaker 7:  fun like you see it and you're like, oh I don't, I don't know what is this.
Speaker 7:  But then I've come around to like, it's a gadget. Like this is fun.
Speaker 7:  Why? Why shouldn't we have fun?
Speaker 2:  I totally agree. And then I think all the way on the other end of the like
Speaker 2:  is this a thing spectrum? You also saw the Galaxy ring which you mentioned,
Speaker 2:  which I'm totally fascinated by. I am desperate to become a smart ring
Speaker 2:  person but yeah the only one I have is the aura and it's just like a little
Speaker 2:  big and I notice it too much on my hand and I don't love it but I'm
Speaker 2:  very excited about the Galaxy ring and you got to try it, which we had not
Speaker 2:  before. How did it go? What'd you make of it?
Speaker 7:  So as a disclaimer, I do not have an aura ring. I'm not super
Speaker 7:  familiar with the category, but I was allowed to put the Galaxy ring on.
Speaker 7:  It's surprisingly light, like the pictures of it, it looks kind of
Speaker 7:  dense and you think, you know, there's like a battery and a bunch of
Speaker 7:  sensors in there. It might be kind of heavy but it, it wasn't, it
Speaker 7:  has kind of like this concave shape on the outside
Speaker 7:  so it sort of like takes up less space on your finger
Speaker 7:  than you think it's going to. And just the, the overall concept is
Speaker 7:  like, you know, not everybody wants a smartwatch or
Speaker 7:  can really wear awar smartwatch. Maybe you don't want like
Speaker 7:  notifications buzzing on your arm all day but you want some kind of fitness
Speaker 7:  tracking or wellness tracking kind of deal And that's where
Speaker 7:  this will come in and I think that's a pretty compelling pitch.
Speaker 2:  I agree. John, are you a smart ring guy?
Speaker 6:  I'm not a smart ring guy. I okay. So I wasn't able to actually hold the ring
Speaker 6:  but I did peer it through a perspec box at Samsung's booth and that thing
Speaker 6:  looks so slim and spelt so I'm really tempted by it.
Speaker 6:  But I'm also kind of really in the Garmin like
Speaker 6:  health tracking ecosystem. And so the thing I
Speaker 6:  want out of Smart Rings at the moment is basically for them to kind of be
Speaker 6:  a little bit more commoditized and kind of work across different ecosystems.
Speaker 6:  I believe there's, there's one quote that kind of suggested that maybe the
Speaker 6:  Galaxy ring would work exclusively with with Android phones to start and
Speaker 6:  that they're kind of hoping to to support iPhones down the line.
Speaker 6:  And that feels like that could be the tricky thing to get
Speaker 6:  over in initially. That if this thing is gonna be a hey you're like you're
Speaker 6:  in Samsung's ecosystem or you're in the Android ecosystem, it works with
Speaker 6:  all that stuff but there's a, there's a wall between that and then kind of
Speaker 6:  like the broader wearables market. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That that is very fair. Speaking of wearables actually I think there were
Speaker 2:  two kind of big name watches that dropped at the show, right? Was it the
Speaker 2:  Xiaomi one and the OnePlus watch? Were there any other big watches that people
Speaker 2:  were talking about? I I just saw those two.
Speaker 7:  I think that was it. The Xiaomi is super cool 'cause you can take
Speaker 7:  the bezel off and like they have different ones you can interchange it
Speaker 7:  with
Speaker 2:  Like instead of just changing your your strap out to make it look different,
Speaker 2:  you can actually change the bezel. Like that's cool, I'm into that. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Like hypothetically maybe you got a Garmin watch as a gift and it's in this
Speaker 6:  kind of fetching turquoise color and then you can change the strap but you
Speaker 6:  can't change the bezel around the screen so it'll never quite look right.
Speaker 6:  So you're just kind of stuck with turquoise hypothetically if you're in
Speaker 6:  that situation. Yeah, the Xiaomi watch S3 could be
Speaker 6:  exactly exactly what you need. So Xiaomi actually had two watches. They had
Speaker 6:  the the watch S3 which is their kind of like lower end watch and then they
Speaker 6:  had the Xmi watch two, which is their kind of slightly
Speaker 6:  higher end wear os watch. We didn't really get like get too much of a chance
Speaker 6:  to to play around with those. But certainly from like an industrial design
Speaker 6:  perspective they look, they look pretty cool like a lot of Xiaomi stuff really
Speaker 6:  the, I think Allison got a chance to try out the, the Xmi 14 and
Speaker 6:  just, there's a very nice looking phone.
Speaker 7:  It is,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Tell me about it. Allison
Speaker 7:  Yeah into the straight edge phones these days and the
Speaker 7:  Xiaomi 14 has embraced, you know they're on the right side of history with
Speaker 7:  the no curves, the straight edges. No it's just very
Speaker 7:  nice. And we got to see the 14 Ultra,
Speaker 7:  that's the one with the like one inch camera sensor
Speaker 7:  and all the stuff and the vegan leather back, which I also
Speaker 7:  like.
Speaker 2:  That's the one that has the round camera bump, right? Yes. I love a round
Speaker 2:  camera bump.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, yeah, it's like we're not trying to hide this thing. It is right here.
Speaker 7:  This is, this is a camera with a phone attached basically.
Speaker 7:  So I've used the, the jam 14 a little bit but 14
Speaker 7:  Ultra wasn't quite available yet to us and I really wanna
Speaker 7:  get my hands on that one.
Speaker 2:  It looks, it looks awesome. You have a, you have a pull quote in the story
Speaker 2:  you wrote about it that just says I witnessed the aperture moving.
Speaker 2:  Which is such a like ominous thing to say but it's also like it, it means
Speaker 2:  it's a camera. That's so
Speaker 7:  Exciting. Yeah. Yeah that's their thing this year is that it has a variable
Speaker 7:  aperture that actually like every smartphone camera basically has a
Speaker 7:  fixed aperture. This one the aperture can get bigger and
Speaker 7:  smaller just like a dedicated camera lens. Is that a good
Speaker 7:  idea? I don't know like I don't think it's actually that
Speaker 7:  practical, I kind of put it in the category of like Sony
Speaker 7:  Xperia phones that had like a actual continuous
Speaker 7:  zoom between two focal lengths and it was like very
Speaker 7:  small and you're like, I don't know quite what the point of this is
Speaker 7:  but you did it. It works.
Speaker 2:  You did do it. You can't argue with that. I
Speaker 7:  Did
Speaker 2:  John, you get to see nothing's new phone right? At what seemed like
Speaker 2:  one of the more bizarre showings of any kind of gadget
Speaker 2:  that we had at MWC this year. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  This phone is ostensibly being launched on March the fifth,
Speaker 6:  but nothing is at the point in its hype cycle where it is just posting full
Speaker 6:  on unboxings on its YouTube channel. Right.
Speaker 6:  And we kind of, we know the processor to media tech identity 7,200
Speaker 6:  pro I think. And then we kind of went along to this event in the
Speaker 6:  evening. So of course nothing like the MWC show floor is so
Speaker 6:  stuffy. It's just that's for like Deutsche Telecom and
Speaker 6:  Qualcomm, you know, nothing doesn't play by their rules. So nothing instead
Speaker 6:  has has this kind of like evening event where we show up and like
Speaker 6:  everyone, everyone's kinda like milling around and there were just these
Speaker 6:  like 2001 style monoliths just kind of like
Speaker 6:  dotted around and I just like catch Allison's eye and and I'm like, I'm betting
Speaker 6:  you, there's a phone two A behind inside that monolith. So we
Speaker 6:  just kind of spend the rest of the evening just like standing by one of these
Speaker 6:  things and of course then nothing stand up on stage and they go, oh you know,
Speaker 6:  thank thanks much for coming everyone this is our, this is gonna be our third
Speaker 6:  smartphone. We we're so, we're so excited to reveal it to the world and and
Speaker 6:  then suddenly like all of these monoliths that the, the sheath gets
Speaker 6:  taken off and it's, oh look, it's a Perspex box where a nothing phone two
Speaker 6:  A in it and oh there it's the flashing gif. Oh so we
Speaker 6:  got, we, okay. I don't know like how much inside baseball you want here
Speaker 6:  David. Very
Speaker 2:  Keep going.
Speaker 6:  Okay cool. So Alice and I game planned this. We were like, we're gonna
Speaker 6:  stand by where we think The Phone is gonna be revealed. I will have my camera,
Speaker 6:  you will have your iPhone 15. I will snap the photo as quickly
Speaker 6:  as I can and I will hand you the SD card. You will quickly put the
Speaker 6:  SD card into your like USB C adapter, put that on The Phone, get
Speaker 6:  that uploaded on The Verge and then like rather than like tweeting it or
Speaker 6:  putting it on on threads or whatever, we'll like have the images on The Verge
Speaker 6:  super quickly. And then of course just way over-engineered
Speaker 6:  this entire situation.
Speaker 7:  It all fell apart. It's
Speaker 6:  So quickly and the iPhone sucked up the
Speaker 6:  raw file. Well first off, like Alison opens up my SD card and is like, why
Speaker 6:  do you have so many pictures of keyboards in here John? And you have to scroll
Speaker 6:  through
Speaker 7:  It was 1000 pictures of keyboards. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And then right at the bottom we had the nothing phone two A shots and then
Speaker 6:  she kind of copies them over, then we upload them into our, our CMS
Speaker 6:  chorus.
Speaker 7:  I had to log back into chorus, it logged me out of course.
Speaker 6:  And then chorus is like, we can't, we can't take a raw file. We're sorry.
Speaker 6:  And so just the whole, it was not nearly as quick or seamless. Yeah
Speaker 7:  This was in the category of you know, luxurious trip
Speaker 7:  to overseas countries where I'm like literally standing under a plant.
Speaker 7:  Like there was a big plant like right. And I had my laptop out at this
Speaker 7:  fancy restaurant and I'm like opening, I mean camera raw like trying
Speaker 7:  to retouch some photos and upload them with chorus and I'm like,
Speaker 7:  this is, I just don't know how to explain this to any normal person.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Waiters and waitresses kept on coming by and like leaning 'cause we
Speaker 6:  were on the kind of make D table and they were trying to get like
Speaker 6:  cutlery out of this. And then of course friend of The Verge Sam Byford just
Speaker 6:  like shows us his phone is just like, should've just taken on your smartphone.
Speaker 6:  Smartphone cameras are real good.
Speaker 7:  He was just watching us like not saying I told you so, but it was like
Speaker 7:  all over his face.
Speaker 2:  If you're listening to this and you're wondering If, you should get into
Speaker 2:  tech journalism. The answer's yes, but also that is what all of your days
Speaker 2:  will look like. It just is what it is.
Speaker 8:  Alright,
Speaker 2:  We're gonna take a quick break and then more MWC talk. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we're back with Allison and John. So the, the last thing I had on
Speaker 2:  my like cool things you guys saw list is also kind of the
Speaker 2:  big picture thing that I feel like was happening at MWC, which is basically
Speaker 2:  what is a phone if it's not just a collection of apps that Google
Speaker 2:  or Apple runs. And John you wrote about this going in as kind of
Speaker 2:  what you were thinking about entering into the show and I think it really
Speaker 2:  proved out right that the idea is what is sort of the post
Speaker 2:  app smartphone look like and Allison you got a demo I think of
Speaker 2:  an a phone or an app or I don't even know what to call it, from a company
Speaker 2:  called Brain AI that is doing something along these lines, right?
Speaker 2:  I still, I have trouble explaining what this thing is to people, but you've
Speaker 2:  now seen it. Can you explain what this thing is?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, so they're kind of billing it as an
Speaker 7:  aless phone and the spoiler alert is that it The Phone
Speaker 7:  has apps, it's like a regular phone, but this company Brain AI is
Speaker 7:  launching it. We're planning to launch it with Deutsche Telecom, AKA
Speaker 7:  T-Mobile. And it's, right now what it is is this sort of
Speaker 7:  like you have the normal OS and then there's this like almost like digital
Speaker 7:  assistant where you can launch a page and it's, it
Speaker 7:  looks a little bit like a chat GPT kind of text box where you're like, tell
Speaker 7:  me about this. But the idea is you, you ask for things, you wanna
Speaker 7:  book a flight, you wanna look for a gift or something, you
Speaker 7:  kind of type it in and it starts building this interface around whatever
Speaker 7:  you're asking for. So you're not going directly into like
Speaker 7:  a travel booking app, you just sort of like ask it to
Speaker 7:  become a travel booking app and it builds it around you.
Speaker 2:  But instead of just doing text for everything, it'll actually try and like
Speaker 2:  redo the interface for whatever you're trying to do. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  They say they've trained this AI on
Speaker 7:  interfaces. It's not like a large language model.
Speaker 7:  It's sort of like here's how you present information so
Speaker 7:  someone can do something with it. And then I think the really cool part
Speaker 7:  is like you ask for something like the demo they gave me was like, show me
Speaker 7:  a ideas for a gift for my girlfriend who likes tennis. And you
Speaker 7:  get, you know, kind of a page of results and you're scrolling through and
Speaker 7:  you can stop at something and kind of tap on it and ask for,
Speaker 7:  you know, a question. You can ask a question about it, you can say, show
Speaker 7:  me a video of this thing. And it did like, it answered the question
Speaker 7:  correctly about how fast it could shoot the tennis balls. It was a
Speaker 7:  tennis ball machine or like a little YouTube video module
Speaker 7:  kind of pop up under it. So it all just kind of
Speaker 7:  happens in the sa like kind of fluidly in the same
Speaker 7:  space. You're not going, I wanna watch a video of this, I'm gonna jump
Speaker 7:  over to a different app, I'm gonna type in some text. Which is a really
Speaker 7:  compelling way to think of like, yeah, maybe our
Speaker 7:  phones don't have to be these, you know, boxes with
Speaker 7:  drawers in them where you're constantly, you know, drilling down to the thing
Speaker 7:  you want. There's so much that's unproven about this right now.
Speaker 7:  It's very focused on like shopping, which is, I think
Speaker 7:  AI companies love the idea that we just always wanna book flights, you
Speaker 7:  know, from San Francisco to Maui or whatever. I'm sorry, like I want
Speaker 7:  help with my email. Like what about productivity and all those things. And
Speaker 7:  Jerry, you the, the founder of the company is like, that is coming, that's
Speaker 7:  kind of the next step. But yeah, and they, they don't have a launch date.
Speaker 7:  They are targeting Europe and the US but they couldn't give
Speaker 7:  like a, a definitive timeframe. But I'm super interested in it.
Speaker 2:  It's a neat idea. Yeah. John, what did you see, I know you came in kind of
Speaker 2:  looking at this question of like, what's next after app stores.
Speaker 2:  Do you see anything that piqued your interest?
Speaker 6:  I will say no. I think I saw, I saw a much more
Speaker 6:  traditional show than I think I was,
Speaker 6:  I was expecting, but also I think my kind of, my takeaway for a lot
Speaker 6:  of the stuff we saw was for me, I I kind of, I ended up kind of comparing
Speaker 6:  and contrasting the Humane ai Pin with the rabbit R one
Speaker 6:  from CES, the, the rabbit R one, like wasn't wasn't present NWC, but I think
Speaker 6:  that so much of introducing a new product
Speaker 6:  category is talking about a potential rather than what exactly it can
Speaker 6:  do. And I think when talking about potential, it's very easy to kind of get
Speaker 6:  very philosophical and very naval gey in a way that kind of puts people off,
Speaker 6:  which I think is the direction that Humane has kind of gone in. And then
Speaker 6:  if everyone's kinda actually seen the Pin kind of goes, oh this is, this
Speaker 6:  is a gadget, this is a gadget, gadgety gadget that like does a bunch of gadget
Speaker 6:  stuff and that's, and that's cool, but it's kind of been wrapped up in this,
Speaker 6:  in this very philosophical idea of, oh we, we wanna get rid of smartphone
Speaker 6:  and screens are bad and stuff. And it's so interesting kind of comparing
Speaker 6:  the, the reception of the Humane eye open to the, to the rabbit
Speaker 6:  R one, which from what I could see was very warmly
Speaker 6:  received despite having a, a similarly kind of
Speaker 6:  experimental approach towards what a
Speaker 6:  non phone gadget can be. And the difference seemed to be in, in that, in
Speaker 6:  that kind of like pitch. I mean also I think that the rabbit r ones kind
Speaker 6:  of teenage engineering industrial design kind of helped and you kinda have
Speaker 6:  to look at the Humane eye opinion and go, well you just won teenage engineering
Speaker 6:  deal away from like a much more positive. But
Speaker 6:  yeah, so this, that was like a lot of my takeaway is that it's
Speaker 6:  the, the story that you want to tell about the next step.
Speaker 6:  I think If, you kind of shoot high, you lose people and If you shoot low,
Speaker 6:  then you end up with a kind of, this is today's smartphone, but but slightly
Speaker 6:  faster. And so there's that kind of like the, I think the, the
Speaker 6:  Atla phone thing kind of sits in the middle there quite nicely where you
Speaker 6:  go, you already have this thing, you already know the form factor of it,
Speaker 6:  but what if, what if there were less apps that you downloaded and, and what
Speaker 6:  if it was more kind of customized to towards your needs?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Allison, you got to use the Pin, well use, use might be a slightly
Speaker 2:  strong word for what happened with you and the Pin, but what was your experience?
Speaker 2:  What'd you make of it?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I I hovered near a couple of people as they used the Pin
Speaker 7:  and I just, yeah,
Speaker 2:  I think the way you said it was somebody used the Pin at you. Yeah. And that's
Speaker 2:  that's good enough. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  I, I did try to like, I was like, can I just like stand real close to
Speaker 7:  you and like have it project onto my hand and we like tried that for a second.
Speaker 7:  It was very awkward and didn't really work. You had to
Speaker 2:  Like hug them from behind. Yeah, yeah. And reach your arms around it's like,
Speaker 2:  can
Speaker 7:  I just like put my head on your shoulder? It was like very sweet of them
Speaker 7:  to let me try that. That's nice. Yeah, exactly like John said,
Speaker 7:  it's, it's a, a gadget, like you hear all the marketing and the
Speaker 7:  TED talks and all this stuff and there's just like no
Speaker 7:  piece of technology could ever live up to like what I am hearing about
Speaker 7:  and you see it in person and you're like, this is just kind of cool. Like
Speaker 7:  I think it would make a lot more sense if it was something that
Speaker 7:  was designed to compliment your phone and, and the
Speaker 7:  spokespeople I talked to were very like, no, no, this isn't supposed
Speaker 7:  to replace your phone. It's like, you know, it just, when you kind of wanna
Speaker 7:  unplug from your phone, you have it, but it costs
Speaker 7:  $700. It has a subscription fee, it has its
Speaker 7:  own sim card. Like, I don't know a lot of people who are gonna have
Speaker 7:  a phone and a budget for like a basically another phone.
Speaker 7:  So it's, I still have weird feelings about it. I still have questions, but
Speaker 7:  what I saw was, was kind of cool like the, the navigation,
Speaker 7:  you know, that you do kind of a, a pinchy pinch thing to
Speaker 7:  scroll through the menus that the laser's projecting onto your hand.
Speaker 7:  I saw one of these spokespeople, she had to like check the wifi
Speaker 7:  settings on it, which is just sounds like a nightmare thing to,
Speaker 7:  to do and it kind of made sense. She was like, okay
Speaker 7:  doing the little like maneuvers and I don't know, it's gonna be
Speaker 7:  a wild one. I think
Speaker 2:  I really love the idea of projecting a settings menu like
Speaker 2:  huge onto the wall next to me while I slowly scroll through all the
Speaker 2:  wifi options. This works for me. I'm into this,
Speaker 7:  It's the feature. All
Speaker 2:  Right, let's do, we're gonna do a really quick MWC awards lightning round
Speaker 2:  and then I'm gonna let you guys get outta here because you, you both need
Speaker 2:  to sleep after MWC the silliest thing that you saw at MWC that you kind of
Speaker 2:  love anyway. John, go first.
Speaker 6:  The idea of HMD make a big song or dance about a Barbie flip phone that's
Speaker 6:  coming.
Speaker 7:  That's a good one.
Speaker 2:  Fair. Very good answer. Allison, what do you got?
Speaker 7:  I think I gotta go with Bendy phone. I played Connect four on it. They
Speaker 7:  had it like set up. That's like one of the things you can do with it. I'm
Speaker 7:  like, oh I love this.
Speaker 6:  Actually I'm so sorry. Can I change my answer?
Speaker 2:  Sure.
Speaker 6:  28,000 million power battery phones.
Speaker 6:  Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think your headline for that was this Gigantic Battery has a phone
Speaker 2:  attached to it.
Speaker 6:  I a hundred percent stole a former colleague Vlad sas. Oh yeah. Like
Speaker 6:  four, four or five years ago they had an 18,000 million power phone. Now
Speaker 6:  they're back 28,000 million power. That's called Progress baby. Yeah. Get
Speaker 2:  Out here with 18,000, come on in. That's what inflation does. I
Speaker 2:  love
Speaker 6:  This.
Speaker 2:  Alright thing you think a lot of people are most likely to buy very soon
Speaker 2:  that you just saw what screams like big hit
Speaker 2:  coming soon?
Speaker 6:  Well, I mean, I dunno about big hit, but Lenovo's repairable laptops,
Speaker 6:  that's, that's just gonna be businesses all over the world are gonna have
Speaker 6:  those things and people are barely gonna think about it, but there's gonna
Speaker 6:  be some it admin with his little Philip Head screwdriver
Speaker 6:  just going like, ah, yes, this laptop will live live another day. Thank you
Speaker 6:  very much.
Speaker 2:  Love it. Allison, what about you?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I don't know if big hit but like Galaxy ring I think has
Speaker 7:  a lot of potential I would say, especially for something that,
Speaker 7:  I mean it's not brand new but it's sort of a new category for Samsung
Speaker 7:  and it, so it's kind of rare to be like, oh yeah, I can, I can see where
Speaker 7:  you guys are going with this and I, I am, I'm curious to see
Speaker 7:  what happens. Okay,
Speaker 2:  I love it. Yeah, I am super bullish on Smart Rings as a thing. I think there's
Speaker 2:  like a lot of stuff left to do, but I think that category is gonna be really
Speaker 2:  interesting for a while. All right, last one thing you held in your
Speaker 2:  hands in a most wished you could have just taken home with you in that moment
Speaker 2:  that you're like, this is mine now I'm going to leave, I'm going to pickpocket
Speaker 2:  someone in Barcelona and this belongs to me now. John, what do you got?
Speaker 6:  Okay, it's like, so this company Infinix, this wasn't like brand new for
Speaker 6:  MWC, but they had a concept concept phone called the e color shift where
Speaker 6:  basically whenever it charges, it has an e Ink display on its rear
Speaker 6:  that rapidly changes between different color schemes. And then the idea is
Speaker 6:  you like yank out the power cord when it kind of hits the, hits the the
Speaker 6:  color that you like and you're like, cool, this is, this is the color of
Speaker 6:  my phone now. This is great. That's so fun. It's so, it's so great and like
Speaker 6:  it's not even a functional phone and it is, it's a concept thing. They think
Speaker 6:  maybe in the next couple of years they'll, they'll actually bring this thing
Speaker 6:  out but yeah, you're just like a checkout. You can't decide between
Speaker 6:  the like really adventurous color and and black W like why not both?
Speaker 2:  I love that Allison, what about you?
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna go with the Xiaomi 14 ultra with the like
Speaker 7:  sub category of the photography kit. They
Speaker 7:  introduced this with last year's series and it's like a little
Speaker 7:  camera grip you put on The Phone. It sounds so stupid but I loved
Speaker 7:  it. It has a little shutter button. They're doing it again this year for
Speaker 7:  the 14 Ultra, but it's like actually more useful and it has a battery in
Speaker 7:  it. I love what they do with their cameras and it's just like
Speaker 7:  a camera nerds phone. I want one.
Speaker 2:  That's a good one. I like it. Alright, you both need to go get some sleep
Speaker 2:  and recover from all of your many travels. Thank you both for doing this.
Speaker 2:  This was, this was super fun. Can't wait to do it again.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, thank you. My
Speaker 6:  Pleasure. Thank you having me.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna come back and answer
Speaker 2:  our question from the first cast Hotline
Speaker 11:  Sweat.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the Hotline as always. The number is
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 Verge one one. The email is Vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com. We love all your questions, we try to answer at least one on the
Speaker 2:  show every week. Thank you as always. To everybody who calls and emails,
Speaker 2:  we love hearing from you. This week we have a question from Taylor.
Speaker 14:  Hi, this is Taylor from Colorado, love the show. And I was curious
Speaker 14:  this week with you talking so much about Crawler Bot and the consequences
Speaker 14:  of ai, what do you think the impact is gonna be on websites
Speaker 14:  like the way back machine that are archiving the internet and in some ways
Speaker 14:  have already been accessing New York Times and other
Speaker 14:  places behind paywall, but also are really important to
Speaker 14:  Wikipedia and the history of the internet would look to
Speaker 14:  know more what y'all think next? Bye.
Speaker 2:  I love this question because it gets at something that actually I
Speaker 2:  wrote about on The Verge a couple of weeks ago. I'll put the link in the
Speaker 2:  show notes. But this idea of access and basically who
Speaker 2:  controls what is public and what is private on the web.
Speaker 2:  And just Taylor, to answer your question directly, the answer is yes, it's
Speaker 2:  a huge deal and it's potentially a huge change in how
Speaker 2:  a lot of these things work. So there's things like the internet archive,
Speaker 2:  right? Which is going out and literally just downloading versions of
Speaker 2:  webpages periodically in order for you to be able to go find them later.
Speaker 2:  The internet archive a bunch of years ago essentially said, we're doing
Speaker 2:  this for the good of humanity and we are going to do it no matter what you
Speaker 2:  think. So every website in theory has this thing called robots
Speaker 2:  dot txt, which is just If. You go to whatever the website is,
Speaker 2:  amazon.com/robots.txt. It's just
Speaker 2:  a simple text file and basically what it does in most cases is
Speaker 2:  say which web crawler bots are allowed in and which
Speaker 2:  are not allowed. And for like three decades, this was actually
Speaker 2:  a thing that was created in the nineties back when you know, having a bunch
Speaker 2:  of crawlers on your website could actually crash your website because internet
Speaker 2:  infrastructure was slow and didn't work all that well. But for the last three
Speaker 2:  decades it's mostly been about search engines. The idea was do I
Speaker 2:  as a website owner want Google to crawl my website? And it's essentially
Speaker 2:  a question about exchange of value, right? So you say, I want Google to crawl
Speaker 2:  my website, that means Google is going to use some of my bandwidth costs,
Speaker 2:  it costs money to let its crawler come and look at all of my webpages and
Speaker 2:  it means Google has access to a cache of every one of my
Speaker 2:  webpage at some interval of time. In exchange I get to be
Speaker 2:  in Google's search engine and Google will send traffic to my website. So
Speaker 2:  there are a bunch of versions of that. Bing runs a crawler that does very
Speaker 2:  similar things, but for a long time that was the exchange. The internet archive
Speaker 2:  was a slightly different one where in a sense you're getting something back
Speaker 2:  from the internet archive, but it's not like they're sending you traffic.
Speaker 2:  The traffic to the internet archive goes to the internet archive,
Speaker 2:  their download of your website. In general, I think most people think the
Speaker 2:  internet archive is like a net good for humanity. So, I think this wasn't
Speaker 2:  really a huge issue, but If, you didn't want the internet
Speaker 2:  archive to crawl your website for whatever reason and there are plenty of
Speaker 2:  valid reasons not to. You could in theory in that robots
Speaker 2:  txt page block the internet archive. The internet archive said I think in
Speaker 2:  2017 that it was just no longer going to respect that, that its mission
Speaker 2:  was too important, that it was doing things that were good and valuable and
Speaker 2:  it was no longer interested in respecting the wishes of somebody's robots
Speaker 2:  txt page. That page has huge sort of normative
Speaker 2:  value on the internet, but no actual real legal authority. It
Speaker 2:  has no technical authority. It's just kind of a way of saying, you know,
Speaker 2:  please keep out. It's like putting a sign on your tree house. It doesn't
Speaker 2:  really accomplish anything, but it does send a message. But If, you don't
Speaker 2:  wanna listen, you don't really have to. So that has all been happening
Speaker 2:  over the years and there have been people who want more sophisticated tools
Speaker 2:  to actually keep people out. There have been more sophisticated
Speaker 2:  reasons for the protocol to exist behind robots
Speaker 2:  txt, but in general it has just been around and it has more or less worked
Speaker 2:  and more or less been okay with people. But now like Taylor is saying with
Speaker 2:  ai, two things are happening. One, a lot of these companies that
Speaker 2:  run websites are starting to think a lot more carefully about what is and
Speaker 2:  is not allowed on their website. So you can say
Speaker 2:  not just, I wanna block Google, but I wanna block open AI because I don't
Speaker 2:  want my stuff going into open AI's training data for
Speaker 2:  its large language models. So you could block GPT bot, that's the one that
Speaker 2:  OpenAI does. Most of the other AI companies have crawlers of their own, they
Speaker 2:  all need this giant mass of training data. So not only are all of these
Speaker 2:  website owners having to go into that webpage and say, I
Speaker 2:  wanna block GPT bot or whatever else, it's causing them to think more
Speaker 2:  broadly about access, right? You have an
Speaker 2:  antitrust case against Amazon that is fundamentally in large part
Speaker 2:  about Amazon's ability to crawl the web. It was doing this thing where it
Speaker 2:  would go around the web and look for prices on products that were
Speaker 2:  also listed on Amazon and then allegedly doing a bunch of
Speaker 2:  really shady stuff. If it found that you were listing something for cheaper
Speaker 2:  than you were listing it on Amazon, you can't do that If, you don't have
Speaker 2:  an automated way to crawl the web, it's just too much work for a single person
Speaker 2:  to like go click on every product page on the internet. So this is the
Speaker 2:  kind of thing that's used in tons of ways, right? And not only are these
Speaker 2:  companies going in and saying, okay, who do I want in and who do I want out?
Speaker 2:  One particularly powerful way to keep people out is a paywall.
Speaker 2:  And like Taylor said, one of the things we're starting to see is more and
Speaker 2:  more companies, publishers, whatever, putting their
Speaker 2:  stuff behind the paywall, like one of the reasons Facebook has always required
Speaker 2:  you to log in is because it doesn't want Google
Speaker 2:  and everybody else to be able to access all of the data on Facebook because
Speaker 2:  that data is really valuable. And now we're seeing companies like Reddit
Speaker 2:  start to realize how valuable their data is in strike deals with AI companies.
Speaker 2:  So there's just this shift in how data
Speaker 2:  on the internet is understood. For a long time it was kind of net public.
Speaker 2:  The idea was to be in their place, it was gonna be fine. And now to some
Speaker 2:  extent the website or the app or whatever is actually less
Speaker 2:  valuable in sort of real dollar terms. Then
Speaker 2:  the data underneath it, like the content of Reddit posts
Speaker 2:  is probably more valuable and more important than Reddit, which is weird
Speaker 2:  because one can't exist without the other, but that is very much
Speaker 2:  where we are. So all of this is up in the air right now for the first time
Speaker 2:  in a really long time and in a pretty big way I think threatens
Speaker 2:  to kind of rewrite the web. It could put much more stuff
Speaker 2:  behind registration walls and start to silo things off even more. We've talked
Speaker 2:  a lot about the sort of open future of social with Activity pub and the Fedi
Speaker 2:  verse and Mastodon, and I think all of that is very cool. I also think there
Speaker 2:  are lots and lots of incentives for all of these platforms to build
Speaker 2:  bigger walls, not knock them down because If, you knock them down,
Speaker 2:  you give lots of companies and crawlers and people access
Speaker 2:  to your stuff in ways that can be adversarial and problematic for you. This
Speaker 2:  is one of the things I have spent a lot of time thinking about and talking
Speaker 2:  about with people because it's one of these sort of norms of the internet,
Speaker 2:  right? That like if I have a webpage and you have a webpage, we should both
Speaker 2:  just be cool. And it is amazing how far that got us, but now there's so
Speaker 2:  much money and so much change and so many new
Speaker 2:  reasons both to crawl someone else's website and to be worried about someone
Speaker 2:  crawling your website that I think a lot of this is about to change and what
Speaker 2:  I've heard from publishers and stuff is that they didn't touch their robots
Speaker 2:  txt page for years and now it's becoming like a
Speaker 2:  C-suite level meeting. You have to have about who do we want in, who do we
Speaker 2:  wanna block and who do we want to go try to make some kind of commercial
Speaker 2:  agreement with So I. Don't wanna overstate it, but I'm
Speaker 2:  gonna kind of overstate it. Like I think this is possibly going to be part
Speaker 2:  of the huge change that we're about to see on the web. We've seen the
Speaker 2:  problems with closed platforms and we're now in a phase I think where
Speaker 2:  there is a real push back toward the open web, but there are also really
Speaker 2:  good reasons, If, you are part of that open web to close your
Speaker 2:  doors. So we'll see. But my great hope, if I'm completely honest, is that
Speaker 2:  things like the internet archive and Wikipedia and all of these things continue
Speaker 2:  to be free and open because I think the idea that they are generally good
Speaker 2:  things and should continue to exist on the open internet, that feels right
Speaker 2:  to me. Alright, anyway, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thanks to
Speaker 2:  John and Allison for being here. And thank you as always for listening. There's
Speaker 2:  lots more from everything we talked about on The Verge dot com. Our MWC coverage
Speaker 2:  was awesome. John and Allison made a bunch of really great videos. So If,
Speaker 2:  you go to our TikTok or Instagram channel, you can see tons of good stuff
Speaker 2:  from them touching and spinning around and playing with all these cool gadgets.
Speaker 2:  But in general it's a super newsy time right now. So check out The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com. Lots going on as always. If you have thoughts or questions or feelings
Speaker 2:  or want to get my Humane ai Pin from me when I finally get
Speaker 2:  one. You can always email us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or keep calling
Speaker 2:  the Hotline 8 6 6 Verge one one. we love hearing from you. Send us all of
Speaker 2:  your thoughts and questions and ideas. We are rapidly
Speaker 2:  nearing what I would say is like the first gadget season of the year. We're
Speaker 2:  gonna get some AI stuff, we're gonna get some Apple stuff, we're gonna get
Speaker 2:  some Google stuff. There's just a lot coming, so keep all your questions
Speaker 2:  coming. Tell us what you wanna hear about. we love hearing from you. This
Speaker 2:  show is produced by Andrew Marino, Liam James, and Wil Poor The. Vergecast
Speaker 2:  is Verge production and part of the Vox Media Podcast. Network, NELI Alex,
Speaker 2:  and I'll be back on Friday to talk about the new MacBook Air and everything
Speaker 2:  else happening at Tech right now. We'll see you then. We rock and roll.