# Transcript
ID: 5d2ab537-6801-423c-aa54-32e3549033c2
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-413040593540717371/8061311869007081849/s93290-US-5730s-1731672284.mp3
Description: Nilay and David talk about the future of social, in light of Bluesky's recent surge in growth. Threads is huge, Bluesky is ascendent, Mastodon is... around, but can any of them become the next Twitter? Is that even the goal? After that, Kylie Robison joins the show and the gang discusses Apple's smart home device (which is just an iPad), the AI scaling slowdown, and a new twist in the delivery wars. In the lightning round, it's all about disclosures, wireless carriers, and the sad end of Freevee.
Speaker 2:  Hello and welcome to Vergecast, the flagship podcast of six inch Wall
Speaker 2:  tablets.
Speaker 2:  So what everybody wants, do we have
Speaker 3:  To be, I don't like that one very much
Speaker 2:  Fr from what I gather, this is the product that's gonna set the tech industry
Speaker 2:  on fire.
Speaker 2:  It's gonna happen, David.
Speaker 3:  Sure. Listen, if it'll make you shut up about your garage door, I'll take
Speaker 3:  it. Oh no.
Speaker 2:  Well there's gonna be some, some garage door talk on this show. Hi, I'm your
Speaker 2:  friend Eli. David Pierce is here. Hello. A little later. Kylie Robinson is
Speaker 2:  gonna join us. We're gonna talk about whether or not AI is is real, whether
Speaker 2:  it's just a fake idea. The Vergecast,
Speaker 2:  there's a lot of news talk about this week. It is week negative eight of
Speaker 2:  the Trump administration. So that Is that how they count and that's how George Washington
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that seems right. That's in the
Speaker 3:  Constitution. As he was in a boat, he was like, this is week negative six
Speaker 3:  and then it, yeah, no, that makes sense. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Elon is already doing stuff. There's a fake department of government efficiency
Speaker 2:  that we should talk about for as much as we need to talk about it. There's
Speaker 2:  a fake wireless carrier called Boost Mobile that we should talk about that
Speaker 2:  I'm excited to talk about.
Speaker 3:  It's a real carrier
Speaker 2:  Dli. There are rumors that Apple's gonna make a wall tablet, so we gotta
Speaker 2:  talk about garage droppers as promised. But let's start with
Speaker 2:  what's happening on social media. We've talked a lot about
Speaker 2:  the Fedi verse on this show, about the idea of the open social web
Speaker 2:  that maybe you weren't gonna be locked into one platform that you can
Speaker 2:  move around. That's Mastodon. There's a protocol called
Speaker 2:  Activity Pub that we've talked about a lot. Threads from Meta is using Activity
Speaker 2:  Pub the very slowly inched their way to support
Speaker 2:  people. Have a lot of issues with threads overall because of its moderation.
Speaker 2:  And then this week after the election, after Elon
Speaker 2:  has basically turned the X algorithm to being a pure
Speaker 2:  flood of propaganda for himself, not, not even I would say conservative ideas
Speaker 2:  just for Elon Musk. People are fleeing X,
Speaker 2:  they're, they're out of there. Huge drop in users and they're not going to
Speaker 2:  Threads or MA on. They're going to Bluesky, which is a different federated
Speaker 2:  social platform that uses a different protocol called At Protocol.
Speaker 2:  At Protocol I, I've talked to Blue Sky's, COJ Grabber on
Speaker 2:  decoder. We can get into the weeds of it, but it seems like that is the winner
Speaker 2:  in social media this week. David, what do you think is going on here?
Speaker 3:  Is it the winner? This is such an interesting question
Speaker 2:  This week.
Speaker 3:  This week, yes it is. It is the vibe's winner in a very real way.
Speaker 3:  And I think the thing that we've discovered over the two years since
Speaker 3:  Elon Musk bought Twitter is that the vibe shift really
Speaker 3:  matters. And I think your, your diagnosis is exactly right,
Speaker 3:  right? Like Threads was the thing. Threads probably still is the thing and
Speaker 3:  we should talk about it, but Threads has
Speaker 3:  275 million users. That's what Mark Zuckerberg announced. They're signing
Speaker 3:  up a million people a day like that. That thing is growing like a weed.
Speaker 3:  There's been some news that Threads is gonna turn on ads next year, which
Speaker 3:  means it's going to be a big scale business. All anyone
Speaker 3:  wants to talk about right now is Bluesky. And I think Bluesky has
Speaker 3:  hit something like mainstream
Speaker 3:  critical mass, which I think is a really exciting
Speaker 3:  B, really annoying in some ways that we should talk about. And C
Speaker 3:  really surprising, I think if I'm being completely honest, I kind of left
Speaker 3:  Bluesky for Dead a while ago. It, it had its first spike. People
Speaker 3:  were really excited. I think Bluesky has done a lot of things really right
Speaker 3:  in how to build this kind of thing. It was very smart about how to think
Speaker 3:  about identity. It was very smart in thinking about discovery. They
Speaker 3:  built products like List and messages and like as a, as a platform.
Speaker 3:  Bluesky is dramatically better than any of the other competitors right now.
Speaker 3:  But it was weird and it was like all the people who went to Bluesky
Speaker 3:  at the beginning went to be weird on purpose and that is like fine and
Speaker 3:  good as far as it goes, right? And so my thinking was
Speaker 3:  there's going to be this subset of people like the the Twitter shit posters
Speaker 3:  who were going to be very happy of Bluesky and we just going to sort of hang
Speaker 3:  out with each other over there. And it got out of that this week.
Speaker 3:  We're now in a moment where people who don't want any part of that
Speaker 3:  are coming onto Bluesky. People are coming back to Bluesky, A OC came back
Speaker 3:  to Bluesky and caused like a mini uproar when she started posting. There
Speaker 3:  again, everybody's trying to make Skitting happen again instead of calling
Speaker 3:  it posting like Bluesky is is I think by
Speaker 3:  far like an order of magnitude out of the
Speaker 3:  actual competitor to Threads World right now. But in
Speaker 3:  terms of like who has the juice, I think Bluesky
Speaker 3:  legitimately has the juice at this point. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Two things about this that I think are really important. One Threads is an
Speaker 2:  algorithmic platform and so is X now?
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  You open XI open my X account and it is just the
Speaker 2:  algorithm feeding me whatever Elon Musk wants me to see,
Speaker 2:  which is mostly himself. Yeah. Weird. And I, I think
Speaker 2:  people are just reacting to that and reacting to that poison. It is a right
Speaker 2:  wing, echo chamber. It is impossible to participate there unless you say
Speaker 2:  exactly what that audience wants to hear. That's bad. Like that's
Speaker 2:  algorithmic collapse is real. I don't think anybody wants to be in an echo
Speaker 2:  chamber that powerful in any way, shape or form.
Speaker 3:  Some people do. I mean to, to be blunt, some people do and that's fine. Right?
Speaker 3:  But it is like the distance between X and like truth social
Speaker 3:  and Rumble is smaller and smaller every day. Yeah. And there is a
Speaker 3:  community of people who is, well-served by that, great. But it is
Speaker 3:  like if that platform has run away from anything like
Speaker 3:  mainstream appeal, like actively running away from it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And, and we should talk about the extreme hypocrisy of Elon
Speaker 2:  Musk in general who is like, I'm a free speech warrior and then slowly closed
Speaker 2:  the boundary of speech on X to be exactly what he wants. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  The point I'm making is Threads is also an algorithmic platform. You
Speaker 2:  open it and you just see a fire hose of whatever meta wants you to see, which
Speaker 2:  is the most inane engagement bait that has ever been produced in the entire
Speaker 2:  Yes. Right. Like, and it's so, it's like not a you open it, you're like,
Speaker 2:  what is happening here? What am I seeing? And yes, there's a reverse chron
Speaker 2:  feed that you can like slide over to, but it's not the default. Even If,
Speaker 2:  you do set it, they'll drop you back into the algorithmic feed at a moment's
Speaker 2:  notice. And really you just get to a place where
Speaker 2:  they're not platforms that replace Twitter. Like
Speaker 2:  they, they don't serve the same role. They're not doing the same job threads.
Speaker 2:  I think intentionally they've talked about how they don't want it to be that
Speaker 2:  XI think intentionally in another way, which is he just broke it,
Speaker 2:  you know? He just like took the thing and yeah, used it for his own purposes.
Speaker 3:  Super successfully by the way, like just to, he did, just to briefly give
Speaker 3:  credit where credit is due. Like I, I got a bunch of crap from
Speaker 3:  people after the election. 'cause we've, we've said many times how stupid
Speaker 3:  a purchasing decision Twitter was, which I would also remind you
Speaker 3:  Elon Musk also agrees with that fact. Yeah. He tried very hard to not
Speaker 3:  purchase it, but it, like, in a, in a certain way of thinking about it,
Speaker 3:  boy was buying Twitter a good move for Elon Musk who is now just
Speaker 3:  the shadow president of the United States.
Speaker 2:  I totally think that's debatable. I think he spent a lot of money and he
Speaker 2:  got a bunch of votes and he did a bunch of rallies and he gave away a million
Speaker 2:  dollars to sign people to a petition that may or may not have been in Constitu.
Speaker 2:  Who knows the I'm gonna make the X algorithm
Speaker 2:  just do whatever I want. Debatable, I think, I think, I don't
Speaker 2:  know that the average swing voter got swayed by the amount of garbage on
Speaker 2:  X. No,
Speaker 3:  But he's now the second most powerful person in America.
Speaker 2:  Right. But did X make him that or, or did his money spent
Speaker 2:  like literally handing novelty checks out on saving like, I don't know
Speaker 2:  the answer. It's a reasonable question. Yeah. But the point, the broader
Speaker 2:  point of making the second part is these are now creator
Speaker 2:  platforms. That's what they are. Yes. They're closed in
Speaker 2:  insanely closed X will deran your post If, you put links in
Speaker 2:  them, so Will threads. Yep. Because they're algorithmic, they're
Speaker 2:  designed to promote engagement on the platform themselves. So they are
Speaker 2:  just very closed. They're in they're little walled gardens
Speaker 2:  that you're supposed to be in. And even if Threads finishes its activity
Speaker 2:  pub integration, even if it all works out the way that I, I would
Speaker 2:  very much want it to work out, it's still closed. Like it's de
Speaker 2:  designed to be a closed ecosystem. And I think
Speaker 3:  Crucially that, that that thing has kind of calcified
Speaker 3:  since really the last time we talked about this, right? Like threads has
Speaker 3:  now been telling us what threads is for long enough
Speaker 3:  that the smart thing to do is just believe it, right? Yeah. Everybody is
Speaker 3:  after being like, Adam Moer, please, dear God, let me
Speaker 3:  just see the reverse crown of all the people I follow. If, if Adam
Speaker 3:  Moer and Mark Zuckerberg and the Threads team wanted to do that, they would
Speaker 3:  have, they were like, this is, this is where we are. The thing you're describing
Speaker 3:  is what threads is going to be for the foreseeable future. And I think to
Speaker 3:  me that is what is underlying a lot of this is there is this sense of like,
Speaker 3:  threads was new and it was early and we weren't sure what it was gonna be.
Speaker 3:  And they seem to have these big interesting ambitious goals. None of that
Speaker 3:  counts in its favor anymore. Like Threads is threads now and we, we should
Speaker 3:  take the thing for what it is
Speaker 2:  And, and and, and it's gonna grow however it grows, right? Yeah. It is growing
Speaker 2:  at some rate, but it is very much meant to be a creator platform.
Speaker 2:  And, and I think that's how they're gonna think about it. Bluesky for
Speaker 2:  whatever it will become is way smaller. As you noted David, it's 15 million
Speaker 2:  users just today as we're talking. But it's designed to be an open
Speaker 2:  platform. Links are not suppressed in the algorithm. It is leading you
Speaker 2:  towards revon feeds by default. There are algorithms
Speaker 2:  you can get that sort the fire hose in different ways. That's a part of their
Speaker 2:  monetization strategy is actually to sell you algorithms, which is
Speaker 2:  like fascinating. Yes. The moderation is quote
Speaker 2:  composable, so you can tell it how you want to moderate the feeds.
Speaker 2:  The protocol I think is wonkier, right? Like there
Speaker 2:  isn't another Bluesky server yet, right? So everything is happening on one
Speaker 2:  server. You can kind of set your own domain name so you can like make it
Speaker 2:  feel a little bit different. But eventually when there is one,
Speaker 2:  the idea of following someone from another server is not as political as
Speaker 2:  it is on Mastodon. Like you're not getting at these like server wide block
Speaker 2:  lists. Like it's just not how it works, right? All the federation is at the
Speaker 2:  user level. So if you're like, I don't like this Bluesky server that I'm
Speaker 2:  on, I can take my whole account and take it to another server because
Speaker 2:  that's the, the, the element that is moderated is
Speaker 2:  the user account. Whereas on Activity Pub and MAs that and whatever else,
Speaker 2:  the thing that is federated is the servers, right? So like
Speaker 2:  if The Verge Mastodon existed, that would be the the thing that
Speaker 2:  is federated. And you could be like, I hate uni and like leave and go to
Speaker 2:  mastodon.com or whatever of Bluesky. It's your
Speaker 2:  account is the thing that moves around, right? And you can take that
Speaker 2:  from server to server at will kind of, right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And I think that's the thing. It it Bluesky like I said, got a lot
Speaker 3:  right? But I think that is the thing it got most right. And I think is the
Speaker 3:  thing that is proving to be the hardest about the Fedi verse
Speaker 3:  and, and this kind of whole universe is nobody can figure out who you are
Speaker 3:  like in a, in a sort of meaningful way. Like what is my
Speaker 3:  username and identity and profile is actually like a crucially important
Speaker 3:  part of this entire system. And it is the most complicated
Speaker 3:  thing going in Activity Pub and Masson and Bluesky. It is like central
Speaker 3:  and they've done a bunch of really smart stuff and like your, your username
Speaker 3:  is also just a URL. You can just type your username into a bar and it will
Speaker 3:  load up your profile. Like that stuff is powerful and I think is
Speaker 3:  is a big win. Like you said, Bluesky desperately needs
Speaker 3:  a second thing because it is, it is currently it is exactly as
Speaker 3:  open as Facebook. It has a bunch
Speaker 3:  of big ideas about being open and it just isn't right now. And
Speaker 3:  they've gotta build the next thing. But I
Speaker 3:  I, a big part of this honestly is I, I believe Bluesky is telling the truth
Speaker 3:  much more than I believe Threads is telling the truth about where they want
Speaker 3:  to go. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And Adam er again very direct, we don't wanna do news.
Speaker 2:  It's more trouble than it's worth. Yeah. Okay, well you have
Speaker 2:  an X in this election you had an X platform that was explicitly
Speaker 2:  showcasing one view of America
Speaker 2:  explicitly in the tank for one candidate. Yep. And then the alternative was
Speaker 2:  nothing. Right? The alternative platform and that and that style
Speaker 2:  of social media was we don't want this here. And that's a weird
Speaker 2:  imbalance, right? Because all the people who were leaving X were going to
Speaker 2:  a platform where that stuff was not there the way that it was
Speaker 2:  on the other platform. Certainly not as overt. And I think now what you're
Speaker 2:  getting is, okay, that didn't work either. And I think now what you're getting
Speaker 2:  is a bunch of people saying, well this didn't feel right. Let's go to a platform
Speaker 2:  where we can make it what we want. Right? And Bluesky literally has the tools
Speaker 2:  built into it to make it what you want. They have the APIs
Speaker 2:  are there, the, the availability of just the fire hose of posts is
Speaker 2:  there and people can build tools. There's already
Speaker 2:  like Deck Blue I think it's called is the tweet deck for Bluesky. It like
Speaker 2:  already exists. Yep, there it is. You can just use it. So there's something
Speaker 2:  really interesting happening here. We have kind of like a VHS beta
Speaker 2:  situation inside of federated social media, open social media.
Speaker 2:  But a lot of the smart people that I talk to are like, this isn't gonna matter
Speaker 2:  at the end of the day because there's software that bridges between all of
Speaker 2:  these things. And actually the best outcome is for MAs on
Speaker 2:  and Bluesky and Threads and whatever else part of the Fed verse ghost
Speaker 2:  to all just be able to talk to each other and the protocol shouldn't matter
Speaker 2:  as much. I don't know if we'll get there. I think that's a long way away.
Speaker 2:  I think people are still trying to make their specific protocols work and
Speaker 2:  you gotta make technology bets, right? So you gotta start with something,
Speaker 2:  but I can see a future where yeah, actually everything does work
Speaker 2:  together way better. And If you, what you want to do is pick the creator
Speaker 2:  platform. You can go pick the creator platform, but if what you
Speaker 2:  want is the more open, here's where we share a bunch of links and
Speaker 2:  talk about them platform that is also available to you.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I think the outcome you're describing I think is pretty
Speaker 3:  clearly the best version of this story. And
Speaker 3:  it was always gonna take a long time, right? Like we've, we've been talking
Speaker 3:  a lot about the Fedi verse and activity pub for the last couple of years
Speaker 3:  and I've reached a point where I'm, I'm sort of itchy that it
Speaker 3:  hasn't happened yet and it's like, okay, maybe this just isn't gonna ha
Speaker 3:  and then it's like, okay, every time I talk to people they're like, everyone
Speaker 3:  who works on this has been working on this longer than you realize and is
Speaker 3:  un is aware of the fact that this is going to take a long time. Right? So
Speaker 3:  it's like none of this gets built in a day. I also
Speaker 3:  think these things are in some ways getting further apart
Speaker 3:  and that's the part that gets problematic, right? Like everyday Threads
Speaker 3:  doesn't build out really strong activity pub integration,
Speaker 3:  it gets harder to build really strong activity. Pub integration and everyday
Speaker 3:  threads gets more successful. Building that stuff well becomes less
Speaker 3:  and less compelling, right? Like Threads as a
Speaker 3:  powerful closed creator platform could be very
Speaker 3:  successful. It is already very successful. It's just like there
Speaker 3:  comes a time when being a good steward of an open ecosystem is not as
Speaker 3:  exciting as it once was when you were teeny tiny and kind of needed that
Speaker 3:  ecosystem. I still believe the people who work there are serious when they
Speaker 3:  say they wanna do that, but
Speaker 3:  that doesn't get you very far.
Speaker 2:  Lemme make the defense of the Threads team not of Meta, but
Speaker 2:  specifically the, the challenge facing the Threads team. Sure. 'cause I I
Speaker 2:  think they've done something here that is smart, interesting at least, but
Speaker 2:  potentially Smart If, you look light Bluesky, they built all their features
Speaker 2:  and they have struggled to scale them to even 15 million users, which is
Speaker 2:  why they had invites at the beginning, which is why they, the thing called
Speaker 2:  the health thread where like all you could see was one insane thread that
Speaker 2:  was going crazy every day, but they built the complete product
Speaker 2:  and they scaled it. And that has, and that's how most
Speaker 2:  people build things. The Threads team is taking a productivity pub
Speaker 2:  where they're adding one piece of federation at scale
Speaker 2:  immediately, right? So they're like, okay, you can now see
Speaker 2:  who follows you in the Fedi verse. All 275 million of you can see this at
Speaker 2:  scale. It works. Okay, now we're gonna let you see who liked it.
Speaker 2:  We're not gonna let you reply yet. Now we're gonna let the next thing happen.
Speaker 2:  And they're adding sort of like one piece of the stack at the scale of
Speaker 2:  the whole platform, which is just a different way of going
Speaker 2:  about it. But the fact that the loops haven't closed yet, I think is what's
Speaker 2:  striving everybody crazy. Right?
Speaker 3:  And and I I I agree
Speaker 2:  With you that right? If someone replies to you from the Fed verse and you
Speaker 2:  can't write back to them, it's like, what is the point of this? Right?
Speaker 3:  That's actually like an actively bad experience. Yeah. If you're, if you're
Speaker 3:  someone who is paying attention to protocol development, that is like exciting.
Speaker 3:  But the thing where somebody replies to me,
Speaker 2:  I'm sorry everybody, sorry, this is
Speaker 3:  What I mean, right? But it's like what it actually looks like is a user is
Speaker 3:  I see a thing that asks me periodically if I want to keep sharing
Speaker 3:  to the Fedi verse that I have to figure out what that means and decide.
Speaker 3:  And then I get a bunch of people who are like concerned trolling me into
Speaker 3:  sharing to the Fedi verse. And then people reply to me, but I can't reply
Speaker 3:  to them. And if I like what they reply to, they don't see it like it's bad
Speaker 3:  product until it works. And I think the longer it goes being bad
Speaker 3:  product, the less compelling it becomes kind of to
Speaker 3:  everybody involved. I'm still very hopeful and I do still think it's the
Speaker 3:  right answer, but I, I worry increasingly, like the reason
Speaker 3:  I think this Bluesky thing has been such good news is I think Threads
Speaker 3:  really didn't seem like it was gonna have meaningful competition there
Speaker 3:  for a while. And I think the idea that Bluesky,
Speaker 3:  even if it doesn't like federate in the way that we want, even
Speaker 3:  if it doesn't become this sort of big beautiful open thing like competition
Speaker 3:  is good. And the idea that Threads was just going to sort of walk away with
Speaker 3:  this because we all wanted some other place to
Speaker 2:  We're back. If I was starting The Verge cold today, you can already see
Speaker 2:  it in our design. What I want it to be. But if I was starting it cold today,
Speaker 2:  the open source licenses of these various platforms aside, 'cause
Speaker 2:  they're complicated. I would be like we're starting a server and
Speaker 2:  you can follow our feeds. Like I'm just gonna post all day on my server and
Speaker 2:  we'll have some ads on it or whatever. Yeah. And If, you wanna follow my
Speaker 2:  posts? You can follow them. But we're gonna own this and we're gonna curate
Speaker 2:  a bunch of stuff from these other places using activity pubs. So If, you
Speaker 2:  wanna see the best of what we're looking at. You can see it here. You can
Speaker 2:  already see what we're doing with Quick Post You, we've talked about federating
Speaker 2:  our site quite a bit. Like you, you can add all these ideas together, right?
Speaker 2:  Right. You're Vergecast listeners, you're smart. You can see what I'm trying
Speaker 2:  to do here. Yeah, it's harder when you have a giant website with 13 years
Speaker 2:  of archives and static site CSS
Speaker 2:  features that animate and blow up your phone when you scroll. To be
Speaker 2:  honest. Yeah. Some of our old ones were were, look, the technology was
Speaker 2:  not ready yet. We, we have a, we have a big archive that we gotta deal with.
Speaker 2:  But if I was starting one today, I would be like, the thing to do
Speaker 2:  is lean into federated distribution and to actually own
Speaker 2:  your own distribution. Not be like, I'm gonna start a website and
Speaker 2:  make SEO content for the Google robot or I'm gonna start a YouTube channel
Speaker 2:  and eventually get buffeted around by this algorithm until I have to make
Speaker 2:  a video about how mad I am at YouTube. Which everyone does.
Speaker 2:  That's when you get your wings. It's actually
Speaker 2:  lean into the next phase of what the internet looks like.
Speaker 2:  And that's why it's like which of these protocols is gonna win? 'cause I
Speaker 2:  don't, I think there's a bunch of businesses that are sort of like waiting
Speaker 2:  to start once it's clear like how to do it
Speaker 2:  but nobody knows yet. Like there's just a bunch of this foundational work
Speaker 2:  that is still just inching towards a finish line.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Well and it's weird because I think we're at a moment now where
Speaker 3:  at a protocol level activity pub is way ahead, right?
Speaker 3:  Just in terms of sort of adoption and belief.
Speaker 3:  It is the one that everybody who is making bets is betting on at this moment.
Speaker 3:  But in terms of actual places people are,
Speaker 3:  Bluesky is winning. Like I, I think it is
Speaker 3:  it, it is going to keep growing like this because
Speaker 3:  it made the bet that what people want is Twitter minus
Speaker 3:  the mess. And I think truthfully one of the things that I
Speaker 3:  have come to feel over the last couple of years is like Twitter was
Speaker 3:  a disaster of a company run poorly in so many ways and
Speaker 3:  also was kind of like a magical thing that really
Speaker 3:  accomplished a lot of goals that are hard to accomplish in one place.
Speaker 3:  And we're seeing that now, right? Like what, what all of these companies
Speaker 3:  are doing is sort of pulling pieces apart of Twitter and doing
Speaker 3:  one or two of those things. Well no one is
Speaker 3:  trying to do full Twitter and frankly you probably shouldn't. Like was Twitter
Speaker 3:  good for the world? Who knows? But the thing where it was like a place to
Speaker 3:  hang out with your friends and also a place to discover creators
Speaker 3:  but also a place to get like government information at incredible speed
Speaker 3:  is like Twitter was central in our
Speaker 3:  culture in a way that I think we still kind of underrate
Speaker 3:  now and nothing out there is even close to
Speaker 3:  getting to that. But
Speaker 2:  To be clear, this is what, what I'm saying, it would be better if that
Speaker 2:  was reconstructed but actually the government agencies
Speaker 2:  owned their own servers. Yes. So the next time a billionaire shows
Speaker 2:  up and breaks it, we're not like where do I get earthquake information from?
Speaker 2:  Right. Right. Like that's a real thing that has occurred in the past several
Speaker 2:  years. Yeah. Right. The next time someone shows up and breaks it. We're not
Speaker 2:  like where will independent creators post their apologies?
Speaker 2:  Which is a, a real question that was asked this week.
Speaker 2:  It's just a lot of that that's like, oh we should actually just own our own
Speaker 2:  tools like in a, in a meaningful way. We should own our own tools. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And I know I'm always ranting and raving about this 'cause we have our own
Speaker 2:  website and it's the last website on earth and all, but I'm,
Speaker 2:  you look at the who gets to control speech in America and it's like three
Speaker 2:  guys. Yeah. Like at the end of the day Yeah. It's not the government
Speaker 2:  that's bad. It's like three guys and they can come and go
Speaker 2:  like very clearly they can come and go. I think one of the miracles of Twitter
Speaker 2:  and people can, you are free to disagree with me about this, but by and large
Speaker 2:  they got the balance of moderation. Correct. Yeah, I agree with that.
Speaker 2:  That platform was lively. It it, everybody was mad
Speaker 2:  it like sort of exactly the right volume. Jack Dorsey
Speaker 2:  was bizarrely the sort of right personality to go sit
Speaker 2:  in front of Congress and just accept blame with a beard in his kitchen. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Right. He was just like, I'll never forget that. He was like, I suck. I want
Speaker 2:  to be clear. I agree with you that I suck. Like I
Speaker 2:  don't, I sad that I did this, that Mark Zuckerberg quote about Twitter is
Speaker 2:  as a clown car that fell into a gold mine and they've dismantled all that
Speaker 2:  and they've turned the knobs on moderation and algorithms and you can just
Speaker 2:  see, okay, this is a thing that can happen right in in America
Speaker 2:  at least for the next eight weeks. We have a First amendment that prevents
Speaker 2:  the government from passing content moderation rules that let
Speaker 2:  the government level set. So you, what you need is competition.
Speaker 2:  I'm actually, we, we should not talk about Trump too much at all, but I'm
Speaker 2:  confident the next chairman of the FCC is gonna be Brendan Carr. Brendan
Speaker 2:  Carr does not think the the First Amendment should keep the FCC out of
Speaker 2:  content moderation. It's like a real thing that he's talked about. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And if he becomes a chairman we will talk about him a lot. So I'll set that
Speaker 2:  aside. But up in up until now, the
Speaker 2:  who gets to make the rules about what you see is guys.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Mostly just guys. It's just dudes and Sherry Redstone. Yeah. And I'm
Speaker 2:  hopeful that this moment where people are like, screw it, we'll go to Bluesky.
Speaker 2:  It's fun Here points to a future where future, if
Speaker 2:  not the protocols push people towards a better outcome.
Speaker 2:  The fact that everybody can still vote with their attention
Speaker 2:  points to the better outcome. Yeah, I agree. Like Twitter is not like
Speaker 2:  Elon's mistake with Twitter has always been believing it's a monopoly. And
Speaker 2:  I think right now you can just look at the numbers.
Speaker 2:  People are leaving Twitter to join Bluesky and like that means
Speaker 2:  it's not a monopoly.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I I tend to think all of this is going to be
Speaker 3:  a blip in the direction of something else.
Speaker 3:  Right. And it's like the, what what we've learned so far is that
Speaker 3:  leaving Twitter is harder for a lot of people than we think.
Speaker 3:  Everybody who goes to a new platform loves to talk about the new platform
Speaker 3:  and then once the novelty of the thing dies down,
Speaker 3:  it's very hard to know what to do. Right. Like I feel like to some extent
Speaker 3:  we had the same feelings about Mastodon in the early
Speaker 3:  days and it was like maybe this is the thing. It's, it has different values.
Speaker 3:  It, I
Speaker 2:  Wanna be clear, I never had that feeling.
Speaker 3:  No
Speaker 2:  1000% ever had that feeling of mask on.
Speaker 3:  Why then why do you have it about Bluesky?
Speaker 2:  I think do you know that Steve Jobs quote
Speaker 2:  about Microsoft and taste? Mm I hope listeners know what I'm talking about.
Speaker 2:  There's this very famous Steve Jobs, he, it's like young Steve Jobs and,
Speaker 2:  and it's in his wilderness period after he got fired from Apple, he was at
Speaker 2:  next and he was a little more bum astic than usual 'cause he was constantly
Speaker 2:  trying to solve the X thing and prove himself whatever. I'm just contextualize
Speaker 2:  the quote. They asked about Microsoft and he said the problem with Microsoft
Speaker 2:  is that they have no taste and he looks very pleased with himself. And he
Speaker 2:  said, I don't mean that in a small way, I mean that in a big way.
Speaker 2:  Right. They just, the company doesn't have taste, it doesn't have a sense
Speaker 2:  of what it is doing or how it should feel. Yeah. And I've always felt that
Speaker 2:  Mastodon lacks that particular kind of taste like it is. Software
Speaker 2:  threads has no taste in a big way.
Speaker 2:  I like the people who are making threads. I've, I've talked to them, they've
Speaker 2:  shown up at VERGE parties. We threw a funeral for Twitter. The team
Speaker 2:  was there, it was great. I they're cool as a company. Meta
Speaker 2:  does not have taste. There's a reason Mark Zuckerberg is like wearing Roman
Speaker 2:  fonts on his shirts. Yeah. And signing deals with RayBan. 'cause they need
Speaker 2:  to buy taste, they need to, they need to demonstrate taste because it does
Speaker 2:  not exist in their products.
Speaker 3:  They've also decided several times that having taste is dangerous. Yep.
Speaker 3:  And the only way to get as big as Meta has gotten is to not have taste
Speaker 3:  like it's, they made a business decision to not have any taste.
Speaker 2:  I challenge anyone to open the Facebook app and be like, I
Speaker 2:  sense taste here. Right. Bluesky largely is a clone
Speaker 2:  of Twitter. So like I'm not, I'm not imputing taste onto that.
Speaker 2:  Twitter had Desi, like Twitter had famous designers, like
Speaker 2:  important parts of Culture came out of the user base of Twitter filtered
Speaker 2:  through Twitter's designers and product people and then out into the world.
Speaker 2:  Right. The at mention the hashtag like all the stuff is stuff
Speaker 2:  Twitter took from its community, productized put design around and
Speaker 2:  then gave to the world. Pull to Refresh was a third party
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Twitter app, Tweety mechanic that Twitter bought and they
Speaker 2:  signed a patent pledge so that anybody could use it. So they have the patent
Speaker 2:  on it but they won't use it. But that is like part of the culture now. Like
Speaker 2:  Pull to Refresh is like an app mechanic. Yeah. That is like actually If you
Speaker 2:  like spend a lot of time thinking about it has led to an entire culture.
Speaker 2:  Blue Sky's design is a lot of copies, but the, you can see it in the people
Speaker 2:  who are making it that they have taste, they have a very clear sense about
Speaker 2:  what the product should be and how it should make people feel. And that is
Speaker 2:  why they talk about composable moderation. That's why Jay's go-to response
Speaker 2:  when you ask for about what does that mean is I have a custom feed that just
Speaker 2:  shows me moss, like kinds of moss that I like, like they're weirdos and
Speaker 2:  they're posters and I think that's why they attracted a bunch of weirdos
Speaker 2:  and posters. I think that's why they've leaned into being weirdos and
Speaker 2:  posters and like having that community there. I think that's why a culture
Speaker 2:  has been built like slowly in the way that cultures on platforms get built.
Speaker 2:  I don't know if any of it will be successful, but when you ask me like what's
Speaker 2:  the difference? It's, I just think about that quote. It's like, oh they're,
Speaker 2:  they they don't have taste and I mean that in a big way.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, no I I I agree with that in large ways. I think
Speaker 3:  the challenge there is like, do you know the 99 1 rule?
Speaker 3:  This is, I don't, I don't know where it came from, but it's now like a truism
Speaker 3:  of all sort of social posting play platforms
Speaker 3:  that 90% of people are the audience. Right? They never post, they
Speaker 3:  never do anything. They're just there to look. 9% of people
Speaker 3:  are kind of light interactors. They might post a little bit, they like things,
Speaker 3:  they reply to things, whatever, but they're, they're sort of around and
Speaker 3:  making their presence known. And then 1% of people do the vast majority of
Speaker 3:  the things that the other 99% of people are there for.
Speaker 3:  The problem I think we have right now is that Bluesky is doing a really good
Speaker 3:  job of appealing to that 1%. Like the the people
Speaker 3:  or maybe it's the 9%, I don't know, the people who like live to post
Speaker 3:  Love Bluesky and Bluesky is built for those people and it is fun
Speaker 3:  and it is exciting and the vibes are good and you wanna participate.
Speaker 3:  But that's, that is a small percentage of the thing. The 90% is who
Speaker 3:  Meta builds for better than any other company on planet Earth. Right.
Speaker 3:  Like that is what has made Instagram successful. It is what has made Facebook
Speaker 3:  successful. The meta builds platforms that you come to and do nothing
Speaker 3:  but you come to them over and over and over and over again. And so you look
Speaker 3:  at ads and so Meta makes a ton of money, but
Speaker 2:  That's why Meta has to go to weird algorithmic feeds where you open Instagram
Speaker 2:  and none of your friends are there anymore and it's just creators
Speaker 2:  bootlegging video clips of eighties movies. Right.
Speaker 3:  But so this is the thing, right? Can you, can you build a place that is both
Speaker 3:  fun to post and full of good stuff every time you open the app?
Speaker 3:  I'm honestly not sure that it is. And I think again, we go back to like the
Speaker 3:  magic of Twitter. Twitter at its peak did both of those things. You,
Speaker 3:  you could have a Twitter experience that felt like lively
Speaker 3:  and real time and interactive and exciting and you could also show up and
Speaker 3:  see what the rock was talking about. Like we, none of these things that we
Speaker 3:  have now do both of those things. None of them.
Speaker 2:  All right. Lemme point a few things out just because I know The, Vergecast
Speaker 2:  listeners are screaming in their cars right now weaving all over the road.
Speaker 2:  One, any criticism of Elon's handling of Twitter is not
Speaker 2:  praise for the previous administration. No. Who by and large did a bad job
Speaker 3:  Clown car goldmine. Right.
Speaker 2:  There's not
Speaker 3:  Agree more.
Speaker 2:  Two, they never made any money even though they had whatever
Speaker 2:  success you're describing and three, the service at its peak was like
Speaker 2:  300 some million users. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But it was the single most cable news was people reading tweets
Speaker 3:  like yeah. It, it just was like there, there, there was a
Speaker 3:  decade in our culture that was mediated by Twitter in a like very
Speaker 3:  real way that If you wanted to share information with a lot of people
Speaker 3:  no matter who you were a famous person, a government, a company,
Speaker 3:  you went on Twitter, you just did. And that it's still true because
Speaker 3:  the vestiges of that are still so powerful and
Speaker 3:  nothing coming up now looks like it has a chance to replace
Speaker 3:  that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I don't think it should. That's, I I'm just gonna keep coming back
Speaker 2:  to that. I think it would be better if we all owned our own distribution
Speaker 2:  or we built a distribution network that allowed people to come and go more
Speaker 2:  freely. That's what the web is until Google
Speaker 2:  search became this hegemon that sort of made the web look exactly how it's
Speaker 2:  gonna look like. That's the web, that's RSSI think we're on the cusp of doing
Speaker 2:  it. It's podcasts by and large that is,
Speaker 3:  We've made it this far and I haven't brought up Google reader yet and So
Speaker 3:  I won't.
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta, we gotta get off this now. It's,
Speaker 3:  Can I just read you some user numbers before we go? Yeah. I went and pulled
Speaker 3:  the user numbers for all of these platforms and I just found 'em fascinating
Speaker 3:  and I just want to read them all out loud because it's, it's useful context
Speaker 3:  for everything we've talked about. So Threads, as we mentioned,
Speaker 3:  as of October 30th when meta reported earnings has
Speaker 3:  275 million active users. What
Speaker 3:  that means is always hard to know how companies measure these things
Speaker 3:  as different across the board in all ways. But that's the number they reported
Speaker 3:  and they're getting a million signups a day. Bluesky
Speaker 3:  today, Wednesday as we're recording this passed 15 million total users
Speaker 3:  and I yesterday on Tuesday the 12th had
Speaker 3:  798,142 unique posters, which
Speaker 3:  is people who actually posted a thing, which I love as a metric and I think
Speaker 3:  everyone should do it and 990,464
Speaker 3:  unique Lakers. So that's a decent like balance of
Speaker 3:  who's here and who's doing stuff. Mastodon, this is the one that really
Speaker 3:  surprised me and why I wanted to do this has
Speaker 3:  9,034,753 total users as of
Speaker 3:  today.
Speaker 3:  886,711
Speaker 3:  activities. It's brutal. Like Mastodon and, and you go look
Speaker 3:  at this a a lot of this stuff comes from like open APIs that these things
Speaker 3:  have, they just ping every day. You can see how they go. Mastodon had that
Speaker 3:  big bump real momentum after the Twitter thing
Speaker 3:  happened with Elon Musk and it was it, it had a moment and it just
Speaker 3:  lost all of that momentum and it, it has settled back slightly higher than
Speaker 3:  it was before. It went from like a half a million active users every day
Speaker 3:  to 886,000 active users every day day. Which is not nothing but like
Speaker 3:  that's also not momentum two years later like Mastodon just kind of lost
Speaker 3:  it And I feel like right now we got a ton of people who are asking us like
Speaker 3:  oh where should I go? And I feel like the only two
Speaker 3:  answers I would even think about at this moment are Bluesky and Threads and
Speaker 3:  I would tell you like go to Bluesky is more fun and threads is
Speaker 3:  easier is I guess the place I'd land.
Speaker 2:  I don't even know if it's easier. The Bluesky app is the number one app in
Speaker 2:  the app store today mostly. 'cause speaking of cable news, Chris Hayes
Speaker 2:  brought it up on MSN BBC last night and said I really like Bluesky and they
Speaker 2:  had a bump. The Bluesky devs were pointing out that this made the line go
Speaker 2:  up. So it's the number one app in the store today. People are leaving.
Speaker 2:  The thing of Bluesky is that right now is it's self-contained. There isn't
Speaker 2:  another app protocol server. The everything it's of
Speaker 2:  Bluesky and I feel like the ma cell number is a little bit
Speaker 2:  confusing because all those people on masks it on have the ability to see
Speaker 2:  content from threats.
Speaker 3:  Right. True.
Speaker 2:  'cause that is the promise of federation. So it kind of doesn't matter if
Speaker 2:  that number stagnates as long as the threads number goes up because you are
Speaker 2:  still being able to follow Threads user depending on your mass on server.
Speaker 2:  And this is the complexity, it's all weird, right? But if your mass on server
Speaker 2:  inter operates with threads, as long as threads, numbers keep
Speaker 2:  going up, you have the ability to follow and interact with all those people
Speaker 2:  or you will over time. So there, there's some promise of
Speaker 2:  federation here that I think, excuse these numbers, but the one thing that
Speaker 2:  is clear is that a smaller number of
Speaker 2:  bad people are interacting in higher rates on Twitter. Yes. X
Speaker 2:  It's weird, it's a weird time but I, I think the shakeup is going to be good.
Speaker 2:  I think it is time to think about distribution on the internet in way different
Speaker 2:  ways, particularly as the creator platforms
Speaker 2:  just shove creators and influencers around and like start
Speaker 2:  adding. I opened my Instagram yesterday and it was like, do you wanna make
Speaker 2:  an AI of yourself to talk to your fans
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Kylie Robinson's here. Hi Kylie. Hello. Welcome to
Speaker 2:  the V House. Thanks. Have we been on the show together yet? No, I don't think
Speaker 2:  so. Well spooky. There was a reason.
Speaker 2:  I dunno, that's so rude.
Speaker 2:  You're here. We're gonna do a new segment. We're calling show and tell.
Speaker 2:  Are we actually calling it Show and tell David?
Speaker 3:  We're calling it that until someone calls their emails with a better name.
Speaker 3:  We've had very good luck in the past letting smarter people than us name
Speaker 3:  things for us. So please, If, you have a better idea. Call the hotline, send
Speaker 3:  us an email. Name this segment for us.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so here's what we're gonna do during the
Speaker 2:  presumptively named show and tell.
Speaker 2:  All of us are gonna bring one story to the table. We're gonna say what it
Speaker 2:  is and then we're gonna talk about, but it has to be good.
Speaker 2:  Oh God. So we're putting David on the spot first. Okay. David, what's your
Speaker 2:  story this week?
Speaker 3:  I feel like we have to talk about the Square iPad.
Speaker 3:  You mentioned it briefly at the top, but we, we this, this is
Speaker 3:  the only thing I can think about. So we have to talk about this now. So we've
Speaker 3:  been hearing rumors and reporting for a long time that Apple was
Speaker 3:  really interested in getting into the smart home. Mark Erman at Bloomberg,
Speaker 3:  who is better at reporting what Apple is going to do
Speaker 3:  than everybody. Had a big story this week about what
Speaker 3:  this thing is going to be. Apple is is essentially building a smart
Speaker 3:  home controller that is going to live inside of your house.
Speaker 3:  Can I just read you several sentences from this article? And I would like
Speaker 3:  you to tell me what device it sounds like I am describing
Speaker 2:  For a segment called Show and Tell. I feel like this is a little backwards
Speaker 2:  and that you're reading and then I'm describing what I think you've shown
Speaker 2:  me. But let's go ahead. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  It's it's a, it's a telling show. It's fine, don't worry about it.
Speaker 3:  Other people are gonna name this for us. So Mark Iman says it's about the
Speaker 3:  size of two iPhones, side by side with a thick edge around the display. There's
Speaker 3:  also a camera at the top front, a rechargeable built-in battery and internal
Speaker 3:  speakers. Apple plans to offer it in silver and black options. If you're
Speaker 3:  already thinking, gosh, I know what David is describing, I have more for
Speaker 3:  you. The product has a touch interface. The company
Speaker 3:  expects most people to use their voice to interact the device relying on
Speaker 3:  the Siri digital assistant and Apple Intelligence. It. The product
Speaker 3:  will be marketed as a way to control home appliances, chat with Siri and
Speaker 3:  hold intercom sessions with FaceTime. It will also be loaded with Apple apps,
Speaker 3:  including ones for web browsing, listening to news updates and playing music.
Speaker 3:  Users will be able to access their notes and calendar information and the
Speaker 3:  device can turn into a slideshow display for their photos. Do you know what
Speaker 3:  device I'm describing?
Speaker 2:  Is it a $329 iPad?
Speaker 3:  It's an iPad. Apple is going to make an iPad and they're going to
Speaker 3:  sell it to you to use in your house. Let me, let me read you the thing that
Speaker 3:  is actually new and is actually interesting. If, you just imagine an
Speaker 3:  iPad. Mark Kerman writes this in his story. He says, apple has designed different
Speaker 3:  attachments for the device, including ones that affix the screens onto walls
Speaker 3:  like a classic home security panel. There will be bases with additional speakers
Speaker 3:  that can be placed in the kitchen on a nightstand or on a desk. Apple imagines
Speaker 3:  the FaceTime feature being used while cooking or for video conferencing during
Speaker 3:  work meetings. A still just an iPad. It's
Speaker 3:  it, honestly, it sounds very much like the thing Apple is going to make is
Speaker 3:  a bad iPad that it wants to sell you lots of for your
Speaker 3:  house. B, an accessory ecosystem
Speaker 3:  of cool new things that you can add to your iPad just by docking it
Speaker 3:  on these different docs around your house is a kick ass idea that Apple should
Speaker 3:  totally do. Just not with a stupid six inch bad
Speaker 3:  iPad. I'm like losing my mind about this thing.
Speaker 2:  I just wanna say out loud, I've said this many times before, apple is horrible
Speaker 2:  accessory ecosystems actually. It's just a thing. It's just reality.
Speaker 2:  How many smart keyboard covers are there for the iPad today?
Speaker 3:  Oh, agree.
Speaker 2:  Zero.
Speaker 3:  Belkin has become like the official Apple accessory maker because Apple
Speaker 3:  either can't or won't do it itself. Well,
Speaker 2:  Balcony is owned by Foxcon. So you get the idea that every now and again
Speaker 2:  an Apple designer goes in the Foxcon factory and it's like, I have a number
Speaker 2:  of ideas.
Speaker 2:  There's, there's something real there I find, but
Speaker 2:  great and a third party ecosystem of like weird docs and adapters. Everybody
Speaker 2:  wants this to exist for every Apple product and I just don't,
Speaker 3:  Sure, but like I just, I have, I just have to keep reading. The newly designed
Speaker 3:  operating system will also include a customizable home screen.
Speaker 2:  Stop telling me about iPads
Speaker 3:  Where users can run widgets for checking stock, tickers the weather and appointments.
Speaker 3:  That's an iPad. Or they can configure the screen to highlight key home controls
Speaker 3:  iPad. There will also be a doc, hold on for quick, fully launching favorite
Speaker 3:  apps and an screen grid of software icons. It's an iPad.
Speaker 2:  I look in all fairness, they
Speaker 3:  Did iPad again.
Speaker 2:  Mark Bloomberg is a very traditional news organization and Kerman has to
Speaker 2:  hit a word count.
Speaker 3:  Also, none of this, this is all very good reporting from Kerman. The fact
Speaker 3:  that this is all, that's what I'm saying, this is very good reporting. It's
Speaker 3:  just Apple is just going to make an
Speaker 3:  iPad again and they're gonna try to sell it to you as a new thing because
Speaker 3:  it can dock on a speaker. Yeah, that's nothing. Make the
Speaker 3:  iPad
Speaker 2:  Better or they're, they're gonna, they're gonna cut down the, the interface
Speaker 2:  right. To make it more smart, homey, you're gonna let people talk to, you
Speaker 2:  know, the presumably smarter Siri. That's a thing that could happen
Speaker 3:  During development. Apple discussed launching an app store as part of the
Speaker 3:  device, but it recently decided to exclude this feature. At least in the
Speaker 3:  initial version. It's an iPad without the app store. So it's
Speaker 2:  Just worse. I'm just gonna point out that a couple weeks ago we had Joanna
Speaker 2:  Stern on the show and we talked about garage door openers for five hours.
Speaker 2:  And Apple's dreams of making a smart home product are gonna run head first
Speaker 2:  into the reality of smart home products. Yes. That's what's gonna happen.
Speaker 2:  Which is they're, it's impossible.
Speaker 2:  Fascinating. That's the whole answer. That
Speaker 3:  Really is the whole answer.
Speaker 2:  Very smart People get tripped up at whether the smart part of the
Speaker 2:  light bulb should be in the light bulb or the switch. And there are, there
Speaker 2:  are religious arguments for both. There are good reasons
Speaker 2:  to do In my own home, I have both. Yeah. I have smart light bulbs and I have
Speaker 2:  smart switches and no one, no one in my family that literally
Speaker 2:  I'm trying to illuminate knows why or how any of it works. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  so you put the thing on the wall and you're like, now your house is smart.
Speaker 2:  You end up having to tell a bunch of consumers
Speaker 2:  where a bunch of other computers in their houses have to go. Yeah. And that
Speaker 2:  just falls, it just falls flat immediately.
Speaker 6:  So would you guys not do this though? This is not something, 'cause I all,
Speaker 6:  I'm thinking as you say this is, don't hate the player, hate the game.
Speaker 6:  There's gonna be a dozen people in this office who buy this. It feels like
Speaker 6:  it's, it's just gonna happen.
Speaker 3:  Sure. But if you're Apple, you have this
Speaker 3:  tablet lineup that is very mature and
Speaker 3:  full of identity crises and what if instead you
Speaker 3:  just took the thing and said, now here's a doc that
Speaker 3:  makes it have an always on screen and thus you
Speaker 3:  can control all the things you can still control from your iPad. Like it's
Speaker 3:  just, it's such a tiny leap from an iPad
Speaker 3:  to this. I think the reason you don't do it if your Apple is because you
Speaker 3:  can sell a bad iPad a lot cheaper than you can sell a good iPad. Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  so they're gonna make a bad iPad and stick it to your wall. Fine.
Speaker 3:  That, that, there's also, Gerin has been reporting that the next version
Speaker 3:  of it is gonna have a robotic arm and cost a thousand dollars. Like sure
Speaker 3:  that's all fine and good, but I think there is, there is a really interesting
Speaker 3:  case to be made that you could turn an iPad, which is already, for most people,
Speaker 3:  kind of statistically speaking like a home bound device. It is a thing
Speaker 3:  that lives on your bedside table or on your couch or on your coffee table.
Speaker 3:  Like it's not as portable a thing as it, it
Speaker 3:  maybe is presumed to be in a lot of ways you could
Speaker 3:  just turn that up a little bit and turn it into something really
Speaker 3:  cool and powerful with this accessory ecosystem. But
Speaker 3:  instead Apple is going to reinvent the entire wheel in a way that just
Speaker 3:  feels ridiculous to me.
Speaker 2:  I'm excited for you to buy an iPad that you stick to your wall, David. Yep.
Speaker 2:  I think you're gonna love it. You're gonna love talking to Siri and be like,
Speaker 2:  Siri, do this automation and then Siri's not gonna work. And you're gonna
Speaker 2:  be like, what is the answer? Then you're gonna Google it and the answer for
Speaker 2:  some reason is gonna be restarting your iPhone, which is
Speaker 2:  100% the Apple Home story.
Speaker 3:  A big part of this feels like what you do when you
Speaker 3:  build all of this other AI stuff like the app
Speaker 3:  intent stuff that Apple is working on with Siri, this new Siri, all the Apple
Speaker 3:  intelligence stuff, and you go, Hmm, what does any of this actually useful
Speaker 3:  for? This is the same thing by the way that Google did with Google Assistant
Speaker 3:  and Amazon did with Alexa. And you realize, oh, it's just you can turn off
Speaker 3:  two sets of lights at once instead of one set of lights. And that that
Speaker 3:  Apple is, is running directly towards that and nowhere else.
Speaker 2:  I, I do wanna call it the number of listeners who responded
Speaker 2:  to our Jovanna conversation on garage door openers in which she said cred,
Speaker 2:  FEI uses Siri to open his garage door by pointing out that there is
Speaker 2:  0% chance that Craig Federighi has an Apple home
Speaker 2:  home and instead definitely has a custom Crestron home
Speaker 2:  automation system. Yeah. Oh agreed. The emails we got, they were like,
Speaker 2:  you all understand that there's a custom that this man has a Crestron
Speaker 2:  system. Anyhow, all right. You've shown,
Speaker 2:  you've told, do I do I give you a score
Speaker 2:  seven
Speaker 2:  Kylie,
Speaker 6:  I'm going for 7.7. I'm
Speaker 2:  Leaving now. Some meanest thing you've ever said to me. Jesus. It's a new
Speaker 2:  segment. We're figuring out how it works.
Speaker 2:  All right, Kylie, what do you have?
Speaker 6:  Oh my God. It's gonna be hard to top a bad
Speaker 2:  A seven iPad.
Speaker 6:  No bad iPad. Well now I'm talking about
Speaker 6:  scaling laws, which are really interesting.
Speaker 6:  Everyone's reporting this week that scaling laws are failing.
Speaker 6:  So what that is is just put more compute and
Speaker 6:  more data into an LLM and it will get bigger, better,
Speaker 6:  smarter. And everyone has the same training
Speaker 6:  data, which is the internet, the entire internet and all of our work.
Speaker 6:  So they have all that, they're all building sort of the same thing and they
Speaker 6:  are all finding Google open AI anthropic that it is not
Speaker 6:  working anymore. That they are not getting better than their last generation
Speaker 6:  of models and they're all pissing their pants about it. That's the story
Speaker 6:  this week. Yeah. I think this is, I keep thinking about
Speaker 6:  that tweet, which is like, you know, the haters said I couldn't do it and
Speaker 6:  they were right. Great call from the haters. I think all of the,
Speaker 6:  I think all, all of the AI skeptics are like, yeah, we told you
Speaker 6:  Yeah, we told you that this wasn't something you could scale infinitely.
Speaker 6:  So yeah, I don't think it's like doomsday, like it's over for ai, but still
Speaker 6:  it's, it's interesting that they're all sort of frustrated that they can't
Speaker 6:  make that giant neck leap and it costs so much money. So
Speaker 6:  if people, if they wanna release something that costs so much money for people
Speaker 6:  to use, it's gotta be way better and it's just not.
Speaker 2:  So the idea here is, okay, we made, I know GPT-4 Yeah. But training on the
Speaker 2:  entire internet, we'll get more data, which was always confusing to people
Speaker 2:  where the more data would come from Yes.
Speaker 6:  Synthetic data. So
Speaker 2:  So we'll make some fake AI data. Yes. We'll train an even bigger model and
Speaker 2:  that one will necessarily be smarter. Yes. And that just hasn't worked out
Speaker 6:  And it hasn't worked out. It does not appear that any of them are going to
Speaker 6:  be more capable than the last. So that means, you know, for
Speaker 6:  instance, I believe it was reported that oh one was helping train
Speaker 6:  the next generation of open AI's GBT models.
Speaker 6:  But that has become a problem because then, you know, it just gets
Speaker 6:  confused by synthetic data. It's not high quality data. So yeah,
Speaker 6:  they're all running into that same issue and
Speaker 6:  that means that there's gonna be ha there's gonna have to be some like research
Speaker 6:  breakthrough that gets them to that next step that they don't currently have.
Speaker 6:  And there's just tons of money riding on this for them to figure it out.
Speaker 6:  So, I, think they're all again pissing their pants over it
Speaker 2:  As one of the haters. I definitely feel like I should say I told you
Speaker 3:  So this so exposes to be something Kylie that you've been saying to us
Speaker 3:  and on The Vergecast for forever, which is there has been this
Speaker 3:  ongoing line from all of these AI companies that it's like, we're gonna do
Speaker 3:  a model and then we're gonna do another model and we're gonna do another
Speaker 3:  model and we're gonna do another model and then it's God. And it's like,
Speaker 3:  well what, what's, what is it gonna be on the way? And they're like, don't
Speaker 3:  worry about it. God, none of this shit matters. 'cause God,
Speaker 3:  we're gonna make God and then you're gonna feel dumb for not giving us money.
Speaker 3:  And what happens now is they're gonna get to the point where
Speaker 3:  they're like, okay, you've built this thing. It's actually very cool, it's
Speaker 3:  very capable, it can do lots of things. What's it for? What are people gonna
Speaker 3:  do with it? And all of these companies are like emails.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna write some bomb emails. Yes. And, and we're like, I
Speaker 3:  we are going to be stuck in this. What can you do with
Speaker 3:  this phase for a lot longer than any of these companies
Speaker 3:  would like you to believe?
Speaker 2:  Well there's that, but there's just also this week, right.
Speaker 2:  Dio Modi from Anthropic is telling Lex Friedman that we'll have a GI
Speaker 2:  in like two years. Yes. Sam Altman, I think in the past couple weeks has
Speaker 2:  said on current hardware we can have a GI, which by the way means
Speaker 2:  the tech industry should stop like If. you can make
Speaker 2:  current If, you can make God on NVIDIA's current hardware. We should,
Speaker 2:  we should stop. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. We did it. We're we're good. We did it, we're done.
Speaker 2:  Let God build the next version of the GPU. Like it'll be here
Speaker 2:  soon. Totally.
Speaker 3:  The God processing unit, that's
Speaker 2:  The
Speaker 2:  what If, you're like, if I just put enough H one hundreds in a room, I can
Speaker 2:  have God to like, we should, Nvidia should just slow the fuck down.
Speaker 2:  Sure. Right. And it that there's something very incompatible with
Speaker 2:  in two years we'll have a GII can build a GI and current hardware and
Speaker 2:  the bigger models we just trained aren't more capable than the previous models.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Is that what, what's going on?
Speaker 6:  I've been asked on Vergecast, or sorry, I think it was decoder. Should we
Speaker 6:  trust them? And I'm, I, I mean I as a journalist am just
Speaker 6:  very skeptical. So Dario's saying, you know, we're gonna
Speaker 6:  get, AGI i's gonna do all these beautiful things. And I mean they just have
Speaker 6:  to sell products at the end of the day. The Reddit a a
Speaker 6:  MA that Sam Altman did recently where he said, oh, it's really hard to release
Speaker 6:  these things in parallel. We have like such limited compute and it's hard
Speaker 6:  to work on all of these things. But the next big thing I think is gonna be
Speaker 6:  agents. It's just feels like they're pivoting. They're like, don't, don't
Speaker 6:  look at this. Don't look, don't look at this right here. We haven't figured
Speaker 6:  it out. Just don't think about agents on current hardware, current models.
Speaker 6:  Look at that. Please give us money. Don't look at how we are failing to
Speaker 6:  make the next big model. And I don't think we
Speaker 6:  need a next bigger model. I think we really enjoyed these companies, really
Speaker 6:  enjoyed making these huge leaps from model to model. And
Speaker 6:  if they're capable enough now of achieving some good emails,
Speaker 6:  then fine. They think that they can combine,
Speaker 6:  you know, the GBT series with the o reasoning series and perhaps get a
Speaker 6:  GI again, I think all of this is to sell more products and get
Speaker 6:  more money. That is always been my position. So yeah,
Speaker 6:  I mean,
Speaker 2:  I just wanna read you the quote from Daria, please. If, you believe the straight
Speaker 2:  line extrapolation. We'll have artificial general intelligence in
Speaker 2:  2026 or 2027.
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 2:  If line go up forever, I will make God,
Speaker 3:  Have you guys seen the tweet from the guy? I'm sorry, I don't remember who
Speaker 3:  it is. We'll we'll find it and put it in the show notes. Who was like, he
Speaker 3:  has two pictures of him with his newborn baby and then his baby who's now
Speaker 3:  three months old. Yes. And he's like, wild guys, my baby has doubled in weight
Speaker 3:  in three months at this rate by his 10th birthday he'll be
Speaker 3:  7 trillion pounds. I think about that every single time somebody talks
Speaker 3:  about one of these things, like it's, it's really, and people talk about
Speaker 3:  this stuff as if it is guaranteed. Like you look at Moore's law, right? And
Speaker 3:  this, this thing that has like governed technolo technological progress for
Speaker 3:  so long, we now take it as truth that everything that grows
Speaker 3:  grows the same way and forever and it just doesn't like, yeah. There
Speaker 3:  is no guarantee that any of this will work like that just because the way
Speaker 3:  we make semiconductors works like that. It's just not how it works.
Speaker 6:  Okay. To add to this too, you know how Sam Altman was going across the world
Speaker 6:  trying to get these trillion dollar data centers built somewhere. Someone
Speaker 6:  give me the money to build these data centers. So, I can power Digital, digital.
Speaker 6:  God, there was a story in the information today that
Speaker 6:  a competitor flew like a crop plane over X's
Speaker 6:  data center to figure out how he was cooling those chips because they're
Speaker 6:  so scared about liquid cooling and it's so confusing. And I thought that's
Speaker 6:  crazy that we're getting to a point where people are just flying, you know,
Speaker 6:  little planes over Elon's data center to figure out how
Speaker 6:  the fuck they can build digital God in the same way. It's just such a funny
Speaker 6:  thing.
Speaker 3:  The next Mission Impossible movie is just Tom Cruise breaking into a data
Speaker 3:  center to figure out how they power all this stuff.
Speaker 2:  I think that was the last mission impossible
Speaker 6:  David. What what,
Speaker 2:  What Underwater. Exactly. But it was that, oh
Speaker 2:  my God, they did that. All that's a
Speaker 6:  Furious in space man.
Speaker 2:  By the way, If, you look on, on all the streaming services, they've taken
Speaker 2:  part one off of that movie because it ends on such a garbage
Speaker 2:  cliffhanger. People are mad.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. They're like, nevermind, we're just doing a different one now.
Speaker 2:  This is a full movie.
Speaker 2:  I don't know man. All right, Kyle, you've shown, you've told Yes David, you,
Speaker 2:  I think you have to score this one, two and a half. Oh God,
Speaker 2:  that's
Speaker 3:  Outta three. To be clear.
Speaker 6:  Sorry. You're so jealous.
Speaker 3:  We didn't say what our scoring
Speaker 2:  Was. We actually didn't say that we were scoring.
Speaker 3:  Nila gave me a seven outta 10. I'm giving you a two and a half outta three.
Speaker 3:  Perfect. And then we'll see. Actually you get like the Netflix one thumb
Speaker 3:  up but not the two thumbs up. It's like a like it but not a love it kind
Speaker 3:  of thing. You know what I mean? Okay, I'll that, so that's your score.
Speaker 2:  Digital God, David, we can do it on current hardware. I
Speaker 2:  want to say this as directly as I can. If you believe we can build a GI and
Speaker 2:  current hardware, the tech industry should stop. We should just stop
Speaker 2:  doing everything and focus on that one goal so that digital
Speaker 2:  God can design the next iPhone. But I don't think that's true,
Speaker 2:  right? Like that, that claim just implies you should stop working
Speaker 2:  and let you know a GI do it for you. Please. I beg you
Speaker 2:  let a GI write about Donald Trump for the next four years. It'll be, it'll
Speaker 2:  everyone can take a break. All right, here's mine.
Speaker 2:  Just a series of words is so silly.
Speaker 2:  Just eat is selling GrubHub to wonder
Speaker 3:  What
Speaker 2:  None of those words make any sense. So GrubHub is, you know, is is the delivery
Speaker 2:  service, right? It's, it's like probably the one that you are most familiar
Speaker 2:  with it. They bought Seamless a while ago, so all it's all the same app.
Speaker 3:  That was such a New Yorker thing to say by the way. That was seamless.
Speaker 3:  GrubHub is the one is such a New York center isn't Grub say the one, what
Speaker 3:  is
Speaker 6:  None of these words were in the Bible. I
Speaker 3:  Dunno what's going on. Yeah. I dunno what's going on. All right. It's like
Speaker 3:  in LA it's just Postmates, but nowhere else. SF is,
Speaker 3:  I think probably still like a DoorDash town. DoorDash. Yeah. This is
Speaker 3:  like, this is like when you live in New York, it would like, oh, just seamless
Speaker 3:  it. And it's like, what? That's nothing. That doesn't, that's, that's not
Speaker 3:  a word
Speaker 2:  That for Chicago though. When we moved to New York from Chicago. Anyway,
Speaker 2:  it doesn't matter. They, these are all nonsense words and failing businesses
Speaker 2:  that are just selling each other in different configurations. Fair. What
Speaker 2:  I want to get to is they're selling it to a company called Wonder, which
Speaker 2:  is owned by a part owner of the Minnesota Timberwolves and a former Walmart
Speaker 2:  VP and Wonder's business model is bananas. Perfect.
Speaker 2:  They, he licenses recipes from famous chefs.
Speaker 2:  So you're like, yes. What so wonder is like a high end food
Speaker 2:  hall and it's a ghost kitchen with like famous
Speaker 2:  restaurants logos on the front. So you, you go in there and you're
Speaker 2:  like, here's all these like famous local restaurants or like
Speaker 2:  restaurants I've heard of that. Like celebrities go to
Speaker 2:  So Wonder licenses recipes from famous chefs. So you
Speaker 2:  open Wonder and there's Bobby flas steak, there's Street Bird by
Speaker 2:  Marcus Samuelson.
Speaker 2:  There is Detroit Brick Pizza, there's all this stuff
Speaker 2:  De Farro Pizza, which is like a famous New York pizza place in there. But
Speaker 2:  they don't actually make the food. They license the recipes and they have
Speaker 2:  one big commissary kitchen that like pre-make the food
Speaker 2:  so gross. And then it goes to the food hall where they with like
Speaker 2:  steam baths and microwaves, reheat the food and assemble it and then deliver
Speaker 2:  it to you or serve it in the food hall. So they have like
Speaker 2:  commoditize the famous chef's recipe at
Speaker 2:  industrial scale and now they're gonna buy GrubHub and they're
Speaker 2:  gonna bring that model to an even bigger delivery system and it's like, oh
Speaker 2:  this is wild. Wow. Like the reason that the chefs are famous
Speaker 2:  is 'cause you think Jose Andres is gonna make you the food. Yeah. And now
Speaker 2:  he's just licensed a recipes so someone else can steam bath the food to you
Speaker 2:  and send it to you.
Speaker 6:  And we don't know how much they're making off these licenses. Yeah. That
Speaker 6:  hasn't leaked. Wow.
Speaker 2:  And it's all, it also just be clear some, it's very expensive because it's
Speaker 2:  famous chefs. So you're buying,
Speaker 6:  But it's not famous chefs.
Speaker 3:  This is like a knockoff version of eating dinner in a Vegas
Speaker 3:  casino, right. Where it's like a bunch of restaurants
Speaker 3:  that all claim to be, you know, run by famous
Speaker 3:  people, but it just has their name on it. It's like getting, this
Speaker 3:  is the equivalent of getting room service from a Bobby Flay restaurant in
Speaker 3:  a Vegas casino. Well,
Speaker 6:  Gordon Ramsey Burger is delicious. Let's be clear. Look,
Speaker 3:  I'm sure some of this stuff is good. It's just, it also isn't the point of
Speaker 3:  going to Gordon Ramsey Burger
Speaker 3:  places the like vibe like getting take out Gordon
Speaker 3:  Ramsey seems
Speaker 2:  Just wrong.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, no, that's gross.
Speaker 2:  Well, I mean, you want to be screamed at in the Face by Gordon Ramsey. Exactly.
Speaker 2:  To some extent the Vegas version of the chain restaurants like the
Speaker 2:  Vegas carbon some people think is the best carbon. 'cause it
Speaker 2:  just like moves the most business and there's the most dumb money flowing
Speaker 2:  through it. Sure. Fine. This is very much like we're
Speaker 2:  gonna half make the famous pizza, send it to a food hall
Speaker 2:  and then a steam oven. We'll finish the famous pizza. Right. And then we
Speaker 2:  will put that on GrubHub and you know, it's just like, oh, this is the end
Speaker 2:  point of a very particular business model that
Speaker 2:  started with Cloud kitchens, right. Where you like open the delivery
Speaker 2:  app, right. And it's actually Chuck E Cheese. And then people are
Speaker 2:  like, what If, you didn't even have the Chuck E Cheese. And they're like,
Speaker 2:  but then you still, you can't just have like wings.com or
Speaker 2:  whatever was in the, so now you need Bobby Flas name next to it and you're
Speaker 2:  just kinda like, oh this is this, this circle is getting real weird.
Speaker 3:  It's almost like, but it's all of that. But it ends at like a, a Golden Corral
Speaker 3:  Buffet is essentially the end point of this whole system.
Speaker 2:  Donald Trump's America. Every restaurant is Carbone.
Speaker 6:  Have you seen people joking about how they don't want DoorDash coming in
Speaker 6:  like a Nissan Ultima? They want it in an uber black like this Is that same,
Speaker 6:  that same thing. Are you
Speaker 3:  Serious?
Speaker 6:  It's just like, it's like sending an uber black to a, a commissary
Speaker 6:  to get your food. Like what is the point anymore? Yeah. I feel like we've
Speaker 6:  just reached a new level of consumerism that is absolutely absurd. And I'm
Speaker 6:  pure,
Speaker 2:  That's not absurd enough yet.
Speaker 3:  I would like every part of this process to feel fancy but actually not be
Speaker 3:  fancy at all.
Speaker 6:  Right, exactly.
Speaker 3:  I wanna think it's expensive even though it's, it sucks.
Speaker 2:  I just like the idea that you would order any steak from a delivery app has
Speaker 2:  always seemed odd to me. Like it's just, that's not
Speaker 2:  right. That's not a great environment for a state to be in. Like in the back
Speaker 2:  of a Nissan Altima for a while.
Speaker 3:  They feel the same way about delivery sushi. Like not about it.
Speaker 6:  Sorry, I can't relate.
Speaker 2:  Do you know why Meryl Streep was angry in the Devil Wars Prada? 'cause she
Speaker 2:  was having delivery steak for lunch every day. Such a good point.
Speaker 2:  All right. That's it. I've, I've shown, I've told what what do you got? Wait,
Speaker 3:  Can I, can I add one more thing to this? Yeah. So four years ago
Speaker 3:  when there was some other stuff going on in the world, just Eat,
Speaker 3:  which was then called Just Eat Takeaway 'cause Sure.
Speaker 3:  Bought GrubHub for $7.3 billion
Speaker 3:  and is now selling it to Wonder for $650 million. Wow.
Speaker 3:  I don't know enough about this world to like really process
Speaker 3:  why that is, but that is a giant loss in four years.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I don't remember the last time I used GrubHub. Maybe 2020.
Speaker 3:  I mean, it might have been
Speaker 6:  So makes sense to me.
Speaker 3:  Well, and just Eat Takeaway was for a minute they were like, it just, it
Speaker 3:  was called Just Eat Takeaway because that was the combination of two businesses
Speaker 3:  and it was supposed to be the like giant delivery
Speaker 3:  conglomerate that was going to eat everything. And that just has not
Speaker 3:  panned out for anybody.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean the margins can't be good. Right. I know nothing about this
Speaker 6:  world, but it's,
Speaker 2:  I'm I'm guessing the margins on selling microwave Gordon Ramsey
Speaker 2:  is, I don't think it's true. Well that's,
Speaker 6:  That's probably better than,
Speaker 2:  I mean, not say Gordon Ramsey name. I'm sure that margin than selling microwave
Speaker 2:  Bobby Fla is like very good.
Speaker 6:  That's probably a better business idea than
Speaker 6:  people enslaved to McDonald's on motorcycles.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Well, and all of these companies have said for years in like Uber
Speaker 3:  and DoorDash among them that shipping food and stuff is a
Speaker 3:  much higher margin business around a city than people.
Speaker 3:  Right? Mm. Giving humans rides is not nearly as good a business
Speaker 3:  as moving stake around for a huge profit.
Speaker 3:  So like, you can see it, I, there was just gonna be this time when
Speaker 3:  all of these companies were competing and whoever won was gonna be a giant
Speaker 3:  and it was gonna be epic and they were gonna be the biggest company in the
Speaker 3:  world. And what actually seems to have happened is it's a bunch of like
Speaker 3:  reasonably successful but fairly low margin businesses. Yeah. That
Speaker 3:  worked well in some places and not in others.
Speaker 2:  The VC dollars were not able to buy monopolies and then raise the prices,
Speaker 2:  which is the business model for in particular Uber for a long time. Yep.
Speaker 2:  But look, again, this the words I'm using just Eat has sold
Speaker 2:  GrubHub to wonder is a sentence that you now understand.
Speaker 6:  I don't wanna understand it. I wanna go back.
Speaker 2:  Give me a score.
Speaker 6:  Three Michelin stars. Very
Speaker 2:  Good.
Speaker 3:  Wow.
Speaker 2:  That means I'm now a raging asshole and I can't be stopped.
Speaker 2:  I'm a made man.
Speaker 6:  No, I'm gonna put you in the ring with Bobby play and then we'll figure it
Speaker 6:  out from there. It's all over.
Speaker 3:  Yes, chef.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  We gotta stop. That's it. That was show and tell. We have to take a break.
Speaker 2:  Thank you Kylie. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  We're back with the lightning round. I have news,
Speaker 2:  it's not today, but I'm told the lightning round is sponsored. It's very
Speaker 2:  exciting. Big money.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna be doing this podcast from a yacht starting sometime soon.
Speaker 2:  It was sponsored by a boat show. If. you run a boat show and
Speaker 2:  you'd like to sponsor the wedding round, please let me know.
Speaker 2:  Talk about a sponsor integration, which we are ethically not allowed to do.
Speaker 2:  I have
Speaker 3:  Been trying to come up with a reason to go to the
Speaker 3:  Monaco Yacht Show for journalism for approximately my entire journalism
Speaker 3:  career. That is my, I've always said that the main thing I wanna do is figure
Speaker 3:  out a reason to expense drugs, figure out a journalistically
Speaker 3:  real reason to go to the Monaco Yacht Show is now number one on my list.
Speaker 3:  You've
Speaker 2:  Mellowed in your old age.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I just wanna be on a boat now. I I'm just sober on a
Speaker 3:  boat. Seems great.
Speaker 2:  It's very good. All right. Lightning round.
Speaker 2:  What do you think? We,
Speaker 3:  I you, you have selected three things, In the lightning round, which is the
Speaker 3:  least lightning round thing I could imagine. So why don't you go first, Cindy,
Speaker 3:  do one.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so my first one, which I just wanna talk about very quickly is something
Speaker 2:  a bunch of people have asked me about this week and it's ethics and
Speaker 2:  disclosure. So talk about this for as much as anybody wants me to talk about
Speaker 2:  it and we'll move on to more fun lightning round ones. But
Speaker 2:  this week Mark has, Brownley made a video as a sponsored video. And the video,
Speaker 2:  he is speeding his car. People got all mad about it. We wrote about it because
Speaker 2:  Marquez is a huge character in tech. We write about other creators all the
Speaker 2:  time. We think our audience wants to know and keep up with the things. So
Speaker 2:  we wrote about it. Here's what's happening, If, you read the story, it's
Speaker 2:  pretty straight. It's on the website. Here's some stuff that happened. Here's
Speaker 2:  the coverage of it. Marquez, we wrote about his wallpaper app recently too.
Speaker 2:  There's whatever controversy, I don't wanna dwell on the video or what happened
Speaker 2:  in the video or any of that stuff. What people are asking about is that I
Speaker 2:  think it's, it's waveform, right? Mark's podcast at the end of it, or at
Speaker 2:  the beginning of it, they say this is part of the V Media podcast network.
Speaker 2:  And so people are asking, do we need to disclose this? Should
Speaker 2:  we disclose this in the story? Should we talk about it? Now as I think for
Speaker 2:  listeners know, I got no problems with disclosures, disclosures all night
Speaker 2:  and all day. I think we should be as transparent as possible about potential
Speaker 2:  sources of conflicts. I think we should earn people's trust as just
Speaker 2:  transparently as we can. We talk about the, the making of journalism
Speaker 2:  more than any other traditional journalists that I can think of. We
Speaker 2:  certainly do more disclosures than any traditional media or any influencers
Speaker 2:  do all the time. I have literally no problem with this. I'm happy to disclose
Speaker 2:  it. The thing that we're running into right now is like when and why do we
Speaker 2:  disclose things? And so in this case,
Speaker 2:  the Vox Media Podcast network is an ad sales network,
Speaker 2:  right? If, you are If, you start a podcast and you just like go onto YouTube
Speaker 2:  or you go onto Spotify's platform or whatever. You're kind of, unless you
Speaker 2:  have big scale, you're kind of stuck with programmatic advertising. Whatever
Speaker 2:  the platforms will give to you. And If, you want better advertising, you
Speaker 2:  want more money, you need scale. So you join a podcast network that has a
Speaker 2:  lot of inventory across a lot of shows, and then our sellers go out and sell
Speaker 2:  that inventory and then you make more money or whatever. I actually dunno
Speaker 2:  because that's the other side of the house, right? So the conflict here
Speaker 2:  doesn't exist. Like our sales team is selling
Speaker 2:  ads, which they do on our own website that we don't know about, that they
Speaker 2:  do on the show, right? That we basically dunno about. As many of
Speaker 2:  you have heard, sometimes we just run the same ad 500 times, right? Like
Speaker 2:  there's a wall between us and sales and we are very, very, very
Speaker 2:  protective of that wall. We, our coverage often loses
Speaker 2:  them money because various companies are mad at our coverage and they
Speaker 2:  walk away with deals. I've co I've personally cost this company a bunch of
Speaker 2:  money. But that's the whole point of the wall, right? Is to keep
Speaker 2:  our newsroom away from any of those considerations so that we
Speaker 2:  can just write about what's happening and have editorial independence and
Speaker 2:  freedom and we can If you. It's like the first line of our ethics policy
Speaker 2:  is like, is the editorial independence that allows us to cover
Speaker 2:  companies critically without fear of favor or whatever. That's the thing
Speaker 2:  that's the most important. That's the truly the heart of this whole operation
Speaker 2:  is the independence. So what we disclose
Speaker 2:  is where there's a plausible connection to some conflict
Speaker 2:  in our newsroom. So Comcast, NBC Universal is
Speaker 2:  an investor in our company. They're on our board of directors. They
Speaker 2:  can want to fire me, right? They can. They don't like
Speaker 2:  me a lot. They might. Yeah, they right. Like they can have a board
Speaker 2:  meeting and say we should fire this guy. That is a plausible in
Speaker 2:  imposition on our newsroom. It has never happened. You know, we've,
Speaker 2:  we've been running this thing for 13 years, but that's plausible. I think
Speaker 2:  you can, you can fairly look at our company and say they're at the top of
Speaker 2:  it. The Verge is talking about Comcast. Maybe they'll get, get him fired
Speaker 2:  maybe shit in the coverage. Fine. So we disclose it. I made a Netflix
Speaker 2:  show.
Speaker 2:  That's just like an open conflict of interest, right? Like every time I talk
Speaker 2:  about Netflix, I should point out that I made a Netflix show. I didn't get
Speaker 2:  paid for it 'cause the company made it, but you know, whatever. I still made
Speaker 2:  the show
Speaker 2:  great. Like I I think that's fine. That's a totally rational conflict of
Speaker 2:  interest. There's a plausible connection to the thing and the the conflict.
Speaker 2:  There's a million of these. We disclose them all the time.
Speaker 2:  This one, there isn't a plausible conflict. The actually more plausible
Speaker 2:  conflict is that David and I know most of the people on Waveform and we like
Speaker 2:  them. Yeah, So I will disclose to you. I've known Marquez for a long
Speaker 2:  time. David has known Marquez for a long time. We know a bunch of the folks
Speaker 2:  over there. We're friendly with them. We generally wish them success when
Speaker 2:  we cover them. I think we do it as straight as we can, but the actual business
Speaker 2:  conflict it, it's not there. And if I, and if we open the door to
Speaker 2:  disclosing what our sales side is doing, I think we actually threaten our
Speaker 2:  editorial independence because then I have to tell the newsroom every
Speaker 2:  single thing they have to disclose, right? And I have to make the newsroom
Speaker 2:  aware of all of the company's commercial and corporate
Speaker 2:  interactions in a way that I actually don't want them to know. That's the
Speaker 2:  whole purpose of the wall is that they're just gonna do their jobs. So
Speaker 2:  there's, there's a line here. And I'm not saying we always get it a hundred
Speaker 2:  percent right? But in this case that I know what that
Speaker 2:  arrangement is. Like I know what the Box media podcast network is.
Speaker 2:  We have a bunch of these deals like all of Scott Galloway's, prof g shows.
Speaker 2:  We don't own them, we don't make them, but they're in the network. We sell
Speaker 2:  the ads. There are other ones as well. There's all kinds of arrangements.
Speaker 2:  We'll disclose the ones where it's our company. But in this case it's, it's
Speaker 2:  just a little too removed from our newsroom in the same way that we
Speaker 2:  run a programmatic ad tech stack called concert that is on tons of
Speaker 2:  publishers. Every time you see a concert logo on a web ad that's, Vox
Speaker 2:  Media is serving that one. and we, we just cannot disclose
Speaker 2:  every partner that concert. It would, it would bring our newsroom to a halt.
Speaker 2:  And and more importantly, it would force me
Speaker 2:  to make every reporter in the newsroom aware
Speaker 2:  of the company's business deals. Which is the most important thing, right?
Speaker 3:  That's the key, right? Like the, the not knowing on that side
Speaker 3:  is, is important, right? Like there, there is a thing, we talk about
Speaker 3:  this with creators and stuff all the time, that one of the challenges is
Speaker 3:  knowing what something you do will do to your
Speaker 3:  business. And because of who is advertising and who wants to sponsor your
Speaker 3:  videos and all this stuff, that is a thing you have to reckon with. And a
Speaker 3:  big part of what we're trying to do is not even give people the
Speaker 3:  chance to think about that because it just, it just changes things.
Speaker 2:  And I firmly believe that this is getting confusing and muddled and most
Speaker 2:  people do not understand this. Yep. And that's on us. We have to constantly
Speaker 2:  explain it, which is why I'm happy to talk about it whenever anyone asks.
Speaker 2:  That is not how most of the media that most people consume works anymore.
Speaker 2:  Most creators, influencers have absolutely blurred the lines between
Speaker 2:  advertising, between sales. They have investments, their commercial relationships
Speaker 2:  are in the front of their content. I'm not even calling out any creator.
Speaker 2:  This is the reality of the business on those platforms. If, you wanna make
Speaker 2:  enough money to eat, this is how you have to play the game. Yep. But that's
Speaker 2:  not us, right? Like, it just isn't us. And so I'm happy to disclose everything.
Speaker 2:  I'm happy to talk about it. I just, there are times when I'm be like, no,
Speaker 2:  that one doesn't make any sense. And what I'm really talking about is if
Speaker 2:  I extend the rule that much, we're actually gonna
Speaker 2:  defeat the purpose of the rule, right? We're gonna defeat the independence
Speaker 2:  of the newsroom in a way that I, that's, that is the
Speaker 2:  product we sell here is the independence of the newsroom. Lemme just, I'll
Speaker 2:  give you this example. Every, we disclose Comcast n BBC all the time. 'cause
Speaker 2:  everybody knows about it. There are other investors in our company, they're
Speaker 2:  there. And if I extend the rules so far, like I kind of end up in a
Speaker 2:  place where every single morning I'm just telling the newsroom
Speaker 2:  who they should be worried about. Right?
Speaker 3:  Here's, here's a list of problems.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Here's a list of considerations for every story. And it like, I I,
Speaker 2:  I really think that undercuts the promise of what we do here. So
Speaker 2:  like I said, we'll take the feedback, I'll talk about it whenever we want.
Speaker 2:  In this case, I don't, there's not a plausible connection to the
Speaker 2:  company's commercial activities in our news room there. I I just assure you
Speaker 2:  that there isn't one to the point where until people mentioned it to us,
Speaker 2:  I hadn't even thought about it. And so, we'll, we'll keep, we'll we're gonna
Speaker 2:  keep doing disclosures. My ask of you, If, you want to yell at me about this?
Speaker 2:  Take 20% of the energy and point it
Speaker 2:  at other media outlets and other creators and influencers because
Speaker 2:  I would rather be in a world where the audience is that demanding of everyone.
Speaker 2:  And I'll do my best to live up to it because that's the thing that's gonna
Speaker 2:  rebuild trust in whatever kind of journalism exists in that
Speaker 2:  we do it. So we get it a lot. Right? It's an expectation that we have created
Speaker 2:  with all of you. And I'm happy about that. We receive the expectation,
Speaker 2:  but If, you think we're failing? Take just 20% of the energy and
Speaker 2:  point at everybody else. Like it'll make everything a little bit better.
Speaker 2:  All right. David, what's your last name? Round item.
Speaker 3:  Mine's gonna be much quicker because I really don't wanna talk about it.
Speaker 3:  Like we went from something that we like talking about too. I don't under
Speaker 3:  any circumstances want to talk about this, but we have to. And it is
Speaker 3:  that President-elect, Donald Trump has said that Elon
Speaker 3:  Musk is going to be leading a thing called the Department of Government
Speaker 3:  Efficiency that is going to do some stuff, cut
Speaker 3:  wasteful government spending. There's apparently gonna be a leaderboard on
Speaker 3:  X of all the dumbest ways the government spends money.
Speaker 3:  The, the only reason I wanna talk about this is because I think if, if I
Speaker 3:  have a, if I have a bit on this show, it is the question. Is this
Speaker 3:  anything? It's the meme of a person holding a, like their hand at a butterfly
Speaker 3:  and going, is this anything? This is nothing. This
Speaker 2:  Is nothing. Can I just say it's it, it was announced and it's announced that
Speaker 2:  it's Elon and Vivek Ramaswamy are gonna run it. And it's amazing that the
Speaker 2:  efficiency department has two leaders, leaders like
Speaker 2:  you're just coming out the gate with co-CEOs like Blackberry style. Perfect.
Speaker 2:  Like what are we doing?
Speaker 3:  What could possibly go wrong?
Speaker 2:  That's very good. You can't
Speaker 3:  Just do a department. You can't just do it
Speaker 2:  Like in life. I
Speaker 3:  Declare department is not a thing the president can do.
Speaker 2:  Oh, you mean like in the government? Yeah. You
Speaker 3:  And I could make a department of I just, the Department
Speaker 3:  of David's pillows like that exists. I did it. We're here.
Speaker 2:  I feel like your wife might have
Speaker 3:  Something to say.
Speaker 2:  This
Speaker 3:  Department, I'm the president. I did it.
Speaker 2:  It's my weird pillow room.
Speaker 3:  But the the, the government cannot just create a department
Speaker 3:  out of thin air because someone says, so that's not how this works. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna say what? Yeah. Do you need an act of Congress? Yeah. Is the thing.
Speaker 2:  So whatever. The only other thing I'll add to this, because this is gonna
Speaker 2:  be fake when we're gonna have to talk about it. And this is pure by the way,
Speaker 2:  decoder debate and we'll definitely talk about under decoder, can you make
Speaker 2:  a fake department in the government also, by the way, leader leaderboards
Speaker 2:  of wasteful government spending, they've been doing that shit since the eighties.
Speaker 2:  Like
Speaker 2:  some of the, these ideas we're we're just inventing trains again, like the
Speaker 2:  classic Elon Musk. Yeah. Anyway, all this is to say, there was a New York
Speaker 2:  Mag article today about the scene at Mar-a-Lago and just like the frenzy
Speaker 2:  of corruption that is happening there. And every time Elon Musk walks into
Speaker 2:  dinner, Donald Trump pulls out his iPad and plays Space Oddity by David Bowie.
Speaker 3:  Oh, I don't like that at all.
Speaker 2:  I feel like David Bowie very mad, but I also think it's very funny they pick
Speaker 2:  space side.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's like not exactly the compliment. You might think it is,
Speaker 2:  It's not.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But that's enough. We've talked about that enough. What's your next
Speaker 3:  episode, NELI.
Speaker 2:  Welcome. Come back to it around. All right. I want to check in on our nation's
Speaker 2:  fourth wireless carrier, which you will recall is a product
Speaker 2:  of Trump won when T-Mobile wanted to buy Sprint.
Speaker 2:  And instead of saying no, which is the exact process
Speaker 2:  by which T-Mobile was created, If you recall at t wanted to buy
Speaker 2:  T-Mobile. The government said no. And then T-Mobile had to go out. They took
Speaker 2:  a bunch of money and the breakup fee and, but then they became T-Mobile.
Speaker 2:  Right? They hired a new CEO, they did business. They're like, we're gonna
Speaker 2:  try hard. Yeah, we didn't do that with Sprint. The court
Speaker 2:  literally said Sprint sucks so much, no one can fix it. T-Mobile can have
Speaker 2:  it. And to get around this problem, Macon de was the head of
Speaker 2:  antitrust at the time, brokered personally a deal by which
Speaker 2:  T-Mobile would get a bunch of Sprint and a bunch of Sprint Spectrum
Speaker 2:  would go to Dish Network, America's favorite satellite
Speaker 2:  TV service. And they would create a fourth wireless network, which
Speaker 2:  it has been 1 billion years. And which does not meaningfully
Speaker 2:  exist. There was a pilot network called Project Genis, which offered people
Speaker 2:  NFTs if they signed up for service on the Motorola Edge.
Speaker 2:  So that didn't work. Mostly there's been an NVNO, so they resell at
Speaker 2:  and t and T-Mobile service CL historically
Speaker 2:  successful plan to compete with at and t and T-Mobile. It's just
Speaker 2:  buying their service and reselling it for a fee that really hasn't
Speaker 2:  quaked in their boots. They have lit up some towers in some
Speaker 2:  cities. They've decided they're gonna let go of all the Gen five system stuff.
Speaker 2:  They're just gonna call it Boost Mobile, which is a brand that they acquired
Speaker 2:  in the thing. And now they say, they say
Speaker 2:  they have earned the title of mobile network operator.
Speaker 2:  That's their announcement
Speaker 3:  Con congrats
Speaker 2:  Rather than MVNO, which is mobile virtual network operator, which is what
Speaker 2:  you have to call yourself when you're just reselling other people's service.
Speaker 2:  They have earned the title
Speaker 2:  of mobile network operator, they're a real network now
Speaker 2:  by the end of the year needs to reach 80% of the people. They said, we are
Speaker 2:  well on the way to meeting this goal, they have lit up more than 20,000 of
Speaker 2:  the 24,000 cell sites. That's plum deployed by June, 2025.
Speaker 2:  But has anybody seen it?
Speaker 3:  Has anybody
Speaker 2:  Running
Speaker 3:  Ads? Yeah. Like do you have, do you have any friends who are on Boost?
Speaker 3:  Like has that,
Speaker 2:  I mean, people have friends who are on Boost, but they're just reusing at
Speaker 2:  t service. You go on the subreddits of Genesis or
Speaker 2:  Boost, it's not pretty. And in the meantime, by the
Speaker 2:  way, all, all the other three carriers, all they've done is raise their prices.
Speaker 3:  Yep. Yeah. I, all of the stuff that
Speaker 2:  Not meaningful competition in this market, all the
Speaker 3:  Stuff that I saw on Project Janis are basically like, if I stand right here,
Speaker 3:  I get the carrier that I think that I have. And if I'm literally
Speaker 3:  anywhere else on planet Earth, it's just at t like,
Speaker 3:  great, you just got like a slightly worse at t phone.
Speaker 3:  Congratulations.
Speaker 2:  It's a Motorola edge. You're killing it. We'll see,
Speaker 2:  you know, as as always, something will
Speaker 2:  happen. Time will relentlessly go by.
Speaker 3:  I mean, and you, you mentioned T-Mobile, but it is, it, it is possible to
Speaker 3:  do interesting things in this space. Like there, there, there was a time
Speaker 3:  when T-Mobile did the whole un-carrier bit and everything got purple and
Speaker 3:  John Lager was running around doing crazy stuff. Like there are
Speaker 3:  interesting moves you can make in this market. And there haven't been any
Speaker 3:  in a very long time.
Speaker 2:  Nope.
Speaker 3:  And I, I think it's, it's like I, I am hopeful for Boost
Speaker 3:  I would say I have precisely zero actual expectations of this
Speaker 3:  going anywhere.
Speaker 2:  And I will just point out that all they had to do was not let
Speaker 2:  T-Mobile buy Sprint. And so they brokered this complicated deal.
Speaker 2:  Why is T-Mobile cheaper?
Speaker 2:  Certainly isn't so, and by the way, T-Mobile promised that it wouldn't cut
Speaker 2:  any jobs immediately cut thousands of jobs. Yeah. We're just, we're entering
Speaker 2:  a period now where there, there will be more mergers. The Lena Con era
Speaker 2:  is, is over. Right. All that's gonna get turned over
Speaker 2:  already streaming. Like David Avv is like mergers are back. Yeah. Like
Speaker 2:  the net neutrality is gonna go away.
Speaker 2:  You can just see the, hey, should Verizon buy Paramount and bundle it
Speaker 2:  into its service? And throttle Disney is like, there's
Speaker 2:  accountants that just, just on their boats just staring off into
Speaker 2:  the sunset, dreaming up ways to raise prices and it's not gonna
Speaker 2:  result in faster service or more reliable service. No. Almost a guarantee.
Speaker 2:  You wanna know what the rich cast is gonna be about in the next four years.
Speaker 2:  It's just me ranting about cell carriers. Oh,
Speaker 3:  So the same as always. That's good. It's nice to know that some things don't
Speaker 3:  change. Even do these trying times
Speaker 2:  Three Michelin stars.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, exactly. All
Speaker 2:  Right, one more then we get to go.
Speaker 3:  All right. I just very briefly wanna pour one out for everyone's 11th
Speaker 3:  favorite streaming service freebie, which was
Speaker 3:  I believe once called IMDB free dive
Speaker 3:  I think. And then it was IMDB TV and then it was
Speaker 3:  free V and now it is dying and just everything is being
Speaker 3:  bundled into Prime video. This is not
Speaker 3:  going to be sad for very many people. I don't think free V was actually like
Speaker 3:  a sneakily pretty good, pretty light app. So I'm sad to not
Speaker 3:  be able to use it anymore.
Speaker 2:  Doesn't they do jury duty? They
Speaker 3:  Did do jury duty, which was wonderful. And I actually think jury duty
Speaker 3:  is sort of funny because there's all these, we've talked a lot about the
Speaker 3:  fast channels and the, the sort of rise of ad supported streaming and
Speaker 3:  jury duty is kind of the only giant
Speaker 3:  breakout hit to ever come out of one of these services. Like
Speaker 3:  you look at the, the Roku channels had a few, they had the, the weird Al
Speaker 3:  Yankovic movie that was like kind of around Tuby is
Speaker 3:  doing stuff. Pluto is doing stuff like this. This Fast universe is growing
Speaker 3:  really quickly, but the huge sort of
Speaker 3:  mainstream content has not really happened. And I think If, you look at
Speaker 3:  Amazon, Amazon is all in on ads. And I think this is the thing that
Speaker 3:  is really starting to happen is the ad business in streaming is
Speaker 3:  turning really fast now. Netflix is now two years
Speaker 3:  into it and it's growing pretty quickly. Hulu is doing really well.
Speaker 3:  And so Disney and ESPN is starting to catch up. Like the ad
Speaker 3:  supported streaming universe is here
Speaker 3:  in a big way. And I think Amazon was it earlier this year turned
Speaker 3:  on the thing where now it's ads by default unless you pay more. And
Speaker 3:  now it's bringing all this free stuff in to give people more stuff to watch
Speaker 3:  with those ads inside a prime video. Like this is the future
Speaker 3:  and we're gonna go back to big giant libraries. Mostly stuff you
Speaker 3:  don't wanna watch because they're just trying to turn