# Transcript
ID: 0a8b78e0-0768-4b57-9668-3d87a00d5ae4
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4278979350547449205/-5312822758268822536/s93290-US-7007s-1732491738.mp3
Description: The Verge's Lauren Feiner joins Nilay and David to talk about the US government's proposal in its search antitrust case against Google. They discuss the future of Chrome, what a white-label search engine might look like, and how a Trump administration might change the course of this case altogether. Then Nilay and David talk about the week in AI and gadget news, from the latest on Amazon's new Alexa to Google bailing on tablets all over again. Finally, in the lightning round, they discuss Comcast spinning off its cable channels and the latest in the Threads / Bluesky competition.
Speaker 4:  any of them. It seems like a likely outcome here. I mean,
Speaker 4:  friend Neil I, David Pierce is here. The
Speaker 2:  Browser wars are just the end of web browsers. So I. Love
Speaker 2:  this. This is great.
Speaker 4:  What have we done? Yeah, Lauren finer ISS here. Hey Lauren. Hey,
Speaker 4:  there is a lot of news, A lot of what I would call Lauren finer news
Speaker 4:  this week,
Speaker 2:  Unfortunately for Lauren Finer every week is that,
Speaker 4:  Especially lately, the DOJ has put forth its proposal
Speaker 4:  for what to do about Google antitrust in search, which involves
Speaker 4:  potentially selling Chrome. Google has reacted to this. There are more
Speaker 4:  antitrust lawsuits Apple is trying to get out of, out of its antitrust lawsuit.
Speaker 4:  There's a bunch of AI chaos or some gadgets. We got a lightning round.
Speaker 4:  I want you to hear the excitement in my voice about the lightning round.
Speaker 4:  You know, it's coming, it's, it's, it's gonna be good.
Speaker 2:  I also have some personal news. Can I tell you my personal news? What's that?
Speaker 2:  I bought an M four Mac mini and it is glorious.
Speaker 2:  Liam, our producer, can attest to the number of times I have slacked him
Speaker 2:  over the last two weeks being like, Liam, I'm gonna do it. Talk me out of
Speaker 2:  it. And he keeps not talking me out of it. And so this
Speaker 2:  morning I opened up so many browser windows by accident that I
Speaker 2:  got very frustrated with my computer and So I went to the Apple store and
Speaker 2:  bought a Mac.
Speaker 4:  Alright, let me just pull upon a few themes, few core vergecast themes
Speaker 4:  here. David who had an M1 MAC mini on which he mostly
Speaker 4:  does this, which was fine. It was fine, right? It was like not terrific
Speaker 2:  Computer,
Speaker 4:  Right? And you bought a new computer that is
Speaker 4:  vastly faster than what you need. Because after years
Speaker 4:  of insisting eight gigs of RAM was enough, you ran outta
Speaker 4:  memory and your computer slowed down. So you went and bought an entirely
Speaker 4:  new computer to get eight gigs more ram.
Speaker 2:  Okay, I've I have several responses. Thank you for bringing this to my attention.
Speaker 2:  Eight gigs of memory is fine. No If, you were a regular person.
Speaker 4:  You just bought a new computer I
Speaker 2:  In.
Speaker 4:  No, your M1 MacMini was not slow for this purpose.
Speaker 2:  In no way, shape or form should other people make computer purchasing
Speaker 2:  decisions based on how I use browser taps. Like no one,
Speaker 2:  the only person in my life I've met who is worse about browser tabs than
Speaker 2:  I am is Addie Robertson. But you are the person who sat down next to me last
Speaker 2:  week and I went, oh my god, that's so many tabs.
Speaker 4:  Right? And ADDIE is smart and good at buying computers and probably bought
Speaker 4:  a computer 16 gigs of ram. Whereas you were like, most normals need eight
Speaker 4:  gigs of ram I, David Pierce, tab assassin are going to
Speaker 4:  buy a computer eight gigs of RAM and then unnecessarily buy new.
Speaker 2:  I had to choose between being good at life and having a powerful computer.
Speaker 2:  And I picked powerful computer. Like it just, this is self I
Speaker 4:  I also
Speaker 2:  Point
Speaker 4:  Out self knowledge that you refuse to buy a good tv.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no. That I still feel good about.
Speaker 4:  All right. Still feel solid. It's a mess. I'm, I'm proud of you. One's it
Speaker 4:  coming. Thank you.
Speaker 2:  It's here. I'm on it right now.
Speaker 4:  Oh you look great.
Speaker 2:  If you're like, gosh, David is so much smarter and more attractive than he
Speaker 2:  usually is on The Vergecast, this is it. We did it.
Speaker 4:  It's all, I mean I've spent a lot of time thinking about buying an M four
Speaker 4:  Mac mini, but to do that I have to convert one of my old IMAX into a
Speaker 4:  monitor, which more and more people I will say out there
Speaker 4:  are, are talking about, oh yeah, I wouldn't say doing right.
Speaker 4:  But now that I've opened the door to hey, what if we all broke our
Speaker 4:  IMAX trying to turn in monitors more people, more and more people are like,
Speaker 4:  will you do it first so that I can see if it works?
Speaker 2:  We've definitely successfully made the business case for our roving
Speaker 2:  RV in which we will do this process for you. It's ready.
Speaker 2:  I will
Speaker 4:  Drive to your house in a van and break your old computer. That is the only
Speaker 4:  promise I will make. The listeners of The Vergecast. Perfect. Some of you
Speaker 4:  will come out of it with a monitor. Most of you will not. It's
Speaker 2:  About the friends we made along the way.
Speaker 4:  Will we spend time together in a van? Yeah. That is a guarantee.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying when I was a child, my, my father owned not one
Speaker 4:  but two different conversion vans. They were great and I think they should
Speaker 4:  come back as a market. And the specific market I'm proposing
Speaker 4:  is the back of the van is where we hang out and play video games. And the
Speaker 4:  front of the van is where I break your old iMac.
Speaker 2:  Oh, I like that.
Speaker 4:  Do you see what I'm saying? Yeah. It's like inside of captain's chairs, there's
Speaker 4:  like a little lab situation and the back is like couches
Speaker 4:  a good tv, David, some game consoles,
Speaker 4:  I'm not sure this is gonna work. And mostly it'll probably just get me arrested
Speaker 4:  'cause I'll be driving around and be like, I'd like to break your computer
Speaker 4:  and play video games with you in my band.
Speaker 2:  So it's transparency. It gives, it gives you everywhere. Yeah. and we'll
Speaker 2:  make content about it and be huge on TikTok and it'll be fine.
Speaker 4:  That's finally, finally a business model of media. That makes sense. Alright,
Speaker 4:  we should get into the news. There's a lot to talk about. Lauren, let's start
Speaker 4:  with the DOJ in Google. Just to lay some foundation for
Speaker 4:  folks.
Speaker 4:  I wanna talk about the, the proposal this week. There are multiple
Speaker 4:  antitrust lawsuits against Google and it's, it's actually, I find
Speaker 4:  it quite difficult to keep them all apart because it's not
Speaker 4:  clear how all of the things that happen will ultimately
Speaker 4:  play out and make a new Google. And then on top of it there's a
Speaker 4:  new president and a new administration and a new
Speaker 4:  attorney general. Although Mac Gates dropped out like minutes before we started
Speaker 4:  recording So. I don't even know who the attorney general's gonna be,
Speaker 4:  but there's the one we're talking about today, which was the Google pays
Speaker 4:  apple money for search defaults in safari. Google
Speaker 4:  was found guilty of having a monopoly in search. And the
Speaker 4:  remedies are at this. There's another case which is what advertising right
Speaker 4:  Lauren?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The ad tech industry. And that one is going to closing
Speaker 5:  arguments on Monday back in Alexandria, Virginia. And that's all about
Speaker 5:  Google. How Google connects publishers and advertisers
Speaker 5:  through its tech. That
Speaker 2:  One's the much Wonkier one. Yes. But also maybe the more important
Speaker 4:  One because it's the money. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Exactly.
Speaker 4:  So I just wanna like start there. There's a lot of activity around
Speaker 4:  Google's business and how it all works together. And the reason I wanna start
Speaker 4:  there is all of that flows through Chrome, right? At the end of the
Speaker 4:  day, Google's ad tech is worthless unless there are web browsers
Speaker 4:  that show you hats and Google has the biggest one and
Speaker 4:  at the end of the day, the reason it's paying for a default placement in
Speaker 4:  other browsers is because it can't run Chrome on the iPhone.
Speaker 4:  So it just pays Apple to do what it does on the desktop in Chrome. So that,
Speaker 4:  I just want to lay all that out. Like there's a lot of swirling activity
Speaker 4:  around Google and we're facing down this proposal
Speaker 4:  inside of one case, but I'm not sure how it will affect the other case and
Speaker 4:  we won't know because it's just a closing arguments. Oh and then this, by
Speaker 4:  the way, this trial, there's so much, it's so confusing. This trial is
Speaker 4:  not even over. Yeah. This is just a proposal and then there's gonna be another
Speaker 4:  trial to debate this proposal.
Speaker 5:  Right? Right. So I mean, just to give you a sense of kind of the timeline
Speaker 5:  of both of these cases here. Like the ad tech case is gonna closing
Speaker 5:  arguments on Monday and then we go,
Speaker 5:  then we might get a decision in that case by like the end of the
Speaker 5:  year. And then that goes to the remedies phase.
Speaker 5:  If the judge says that Google is a monopolist in that case.
Speaker 5:  And then we'll have to schedule that. And then in April we have
Speaker 5:  the remedies trial in the search case in DC So,
Speaker 5:  and then after all of that, you know we, we know Google wants to
Speaker 5:  appeal the search case and I'd imagine whoever loses in the ad tech case
Speaker 5:  is gonna wanna appeal there. So this is not happening very soon.
Speaker 5:  No,
Speaker 4:  But so it's, it's just a mess. 'cause I've seen people react to the
Speaker 4:  news today about Chrome is, Google's gonna have to sell Chrome and that's
Speaker 4:  just not where we are. It's this government is currently composed in the
Speaker 4:  Biden administration has put forward this proposal. Many things will
Speaker 4:  happen including the inauguration of Donald Trump and whoever his attorney
Speaker 4:  general is being confirmed and all. And then further trials in April.
Speaker 4:  So I, just that's the foundation. I, so we're gonna talk about this 'cause
Speaker 4:  the ideas are really interesting, but I, I just want people to know like
Speaker 4:  nothing is happening. Like we're, we're a long way from from
Speaker 4:  here to there. So talk about this proposal. So the, the Justice Department
Speaker 4:  put out this proposal. What's in it?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, so the proposal that the DOJ put out, it's their kind of initial
Speaker 5:  proposed final judgment. So this is, you know, them saying to the judge,
Speaker 5:  this is what we want you to do. This is what we want you to tell
Speaker 5:  Google that they have to do in order to restore competition to the
Speaker 5:  online search market. And so basically, you know, they
Speaker 5:  had filed a kind of high level version of this not that
Speaker 5:  long ago and it was sort of like, here's what we're kind of thinking about
Speaker 5:  and you know, we're looking at Chrome, we're looking at Android, we're looking
Speaker 5:  at all these other things. This is like the more concrete version of that
Speaker 5:  where they're saying, you know, this is what we intend to ask
Speaker 5:  for in this trial and you know, they're gonna get to go through a whole
Speaker 5:  discovery process around this too. So now we can see that
Speaker 5:  they are saying that they feel strongly that Google
Speaker 5:  must divest Chrome. It's not just an option that's on the
Speaker 5:  table. They think that this is a critical access point for
Speaker 5:  Google search that needs to be separated from the company.
Speaker 5:  And then on top of that, you know, they also considered
Speaker 5:  divesting having Google divest Android, but they're kind of
Speaker 5:  I guess holding their fire on that for now, but they're leaving it on the
Speaker 5:  table. So it's kind of an incentive for Google to comply with the rest of
Speaker 5:  the remedies that they're proposing. And it's also, you know, something that
Speaker 5:  they can turn to if they say, you know what these other remedies aren't actually
Speaker 5:  working to restore competition in the
Speaker 2:  Market. Yeah. They're pretty deliberately hanging that over Google's head.
Speaker 2:  Right? They're like Right, you can do all of these other
Speaker 2:  hugely consequential things that you've only begun to list, which is
Speaker 2:  insane but If, you don't do them like the, the
Speaker 2:  big gun is we will take Android away from you. Right. That was the, that's
Speaker 2:  the, it's just like this looming threat throughout this entire filing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah and I think what really comes through in this filing is that, you know,
Speaker 5:  the DOJ really wants to have, you know, as
Speaker 5:  many options that it can have available to to them
Speaker 5:  on the table. You know, they don't wanna end up in a situation where,
Speaker 5:  you know, some of the remedies they propose don't work or you know, the landscape
Speaker 5:  changed such that none of these things really matter anymore because we know
Speaker 5:  this is gonna take years and we know that AI is going to become
Speaker 5:  a very important part of search. So they are clearly
Speaker 5:  trying to be very deliberate in making sure that anything they ask the judge
Speaker 5:  to impose isn't something that's gonna be obsolete tomorrow.
Speaker 4:  So Chrome is I think the highlight by far. It's the easiest one
Speaker 4:  that for people to understand the looming threat of we will take
Speaker 4:  Android away from you. I think also pretty easy to understand then there's
Speaker 4:  a bunch of other stuff in here. Yeah. Which also seems tremendously impactful
Speaker 4:  but maybe a little bit more opaque. Can you go through those Lauren?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, sure. So, I. Guess just some of the most important ones
Speaker 5:  that come to mind. You know, going back to how this case began,
Speaker 5:  it's really about contracts when you boil it down to it
Speaker 5:  and these contracts are contracts that Google
Speaker 5:  has with phone makers and browser makers to be the default
Speaker 5:  search engine on those platforms. And
Speaker 5:  the DOJ basically wants to say, alright, Google can't enter
Speaker 5:  into certain exclusionary agreements with those kinds of
Speaker 5:  companies. They can't exchange something of value for
Speaker 5:  like preferred placement or for boxing out rivals from
Speaker 5:  those, those kind of platforms.
Speaker 5:  And so, you know, that's kind of like the most straightforward thing that
Speaker 5:  they're asking for
Speaker 2:  And that's kinda what we thought this would boil down to. Right. Like I feel
Speaker 2:  like we've been saying for months that the easiest answer to where would
Speaker 2:  this go is just The government is going to say you're not allowed to make
Speaker 2:  these deals anymore, period. The end. Goodbye. Yeah. And it seems like everyone
Speaker 2:  is prepared for that to be an outcome here.
Speaker 5:  Totally. I mean that seems pretty baseline. It's pretty much like exactly
Speaker 5:  what was in the complaint and exactly what the judge ruled was
Speaker 5:  some of their anti-competitive behavior. So that seems pretty cut and dry.
Speaker 5:  But at the same time, you know, okay sure. Like Google could stop
Speaker 5:  doing these agreements and then they could figure out another way to be the
Speaker 5:  default or to, you know, just maintain their dominance in this area.
Speaker 5:  So I think DOJ clearly thinks like that's not enough. That just
Speaker 5:  kind of like stops the bleeding.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And it's the flip side of that that really gets me reading through
Speaker 2:  this filing that like this whole thing is so much
Speaker 2:  more punishing of Google than I expected it to be. And
Speaker 2:  like I'm not a lawyer and maybe I should have seen this coming, but there
Speaker 2:  is a, there is a real thing they're doing in this filing where they're saying,
Speaker 2:  okay, not only do we have to prevent Google from doing these monopolistic
Speaker 2:  things, we have to take aggressive steps to
Speaker 2:  unwind all of the things that Google has been doing and the lead it has built
Speaker 2:  over the last 15 years. Like a huge portion of this
Speaker 2:  is just them saying we need to break Google in half and give everybody else
Speaker 2:  every advantage that Google has had in order for them to catch up.
Speaker 2:  Right. Like am I, am I overreading that part?
Speaker 5:  No, I think that's fair. I mean I think a lot of antitrust is kind of
Speaker 5:  backward looking by nature and I think, you know, often you hear companies
Speaker 5:  say like, you know, we are not even doing this anymore. Like this is all
Speaker 5:  in the past. And like that might be true, but it doesn't make it, it
Speaker 5:  doesn't mean that their conduct wasn't anti-competitive or that they can't
Speaker 5:  still be held accountable for it. So, and I think, you know,
Speaker 5:  the DOJ kind of often talked about in trial how there was this
Speaker 5:  self-reinforcing cycle of Google is
Speaker 5:  a good search engine. So then people come to it and they put in queries and
Speaker 5:  then Google gets data and then it uses that data to make the search engine
Speaker 5:  better and no one else has access to that whole cycle.
Speaker 5:  And So I think they really feel like they need to break that cycle somehow
Speaker 5:  for anyone else to even stand a chance.
Speaker 2:  And the way the DOJ is doing that basically seems like it just wants to open
Speaker 2:  source Google now it's basically like all of your query data,
Speaker 2:  your whole search index, your, the information people give you in
Speaker 2:  YouTube searches, all the stuff across all of your surfaces, which is like
Speaker 2:  the internet should be made available. The, what's the
Speaker 2:  phrase they keep using at marginal cost? Just to everyone,
Speaker 2:  anyone, anyone who wants to run a thing that looks and works like Google
Speaker 2:  should be allowed to, is essentially the, the vibe of
Speaker 2:  what's coming here. And that to me is the part that surprised me the most.
Speaker 2:  Like they're just like everything that has made Google special and successful,
Speaker 2:  you have to give it to everybody else for free now just so they can catch
Speaker 2:  up. Right. Wild.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The thing that really strikes me about this is If, you
Speaker 4:  just take it at face value. I don't know how Google makes any
Speaker 4:  money after this, right? And, and then there's the ad tech case like
Speaker 4:  right next to it, which who knows how that will go, but
Speaker 4:  it's all, that's also a case about contracts and pressure and I
Speaker 4:  just get the sense that it is more likely than not, than Google will face
Speaker 4:  some penalty in that case as well. So who knows. But this part where
Speaker 4:  you're like, you have to stop preferencing Google search
Speaker 4:  on YouTube. Yeah. And let other people search YouTube the way that Google
Speaker 4:  can search YouTube. YouTube is a closed platform.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I guess I, I think that's, that's a completely fair point, but I
Speaker 5:  also wouldn't cry too many tears for Google because I think, you know, they
Speaker 5:  will be able to make money off of, you know, selling
Speaker 5:  access to these APIs or you know, to their index and
Speaker 5:  to their search results and click and query data. And they'll also
Speaker 5:  be able to, you know, they're still gonna be this like
Speaker 5:  amazing huge company full of great engineers and
Speaker 5:  be able to create a product that's really attractive to people in search.
Speaker 5:  So well
Speaker 4:  Just hold on. They are currently an amazing company full of great
Speaker 4:  engineers and their ability to launch great products True at scales,
Speaker 4:  you know, if there's a graveyard for a reason. Yeah. They had a good run
Speaker 4:  back in the day. Like a lot of Google is, you can trace it back to the fact
Speaker 4:  that they have a monopoly in search. It just throws off cash and everything
Speaker 4:  else is like, well whatever We tried messaging apps, you know, like, and
Speaker 4:  this might make it better, it might make it worse. There's just a part of
Speaker 4:  this where I, half of me says this is a negotiation. So you just put
Speaker 4:  forward the most intense first offer that
Speaker 4:  you can make, which is we're gonna break your business in half. And also
Speaker 4:  If, you don't like it, we'll take Android too and then we'll just see where
Speaker 4:  we come back to from there. And then there's a part of me that says we,
Speaker 4:  you know, we sent, we, we just spent a few minutes talking about breaking
Speaker 4:  up in Google search and the first part of this offer is we're gonna take
Speaker 4:  Chrome away from you. Right. And it's like, oh, this is a complete
Speaker 4:  restructuring of Google, like at every level. Yeah. What we're saying is
Speaker 4:  there should be a search engine that is almost like a
Speaker 4:  utility for other people to build search products on top of and
Speaker 4:  other parts of Google, like YouTube need to let other search products come
Speaker 4:  into there. and we are basically gonna take a closed
Speaker 4:  platform in YouTube and make it a more open one, which is really interesting.
Speaker 4:  And then there's, we're gonna take this browser away, which
Speaker 4:  is the window to almost your entire ecosystem and someone else
Speaker 4:  will have to buy it, which will accomplish what,
Speaker 4:  right. And there's just a, yeah, those are two pretty different ideas from
Speaker 4:  what I can tell. Like you're basically telling Google, you have to be a search
Speaker 4:  engine company now and we're gonna prescribe how that search engine company
Speaker 4:  works. And then you're saying we are gonna make
Speaker 4:  a browser company that someone else will buy. And the number one way browser
Speaker 4:  companies make money is by betting paid for default search, which we
Speaker 4:  will no longer allow you to do. And that there, I'm I'm just trying to
Speaker 4:  puzzle all that through.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. I mean there's no doubt this is, you know, a huge swing by
Speaker 5:  the DOJ and you know, they, they might not get everything
Speaker 5:  they want. Like you said, this is a negotiation, this is their starting point.
Speaker 5:  They're asking for a a lot here and it's
Speaker 5:  gonna be up to the judge to figure out, you know, what is really
Speaker 5:  necessary to restore competition here. And you know, courts really don't
Speaker 5:  like to be, you know, playing
Speaker 5:  babysitter or you know, restructuring, like playing
Speaker 5:  the,
Speaker 5:  just really being the hand of God in the market. You know, they're not trying
Speaker 5:  to dictate how the business goes. They're just
Speaker 5:  trying to restore competition to this market. Generally So
Speaker 5:  I think the more that it gets into things that
Speaker 5:  are about picking winners and losers, the more
Speaker 5:  the judge is going to be skeptical and perhaps
Speaker 5:  restrained on those things. So I think it really depends on how well The
Speaker 5:  government makes the case in court for why these sorts of things are
Speaker 5:  necessary.
Speaker 4:  And when I've talked to Jonathan Cantor, who is the assistant attorney general
Speaker 4:  for antitrust who's been leading this case,
Speaker 4:  you can go listen to him on decoder. His point is these consent
Speaker 4:  decrees where we make companies promise to behave and then we have to like
Speaker 4:  watch them and go to court when they misbehave don't work. 'cause everyone's
Speaker 4:  smart and they can get around it. And what we want is big structural, like
Speaker 4:  you break up the company that's clean, like then it's over and we can just
Speaker 4:  see what happens next. And I, I think courts tend to agree with that because
Speaker 4:  courts the only humility that our judicial system shows
Speaker 4:  is like, I shouldn't run your business. And I think it, I can't tell if that's
Speaker 4:  humility or laziness or what it is, but that's usually how they respond to
Speaker 4:  that idea of like ongoing compliance. Like the courts don't wanna be in that
Speaker 4:  business. I just think like at the, at the end of this, you
Speaker 4:  look at the amount of change that would be imposed on Google
Speaker 4:  and it Sure. Google will have its opinions. Kent Walker,
Speaker 4:  their chief legal officer put out, you can tell like he's writing
Speaker 4:  directly to Donald Trump. He's like, this is a radical interventionist agenda
Speaker 4:  that will harm America.
Speaker 2:  Like it's pretty saucy. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Audience of one, like obviously Google's gonna push back against this what
Speaker 4:  happens in the trial, right? Because there's the remedies trial and this
Speaker 4:  is the proposal in the trial. Are they just going to, and they're all just
Speaker 4:  like gonna sit down and be like, this is a bad idea. Do you have to like
Speaker 4:  show proof? Like how does this work?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean, my understanding is there's another discovery process. They
Speaker 5:  get to call in witnesses, so it's gonna be, you know, kinda like the first
Speaker 5:  trial, but this time they kinda have to take as a given that
Speaker 5:  the judge found that Google's Google had an illegal
Speaker 5:  monopoly and they're just talking about what is
Speaker 5:  reasonable to impose on Google or not. So
Speaker 5:  yeah, it it's definitely, it's going to be a fight here.
Speaker 2:  What's strange to me about this one is it feels like either
Speaker 2:  of the options that the DOJ is presenting here would make sense, right? I
Speaker 2:  think force Google to spin off
Speaker 2:  Android and Chrome into its own company
Speaker 2:  I think is, is I, you can see a world in which that makes sense.
Speaker 2:  Both of those are search businesses I would point out, but like there are
Speaker 2:  people who have made a lot of money selling operating systems, right? So
Speaker 2:  like I can you, you can see it, there's a, there's a thing there. Somebody
Speaker 2:  would spin up an app store, it'd be a whole thing. Sure, great fine. Or
Speaker 2:  force Google to essentially white label its search engine and make it
Speaker 2:  available to everybody, right? So now if I wanna run a search engine, all
Speaker 2:  I have to do is compete with Google on user experience, right there, there
Speaker 2:  is an assumption of like common infrastructure that whatever I search for,
Speaker 2:  it's going to be as good no matter where I search for it. Let people compete
Speaker 2:  on top of that. I actually think that could be super interesting. And suddenly
Speaker 2:  you have a bunch of people with a bunch of different ideas about how search
Speaker 2:  could work. AI becomes really interesting on all of that. And then it's like,
Speaker 2:  okay, the, the foundation of how we search is common.
Speaker 2:  Let's compete for real. I don't understand how you can do both of these things
Speaker 2:  because it, it, each one makes the other one worse, right?
Speaker 2:  Like Google's white label search engine will be better if Google
Speaker 2:  controls Android and Chrome because it will get that data that it is then
Speaker 2:  forced to share with everybody else. Wait,
Speaker 4:  I feel like I'm like required si to point out
Speaker 4:  that every time you make this claim, like some Google PR person leaps out
Speaker 4:  of a bush and is like, we don't use chrome click data to inform search and
Speaker 4:  that is what they say every time. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And that continues to be provably not true. I'm
Speaker 4:  Just say Sure. Like I said, I feel required to say this and there's, I
Speaker 4:  don't, I don't know if I believe it for one second.
Speaker 2:  I trust things that come up in court and in discovery more than in the PR
Speaker 2:  emails in my inbox. I'm
Speaker 4:  Sorry, I saw all people, like right now outside of David's house, there's
Speaker 4:  like a Google PR person peering through the bushes,
Speaker 2:  But like if the goal was to build the best search infrastructure
Speaker 2:  for the whole internet, you do that, right? And like, that's how you get
Speaker 2:  the user data. It's how you get the query data like on and on and on. These
Speaker 2:  things can actually reinforce each other in a way that would make the one
Speaker 2:  product better if they were together and then you're giving that product
Speaker 2:  to everybody else.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I can see a world in which that makes sense, but instead you're saying we're
Speaker 2:  gonna make Google search engine worse and also take away its engine to make
Speaker 2:  it better and then force Google to give its worst search engine to everybody.
Speaker 2:  It's like, what are we, what are we actually, we're just making the whole
Speaker 2:  search market worse.
Speaker 4:  And I always thought that the whole point of this at the end of the day was
Speaker 4:  who can build anything to compete with Google? And there's only one answer,
Speaker 4:  which is Apple and Google has been spending billions of dollars
Speaker 4:  a year to make sure that doesn't happen. And really the the outcome
Speaker 4:  you want is Apple builds a search engine because it has
Speaker 4:  enough incoming click data and query data from Safari on the
Speaker 4:  iPhone. It has the compute capability,
Speaker 4:  it has the money that like just a free, you know, what they should have done
Speaker 4:  instead of chasing a car is they should have built a search engine and they
Speaker 4:  didn't 'cause Google just paid them money to waste on a car. Like that's
Speaker 4:  a weird economic outcome, but this doesn't seem like it
Speaker 4:  creates that outcome at all, right? You're, you're gonna prevent Google from
Speaker 4:  paying Apple and then you're gonna spin off Chrome,
Speaker 4:  then you're gonna say everybody can just use the Google utility
Speaker 4:  version of search, which Apple will just use at marginal cost.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, well we didn't, we didn't build the, we didn't make anybody
Speaker 4:  build a new search engine. Maybe you're just bet on ai. Like are you, is
Speaker 4:  this all just that's coming and it's gonna change everything?
Speaker 5:  I think the licensing actually does get you closer to that
Speaker 5:  because you know, if Apple and If, you know, really any other
Speaker 5:  search engine that wants to is licensing the Google search results
Speaker 5:  and click and query data, they really have a jumpstart on
Speaker 5:  creating a very quality search engine. And you know, if
Speaker 5:  Apple combines that with its own data and own
Speaker 5:  engineering of product, you know, I think they then you're much closer
Speaker 5:  to a very good product from Apple and they're not, they're no longer
Speaker 5:  constrained by, you know, if the judge decides to grant
Speaker 5:  the, the contract remedies here, they're no longer constrained
Speaker 5:  by their contract with Google.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean if this goes a certain way, you basically get to the point where
Speaker 2:  I, as a developer, all I have to do is write a pretty front
Speaker 2:  end and do like three API calls and I have a Google level
Speaker 2:  quality search engine. Like yeah, that's pretty
Speaker 2:  compelling. All of a sudden duck do go can re reliably say
Speaker 2:  we're doing the privacy thing correctly. And also our results are exactly
Speaker 2:  as good, if not exactly the same as what you get from Google. And
Speaker 2:  other people can compete on the AI stuff, you can compete on interface like
Speaker 2:  Right. The the moves become really different because what you're saying is
Speaker 2:  not,
Speaker 2:  we can't compete with Google in order to have results quality
Speaker 2:  and because that is a flywheel that we have no access to. I mean this is,
Speaker 2:  I just keep coming back to Satya Nadella, the Microsoft CEO sitting in the
Speaker 2:  courtroom basically explaining why Bing is worse than Google and why it's
Speaker 2:  completely insurmountable. And everything in this filing makes me think that
Speaker 2:  that is sitting in the heads of both Judge Meta and the DOJ
Speaker 2:  in particular and they're like, what we are going to do is just give that
Speaker 2:  flywheel to anyone who wants it. Exactly. And like, and just there it'll
Speaker 2:  be, and if that works, you'd get
Speaker 2:  a million interesting search engines really fast. I think it would
Speaker 2:  decimate Google,
Speaker 4:  The Google comms person outside your house table right now. I can see them
Speaker 4:  in the window back there. They're holding up a sign that said, or Microsoft
Speaker 4:  could have made Windows good.
Speaker 2:  There's also that there is also that,
Speaker 4:  And these arguments are hard. Like I they're they're, they are hard and,
Speaker 4:  and Microsoft has mostly failed at, at competing with Google
Speaker 4:  on search. And even Microsoft's AI work
Speaker 4:  has not really meaningfully move the needle. So I do see the argument
Speaker 4:  that you have, you gotta break this wide open, otherwise you're gonna end
Speaker 4:  up in the same kind of Apple Google duopoly that kind of
Speaker 4:  defined the last era of computing into whatever this next era is. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  The other argument is that AI comes to nothing and this is all garbage
Speaker 2:  And that Google is better at this because it's better at this, not because
Speaker 2:  it's somehow structurally impossible to compute.
Speaker 5:  Right. I think, I mean two things. One is that I think it would result in
Speaker 5:  a world where you're competing more on the product and the wrapping
Speaker 5:  and the extra bells and whistles around search if everyone
Speaker 5:  has access to the same kind of underlying data. And the second
Speaker 5:  thing is that, you know, most of these remedies, the behavioral
Speaker 5:  remedies, the things about licensing and that kind of thing
Speaker 5:  would be enforced for 10 years. So it's not forever, but it's long enough
Speaker 5:  that the DOJ feels that, you know, it would be able to
Speaker 5:  create some sort of dynamic shift in the market. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  See I look at 10 years and I'm like, 10 years is an eternity. Yeah. Like
Speaker 2:  10 years is, is and there, what was it after five years if
Speaker 2:  Google's market share was less than 50% of search, they could
Speaker 2:  petition to have this stuff called like that. That's what we're asking for
Speaker 2:  here, right? Like Google, which has been somewhere between like 85 and
Speaker 2:  95% of search for forever. They're like, no, no, no,
Speaker 2:  we would like you to be less than 50 and we will consider this to be a competitive
Speaker 2:  market. Again,
Speaker 4:  So I wanna talk about the politics of that timeline specifically But first,
Speaker 4:  I just wanna play a quick game. It's called who Can Buy Chrome?
Speaker 4:  Does anyone Apple, would anyone like to buzz in
Speaker 2:  Amazon? Amazon
Speaker 4:  Meta, Amazon's. But wouldn't the d oj not like it if Amazon
Speaker 4:  or Meta or Microsoft or Apple bought Chrome? Like didn't we just
Speaker 4:  recreate the problem?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. I mean I think it's possible that they say, you know what,
Speaker 5:  these are, you know, different business lines and it's not and it is
Speaker 4:  Not competitive. Wait, don't think Amazon Silk browser is a competitor to
Speaker 4:  grow?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean that's the problem they're gonna run into here. And I think
Speaker 5:  that that, that is an issue for that remedy. And I think on top of that
Speaker 5:  it's like, okay, well what if this other theoretical big tech company that
Speaker 5:  buys Chrome then decides that they wanna make a search engine? And then are
Speaker 5:  we back in the same place, just like under a different company name?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean the number being thrown around is what, $20 billion? Yeah. The
Speaker 2:  number of companies that could spend that on a web browser with,
Speaker 2:  like you said earlier, NELI no inherent business model. Like it's, it's so
Speaker 2:  important to, to underline the fact that a web browser on its own
Speaker 2:  is not a business. Yeah. There is just no evidence that you can build a web
Speaker 2:  browser that will be a business at any scale
Speaker 4:  For Josh from from Arc on the browser company and a coder and
Speaker 4:  they just pivoted away from making a web browser. It's very
Speaker 2:  Obvious. You just, you just can't do it. You certainly can't do it to make
Speaker 2:  a $20 billion acquisition make any sense. By
Speaker 4:  The way, $20 billion is low. That's the number that Google is paying Apple
Speaker 4:  just to be the default in search. That's the yearly number.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I saw somebody say, just take over Chrome, get the same deals because
Speaker 2:  you'll be allowed to and it's the greatest private equity arbitrage
Speaker 2:  opportunity in history.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah, this is, you should buy Chick-fil-A and open it on Sundays. Like
Speaker 4:  you don't have to do anything.
Speaker 4:  It's very easy. Yeah, but I but Google won't be allowed to make those deals,
Speaker 4:  so you're already, you're just like operating very much behind.
Speaker 4:  Right? I, I think Chrome, the more we talk about it just even in
Speaker 4:  the past half an hour here, it feels like Chrome is a side show. We're going
Speaker 4:  to train all of our attention and argue about whether, whether or not you
Speaker 4:  can, you should sell Chrome or who you can sell it to and the DOJ will take
Speaker 4:  will give it up so that Google can't make these deals and
Speaker 4:  that Google has to be this like weird kind of utility that anybody can do.
Speaker 4:  Like, that feels like part of the negotiation here. Maybe I'm wrong. I have,
Speaker 4:  I have no insight. It's just as we talk about it, yeah, it just seems so
Speaker 4:  it, it feels like it accomplishes so little in the end versus
Speaker 4:  actually opening up the search engine.
Speaker 5:  I think this is a weird case where, you know, generally structural remedies
Speaker 5:  or breakups are thought to be like cleaner and easier and you know, the
Speaker 5:  court can just say, all right, let's like s this and then we're done. We
Speaker 5:  can wipe our hands of it. But it's complicated in this case because
Speaker 5:  who's gonna buy Chrome and you know, how does that look? You know,
Speaker 5:  there's a lot of questions there. Whereas the behavioral
Speaker 5:  remedies are often thought of as, alright, this requires more
Speaker 5:  oversight by the court. This is like a little bit harder to execute.
Speaker 5:  But in this case it does seem to get at the heart of what the DOJ had
Speaker 5:  argued in the case was the problem and was the reason that other search
Speaker 5:  engines couldn't catch up. And So I think we might,
Speaker 5:  I could see the logic of, you know, why they might tend toward a more
Speaker 5:  behavioral remedy here. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean it it it's like negotiation 1 0 1, right? To go in with something
Speaker 2:  like this that you're, you know, you're willing to give up Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Soon after shot and it is, you'll be the CEO of just Google
Speaker 4:  duo, right? Like yeah Zach, you gotta have, what do you
Speaker 4:  wanna give me in return? Right? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You gotta have the one thing that you're willing to part with just in the
Speaker 2:  name of seeming like you're arguing
Speaker 4:  In Good. I would be good see of Google Docs just sell, give me Google. I
Speaker 4:  have a number of ideas already from the jump.
Speaker 2:  They already did taps. Google Docs is perfect. Don't touch Google Docs.
Speaker 5:  I wonder if they would make it so that they do something similar like they're
Speaker 5:  proposing with Android where it's like, all right, fine, we don't have to
Speaker 5:  spin out Chrome, but you know, we will hang it over your head
Speaker 5:  in case you don't comply with everything else. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That's what I feel like you have to sell. Chrome is such a big
Speaker 4:  shiny distraction from all of this other stuff, right?
Speaker 4:  The marginal cost access to the Google search index is also a dagger to that
Speaker 4:  company's business. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  But those are the things like, like you're saying, Lauren, that actually
Speaker 2:  get to the trial that we had last year, right? Like yes,
Speaker 2:  the Chrome thing I think came out of left field for a lot of people because
Speaker 2:  it, it just doesn't address the stuff that they spent months in court arguing
Speaker 2:  about it is it, you can sort of get there from Chrome,
Speaker 2:  but all of these arguments were about like the, the structural system
Speaker 2:  that makes the underlying infrastructure of Google
Speaker 2:  search unstoppable and, and all, all the rest of the stuff
Speaker 2:  in the filing is like poking at how it appeal that apart and then there's
Speaker 2:  Chrome. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I think, I mean another aspect of the trial was like where
Speaker 5:  are you able to access search and Chrome and web browsers generally
Speaker 5:  are one of the big access points. You either access search
Speaker 5:  through your browser or your phone basically. So
Speaker 5:  I, I think the thing with Chrome is that it's the one like
Speaker 5:  entity and Android, they're the one entity that Google actually owns.
Speaker 5:  Like the court can't impose a, a remedy on another company.
Speaker 5:  It can't impose a remedy on Apple or or Samsung. But I can,
Speaker 4:  That's not true,
Speaker 4:  but
Speaker 5:  It can impose a remedy on Google to say, alright, at least for this
Speaker 5:  one browser that you own, you can't use it in a self
Speaker 5:  referencing way.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So I do wanna talk about the, the politics of this. I think it's a
Speaker 4:  good segue. So we've been comparing this case and the Apple case to the Microsoft
Speaker 4:  case in the nineties for some time since they started basically, and it
Speaker 4:  strikes me even the timeline here and the
Speaker 4:  politics of the timeline are the same. So Microsoft case in the nineties
Speaker 4:  started 1998 under Bill Clinton,
Speaker 4:  the DOJ won, they pursued a breakup. George Bush gets
Speaker 4:  elected and the DOJ says, ah, nevermind we're gonna settle a case. And there's
Speaker 4:  some like winding back and forth in there, but there was a moment when Microsoft
Speaker 4:  was gonna get broken up and then there was a moment when the DOJ said, nah,
Speaker 4:  we're done with that. We're gonna do these big consent decrees and you're
Speaker 4:  fine. And all that was chaos, right? And the executives at Microsoft who
Speaker 4:  were there at that time will tell you it was super distracting and you know,
Speaker 4:  bill Gates is like, this is why I didn't invent the cell phone, which is
Speaker 4:  you just tell yourself that Bill, right? Like you did the Zoom,
Speaker 4:  I'm sorry. But that, that distraction from the giant
Speaker 4:  created the opportunity for Google to exist in many ways. It
Speaker 4:  created the opportunity for Apple to make its big comeback because
Speaker 4:  it's not like Mac OS nine software was selling the iMac,
Speaker 4:  web browsers were selling the iMac. So all of this distraction
Speaker 4:  about Microsoft and bundling in Air Explorer and all this stuff in the nineties,
Speaker 4:  whether it came to anything, it just created the opportunity for other players
Speaker 4:  to enter. 'cause Microsoft was constrained by whatever. Here we have a
Speaker 4:  very similar situation. This case actually started in the Trump administration.
Speaker 4:  It got won in the Biden administration under this DOJ. Now we're gonna head
Speaker 4:  into a remedies phase with a new president,
Speaker 4:  a much more transactional president who will pay direct attention to the
Speaker 4:  CEO EO of this company who has already said, he's talking to the CEO EO of
Speaker 4:  this company with Elon Musk on the call that was reported this week. And
Speaker 4:  who knows who the Attorney general will be. Let's just start with the basics
Speaker 4:  is, is Jonathan Kanter still gonna be the assistant attorney general of
Speaker 4:  antitrust when this case goes to the remedies phase?
Speaker 5:  That would seem highly unlikely. You know, even when
Speaker 5:  I, I think administrations are aligned on certain policies, you know, they
Speaker 5:  often just wanna bring in their own people. So I think, you know, we're likely
Speaker 5:  to see a different antitrust chief and at the DOJ under Trump.
Speaker 5:  But I think it is a big open question of what
Speaker 5:  way that person will lean. Are they gonna be a more populous
Speaker 5:  neo Brandeis antitrust person who
Speaker 5:  actually does want to pursue really strong remedies against Google? Or are
Speaker 5:  they gonna be more of the, you know, conserv establishment
Speaker 5:  conservative type that wants to
Speaker 5:  kind of do as light a touch a thing as they can So
Speaker 5:  I think. We still don't really know what that's going to be. I mean, we don't
Speaker 5:  even know who the ag nominee is gonna be after Matt Gates dropped out.
Speaker 5:  So I think there are a lot of big questions about that,
Speaker 5:  but I, I do think it's important that it was brought under the first Trump
Speaker 5:  administration, So I. Don't think we're gonna see it completely wither away,
Speaker 5:  but I could see for sure that maybe the next DOJ
Speaker 5:  doesn't wanna go as far as this DOJ has put out there.
Speaker 4:  Do you think there's any gamesmanship here, which is actually what we should
Speaker 4:  sell Google into as many component parts as we think that's our proposal
Speaker 4:  so that the next DOJ shows up and even the walk like
Speaker 4:  pre-negotiated against the next administration
Speaker 5:  Perhaps. I mean, I think any, any administration that
Speaker 5:  walks back some of these, they're going to have to deal with what that
Speaker 5:  looks like to the public. You know, they, I'm sure they would say that's
Speaker 5:  not really a factor for them, but I think for any, anyone who
Speaker 5:  works in politics, it is to an extent they're gonna have to say,
Speaker 5:  alright, well we did pull our punches here and explain
Speaker 5:  that So I think it, you know, it's harder to take
Speaker 5:  something away than to add something back in and
Speaker 5:  you know, I could see that potentially being a consideration here. The
Speaker 4:  Other piece, and I'm I'm just curious here to read on this, we obviously
Speaker 4:  don't know who the attorney general will be and
Speaker 4:  Matt Gates had so many problems that he just withdrew. Like he literally
Speaker 4:  went to Capitol Hill for 20 minutes. He met with senators and was like, I'm
Speaker 4:  out you guys like, and so that, that is whatever it is.
Speaker 4:  And that's not the kind of politics we ever really talk on the show, but
Speaker 4:  he was kind of an antitrust guy. Like he was into it maybe
Speaker 4:  Yeah, in a bad faith way. Like I just wanna punish big companies, which is
Speaker 4:  seems to animate a lot of Trumpist antitrust, but he was still
Speaker 4:  like, that's pretty cool. JD Vance, we've watched video of
Speaker 4:  him saying Google is a problem and Lena Khan is doing a good job.
Speaker 4:  We Josh Hawley, right? Like there there is a strain of
Speaker 4:  antitrust thinking in the modern Republican party
Speaker 4:  that says, yeah, we probably should break up Google, Elon Musk.
Speaker 4:  I mean he says everything you can, you can find a tweet of anything
Speaker 4:  at this point. But he is, he's said Google is a problem. Mark Andreessen
Speaker 4:  and Ben Horowitz benefactor is the Trump campaign and now benefactors the
Speaker 4:  administration, they, they think Google is a problem, like openly. They've
Speaker 4:  openly said it. What, how does that tie up
Speaker 4:  with actually want The government out of messing with big American companies
Speaker 4:  because it, there's, there's a ideological inconsistency there and
Speaker 4:  I have no idea how that resolves.
Speaker 5:  Well I think the staying out of American companies comes more from the
Speaker 5:  establishment arm of the Republican party and I think Trump, you know,
Speaker 5:  I I think he can kind of talk that part of it
Speaker 5:  when it, it is beneficial to him or you know, in
Speaker 5:  areas that make sense for him. But I think, you know, when it comes to big
Speaker 5:  tech, he has often wanted to speak out on them and
Speaker 5:  you know, has an elevated antitrust
Speaker 5:  enforcers in his previous administration who did go after both Google
Speaker 5:  and Meta So I think there's always been that strain within
Speaker 5:  Trump and, you know, Trump's previous administration, So I think,
Speaker 5:  you know, it is definitely notable that he continues to surround himself
Speaker 5:  with people who do believe in this kind of
Speaker 5:  more progressive view of antitrust. But at the same time, I would caveat
Speaker 5:  that like with Trump, we never really know, you know,
Speaker 5:  what's going to happen? You know, is he gonna change his mind the next day
Speaker 5:  and who's really got his ear So I think it's hard to
Speaker 5:  pull any policy from any one of those people.
Speaker 5:  But I think just seeing that there are so many of them that
Speaker 5:  he's surrounding himself by and you know, the
Speaker 5:  animosity that he has had towards certain tech companies and tech executives,
Speaker 5:  I think it's not hard to imagine that there would be some incentive to
Speaker 5:  continue these fights against the tech companies.
Speaker 2:  I would also just point out that the, the, the unifying theme of a lot of
Speaker 2:  these antitrust fights is against companies that have they, they
Speaker 2:  have decided have wronged them in some way on the internet. Like I think
Speaker 2:  it's less about like a broad moral belief about antitrust and
Speaker 2:  more about big companies that say bad things about me
Speaker 2:  in search results.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, there's no, I I wanna be very clear, there's no rationalizing these
Speaker 2:  Decisions. No,
Speaker 4:  I'm just pointing out it's a bunch of people who are mad. Yes. And they act
Speaker 4:  in ways that accomplish retribution. And Trump in
Speaker 4:  particular has said they gotta treat me better, I will break them up like
Speaker 4:  right
Speaker 2:  And right or wrong, like however you wanna feel about it. They have been
Speaker 2:  mad at Google in particular long enough that I think it stands
Speaker 2:  to reason that they're going to continue to be mad at Google. Right.
Speaker 4:  And Anderson Horowitz can probably find a way to buy Chrome,
Speaker 2:  Elon Musk Yeah. Or fund a bunch of government that are gonna have a really
Speaker 2:  easy time building ad funded search engines now, right. Like that suddenly,
Speaker 2:  suddenly you take the best market in the history of the internet and
Speaker 2:  you break it into a thousand pieces and make it available for anyone to come
Speaker 2:  into like that you've just made every VC's year, right?
Speaker 2:  Like v they, we've heard this for years, it came up at the trial
Speaker 2:  that VCs won't fund search companies because it is, it's a, it's a dead area.
Speaker 2:  It's not even worth trying to compete with Google. And instead what you're
Speaker 2:  doing is you're saying here's a hundred billion dollar a year industry that
Speaker 2:  is suddenly completely up for grabs and you don't even have to try that hard
Speaker 2:  to be competitive. Like Yeah, yeah. I'd be into that if I were a
Speaker 2:  fe.
Speaker 4:  I will point out that the first Trump administrations antitrust
Speaker 4:  efforts ended with one
Speaker 4:  T-Mobile buying sprint in a negotiated deal that created project channel
Speaker 4:  fivey America's fourth wireless carrier,
Speaker 4:  which to this day I think strikes terror in the heart of everyday Americans.
Speaker 4:  I don't who the fuck knows what's going on over there. That's one. And then
Speaker 4:  the other one they fought against at and t buying T
Speaker 4:  Time Warner because Trump hated CNN so much.
Speaker 4:  That's it. That was the entire intellectual justification for opposing that
Speaker 4:  merger they lost, which is fine. And that resulted in a four three
Speaker 4:  gray scale Justice League directed by Zack Snyder. Those are the two
Speaker 4:  outcomes of the previous Trump administration's antitrust efforts.
Speaker 2:  That's good. We've now hit the bingo card for the first cast talks about
Speaker 2:  antitrust. So it's, I'm
Speaker 4:  Just pointing out, you're like, how will Trump deal with Chrome? And you're
Speaker 4:  like, well the evidence suggests they will force them to hire Zach Snyder
Speaker 4:  to make Grayscale Square YouTube videos and start Boost
Speaker 4:  Mobile. Like I don't know what to make of all that, but you could
Speaker 4:  actually outta the pieces of Google, you could probably do that. Google file
Speaker 4:  is now Boost mobile. Yeah, I was gonna say that's my, that's my prediction.
Speaker 4:  The last thing I wanna ask you about Lauren, real quickly, this case, the
Speaker 4:  Google case is done right? They were found guilty of having a monopoly and
Speaker 4:  now we're in the remedies phase. The other case, it's wrapping up,
Speaker 4:  right? It's gonna come to a conclusion. The judge is gonna decide the judge,
Speaker 4:  not a political actor in the way that some other folks are political actors
Speaker 4:  or at least not supposed to be. That will come to a conclusion.
Speaker 4:  Apple's case is still pending, right? It hasn't gone to trial,
Speaker 4:  no one's been ruled anything. We're Apple asked for a dismissal today.
Speaker 4:  They said make this go away. Apple has a lot to want
Speaker 4:  from an incoming Trump administration just straightforwardly. Apple makes
Speaker 4:  a lot of stuff in China and Trump wants to impose tariffs on goods made
Speaker 4:  in China. So you can see Tim Cook has to horse trade his way out of that.
Speaker 4:  He did an excellent job of that last time. Like maybe Tim
Speaker 4:  Cook's singular achievement as CEO is navigating Donald Trump to
Speaker 4:  excuse Apple products from tariffs. You can make the argument, I'm not saying
Speaker 4:  it's good or bad, I'm not, not out outside of the morality of it. He did
Speaker 4:  a good job of it. He, he excused Apple from a lot of noise by
Speaker 4:  managing one man very directly. Do you think that he's gonna be able to
Speaker 4:  manage his way outta this antitrust lawsuit because the incoming
Speaker 4:  attorney general could just drop it?
Speaker 5:  That's true. Yeah. I, I think, you know,
Speaker 5:  when it's something like the, when it's coming from the DOJ, it really is
Speaker 5:  up to the DOJ where they, if they want to continue the case and what direction
Speaker 5:  they want it to go, you know, they certainly could
Speaker 5:  withdraw it, but I think that's hard. It's already,
Speaker 5:  you know, in this kind of pretrial phase,
Speaker 5:  they were just arguing a motion to dismiss and you know, now that's gonna
Speaker 5:  be up to the judge to decide whether any part of the case can move forward.
Speaker 5:  And I guess it's theoretically possible that the judge dismisses the case.
Speaker 5:  I think often in these really big cases we might see them
Speaker 5:  narrowed but not fully dismissed. So yeah, then it's on the
Speaker 5:  DOJ to decide what they do. And I
Speaker 5:  think
Speaker 5:  Apple is in much more of a friendly position with
Speaker 5:  Trump in a sense, just based on the past administration. When
Speaker 5:  Tim Cook managed to really kind of walk this really precarious
Speaker 5:  line in, you know, just being on
Speaker 5:  Trump's good side, So, I think if any company could do it,
Speaker 5:  perhaps it's Apple, but you know, that
Speaker 5:  would obviously be a big deal if DOJ just dropped the
Speaker 5:  case entirely. I think that would be somewhat unusual.
Speaker 4:  And the DOJ is supposed to be independent of the presidency and I don't think
Speaker 4:  Donald Trump wants a DOJ that's independent of his presidency. Right? Like,
Speaker 4:  I don't wanna be, this is what we're talking about is corruption, like sort
Speaker 4:  of straightforwardly corruption. Can Kim Cook call Donald Trump and say drop
Speaker 4:  my antitrust case Like in a normal administration
Speaker 4:  that would end there, like right lawyers would come screaming into the White
Speaker 4:  House, they would burst into the Oval Office and be like, Mr. President,
Speaker 4:  you can't do that and that is not gonna happen this time. Like Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 4:  Very clearly. He does not want that to happen. He does not want that constraint
Speaker 4:  on his behavior. The question is what happens
Speaker 4:  next? Right? And, and honestly, what's a sym hook trade away? Like do
Speaker 4:  you care more about tariffs or do you care more about your antitrust lawsuit?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, there's still a North Carolina factory that either does or
Speaker 2:  doesn't exist and either will or won't exist that Tim can always throw into
Speaker 2:  this
Speaker 4:  Saying.
Speaker 4:  Whenever I say his name, we sure can In our emails, I'll tell you that.
Speaker 4:  No, we're gonna do gadgets. We, it's all the politics are out of our system.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna do gadgets. Well, there's gonna be a little politics later, but
Speaker 4:  for now, we're gonna do gadgets.
Speaker 2:  Everything is politics. Eli,
Speaker 4:  Just like Alexa calling an Uber. Only the Uber has a giant
Speaker 4:  American flag mount to the back of it now by wall.
Speaker 4:  So there's like a bunch of
Speaker 4:  great If, you know, it came home from JFK yesterday and it Uber has a bunch
Speaker 4:  of choices at the airport. Like, do you want Uber comfort? Do you want business
Speaker 4:  comfort? Do you want Uber Electric or whatever? If I could pick giant
Speaker 4:  American Flag truck,
Speaker 2:  Uber, patriot, I would
Speaker 4:  Uber Raptor. Like I would take, it's good. I'm just saying, you know me,
Speaker 4:  I would take it. All right. Lots of AI stuff, lots
Speaker 4:  of gadget stuff. Just a big mix of companies
Speaker 4:  trying to figure out what on earth is going on. I I would say,
Speaker 2:  Yeah, what do we do now? What do we do here? Is like a real question facing
Speaker 2:  the tech industry at this moment.
Speaker 4:  So let's start with Amazon. Just bundle these up. So
Speaker 4:  there's a lot of rumors about what's gonna happen with the next version of
Speaker 4:  Alexa. There was some reporting earlier this week that Amazon
Speaker 4:  really wants to roll it out, but it's still too slow.
Speaker 2:  Yep. It's tough. I, the, the, the vibes
Speaker 2:  coming out of Amazon about what Alexa is and might be when
Speaker 2:  it comes out next. Just keep getting worse. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  it was supposed to launch on October. It's now the end of November,
Speaker 2:  and I would say there is no sign of it yet. And it's, it's one
Speaker 2:  of those things like you, you kind of get to the point where once these things
Speaker 2:  have been leaked in the way that they have several different times
Speaker 2:  in several different ways, it starts to become clear. This is like,
Speaker 2:  this is people who think this is a problem and want to talk about it.
Speaker 2:  Right? It's like, it was like, it's, it, there is so much
Speaker 2:  smoke now that it's like this. There's something really problematic happening
Speaker 2:  here.
Speaker 4:  But, and then there's smoke on the other side, which is they've all been
Speaker 4:  leaked in the other way in like big hypey ways to like juice stock
Speaker 4:  prices and make everyone think that, you know, they're not gonna get
Speaker 4:  lapped by open ai. Like Jesus will, digital Jesus will
Speaker 4:  turn on your lights soon, we promise. Yeah. Is like a pro is
Speaker 4:  is like a thing that all these companies are saying, and then the reality
Speaker 4:  of building those products is still very challenging. Yes. So
Speaker 4:  here you have Amazon, which I think suffered the most
Speaker 4:  from the first wave of like chatbots. Like why wasn't Alexa doing
Speaker 4:  this already? Totally right. You, you didn't even have an
Speaker 4:  iPhone services business to distract you the way that Apple got distracted
Speaker 4:  from Siri. Like you didn't have some cash cow, you just had like, this
Speaker 4:  was your bet. You wanted Alexa to be Windows, the interface is voice.
Speaker 4:  This is the platform shift is we can talk to computers, they can talk to
Speaker 4:  us like, where, what are you doing? And the answer is, don't worry, we got
Speaker 4:  it. And it seems like yep. They they wanted to agency stuff,
Speaker 4:  they want it to call an Uber for you. They wanted to go buy concert tickets
Speaker 4:  probably in the same way that everybody's talking about, right? Which is
Speaker 4:  like click around on some websites on the backend and a AWS, but it's still
Speaker 4:  too slow.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's, it's been really interesting to me thinking about the difference
Speaker 2:  between the way that Google reacted to chat GPT and the way that
Speaker 2:  Amazon reacted to chat GPT. Because what Google started saying almost immediately
Speaker 2:  was basically we built all this technology,
Speaker 2:  like these things you think you did, we invented, and we've been doing it
Speaker 2:  for a long time. And what Google had was a lot of very good technology that
Speaker 2:  it hadn't built into anything. And so Google all of a sudden raced
Speaker 2:  to basically productize this stuff. It had been working on internally
Speaker 2:  for a very long time. And I think the speed with which Gemini has become
Speaker 2:  like ubiquitous inside of Google and also pretty good
Speaker 2:  suggest that most of what Google was saying was true, right? Like, it, it
Speaker 2:  had the tech and it changed the company a lot to productize it, but like
Speaker 2:  it had it, Amazon was the opposite, right? Like Amazon had
Speaker 2:  the thing you would think would be the product, right? Like chat GPT is coming
Speaker 2:  out being like, we've made voice mode and it's like Alexa is just voice mode
Speaker 2:  and we've had it for 10 years. And
Speaker 2:  what Amazon had to do was basically say, no, no, no, we, we can build these
Speaker 2:  underlying capabilities to the point where it it soft launched this
Speaker 2:  thing over a year ago in the middle of a bunch of like weird personnel
Speaker 2:  changes where Dave Limp was leaving to go run Blue Origin Panos Pane
Speaker 2:  was leaving Microsoft to come in and run all this stuff. But like, they launched
Speaker 2:  this thing already a year ago. They told us what it was gonna be and
Speaker 2:  made these grand promises about how it was coming soon. And it is, it, it
Speaker 2:  has become abundantly clearer over that last 12 months that building the
Speaker 2:  technology is the hard part and, and
Speaker 2:  Amazon just doesn't seem to be able to do it.
Speaker 4:  But do you think it's the technology or do you think it's the product? I
Speaker 4:  think the product, Amazon, you could cheat, right? You could just go pay
Speaker 4:  OpenAI to use whatever, and you still have to turn on the lights.
Speaker 2:  And there's some, there's some reporting and evidence that that is a thing
Speaker 2:  Amazon is either doing or has pretty aggressively considered doing
Speaker 2:  is just paying for that. And you're right, that then attaching all that stuff
Speaker 2:  to the things that Alexa can already do is a challenge,
Speaker 2:  right? Like no matter what, you can't just like write a check to open AI
Speaker 2:  and suddenly Alexa is way better. It's a lot of work. Oh,
Speaker 4:  But I, I think Sam Altman really wants everyone to believe that you can just
Speaker 4:  write a check to.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think, I think Sam Walman would love for you to believe that. And
Speaker 2:  Dario at Anthropic is like, no, we'll do it for a smaller check, but like,
Speaker 2:  you can't do that.
Speaker 2:  But it, it is also If. you want to be Amazon and you wanna do this at the
Speaker 2:  scale that they're going to, you at some point have to build it yourself.
Speaker 2:  And there are a lot of little tentacles to doing that well,
Speaker 2:  but the first thing is just like, what if Alexa was just a little better?
Speaker 2:  Like, you don't, you don't have to fix it all at once. Just just do the thing
Speaker 2:  that like Apple has been doing with Siri for forever, where it just like
Speaker 2:  quietly gets a tiny bit better all the time.
Speaker 4:  No, I I I reject this comparison. What are you talking about? That is not
Speaker 2:  True at all. Yeah, that's fair. That's a bad comparison.
Speaker 4:  Yesterday I asked Siri to call my wife and it was like, no, like, and it
Speaker 4:  did the new animation and everything, you know, like the, the
Speaker 4:  glow, the screen glow. Yeah. It's like beautiful. And I was like, call back
Speaker 4:  and it was just like, I don't, I'm, you know, I'm off the clock, man. Like,
Speaker 4:  like it's not better.
Speaker 2:  I tried to just set a reminder this morning. I I put my coffee mug on the
Speaker 2:  roof of my car and then forgot it so it fell off and exploded
Speaker 2:  and So I, I'm driving and I go on CarPlay and I'm like, Hey,
Speaker 2:  remind me in an hour to buy a new Yeti. That was what I said. 'cause it's
Speaker 2:  a Yeti mug. I love the thing. It's great. Yeah, what it said was, in an hour
Speaker 2:  buy any popular was the name of the reminder. Very good. So
Speaker 2:  you're right. I take back the Siri comparison, but at any rate, if Amazon
Speaker 2:  wants to do this, it has some of the hardest things
Speaker 2:  already out there, right? It has hundreds of millions of devices that support
Speaker 2:  this thing. It has a big ecosystem of devices that work on its devices. Like
Speaker 2:  you just have to build the underlying part. And that is an
Speaker 2:  easy thing to think is the easy part. And it is very clearly not the easy
Speaker 2:  part.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I, and I I think with Apple you can see it's also not the easy part.
Speaker 2:  Totally. And Apple just decided to punt it to chat GBT in a very
Speaker 2:  real way.
Speaker 4:  And and even that is not it, like the part where you talk to the phone and
Speaker 4:  it goes and does stuff for you. That's not chat GBT.
Speaker 2:  No, I
Speaker 4:  I actually think that can you make the existing voice
Speaker 4:  assistant incrementally better with AI is not
Speaker 4:  possible. Like I think the way that Alexa and Siri and Google
Speaker 4:  assistant are currently architected is they're dead
Speaker 4:  ends. Like it's, it feels very clear that these are dead ends and that
Speaker 4:  everyone is struggling to rebuild the general purpose
Speaker 4:  LLM into a thing that can do that, the same stuff that
Speaker 4:  Siri can do and then make it more capable.
Speaker 4:  And you're, they're just stuck. Like, I don't, I don't think you can be like,
Speaker 4:  it's Alexa the same Alexa you know and love, but sometimes it's a thousand
Speaker 4:  times smarter. Like I don't, I don't think that that is like working
Speaker 4:  and so Yeah, we'll see, I mean I, you know, my sense is that
Speaker 4:  they brought in Panos to make this go because they
Speaker 4:  needed strong leadership to make calls and Yep. He's as strong of a product
Speaker 4:  leader as you can get. So we'll see how it goes. But the basic
Speaker 4:  problem of, on the one hand you have
Speaker 4:  Sam Altman and Dario out there being like, we can build a GI on current
Speaker 4:  hardware, which is a real thing these people have said. Yep. And then on
Speaker 4:  the other hand, you've got Amazon being like, well it's, it's turning, it's
Speaker 4:  turning out to be very difficult to, to switch on a light switch with the
Speaker 4:  these tools. It's like we're just like all over the place.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well this is why there was the, the one bit of Amazon news that I thought
Speaker 2:  was super interesting this week was, I believe it was Business Insider that
Speaker 2:  had a story that Amazon is, instead of trying to
Speaker 2:  do all of this stuff itself and do the like agentic AI that can go use
Speaker 2:  websites on your behalf, it's just making deals with partners
Speaker 2:  to do this stuff, which is like a thing you and I have been talking about
Speaker 2:  for forever, right? Like a APIs over AIS is like
Speaker 2:  a thing I keep saying to people that like, why can't you just
Speaker 2:  make the Uber app do it for you? Because you don't have to go
Speaker 2:  fake the Uber app, just, just let Uber do it. And that appears to be the
Speaker 2:  way that Amazon is going. Which I think a, you can read as a total referendum
Speaker 2:  on how good Amazon's own AI stuff is, but also
Speaker 2:  like they're, they're making deals with Uber so that when you say Get me
Speaker 2:  a ride, it'll just call you an Uber and DoorDash for food
Speaker 2:  deliveries and Ticketmaster for buying tickets to things. And
Speaker 2:  these are ideas that raise other complicated questions like should it tell
Speaker 2:  me that it's DoorDash doing it so that I understand the like, transparency
Speaker 2:  of this process and the fees and who all this stuff is going to and who has
Speaker 2:  my information. All that stuff is really complicated ui, but like
Speaker 2:  DoorDash is gonna do it better than Amazon hacking DoorDash.
Speaker 2:  You know what I mean? So like I think that is actually
Speaker 2:  a good sign to me that there is a, a version of Alexa that is going to be
Speaker 2:  better at this stuff in a more integrated way that Amazon has stopped saying,
Speaker 2:  we're going to solve all of this problem with fake rabbit style AI
Speaker 2:  where we're just gonna go use websites for you. We're just going to
Speaker 2:  be partners with the people who know how to do this. And I think that is
Speaker 2:  going to be the right approach for a pretty long time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean Amazon, Amazon has the money to do it, right? I mean, you know,
Speaker 4:  Jesse from Rabbit is like, I don't have the money to do it, so I've gotta
Speaker 4:  do some clicking around. We'll see, I just, again,
Speaker 4:  we can achieve a GI and current hardware, but Apple and Amazon can't
Speaker 4:  quite deploy this stuff at scale in a way that makes sense and doesn't break
Speaker 4:  light switches. Just something to consider. Speaking of light
Speaker 4:  switches, there one other bit of Amazon news, which is fascinating. They
Speaker 4:  announced new echo shows this week. Chen has the writeup Echo
Speaker 4:  show 15 and 21, which is basically just a tv,
Speaker 4:  like just a 21 inch echo show in your kitchen. They show it
Speaker 4:  in their own press photos, running the fire TV interface. Like
Speaker 4:  it's a TV with some on
Speaker 2:  A stand with a remote. Like it's just a television.
Speaker 4:  It's just a tv. Pretty good. People like having TVs in their kitchens in
Speaker 4:  in particular, great. They, they're doing some adaptive light stuff.
Speaker 4:  I don't think Amazon's photo stuff is very good, but they're obviously making
Speaker 4:  a run, put photos in here and making 'em look good. Do you
Speaker 2:  Have a kitchen tv? Like do you have a, do you have a dedicated screen for
Speaker 2:  watching stuff in the kitchen?
Speaker 4:  No, we, we have a Nest hub that shows photos
Speaker 4:  that often just mis responds to Google queries. We, we use it for setting
Speaker 4:  timers and because it is a Google device,
Speaker 4:  you can run YouTube TV on it. Right. But it's, it's small.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And then our, you know, it's like our house, the first part of our
Speaker 4:  house in gigantic. So you can just see the big TV in the kitchen. You can
Speaker 4:  just like look across the house to that TV and to whatever extent we are
Speaker 4:  watching tv, that is the solution. But we're just not
Speaker 4:  like TV people in that way.
Speaker 2:  That's fair.
Speaker 4:  And also Becky's just constantly listening to podcasts on our phone, built
Speaker 4:  in speakers on our phone. Like that's the real TV in our house. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  understood.
Speaker 4:  What's fascinating about these two echo shows, aside from the fact that they're
Speaker 4:  enormous and cheap, although a 21 inch screen with hep resolution
Speaker 4:  for 2 9 9, that's like some David Pierce stats right there,
Speaker 2:  Literally that is more expensive than my 4K TCL Pierce
Speaker 2:  P series that is 50 inches right behind me. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  No, that thing looks great. I'm sure no banding in the colors.
Speaker 4:  It's great. 2 99 for the 15 all that's all that aside,
Speaker 4:  the screen's aside, they've got builtin cameras for video calling. They're
Speaker 4:  proud of the cameras and then they have builtin wifi thread and ZigBee radios
Speaker 4:  for smart home stuff. And so you just see, okay, the idea is we're
Speaker 4:  gonna put a little computer in your house, a little server, it's gonna connect
Speaker 4:  everything for you. You're not gonna have a bunch of little hubs like your
Speaker 4:  Hugh hub or your smart things hub or whatever. It's all gonna be built into
Speaker 4:  this device. And then you'll have this device and this will be the locus
Speaker 4:  of smart home control. Also the thing you talk to and also your tv. Pretty
Speaker 4:  interesting whether any of that actually works or whether matter plays out
Speaker 4:  the way it's supposed to play out. So you can buy a bunch of stuff and still
Speaker 4:  control it from your iPhone and also have this home hub, but who knows? But
Speaker 4:  at least we're making like confident steps towards
Speaker 4:  you just buy this thing. Yeah. Everything connects to this thing
Speaker 4:  and then it is expressed out to your phones and your voice assistants or
Speaker 4:  whatever mess. It's still messy. Yeah. But it, you can see the idea.
Speaker 2:  I do think it's the right infrastructure. I mean you, you pit this against
Speaker 2:  what we've heard about Apple's stuff, which is very much like buy a little
Speaker 2:  controller for every room kind of thing. And I think, I think you're right
Speaker 2:  that having sort of the one big screen you can yell at from almost
Speaker 2:  anywhere and then your phone is actually a much closer
Speaker 2:  answer to the right one. And I also think, like Jen talks about this all
Speaker 2:  the time, having a screen with big ass buttons on it goes a really long
Speaker 2:  way towards making your smart house usable by actual humans.
Speaker 4:  It sort of does. I just want to, I will offer, I will
Speaker 4:  offer this one piece of evidence, okay. Which is both a huge victory and
Speaker 4:  a gigantic failure. There are so many ways to turn lights on and off in this
Speaker 4:  house, infinite ways you can, you can just speak to the heavens
Speaker 4:  and lights will turn off. You can just, you can just wish for lights to turn
Speaker 4:  on
Speaker 2:  And off. Just yell darkness and things happen like
Speaker 4:  It'll happen. And so in our kitchen, which is pretty dark,
Speaker 4:  I have hue at lights in adaptive mode. So they just turn on in
Speaker 4:  the morning and they're in daylight and then as the day goes on, they get
Speaker 4:  warmer and warmer and warmer and at the end of the day they were warm and
Speaker 4:  yesterday they were outta sync. And I was in California, So I get a text
Speaker 4:  from Becky, which is a huge victory. A huge victory.
Speaker 4:  She said, I hate you, the lights are the wrong color because when I
Speaker 4:  put them in, she's like, who gives a shit about this?
Speaker 2:  Right, right.
Speaker 4:  Now she knows this is of a, of a piece with I hate you. I
Speaker 4:  can see the motion smoothing on my parents' tv. I hate you. The lights are
Speaker 4:  the wrong color. Yep.
Speaker 2:  You did it.
Speaker 4:  Huge victory. I was like, I'm done. Welcome
Speaker 2:  To my particular circle of hell
Speaker 4:  Marriage over. Yeah. Mission accomplished.
Speaker 2:  I got another one
Speaker 4:  Onto the next. And then she was like, how do I fix it? And I was like,
Speaker 4:  just, there's like 50 different ways to fix this problem. You can
Speaker 4:  open your phone, there's scenes in home on your phone. But it
Speaker 4:  occurred to me that one, there's a button on one of
Speaker 4:  our Lutron light switches. You can just push to fix it. And she didn't,
Speaker 4:  she was like, I don't care about that. Like I don't wanna do that. I don't
Speaker 4:  wanna figure out what button that is. 'cause it's like, it's just an unlabeled
Speaker 4:  little round button. And she don't, she was like, I don't care. And then
Speaker 4:  I was like, well you can go to the Nest hub and you can,
Speaker 4:  you can just like yell at it. She's like, I, she literally said voice
Speaker 4:  commands are so inefficient. And I said one day, sometime the next 50 years
Speaker 4:  that we were married and live in this house together, I, we didn't, you weren't
Speaker 4:  going to say movie time out loud just once
Speaker 4:  that didn't get anywhere and it got all the way to, there is an
Speaker 4:  old iPhone mounted on one of those new standby
Speaker 4:  mode stands that just shows the buttons.
Speaker 4:  It is next to the home, the Nest hub. They're physically next to
Speaker 4:  each other, but because the Nest hub doesn't see the home kit scenes,
Speaker 4:  I needed an old iPhone on a stand and it says kitchen day time
Speaker 4:  lighting. And she went and pushed that button and I was like, this is just
Speaker 4:  a gigantic failure. There's so many ways to accomplish this and she just
Speaker 4:  didn't do it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. A matter will fix it.
Speaker 4:  Sure, sure. But b,
Speaker 2:  You just described the exact problem with everyone's
Speaker 2:  smart home. Yeah. Which is that what you end up doing is you're like, oh,
Speaker 2:  I've built a million ways to do everything. It's totally redundant, it totally
Speaker 2:  works. And it's like, no, no, no. The actual thing she wanted from you
Speaker 2:  is tell me to walk up to the big screen, slide the thingy, that's the
Speaker 2:  colors and I'm done. That's a better answer.
Speaker 4:  Which is more or less effectively what happened, right? Yeah. She walked
Speaker 4:  up to the phone on the stand, it said kitchen, daytime. And she just pushed
Speaker 4:  it Fine. But it, but it's a next, it was next to the Nest
Speaker 4:  hub, which cannot do that 'cause it doesn't support the home kit scenes.
Speaker 4:  Right. Which is not good.
Speaker 2:  Therein lies the, the actual cru of the problem.
Speaker 4:  But she could also should, she could have just said movie time d our phone,
Speaker 4:  not movie time. She could have said kitchen. She will, she will never say
Speaker 4:  movie time. We sit down and watch a movie. I'm like, are you gonna say it?
Speaker 4:  She's like, I'm never saying this.
Speaker 2:  And you, I'm just imagining you doing it like hammer time, just like stop
Speaker 2:  movie time.
Speaker 4:  It doesn't even do much. Turns
Speaker 2:  Everybody turns else leaves and you watch a movie looking,
Speaker 4:  It just turns off lights in one room. But it's such a funny thing to say
Speaker 4:  like other people have it where like the shades come down, the projector
Speaker 4:  turns on
Speaker 2:  The popcorn starts. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The whole like all this stuff happens. Mine is just like lights off
Speaker 4:  in one room. But it's still the funniest thing you can say's
Speaker 2:  Pretty good. It's pretty good.
Speaker 4:  Alright, we'll see, we'll see if Matter can fix it. I think is the end of
Speaker 4:  that. That
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Matter 1.5. I hear that's the one
Speaker 4:  Ai, it's funny how AI and Matter and Bluetooth are all the same, on the
Speaker 4:  same cadence. Like, we're gonna get there, we're gonna build digital God
Speaker 4:  and it's gonna turn off the lights. You guys,
Speaker 2:  I'd take it. Honestly, if that's the one thing digital God can do, I'm, I'm
Speaker 2:  ready for
Speaker 4:  It. Let's move on to Sonos 'cause it's of a piece with all this. So there
Speaker 4:  have been rumors that Sonos is gonna make like a TV streamer for a long time.
Speaker 4:  This is the next logical thing for them to make. A huge part of their business
Speaker 4:  is Soundbars and Home Theater Systems and
Speaker 4:  lately improving their app. Set that aside.
Speaker 4:  So it's been very logical. They're gonna do this. The many, many questions
Speaker 4:  about how Sonos could build the TV streamer. Like you need an operating
Speaker 4:  system, you need app support, you need all this stuff. So Bloomberg
Speaker 4:  reported a price, it'll hit somewhere between 150 and
Speaker 4:  $200. And then Chris Welch put together some
Speaker 4:  evidence based on some previous reporting by Yanko Rutgers, who's an excellent
Speaker 4:  reporter that this operating system will be
Speaker 4:  called Ventura and be made by a company called the Trade
Speaker 4:  Desk.
Speaker 4:  This is very confusing. Do you know what's going on?
Speaker 2:  Here it is. Er So, okay, so the Trade Desk is an advertising company.
Speaker 2:  Like it's more complicated than that, but it's also not more complicated
Speaker 2:  than that. Like they're an advertising company and they just launched this
Speaker 2:  thing. The thing that Yanko reported a while ago was that the Trade
Speaker 2:  Desk was building a smart TV operating system. And he got a bunch of pushback,
Speaker 2:  including from people who just straightforwardly like, no, we're not.
Speaker 2:  Yes they were. And they launched it officially and it's called Ventura. The
Speaker 2:  Trade Desk wouldn't tell us anything about it. They wouldn't share images,
Speaker 2:  they wouldn't share videos, but it is apparently a thing. And it is so
Speaker 2:  abundantly clear that what they are doing is offering a place on
Speaker 2:  which you can show ads and run Netflix. That seems to be the whole vibe of
Speaker 2:  the thing. And they had a bunch of
Speaker 2:  information, you know, from, from partners and it was like
Speaker 2:  heads of advertising at various streaming services being like sick
Speaker 2:  ads. We love ads. Ads are great. And then Sonos being
Speaker 2:  like, we are excited to be part of this. And and like
Speaker 2:  you said, Chris Welch has been reporting on this for forever and he, he
Speaker 2:  put two and two together and is basically like, this is pretty clearly what
Speaker 2:  Sonos is doing. Which is weird but
Speaker 2:  also pretty sensible if, if you're Sonos and you're like, oh, we desperately
Speaker 2:  need not only for people to buy this thing, but for this to be a real
Speaker 2:  source of revenue for us outside of hardware, which Sonos has been
Speaker 2:  desperately trying to figure out how to do for a long time. And so
Speaker 2:  throwing in with a thing that is fundamentally about building an advertising
Speaker 2:  business seems like a bummer of a user experience, but
Speaker 2:  probably a good business for Sonos.
Speaker 4:  So I'm just gonna read you this paragraph from Trade Desk about Ventura.
Speaker 4:  Ventura represents a major advance in streaming TV operating systems as it
Speaker 4:  solves key issues with prevailing market systems today. Including
Speaker 4:  frustrating user experiences, inefficient advertising, supply chains
Speaker 4:  and content, conflicts of interest.
Speaker 2:  I mean, those are my three biggest issues. I would say, when I think about
Speaker 2:  what I hate about watching tv, inefficient advertising supply chains is number
Speaker 2:  two on the list for sure.
Speaker 4:  That's very good. It's very good in that
Speaker 4:  like, young people are just watching YouTube, like it doesn't even matter.
Speaker 4:  Like
Speaker 2:  That's a pretty efficient advertising supply chain actually. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's pretty good. It's like I watch the NFL and YouTube and
Speaker 4:  then the Jake Paul fight on Netflix.
Speaker 4:  The I I know what they mean by inefficient advertising supply chain. It's
Speaker 4:  my curse to know what that means. Yeah. I I don't even
Speaker 4:  want to tell you 'cause it's so stupid. All they mean is that when
Speaker 4:  you open a TV box, you have multiple apps in the TV box
Speaker 4:  and those apps don't know what ads you have seen. And so
Speaker 4:  different ad providers are selling the same ad to like Hulu and Netflix
Speaker 4:  and whoever else. YouTube tv
Speaker 4:  and the supply chain is inefficient. 'cause it can't just target you the
Speaker 4:  user. It's targeting apps which then have user, like this is all a mess.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And Roku's entire business model is, you can't even put that stuff
Speaker 4:  on a Roku unless you give Roku a, a cut just like the app store.
Speaker 4:  And that means Roku makes money. But all these other companies are like,
Speaker 4:  why are we all paying this fees to run the same ads in the same box, the
Speaker 4:  same person and Roku's like, I don't know, I'm rich.
Speaker 2:  Gimme $5.
Speaker 4:  Is this something you can sell to a consumer? We've solved the problem If,
Speaker 4:  you might see the same ad a bunch of times in our, I don't
Speaker 2:  Know. To be fair, yes. Like honestly, if I could just stop
Speaker 2:  getting the one ad that I get a hundred thousand times
Speaker 2:  a day for a stupid HVAC cleaning company,
Speaker 2:  like I would, I would pay more money for that. I would You
Speaker 4:  Would pay more money for an efficient advertising.
Speaker 2:  Yes. It was. If if Peacock was like 5 99 a month, they are
Speaker 2:  like that 6, 9 9 a month. We'll only show you the same ad once I would pay
Speaker 2:  the, but they do say that
Speaker 4:  They pay more money and we won't show you any ads or real
Speaker 2:  No, no, no. That's not what I'm saying. I'm fine with ads.
Speaker 4:  I thought you want a middle tier.
Speaker 2:  I have to look at my phone sometimes, right? Like I'm good with ads. I just
Speaker 2:  want, I want, I want more ads. I want ad
Speaker 2:  variety. We'll
Speaker 4:  See, I just think like it's, it's great to chase a TV box. It's,
Speaker 4:  it's very hard. And nothing about this makes
Speaker 4:  me confident that they will solve the core problems, which are is like, where
Speaker 4:  do I find the thing I wanna watch? And sometimes it's on Netflix and Netflix
Speaker 4:  has no incentive to play. Like that's just real. And
Speaker 4:  like, and then you gotta integrate it. You gotta be able to say movie time,
Speaker 4:  have the curtains come down, I gotta get some curtains in my house.
Speaker 2:  All right. There's also the question of like, why would you buy this from
Speaker 2:  Sonos ever? Like what, what TV streaming box could
Speaker 2:  Sonos possibly offer you that would be super
Speaker 4:  Compelling? A soundbar? Sure. I don't know that they will ever do an actual
Speaker 4:  box. I think they will do a soundbar with a bunch of HTMI inputs and say,
Speaker 4:  just buy this thing. It'll sound amazing. And also it's got this streaming
Speaker 4:  stuff built into it. But the reality is more and more people are not buying
Speaker 4:  boxes at all. They're just buying the TVs and using the built-in garbage
Speaker 4:  TV software.
Speaker 4:  And like is someone's gonna make a tv? Who knows? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Speaking of who knows what anyone is doing in hardware. That's my
Speaker 4:  segue. Google is purportedly canceling the Pixel tablet. Two, it might
Speaker 4:  leave tablets entirely, but then also might be about to
Speaker 4:  reboot all of laptops and tablets. And then also there's a rumor that they're
Speaker 4:  gonna shut down Chrome OS and rebuild it on Android.
Speaker 2:  I kudos by the way. You just explained a thing that doesn't make any sense
Speaker 2:  in about the most sensible possible way
Speaker 4:  Who know what's going on. Yeah. And also The government forcing the so wrong.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Right.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean there is an interesting thing here that is a
Speaker 2:  line between those two things. Like do you remember the thing that Meta did
Speaker 2:  where they were like, oh, you're gonna, you're gonna make us break up our
Speaker 2:  messaging apps so we're gonna stitch them all together in such a way that
Speaker 2:  that's impossible. Like, is that what's happening here
Speaker 2:  as Google says, no, no, no, we shouldn't do these things.
Speaker 4:  No, no. That Meadows thing was ice cold was calculated. They
Speaker 4:  saw it come in, they made a move. They still, they haven't actually actually
Speaker 4:  to move. Like they're, they're short of interoperable. Yeah, but
Speaker 4:  this is not that
Speaker 2:  There is nothing ice cold or calculated about Google's hardware
Speaker 4:  Strategy. This is, we made another run at tablets and nothing has happened.
Speaker 4:  We might cancel this whole deal. Also, maybe Chromebooks should
Speaker 4:  run Android they said for the 50th time in the past five years.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean I, the thing I think is interesting about this is
Speaker 2:  the, the Pixel tablet thing is weird. There's been some conflicting reporting
Speaker 2:  on a bunch of a bunch of sites that primarily report on Google and Android
Speaker 2:  about what was coming for the Pixel tablet three. And then there was a report
Speaker 2:  on Android headlines that the Pixel tablet three was canceled. And then there
Speaker 2:  was another report that actually the thing that was canceled was not the
Speaker 2:  pixel tablet three, it was the pixel tablet two, which would imply that there
Speaker 2:  are no more pixel tablets coming.
Speaker 2:  I would say, what seems to be clear is that Google is getting out of the
Speaker 2:  tablet business in some fairly short order, which like,
Speaker 2:  I don't see a lot of pixel tablets in the world. I'm not super shocked by
Speaker 2:  this. But also, boy was it not a long time ago that
Speaker 2:  Rick Oslo and the whole Google crew were like, no, we're serious about this.
Speaker 2:  We're doing this for real. We're in it to win it. All we can do is keep making
Speaker 2:  stuff that people like and we're in it for the long haul and like, whoops.
Speaker 2:  I think the, I think the Chromebook Chrome os Android thing is
Speaker 2:  probably more interesting because the thing that happened not that long ago
Speaker 2:  is that Android and hardware all became Rick
Speaker 2:  Oslo's problem. And, and what you need in order to do this
Speaker 2:  thing that Google has tried and failed to do a thousand times, which is combined
Speaker 2:  Chrome OS and Android, is you need somebody to just make that call
Speaker 2:  who can direct every single person involved what to do. And now that person
Speaker 2:  is Rick Oslo. and we reported a while ago that Google was
Speaker 2:  canceling the next Pixel book and that that was just
Speaker 2:  not going to be a thing. And what seems to be the case now,
Speaker 2:  if Google is going to get back into the laptop business, it's going to be
Speaker 2:  something like the Pixel laptop and it's going to run Android. And
Speaker 2:  basically Android plus desktop class Chrome browser
Speaker 2:  could work. Like it's just, it's just sitting there. Right? But it requires
Speaker 2:  a big leap from Google to say, we're out of the
Speaker 2:  Chromebook business. Or to at least just say, we're doing this other thing
Speaker 2:  instead. Chromebooks are gonna be low end education things and we're
Speaker 2:  we're gonna do Android for the high end boy. Is that,
Speaker 2:  yeah, probably not gonna work. But it's like, it's, it's a thing you can
Speaker 2:  organizationally do inside of Google now I think kind of for the first
Speaker 2:  time ever.
Speaker 4:  Sure. I just think the, the promise of the Chromebook is that it is simple
Speaker 4:  and being like, now it's Android really gets you away from
Speaker 4:  that promise, right? Because you're you, and by simple what I mean is there's
Speaker 4:  only one, I mean you can run Android apps, not Chromebook now. And
Speaker 4:  it's, they've gotten vastly more complicated over the past few years. But
Speaker 4:  what I mean is generally the application model on a Chromebook is
Speaker 4:  Chrome.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's browser
Speaker 4:  Caps. You're gonna, you're gonna run a bunch of browser tabs and you, you
Speaker 4:  can run most applications in browsers and that is a powerful application
Speaker 4:  environment and it's taken over. Most things, like most desktop apps are
Speaker 4:  really just web apps and various wrappers. Like that's a big idea. And they
Speaker 4:  have just abandoned it, kind of, which is weird. And now they're gonna have
Speaker 4:  to sell Chrome. So who knows? That's a joke. Yeah. But to
Speaker 4:  say, actually we should run this on our other operating system with a vastly
Speaker 4:  different application model. We're just, we're just like right back in a
Speaker 4:  mess now. Now it's just a laptop.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Right. It just, it's just a Windows laptop or a, a Mac because you've got
Speaker 4:  the native application model and then you've got what everybody is actually
Speaker 4:  doing on their laptops, which just running web apps.
Speaker 2:  Right. And you end up in a weird iPad zone where
Speaker 2:  like, we're starting to see bits and pieces of this with Android as it gets
Speaker 2:  into Foldables, right? Where they're, they're testing the, the freeform
Speaker 2:  desktop windowing, which makes no sense on some Android devices.
Speaker 2:  Slight sense on some Android devices. And like,
Speaker 4:  Maybe that's why they're getting outta tablets. 'cause they're just like,
Speaker 4:  foldables are it, and we're just gonna put all of our effort into that
Speaker 2:  Foldables and laptops. Like I think it's a, it's a not crazy thesis.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I was, I was out with somebody who had a pixel fold the other day.
Speaker 4:  It wasn't Liam who bought one and returned one. I will call out our producer,
Speaker 4:  but I was out
Speaker 2:  around, I think the idea that people are going to completely stream their
Speaker 2:  computer is still a long way away. But this is like a, you know, I
Speaker 2:  need it for a developer environment at work or we're,
Speaker 2:  we're running our dentist office on streaming windows. Like
Speaker 2:  sure. I'm into it.
Speaker 4:  I mean, this thing just looks like a, it's a, this, when you get your first
Speaker 4:  job and you sit down at your first computer and your first cubicle and this
Speaker 4:  thing is looking at you, it's like, oh, this sucks.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like that's, that's my reaction to this. David's like, I
Speaker 4:  wanna stream windows at my house. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  But the beauty of it is, unlike the crappy desktop computer
Speaker 2:  that you get your first day at work at the, at the, you know, accounting
Speaker 2:  firm, this one just runs the internet and the internet is fast
Speaker 2:  now. So that's good. You don't have to do much on this thing. It just
Speaker 2:  has to run the
Speaker 4:  Internet. You just have to be surveilled by your boss. Well, yeah. This thing
Speaker 4:  as built anyway. Built in Mouse Jiggler detect like
Speaker 4:  the cops come, if it detects your fake working, it
Speaker 2:  Is perfect. No, it is very funny. Google is like desperately trying to get
Speaker 2:  a, become more like Windows. And Microsoft is like, nevermind. We're done
Speaker 2:  being Windows. Let's just do the internet now. If, you
Speaker 4:  Were a member member. The first iPad was explicitly positioned by Steve
Speaker 4:  Jobs as not a netbook. Yeah, right. This idea that you would have a
Speaker 4:  thin client PC that like, maybe not stream the entire operating system but
Speaker 4:  just ran web apps. I mean that was the EPC.
Speaker 4:  I cut my PI cut my teeth writing about EPCs. Joanna Stern,
Speaker 4:  she became a name in the gadget world by getting netbook
Speaker 4:  scoops by EPCs. That's
Speaker 2:  Very good. Were net boxes a thing? Can we, can we net NetBox is a thing.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They were, they were a little e whatever. And the idea was you're gonna
Speaker 4:  buy this cheap Linux computer that's gonna run web apps and that's
Speaker 4:  gonna cost $500. And then Steve Jobs was like, here's an iPad, would you
Speaker 4:  like a good computer? And they went away. That was
Speaker 4:  it's time. All right, we gotta take a break one day we're gonna have Joanna
Speaker 4:  back and I'm gonna, I'm gonna, I'm gonna make her
Speaker 2:  But a lot of users and app developers are saying actually things that we
Speaker 2:  like, like these automatically generated leaderboards that let us compete
Speaker 2:  with our friends inside of these apps or like, you know,
Speaker 2:  summaries and things over time that let you track information. Like things
Speaker 2:  you can do that Strava doesn't let you do, but you can do with Strava data
Speaker 2:  is all just gonna disappear. And I think it's happening really fast. Strava
Speaker 2:  gave everybody like 30 days notice that this was happening, which is really
Speaker 2:  fast in, in any kind of like developer environment.
Speaker 2:  And so people are just kind of freaking out and I think what it will actually
Speaker 2:  be remains to be seen but it's, it's just one of those things that
Speaker 2:  is like
Speaker 2:  one company is in the middle of a lot of this stuff and this data
Speaker 2:  means a lot to people and you can read it as Strava trying to be good to
Speaker 2:  its people and you can read it as Strava trying to close the windows so that
Speaker 2:  you have to use Strava more and
Speaker 2:  it'll, it remains to be seen which one it's actually gonna be.
Speaker 4:  So lemme make the comparison to, of all things Reddit. Okay. Reddit just
Speaker 4:  had a good quarter. Its public company profitable for the first time ever.
Speaker 4:  Crazy like they around for a long time,
Speaker 2:  20 years later. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Reddit got there by going to war against its developers and its users
Speaker 4:  and taking what had been a pretty open ecosystem and closing it down and
Speaker 4:  saying, you're gonna use our app If, you wanna make another app you we're
Speaker 4:  gonna pay us so much money that it's not even remotely worth it. If, you
Speaker 4:  want to be a moderator of a sub Reddit, you're gonna play by our rules or
Speaker 4:  we're gonna take it away from you. And this was generally bad, right? This
Speaker 4:  is a large platform that pissed off. Its most important
Speaker 4:  constituency. I think we, we've, we've said it like the power users of Reddit
Speaker 4:  who moderate the subreddits, the app developers make the apps. People like,
Speaker 4:  they're basically like, get out like we our way the highway. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  it has had effectively no negative repercussion that we can
Speaker 4:  see, right? Reddit's still growing. It just made money. It signed a big deal
Speaker 4:  with Google. People are still using Reddit. It's the only non AI
Speaker 4:  spam source of data for Google search. Like there's a lot going on with Reddit
Speaker 4:  that is positive, but they had to go through this wrenching change, which,
Speaker 4:  you know, can't make it on without breaking some eggs. Some very important,
Speaker 4:  very meaningful eggs. Yeah. Still broken. Is that Strava? Right? They're
Speaker 4:  just closing it down saying Screw this ecosystem. We're gonna make money
Speaker 4:  off of what we have here.
Speaker 2:  That's certainly the cynical read. And one of the things that's happening
Speaker 2:  is Strava is starting to build its own AI features. Like they have
Speaker 2:  a a v song who's been covering all this for us,
Speaker 2:  mentioned that, I think it's called Athlete Intelligence Strava's thing,
Speaker 2:  which is essentially like a summary of all of your training data that tells
Speaker 2:  you how you're doing. That's the kind of thing that you've been able to use
Speaker 2:  Strava data for in other apps. And now Strava is saying, no, you can't do
Speaker 2:  that, but we're doing that. And that is precisely the thing that
Speaker 2:  Reddit said to like third party app developers, right? Like that's, that's
Speaker 2:  the speech. The difference is, I think it's, I
Speaker 2:  I don't use Strava, So. I could be wrong about this and I would be curious
Speaker 2:  to hear from people who have been using Strava for a really long time. But
Speaker 2:  to me the switching costs out of Reddit are much higher
Speaker 2:  than they are out of Strava. Like If, you don't If you want something
Speaker 2:  like Reddit, but not Reddit. It doesn't exist. There's nowhere to go. You
Speaker 2:  just, there are no other places. Strava has lots of competition
Speaker 2:  and, and you've seen this even in like the, the forums and on ironically
Speaker 2:  the subreddits where people are talking about this stuff. People are encouraging
Speaker 2:  people to go like invest in the Garmin ecosystem more or like there are
Speaker 2:  other ways to track this kind of stuff. I think for people who have been
Speaker 2:  in this ecosystem a long time, getting out will be very hard, but
Speaker 2:  it'll be interesting to see if Strava can actually pull this thing off because
Speaker 2:  I just don't know that its Walls are quite as like high and
Speaker 2:  impenetrable as Reddits were, and that was Reddit's bet all along, right?
Speaker 2:  Was like, we can do this because fundamentally most of you like it here.
Speaker 2:  And also where are you gonna go? Yeah, we
Speaker 4:  Use Facebook groups.
Speaker 2:  Right, exactly. I just, I don't know that Strava has quite that same
Speaker 2:  tie to people. But again, I am not a Strava user. And If you are. I would,
Speaker 2:  I would love to hear like what the perils of leaving
Speaker 2:  Strava feel like.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'm very curious. I also choose not to track how much I run every day.
Speaker 2:  I track it just by sitting at my desk.
Speaker 4:  I'm like, is it zero? Was it zero again?
Speaker 4:  All right, that's it. Ding ding, ding. The clock went off. Imagine this,
Speaker 4:  you can see the future of the lightning round coming now that we're swimming
Speaker 4:  in cash, we
Speaker 2:  Can, we buy an alarm o the Nintendo's alarm clock and have that be our little
Speaker 2:  mascot of the lightning ground.
Speaker 4:  There were some documents filed by Elon Musk and his pending
Speaker 4:  extremely shaky loss against OpenAI, but at least it's
Speaker 4:  generating discovery emails between Elon,
Speaker 4:  Sam Altman, between the other founders of OpenAI and Sam Altman. It
Speaker 4:  sort of document how this company went from a
Speaker 4:  non-profit to Sam Altman's House of Profits.
Speaker 4:  I dunno what else to describe it. Like in the beginning, Elon's like Deep
Speaker 4:  mind to Google is gonna hire everybody. Here's some money, start a non-profit
Speaker 4:  so we can make ai and now we're at, we're gonna make this a for-profit company
Speaker 4:  control only by Sam Altman Lots in these emails. Like Kylie
Speaker 4:  wrote them up. But it, it really does seem like, I think the
Speaker 4:  Elon gave a bunch of money to Sam Altman without a contract. Step one
Speaker 4:  from your friend who is not your lawyer but is a lawyer and Eli Patel have
Speaker 4:  a contract. Yeah. With it's really hard to file a claim for breach
Speaker 4:  of contract without a contract is basic stuff guys. So they don't have a
Speaker 4:  contract. So he is inventing all these other legal theories, which are all
Speaker 4:  very tenuous. But the emails make it very clear
Speaker 4:  that Sam Altman was like, here's a non-profit and then slowly made it a for-profit
Speaker 4:  and it now is about to actually flip the switch, make it a for-profit.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And also the the ways in which Sam in
Speaker 2:  particular has like consolidated his power over time. And all of this
Speaker 2:  happened almost to the day, a year after
Speaker 2:  the insane events of last Thanksgiving when Sam
Speaker 2:  got briefly fired and then came back with more power and
Speaker 2:  more autonomy and ability to do whatever he wants. My read
Speaker 2:  of this whole lawsuit and there's a, I I'll link to the blog post, I'm sorry
Speaker 2:  I don't remember who wrote it, but somebody just put all the emails in a
Speaker 2:  blog post in a row. And it is so funny to read because you can tell
Speaker 2:  Elon Musk's angle here is basically just to like big brother Sam
Speaker 2:  Altman, that he's like, listen, bucko, you couldn't have done this without
Speaker 2:  me. I'm the reason open AI exists. I did it,
Speaker 2:  but then all the bad stuff that's happened and the fact that it's not what
Speaker 2:  we wanted is your fault. And it's, it's very,
Speaker 2:  it's very funny 'cause a lot of the emails are basically Sam going to
Speaker 2:  Elon with every question, every problem. And Elon being like the
Speaker 2:  the grand fixer who's like mostly just says, throw money at the problem,
Speaker 2:  it'll be fine. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Elon stuff, which
Speaker 2:  Is a, a, a theory and it seems to be working in a lot of ways for him.
Speaker 4:  And about half the time he says, do you wanna have one of my babies? Which
Speaker 4:  is Elon's other move,
Speaker 2:  Right? And Sam I don't think has said yes to that yet, but,
Speaker 4:  But an open AI board member did in fact ultimately have three of Elon's babies.
Speaker 4:  Correct.
Speaker 2:  Three of the 12 that we know about.
Speaker 2:  But yeah, it's, it's just, there's a lot more to come. We've heard,
Speaker 2:  we've seen reporting that there are a lot of messages from inside of OpenAI
Speaker 2:  including in like Signal and other messaging apps that we're gonna see as
Speaker 2:  part of this discovery. Like, we're gonna learn a lot about how this company
Speaker 2:  operates
Speaker 4:  'cause of this one lawsuit that
Speaker 2:  Because of this ab
Speaker 4:  He, I I promise you he will lose this lawsuit. Well
Speaker 2:  That's what I, that's that's kind of what I mean. I think this is as much
Speaker 2:  a push to make this stuff public as it is to win
Speaker 2:  the lawsuit. Like this is a e Elon Musk trying to insert
Speaker 2:  himself as the brains behind open AI as much as it is an attempt to
Speaker 2:  actually win the lawsuit, which I just find totally fascinating. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  And we we're gonna cover every twist and turn of it. Read the emails, read
Speaker 4:  Kylie's piece. It's very good. Yeah. Okay. We should end, actually can I
Speaker 4:  insert one extra lightning round please. Bose acquired the company that makes
Speaker 4:  Macintosh the super high-end speakers. I don't know why. I just
Speaker 4:  want to point out there's incredible amount of consolidation in high-end
Speaker 4:  audio, which is a very funny because
Speaker 4:  there's Bose, which now owns Macintosh, which like makes like
Speaker 4:  $10,000 amplifiers and I've always wanted one. So
Speaker 4:  cool. Like cool, like legitimately cool. I'm, I'm happy
Speaker 4:  this company continues to, to succeed
Speaker 4:  over there. And then there's another company that owns like
Speaker 4:  Pioneer and Ono and they're all the same.
Speaker 4:  Like, it's just bananas, like all over the,
Speaker 4:  like that's all consolidated over there. And now Bose owns Macintosh and
Speaker 4:  there's just this like wild consolidation and audio
Speaker 4:  and you're basically end up picking like the same products but at different
Speaker 4:  levels of expense because that's how they
Speaker 2:  Position for. So if I'm, if I'm like the kind of person who wants $10,000
Speaker 2:  speakers, which as you know, I obviously am, as you can tell
Speaker 2:  by the incredibly powerful audio setup behind me in the room here.
Speaker 2:  Is this good news or bad news? Like I can't, Ima I I, on the one hand,
Speaker 2:  Bose is like going to allow this company to keep existing. But on the
Speaker 2:  other hand, are these just gonna be the like
Speaker 2:  brand names they slap on their existing products so that they can charge
Speaker 2:  five times as much money for?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, there's a little bit of that. There's a little bit of like every car
Speaker 4:  company needs a name so you can like license the names to car companies.
Speaker 4:  Like my Jeep has Macintosh but does it really? Harmon
Speaker 2:  Cardin was everywhere in cars for a minute there.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. My Jeep is actually funny 'cause it runs Android and there's
Speaker 4:  a little Android app on the screen that puts up the blue Macintosh meters
Speaker 4:  and it is all That's great. And I love it. Like I was like, yep, I'm buying
Speaker 4:  that car. And then it's a slow Android app that is like very slow and it's
Speaker 4:  like the meters are like a full second behind me. Oh my God, I paid
Speaker 4:  extra for this. I just wanted to know this is who I am,
Speaker 4:  but I'm, I'm just fascinated with this market in particular because it is
Speaker 4:  consolidating such a high rate because consumer audio
Speaker 4:  is going away just like it just is, right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  There's not a headphones market anymore. There's an AirPods market and then
Speaker 4:  everything else. Right? Right. And then, and those things are becoming wearables.
Speaker 4:  Like they're putting a lot of compute into those. You can see that If, you
Speaker 4:  buy a Samsung phone, the best headphones to buy are Samsung's headphones.
Speaker 4:  You buy a Pixel, the best headphones to buy a Pixel Bots If, you buy an iPhone.
Speaker 4:  Best headphones to buy are AirPods 'cause they're extensions of the phones
Speaker 4:  Now. Weird. That's a weird bad outcome that I
Speaker 4:  promise you happen because they took the headphones jack out of phones. And
Speaker 4:  so all these other companies are racing to consolidate the very, very high
Speaker 4:  end of the market where the money is.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. I never thought about like that, that headphones are now, they're
Speaker 2:  a phone accessory much more than they are their own gadget.
Speaker 4:  They're got like, that market just got wiped out,
Speaker 2:  Which is why everybody is trying to do those like $350 noise canceling headphones
Speaker 2:  because that's like the only thing left.
Speaker 4:  That's what's left. Yeah. And even that kind of shaky. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Although I did, I, on my flight home from California yesterday, I saw so
Speaker 4:  many knockoff AirPod Max.
Speaker 2:  I believe that
Speaker 4:  There we were. Alright, last one. This is a good one. You take this one.
Speaker 2:  So we talked a lot about the, the
Speaker 2:  state of social last week, blue Sky being
Speaker 2:  ascendant, Threads being Threads. And
Speaker 2:  the fascinating thing that has happened in the seven days since I would say
Speaker 2:  is that Blue Sky has continued to grow. It's over 20 million people now
Speaker 2:  continues to grow at like, somewhere on the pace of like a million people
Speaker 2:  a day, which is huge. And Threads is
Speaker 2:  terrified. I would say is is the, the simple way I would put it.
Speaker 2:  Threads has already started copying some of the feeds. They're letting you
Speaker 2:  do the, the custom feeds thing. Just today,
Speaker 2:  you pointed this out just before we started recording, I had missed it. It
Speaker 2:  had happened so recently. Adam er, who runs Threads and
Speaker 2:  Instagram said that they're tweaking the algorithm to focus more on
Speaker 2:  people you follow, which people have been asking Threads for since the
Speaker 2:  first damn day of Threads. Yeah. And it is, it is just not
Speaker 2:  a coincidence that they're doing this because of and after
Speaker 2:  the crazy flight to Blue Sky.
Speaker 2:  So Threads is like moving pretty fast to start to do some of the
Speaker 2:  stuff that Blue Sky is doing really well. I made a joke the other day
Speaker 2:  that Blue Sky's legacy is going to be unfortunately the same as
Speaker 2:  Snapchat, which is that it's gonna have all the good ideas that get eaten
Speaker 2:  by Meta. And instead of Evan Spiegel being the defacto
Speaker 2:  product chief of Facebook, it's going to be Jay Grabber. And that
Speaker 2:  is coming true much faster than I expected.
Speaker 4:  I disagree. I disagree. Okay. A couple reasons.
Speaker 4:  One, you know, we should just have like a soundboard
Speaker 4:  where I just, you can just play clips of me talking to the Fedi verse.
Speaker 4:  Like ultimately these things should interoperate, right? Oh sure. So
Speaker 4:  Blue Sky gets some benefit if it's interoperable with Ma Iton and, and the
Speaker 4:  protocols are different, but I think there's just a lot of bridges that are
Speaker 4:  gonna get built and like that'll be fine. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  They, they will crosstalk pretty quickly here. I think that's coming.
Speaker 4:  We'll see, I mean the, the protocols are very different. Yeah. Very, very,
Speaker 4:  very different and wildly different levels of maturity. And honestly, Threads
Speaker 4:  isn't fully federated and neither is Blue Sky. Like there isn't, I think
Speaker 4:  now there are personal data servers that you can, you can just like run,
Speaker 4:  you can host, you can self-host Blue Sky, but there are no other apps like
Speaker 4:  the actual app of Blue Sky. Only Blue Sky makes sure. And there's pieces
Speaker 4:  of it that are still kind of proprietary. They're early. Yeah. They just
Speaker 4:  started. Yeah, they promised to do it. They haven't done it all the way yet.
Speaker 4:  Same with threats. They promised to do it. They haven't done it all the way
Speaker 4:  yet. But the network effect here will benefit both companies
Speaker 4:  in a way that did not happen for Snapchat.
Speaker 2:  That's true. I agree
Speaker 4:  With that. That, that should be the promise. Second Threads has not
Speaker 4:  boosted the best idea, which is starter packs.
Speaker 4:  So you can steal feeds, you can show people more people they follow.
Speaker 4:  But starter packs on Blue Sky are the thing,
Speaker 2:  They're such a great product.
Speaker 4:  Like I made a list of people you should follow If, you care about k-pop and
Speaker 4:  you publish the list and you can just hit follow and you're done. Like that
Speaker 4:  is driving so much growth over there. Yeah. In addition to it being
Speaker 4:  revon by default in addition to having multiple feeds and block lists and
Speaker 4:  all that stuff. But they have made it really easy to just start.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Even in a way that like Twitter never figured out like the, the, there
Speaker 2:  were the Twitter suggested follows when you would start and that was like
Speaker 2:  really great for whoever made it on those lists, but it wasn't specific in
Speaker 2:  a way. But now you're right. You can, you can go to Blue Sky, you can type
Speaker 2:  in, I did this the other day. I was like, I, I like Arsenal the soccer team.
Speaker 2:  I just typed in Arsenal to the list of charter packs clicked follow on one
Speaker 2:  of them that was like all the Arsenal people. And all of a sudden my feet
Speaker 2:  is full of Arsenal people like it's wild that
Speaker 2:  no one invented this before and Blue Sky just nailed it. I think Threads
Speaker 2:  is going to be somewhere between one day and several
Speaker 2:  days from putting out something very much like that. But
Speaker 2:  kudos to Blue Sky.
Speaker 4:  I really think, and again, I'm very nervous about the First Amendment
Speaker 4:  and the Trump two administration. Brendan Carr,
Speaker 4:  you're gonna, I'm so sorry. We're gonna find some way to algorithmically
Speaker 4:  cut out the Brendan Carr segments of The Vergecast over the next four years.
Speaker 4:  But then the, those of you who like it, we're gonna find a way to turn the
Speaker 4:  volume up on those. Perfect. We've got, we've got ideas for podcasts.
Speaker 4:  Everybody. I'm nervous about it. And federation is a thing
Speaker 4:  is the escape hatch for social media. Yep. Right. Where I think
Speaker 4:  Jay Grabber can say, look, we moderate Blue Sky this way, but If you don't
Speaker 4:  like it. There are other servers or other apps. You can compose your own
Speaker 4:  moderation and you can just have it that way. And that is the, no
Speaker 4:  other company has built that yet. I think Threads wants that for various
Speaker 4:  EU reasons, right? This isn't a closed network, we're building it any
Speaker 4:  way you want. But If, you wanna follow our accounts on another network? You
Speaker 4:  can. There's, these are big ideas. Yeah. Again, they're not fully
Speaker 4:  baked, but they're the thing that is gonna escape a bunch of weird
Speaker 4:  regulatory pressure on speech on the internet. I'm excited for them. Like
Speaker 2:  Yeah. and we are still in kind of the rising tide lifts all boats moment,
Speaker 2:  right. Where like what these things are trying to do fundamentally is less
Speaker 2:  compete with each other and more lure people away from X and
Speaker 2:  the, the more, the more the balance shifts away
Speaker 2:  from X and into all of these other things. They
Speaker 2:  all stand to benefit as they interconnect. And I think they all have
Speaker 2:  incentives like you're saying to interconnect. It's gonna take a minute,
Speaker 2:  but they'll do it. But I think whether you're Blue Sky or Threads, you can
Speaker 2:  look at the success of the other one as a victory. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  As long as Threads keeps being
Speaker 2:  the winner. If you're, if you're outta Missouri right? Like you've, you've
Speaker 2:  got to, there is still some victory in being the
Speaker 2:  one that people are excited about. And I think Threads has lost that in a
Speaker 2:  pretty big way. It had it for a while. People were psyched about Threads,
Speaker 2:  people wanted Threads to win. And I think really quickly in
Speaker 2:  the last three weeks, all of that like good energy
Speaker 2:  has shifted to Blue Sky. And I think if you're at ary, that's the thing you
Speaker 2:  worry
Speaker 4:  inaugural one. Just say the name of the sponsor again.
Speaker 1:  AWS Ah,
Speaker 4:  That feels so good. It's beautiful. That's it's good. Beautiful. Play the
Speaker 4:  music again. It's the whole thing we did. I don't even know what the music
Speaker 4:  mission accomplished. Mission accomplished. We did it everybody. That's it.
Speaker 4:  That's The Vergecast. Thank you to Lauren Finer for being on the show. That's
Speaker 4:  it. That's The Vergecast Rock.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one. One The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Liam James Will Pour and Eric Gomez. And that's it. We'll see you
Speaker 1:  next week.
Speaker 1:  Support for this episode comes from
Speaker 1:  A-W-S-A-W-S.