# Transcript
ID: f4727fd9-e67a-4d8f-86ec-e514c5def252
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6717383381074197807/-3697048683362936912/s93290-US-4723s-1707470547.mp3
Description: The Verge's David Pierce, Alex Cranz, and Adi Robertson discuss sports streaming, Apple Vision Pro updates, Bluesky removing its invite system, and more.
Speaker 5:  Welcome To. The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of multi-stakeholder
Speaker 5:  media companies. I'm your friend David Pierce. NELI Patel is
Speaker 5:  not here, but we all are, which is very exciting. Alex Cranz is here. Hi
Speaker 5:  Alex.
Speaker 3:  Hey, I'm your friend who's ready to do a victory lap. Let's go in second.
Speaker 5:  Let's, it's coming. It's coming. Addie Robertson's here. Hi Addie. We have
Speaker 5:  a lot to talk about this week. There's a bunch of streaming news. Disney
Speaker 5:  did a just all the things we're gonna talk about that, A bunch of Vision
Speaker 5:  Pro stuff. This is like the first week that regular humans got vision pros
Speaker 5:  and it got real weird. So we're gonna talk about that Bluesky stuff, bunch
Speaker 5:  of other stuff. We'll do a big lightning round. But let's start with Disney,
Speaker 5:  right? I feel like we have to start with Disney. I hate, hate, hate talking
Speaker 5:  about earnings on the podcast. Technically it is my least favorite thing,
Speaker 5:  but every once in a while Bob Iger shows up and is like, what's up losers?
Speaker 5:  It's earnings time.
Speaker 3:  Well, I think technically it's not just Disney, right? Like it's Disney and
Speaker 3:  and Warner Brothers discovery. True.
Speaker 5:  Okay. You're right. Fox. So within the Disney story there are like somewhere
Speaker 5:  between two and three individual stories.
Speaker 5:  Yes. We should probably start with the sports thing, right? That was kind
Speaker 5:  of the big streaming wars news of the week and Alex, this is where your victory
Speaker 5:  lap begins. This, this tell us what's going
Speaker 3:  On. Yeah. So what's happening is, is ESPN and Fox, which are both
Speaker 3:  currently owned by Disney, are Oh yeah. Are teaming
Speaker 3:  up with Warner Brothers, which is not owned by Disney currently.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Give it time.
Speaker 3:  Give it time are all coming together to make a giant streaming app,
Speaker 3:  which is effectively what Hulu was back in like 2009, which is
Speaker 3:  when A, B, C and Fox and NBC
Speaker 3:  all eventually came together to make Hulu and like fund Hulu
Speaker 3:  and put all their content on it. It didn't start that way, but that's, that's
Speaker 3:  where it went after like a year or two and that's what's happening now. It's
Speaker 3:  like Hulu for sports. And I said that right as the news broke
Speaker 3:  and then as more came out it was like, yes, I'm right. It is Hulu for sports.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You were increasingly vindicated. Yeah, just bit. So, okay, lemme lemme
Speaker 5:  see if I understand this 'cause we've gotten sort of bits and pieces of information
Speaker 5:  about what this thing is, but it's, it's a streaming service that is launching
Speaker 5:  later this year sometime. Yep. It will have a name. Yep. We don't know
Speaker 5:  what the name is. Warner Brothers is involved. So it will probably be
Speaker 5:  stupid but it will have a name, it's gonna be a
Speaker 5:  mix of all of the linear networks
Speaker 5:  owned by those companies. Right. So like all the ESPNs,
Speaker 5:  all the Fox sports', A, B, C, all the TT of
Speaker 5:  the world,
Speaker 3:  TBS
Speaker 5:  And just like those full channels. Yes. Right. It's just like it is, it is
Speaker 5:  live television of those channels. Sports are not sports. Right, right. Okay.
Speaker 5:  'cause that was one of the big questions is like is this just sports? Is
Speaker 5:  this not it's just, it's just channels. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It'ss just channels, but it basically is sports. Okay. Right. And
Speaker 3:  and and so it's gonna be like, it's gonna be all of these different sports
Speaker 3:  things and then Disney is still saying they're gonna do something with ESPN
Speaker 3:  as its own standalone, which has me wondering what the hell's going on with
Speaker 3:  the ESPN Plus, which I think you are one of the few people
Speaker 3:  I've ever met that was like, yes, this is a rad service.
Speaker 5:  No this is good. Okay. You're explaining that this makes no sense. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Which is the thing that I have been trying to figure out is does this actually
Speaker 5:  make any sense? Because all of that is there right. And then there's going
Speaker 5:  to be what I think amounts to like
Speaker 5:  individual sports, right? Yeah. So the stuff on ESPN plus the stuff that
Speaker 5:  Warner Brothers gets through the Bleacher report,
Speaker 5:  the stuff that Fox has streaming, like all that will also exist
Speaker 5:  inside of this Hulu for sports
Speaker 3:  Theoretically. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Thing.
Speaker 5:  And that's, that's it, right? It will have its own price, you can pay for
Speaker 5:  it, but also If, you wanna watch all of that stuff on the other services
Speaker 5:  that are also part of this. You can, and a lot of that stuff will
Speaker 5:  also be on cable because it's just the cable channels that you're getting
Speaker 5:  in the streaming bundle. So what is this thing?
Speaker 3:  I think, I think it's like a question I think I hear a lot from my brother
Speaker 3:  and sometimes from you and Eli, but you guys are much more technically savvy
Speaker 3:  is streaming is really hard. If, you wanna watch sports? Yes. Like my brother
Speaker 3:  is constantly complaining because he, he thinks okay, I have this sports
Speaker 3:  service that means I can watch the Cowboys anytime I want. Well
Speaker 3:  the Mavericks now, now I can watch the Mavericks anytime I want and and then
Speaker 3:  he'll be like, no, it's a blackout and and it's really annoying
Speaker 3:  and he has to then go buy another streaming service or he has to find someone
Speaker 3:  who like can like stream just that one channel to him and
Speaker 3:  it's all stupid and confusing and this I think is going to potentially reduce
Speaker 3:  that confusion but not a lot because sports streaming is still
Speaker 3:  a huge mess because every single sports like owner
Speaker 3:  like NFL and everybody is selling their rights all over the place in
Speaker 3:  all these different ways and like trying to put all of their eggs
Speaker 3:  in every single basket. And it feels like this is kind of
Speaker 3:  solving for that
Speaker 3:  but kind of not.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It feels like don don't know. Addie, does any of this make any sense
Speaker 5:  to you? Can you explain this to us? Sports as the resident sports lover,
Speaker 5:  the
Speaker 3:  Person, the person who clearly knows
Speaker 6:  Anything about sports. I mean this seems mostly it.
Speaker 6:  That is absolutely the impression I get is that sports is the great thing
Speaker 6:  that streaming hasn't managed to do anything with yet, right? Yes. Which
Speaker 6:  also I think means that there's more of a piracy ecosystem around it in a
Speaker 6:  lot of ways. And I do wonder what impact that's going to have on this
Speaker 6:  at a time when my sense is piracy and all the other areas that streaming
Speaker 6:  once decimated has grown a lot. Yes.
Speaker 5:  That's interesting. Yeah. Yeah. I don't really pirate anything except off
Speaker 5:  of Alex's plex server. Totally legal. But I have
Speaker 5:  watched more sports than I'm proud of on like a TikTok
Speaker 5:  live stream because I literally couldn't find anywhere else to watch it.
Speaker 5:  I generally feel like if I try my hardest to find a legal way to watch something
Speaker 5:  and there isn't one, it's no longer my fault. Which is not a good legal argument,
Speaker 5:  but it's how I feel about streaming. And often with sports I'm like okay,
Speaker 5:  I pay for every single streaming service I can find that will
Speaker 5:  show me sports and still there's like a one in three chance I just can't
Speaker 5:  watch whatever is on. And
Speaker 3:  You pay for Life TV too, right?
Speaker 5:  Not anymore So. I got rid of cable. But the, this is part of the whole thing
Speaker 5:  is like the only reason now to have cable
Speaker 5:  is If you like sports because it is the one place that generally has all
Speaker 5:  the sports. Unless you want, like if you're big into like college volleyball,
Speaker 5:  you're on ESPN Plus, right? But for the most part, live
Speaker 5:  TV is like the last bastion of, it's just where all the things
Speaker 5:  are. Which is very funny because now that's the biggest problem in streaming
Speaker 5:  is there is no place where all the things are. So we all just want cable
Speaker 5:  again. Well
Speaker 3:  And there are also these, these smaller services that do live streaming
Speaker 3:  that sports is kind of what they do. Like I think FUBU is one
Speaker 3:  and Sling TV is another one where like they still have
Speaker 3:  all of these channels and so they've been making 40, $50 a month on people
Speaker 3:  for just this. Right. And they're about to get bodied.
Speaker 5:  Do you think so like is this the end of online tv
Speaker 3:  I, don Dunno, a lot of live tv? No, I don't think it's the end of online,
Speaker 3:  live online tv. I think it's probably going to be
Speaker 3:  devastating for a few specific companies like
Speaker 3:  Sling and fubu. Yeah, right.
Speaker 5:  Who I pay for Sling exclusively to watch sports. Yeah. And I will stop now.
Speaker 3:  Hulu's gonna be fine. Right.
Speaker 3:  Who else does live streaming at this point?
Speaker 5:  YouTube TV is the big one now. YouTube. Yeah. And YouTube TV has even made
Speaker 5:  a big deal out of sports as the reason to have YouTube tv.
Speaker 5:  Like they got the NFL Sunday ticket deal. They paid a whole bunch of money
Speaker 5:  for it's, it's the core thing that YouTube TV is,
Speaker 5:  is a sports package. And increasingly
Speaker 5:  if this thing works and there are a million reasons to think it might not,
Speaker 5:  like did you see guys see the news today that the leagues were blindsided
Speaker 5:  by this and had no idea this was coming, which is bananas. And
Speaker 5:  I feel
Speaker 3:  Like the FTC is gonna be very busy with this soon. I'm
Speaker 6:  Actually curious why this hasn't happened earlier
Speaker 3:  With the, everybody bundling together
Speaker 6:  Just the sports sport. Like a, someone making a really big play for
Speaker 6:  live a large live sports.
Speaker 3:  It's because partially the leagues, the leagues don't, like the leagues wanna
Speaker 3:  control their rights. Their rights are super, super lucrative. Which is why
Speaker 3:  Google spent a ton of money to get YouTube TV and and the
Speaker 3:  NFL Sports
Speaker 5:  Sunday ticket Sunday
Speaker 3:  Ticket. Yeah. There we go. Sports ticket. Sports ticket.
Speaker 5:  It's the same thing. It's, no, I it's, it's, I think it honestly begins and
Speaker 5:  ends there. It is so expensive to have sports and it is like
Speaker 5:  the last thing that is that expensive. And I think it,
Speaker 5:  but I think it spins both ways, right? I think for a while it was like, oh
Speaker 5:  okay, we can use sports to grow our own thing. And
Speaker 5:  I think it was when Max launched that they made a big deal outta
Speaker 5:  Bleacher Report being part of it, right? Right. They were like, we have HBO
Speaker 5:  and we have Bleacher Report as if those things were like equals. And that
Speaker 5:  didn't really work. And now I think all these companies
Speaker 5:  are at a point where it's like, okay, if you're trying to buy sports rights,
Speaker 5:  which again are the best way to win in tv,
Speaker 5:  right? Is to like If, you have the NFL, you're going to have a successful
Speaker 5:  television business. It's just how it works. If, you want to do that?
Speaker 5:  You either have to have tech company money because now
Speaker 5:  Amazon and Apple and Google are all in this fight and they just have infinity
Speaker 5:  money to throw at this or they have to band
Speaker 5:  together and find a way to fight this. Because what the leagues want is
Speaker 5:  they want their stuff to be everywhere, which is why they're also on broadcast
Speaker 5:  tv. Roger Goodell, the NFL commissioner, just gave a long
Speaker 5:  speech basically about how they're not gonna ditch broadcast TV because that's
Speaker 5:  how most people experience the games. It's like that's true and it's gonna
Speaker 5:  be true for a while. So you either have to replace that
Speaker 5:  unbelievable scale with some other kind of unbelievable scale, which I think
Speaker 5:  each of these companies wanted to do. I know for sure Disney has been trying
Speaker 5:  to do this, right? They're like, oh, ESPN is going to be the thing. And they're
Speaker 5:  like, well it's gonna cost you like a hundred billion dollars. And they're
Speaker 5:  like, well nevermind. And so it, it does seem
Speaker 5:  like kind of a sign of desperation out of these companies that they're like,
Speaker 5:  our only chance is to all do this together or else we're host.
Speaker 3:  Well we, we saw that last year because ESPN has been book looking for a partner
Speaker 3:  for a while now and yeah. And apparently it had one over at Fox, which is
Speaker 3:  part of Disney. They could've just like walked down the street and knocked
Speaker 3:  on the door, but like, let's work together, come on. And I,
Speaker 3:  I guess they finally did. And then Warner Brothers who has very, very vocally,
Speaker 3:  like David Zoff has been like, anybody wanna do business with me? I'm ready
Speaker 3:  to do business.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. He's like, I'll buy you, you buy me. I don't care. Let's just whatever
Speaker 5:  you want, let's just, let's sign some checks. And
Speaker 3:  And this like is a great deal for them because most of these,
Speaker 3:  most of these big channels are owned by Disney. Only a few of these channels
Speaker 3:  are owned by Warner Brothers and now they've got like an
Speaker 3:  actual leg into sports, no disrespect to Bleacher Report. They've got an
Speaker 3:  actual leg into like live broadcast sports. Yeah. And that's huge
Speaker 3:  for them. And then these other two have some money bags over in the corner
Speaker 3:  who are gonna pay them more money and hopefully fund whatever
Speaker 3:  massive lawsuits I guess they're gonna deal with from the leagues and
Speaker 3:  probably the FTC. It does absolutely feel like the kind of
Speaker 6:  Consolidation that the FTC right now is, is
Speaker 3:  Gonna be
Speaker 6:  Like. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Hmm.
Speaker 5:  Do you think I've been, I've been going back and forth on this. 'cause on
Speaker 5:  the one hand it's just a thing they're all doing together, right? And I think
Speaker 5:  the case that they seem to be making to each other and to the sports
Speaker 5:  leagues and to the world is like, this isn't a new product. We're just taking
Speaker 5:  a bunch of existing things. Like one of the things I was reading made an
Speaker 5:  interesting case that the fact that they are linear streaming
Speaker 5:  channels and not some new way of disseminating
Speaker 5:  the content is how they've managed to do this without signing new deals with
Speaker 5:  the league. And don don't know if that's true or not, but I assume the case
Speaker 5:  that they're gonna make is, this is okay because it's all, you know, stuff
Speaker 5:  we were doing anyway, we're just packaging it differently. But I have a hard
Speaker 5:  time imagining that's how it reads to feel like Han or anyone else.
Speaker 6:  We've just spent a bunch of time talking about these small streaming players
Speaker 6:  that are going to get bodied by this. Yeah. And that is just the biggest
Speaker 6:  argument that Yeah. That people could make.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think that's probably right.
Speaker 3:  It's all down to Fuo, FUO and Sling TV are about to change
Speaker 3:  the history of sports broadcasting in America.
Speaker 5:  But wait, let's talk about Hulu because yeah, the, you made
Speaker 5:  the case when this is first coming out that this is Hulu for sports, right?
Speaker 5:  Which congratulations, you were precisely correct on that. We should also
Speaker 5:  probably do a disclosure here. Let's see, NELI ISS not here so we'll, we'll
Speaker 5:  do it. Comcast is an minority investor in Vox Media
Speaker 5:  through its subsidiary NBC Universal, which owns Peacock, notably
Speaker 5:  not a part of this. Notably also owns lots of sports rights as does CBS and
Speaker 5:  Paramount plus. So lots of sports still not in this.
Speaker 5:  We made a Netflix show. It's good. I had nothing to do with it. Y'all might
Speaker 5:  have, it's a show. Oh, you did
Speaker 6:  An interview.
Speaker 5:  There you go. So Addie is wildly conflicted. Oh my
Speaker 3:  God. Addie, why are you doing
Speaker 5:  Don Don't know other things. Alex as a black server, I have a black dubious
Speaker 5:  legality. But we should just
Speaker 5:  like, let's, let's do a little bit of a retrospective on whether
Speaker 5:  Hulu was a good idea because If you rewind a million years ago, it was
Speaker 5:  sort of a similar thing, right? They were like, okay, Netflix exists.
Speaker 5:  What we need is a way to take all the things that we like about broadcast
Speaker 5:  TV on the internet. Well
Speaker 3:  They weren't even fighting Netflix at the time. They were explicitly fighting
Speaker 3:  pirates. Like they were they were No, that's right. It was Torrance. They,
Speaker 3:  they were, they were fed up with Torrance. don don't know who does those.
Speaker 3:  And and they were too super upset with it. And so they said So I think it
Speaker 3:  was like NBC Universal was one of the first ones was like, Hey, let's, it
Speaker 3:  got with some private equity companies and, and made this deal. And then
Speaker 3:  A, B, C and Fox, who at that point, only one of them was owned
Speaker 3:  by Disney all said, oh, we, we wanna be in on this too. We want like a
Speaker 3:  nice controlled way to get our stuff out there without having to manage
Speaker 3:  like abc.go.com. Remember that website? Oh yeah.
Speaker 3:  And, and so they said, okay, let's all bundle together. Let's, let's do it
Speaker 3:  this way. And then CBS was like, F you guys we're gonna go do
Speaker 3:  our own thing. And eventually that became Paramount Plus, which
Speaker 5:  Is weird. We we choose not to reference CBS all Access.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It was like, it, it just went off and did its own thing. But everybody
Speaker 3:  else came together to fight piracy and at the time Hulu was
Speaker 3:  huge. Like it was like the second most followed website after like YouTube
Speaker 3:  or something at the time because people were really into it. 'cause they
Speaker 3:  got all the stuff and then everybody immediately started to like
Speaker 3:  bicker and, and fight. Because apparently when you have all of these huge
Speaker 3:  egos and, and big companies in the room all trying to work together,
Speaker 3:  they don't. So Right.
Speaker 5:  Well, and and I feel like that the other reason this is
Speaker 5:  just Hulu again is it's that dynamic. Exactly. Yeah. Right. It's, I don't
Speaker 5:  think pirates are so much the fight here. Like I, I really
Speaker 5:  increasingly believe this is about like rights consolidation and making sure
Speaker 5:  a hundred they can, they can like continue to stay in the game together and
Speaker 5:  build a sports thing. Both because it's what people want and because it's
Speaker 5:  the only way any of them can afford it. But this sense of like, okay, if
Speaker 5:  we don't give people one place to come to do it, they will find other ways
Speaker 5:  that are worse for us. Yeah. Which is what Hulu was. And Hulu really worked
Speaker 5:  because it was like, oh I wanna watch Parks and Rec, which was just on tv.
Speaker 5:  I can either go torrent it tomorrow or I can just go to Hulu tomorrow. And
Speaker 5:  everybody went to Hulu 'cause it was easier. Yep. It was like it was Spotify
Speaker 5:  in the music industry, like same thing. But then it turns out that
Speaker 5:  having three large companies own a company together
Speaker 5:  goes badly. Yeah. And like, you know, who's been through this now is Disney
Speaker 5:  Disney knows this better than anybody and is now willingly
Speaker 5:  signing up for this again, Disney just screwed itself into paying like
Speaker 5:  20 billion more dollars to acquire the rest of Hulu from Comcast after all
Speaker 5:  of this. And now is just happily jumping back
Speaker 5:  into bed in this exact same agreement again. It doesn't make any sense to
Speaker 5:  me. I
Speaker 3:  Think it, it kind of makes sense. I think Disney has been facing a lot
Speaker 3:  of existential crisises with its various bus businesses. Fair.
Speaker 3:  Particularly broadcast tv, particularly ESPN. And
Speaker 3:  this gives them like a lot of opportunity to make some money back and make
Speaker 3:  those businesses viable again provided they don't get
Speaker 3:  fully bodied by the FTC Fu Bo, everyone
Speaker 3:  else involved. I'm honestly, let's
Speaker 6:  Just be clear that no matter what the FTC does, the FTC also tends to have
Speaker 6:  to go through the courts and the FTC has not a great track record with
Speaker 6:  the courts
Speaker 5:  Right now. Yeah, no. They mostly lose.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So that's fair. That's fair. They'll get like bodied on
Speaker 3:  Twitter or excuse me, they'll get like bodied on Threads, maybe X
Speaker 3:  possibly TikTok.
Speaker 5:  I think Bob Iger will get over it. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I think he'll survive it.
Speaker 5:  And speaking of Bob Iger, so let's, let's switch to the other story here.
Speaker 5:  'cause I think the other thing happening at Disney right now is like
Speaker 5:  Disney is both I think to your point kind of in an existential crisis.
Speaker 5:  It's been a weird couple of years for Disney. It's not growing as fast as
Speaker 5:  it wanted to. It's not making much money as it wanted to. ESPN is still this
Speaker 5:  like giant fountain of cash. Yeah. That now seems threatened. So they're
Speaker 5:  trying to figure out all this other stuff and yet our man Bob Iger
Speaker 5:  shows up to the earnings this week and is really like kind of feeling himself
Speaker 5:  rolls out these big giant initiatives and it's just like, what's up everybody?
Speaker 5:  Like we're still the Walt Disney company.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It was it, it had like big Bob Capic energy
Speaker 3:  particularly 'cause it was so like tech focused. A lot of the stuff he was
Speaker 3:  saying. 'cause one of the things is that they're gonna have their own like
Speaker 3:  persistent universe tied to Fortnite, which we
Speaker 3:  don't entirely know what that means or what that's gonna look like. We have
Speaker 3:  a vague idea, but it's got Fortnite, persistent
Speaker 3:  universe and Disney involved. So that sounds like money and cool.
Speaker 5:  It feels like that's gonna
Speaker 3:  Work. Yeah. It feels like that. That's like a Bob Chappy. Like that's the
Speaker 3:  sort of thing he wanted to do. Right? Like he wanted to turn his that's true
Speaker 3:  company into a tech company. And so this is like, okay, this is giving them
Speaker 3:  some inroads and taking their their like terrific IP
Speaker 3:  and putting it out there in the Fortnite space and and making those deals.
Speaker 3:  And then you also have like, okay, they're gonna start cracking down on Disney
Speaker 3:  plus password sharing, which is another like tech thing where it's like,
Speaker 3:  okay, no more free rides. Get outta here. Which Bob did when he was
Speaker 3:  like, no more free rides at Disney World or
Speaker 5:  Whatever he did. And Bob Iger was like, how dare you do that. Yeah. That's
Speaker 5:  so hostile to our customers. We love everybody who comes to Disney World.
Speaker 5:  How dare you raise prices. But he
Speaker 3:  Doesn't love people who share passwords. Yeah. Don't do it. Bob will hate
Speaker 3:  you. Well
Speaker 5:  Let's, let's talk about this Fortnite thing. 'cause I think this was
Speaker 5:  a surprise in a lot of ways. Disney said they're
Speaker 5:  investing $1.5 billion, I think in Epic
Speaker 5:  to create a, a persistent universe, as you said. Yeah. tied to
Speaker 5:  Fortnite. Again, we have no details on this, but Disney and
Speaker 5:  Epic have partnered a ton on stuff over the years. Yeah. There's been all
Speaker 5:  kinds of Marvel stuff inside of Fortnite and my sense is this stuff has done
Speaker 5:  very well and feels like in a lot of ways kind of a natural
Speaker 5:  place for Disney as a company to go. Right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I, the absolute first thing I thought is, oh, I kind of thought this
Speaker 6:  had already somehow happened.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So, I mean I think what we've seen from Fortnite over
Speaker 5:  the last year or from Epic really is this idea that they can take the thing
Speaker 5:  that is Fortnite and the Unreal engine underneath it and build it out into
Speaker 5:  more stuff. Right. They did, they did Lego Fortnite. They have the racing
Speaker 5:  game that I can't remember the name of right now, but it's very fun and everybody
Speaker 5:  should play and there's just like, there is a universe around Fortnite now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That seems very powerful.
Speaker 6:  Which also ties into, it seems like what they kind of want to be is
Speaker 6:  corporate Roblox. Yeah. Roblox is incredibly popular. Roblox
Speaker 6:  is also just the Junkiest thing in the world. Yes. You go to a website and
Speaker 6:  click on a thing and you find like a prison simulator made by a 13-year-old
Speaker 3:  By my godson. Loves it.
Speaker 6:  This is more it is. They want to be a game full
Speaker 6:  of games and, but it's these very well recognized
Speaker 6:  ips
Speaker 5:  And it seems like if that's the goal, you literally could not imagine a better
Speaker 5:  partner than Disney, right? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So is is Roblox Well
Speaker 6:  Lego was a pretty good partner.
Speaker 5:  Lego's That's true Lego. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Because they did Lego first, right? Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  Lego for and Lego Fortnite bio accounts is doing super well and makes sense.
Speaker 5:  It's like, the thing I keep coming back to is like, I'm, I'm very old.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And So I play Fortnite, like, it's like a game for shooting most
Speaker 5:  people, especially younger than me, because again, I'm very old.
Speaker 5:  Fortnite is just like a place to hang out. It's
Speaker 3:  Just a place to like do fun stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And there's like, there are, there are purely creative worlds in Fortnite
Speaker 5:  where you just go to build stuff and it's, the Roblox is kind of the same
Speaker 5:  thing, right? Like the, the being there is the point. And like
Speaker 5:  Disney world, it just, it just is digital Disney world in so many
Speaker 5:  ways. And I feel like Disney, I'm almost
Speaker 5:  surprised Disney didn't try to do this itself, but it seems like a
Speaker 5:  big, big bet on who is going to win this race that it would pick Epic to
Speaker 5:  go with.
Speaker 6:  I also think the scaffolding of a game, even if you're mostly hanging out,
Speaker 6:  is really important. Just because we have seen at this point, two or three
Speaker 6:  decades of things like MMOs tend to be really successful
Speaker 6:  even if people are using them to get married or hang
Speaker 6:  out with friends. Whereas things like Horizon where the
Speaker 6:  entire goal is why don't you do the things you do in real life but you can't
Speaker 6:  actually get any of the sensory experience. It seems like people just don't
Speaker 6:  like, obviously some people use them. Things like VR chat definitely have
Speaker 6:  a a base. Yeah. But I think it's a little less intuitive
Speaker 6:  why you should get into them. I
Speaker 3:  Mean, my godson, I was back in in Texas
Speaker 3:  recently and that night he's like, I'm gonna play Roblox with my friends.
Speaker 3:  And we were like, all right, cool. And we off, we went off to the rodeo.
Speaker 3:  We came back that night and he was asleep. We get up the next morning and
Speaker 3:  he's like, my favorite game in the world is Lego Fortnite. The
Speaker 3:  babysitter showed it to me and now I'm obsessed. And that's all he plays
Speaker 3:  now. Like, it was just like an instant drug for him. And he was not a big
Speaker 3:  Fortnite player. He was like Roblox fan. But that like, it was just very
Speaker 3:  clear, built that world to give him that thing and then he could be like,
Speaker 3:  there's my babysitter's house over there in Fortnite. And I was like, well
Speaker 3:  that's a little creepy. But also I love this for you and I love that she
Speaker 3:  has the patience to play this with you 'cause you're eight. Yeah. but it's
Speaker 3:  like, it's a very weird, like, it's not weird, but it's just kind of
Speaker 3:  how quick it is for, for people to just jump into it and, and
Speaker 3:  it feels like with Disney that's just gonna be like huge.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, yeah. Having the pull of like characters you
Speaker 5:  recognize and that storytelling that Disney is so good at goes a really
Speaker 5:  long way. but it, it breaks my brain to think about all of this. Because
Speaker 5:  on the one hand, I think the two things that this says to me are Epic
Speaker 5:  is winning in some vague but real way.
Speaker 5:  And also that we're all still betting on this idea
Speaker 5:  of the Metaverse being a thing. And I really thought we had just given up
Speaker 5:  on that idea. Like I've made so much fun of the whole concept of the Metaverse
Speaker 5:  for the last two years. And now I'm sitting here being like, this is an unbelievably
Speaker 5:  good idea. Of course Disney is dating.
Speaker 6:  I feel vindicated because I feel like that it was not me who wrote this,
Speaker 6:  but several people just said, look, the Metaverse is just video games.
Speaker 6:  It's just that we went through a weird period where a bunch of men in
Speaker 6:  suits decided that we, what if it was video games, but
Speaker 6:  minus the things that people actually like about video games. I
Speaker 3:  Feel like you used to make the point a lot that Roblox was the metaverse
Speaker 3:  and like Roblox was one of the biggest metaverses, right.
Speaker 6:  I think And when Roblox itself decided it wanted to make that point. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  true. That's too, it it ended up changing its name away from
Speaker 6:  games. And that's also I think kind of silly because clearly
Speaker 6:  what people are doing games there. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's what they think.
Speaker 6:  Even they're highly social.
Speaker 3:  Right.
Speaker 6:  But I just, I think we've gotten away from the idea that you're going to
Speaker 6:  work in Fortnite, which is kind of what I associate the metaverse
Speaker 6:  boom of the pandemic era with.
Speaker 5:  So there's no like B2B Fortnite software
Speaker 6:  Is that Roblox told all its employees to come into the office
Speaker 6:  because you can't work in Roblox.
Speaker 3:  We try to work in Lego Fortnite.
Speaker 5:  I'm down. I would try that. Yeah. I do podcast in Lego Fortnite. Yeah. Come
Speaker 5:  on, let's
Speaker 3:  Do a whole show in Lego Fortnite. We can do it.
Speaker 5:  I'll wear Myre Meta smart glasses. Same. And we'll, we'll hang out on Lego
Speaker 5:  Fortnite. It'll be sick. So you, you like
Speaker 5:  this thing works for you. You're, you're in on this concept. Like,
Speaker 6:  I mean, not me personally, but it makes sense to me.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Why not you personally?
Speaker 6:  Because I don't like being around other people virtually.
Speaker 5:  That's honest. Yeah. Okay. I respect that. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I I think this part of Disney feels
Speaker 5:  like in many ways the biggest bet where like
Speaker 5:  it's, they're still very much calling Disney like the Disney plus
Speaker 5:  company. Like that is the thing. Disney needs to work, but Disney
Speaker 5:  spent I think $2 billion to do a gambling thing that
Speaker 5:  will work because it's sports gambling and it can't help but work. It's doing
Speaker 5:  great. Yeah. But this feels like in terms of sort of big swings with
Speaker 5:  a lot of room for error and a lot of like monstrous room for success,
Speaker 5:  the the Epic thing seems like it could be a big Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Because I feel like Disney when it comes to games has had like a
Speaker 3:  very mixed run of things. Right. Like they've had some good stuff,
Speaker 3:  they've had some bad stuff.
Speaker 5:  That's true. Disney's not, I'm trying to think of the good, they've licensed
Speaker 5:  games based on Disney IP and they're
Speaker 3:  Like, they've licensed stuff. So you have like Kingdom Hearts and they're
Speaker 6:  Many Star Wars games. All of the
Speaker 3:  Star Wars,
Speaker 5:  They do exist. Right.
Speaker 3:  But then they
Speaker 5:  Are they good and fun and exciting and worth playing. Yeah. Shit.
Speaker 3:  Disney's also had like it own, they're out there internal studios and then
Speaker 3:  it's like moved away from those internal studios. I think under Bob chap
Speaker 3:  it, it, it did some a lot of like heavy reorg Yeah. With the
Speaker 3:  studios. And, and so this is like an interesting, almost like return
Speaker 3:  to form for Disney to be like Oh yeah. Games.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean the thing I associate mo weirdly most with it is, is we inspector's
Speaker 6:  Epic Mickey. Yes. That's which I don think anyone would really call a, an
Speaker 6:  absolutely massive financial success.
Speaker 3:  No, but it was like, that was at the most Disney of Disney games. Right.
Speaker 3:  Like, that was like, anytime I think of a video game of Disney, I go back
Speaker 3:  to him being like, yeah, you're gonna paint your way like into The future
Speaker 3:  with like Mickey Mouse say
Speaker 6:  Revel was symbolic of that period though. That was like the height of
Speaker 6:  prestige aa single player games.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I just Googled best Disney video games ever just to make sure there wasn't
Speaker 5:  like an obvious one I was missing. And we're looking at things like Castle
Speaker 5:  of Illusion starring Mickey Mouse from 1990 and Quack Shot
Speaker 5:  from 1991. Like the track record's not amazing.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. And so they, they've got all these terrific IP that
Speaker 3:  they've been very good at selling out to other companies and now doing this
Speaker 3:  with Epic in what seems like a, it is gonna be a much tighter
Speaker 3:  relationship. I'll be really curious to see what happens there.
Speaker 3:  And also if it explodes, it's gonna be like really
Speaker 3:  interesting to watch.
Speaker 5:  It's also very fun that this is one of Apple's best friends Yes.
Speaker 5:  Partnering with one of Apple's Mortal enemies. Yeah. Which I just enjoy
Speaker 5:  very much. Like Bob Iger and Tim Cook are going to have a lot of
Speaker 5:  very polite, very testy phone calls over the next couple of years. And I'm
Speaker 5:  very excited about it. Yeah. It's gonna be great times. Oh my God.
Speaker 6:  I mean, Disney was a big launch partner. It was supposed to be for The Vision
Speaker 6:  Pro. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, you can, you can go hang out, you can watch a movie like I think in,
Speaker 3:  in Darth Vader's Palace
Speaker 3:  for something. It's,
Speaker 6:  I don't remember if it is that exactly, but yes, it is Disney definitely
Speaker 6:  Star Wars themed. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. There's, I think there's one that's like on on the Volcano Planet where
Speaker 3:  he lived for a while. I know far too much about Star Wars apparently.
Speaker 3:  Judging by both of your faces.
Speaker 6:  Oh no, I remember, I remember all those things. I'm trying to remember because
Speaker 6:  I went into the theater and I do not remember where it was. I wanted
Speaker 6:  to say Tattoo Queen
Speaker 3:  Is there Was there,
Speaker 5:  Oh, there was a tattooed that I know Tattoo Queen. Yeah. I don't know if
Speaker 5:  there were others, but there was definitely a tattoo. Maybe
Speaker 3:  I just made up Darth Vader. I wanna watch a movie on Darth Vader's like thrown
Speaker 5:  It's a good idea in his giant house. Listen, I know for sure Bob Iger is
Speaker 5:  listening to this podcast. So Bob, get it done. Do make it happen. Come on.
Speaker 5:  Alright, one more thing before we switch gears and take a break here. I don
Speaker 5:  Know If, you guys saw it, but the, the Feistiest argument of the week on
Speaker 5:  Threads, everyone's favorite feisty social media platform
Speaker 5:  was about Apple TV Plus and HBO. Yeah. And I just, I
Speaker 5:  just wanna, I just wanna feel everybody out on, on how we feel about this.
Speaker 5:  So Wired wrote a story basically positing that Apple TV
Speaker 5:  is the new HBO and that it's, it is where you go to get
Speaker 5:  basically nothing but very good things. They don't do that much, but the
Speaker 5:  things that they do are very good. And then Lucas Shaw, who's a reporter
Speaker 5:  at Bloomberg and very good and knows this stuff better than most quote tweeted
Speaker 5:  somebody saying something to the effect of anyone writing something like
Speaker 5:  this should be required to say that nobody watches Apple TV Plus. And the
Speaker 5:  feelings that that brought out in people on the internet, people
Speaker 5:  blogged about it, people posted about it. People got very angry at Lucas.
Speaker 5:  Somebody called him a funny name that he then quote tweeted and it just became
Speaker 5:  this whole thing. But I, I think the, the question underneath it
Speaker 5:  is like, is Apple TV the the
Speaker 5:  one now? Like is it, is it, is it the best one?
Speaker 5:  Is an interesting one.
Speaker 3:  I mean, here, here's a question if, do you like science fiction?
Speaker 5:  Sometimes.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Do you like weird
Speaker 3:  modernist takes on historical women's stories?
Speaker 5:  Yes. Okay. Universally,
Speaker 3:  And do you like Ted Lasso?
Speaker 5:  This is Scar Accurate
Speaker 3:  If, you like those three things then like Apple TV is great.
Speaker 3:  I think Apple TV Plus is very much like HBO in that it has
Speaker 3:  really high standards. It maintains those really high standards. And like
Speaker 3:  HBO for a very long time, nobody watched it. Everybody's just like, like
Speaker 3:  we, we love to be like, oh yeah, HBO Game of Thrones Game of Thrones is huge.
Speaker 3:  It, it's massive. And a ton of people watched Game of Thrones that
Speaker 3:  was not normal for HBO. That was a surprise
Speaker 3:  and a shock and a delight for HBO. And,
Speaker 5:  And also I'm pretty sure that like the Game of Thrones ratings would've
Speaker 5:  been like a pretty bad episode at the Big Bang Theory. No,
Speaker 6:  No, there were still, yeah. Isn't, I just don't say a conflict between the
Speaker 6:  two things you just mentioned. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's totally fair.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I think they were doing like 10, 11 million average viewers for,
Speaker 3:  which was massive for HBO. Yeah. And at the time for broadcast TV was
Speaker 3:  like pretty Okay. But you know, you think about the Mash finale
Speaker 3:  or was it Grey's? My, my big one is Grey's Anatomy Season two
Speaker 3:  was over 20 million people watching it. So you're like,
Speaker 3:  no. Yeah. I, I, 20 million people did not watch the,
Speaker 3:  the latest season of for all mankind. They should have.
Speaker 6:  I guess the thing that interests me about this comparison is that a lot of
Speaker 6:  the way that I experienced early, like Prestige TV and HBO shows was through
Speaker 6:  a critic's ecosystem that doesn't exist anymore. That a lot of
Speaker 6:  the, I think you've written about this, that there was the idea that
Speaker 6:  nobody's, like, not that many people are watching this show, but every critic,
Speaker 6:  you know, is watching this show. Yes. Everything on the internet is writing
Speaker 6:  about it. There are these whole little ecosystems. I'm really curious what
Speaker 6:  that looks like for Apple.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And I think Apple's been doing kind of okay with it. That's one of
Speaker 3:  the reasons it's gone so far into science fiction is because like you have
Speaker 3:  Monarch, which is a big show that's based in, in the Godzilla world, and
Speaker 3:  it does ask you to care about the Godzilla movies. You shouldn't,
Speaker 5:  But it, it wants you to so bad. It wants
Speaker 3:  You to, and the show is, the show is legitimately good. I think it's got
Speaker 3:  a great like time ahead of it. And same with for all mankind,
Speaker 3:  but it doesn't really, like, they're not really hitting
Speaker 3:  at the same kind of like pace that traditionally those critically
Speaker 3:  acclaimed like shows like we don't have a television without pity anymore.
Speaker 3:  AV club is very, very different than it was 10, 15 years ago, shit,
Speaker 3:  five years ago. And, and so You don't have those like
Speaker 3:  conversations happening. Instead you have like people on TikTok
Speaker 3:  going through and judging Emma Stone's favorite movies and saying why they
Speaker 3:  suck, which is like not particularly useful criticism. Or
Speaker 3:  you have, what is it? You have Threads and, and people making fun of
Speaker 3:  Lucas for something. He was right about like, nobody watches Apple TV except
Speaker 3:  for B and David I think. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Well there were, there were a lot of people who responded being like, well
Speaker 5:  Apple TV Plus has 25 million subscribers.
Speaker 3:  That's different than how many people viewers.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. They all watch Ted Lasso. Yeah. They, I'll give you that. They
Speaker 5:  did all watch Ted Lasso
Speaker 3:  And then they, they they maybe watched, did they watch Foundation? Probably
Speaker 3:  not Severance.
Speaker 5:  They all said they watched Foundation. Yeah. They watched like an episode
Speaker 5:  and a half and they're like, yeah, totally. The
Speaker 3:  Only person in the world who watched all of Foundation is Dan Seaford.
Speaker 5:  And he's, and then they had to leave The Verge because of it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. That's why he's not at The Verge anymore is because we found out he
Speaker 3:  watched all of Foundation and we were like, wow.
Speaker 5:  No, but Addie I think you're the point you're making about critics made me
Speaker 5:  think of something which is that like, even still, like I think about a,
Speaker 5:  a website like The Ringer, which is a lot of really good pop culture coverage.
Speaker 5:  They sort of instinctively cover every new
Speaker 5:  like 9:00 PM on Sunday HBO show. Right. Because there's just an assumption
Speaker 5:  that this show sort of matters, right? Whether it's the White Lotus or
Speaker 5:  succession or any of those kind of handful of times
Speaker 5:  a year shows that gets out.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I'm getting that true detective right now. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Totally. And there's just a like cultural
Speaker 5:  assumption that this show is relevant because it is like the Sunday night
Speaker 5:  show on HBO Apple TV definitely doesn't have that. No.
Speaker 5:  Like I could not tell you what day any Apple TV show comes out, which I think
Speaker 5:  is like a meaningful thing. Was
Speaker 3:  Ted Lasso Tuesdays?
Speaker 5:  I honestly couldn't tell you like the, the only streaming one in general
Speaker 5:  I remember was the first season of the Mandalorian on
Speaker 5:  Disney Plus came out Friday mornings. And I had friends who would
Speaker 5:  literally like wake up early in the morning on Friday morning to watch the
Speaker 5:  show in order to like be able to talk about it at work. And so like
Speaker 5:  that's the level that you get to. And I think HBO just sort of is granted
Speaker 5:  that level of, of cultural relevance, even if it's not real.
Speaker 5:  Like we were just looking this up before we started and 4 million people
Speaker 5:  watched the series finale of succession, like one of the great TV
Speaker 5:  shows that every critic on the internet was writing about, which is like
Speaker 5:  half the number of people who watch an episode of Chicago Fire, like everybody's
Speaker 5:  95th favorite TV show.
Speaker 5:  But nothing has hit that sort of cultural
Speaker 5:  relevance that HBO just gets to have because it's an
Speaker 5:  HBO. Yeah. And even that Apple TV has a lot of good shows. I actually think,
Speaker 5:  like If, you just took 50 random shows from
Speaker 5:  any streaming service. I would bet that Apple TVs are better
Speaker 5:  than any random 50 on any other restric.
Speaker 3:  And that's what there were, I mean that was like the kind of the core argument
Speaker 3:  I think of that HBO piece. The Apple TV plus piece was that
Speaker 3:  hey, it like pound for pound. It's, it's, it's hitting above its weight.
Speaker 3:  Like it's, it's doing well. Yeah, I think that's probably right. But it's
Speaker 3:  also, it's not doing true detective numbers. It's not doing
Speaker 3:  Chicago fire numbers. And historically Prestige TV
Speaker 3:  doesn't do Chicago fire numbers. That's why part of why it's Prestige TV
Speaker 3:  is because a lot of people say, I don't wanna watch that. It's too smart.
Speaker 5:  It's too prestigious.
Speaker 3:  It's too prestigious.
Speaker 5:  I will say though, and we need to take a break, but criminal record on Apple
Speaker 5:  TV Plus Kicks Ass, I'm pretty sure it's not gonna land the plane and it's
Speaker 5:  not gonna make any sense at the end, but it's like five episodes in and they've
Speaker 5:  all been great. So I, love this one. Highly recommend, but I might take that
Speaker 5:  back. Anyway, we need to take a break. We'll be right back.
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back. Let's talk Vision. Pro.
Speaker 5:  So as you're listening to this on Friday, it's now been a week since The
Speaker 5:  Vision Pro came out into the world. We've got a bunch of news, but
Speaker 5:  Addie I just want you to like describe the vibes of what you've seen from
Speaker 5:  a week of Vision Pro being in the world.
Speaker 6:  It feels like I've seen sort of three things. One is
Speaker 6:  everyone noticing all of the little annoying things about The, Vision Pro
Speaker 6:  that NELI and the rest of us noticed. Two is people
Speaker 6:  going, oh wow, I'm like a developer or I'm a person who is interested
Speaker 6:  in technology and this thing is a technologically interesting system, both
Speaker 6:  of which were, I feel like kind of prefigured by our review. Yes. The third
Speaker 6:  is this thing's really expensive. This is a cloud symbol.
Speaker 5:  Agreed. And that is the one I should have seen coming more
Speaker 5:  than I did. I think I sort of took it as this thing is
Speaker 5:  really expensive. Maybe it'll be kind of
Speaker 5:  ridiculous and g to wear outside. Holy God. Was I wrong?
Speaker 5:  No. Oh man. Was I wrong?
Speaker 3:  You're right. You're still right. Don't don't. It's still Gsh.
Speaker 5:  I'm right in the abstract, Don, I'm wrong. In actual reality, don't
Speaker 3:  Give people power.
Speaker 5:  I mean, what was it? I think, I think Jake posted something on the site.
Speaker 5:  The headline of the quick post he did was just, it's been 10 hours and
Speaker 5:  this is a video of a man in his car driving while
Speaker 5:  wearing a Vision Pro, which like we knew was gonna happen. And we got a bunch
Speaker 5:  of cyber track, wasn't impressed. Posts from people saying, boy, you guys
Speaker 5:  called this. And I kept being like, this was not a tough call guys. Like
Speaker 5:  this was what it was gonna be. But now we've seen, we've seen people walking
Speaker 5:  around the mall, you see people on the subway. Like you're totally right.
Speaker 5:  That being the person with this out in the world
Speaker 5:  makes you interesting. And I don't think that'll last, but it's very much
Speaker 5:  where right now I,
Speaker 6:  I feel like there are two ways this could go. One is the iPhone, which having
Speaker 6:  an iPhone in the early days, like if somebody else had one, you were like,
Speaker 6:  oh my God, iPhone. Totally. The other way is, I remember Google Glass,
Speaker 6:  I remember the period like the week or two where Google Glass, it was like,
Speaker 6:  oh, this is so exotic. All of these models where it, it's like this
Speaker 6:  incredibly exciting sci-fi thing. And it looked a lot, a lot cooler than
Speaker 6:  The Vision Pro, frankly. Yes. And then within a month or two you were getting
Speaker 6:  banned from bars. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  No, no. I I a hundred percent it's gonna be that side because right now all
Speaker 3:  the people doing it aren't using The Vision Pro correctly, which was pointed
Speaker 3:  out to me by someone in our office who has a Vision Pro.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. If you're walking down the street with a Vision Pro on just like
Speaker 5:  pinch, pinching the air, you're not doing anything. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Apparently you can only have one. Sorry. Apparently you can only have one
Speaker 3:  window open and you have to hold it like this all the time. So theoretically
Speaker 3:  the only way to actually make it,
Speaker 5:  It's carrying your window
Speaker 6:  Down the street,
Speaker 3:  Walking around like that. And I'm like, yeah, you guys, and he got so mad,
Speaker 3:  he was like, they're not doing it right. You can only have one window at
Speaker 3:  a time. And he was like walking through the office showing us how to make
Speaker 3:  it works.
Speaker 5:  I was kind of hoping it would be like, you wake up in the morning and you
Speaker 5:  like walk to the subway, just sort of leaving browser tabs behind you. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And then you just pick them all up on the way home. You just, you come back
Speaker 5:  out, you put it on and it's like, oh cool. There's all this stuff I had to
Speaker 5:  do today. Like, that sounds awesome. That is super not how it works.
Speaker 3:  No,
Speaker 6:  I would just like to note also, this is a thing that I have had many people
Speaker 6:  mention about pass through is I am waiting someday
Speaker 6:  this thing is going to crash while you are wearing it, it is going to be
Speaker 6:  incredibly annoying to suddenly be blind. Yeah, yeah. While you are driving.
Speaker 6:  Right.
Speaker 3:  Don't drive with it. Yeah. Don't be dumb.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's a good, just quick PSA don't do that. Yeah. Just don't, don't
Speaker 5:  do that. Well
Speaker 3:  I think like when, when when the Wall Street Journal did theirs,
Speaker 3:  when Joanna did her her review and she did like a ski slope thing, they just
Speaker 3:  shut down the ski slope. 'cause they were like, oh, we can't have other people
Speaker 3:  like on this slope with her. And what if she goes blind right
Speaker 3:  into somebody can't have that happen. So it's like, oh boy, don't, don't
Speaker 3:  drive with it.
Speaker 5:  I like that Joanna shows up and she's like, guys, I have an N-D-A-I-I have
Speaker 5:  to do this separately. And they're like, don't worry, we don't won't anywhere
Speaker 5:  run around you anyway. Like you're cool. but it
Speaker 5:  doesn seem like the people have landed on the thing that
Speaker 5:  we've all been talking about for the better part of a year now, which is
Speaker 5:  like, this thing is a, is a television that seems to be overwhelmingly the
Speaker 5:  takeaway is like, like you're saying, there's some cool technological
Speaker 5:  stuff going on here in in certain like engineering ways. This thing is
Speaker 5:  masterful and amazing, kind of useless for a lot of things,
Speaker 5:  but holy crap, is it a great TV watching experience That's like the
Speaker 5:  thing I've seen overwhelmingly seems to be that
Speaker 6:  Which is driving me insane because it is a TV that I cannot
Speaker 6:  use in the way that I would use a TV because it is single user, the single
Speaker 6:  user this of this thing has been driving me just up a wall for a week.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Oh no, I completely agree. And you're
Speaker 3:  Getting mad, like watching you think here
Speaker 6:  I'm, I'm angry. Like I'm genuinely angry because I have
Speaker 6:  so many electronics and I look, I share them with a person.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And the point is, we are both able to use this thing
Speaker 6:  and I can't, it's not just like, oh, it's fitted for your face or whatever.
Speaker 6:  It's, you literally can't use the interface. Right. It won't recognize your
Speaker 6:  eyes. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  We we haven't all been using Eli's review unit because
Speaker 3:  we can't.
Speaker 6:  Right. I mean, you can start a guest, like, to be clear, the thing that happens
Speaker 6:  is there's one person who can own this thing. It recognizes them. You can
Speaker 6:  start a guest session by pressing the button and then you have to do this
Speaker 6:  like minute long calibration process of picking colored Dots out. Yeah. And
Speaker 6:  then it can recognize you and it can recognize you basically until it swaps
Speaker 6:  back. And then you have to start a new guest session. So there is gets to
Speaker 6:  be one designated TV user in the house.
Speaker 3:  That's it. No one else watches TV in the house.
Speaker 6:  Everyone else has to spend a minute getting their TV ready.
Speaker 5:  And I do think I, I was less worried about this
Speaker 5:  before it launched than I have become now. I'm with you. I think it's, it's
Speaker 5:  actually the single biggest thing missing from The. Vision Pro right now
Speaker 5:  is decent multi-user support. Because if it is a
Speaker 5:  television and or a game console, it's gonna be a thing you pick up
Speaker 5:  put on use for a bit and then put down. Right. It is, it is a
Speaker 5:  like very much a, an episodic device like all headsets are right now. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like Chris Grant made this point on this show a while ago, and I haven't
Speaker 5:  stopped thinking about it ever since. I was like, oh, why aren't there VR
Speaker 5:  games that are fun to play for eight hours? And he was because like, who
Speaker 5:  the hell wants to play a VR game for eight hours? Like, I think that's right.
Speaker 5:  And so the idea that I take off my headset and put it down on my couch and
Speaker 5:  the headset is the television and my wife can't then put it on
Speaker 5:  is stupid. Like, there there are people who are saying,
Speaker 5:  you know, it's, it's lonely and you can't watch TV alone
Speaker 5:  or you have to watch TV alone in it. And I both think that's true and also
Speaker 5:  kind of overstated. Like a lot of people spend a lot of time watching TV
Speaker 5:  alone. I think that's basically Okay. Yeah. Somewhere Richard Lawler is
Speaker 5:  listening to this feeling very vindicated. But this idea
Speaker 5:  that it, it would be like no one else in my house is allowed to watch
Speaker 5:  my TV ever. It's just bad.
Speaker 3:  It's just fifties.
Speaker 6:  Well, or like no one's allowed to use a my PlayStation.
Speaker 5:  Right? Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 3:  So like ri rich multi kid families,
Speaker 3:  you, you remember, did you ever have friends like that when you were a kid?
Speaker 3:  And they'd be like, oh, this is my PlayStation. My brother has his own PlayStation.
Speaker 3:  What? No. You'd be
Speaker 6:  Like, I did not have this. Now
Speaker 3:  Why? Why do I have that? Why do I have my own PlayStation? And your parents
Speaker 3:  would be like, because they cost money. Get out. Yeah. Go go
Speaker 3:  mow the yard.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They'd be like, go outside. That's your PlayStation. And because
Speaker 6:  It's extremely easy to switch because every other entertainment focused computing
Speaker 6:  device on the market, except maybe the iPad recognizes you are supposed to
Speaker 6:  have multiple profiles.
Speaker 3:  I just like watching Addie get so bad
Speaker 5:  About, I was talking, I was talking to Jake on our team earlier. The fun
Speaker 5:  of being in the office is I get to just randomly get in arguments with people
Speaker 5:  and he got very heated and was started, was saying that we should start giving
Speaker 5:  every iPad a zero out of 10 until they give proper multi-user support.
Speaker 5:  Mm. And I'm just like, hell yeah dude. Like that's, it's a
Speaker 5:  stance. Let's go for it. No multi users are
Speaker 3:  Nothing more, only zeros.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I support this. I'm into this. Any other Vision Pro stuff we
Speaker 5:  should talk about? don don't wanna linger on this. We've talked a lot about
Speaker 5:  Vision Pro on the show. We, we,
Speaker 3:  We, I fixed it. Did a big breakdown. Oh yeah. And
Speaker 3:  boy howdy is the, the pixels per inch. Awesome.
Speaker 5:  Is it nuts? Yeah. It us through the numbers.
Speaker 3:  It's 3,386 pixels per inch.
Speaker 5:  That seems high.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's it's only, it's only a few, a few pixels
Speaker 3:  less than what you would expect for like four, like what 4K
Speaker 3:  requires. Which is why it's not technically a 4K display, but it's like,
Speaker 3:  but it's
Speaker 5:  This big. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  In fact that it's an inch. Wow. And it has that many pixels on it is is kind
Speaker 3:  of insane. Do
Speaker 6:  Do you wanna give the Quest three and the, the other numbers that were in
Speaker 6:  our post? Yeah, yeah, yeah. I gotcha. A useful comparison. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And, and by comparison, the, the Meta Quest three has
Speaker 3:  1,218 PPI and then the
Speaker 3:  HT vi, the HTC Vive Pro has
Speaker 3:  950 and If, you want something that you actually look at
Speaker 3:  more than like once a day. The iPhone 15
Speaker 3:  Pro Max has 460 PPI. Wow. So this thing is,
Speaker 3:  and they
Speaker 6:  Point out that pixels per degree is a lot of, is in some ways more accurate.
Speaker 6:  That's like the degree of field of view that Right. Pixels
Speaker 6:  because it headset is like this thing where it just blows up a gigantic,
Speaker 6:  a small screen to a gigantic field. Right. But even those numbers are also
Speaker 6:  pretty
Speaker 3:  Good. Yeah, it is. It's like the numbers here are just
Speaker 3:  outrageously high and you're like, okay, so this thing is like
Speaker 3:  damn good. Yeah. 'cause the pixels per degree, The, Vision Pro is at 34
Speaker 3:  PPD, which is lower than the 94 and the 95
Speaker 3:  ratings for the iPhone 15 from 15
Speaker 3:  feet away. Or No, the iPhone 15 from a foot away
Speaker 3:  or the standard 65 inch 4K TV from 6.5
Speaker 3:  feet away, So, I, guess low is lower number better here for the PPD
Speaker 3:  for the pixel
Speaker 6:  Higher
Speaker 3:  Per degree.
Speaker 5:  Higher, higher, higher, higher. Typically
Speaker 6:  Better. I think that the point is that it is still not
Speaker 6:  going to get you the kind of clarity that you get from like looking at Okay.
Speaker 6:  A very small field of view for a small screen. but
Speaker 6:  it is still, I don't know that I have the numbers here, but it is still pretty
Speaker 6:  good for comparing it against other headsets. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But it also makes pretty clear how hard a technical problem this is
Speaker 5:  because, I mean, Neela, I was talking about this when we talked about his
Speaker 5:  review. It's like the, the comparison to like blood cells, which means
Speaker 5:  nothing. but it is, it is technologically insane. Yeah. That Apple got this
Speaker 5:  many pixels onto a screen this small and it's still not enough to do
Speaker 5:  the thing that we need to do in order for this stuff to be really realistic,
Speaker 5:  right? Like that is the scale of this problem is you can have
Speaker 5:  that many pixels on that small space, but because it's so close to your eyes
Speaker 5:  and because it is literally trying to simulate reality, the bar is just
Speaker 5:  so, so, so high that even that Apple has done like
Speaker 5:  an order of magnitude more than anyone else has been able to do, we're still
Speaker 5:  not there. Like, it just, it the road for really making this stuff amazing
Speaker 5:  is so long. It's crazy.
Speaker 6:  It's also yeah, a reason why pixels are just not the be all and end
Speaker 6:  all of headsets. Totally. Like things like field of View turn out to be a
Speaker 6:  really big deal with The Vision Pro. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. It's been really interesting watching everybody go through,
Speaker 5:  I would say the kind of normal honeymoon phase of a Vision Pro where you
Speaker 5:  get it on, you do the first couple of things, you get the setup, you learn
Speaker 5:  how to do, the pinch, the eye tracking, and it's like, oh my God, it works.
Speaker 5:  And it feels amazing. And then very slowly you start to notice like, oh,
Speaker 5:  I can see the edges of, of my vision here as I'm going. And then, oh,
Speaker 5:  the pinching doesn't really work and you just like, slowly but surely the
Speaker 5:  things that don't quite work start to creep in. But everybody seems to have
Speaker 5:  that very first 20 minutes in the headset where it's like, oh my God,
Speaker 5:  I'm never taking this off. This is the greatest thing that's ever happened.
Speaker 5:  That
Speaker 6:  Is also the impression that I feel like everyone who put on a VR headset
Speaker 6:  in 2013 got. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's probably true.
Speaker 3:  No, that's that's true. Yeah. I, I was talking to a friend who he did when,
Speaker 3:  when I worked with him, we, we worked on the, the original Oculus Quest
Speaker 3:  review. Was it the Oculus Quest? The Rift?
Speaker 6:  The Rift was the
Speaker 5:  First the original Rift. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And we worked on the original Rift review and he's like, wow. I, I kind of
Speaker 3:  called it like, then I said basically my review is a lot like all of the
Speaker 3:  The Vision Pro reviews right now. And it's like, look back. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  No, he's, he's right. Like, like when you finally try really cool vr, you're
Speaker 3:  like, oh wow, this is awesome. And then it kind of goes away, which is why
Speaker 3:  nobody talks about VR cardboard anymore. 'cause that was really cool when
Speaker 3:  you first put on like the cardboard, right. And then five minutes later you're
Speaker 3:  like, okay, what do I do now?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think a lot of this stuff is just a question of how long it takes
Speaker 5:  to reveal its problems to you. Yes. And The Vision Pro to its
Speaker 5:  credit seems to take a pretty long time to reveal its problems to you. But
Speaker 5:  right about the time it starts getting heavy and the battery starts dying
Speaker 5:  and the gestures don't work quite so well. And
Speaker 3:  You remember you spent 300 and or $3,500 on it.
Speaker 5:  Every once in a while. Somebody has just been posting in all caps
Speaker 5:  $3,500. And I feel like this is now my legacy on The Vergecast. I'm very
Speaker 5:  happy about it.
Speaker 6:  I do feel bad. You mentioned Google Cardboard. I feel really bad for all
Speaker 6:  of the people who spent a bunch of time making 180 and 360
Speaker 6:  degree videos, I guess, including us many years ago. And Apple's just like,
Speaker 6:  no, they're not good enough. You're not looking at 'em. Yeah. Can't look
Speaker 3:  At 'em. They look like potatoes.
Speaker 5:  Which is wild because it's not like Apple is going way
Speaker 5:  out of its way to ensure every experience you have in The
Speaker 5:  Vision Pro is like perfect, insane. And a lot of people are having issues
Speaker 5:  with, you know, motion sickness and, and some of the like problems
Speaker 5:  with the ways that apps work. And there are not that many
Speaker 5:  guardrails except on videos that Apple doesn't think look good enough. And
Speaker 5:  I think that's kind of a silly set of guardrails.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's, it's frustrating. Yeah. Especially that it's even just on the
Speaker 6:  web. Like the web is the place I think of as you should be able to just go
Speaker 6:  and experience a thing, even if the quality is not great. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  If I'm willing to go onto that stupid keyboard and type www
Speaker 5:  dot YouTube dot com slash 360 videos that are gonna make me
Speaker 5:  throw up. Like, that is my right. Yeah. This is the internet. I should be
Speaker 5:  allowed to dot that. Alright. Anyway, we should move on
Speaker 5:  before we get to the laying ground. One more thi one and a half more things
Speaker 5:  I want to talk about. I'm only giving Alex a half, we'll half get to that
Speaker 5:  in a second. Bluesky opened up this week, which I think is interesting.
Speaker 5:  This is the, the new Twittery social network that all
Speaker 5:  the shit posters went to and have been kind of hanging out in secret for
Speaker 5:  the last year. And now Bluesky is opened to everybody.
Speaker 5:  The Jay, their CEO did an interview with Alex Heath talking about how they
Speaker 5:  plan to make money and
Speaker 5:  what do you, what do you guys make of this? Is like, is Bluesky, do you know,
Speaker 5:  is Bluesky coming?
Speaker 3:  How I fully understood, I I didn't, I hadn't looked at the website yet.
Speaker 3:  I was scrolling through Threads and I saw a bunch of post saying I'm on Bluesky,
Speaker 3:  but I'll still be posting here on Threads. And that's how I knew that Bluesky
Speaker 3:  had opened. And I was like, Hmm, is it good If that's how I find
Speaker 3:  out is just a bunch of people on Threads saying, I'll I'll still be here.
Speaker 3:  I'll still be on both posting on both.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's interesting. You're on Bluesky, right? I'm on
Speaker 6:  Bluesky. I've, I went to Mastodon first. I still use Mastodon.
Speaker 6:  I've slipped to Bluesky just because Blue Skies felt much more low stakes.
Speaker 6:  It
Speaker 5:  Interesting.
Speaker 6:  Part of it was that it was private, that it was just much smaller.
Speaker 6:  but it does feel like where a bunch of a Twitter people that I liked
Speaker 6:  went, and B, it feels like I don't have to be
Speaker 6:  contributing to a greater social good, which was the feeling I ended up getting
Speaker 6:  from Mastodon. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Mastodon is very much like a, an NGO designed
Speaker 5:  to make the world a better place through lots of developmental
Speaker 5:  documentation, which
Speaker 6:  I'm sure is not true for absolutely every instance. Like all of the usual
Speaker 6:  caveats. I just got the sense that I was like, is this really a good enough
Speaker 6:  constructive enough thing? There were just so many people talking about you
Speaker 6:  just, you shouldn't be, you shouldn't be cluttering up our timelines with
Speaker 6:  all of this frivolous stuff. Yeah. And then I went to Bluesky and Drill was
Speaker 6:  there. It's
Speaker 5:  Just all frivolous. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I, and well also a decent amount of law Twitter ended up there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Fair. Yeah. I, part of me thinks it's a success
Speaker 5:  story if they all end up being their own things and different,
Speaker 5:  and I think the weirdest part is gonna be the people who
Speaker 5:  kind of commit to posting everywhere and try to be the same thing
Speaker 5:  everywhere. I just don't think it's gonna work. And I think these things
Speaker 5:  have all developed such different norms that, like
Speaker 5:  the vibe on Bluesky is unrecognizable to the vibe on
Speaker 5:  Threads or on Mastodon largely in good ways, but mostly
Speaker 5:  in just extremely chaotic ways. There's just a lot of people making inside
Speaker 5:  jokes that you don't understand if you've been off of Bluesky for more than
Speaker 5:  10 minutes. But that's a good thing. Right. And I think that part of the
Speaker 5:  big bet that the social web is making right now that is that there
Speaker 5:  can be lots of winners and lots of things to come out, but in some
Speaker 5:  ways I think Bluesky taking this long to open up was both the best and worst
Speaker 5:  thing that happened to Bluesky. Like Bluesky has this very
Speaker 5:  like mature vibe now, right? Like Bluesky knows what it is,
Speaker 5:  but the downside of that is it knows what it is for this small group of people
Speaker 5:  who have been there together, alone, like on a desert island for
Speaker 5:  a year while Threads became sort of the clear mainstream choice.
Speaker 5:  Mastodon continues to be Mastodon, Threads in Mastodon are eventually
Speaker 5:  gonna be integrated. And so it just kind of feels like Bluesky is
Speaker 5:  just relegated to forever being an also ran.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  I mean that's why I didn't, I, I, I have an account but I don't really
Speaker 3:  participate in Bluesky as much just 'cause my brain can only handle so much
Speaker 3:  social media and So I don't wanna, like, I, I am not gonna be one of
Speaker 3:  those people on a bunch of different platforms and always talking. And that
Speaker 3:  one I was like, I just feel like this one is not gonna be the big one. I
Speaker 3:  think a lot of really cool people are there, but a lot of the really cool
Speaker 3:  people there, I'll just text Yeah. And talk to them because they're my friends.
Speaker 3:  On
Speaker 6:  The other hand, I kind of, well a, I do wish that it were much easier to
Speaker 6:  have a single interface where I could at least check all these things. Yes.
Speaker 6:  At the same time, that's very annoying to me. But I also, I don't know,
Speaker 6:  I hope we get more sites that are small and niche and
Speaker 6:  that I can just go to for a small subset of things. Bluesky in some ways
Speaker 6:  reminds me of Tumblr in its post hegemonic era.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. In its current era where it's just like a couple of folks, you know,
Speaker 3:  and they're being really weird and that's great. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Now Tumblr's in the phase where every time somebody mentions Tumblr you go,
Speaker 5:  oh, Tumblr. Yeah. And that is kind of what Bluesky feels like already,
Speaker 6:  Except that I guess one of them allows porn.
Speaker 5:  Well, you know, Tumblr,
Speaker 6:  I'm really curious how long it's going to last because I am just
Speaker 6:  Apple and Google exerted so much pressure a few years
Speaker 6:  ago in getting not saved for work stuff either paywall or take,
Speaker 6:  or not paywall, but like either walled away or taken down. Yeah. The Bluesky
Speaker 6:  getting on it feels
Speaker 6:  odd.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, to some extent I think you could make a pretty, pretty good
Speaker 5:  argument that Bluesky never should have opened up that main, that that sort
Speaker 5:  of managing and slowing down that growth was a good thing for
Speaker 5:  Bluesky. Like, it grew too fast in the beginning. Like remember when people
Speaker 5:  were hacking the invite codes and a ton of people came on all at once, it
Speaker 5:  became a mess. Like the, the norms changed. People started doing weird stuff.
Speaker 5:  The platforms started breaking in weird ways. The health thread ruined everyone's
Speaker 5:  life and forgot about the health. There was I think a a moment where they
Speaker 5:  said, okay, we're gonna, we're gonna slow this down on purpose. And I think
Speaker 5:  that was the right thing to do then. And I think you could make the case,
Speaker 5:  it's the right thing to do. Now the problem is that runs against all of
Speaker 5:  Blue Sky's stated goals. Right. Which are to build a social
Speaker 5:  protocol for the web that is bigger than Bluesky and to kind of reinvent
Speaker 5:  the way that we do everything. Which I think at this point
Speaker 5:  it, it lost, right? Like we're, we're in a VHS Beta Max war with,
Speaker 5:  with at Protocol, which runs Bluesky and Activity Pub, which is underneath
Speaker 5:  Mastodon, which Threads is gonna adopt. And it almost
Speaker 5:  doesn't matter anymore. I don't think which one is better Activity Pub is
Speaker 5:  gonna win. Yes. It's just gonna win. And I think if I'm
Speaker 5:  Bluesky, you either have to look at it and say, okay, do we want to keep
Speaker 5:  fighting this fight that we are now so far behind? Or do we go,
Speaker 5:  like you're talking about and try to be something different and not try to
Speaker 5:  build the next great social media company, but like lean into this thing
Speaker 5:  that we already are, which I think could be very cool,
Speaker 3:  But doesn't at some point they have to make money. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Presumably.
Speaker 3:  And like I think that's gonna be a real challenge if they
Speaker 3:  don't grow. I, and I I totally agree with you. I think having
Speaker 5:  These masson runs on like a Patreon Yeah. I don know you can get, you can
Speaker 5:  get by for a pretty long time. That's
Speaker 3:  True.
Speaker 6:  The source projects Yeah. Used to be taken for granted as just things that
Speaker 6:  could exist.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And there's a way to run this stuff as like an okay business that
Speaker 5:  doesn't involve, like if Bluesky wants to be a
Speaker 5:  trillion dollar company, there are certain things you have to do in pursuit
Speaker 5:  of that. Right. Right. But I think my hope is for the next phase of the social
Speaker 5:  web that not everybody tries to be a trillion dollar company. That there
Speaker 5:  are going to be lots and lots of much smaller ways to do this stuff. Fingers
Speaker 3:  Crossed.
Speaker 5:  And I think Bluesky, I could be totally wrong because there are a lot of
Speaker 5:  things Bluesky does really well and it's a, it's a nice looking app. Everybody
Speaker 5:  on there is, that's where Drill is. It's like, it is the most fun
Speaker 5:  social platform on the internet. Like I really believe that.
Speaker 5:  but it is such an unusual place now that I feel like if I had
Speaker 5:  never been there before, it would show up and it would, it would feel very
Speaker 5:  strange.
Speaker 6:  It also feels like a place that you kind of can only really grasp If, you
Speaker 6:  were on Twitter.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But like, but like on Twitter, like capital o on
Speaker 5:  Twitter and, and God help you If. you were one of those
Speaker 5:  people. It really is. It's full of like decade old Twitter jokes
Speaker 5:  that If you don't get you, you sort of need a glossary to help you understand
Speaker 5:  what the hell is going on in Bluesky.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's funny. But, we'll, we'll see. I I support all of this. I
Speaker 5:  hope Bluesky works. I just don't think it's going to All right. Alex,
Speaker 5:  I'm so afraid to do this Right now
Speaker 3:  I have, I'm so nervous. I have a piece of news here, here
Speaker 5:  About what's gonna happen. I have a piece of this before we take a break.
Speaker 5:  We have one more
Speaker 5:  story we should talk about for such a short amount of time,
Speaker 3:  Shortest amount of time. And, and in fact it says Alex be careful in
Speaker 3:  all caps. As some of you know, I did make a bet
Speaker 3:  with some people that at some point we would probably see
Speaker 3:  a picture of Elon Musk in little Elon.
Speaker 3:  I I don, I don't wanna say any other way. I
Speaker 5:  Already hate this. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And we're one step closer because they are currently
Speaker 3:  dealing with a problem on the platform on x the
Speaker 3:  platform where there is a non-consensual photo of a celebrity
Speaker 3:  in the nude. And
Speaker 5:  I mean, it's Drake's nudes. Yeah. Like we can just say this. It's like there's,
Speaker 5:  there's everyone on the internet knows this. This is why this became a story.
Speaker 5:  It
Speaker 3:  Led to, it led to X being the number one app on the Apple
Speaker 3:  App store. I wanna just be very clear, non-consensual
Speaker 3:  nudes are not Okay. Don't do that. But also, I hate how close
Speaker 3:  we are getting to the, the big nude where I
Speaker 3:  win a bet. I don't wanna win this bet. It's a terrible bet.
Speaker 5:  Everyone loses that bet
Speaker 3:  Everyone loses when I win this bet.
Speaker 3:  Clean up your Act X. Like stop, stop letting non-consensual stuff
Speaker 3:  just be all over your platform. That's not cool.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Well, and that, and then all this stuff, we, we were kind of
Speaker 5:  bookended with stories about the Taylor Swift deep fakes being all over
Speaker 5:  x first there were, there were non-consensual
Speaker 5:  problematic, non-consensual DeepFakes. And now there's a deepfake of Taylor
Speaker 5:  Swift endorsing Donald Trump that's all over the platform. X is
Speaker 5:  just an odd, odd place and
Speaker 3:  It's, yeah, it's, it's an old kind of internet, but not in a good way,
Speaker 3:  particularly If you like, have any vested interest in
Speaker 3:  X and don't wanna be sued. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I'm saying it reminds me of Reddit back in the mid-teens
Speaker 6:  during the period where they were extremely laci faire.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But at least Reddit would like say out loud that they
Speaker 5:  didn't want these things. They wouldn't do anything about it for a long time,
Speaker 5:  but at least they would say, we don't want this awful stuff to be all
Speaker 5:  over our platform. Yeah. You do not get that sense from the leadership at
Speaker 5:  X right now.
Speaker 6:  They're, yeah. Well I think that Elon is definitely operating in a
Speaker 6:  landscape that comes after Reddit's cleanup in which you're
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You're, you can't even just say, don don't endorse this, but it's here.
Speaker 6:  It's like you have to have full throated endorsement of Yes. The Nazis
Speaker 6:  even that like, look, yes, he is condemned the Nazis. He also just talks
Speaker 6:  to a bunch of far-Right people and spreads his own conspiracy theories. And
Speaker 6:  there's just a bunch of stuff that even that Reddit people
Speaker 6:  like hung out with and invited the guy from creep shots into
Speaker 6:  their events. Like they didn't end up doing that. Right.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. No, I I think that's right. And it's just bad times
Speaker 5:  all
Speaker 3:  Around. Yeah. It's just bad times. I don't wanna win this bet. Don't
Speaker 3:  please. I like, I went from kind of wanting to win the bet because I like
Speaker 3:  to be smug and win things to like, I don't actually wanna win
Speaker 3:  this bet with Liz. Don't.
Speaker 5:  It's a terrible bet. And also to everyone who is asking for trending topics
Speaker 5:  to be on Threads. You don't want that, don't click on
Speaker 5:  trending topics. 'cause something bad will probably happen when you do it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. All right. We need to take a break then we're gonna go back, do a lightning
Speaker 5:  ground.
Speaker 10:  Remember November 7th, 2020,
Speaker 11:  You had people discovering that Joe Biden was going to
Speaker 11:  win the election and just bursting out of their houses and going out into
Speaker 11:  the streets
Speaker 11:  and dancing and, and making noise and high fiving each other.
Speaker 12:  The best day of my life, best day the year
Speaker 11:  This was happening in cities across the country. People were celebrating
Speaker 11:  in a way you just don't see anymore. And, and I thought that was an important
Speaker 11:  moment to recall because it captured the joy that people felt
Speaker 11:  about Biden winning, which was not really about Biden's
Speaker 11:  program. People were just thrilled that Donald Trump was going to go,
Speaker 13:  January 20th is gonna be day at the
Speaker 13:  White House because we're gonna get rid of the orange pizza trash
Speaker 13:  Donald Trump,
Speaker 10:  How people went from jubilant to totally jaded and how
Speaker 10:  Biden could maybe win 'em back this week on today
Speaker 10:  explained.
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back. Let's not talk about Drake's nudes anymore.
Speaker 5:  Let's do a laying around. Addie you go first. What do you have?
Speaker 6:  So the FCC has a log against robocalls
Speaker 6:  and this is said you cannot have artificial voices. Do
Speaker 6:  artificial voices include AI voices,
Speaker 3:  Artificial voices? You would in the Yes.
Speaker 5:  You would work. My instinct is yes.
Speaker 6:  And they agreed. Good. Okay. Cool. Good for them. Cool. Nice. They declared
Speaker 6:  today that the, that AI generated voice clones in
Speaker 6:  robocalls definitely do violate the Telephone Consumer Protection Act. That
Speaker 6:  means they can crack down on them. This is partly relevant because the election
Speaker 6:  season is heating up and New Hampshire has just released the
Speaker 6:  results of an investigation about who was making
Speaker 6:  phone calls pretending to be Joe Biden. It's companies in Texas.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it was companies in my hometown.
Speaker 5:  Okay. You need to be less excited about this. I mean,
Speaker 3:  Look, anytime I see my hometown, this is not
Speaker 5:  A cool like, ah, that's, those are my people moments.
Speaker 3:  If. You're not from like New York or like a big town and you and you see
Speaker 3:  like, like I'm from Fort Worth, I see Fort Worth and a name. I'm like, oh
Speaker 3:  cool. And, and then I closer you
Speaker 5:  A little closer. Fort Worth, Texas. Like, it's like a tiny town in Iowa.
Speaker 5:  I mean it's like a large city right next to Dallas, Texas. Oh,
Speaker 3:  This is sort of flattering. Thank you. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I think of it as being a pretty, pretty big place.
Speaker 3:  Look when you're next to Dallas, like they're always over there talking about
Speaker 3:  how cool they are and how you suck. I see. So we have some inferiority
Speaker 3:  complexes over in Fort Worth, right? Well we believe, and apparently we also
Speaker 3:  have spams
Speaker 3:  calling pretending to be Joe Biden. And they were saying like, don't vote.
Speaker 3:  Right? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You gotta save your vote a thing that your doesn't make any sense. Save your
Speaker 6:  vote. Oh wow.
Speaker 3:  Thanks
Speaker 5:  Texas. Wait, didn't, wasn't that a whole story in the last election cycle
Speaker 5:  that there were, there was a guy who was convicted of
Speaker 5:  for posting on Twitter about like telling people not to
Speaker 5:  vote, making fake ads saying you can vote by text message and telling
Speaker 5:  people not to vote. I
Speaker 6:  Think you were thinking of Jacob Wool the troll who
Speaker 6:  Yes. Was doing robocalls. Okay. And robocalls were, yeah,
Speaker 6:  they were an issue in the last election. They're obviously also just an issue
Speaker 6:  as part of the overwhelming span. That means I don't answer my phone anymore.
Speaker 6:  Yep. Same. And
Speaker 5:  I told somebody in an email the other day, oh, gimme a call when you get
Speaker 5:  a sec. And they called me four minutes later and I didn't answer. I was like,
Speaker 5:  I don't know this number. I'm not answering the
Speaker 6:  Phone. Anyway, so now AI has like, it has a lot of things supercharged
Speaker 6:  this, it's starting to become an issue and the FCC is at the very least
Speaker 6:  recognizing it's an issue. And we probably will end up seeing more about
Speaker 6:  this.
Speaker 5:  This also seems like we're already kind of deep in the deep fake
Speaker 5:  election in a very real way.
Speaker 3:  I just If you get a call and it's like, hello, this is President Biden.
Speaker 3:  Why would you ever believe that
Speaker 5:  Call call. I'd like Joe, what's up dude?
Speaker 3:  Like that like that's just like whenever you get the emails that is like,
Speaker 3:  this is President Biden, I need your help right now. Alex Cranz.
Speaker 5:  But you would at least think that is a message he recorded,
Speaker 5:  right? It's like, no you wouldn't.
Speaker 3:  When you see those move on emails, are you like, oh my god, Nancy Pelosi
Speaker 3:  is actually emailing me. David Pierce? No. You're always like, this is stupid
Speaker 3:  and not real.
Speaker 6:  Okay. You want the weirdest version of this though? Is that Eric Adams,
Speaker 6:  who you will hear definitely in conjunction with the weirdest of anything.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. He does his own deep fakes. Like he had a bunch of
Speaker 6:  calls where he auto translated his voice. Yes,
Speaker 3:  I remember that.
Speaker 6:  To make it sound like he spoke languages that he didn't, I'm curious how
Speaker 6:  that stuff is going to end up being affected by this.
Speaker 3:  I mean, hopefully, I would assume it'd be the same way where they're like,
Speaker 3:  no, that's not true.
Speaker 5:  I don't, oh man, what a legal mess that's gonna be. Can you deep fake
Speaker 5:  yourself?
Speaker 5:  I I don don don't know.
Speaker 3:  I feel like maybe just don't do that kind of call. Maybe, maybe just
Speaker 3:  don't like it's so, it's so pi like dumb because it's just like
Speaker 3:  Nancy Pelosi is not writing me this email. Joe Biden is not out here
Speaker 3:  calling me like at the phone, at the phone. Banks calling me because
Speaker 3:  do we do phone banks anymore? Is that really a thing anymore? No.
Speaker 3:  Maybe, maybe in New Hampshire, but it's just dumb.
Speaker 3:  I'm just like, who, who is answering these calls being like, oh wow, Joe
Speaker 3:  told me not to vote. Well, better not vote.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I I mean still people. The answer is forever Don't more people than
Speaker 5:  you think.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, but I'm
Speaker 5:  Just like, what? This stuff is, this stuff is a mess. And yeah, we are only
Speaker 5:  at the very beginning of what's to come Alex, what you got
Speaker 3:  My, my thing is not about Joe Biden or my, my home state or, okay, well then
Speaker 3:  don don't care. Yeah, nevermind. It's all dumb. No, it is cool because
Speaker 3:  Ford, Ford, hold on, let me see. I almost said Fort Worth again.
Speaker 5:  Ford Worth.
Speaker 3:  Ford Worth. Okay. So Ford has been quietly creating a
Speaker 3:  skunkworks team for low cost EVs. And that's exciting because
Speaker 3:  cheaper EVs are good. More competitors with Tesla
Speaker 3:  will be good. Just competition in general. We love that.
Speaker 3:  It is also, did you all watch that show like All American? I think it was
Speaker 3:  called like the auto show. Oh yeah.
Speaker 5:  On nbc, American Auto,
Speaker 3:  American Auto. Yeah. Yeah. It just feels like it was out of a, a storyline
Speaker 3:  from that.
Speaker 5:  So, okay, lemme explain to you what I don't understand about this. Ford
Speaker 5:  notoriously a company that makes cars. Yeah. You don't
Speaker 5:  need to make a car company inside of your car company to make cars,
Speaker 5:  but you can just make cars. Yeah. That's your, that's your thing. It's like
Speaker 5:  Apple's like, well we created a skunkworks team inside of Apple to build
Speaker 5:  smartphones. It's like, nope. You do that already. Just tell them to make
Speaker 5:  a different one. Yeah. What is the, I this what Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I think my, my understanding of it is
Speaker 5:  Ford is like, it's illegal for Ford to make anything other than F1 fifties.
Speaker 5:  So they have to create a whole new thing to make something else. I
Speaker 3:  Suspect it was probably because a lot of the people working on the Skunkworks
Speaker 3:  project, the, the head of it is, is a guy who was at Tesla for
Speaker 3:  years, Alan Clark. But a lot of the people working on it are from this place
Speaker 3:  called Automotive Auto Space
Speaker 3:  Motive, space Power. I had to ah, A MP.
Speaker 3:  Sure. Yeah. I had to, I had to spell it out And, and they
Speaker 3:  acquired this startup last year and So I think it's probably just easier
Speaker 3:  to hold them into a little company than a big company. But still, I, I agree
Speaker 3:  with you. It's like you can just go tell your people to make cheap EVs. Like
Speaker 5:  That just makes me think they call it a skunkworks. 'cause somebody at Ford
Speaker 5:  thinks that makes them sound like a tech company, but Sounds cool. And what
Speaker 5:  that actually is, is just a team at your company that's, that's just some
Speaker 5:  people who work for you.
Speaker 3:  They're, they're gonna go make a really cool stealth bomber. That's
Speaker 5:  Ford. I think it's awesome. I am extremely in favor of Ford and everybody
Speaker 5:  else trying to figure out how to make cheap EVs because that dream seems
Speaker 5:  increasingly dead all over the place now. And
Speaker 5:  like more power to anybody trying to pull this off.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's, it's funny, like Farley, the, the CEO of Ford
Speaker 3:  had an earnings call after all of this came out. TechCrunch reported the
Speaker 3:  story and said the, the Clark and, and the team at ammp
Speaker 3:  slash ford, skunkworks cheap evs.com,
Speaker 3:  whatever you wanna call the place, said this is a flexible platform that
Speaker 3:  will not only deploy to several types of vehicles, but will be, but will
Speaker 3:  be a large installed base for software and services that we're now seeing
Speaker 3:  at Ford Pro. I don't know what any of that
Speaker 3:  means. And I, I don't understand how this company is running
Speaker 3:  and doesn't know that it's a car company.
Speaker 5:  Somebody went to chat GPT and said, listen Dear chat GPTI run
Speaker 5:  a car company
Speaker 3:  Like Jim Farley.
Speaker 5:  What would I say if I ran a tech company instead? And they wrote that press
Speaker 5:  release.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Jim Farley. Don't, don't let Chad GPT write your press releases anymore.
Speaker 5:  Just build cars, man. Just,
Speaker 3:  Just make cool cars.
Speaker 5:  Just make cheaper cars. Yeah. Take the things that you make and make them
Speaker 5:  cheaper maybe
Speaker 3:  Maybe shorter, right.
Speaker 5:  Inside your company. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Maybe I don't need cameras to be able to see out of the front of my car.
Speaker 5:  Listen, it's, we can all dream little
Speaker 3:  Things.
Speaker 5:  Total things. I'm gonna go last because we started on a
Speaker 5:  Cranz victory lap and now we're gonna take a David Victory lap. Yeah. What,
Speaker 5:  what
Speaker 3:  Is it?
Speaker 5:  So the, the information reported this week that Apple is developing,
Speaker 5:  quote, at least two iPhone prototypes that are
Speaker 5:  flip phones
Speaker 3:  In their skunkworks project that's probably not actually owned
Speaker 3:  by Apple.
Speaker 5:  Correct. Which is just they, they take all the people who
Speaker 5:  work at Apple Park and they just tell them to make phones
Speaker 5:  and they say You're a skunkworks now. And somebody raises their hand and
Speaker 5:  says, what does that mean? Does it change anything? And they say, shut up.
Speaker 5:  We're a tech company. This is The future. Just
Speaker 3:  Go do it.
Speaker 5:  But there have been rumors about this for a while that Apple was making these
Speaker 5:  things. And also a thing to know about a company like Apple is
Speaker 5:  that they prototype everything like If. you can imagine a phone of
Speaker 5:  some shape or function or feature.
Speaker 5:  I, I would bet you $10 there is one on a table somewhere
Speaker 5:  in Apple Park. It's just how it works. It's just what you do. If, you are
Speaker 5:  a company this big that makes this many products, but Apple like me
Speaker 5:  thinks flip phones kick ass and is gonna make some And I think it's awesome.
Speaker 5:  I love that. And apparently also Apple is working on a foldable iPad,
Speaker 5:  which is the other dream. Yeah. Like what a, that's just like give me an
Speaker 5:  iPad mini that folds up and I can put it in my pocket. Like hell Yeah. That
Speaker 5:  is also apparently being worked on this stuff is complicated. We've seen
Speaker 5:  flip phones, they're hard and bad and have big creases and have
Speaker 5:  their issues.
Speaker 5:  I still firmly believe this is like the next thing. Yes. And
Speaker 5:  I think it's clearer to everyone, including Apple, that smartphones
Speaker 5:  need a next thing or they're just gonna be laptops. They're just gonna
Speaker 5:  be fine. You're gonna have it, you're never gonna think about it. You're
Speaker 5:  gonna upgrade it when it dies and that's gonna be it. And Apple has a lot
Speaker 5:  of money riding on being able to get you to upgrade more quickly than that.
Speaker 5:  And I think Foldables are gonna be that thing.
Speaker 3:  I think the only part of this that surprises me is that we
Speaker 3:  aren't closer to the Apple foldable given historically
Speaker 3:  their timeline of kind of like following everybody else. Yeah. They're usually
Speaker 3:  only a couple of years with, with the exception of The, Vision, Pro, they're
Speaker 3:  usually only a couple years behind everybody else. This and this one would
Speaker 3:  be like
Speaker 5:  Five or six years. Do you know my theory about this? What they can't call
Speaker 5:  it anything other than the iPhone and you can't make an iPhone
Speaker 5:  that is like a 1.0 anymore. Mm. Like they, they
Speaker 5:  can't come out and be like, it's a new thing. It's called the I flip
Speaker 5:  everybody like no, it's just a flip. It's this iPhone. Yeah. Like what are
Speaker 5:  we doing here? And So I think if I'm Apple, I feel like I have to make an
Speaker 5:  iPhone that is like on par with all the iPhones we already sell,
Speaker 5:  which is now a 17-year-old line of phones. Same.
Speaker 5:  And So I. Think catching up to that is really hard because the flip phones
Speaker 5:  require new components. They require rethinking how batteries work.
Speaker 5:  There's some new software stuff they're gonna have to do. Like it's hard
Speaker 5:  work to do this well. And I think in the way that Apple was
Speaker 5:  clearly very comfortable releasing a Vision Pro that is not the thing they
Speaker 5:  wanted it to be. I don't think you get away with that. Okay.
Speaker 5:  With an iPhone. I think you can maybe get away with that with an iPad. I
Speaker 5:  think if they came out with a foldable iPad and were like, this is a whole
Speaker 5:  new thing. And people were like, it's not perfect, but oh my God, it folds
Speaker 5:  isn Isn't that cool? That I could see. But I think the
Speaker 5:  iPhone is too big and too important to everything that Apple is
Speaker 5:  doing for them to be like, here's a thing that's not quite finished. Okay.
Speaker 5:  I, that's my theory. I guess
Speaker 6:  I can see that the iPhone is also just your phone is a thing that you absolutely
Speaker 6:  need to work in a way that you don't a bunch of other devices. Right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. If if like if my iPad sucks, I just put it down. But like
Speaker 5:  I if Yeah. No, you're exactly right. If I leave my phone at home, life
Speaker 5:  has fallen apart. I had, when I was at, when I was in Vegas
Speaker 5:  for CES, I, my phone just like broke. Yeah. One day. And it was the
Speaker 5:  most stressful, like six hours trying to get all of that to work again. 'cause
Speaker 5:  I couldn't log into anything. 'cause I didn't have the two-factor working.
Speaker 5:  I couldn't talk to my wife because we talk over SMS because she's on the
Speaker 5:  Pixel and I'm on an iPhone. Like it was awful. And I had this moment of
Speaker 5:  being like, oh, I'm way too reliant on my phone. But that's just life now.
Speaker 5:  You're exactly right. You can actually
Speaker 3:  Feel your stress. Like I only sort of tangentially knew about
Speaker 3:  what was happening with your phone, but I could still feel the stress through
Speaker 3:  Vegas. Oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Oh yeah. I about burned our hotel down with my anxiety
Speaker 3:  Trying to Yeah. Like the moment. And you could also at what, at one point
Speaker 3:  you're like, oh, I'm feeling pretty good. David must have gotten his phone
Speaker 3:  fixed. Okay, we're
Speaker 5:  Good. Yeah. I had this moment of like, okay, I have meetings to go to. I
Speaker 5:  have things I'm supposed to do today. I'm not doing any of it because my
Speaker 5:  phone doesn't work. Yeah. It's like, what is this world that I live in now?
Speaker 5:  But that, like, I can't, I cannot leave my hotel room until my phone works
Speaker 5:  again. Yeah. It's not good. It's not good. But, but you're totally right.
Speaker 5:  Like that, that is, that is where Apple is. And so if they're like, here's
Speaker 5:  the iPhone flip, it might break,
Speaker 3:  But gimme the iPad, gimme the, I like, that's what I'm saying. I got my little
Speaker 3:  iPad mini. I wanna get rid of that thing. I want, I want it to fold. I wanna
Speaker 3:  have it in my back pocket.
Speaker 5:  I'm ready. I've been waiting so long to upgrade my iPad Mini, which still
Speaker 5:  has touch id and is like busted and is now old enough that some of the apps
Speaker 5:  won't update, update anymore. And I'm just holding out. I'm like, give me,
Speaker 5:  give me the thing Apple, give it to me.
Speaker 3:  You're gonna have to wait till it's sounds like 2026 is the
Speaker 3:  earliest people are are theorizing. This is gonna come out, but we'll see.
Speaker 5:  I can't wait that long. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I mean we, we've got new iPads coming probably pretty soon. I'm just
Speaker 5:  Gonna listen. Tim Cook. I know you're listening. You're you, you're in a
Speaker 5:  room with Bob. I hear right now listening to this podcast. Just ship
Speaker 5:  me one. I won't even tell anybody. Just get me one. It'll be fine. Everything
Speaker 5:  will be okay. All right. We gotta get outta here. We've, we've
Speaker 5:  gone long as always. Yep. In Eli's honor.
Speaker 5:  That sounds like Eli's dead. Eli's just gone for the day. He'll be back.
Speaker 5:  Everybody always gets very worried about NELI when he's not here. I promise
Speaker 5:  everyone he's okay. He's just, I think on a plane being too ashamed of
Speaker 5:  himself to use his Vision Pro. Yeah. Which I plan to give him a lot of crap
Speaker 5:  for next week. But we need to get outta here. But before we do one quick
Speaker 5:  thing, we The Vergecast are moving to the Verges YouTube
Speaker 5:  channel starting next week. So starting with the show on
Speaker 5:  Tuesday, all of The Vergecast episodes are gonna be on the
Speaker 5:  Verges YouTube channel, not The, Verge casts YouTube channel. We're still
Speaker 5:  gonna use The Vergecast channel for clips and all kinds of other fun extra
Speaker 5:  stuff we're gonna do. But If, you wanna find the full episodes, go subscribe
Speaker 5:  to The Verge channel. If you're already subscribed, hang out there. I think
Speaker 5:  you can subscribe to a playlist on YouTube, which we'll have for the podcast.
Speaker 5:  You can do that too. It's gonna be awesome. So do that.
Speaker 5:  Smash them buttons. Whatever YouTubers say, don don't know.
Speaker 5:  And until then, go listen to decoder. Casey Newton was on it for once. It
Speaker 5:  was a good decoder episode. And Decoder is Decoder is also now twice a week.
Speaker 5:  The Vergecast is now on Tuesdays and Fridays instead of Wednesdays and
Speaker 5:  Fridays. There's a lot of change going on. Love it. but it's The Vergecast.
Speaker 5:  We'll see you next time. Rock and roll.
Speaker 8:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 8:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The Vergecast is a
Speaker 8:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 8:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.