# Transcript
ID: 7decf0f1-b8fb-479b-919f-a334f643842a
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-508278419724900867/3168519231161552762/s93290-US-5969s-1726239732.mp3
Description: Nilay, David, and Alex talk about the new PlayStation 5 Pro — why it's so expensive, why it doesn't have a disc drive, and why it made so many people feel feelings. They also talk about the fallout from this week's iPhone launch, the first days of the Google ad trial, Kamala Harris's earrings, Huawei's triple-folding phone, and much more.
Speaker 3:  Hello and welcome to Road Chest Flagship podcast of advanced ray tracing
Speaker 3:  the technology that everyone flas for every day. Kids going to school
Speaker 3:  screaming for advanced ray tracing. Taylor Swift, get outta here.
Speaker 3:  It's advanced ray tracing for
Speaker 4:  She also wants it.
Speaker 3:  She does. Yeah. Loudly and proudly at the VMAs. Yep.
Speaker 3:  Demanding.
Speaker 4:  That's all she talks
Speaker 3:  About. Hi. Even friend Eli. Alex Kranz is here in the studio. We're together.
Speaker 3:  Yes. This is
Speaker 4:  So exciting. And we're not CGI, even though the ray tracing looks like we
Speaker 4:  are.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Look at those reflections.
Speaker 4:  Oh my God. They're incredible, aren't
Speaker 3:  They? No one can stop them. David Pierce is here.
Speaker 5:  You know how Tom Cruise has like made his thing that he's the enemy
Speaker 5:  of motion smoothing. Taylor Swift should do this for Ray Tracing. Taylor,
Speaker 5:  if you're listening and I know that you are,
Speaker 3:  Please
Speaker 5:  Make a thing where you come on at the beginning of every video game and you
Speaker 5:  tell me how important it is to turn on Ray tracing. This is, this is
Speaker 5:  your moment to do real good in the United States of America.
Speaker 3:  Be like, pick visual fidelity over performance.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Post about that with your cat Taylor.
Speaker 3:  I will say, wow. I will say that in the, in the comments of our YouTube,
Speaker 3:  there's a sort of raging mini conspiracy theory about whether David
Speaker 3:  is actually in a living room or in front of a green screen. And I'm ne
Speaker 3:  we're never gonna tell. Never. We're never gonna tell. We're also never gonna
Speaker 3:  tell you how long the show's supposed to be. We're just gonna keep saying
Speaker 3:  we're going over and David is gonna keep clipping a little bit,
Speaker 3:  but not all the way. I don't think
Speaker 4:  I've ever seen David sit on that couch.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. No one's ever been back there. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  What Couch all Wait, what?
Speaker 3:  But once we get Ray tracing enabled on David, you'll never be able to tell
Speaker 3:  if he's screen
Speaker 5:  Screened or not gonna look so sick back there.
Speaker 3:  Full volumetric, static image of a living room.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna send millions of dollars to distinct
Speaker 4:  Movie. There's just so many like, oh my God, the sun hits it. The reflections.
Speaker 3:  If you're looking for more mediocre Star Wars shows, just wait until we enable
Speaker 3:  David's volumetric set.
Speaker 5:  Oh, there we go now. Okay, Liam. This just changed everything
Speaker 5:  now. Instead of having my one maybe real maybe static background, I
Speaker 5:  get to have a new one. Every single podcast. Yeah. We're doing this. I do.
Speaker 5:  I will say I have a, I think like eight foot
Speaker 5:  wide green screen underneath this couch
Speaker 3:  Over here. Now you've given it away. Well, I guess it's a second eight foot
Speaker 3:  wide green
Speaker 5:  Screen. This is Right. It's a, the green screen. Behind the green screen.
Speaker 5:  But there, the setup to make it work with my
Speaker 5:  computer was so complicated that we just gave up, which is why I don't
Speaker 5:  have a more interesting background, unfortunately. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Well soon we'll get you the full volume and Sean Favre is gonna direct you
Speaker 3:  in a Be Quest
Speaker 5:  Deal. I'll wear the helmet. That's
Speaker 3:  How he directed the Lion King here.
Speaker 5:  I'm into it. I think
Speaker 3:  It might have been a rift actually.
Speaker 4:  I was like, he he wore a headset.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. 'cause he, when they made the Lion King, it's like all, it's all CGI.
Speaker 3:  So he directed it in a headset. I don't know exactly why he
Speaker 3:  was in headset, but there's a lot of photos of him in headset directing Line
Speaker 3:  King just sitting there. It's good. Okay. There's actually news talking about
Speaker 3:  including a legitimate ray tracing segue
Speaker 3:  to what is arguably the news of the week, which is the
Speaker 3:  PS five Pro,
Speaker 4:  Not, not the iPhone.
Speaker 3:  Well, the iPhone, I guess the iPhone happened this week. It did. This is
Speaker 3:  a
Speaker 5:  Lot, if I'm being completely honest, based on just the
Speaker 5:  vibes on The Verge dot com, the PS five Pro might be bigger news than the
Speaker 5:  iPhone, which I think says something about the iPhone this year. But also
Speaker 5:  says a lot about how a lot of people feel about the particulars of the PS
Speaker 5:  five Pro. I just
Speaker 3:  Legitimately forgot that I was the iPhone matter
Speaker 3:  in my mind. We did a VERGE cast. The week ended. I I took a flight home.
Speaker 3:  It was a red eye. I took, I was asleep. I woke up in New York.
Speaker 3:  That's a new week everybody. Yep. Like start the calendar right over.
Speaker 3:  But you're, I think you're generally correct, David. Like, you know, in the
Speaker 3:  room it's, it is like very hard for me to tell. Yeah. 'cause it's just an
Speaker 3:  artificially hype environment. But out here in the world, even
Speaker 3:  other reporters I've talked to, interest is low.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's not great.
Speaker 5:  Not only that, but it was so like disappointing
Speaker 5:  that I think the general Apple vibes are bad
Speaker 5:  because of it. Like a lot of people all over the internet and
Speaker 5:  some of them at this website that we work at called The Verge dot com,
Speaker 5:  who are generally people who like Apple and think stuff that Apple does is
Speaker 5:  cool, are like turning on the company. Like to, to the point where
Speaker 5:  it's like, is this an inflection point where Apple has lost the plot? Like
Speaker 5:  that's a thing you see over and over and over now. Yeah. It's wild.
Speaker 3:  I would say, I saw John Gruber, who I saw at the event. He,
Speaker 3:  John lives it charmed lifestyle. He came to the event with Armed only with
Speaker 3:  a pen and a notebook.
Speaker 4:  I love that.
Speaker 3:  Incredible. I mean, I think he incredible had a phone on him, but he had
Speaker 3:  no laptop. But he tweeted afterwards, apple, Mrs. Steve Jobs like
Speaker 3:  everyone else. Or some variation of that sentence, which is a lot. That's
Speaker 3:  a big one. MG Siegler, who is also a friend, wrote an entire blog post
Speaker 3:  about Apple needs. An editor has too many products and I can't say no. And
Speaker 3:  hi, part of his thesis was
Speaker 3:  there too, stuck to the way Steve Jobs would've done things. And they
Speaker 3:  need to change for, they need to make more aggressive changes. His
Speaker 3:  example, of course, being the iPad. Yeah. Just let it run Mac os, which is
Speaker 3:  kind of like a hard diversion, you know, it's like extreme nerdery.
Speaker 3:  But you see that that vibe is out there, right. This, this is a company
Speaker 3:  that's no longer saying no. It is, it knows it's about to make more money
Speaker 3:  from services than the hardware. So it's just making all the hardware without
Speaker 3:  a point of view. I don't know, man. I think the thing that's weirdest for
Speaker 3:  me is they're gonna ship the phones without the
Speaker 3:  software.
Speaker 4:  It's sloppy feeling.
Speaker 3:  And it th there's just something about that, that they wouldn't have done
Speaker 3:  that before.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well th they, it was only a couple of years ago where they did that
Speaker 4:  whole thing where they said, we are gonna slow down on all of our software.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. 'cause we are going too fast and we're getting too sloppy. And then
Speaker 4:  to see them just kind of do it again, but even more
Speaker 4:  aggressively is surprising.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So we'll see. And, and there's, you know, I think a big question that
Speaker 3:  I have in general is whether any of the AI stuff comes to anything. We're
Speaker 3:  gonna talk about some AI products later on the show. There's some interesting
Speaker 3:  ones that have come out. Some, some stuff is happening that is legitimately
Speaker 3:  interest raising. Whether it's gonna make all of the money that the AI industry
Speaker 3:  is currently spending, who knows? But Apple's in a rush to ship this
Speaker 3:  stuff. For what? I dunno. So, yeah. But I, I agree with you, David. Like
Speaker 3:  I, to my mind, the PS five pro is, it's generated more
Speaker 3:  interest because it is a more considered product. It has a
Speaker 3:  stronger point of view on what's gonna happen next. Whether you agree with
Speaker 3:  that point of view or not. Yeah, yeah, yeah. You can disagree with, but
Speaker 3:  it, it, it just, it's a, it's a stronger statement of like, whatever
Speaker 3:  might, whatever Sony thinks is next. Well, Microsoft is making the opposite
Speaker 3:  statement of like, maybe we should shut this down. Right. And like, there's
Speaker 3:  some turmoil happening in that industry and there's, there's like winners
Speaker 3:  and losers and it just seems, at least on the smartphone side, and we have
Speaker 3:  covered smartphones since the day The Verge started. Like our, we began
Speaker 3:  this thing in 2011 because of smartphones. And it feels like
Speaker 3:  whatever wave that is has crested into it. Like a steady state, even though
Speaker 3:  like just over there are some of the most interesting smartphones that have
Speaker 3:  ever existed. Like
Speaker 4:  The trifold.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like the, the honor trifold got more co it was at the top of CNBC.
Speaker 3:  That's how I know things have like, broken out of Gadget world is like when
Speaker 3:  more mainstream outlets cover things in weird ways. Yeah. And so he looks
Speaker 3:  at the top of the CN BC website on Apple Day or the day after.
Speaker 3:  And it was like the normal stuff like rate cut. No. Yes. Who knows, like
Speaker 3:  on CN bbc. And then just in the middle of that was
Speaker 3:  $2,800 triple fold smartphone. And it was like,
Speaker 3:  that's the key word. Like a bunch of finance bros were like, hell
Speaker 3:  yeah. Like, I wanna spend $3,000 on an wanna
Speaker 4:  Smart. They watch the charts go up and down.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean they, they can. And it's like, that is more interesting to people
Speaker 3:  than whatever is happening. It wasn't Apple announces iPhone 16, right? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And there's something there. It's a gimmick. Who knows? Right. We'll
Speaker 4:  See.
Speaker 3:  But there's just something, something is up. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  We're going to, you know, we're gonna carry on with the coverage. Ideally
Speaker 3:  we'll review the phones. We'll have something to say about them. Like I said,
Speaker 3:  I'm still open to audience feedback on how to cover phones that are
Speaker 3:  launching without the core software that they're
Speaker 4:  Supposed to
Speaker 5:  Finish. We've gotten a lot of that feedback, by the way. And I think it's,
Speaker 5:  it, it, it's interesting to me, and I would say the, the plurality of
Speaker 5:  the folks who've reached out to us agree with me that you in particular are
Speaker 5:  so hung up on this software that hasn't launched. Because I would say there
Speaker 5:  is very little indication that anything in that software is going to like
Speaker 5:  meaningfully change your life in any way. Like
Speaker 5:  this is, this is the, the I AI story right now is you have to tell
Speaker 5:  people you have an AI strategy and what cool products are there
Speaker 5:  that exist that are mattering to lots of people all the time. The
Speaker 4:  The thing is, you don't have to do that unless you do. You're totally
Speaker 4:  beholden. Unless
Speaker 5:  You're total, you get fired and your company goes outta business If. you
Speaker 5:  don't.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You have to. You are so beholden to the stock market and you're so
Speaker 4:  beholden to your shareholders that you are not actually considering what
Speaker 4:  is a good product. And that, that, that feels like what we're butting
Speaker 4:  up against is people chasing the shareholders at the expense of the audience.
Speaker 5:  Oh, I agree. I think it's the whole thing. And actually shipping is all downside.
Speaker 5:  Like Yeah. When, when you put this stuff out in the world, that's when all
Speaker 5:  the bad stuff happens. It's, it's like it's
Speaker 4:  That's, we know the
Speaker 5:  Rabbit sucks Silicon Valley line, right? Like don't start making money because
Speaker 5:  then people start asking why you're not making more money. Like don't start
Speaker 5:  shipping AI because then everybody will ask why you're not shipping better
Speaker 5:  AI like this. Google has been through this 10 times over at this point.
Speaker 5:  Like it just keeps shipping stuff and it's broken and people freak out and
Speaker 5:  it's bad. And it is just nuking its core business in the name
Speaker 5:  of chasing AI stuff. And people are starting to wonder why. But If,
Speaker 5:  you don't tell investors that you have an AI strategy.
Speaker 5:  You won't have a job long enough to see any of it through. Yeah. Yeah. So
Speaker 5:  it's like, if, if I'm Apple, I, I think this is a total conspiracy
Speaker 5:  theory that is not actually what's going on. But like, it is an, it is not
Speaker 5:  a stupid idea to slow roll this as much as you can talk it up and don't ship
Speaker 5:  it is like a pretty solid save your ass strategy
Speaker 3:  Right now. But it's totally out of character for them. It's totally, totally
Speaker 3:  outta
Speaker 5:  Charact I'll say that I've been playing with, but AI has been out of character
Speaker 5:  for everybody. Like so many companies have not been themselves since
Speaker 5:  chat GBT launched.
Speaker 3:  That's true. I will say I've been playing with a Pixel nine pro these past
Speaker 3:  few days and every time you pick up that
Speaker 3:  phone it's like, do you want me to do something for you? Have you met Gemini?
Speaker 3:  Here? I am. Would you like to add yourself to this photo? You're not in this
Speaker 3:  photo. Put yourself in the photo.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And you're like, can you just turn off Bluetooth? And it's like, ah,
Speaker 5:  I can't, so sorry.
Speaker 3:  It's like, it it is like a, it is like a version of clippy from hell. You
Speaker 3:  know, it's like, do you want me to add some text to this email for some reason
Speaker 3:  I could. Yeah. Huh. Yeah. Why not? Why are we not? It's fine.
Speaker 3:  It's just a very, it's a weird time that said, we'll, we'll
Speaker 3:  we'll pick up the Apple stuff later. One thing to note,
Speaker 3:  I hear what you're saying, that it's weird that I'm focused on the softwares
Speaker 3:  in shipping 'cause I'm Mr. Review what's in the box. One thing that did get
Speaker 3:  announced just in the time between the event and today the
Speaker 3:  FDA actually did approve the hearing aid features for the AirPods too. That's
Speaker 3:  very cool. Which I continue to believe will be the biggest, the the most
Speaker 3:  impactful announcement of this event. Yes. So that, that did happen. We
Speaker 3:  assume it will ship later this fall now because they have the clearance.
Speaker 3:  That's a big deal. Yeah. But that's it. Like I don't, we're waiting on everything
Speaker 3:  else. Alright. Let's actually talk about PS five Pro. What, what is it
Speaker 3:  Alex? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You know, have you ever like looked at a computer
Speaker 4:  and you're like, what if this computer was a little cheaper? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It didn't do as much stuff. It played video games really, really
Speaker 4:  well. But it was also twice as much as another thing we have
Speaker 4:  that plays video games really, really well. Yeah. And, and, and
Speaker 4:  it just plays it a little better.
Speaker 3:  Is this just like a GPU upgrade for the PS?
Speaker 4:  It basically is, yeah. It's a GPU upgrade. You, it's got a much bigger GPU.
Speaker 4:  They are claiming much better ray tracing and also their version of
Speaker 4:  DLSS, which is an NVIDIA thing that like upscales so
Speaker 4:  much more intelligent ai.
Speaker 3:  But it's not actually DL DLSS.
Speaker 4:  It's not actually DLSS 'cause that's Nvidia,
Speaker 3:  It's just their a MD based riff on. Right.
Speaker 4:  Okay. They're a MD based, but not actually the a MD version. This is a
Speaker 4:  Sony version Oh, good. Of the same thing. AI upscaling and,
Speaker 4:  and those are kind of the three big deals out of it. And, and the other big
Speaker 4:  part of it is that the price, it's $700. The normal one's
Speaker 4:  about four 50, and so it's not quite twice, but
Speaker 4:  it's expensive. Yeah. And it's, it's also got,
Speaker 4:  you know, no dis disk drive and people are having a lot of feelings about
Speaker 4:  the disk drive. Well
Speaker 3:  You can get an accessory one, right. You can get
Speaker 4:  An accessory one. But it's kind of like, remember when they took the disc
Speaker 4:  drive out of the, the, the MacBook and everybody lost their mind?
Speaker 4:  It's the same thing. It's like physical media. I love physical media. It
Speaker 4:  feels like physical media has been like on an uptick. And now it's like,
Speaker 4:  oh, so I've just done $700 for this and then another $80
Speaker 4:  for the disc drive. What
Speaker 5:  This feels like to me is as if Apple
Speaker 5:  revved the Mac Pro and was like, this thing is sick
Speaker 5:  fastest ever, everything is amazing. You're gonna love it. It has
Speaker 5:  one USBC port. Yeah. That's it. Enjoy. Like,
Speaker 5:  it, it, it doesn't make any sense to me that you would make your highest
Speaker 5:  and most impressive looking thing, which
Speaker 5:  has a Venn diagram of users that I would say overlaps fairly aggressively
Speaker 5:  with the section of users who care about things like physical media and
Speaker 5:  having a collection of discs and cares about the, the liner
Speaker 5:  notes and all that stuff. Like those two people are the same person. And
Speaker 5:  so the idea that you're gonna be like, we're gonna give you all
Speaker 5:  the power in the world, but no, physical media
Speaker 5:  is just so strange to me. Even if it were gonna make this thing more expensive,
Speaker 5:  if it was $800 and had a disc drive, I would understand it way more than
Speaker 5:  I understand $700 at no disc drive. But you
Speaker 3:  Can spend $780 and get the discount
Speaker 5:  You can.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But I, I think it's, it's the fact that it's called the pro. It is
Speaker 4:  so much more expensive and then it doesn't have a disk drive it. So,
Speaker 4:  so that, that's where people are getting concerned. But at the same time,
Speaker 4:  as we talked about earlier, this is, this is where they're heading. Right.
Speaker 4:  Like they've been heading this way for a long time. They don't want you to
Speaker 4:  have a desk drive. Yeah. They don't want you to using the desks. They, they
Speaker 4:  want you,
Speaker 3:  They certainly do not want used games to exist. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They want you buying the thing on their store and then when it doesn't work,
Speaker 4:  going and buying the new upgrade on their store over and over and over again.
Speaker 4:  They're very happy with that. And, and most of the developers and stuff seem
Speaker 4:  pretty fine with that. It's just the, the real
Speaker 4:  hardcore fans. But the hardcore fans so far are really excited about this
Speaker 4:  thing.
Speaker 3:  Wait, I'm, I like, I like Best drive. I like
Speaker 3:  physical media. I like owning software. Yeah. I think my prerequisites on
Speaker 3:  this are, you know, my quiet is there. You've
Speaker 4:  Talked about it a bit. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  You know, I, I, I feel, so let me just make the argument here. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  The PS five in particular from inception has been all about
Speaker 3:  wicked fast SSD speeds. Yes. So you were never playing the
Speaker 3:  game off the optical disc. You were always copying it to the Yep. SST So
Speaker 3:  the, the disc is like a totem. Yes. Right? It's
Speaker 3:  you're always downloading the game.
Speaker 4:  You're holding it and you're like, yeah, I can do this. Theoretically you
Speaker 4:  can play parts of the game off of the disc, but for the most part it's, it's
Speaker 4:  downloading it on versus
Speaker 3:  Well you're definitely, you're definitely at least copying a enormous chunks
Speaker 3:  of the game for this.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And then you have to do your day zero updates and all of that stuff.
Speaker 3:  So what I'm just like If you, like I am a person with a vinyl collection.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And you, you know, it's like, I like to put on a record and then like
Speaker 3:  shake my fist at the man because they can't, the internet has
Speaker 3:  nothing to do with listening to music in that case. I,
Speaker 4:  I think the concern here is that now you can't, like If, you wanna play a
Speaker 4:  PS four game or something. If, you wanna play an older game. Sure. You can't
Speaker 4:  use, you know, you have to pay extra for that If, you wanna watch a movie,
Speaker 4:  which, like the PS five has historically been a very good Blu-ray player.
Speaker 4:  You have to now pay extra for that. And it's got that pro moniker.
Speaker 4:  So you're like, okay,
Speaker 3:  I see what you're saying. It is just like value for doll.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It, yeah, it's just like, it's, it's just a, it's a squirrely, squirrely
Speaker 4:  space, but like the PS five Pro is really cool,
Speaker 4:  but I'm one, I'm like a graphics nerd, so I'm like, yeah, this is sick. But
Speaker 4:  also I don't need to spend $700 on this thing. I've got a PS five
Speaker 4:  Yeah. With a disc drive. It rules.
Speaker 3:  I play games in it. The thing that actually gets me is right next to
Speaker 3:  this they released Astro Bott, which is like Game of the Year Contender.
Speaker 3:  Yes. I've been playing Astros playroom with Max. We are like gonna, we bought
Speaker 3:  the controller, which is adorable. We're gonna play Astro Bott
Speaker 3:  whenever she tires of Astros playroom. The thing about a 6-year-old is like,
Speaker 3:  yeah, just keep playing this game. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's just the first five minutes over and over and over
Speaker 3:  Again. You're you're good. Actually, we don't need to introduce new ideas
Speaker 3:  or spend money, but like, from what I can tell Astro Bot is
Speaker 3:  the reason to buy a PS five. Yeah. And it is not the reason to buy a
Speaker 3:  PS five Pro. It just feels, those things feel disconnected to me in a way
Speaker 3:  that seems ridiculous. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  'cause the Astro Bott is focusing in kind of like the Nintendo play style
Speaker 4:  of, of Nintendo is all about, it doesn't care about the graphics as much.
Speaker 4:  It cares about how the game plays. Whereas PlayStation and Xbox have historically
Speaker 4:  been like, we care about how the game plays, but also we want it to look
Speaker 4:  fucking sick. Yeah. And, and in this case they're like,
Speaker 4:  nah. Like we've got this one side where we had this asbo and you can use
Speaker 4:  the controller in all these really incredible ways. Feels like a switch.
Speaker 4:  It feels just new and dynamic and fun. And then
Speaker 4:  we got this like
Speaker 3:  Other thing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. This thing. So you can go play Grant Ismo.
Speaker 3:  What's the best, that's really cool. The, what's the best argument for the
Speaker 3:  PS five Pro?
Speaker 4:  Do you really like Spider-Man two?
Speaker 3:  I mean, that's always, that's like the core argument for the PlayStation.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like
Speaker 3:  The PlayStation two is literally had the Spider-Man font on it.
Speaker 4:  It really is like, like the, the core argument is, do you really like
Speaker 4:  the last of us in SPI and Spider-Man and, and some of these
Speaker 4:  other games that have actually implemented ray tracing and do you really
Speaker 4:  want to, like, you really, really like that? And if so, go get this
Speaker 4:  because it's gonna look a little sharper. It's gonna look a little cleaner.
Speaker 4:  I think If, you are playing on a con or if you're playing your console on
Speaker 4:  a monitor, it makes sense.
Speaker 3:  Sure.
Speaker 4:  If you're playing it on a big TV in like a huge sunlit room,
Speaker 4:  don't do this. Like, that's just a waste of money. You will not be able to
Speaker 4:  appreciate a single bit of this. I
Speaker 5:  I will say, I think the, the most compelling argument of this, and I think
Speaker 5:  is his name, mark Cerney, the lead architect. Okay. I can never remember
Speaker 5:  if it's Matt or Mark. It's like the same. It's, it's two different people
Speaker 5:  in my head. But anyway, it's, mark said basically that
Speaker 5:  the thing that they've seen is that everybody is forever making trade offs
Speaker 5:  between performance and fidelity. Right. So like, do I want
Speaker 5:  it to look good or do I want lots of frames? And and that is, that is like
Speaker 5:  kind of the gaming performance trade off. And with the PS five pro, you
Speaker 5:  don't have to make that trade off. Right? Yeah. Like you can have very high
Speaker 5:  settings at very high frame rates. That's not a thing that
Speaker 5:  most people will notice, but it is the kind of thing
Speaker 5:  that matters, right? Like it's, I I I, I see that as the same argument
Speaker 5:  for like why the two of you spent six times as much money on your
Speaker 5:  televisions as I did. It's, it's, it's not for everybody
Speaker 3:  Because my eyes work, David.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Then, then why not spend $700 on this? And
Speaker 3:  I happily said it to Fidelity mode and I let it drop
Speaker 3:  frames while I try to fi figure out the new kicking indicator from Adam every
Speaker 3:  year. It's, it's fine. It's impossible to use.
Speaker 5:  I think to your Astro Bott point, I think the, the thing that is odd to me
Speaker 5:  about this launch is that there isn't one sort of
Speaker 5:  great example, right? There's a bunch of games. They've actually, I think
Speaker 5:  upgraded a lot of games. There are a lot of things that will look slightly
Speaker 5:  better. But this is the sort of thing that I think works when you can come
Speaker 5:  out with like a, a sort of next
Speaker 5:  generation looking game. Well,
Speaker 4:  And I think that's increasingly hard to do. We've seen this since Oh, for
Speaker 4:  sure. Since like the PS three of saying, oh, I think we're kind of hitting
Speaker 4:  our limit on how we can make, how good we can make these games look. And
Speaker 4:  the difference between a PS four and a PS five game. I'm so sorry to a lot
Speaker 4:  of people out there who are gonna be really upset with me right now isn't
Speaker 4:  actually that different. Like Yeah. I will notice it, Neil, I will notice
Speaker 4:  it. A a few, a small group of fans are really gonna notice those differences.
Speaker 4:  The majority of people are just gonna be like, yeah, that's the game. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Sometimes it's a little blurry, sometimes it's not. And, and, and the majority
Speaker 4:  of people don't care about that. And they're really trying to push this idea.
Speaker 4:  They, they, they said, oh, a lot more people are choosing
Speaker 4:  the performance mode over the Fidelity mode. We wanted to give them the give,
Speaker 4:  make them not have to choose. That's why we did this.
Speaker 4:  How many people like, I don't think it's the majority of people,
Speaker 5:  But that's fine, right? This isn't supposed to be for everybody. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It's for professionals. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But it's for professional who is the professional.
Speaker 5:  This is just for Ninja. That's the only
Speaker 3:  Way.
Speaker 4:  But it's not like there's any pro features here. The pro feature is we put
Speaker 4:  a bigger GPU in because we could fit a bigger GPU in. And one of the criticisms
Speaker 4:  of the original PS five was that it was, it, and the Xbox were underpowered
Speaker 4:  as soon as they arrived because they were based on current, that current
Speaker 4:  Gen A MD technology. And so it's like they've always been a little
Speaker 4:  behind the times, but the exchanges that the games just play.
Speaker 4:  And so now that PlayStation is putting all these options in and making you
Speaker 4:  think about these things, you're starting to think of it less like a
Speaker 4:  console where just you plug it in and go and you're starting to think of
Speaker 4:  it more like a pc. And I think that's a dangerous place for
Speaker 4:  Sony to be historically the famous PC
Speaker 4:  pro successful PC program over there. Yeah. They really know how to do it.
Speaker 4:  But like, like it works for Microsoft, it makes sense for Microsoft. Microsoft's
Speaker 4:  doing the exact same thing. Both of these companies are pushing these things
Speaker 4:  towards PCs. They fundamentally are, they're all the technology in them,
Speaker 4:  or PC technology. They're based on AMD's technology.
Speaker 4:  Nintendo's over on the other side saying, what if we just did cool shit?
Speaker 3:  What if we made good games? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  What if we just make good games? And it's, it's a weird place that, that
Speaker 4:  Sony's taking this. And I don't know if, so like, it makes sense
Speaker 4:  for Xbox. It doesn't make as much sense for Sony.
Speaker 3:  I will, I will point out that
Speaker 3:  the $80 disc drive is sold out on Amazon and Best Buy
Speaker 3:  and Target.
Speaker 5:  So this is the Venn diagram. Like truthfully, it
Speaker 4:  Also works for the PS five slim. So, you know, there's a lot of slim
Speaker 4:  owners out there, I'm
Speaker 3:  Sure. But this
Speaker 5:  Is what kills me. The slim not having a disc drive. I completely understand.
Speaker 5:  Yes. That makes perfect sense. Having it be cheaper
Speaker 5:  and smaller and for people whose games are digital, which is most people
Speaker 5:  makes absolute perfect sense to me. This just
Speaker 5:  doesn't like, and, and in this, in this one tiny
Speaker 5:  lane, you have a group of people who will put up with a bigger console who
Speaker 5:  are likely to pay more for it, who are willing to make all the sacrifices
Speaker 5:  required to get the very best possible everything out of it. Right? Like
Speaker 5:  the only reason to buy this is If. you want like the 10 out of 10
Speaker 5:  experience? Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Let me get in here with my hot take. Okay, let's go Liam. Y'all ready?
Speaker 1:  Yeah, we're ready. The problem with the PS five Pro is not that it's
Speaker 1:  too expensive, it's that it's not expensive enough. They
Speaker 1:  should have released a 9 99 version of this thing. Not a
Speaker 1:  $700. It should actually be a PC that you can
Speaker 1:  hook up to your TV and have the like, lovely experience of
Speaker 1:  just, it always working for your game. You just turn it on and
Speaker 1:  start playing your game. But with the graphics that
Speaker 1:  people are buying their PC games for. Yeah. Sony knows
Speaker 1:  that there are a lot of people out there that care about having the best
Speaker 1:  possible version of their games and they'll play them on pc. I think they've
Speaker 1:  proven that they could sell a 9 99 PS five to
Speaker 1:  the extreme end of the market. The enthusiasts.
Speaker 3:  I like that. You, you've just pitched a home theater pc. I was, everything
Speaker 3:  comes
Speaker 5:  All the way around. Just like somebody at Microsoft is hearing this going,
Speaker 5:  oh God. Oh God. Oh God. We're
Speaker 3:  We're gonna do it again. We're
Speaker 1:  Just too soon. They were just too soon.
Speaker 4:  They're too soon. No, I,
Speaker 5:  I too Liam's point, I do think the idea of
Speaker 5:  play PC games but don't have to deal with Windows would be compelling to
Speaker 5:  a surprisingly large number of people. Which I think is also what Microsoft
Speaker 5:  thinks and can't figure out what to do
Speaker 4:  With. It's, it's trying, it's trying. Like, I mean, I I think the next Xbox
Speaker 4:  not, not the next gen
Speaker 3:  Isn't you just describe the steam deck.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Right? I mean, isn't that the, like you're on a plane, you can play PC games
Speaker 3:  and doesn't run Windows. The battery life is
Speaker 5:  Good. Yeah. But the, the Steam deck runs a, runs a like
Speaker 5:  smartphone chip on a tiny screen. Yeah. It's
Speaker 4:  Like a potato compared to the PS five graphics
Speaker 3:  Wise. All right. Here, here's my poll for The Vergecast audience.
Speaker 3:  But let's assume you own a, a PS five. What would you rather spend money
Speaker 3:  on a Steam deck or a PS five Pro? You know, us. I'm very, I
Speaker 3:  I I feel like just based on this conversation, that's more of a choice
Speaker 3:  than we are, right?
Speaker 5:  No, I I think that's the wrong question. I I don't think this is like every
Speaker 5:  year when people are like, should you upgrade from the iPhone 15 to the 16?
Speaker 5:  Like the answer's no. And no one is doing that. The answer is If. you have
Speaker 5:  a PS four or a PS four Pro. Like to me the
Speaker 5:  interesting upgrade path is If. you have a PS four Pro and you've been sitting
Speaker 5:  around waiting for the PS five Pro to buy one. Is this the thing you were
Speaker 5:  waiting for If, you have a PS five. I I would, I would bet the number of
Speaker 5:  people who were like, oh, throw my PS five in the trash. I'm buying a PS
Speaker 5:  five pro to get slightly better. Ray tracing is like vanishingly
Speaker 5:  small, but I don't think that's who Sony is going for
Speaker 4:  Here. But I also think the PS four Pro people, I was one of those people.
Speaker 4:  I had a PS four pro. I really liked it.
Speaker 5:  I have one right here. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's great. Got a PS five because it was new and I wanted to play all the
Speaker 4:  new games. If you're on a PS four pro, you're now having to pay twice
Speaker 4:  the amount, like the PS five, the PS four Pro wasn't
Speaker 4:  this high a markup between it and the regular PS
Speaker 5:  Four. Didn't it also come out like right after the PS four?
Speaker 4:  No, it took, it, it it took a while. It a couple years. Yeah. It was a couple
Speaker 4:  years and it was a big upgrade. 'cause you were doing 4K you were doing like
Speaker 4:  a lot of big stuff in it. Whereas this one is just like
Speaker 4:  we've do you know what DLSS is?
Speaker 3:  We made our own weird version of it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And like that's a lot harder to sell to the, nor like the, the normal
Speaker 4:  folks. I say because we're all big nerds here. We love having a
Speaker 3:  Good planet. Look, I watch these comparison videos. I waited for Digital
Speaker 3:  Foundry to do its thing. Yeah. And I was still like, yeah, I don't, I'm good.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like I'm horrible at Madden and I play Astro Bott.
Speaker 4:  The whole meme right now is people watching it and like pausing it and taking
Speaker 4:  their glasses off and on. Trying to see where the differences are between
Speaker 4:  the two, the two versions. 'cause it, it's really small and Yeah, it's
Speaker 4:  noticeable, but it's really small. Yeah. And most people don't care that
Speaker 4:  much. They just wanna play the game. I
Speaker 3:  Will issue my almost weekly reminder that you cannot evaluate the quality
Speaker 3:  of anything on your smartphone screen. Yeah. You just can't,
Speaker 3:  you can't look at stuff on a smartphone screen. Just like when people try
Speaker 3:  to, we do it all the time when we're like, listen to these speakers and we
Speaker 3:  like play, we record them and then people watch them on YouTube, on their
Speaker 3:  smartphone speakers. I don't know what's happening there. That's
Speaker 5:  Nothing. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's just like a handshake agreement through the internet to like, we're
Speaker 3:  gonna feel some vibes. Yeah. That's not right. Just
Speaker 4:  Believe us. We're telling the truth.
Speaker 3:  That's how I feel about those VSI videos. I dunno, I am very interested in
Speaker 3:  what is happening in the broader gaming market. 'cause it feels like that
Speaker 3:  shakeup,
Speaker 4:  This split is like really happening, right? Like, like we knew this
Speaker 4:  PC moment was happening for consoles, but this in particular,
Speaker 4:  like it was, it was, it was a moment with PS four Pro. 'cause you were like,
Speaker 4:  okay, now we are fracturing the console market in a way the console market
Speaker 4:  typically isn't fractured. The whole point of the console market is no fracture.
Speaker 4:  Like everything is, you go, you buy this thing, it does the games and now
Speaker 4:  you're getting all these different skews sort of like Apple just introducing
Speaker 4:  all these different SKUs and like, yeah, okay, you're gonna meet more of
Speaker 4:  the market here, but you also lose why people like this product to begin
Speaker 4:  with, which is simplicity.
Speaker 5:  I wonder if what we're seeing is just this like incredible
Speaker 5:  bifurcation of the gaming industry where on the one hand you have the, the
Speaker 5:  handheld revolution, right? Which is like, I think is going to eat the low
Speaker 5:  end consoles alive. It's already happening. Right? Like if I
Speaker 5:  just want to play Astro bot, the idea of me needing a
Speaker 5:  gigantic box to do it, I think is like, that's ending very quickly.
Speaker 5:  Then the flip side is the high end stuff is going to get higher end. So it
Speaker 5:  feels like we're we're gonna end up in a place of like music streaming and
Speaker 5:  vinyl and nothing in between. Right? Yeah. You're either gonna have this
Speaker 5:  sort of like beautiful bespoke setup with a lot of
Speaker 5:  very specific things, but it is going to be extremely high fidelity and wonderful.
Speaker 5:  Or we're going to lean deep into convenience and streaming and
Speaker 5:  everything is gonna be lower quality. But that's what people want. Well
Speaker 4:  I think the, the, the the, there's a third prong here that kind of affects
Speaker 4:  it, which is that they own so many of these studios that they're, that are
Speaker 4:  making these games and these studios aren't making games for anybody else.
Speaker 4:  Right? Like Astro bot. You can't go play that on anything but a
Speaker 4:  Sony device. 'cause Sony wants to keep you in their wheelhouse and that's,
Speaker 4:  Ooh, the FTC, it's gonna have feelings. If you get, I think If
Speaker 4:  you get, if you're like, look, we're basically PCs, we're doing all of this
Speaker 4:  stuff also you can't play last of us on anything else. People will start
Speaker 4:  having feelings about that in a very real, real way that I'm kind of curious
Speaker 4:  about.
Speaker 3:  Well, I think Sony's allowed to have its first party studios, which has been
Speaker 3:  whittling down. It's when Microsoft bought Activision and said, we're gonna
Speaker 3:  close off Call of Duty that you've got all the regulators. I would point
Speaker 3:  out that ever since Microsoft actually closed that Activision deal, it has
Speaker 3:  just been clown cars, cities over there just
Speaker 3:  banging into walls and falling off cliffs. It's great. They announced
Speaker 3:  just today that they're gonna lay off 650 more Xbox employees. That's sucks.
Speaker 3:  This is just a wave of layoffs and strategy shifts all after
Speaker 3:  they, they fought too thin nail to buy Activision
Speaker 3:  because something,
Speaker 4:  Because they wanna have, everybody wants their little fiefdom and you have
Speaker 4:  to go and buy the console to get in to play the games rather than just play
Speaker 4:  them on a pc, which they can all theoretically do because
Speaker 4:  architecturally they're all the same.
Speaker 3:  Well, sure. But I'm Sony at least has a, well, first of all,
Speaker 3:  it's the winner of this generation. Yeah. 'cause it's
Speaker 4:  Got the good
Speaker 3:  Games. If, you don't count the switch. Like it's, it's legit. Which is one
Speaker 3:  every generation that it's been anywhere near. Right? Yeah. And the new switch
Speaker 3:  we think is coming out that will probably win whatever generation it's a
Speaker 3:  part of. Yeah. They, they, the cycles don't quite line up. But Sony has beaten
Speaker 3:  Microsoft pretty soundly this generation. I I hear what you're saying. Like
Speaker 3:  the underlying software or the underlying hardware architectures are similar
Speaker 3:  like their a MD chips, but the PS five is
Speaker 3:  a, it's an opinionated device. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 3:  It Sony has a lot of thoughts about the PlayStation and what it's for and
Speaker 3:  what the game should work like. And Mark Cerney has a lot of ideas about
Speaker 3:  settings. Right? Like there's,
Speaker 3:  there's a vision there for better or worse. And you can not feel it and you
Speaker 3:  can be mad about the dis drive. But yeah, Sony has confidence. Microsoft
Speaker 3:  has confidence. I think Phil Spencer is a confident person. They have a lot
Speaker 3:  of ideas, but actually they're, it feels to me like
Speaker 3:  they knew they were losing, they wanted to make a big swing and they
Speaker 3:  have just whiffed on a bunch of their big swings. They whiffed on cloud gaming,
Speaker 3:  which was supposed to be the biggest swing of all. They haven't pulled it
Speaker 3:  off yet. Yeah. This Activision deal, you know, they let
Speaker 3:  Call of Duty be the side show, but it was really about Candy Crush. And Phil
Speaker 3:  has said this to us, mobile gaming is the future and no one has a foothold
Speaker 3:  there. We gotta win there. That was also kind of a weird Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Side show of cloud gaming and, and none of that. I don't think
Speaker 3:  anybody, any consumer, if you're a, if you're a gamer, please,
Speaker 3:  please use the feature in iOS where it makes your emails a little bit nicer.
Speaker 3:  But then email us. I'm curious, did, did Microsoft buying Activision
Speaker 3:  improve anything about my playing games for you? Like I don't see
Speaker 3:  it yet. And it's true, the deal is pretty new. Yeah. But you,
Speaker 3:  you see that what's happening over there is they are looking for a
Speaker 3:  new strategy or a new vision. And I, I think he
Speaker 3:  needed that before you made one of the biggest acquisitions of all time.
Speaker 4:  But I think Sony's muddied, you talk about it's got this big clear vision.
Speaker 4:  It's muddied that vision because on the one point, hey yeah, you have Astro
Speaker 4:  Bott, you have the last of us, you have Spider-Man, you have these games,
Speaker 4:  these first party games that look gorgeous or stunning, play great
Speaker 4:  on this thing, have really kind of unique things. Be focused on
Speaker 4:  that controller. And then you just have everything else. And, and Microsoft
Speaker 4:  has kind of said, we're gonna be everything else. We're gonna own that space.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna be the PCs, we're gonna bring, you know, kind of gaming pieces
Speaker 4:  into the console space. And Sony's now saying the same thing, even though
Speaker 4:  they've got this, this lead, they're saying, yeah, we're gonna do the same
Speaker 4:  thing. We're gonna muddy the waters here. And and I think that's where like
Speaker 4:  the PS five Pro doesn't have that clear vision you see in in their games.
Speaker 3:  Oh, I think it has one very clear vision. It costs more money costs
Speaker 4:  So much like
Speaker 3:  If you're gonna buy. Yeah. Right. Right. Now if you're gonna buy a console,
Speaker 3:  is there any or and you already have a switch. Yeah. 'cause that's what you
Speaker 3:  should buy.
Speaker 3:  If you're gonna buy a console, you're gonna buy a PS five. Yeah. Right. Is
Speaker 3:  there, they're the winner. That's what most people have chosen.
Speaker 4:  Unless you don't wanna play those first party games. If, you just wanna play
Speaker 4:  Call of Duty and stuff. Go get an Xbox. It'll just,
Speaker 5:  Now most people are still gonna buy PlayStations because
Speaker 4:  All their friends are
Speaker 5:  On it said that there is like a default choice. It's the PlayStation.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Right. So then you have a PlayStation and you can discount the regular
Speaker 3:  one because you have, you have your economy of scale. So you can go into
Speaker 3:  the holiday and be like, here's the cheap PlayStation like you're saying.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You get that series S and then you can ev. But there's
Speaker 3:  some category of people that will just spend more money and you can sit there.
Speaker 3:  We had a CFO at Fox a long time ago. Described his job as waiting to catch
Speaker 3:  the basketball. He's like, I'm just, the money comes and I'm here to get
Speaker 3:  it. And I was like, I don't think that's what A CFO does. But it was a learning
Speaker 3:  experience for me. He was great. I think Sony is just like, here's a
Speaker 3:  more expensive one. Catch
Speaker 4:  The money.
Speaker 3:  We're just here If, you got some If, you have 300 extra dollars. I do love
Speaker 3:  that. We'll take it
Speaker 4:  From you. Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 5:  Thi this is the game. Both of these companies have been playing for like
Speaker 5:  this whole generation. Right. And Microsoft's bet has
Speaker 5:  been for years now that we are on the cusp of a giant
Speaker 5:  shift in how this entire industry works. How we play the games, where
Speaker 5:  they are. Yeah. How they're architected. The kinds of games that we play.
Speaker 5:  Like Microsoft has been making this bet for a long time now. I
Speaker 5:  think Microsoft still thinks it's right and is running out of patience for
Speaker 5:  it to actually happen. Sony is just sitting around saying,
Speaker 5:  look at all this money flowing in. Like, and, and then the question will
Speaker 5:  be, If, you fast forward a few years, is Microsoft going to be
Speaker 5:  right before it gave up? Or is Sony just gonna have so much money
Speaker 5:  at the end of it that who cares? But like Sony is
Speaker 5:  basically betting that this shift is going to happen slowly and Microsoft
Speaker 5:  is betting that it's gonna happen fast. Okay.
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna end by saying one thing that will make everybody mad. Yeah. Or
Speaker 3:  that you will completely agree with. I don't think there's a middle ground.
Speaker 3:  It's weird that Microsoft has tried to run away from the idea of the Xbox
Speaker 3:  being a thing that just plays games really well for so long.
Speaker 4:  It's never wanted that. Right.
Speaker 3:  It's like the whole Xbox One side quest with where it had
Speaker 3:  IR blasters and HDMI passed. Like what? I don't, people got
Speaker 3:  so mad at me when I was like, this is a disaster.
Speaker 5:  My ongoing theory about this is that every once in a while there's an executive
Speaker 5:  meeting at Microsoft and somebody turns to Phil Spencer and goes like, why
Speaker 5:  are you here? And so he has to like explain why Xbox is part of Microsoft
Speaker 5:  And eventually that morphed into like talking about Azure and
Speaker 5:  then it was just toast,
Speaker 3:  Right? Can we run, this is what I mean. Like first, second we're okay, we're
Speaker 3:  gonna do it. We're gonna take over the, we're gonna, we're gonna have a dish
Speaker 3:  network integration in the Xbox. Like they were all the way down the rabbit
Speaker 3:  hole of that stuff. And they walked it all back to games and then it was
Speaker 3:  reasonably successful again. And then the,
Speaker 3:  this generation, they were starting with games and they're like, well, we
Speaker 3:  lost the Sony. We're gonna stream the games from Azure
Speaker 3:  that will disrupt the whole market. And that just has not panned out. No.
Speaker 3:  And it just seems like if they, yeah, because they're maybe some focus on
Speaker 3:  the main thing would continue to be successful.
Speaker 5:  But that's back it up to the first thing and it's a, it's a how do we be
Speaker 5:  part of the Windows strategy thing inside of Microsoft and then fast forward
Speaker 5:  to this generation and it's a how do we be part of the cloud first strategy
Speaker 5:  of Microsoft. Like I think there is a very compelling case to be made that
Speaker 5:  the best and worst thing going for the Xbox team is that they work for
Speaker 5:  Microsoft.
Speaker 4:  But you know, I was gonna say though, I think part of the reason they've
Speaker 4:  been doing all this flip flopping is because their first party games haven't
Speaker 4:  landed the same. Like, they just don't land. Like, like
Speaker 4:  Sony's first party games move consoles. People buy consoles for
Speaker 4:  Sony's first party games.
Speaker 5:  I don't know. Halo was good for a while.
Speaker 4:  Halo name another one
Speaker 5:  Halo too.
Speaker 4:  You see like, like, and, and Microsoft went on this whole buying spree. They
Speaker 4:  were like, we're gonna buy all of these companies. And then they got, they
Speaker 4:  got told, oh, okay. You cannot make Call of Duty exclusive for you.
Speaker 5:  They don't
Speaker 4:  Minecraft. Yeah. Not exclusive. Like, like first
Speaker 4:  party exclusives. You know, the last of us. Yeah. It's yeah. Spider-Man.
Speaker 4:  Those are exclusive. They come to the PC eventually and then you can sort
Speaker 4:  of play it through Xbox, I think through the cloud. But
Speaker 4:  you have to wait a while. Right? If, you wanna play the Last of Us, which
Speaker 4:  all the other gamers are playing and everybody's talking about you go get
Speaker 4:  a pay station.
Speaker 5:  Well, but I, yeah. And, and I think that all like that, that all sort of
Speaker 5:  flows from the same circles, right? Where it's like, okay, if, if our job
Speaker 5:  is to sell consoles, how do you sell consoles? You sell consoles with really
Speaker 5:  good games. But if our job is to like increase the market share of,
Speaker 5:  of our cl or cloud services arm of our company, you just
Speaker 5:  prioritize things very differently.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I think full sensor would take deep issue with that
Speaker 3:  characterization of Xbox. But it's always a little more true
Speaker 3:  than maybe wants to be. Yeah. By the way, can I just read you the first paragraph
Speaker 3:  of his note announcing these layoffs
Speaker 3:  for the past? This is Phil Spencer, his memo to Microsoft employees
Speaker 3:  for the past year. Our goal has been to minimize disruption while welcoming
Speaker 3:  new teams and enabling to do their best work. As part of aligning our post
Speaker 3:  acquisition team structure, managing our business, we've made decision to
Speaker 3:  eliminate approximately 650 roles. We welcome. You're fired.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's tough. And then at the end of it, he like, we've had some good days
Speaker 5:  and we've had some bad days and this is a bad day. It's like, thanks though.
Speaker 3:  I mean, there's no good way to write those notes. No there's not. I think
Speaker 3:  mergers are bad. That's all I'm saying. I think generally they lead to chaos
Speaker 3:  and disruption in actually smaller companies with less focus or less
Speaker 3:  ambition. What do I, I suspect that will be in the long run true of the
Speaker 3:  ion deal. Are
Speaker 4:  You saying Warner Brothers Discovery isn't a good company.
Speaker 3:  We gotta go. We got, we gotta take a break. All right. Yeah, we're taking
Speaker 3:  a break. We'll, we'll talk about whatever Zla is doing a little bit later.
Speaker 3:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  We're back and we have the most breaking news of all
Speaker 3:  in the middle of our break. Literally in the middle of our break,
Speaker 3:  Google put up a blog post announcing the developer preview
Speaker 3:  of desktop windowing and Android tablets.
Speaker 3:  I know that the audience is as lit up by this as we are,
Speaker 3:  but I have to tell you, this whole room got so distracted that we
Speaker 3:  almost forgot to start the show again in the middle of the break. Just looking
Speaker 3:  at this blog post,
Speaker 4:  It's a good
Speaker 3:  Blog post. If you're a Dex head, just know
Speaker 3:  your empire is falling crumbling. Brick by brick is Google
Speaker 3:  ruthlessly sherlock's your entire, your entire operating
Speaker 3:  system away from you. So basically you have pixel fold, which
Speaker 3:  feels like one of the hotter phones going right now. David just got one.
Speaker 3:  Yep. It's sitting here in a FedEx box on my desk. Liam
Speaker 3:  has a pixel watch on right now and a pixel fold. And a pixel fold. 'cause
Speaker 3:  he bought a pixel fold and now he's in the ecosystem. I'm seeing him. People
Speaker 3:  are excited about this phone. And so Google, which has,
Speaker 3:  Liam was trying to run the pixel fold on a desktop monitor the other day
Speaker 3:  and it was the saddest thing I've ever seen. One time. It's adorable. Truly
Speaker 3:  the like no, literally no affordance for running with
Speaker 3:  a keyboard and display. Like it's just, here's your pixel fold. Like here's
Speaker 3:  a media Android tablet and it's
Speaker 4:  Still square.
Speaker 3:  It was still square's, right? It was beautiful. Everything about it was great.
Speaker 3:  As you know, Samsung has decks, as Vergecast listeners know, Samsung has
Speaker 3:  this thing called decks, which is the desktop mode for its phones. There's
Speaker 3:  a lot of weird decks stuff going on.
Speaker 3:  Literally different skews of the same phone and the Samsung lineup
Speaker 3:  run different versions of decks with different capabilities.
Speaker 5:  Samsung baby,
Speaker 3:  It is just not a thing you can depend
Speaker 5:  On.
Speaker 3:  As someone who has desperately tried to live the Dex lifestyle, the
Speaker 3:  only person I know who ever pulled it off successfully is Dan ert, our former
Speaker 3:  reviews editor who now works at Google because Google was like, Dan, can
Speaker 3:  you explain what is going on? Samsung device. Curious.
Speaker 5:  So I was gonna ask. Yeah. So there, there, there's a, there's a man named
Speaker 5:  Dieter Bone there also works at Google who also was a big
Speaker 5:  believer in window freedom. I would say.
Speaker 5:  And and then Dan America's number one Dex user. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Google goes to
Speaker 3:  Google the one and only Dex user. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Listen still number one man goes to Google.
Speaker 5:  Does The Verge get credit for this feature? Yes.
Speaker 3:  This is us. This is our alumni. Right. We, I feel like we did this. I think
Speaker 3:  that, and we don't actually, we don't. I'm still, you
Speaker 3:  know, we're all good friends. We just learned to not talk about work anymore.
Speaker 3:  Which is weird for people that worked in media together. Especially,
Speaker 3:  we just don't, I see data, we talk about anything else? So, I Don't know.
Speaker 3:  I, I have no, we have no inside info and I
Speaker 3:  maintain that line 'cause I like talking to Dieter and he's my friend.
Speaker 3:  So we just enforce this. It's, we had to like learn what to talk about that
Speaker 3:  wasn't work and or gadgets. Very weird. So, I Dunno.
Speaker 3:  But I'm just taking credit for it. Yeah. I'm saying with no literally no
Speaker 3:  evidence. And actually like an ideological
Speaker 3:  resistance to knowing Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And a deep knowledge of that not being how it works. Yes.
Speaker 5:  We're still taking credit. We're still taking credit for
Speaker 3:  It. Absolutely. We will send our armies into your house and introduce
Speaker 3:  desktop windowing.
Speaker 5:  Could not agree more. I'm into it. So,
Speaker 3:  Okay, here's what's actually going on. It's just a developer preview right
Speaker 3:  now. They're showing it mostly in a pixel tablet. I have to imagine that
Speaker 3:  this is gonna be what will happen on pixel fold, which very much acts like
Speaker 3:  a tablet when you unfold it. Yeah. You can just freeform windows. You can
Speaker 3:  just run Android, like a desktop operating system. You, you pull a chrome
Speaker 3:  window down and it opens a window with a nav bar and
Speaker 3:  tabs like, like navigation. It
Speaker 4:  Should,
Speaker 3:  I think there's some weirdness here between what is a Chrome OS
Speaker 3:  device and what is an, like the Google weirdness here is
Speaker 3:  very powerful.
Speaker 4:  Like the, the Chrome OS team just saw this and is like, what the hell?
Speaker 3:  Or they're like, aren't we on the same team, you know is with Google. Yes.
Speaker 3:  So there's some weirdness here about just the differences in between the
Speaker 3:  apps. Like Chromos can run Android apps. Weird that that
Speaker 3:  came to nothing as most of these ideas generally come to nothing.
Speaker 3:  But the idea that Google is taking
Speaker 3:  a bigger step forward
Speaker 3:  in particular with the fold. 'cause I don't think Android tablets is a thing
Speaker 3:  really matter if they free from windowing. But part in particular with the
Speaker 3:  fold and foldable Android devices that when you're closed, they act like
Speaker 3:  Android phones. And when they're open they have freeform windows that
Speaker 3:  can be useful in a variety of like computing situations.
Speaker 3:  That's a big deal. Like Right, it feels like a big deal. They have to actually
Speaker 3:  chip it, it has to like work. But this is the thing that everybody
Speaker 3:  wants, right? You just carry your phone to work and you plug it in and it's
Speaker 3:  a computer. We're a little bit closer there.
Speaker 4:  I'm sorry, I, I'm just looking at the, the desktop windowing
Speaker 4:  thing they have and it feels like the person, the sample
Speaker 4:  they're using here, the person is lying about going to Tahoe,
Speaker 3:  The ta Oh, this is so Gemini can summarize it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The Tahoe debrief and then behind that you see they've been Googling
Speaker 4:  Tahoe.
Speaker 4:  Interesting. Interesting.
Speaker 3:  They're like Gemini, summarize this webpage about Tahoe in an email about
Speaker 3:  my trip to Tahoe.
Speaker 4:  Like Windows
Speaker 4:  calling you out there a little bit.
Speaker 3:  That's good. I will say, yeah, you're right that the, they're like on a video
Speaker 3:  call, they're doing an email while they're searching for literally
Speaker 3:  just the word Tahoe.
Speaker 3:  A little, A little weird. A
Speaker 4:  Little weird. But these look, I, I don't know, I, I think these windows look
Speaker 4:  nice. They seem to move smoothly and a little gifs we're seeing
Speaker 5:  It's such a know, such rising tide lifts all boats thing too. Because
Speaker 5:  the biggest challenge for Android apps on Chrome
Speaker 5:  os once they got past some of the like basic compatibility
Speaker 5:  issues has been that Android apps look
Speaker 5:  like buts when they're big. Right? Like overwhelmingly, and this
Speaker 5:  is a thing that, that Apple has had really good luck with over the years
Speaker 5:  and it has served Apple really well, is making apps look
Speaker 5:  good at different sizes. Google has struggled forever to get developers
Speaker 5:  to care about anything other than the vertical size of a
Speaker 5:  smartphone. And one of the reasons people like to build apps
Speaker 5:  for iOS before they build for even Android smartphones is
Speaker 5:  because the screen sizes are different. Like it's so hard to build a go to
Speaker 5:  Android app because you essentially have to build a hundred of them that
Speaker 5:  all look slightly different at slightly different orientations at slightly
Speaker 5:  different sizes. So like the idea of there just being one
Speaker 5:  software of one screen size is very appealing to people, which is why a lot
Speaker 5:  of people like to build iOS apps. What Google has made an effort to
Speaker 5:  do over the last few years, it has not done it exceptionally well, but it
Speaker 5:  has done it relatively well, is get people to build these more flexible
Speaker 5:  apps that work at tablet size and they work at smartphone
Speaker 5:  size and they work at the size of a laptop screen to run on Chrome
Speaker 5:  os. And so every bit of it that gets better on one of those makes it
Speaker 5:  better for all of them, right? So like the pixel fold being good this year
Speaker 5:  should be very exciting to people who own Chromebooks because it's gonna
Speaker 5:  make people who make Android apps make them better for the fold, which will
Speaker 5:  make them better on the Chromebook. And every one of these pieces just gets
Speaker 5:  better and better as time goes on. Which I think like, and for this, again,
Speaker 5:  I can't imagine there are that many Pixel tablet users out there in the
Speaker 5:  world, but like, this is just a step again, in that
Speaker 5:  direction.
Speaker 4:  Dan's just so happy somewhere. I, I do have one question. Does,
Speaker 4:  does Android design, like, do they not have responsive design
Speaker 4:  where you just like, okay, you make it, and
Speaker 3:  They do in this, in this context, it's called Adaptive. Okay. So they, they've
Speaker 3:  been, they've been, and they pushing that for a long time. Yeah. I,
Speaker 5:  But adaptive is not a checkbox, right? Like it's, it's not a thing that you
Speaker 5:  say that make my app adaptive like that you, you have to build it Yeah.
Speaker 5:  To be all of those things and that's, it takes work.
Speaker 4:  So they don't have like a tool set that'll be like boop, boop, boop, boop,
Speaker 4:  adaptive.
Speaker 5:  So they, they do, you'll see some apps, and this is why like there are a
Speaker 5:  lot of iOS apps that look the same on an iPad
Speaker 5:  because you can basically just sort of like paint by numbers into a template
Speaker 5:  and it'll do it at all the different sizes. And some folks do that and that's
Speaker 5:  fine. But like If, you want to build an app with different ideas about
Speaker 5:  navigation or different animations or like, like literally to load a page
Speaker 5:  at all the different sizes and Android device can be,
Speaker 5:  is a challenge, especially If, you like care about how it looks and works,
Speaker 5:  and then you throw in all the different devices and all the different, you
Speaker 5:  know, screen refresh rates and there's just so many variables. But the,
Speaker 5:  the sheer raw, like x by y size of the app
Speaker 5:  has been the biggest holdup for Google forever because it just, it's a thing
Speaker 5:  people have not invested in doing because Android
Speaker 5:  tablets were not any good Android apps and Chromebooks didn't work and nobody
Speaker 5:  cared about foldable phones. And so like, as each one of those gets better,
Speaker 5:  they all get better. And that's very cool.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I, I think I'm just kinda surprised. 'cause like in, in web design
Speaker 4:  we had this whole moment where everybody was like, you know, you can just
Speaker 4:  download this little theme and it's a responsive theme and it's gonna automatically
Speaker 4:  resize it for anything you do. And the fact that Google doesn't just have
Speaker 4:  like, here's here's the lazy way. Well,
Speaker 5:  No, but somebody built that theme that's like, that theme doesn't just exist.
Speaker 5:  Well, you
Speaker 3:  If you listen carefully. That's the sound of every web designer listening
Speaker 3:  to the show screaming.
Speaker 4:  Exactly. You're welcome.
Speaker 4:  I'd like to piss you off. You
Speaker 5:  Know, just a WordPress cream that just exists.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I paid $40 for it on theme force
Speaker 3:  Taking our thank you site from Desktop mobile. We had an
Speaker 3:  Mdot site for a minute to responsive was nightmare. Just a
Speaker 3:  few.
Speaker 5:  Responsive design is really hard. Yeah, it's really hard. It's gotten a lot
Speaker 5:  easier because it has become so much more important, but it is really hard.
Speaker 4:  Well, I think my question is why doesn't Google do that work?
Speaker 3:  Actually, can I tell you a fun fact about responsive design?
Speaker 4:  I love a fun fact.
Speaker 3:  My fun fact about responsive design is that it was a Vox media designer,
Speaker 3:  Scott Kellum, who invented some of the very first responsive design
Speaker 3:  prototypes. Well really? That's
Speaker 4:  That's awesome.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And he was like, let's take guess. He was like, look at this thing.
Speaker 3:  He was like showing us stretchy web windows. And I was like, make our site
Speaker 3:  do that. And then the office led into flame
Speaker 3:  and talked for a long time.
Speaker 5:  That's awesome.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. See that was live Breaking Gadget news on the rich cast. We
Speaker 3:  still, our hearts still a flame when there's Android
Speaker 3:  windowing. Yeah, we're still, we're still where we came from.
Speaker 3:  David, I think you think that next story is very funny.
Speaker 5:  I do think the next story is very funny.
Speaker 3:  All right, make the case buddy.
Speaker 5:  Okay, so there was a debate. Well, let me back, let me back up.
Speaker 5:  So, so there's an election happening in the United States, actually let back
Speaker 5:  up. So well founding,
Speaker 3:  Do we know where Trump stands in Android windowing?
Speaker 4:  He doesn't like it. Which
Speaker 5:  Candidate do you think is more likely to use texts in the office?
Speaker 4:  Neither one of 'em was a lawyer. She's using like word perfect
Speaker 3:  Tim Walls.
Speaker 4:  Mm. Ooh, that's a good one.
Speaker 5:  Tim is definitely on like a Galaxy note just because he wanted the, you see
Speaker 5:  what I'm
Speaker 3:  Saying? And he refused to
Speaker 5:  He can feel it. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  Tim has a foldable keyboard in his backpack at all times. That feels
Speaker 5:  exactly right to me.
Speaker 3:  JD Vance is like, here's what I want to do. I want to, I want to nationalize
Speaker 3:  iMessage. Like that's where his brain is at.
Speaker 5:  By the way, have I told you guys about how we discovered very recently that
Speaker 5:  JD Vance has a house like right down the street from me and there's now a,
Speaker 5:  a secret service motorcade that goes by my house like almost
Speaker 5:  every day. Oh
Speaker 4:  Wow.
Speaker 5:  That's the whole story. That's it. That's all I wanted to tell you. Cool.
Speaker 5:  There's now a park that is like the size of this room that's fake behind
Speaker 5:  me that is now closed because it's too close to JD Vance's house. And that's
Speaker 5:  how everyone in this neighborhood found out that JD Vance has a house here,
Speaker 5:  but
Speaker 3:  He's never there. He's walking in a donut shops across America, confusing
Speaker 3:  the population.
Speaker 5:  Apparently one of them might be in my neighborhood. I'm gonna have to start
Speaker 5:  walking into donut shops every day just to see if I can find JD Vance. Anyway,
Speaker 4:  Let's, let's talk about the earrings. There's
Speaker 5:  A debate. Kamala Harris was wearing earrings and that became tech news
Speaker 5:  because there was a set of people on the internet who advanced a clearly
Speaker 5:  not correct theory that the earrings she was wearing were actually
Speaker 5:  headphones. And I just, I brought this up for
Speaker 5:  two reasons. One, because it's not true, and this is like a thing that
Speaker 5:  people have tried to do for years. The idea that a, the
Speaker 5:  candidate who does well in a debate is being fed answers in some way, shape,
Speaker 5:  or form is like a long running conspiracy theory that's never proven true.
Speaker 5:  But BI think it's very funny that the earrings in particular that
Speaker 5:  she's being accused of wearing, there's some strong evidence
Speaker 5:  that they don't actually exist. This is like a Kickstarter company
Speaker 5:  that doesn't really seem to have shipped. Like in
Speaker 5:  fairness, we have not covered this company closely, so maybe there's more
Speaker 5:  out there. If, you are an owner of Nova H one headphones.
Speaker 5:  Get at me. I have a lot of questions. Believe you. I wanna know everything.
Speaker 5:  Believe you
Speaker 4:  Need audio earrings. Oh
Speaker 5:  My God, you're right. I apologize. The H one audio earrings,
Speaker 5:  they just aren't what she was wearing. Yeah, they,
Speaker 3:  They look very different
Speaker 5:  If every, it would've been funnier if everybody's like, she's wearing beats,
Speaker 5:  but they're like, she's wearing a
Speaker 4:  Project. Yeah. The only similarity is they both have a pearl on them. Like
Speaker 4:  they're pearl earrings. That's it. Everybody's
Speaker 3:  Like, the fact that the CEO is out there being like, I can't confirm or deny
Speaker 3:  that these are our fake earrings is like, well one, what are you doing? The
Speaker 3:  fact
Speaker 4:  That the guy who can't ship his product to saying that. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And also the battery life only lasts two and a half hours, which means they
Speaker 5:  probably would've died like mid debate if we're being, if we're being realistic,
Speaker 4:  She's putting him on right before she goes out. Yeah, just
Speaker 4:  give 'em to me, let's go.
Speaker 3:  She
Speaker 5:  Takes off her earrings, mid debate, puts them in a charging case, takes him
Speaker 5:  back out.
Speaker 3:  There was a very funny in the in gadget days, way back when,
Speaker 3:  when Obama was first elected, there
Speaker 3:  was all these reports that he wanted to keep his blackberry, I dunno, If
Speaker 3:  you remember this. It was like frothing at the mouth, will Obama get a blackberry?
Speaker 3:  And then there was all this stuff about he would need like a secret blackberry.
Speaker 3:  It was like ultra lockdown. And he really wanted his Blackberry. And there
Speaker 3:  was this company that made a phone called the SEC Edge and the
Speaker 3:  CEO of that, I don't remember what they're called. I don't know what the,
Speaker 3:  I, I refuse to remember, but the CEO of this company is this like military
Speaker 3:  vendor guy. And he's just like on all the TV channels being like, the Sectary
Speaker 3:  Edge is the most hardened military grade, blah, blah, blah. And everyone's
Speaker 3:  like, Obama's getting a sect edge. And like, definitely not. He ended up
Speaker 3:  like a black 38,000 that was just like stripped of
Speaker 3:  its apps. And then later on he had an iPad and it's like, why did
Speaker 3:  we spend so much time talking about the sector edge? I think Josh Polsky
Speaker 3:  had a post in Eng Gadget during those days where he was like, it's not the
Speaker 3:  SuperPhone 9,000, it's Blackberry. Like that
Speaker 3:  was like the headline.
Speaker 5:  It's pretty good.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I'm learning so much about they they were not technically smartphones,
Speaker 3:  The sex edge,
Speaker 4:  Which was made by general dynamic. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  See, I knew it was like, he's like, here's what we do. Cruise missiles and
Speaker 3:  this weird feature phone for the government.
Speaker 5:  Well that was like, remember the Boeing Black that Boeing was like, he made
Speaker 5:  a super secure smartphone. Like this is a whole, it's it's a whole genre
Speaker 5:  floating out there. There
Speaker 3:  Are many stories during the Trump era that I spent much too much time
Speaker 3:  focused on.
Speaker 4:  Are I I where
Speaker 3:  You're going Fox on in particular? Yeah, but I don't know If, you remember
Speaker 3:  they would always describe him as having a super TiVo in the White House.
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah. Like Trump would watch like his super TiVo and he kept referring
Speaker 3:  to it as a super TiVo and like, you know, America's political reporters are
Speaker 3:  not being like, what's a super ti like, I get it. But I was like, what's
Speaker 3:  a super TiVo? Like I've had every TiVo that's ever shipped. Which one
Speaker 3:  is it? Is is there a, that company is now a patent licensing troll. Like
Speaker 3:  which TiVo is it? Dude. And it was just a bog standard direct
Speaker 3:  TV box. And one time they pub someone published a photo of the super TIVA
Speaker 3:  remote and it was a $4 like white direct TV remote,
Speaker 5:  But somebody like painted a racing stripe on it. So like super Tiva phone.
Speaker 3:  It was just like, dude, he's got direct tv. Like I'm aware that it can record
Speaker 3:  four channels at once, but like, so can everything.
Speaker 5:  Honestly, I think if DirecTV had rebranded as super TiVo, it would probably
Speaker 5:  have been more successful.
Speaker 3:  The one Trump has Senior Citizens of America, you, you can all have
Speaker 3:  DirecTV together.
Speaker 5:  It's a remote, but it like has the cover on it so you can only hit two buttons
Speaker 5:  just to make sure. It
Speaker 4:  Is very sad that everybody just assumed Kamala Harris' earrings were
Speaker 4:  earbuds.
Speaker 5:  Do you think Tim Wal has ever backed to Kickstarter? That's my last question
Speaker 5:  for you.
Speaker 4:  A hundred percent.
Speaker 3:  I mean, JD Vance specked at Kickstarter over throw the, the cover from the
Speaker 3:  United States.
Speaker 3:  Let's move on. There you go. I will cop to getting this wrong. Me at
Speaker 3:  the top of the show, I said it was honor because honor has also been hinting
Speaker 3:  at a trifold smartphone, but it's actually the Huawei trifold smartphone.
Speaker 3:  It's $2,800. It looks sick again. Huawei got like
Speaker 3:  booted outta the country, you will recall and almost went out of business
Speaker 3:  because we wouldn't sell them chips. There's like a whole thing that happened
Speaker 3:  with world. They'd
Speaker 4:  Make their own operating system.
Speaker 3:  It start all over and now they're like three screens and
Speaker 3:  everyone's kinda like, what if, what if we let Huawei back in the United States?
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 4:  I, yeah, I I want this the world's first jewel folding
Speaker 4:  triple screen.
Speaker 3:  So it's the mate xt it is
Speaker 4:  Ultimate Design, please. It's
Speaker 3:  Called the Mate XT Ultimate Design. They announced it on the same day as
Speaker 3:  the iPhone, which is very good. It's very
Speaker 3:  expensive. It's $2,800 thereabout depending on the conversion factor
Speaker 3:  to go on. That's two 50 gigs of storage.
Speaker 3:  Our story points out that's $300 more than a 16 inch MacBook Pro. How many
Speaker 3:  times can I fold up my 16 inch MacBook, Pro, Eli? All of the videos, all
Speaker 3:  the assets, all the content that s released is just the thing unfolding and
Speaker 3:  showing people looking at presentations.
Speaker 4:  Somebody got a hands-on with it though. Somebody has
Speaker 3:  A hands-on.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, so Gizmo China got a hands-on with it and, and put in a
Speaker 4:  couple of additional specs. It's only a little thicker than the Samsung
Speaker 4:  Galaxy Z fold. And it looks like, like you
Speaker 4:  can watch this video, it's, we'll put it in the show notes. It looks
Speaker 4:  thick. The camera is huge.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, that is a big camera bone.
Speaker 4:  The, that's a big boy.
Speaker 3:  Oh, there are more. I'm looking now on YouTube. There are more Chinese
Speaker 3:  hands ons with this thing that are, are starting to trickle out, but they're
Speaker 3:  all just the thing unfolding. Yeah. That's the only content that exists
Speaker 3:  is a very controlled demo of a thing unfolding. What else do you need to
Speaker 3:  know? That's, that's, that's the whole
Speaker 4:  Job. Well here's I
Speaker 3:  Well does the operating system do anything when you turn it into a sheet
Speaker 3:  of paper?
Speaker 4:  We need to see before and after. We don't, don't worry about the, the, the
Speaker 4:  process.
Speaker 3:  So one of the things that I am very curious about in this next turn of phones,
Speaker 3:  we've been talking a lot about pixel fold seems to be very popular amongst
Speaker 3:  the gadget population. Whether it's going to move Google's market share
Speaker 3:  at all, it won't. But if you're a particular kind of gadget nerd,
Speaker 3:  it is the device that everyone's like talking about it into lately. Which
Speaker 3:  is interesting. It feels like folding phones that
Speaker 3:  bifold, they've reached a point where
Speaker 3:  now they're just maturing in iterative steps. Yeah. Right. Compared to the
Speaker 3:  where the galaxy fold started, which
Speaker 4:  Means Apple will have one next year, which
Speaker 3:  Maybe yeah, pixel fold still you can still feel the same. It's not perfect,
Speaker 3:  but it's, it's right in a way you can see the
Speaker 4:  Little crease when you open it still. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And you can, you can definitely feel it with your finger, but it's like,
Speaker 3:  it's hit that point. And so now are we just at Okay,
Speaker 3:  add another one. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Do we think think I mean like I under like the Chinese fund market and the
Speaker 3:  Indian fund market are like full of these ideas. Like Yeah. Do
Speaker 3:  bonkers hardware stuff and see what happens. Markets around the
Speaker 3:  world are generally more open to
Speaker 3:  weirdness just because of the way our carriers are. And Apple's
Speaker 3:  iMessage domination, they're all a bunch of stuff. That means we don't get
Speaker 3:  cool phones first.
Speaker 4:  Oh no, he's, he, this one video has the guy actually folding it
Speaker 4:  and then you watch it all like realign itself. Yeah, it looks cool.
Speaker 3:  I mean, Huawei did have to build their own operating system because again,
Speaker 3:  we, the amount of sanctions the United States government put on Huawei just
Speaker 3:  changed the direction of that company. That's fine.
Speaker 3:  But it just seems like this is a, a weird, you look at this, you look at
Speaker 3:  how people are excited about it in a way that the first set of foldables
Speaker 3:  didn't really capture, but now maybe the technology is mature enough.
Speaker 4:  See, I I think there's like, also, there's a weird cultural element here
Speaker 4:  too, because we're seeing all of these things happening in other countries
Speaker 4:  in the United States is so focused on the iPhone and the iPhone is so stuck
Speaker 4:  in, in, in class slab
Speaker 4:  and, and like Google, it's really nice that Google's coming in, but Huawei's
Speaker 4:  been doing this for a while. A lot of the Xmi Hass been doing this. A lot
Speaker 4:  of these other country companies have been doing
Speaker 4:  really, really cool stuff with phones that just don't come to the
Speaker 4:  United States In many ways it's, it's less like they're doing weird stuff.
Speaker 4:  It's more like we're getting a little left behind.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean again, it's so hard to break into us smartphone market
Speaker 3:  because of the essential duopoly of Apple and Samsung, but the
Speaker 3:  carriers have more or less en enforced.
Speaker 3:  Would you? So it goes, I I've talked, we've talked about this so many times.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But I'm just wondering from a hardware perspective, do we think the
Speaker 3:  regular folding phones have reached their sort of like, yeah, we're done
Speaker 3:  with this. We we don't need to figure out any basics here now we're just
Speaker 3:  about Well, because
Speaker 4:  I think a lot people are are the folks are comfortable with that,
Speaker 4:  that little crease. It, it doesn't seem to bother people that much and they
Speaker 4:  figured out the front of the phone. Right. Like, like with the Pixel Pro,
Speaker 4:  that was the thing everybody really likes about it, is that they figured
Speaker 4:  out the front. So you can just use the phone as normal. You never even have
Speaker 4:  to open it up. But then when you do wanna like have a good time,
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You open it up and enjoy yourself.
Speaker 3:  I don't open up David. David you have long,
Speaker 4:  Take me outta this.
Speaker 3:  You have long insisted that it'll be the, the the
Speaker 3:  flip style.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I
Speaker 3:  Does seeing a triple fold change your mind? It should.
Speaker 5:  No, I think, I think the triple fold
Speaker 5:  is an interesting tablet replacement way more than it
Speaker 5:  is a, an interesting phone replacement. Like I think phone
Speaker 5:  that turns into smartwatch is a way more compelling thing to most people
Speaker 5:  than tablet that turns into phone. And but to
Speaker 5:  your point about the hardware, like on one level we are
Speaker 5:  getting there. Like this stuff is pretty good. There's work left to do.
Speaker 5:  They need to get more rugged, the cameras need to get better, the
Speaker 5:  screens need to continue to improve. The, the whole thing needs to get
Speaker 5:  thinner and lighter. Like these phones are big, they're big and
Speaker 5:  there, there's just, there's a lot of work left to do. But in terms of like,
Speaker 5:  can you make a phone that kind of works open and closed?
Speaker 5:  Like the, the answer to that is yes. Right. And I think we've, we've landed
Speaker 5:  on, especially with this last generation, Samsung has
Speaker 5:  gotten closer to the right size. OnePlus is getting closer to the right size.
Speaker 5:  Google is seemingly very close to the right size.
Speaker 5:  I I think what you're seeing from a lot of these companies and Huawei and
Speaker 5:  Xmi and others have done this for years is like unbelievably cool.
Speaker 5:  Really high-end tech demos that like, they don't think a lot of people are
Speaker 5:  gonna buy this phone. But it, it gets people excited. It's like, it's
Speaker 5:  a branding exercise as much as it is like an actual phone to
Speaker 5:  sell to humans.
Speaker 4:  I, I disagree. It's so cool looking.
Speaker 3:  It is 2,800 all it's
Speaker 4:  2,800 look you put on like a what about it makes you, its what
Speaker 5:  Not the whole point is that it's cool looking.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. A 10 year plan paying like $30
Speaker 4:  a month, this would be great.
Speaker 5:  Didn't you just complain about the PS five Pros cost,
Speaker 4:  If it could fold just on folded like an accordion, I would I take it all
Speaker 4:  back if it was like big GPU but also folded like this. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You put the motion in I'm, I'm sold.
Speaker 5:  No, I I do think we're, we're gonna hit a point where people start doing
Speaker 5:  even weirder stuff with this, but also like there's a,
Speaker 5:  there's a thing that's coming that is a lot of
Speaker 5:  new wacky experimenting in phone hardware
Speaker 5:  and I'm very excited about it. Like, it, it got stagnant for so
Speaker 5:  long and then a couple of people tried folding phones and it didn't really
Speaker 5:  work. And I think everybody decided maybe this isn't gonna be the thing and
Speaker 5:  now it feels like it might be the thing. And I think like nothing
Speaker 5:  is gonna beat the candy bar phone anytime soon if ever. But the
Speaker 5:  like the, the experimentation is coming back and I think that's awesome.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I mean the iPhone 16 Pro Max is all 6.9
Speaker 3:  inches Almo almost seven. It's, we're starting to strain the
Speaker 3:  boundaries of how big a phone can be before
Speaker 4:  Has to fold. I wanna accordion that immediately.
Speaker 3:  I haven't f you know, the first thing I did in the hands on air, just fold
Speaker 3:  one that list of things you said about what, what folding phones need to
Speaker 3:  get better. They need to be more durable. The screens need to be better.
Speaker 3:  That's sa the same list of qualities that you could have applied to the first
Speaker 3:  iPhone. Oh, for sure. Right. And so it's just, they're on the same path.
Speaker 3:  Right. That and that's what I mean, like we figured out the, the core technology
Speaker 3:  and now we're just iteratively improving like around the edges to get them
Speaker 3:  even better. That feels like a moment. I'm not sure where that moment's gonna
Speaker 3:  lead to the fact that we're like, screw it, two, two screens fold out.
Speaker 3:  Kind of feels like maybe they figured out how to get one screen to, to fold
Speaker 3:  out and that now we're just seeing what else we can do.
Speaker 4:  I'm put another fold in.
Speaker 3:  I'm just, I am dying for the three screen phone.
Speaker 5:  It's so dumb. Well just, just think about the difference in how the
Speaker 5:  screen looks and feels from the first Z fold
Speaker 5:  to now. Right. Like just the sheer amount of like material science
Speaker 5:  improvements that have been made to get to this point is crazy.
Speaker 5:  Those things were like plastic and was it, it was Dieter
Speaker 5:  right? Who like accidentally peeled part of the screen off thinking it was
Speaker 5:  a screen protector. Like that was not that long ago. No,
Speaker 3:  No. Dieter had a tiny amount of dust in his review unit that broke the screen.
Speaker 3:  Oh, that's right. And then somebody else peeled off the screen protector.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Okay. And then Samsung delayed the launch of the first
Speaker 5:  C. Right. That was not a long time ago. And now
Speaker 3:  Four
Speaker 5:  Years ago. Yeah, like that at the, the speed with which that stuff, and that
Speaker 5:  was always the gating factor, right? Like the question was not how do you
Speaker 5:  build a good hinge? It was can you make a screen that
Speaker 5:  works like this and works means a lot of things. But I think the answer to
Speaker 5:  that is like, yes. And we're almost there. And So I think you're right that
Speaker 5:  like the path now is way more about software and it's way more about use
Speaker 5:  cases and it's way more about details. And again, it's way
Speaker 5:  more about do people actually want this? Which also is can you make
Speaker 5:  this thing for $800 and not $1,800? Yeah. And those are like, those
Speaker 5:  are big hills to climb. But they are, I think like, I don't know,
Speaker 5:  to just ruin the analogy. They're like hills. You can see the top of, whereas
Speaker 5:  I think not that many years ago, like can we make this screen not fall apart
Speaker 5:  was genuinely I think kind of up in the air. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  Now you can just do a little accordion,
Speaker 3:  Just boop boop. You just walk up to any phone you see and fold it in half
Speaker 3:  and see,
Speaker 5:  Dude, I'm telling you there's one shot in this Huawei video where it's open
Speaker 5:  on, it's open on two, so it just looks like a normal foldable phone. And
Speaker 5:  then he just kinda reaches below and pulls up the third part and the the
Speaker 5:  UI just gloriously expands. Yeah. I've I've watched that like 25 times
Speaker 5:  since we've been sitting here talking. It's awesome.
Speaker 3:  It's sick. It's coming. I'm telling you it, it got more attention from a
Speaker 3:  certain audience on iPhone day than the iPhone. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  There's something to that. All right. I wanna end by putting two Google stories
Speaker 3:  together right next to each other. 'cause I think they're kind of really
Speaker 3:  interesting when you put 'em right next to each other. We've actually talked
Speaker 3:  a lot about Google on this episode. They, they seem in one
Speaker 3:  way to have a bunch of confidence. And maybe that confidence is just
Speaker 3:  like, we have to put Gemini in front of you. So here it is.
Speaker 3:  But we reviewed the Pixel Watch three this week. V reviewed it. She gave
Speaker 3:  it an eight. People like it like Yeah, people really
Speaker 3:  like this watch. It is a confident product. The integrations
Speaker 3:  across the sort of Pixel and Google ecosystem are solid. We've been talking
Speaker 3:  a lot about the pixel nines for all of their, you know, general
Speaker 3:  issues with swerving reality into chaos because of their,
Speaker 3:  their just absolute nihilism about AI image editing. But they're good phones
Speaker 3:  that people like. Yeah. And the Pixel Watch three is a
Speaker 3:  good watch that V really likes. And I think people who buy into the ecosystem
Speaker 3:  aren't gonna like it. There's something happening on that side of the house
Speaker 3:  for Google. Yeah. Where they've fallen into a groove. The hardware is good.
Speaker 3:  There's a thesis in the software. Even if the, every
Speaker 3:  time you pick up pixel phone, it's just like Gemini. Like there's still a
Speaker 3:  thesis. There's there's a point of view, which I think is very strong. They
Speaker 3:  haven't had a point of view for quite a while. That's, that's that house
Speaker 3:  on the other side of the house. Well their search engine just got rules
Speaker 3:  via Monopoly. And they are on trial again right
Speaker 3:  now for antitrust for their ad tech stack.
Speaker 3:  And the, you know, there's trial, it's
Speaker 3:  witnesses, there's documents, Lauren fine's in the courthouse covering it
Speaker 3:  for us. It's all very boring. It's a bunch of suits talking about display
Speaker 3:  ads on the web. Like If, you want to go to sleep. Programmatic
Speaker 3:  advertising is the thing to talk about. But what's fascinating is one
Speaker 3:  in all the documents, all witnesses, the way Google's business people
Speaker 3:  talk about its business is ice cold. Oh yeah. Right. Yeah. There's no Google
Speaker 3:  cuddle bugs there. No. At all. It is literally
Speaker 3:  how do we own this market? Here's the value. The value is, there's a line
Speaker 3:  in one of the emails. It's like the value here is that we own everything.
Speaker 3:  Like that's, that's the thing that makes this powerful is we own every part
Speaker 3:  of the stack. And so that they're just saying it out loud and then you
Speaker 3:  have the clients, the actual people buying advertising, being like, Google's
Speaker 3:  technology here is bad. We're just stuck with it. Right? Yeah. And like the
Speaker 3:  core ad tech server that Google's been using to serve all the programmatic
Speaker 3:  ads all over the web, they're like, this is bad. Like this is like 20-year-old
Speaker 3:  technology that we would like to get away from, but we're stuck with it.
Speaker 3:  'cause there's nowhere to go. And that is a weird dynamic for Google.
Speaker 3:  Right? On the one hand, they, with the AI stuff with
Speaker 3:  Gemini, maybe they got, you know, caught on the back foot,
Speaker 3:  but they, it provided some amount of focus for the company it seems like,
Speaker 3:  and it's reflected in these Pixel devices. I I think
Speaker 3:  you can see it like there's, there's a reason for them to be the
Speaker 3:  way they are. Yeah. Which is really interesting. Like, I don't know,
Speaker 3:  I if not for chat GBT would the Pixel nine have been, had this much
Speaker 3:  focus, like, I don't know the answer to that question. Like they weren't
Speaker 3:  on this path all by themselves. Right? Like it took this weird sort of diversion
Speaker 3:  from open AI to, to bring them here, but they, it worked. And then on the
Speaker 3:  other side of the house, the money people are like, this is a monopoly. We
Speaker 3:  don't like using this technology. And it feels based on
Speaker 3:  what happened in the search trial. Like the government knows how to beat
Speaker 3:  Google. This is the case. I would remind everybody that
Speaker 3:  Google tried to avoid in jury trial by just sending
Speaker 3:  a check to the United States government for what it calculated to be the
Speaker 3:  maximum amount of damages. Yeah. Like on Wells Fargo account, they're just
Speaker 3:  like, here's some millions of dollars. Is this good?
Speaker 3:  We, well we, we will put it in the show note. There's a picture of the check.
Speaker 3:  You can just look at the check. Google sent a check. That's how Monopoly
Speaker 3:  works. Right? Here you go. Like literally how Monopoly works. Like they were
Speaker 3:  so desperate for this not to be happening that they just wrote the, they
Speaker 3:  just fronted the money for a settlement.
Speaker 3:  And So, I just, I would just juxtapose those two things. I think it's, you
Speaker 3:  see this company it kind of like at war with itself a little bit.
Speaker 3:  'cause the thing that is funding everything is at all of this risk
Speaker 3:  and the future is like coming into focus over here.
Speaker 5:  Except that in so many ways, so far, all of Google's future stuff
Speaker 5:  has just been ancillary to the other thing. Right? Like Right. I think the,
Speaker 5:  the most damning critique you could make of everything Google has done in
Speaker 5:  25 years is that it actually doesn't care about anything but search. And
Speaker 5:  so everything gets subjugated to the needs of search. Like
Speaker 5:  the people who build Chrome will tell you they could have built a better
Speaker 5:  browser except that what they had to do is optimize for search queries, which
Speaker 5:  is a weird thing to have to optimize for in a web browser. And so like, and
Speaker 5:  this is a story you hear over and over from Google is everything eventually
Speaker 5:  loses at the hand of the search team. And I, I think you could make
Speaker 5:  the case that the only team as powerful at Google as the people who make
Speaker 5:  the search engine are the people who make the ads. And like that that is
Speaker 5:  who is now being thrown into this fight. And the, to your point, like
Speaker 5:  the, the thing we say a lot on this show is that what happens at one trial
Speaker 5:  has very little to do with what happens at the next trial. And I think that's
Speaker 5:  probably true in Google's case here too. Like all this stuff is still very
Speaker 5:  up in the air. But the thing we heard over and over in the last
Speaker 5:  trial was Google's argument was
Speaker 5:  Google is very good, which is why we keep winning. And it's very hard to
Speaker 5:  argue that there are better products out there than Google. And yet Google
Speaker 5:  still lost because, because the, the argument came up over and over that
Speaker 5:  actually what Google is doing is preventing that from happening. Right. That
Speaker 5:  like, maybe the reason there isn't more competition for Google is because
Speaker 5:  Google has not allowed it. And, and Amit Meta, the judge was very receptive
Speaker 5:  to that argument. This one in which the overwhelming thing
Speaker 5:  seems to be actually this sucks and there's nothing anybody can do about
Speaker 5:  it. It's like even the way Lauren was covering in the first couple of
Speaker 5:  days, you, you get the sense that the people accusing Google of being monopolists
Speaker 5:  are very confident coming into this. And how, how that means it'll go,
Speaker 5:  who knows? But there there is a real sense of like, the argument
Speaker 5:  is extremely strong in this particular case. And it's, it's gonna come
Speaker 5:  down to market definitions as it always does. And it's gonna get deeply
Speaker 5:  wonky. And I'm going to court at least once next week and I could not be
Speaker 5:  more excited to listen to people yell at me about ad stacks for for
Speaker 5:  weeks. But, but yeah, it is like Google is is both kind of
Speaker 5:  feeling itself and fighting for its life, like all at the same time. And
Speaker 5:  it's, it's very odd.
Speaker 3:  I feel like I, I need to disclose here. We we have
Speaker 3:  ads on our website. What? That we have That's
Speaker 3:  true. Oh my God. And Vox Media's president of Revenue
Speaker 3:  and Growth. Ryan Polly is on the list of potential witnesses in this trial.
Speaker 3:  Well, I haven't talked to him about it. I dunno if he's gonna get Hal, he's
Speaker 3:  just on the list. 'cause we run a, we run a programmatic
Speaker 3:  ad network called Concert theoretically competes with Google.
Speaker 3:  That's not truly not our side of the house. Like it's all the way over there.
Speaker 3:  I love that Ryan has great hair. I will say that that's the one thing I know
Speaker 3:  about. He does great hair. But like this thing where you
Speaker 3:  say like, you're a anybody listening, pull over in your car and think about
Speaker 3:  the internet. That's my instruction to, to you do, do you like the ads that
Speaker 3:  you're seeing? There's a million companies, a million
Speaker 3:  ad tech companies that are like, we can make better ads. And all of them
Speaker 3:  are like, and then you run into the monster and you, you give up. Yep.
Speaker 3:  Most of those people flip the ad tech companies or they try to bundle 'em
Speaker 3:  up to create a new monster and they get rich and then they, you know, live
Speaker 3:  a healthy life on LinkedIn complaining about the monster. Like, like they're
Speaker 3:  well practiced at this. It's, it is not like they're available to you.
Speaker 3:  The reporting is easy to do, it's just kind of what you're really trying
Speaker 3:  to sell an audience. Even what I'm trying to sell to you right now listening
Speaker 3:  is like, there's a reason ads on the internet are bad and it's because
Speaker 3:  no one, the market is not actually competitive for better ad experiences.
Speaker 4:  Okay. But which is worse ads now the ad
Speaker 4:  experience now, or like in the 1990s where
Speaker 4:  it would be a popup of porn that would then infect your computer.
Speaker 3:  Well, so in the 1990s I was a teenage boy. So you're like,
Speaker 3:  that rules.
Speaker 4:  I'm the teenage girl. I was
Speaker 3:  Early two thousands. Like, this is great. This is what I was here for the
Speaker 3:  whole time.
Speaker 5:  Can I just say one more thing on this before we we Yeah. Leave this subject.
Speaker 5:  One of the things I have been paying a lot of attention to, and I'm, I'm
Speaker 5:  well aware that this is like a giant generalization, but it has, it has really
Speaker 5:  jumped out to me in reading some of these court documents so far. Like a
Speaker 5:  thing you hear a lot from people in and around the tech
Speaker 5:  industry is that like If, you If you want to believe that in the early days
Speaker 5:  of the tech industry, it was like a bunch of, well-meaning hippies who just
Speaker 5:  like wanted to make the world a better place. And then that eventually got
Speaker 5:  morphed and ruined. They all blame the MBAs.
Speaker 5:  They're like, a bunch of people like graduated from Harvard Business School
Speaker 5:  and came here because they thought that's where the money was and they changed
Speaker 5:  the culture and they ruined everything. And like, boy does that
Speaker 5:  ring true when you read some of these documents, like to your point about
Speaker 5:  these people being ice cold, it's like, these are the MBAs, these are the
Speaker 5:  people who like, oh, you wanna build a cool product. I don't, I don't care.
Speaker 5:  That's not interesting to me. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like we're just, we are in charge of this money machine. Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  Make us money. And
Speaker 5:  Like that is the thing that runs Silicon Valley now.
Speaker 3:  And it's just very hard because Google does such a good job of,
Speaker 3:  for the most part being like very cuddly. Like Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I think there's a reason Google still has one of the worst logos in world
Speaker 3:  history. Right. Like it's cuddly and dumb and
Speaker 3:  it still kind of looks like Marissa Meyer drew it herself. Right. And there's
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back the lightning round. I will say that there are
Speaker 3:  now ads on the YouTube. When you watch it on YouTube, there are some ads.
Speaker 3:  Those are not official sponsors of Lightning Round. The Lightning round is
Speaker 3:  still available to be sponsored.
Speaker 5:  There were so many commenters on YouTube who were happy for us that we finally
Speaker 5:  sponsored the lightning round. Wanna
Speaker 3:  And I reject your
Speaker 5:  Happiness back to all of you rooting for us. But it is misplaced. Get this
Speaker 5:  done. Yeah. Give us money and then be happy. How about that?
Speaker 3:  I do get emails and I, I I try to take the money, but I don't know how, because
Speaker 3:  it's not my job. I can be like, I take Stripe. It's just not
Speaker 3:  like a thing.
Speaker 3:  All right, let me around Krantz, what you got?
Speaker 4:  You know how trucks are huge. I, this is actually kinda a sad one for you.
Speaker 4:  I do. 'cause I know you love a big
Speaker 3:  Truck. Every time I see a raptor now I'm like, I my baby. But
Speaker 4:  Sometimes trucks are too big. They're
Speaker 3:  All not sometimes,
Speaker 4:  Many times the trucks are too big. If they come up to my shoulders, I'm like
Speaker 4:  five eight. That's, that's too tall. Yeah. The US is finally taking
Speaker 4:  AIM and they're proposing these new rules and they were gonna use crash test
Speaker 4:  dummies, but instead of for Crashing, it's for pedestrians because,
Speaker 3:  So we're, we're gonna run the car into people like Crash Dummies. Dummies,
Speaker 4:  Okay. Yeah. Yeah. Just a little poop. I I think that's really nice because
Speaker 4:  a lot of the times now we've been seeing these really big trucks and then
Speaker 4:  you see all of these YouTube videos and stuff of people in these really big
Speaker 4:  trucks and, and they can't see little kids in front of 'em and it's like
Speaker 4:  somebody should check that out. And apparently the government was like, we
Speaker 4:  should check
Speaker 3:  That out. And presumably the only way to
Speaker 4:  To do that is,
Speaker 3:  Is to make the truck smaller.
Speaker 5:  I will never be able to describe to you why I just started imagining it's,
Speaker 5:  it's the Beatles Abbey Road cover, but it's four crash test dummies
Speaker 5:  lined up like the Beatles. And then just like a cyber truck just comes
Speaker 5:  floors, all four
Speaker 3:  Of them. That's, and they're like too big. That's an AI prompt right there,
Speaker 3:  David. Yep. Coming soon to our runway generator near you.
Speaker 3:  Just
Speaker 5:  Immediately what popped into my head, but there
Speaker 4:  There is a lot of optimism about these rules. People seem to be really,
Speaker 4:  really excited about it. It feels like it's, it's a good first step.
Speaker 4:  So it's, it's, it's after all these years of just watching the trucks get
Speaker 4:  huge, it's nice to be like, Hey, how about they don't get that tall?
Speaker 5:  So Nila, you're the, you're you're a truck guy. Does
Speaker 5:  this like, is this gonna piss off all the truck people?
Speaker 3:  Sorry, I just typed the Beatles Abbey Road cover, but it's Crash Test Dummies.
Speaker 3:  It's a rock. The, the the AI image
Speaker 3:  generator That's so bad.
Speaker 3:  This is what you get when there's literally no, I'll send it to you Dave.
Speaker 3:  When you, when there's literally no safety standards on your AI image generator.
Speaker 3:  That's why I picked Crock because it it won't stop me. Their
Speaker 4:  Heads are
Speaker 3:  Cute. You were asking. Yes. I as a person who once owned a truck and still
Speaker 3:  thinks of my truck fondly. For example, when I use
Speaker 3:  Grok to generate crash test dummies as the Beatles Abby Road cover, I think
Speaker 3:  about moving back into the woods and driving my truck again instead of living
Speaker 3:  in society. What
Speaker 5:  I wonder is, do people buy the giant trucks because they're
Speaker 5:  the good trucks and people want good trucks. So if they make the good trucks
Speaker 5:  a little smaller, it'll be fine. Or have we gotten to a point where like,
Speaker 5:  I need big truck and if I if can't have big truck big mad.
Speaker 3:  No, I actually, two things, there's two data points
Speaker 3:  that kind of refute the idea that people actually want the big cars. This
Speaker 3:  is why. Yeah. And some people want big cars. One, the Ford Maverick is
Speaker 3:  a small truck that is just selling like gangbusters. Okay. It's a hit, it's
Speaker 3:  a hit product. And then two people are starting to import these Japanese
Speaker 3:  K trucks. I actually saw one at the Apple event driving down the road in
Speaker 3:  front of Apple Park and it was, it was like an attention magnet.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And then there's just these little trucks and the beds. They're still
Speaker 3:  like five and a half foot beds. The beds are about the same size as a full
Speaker 3:  size truck. They're just small. Right. So they're as useful, but
Speaker 3:  they're just small. And I think you're seeing a bunch of interest in small
Speaker 3:  cars again, like the market wants them. And then you look around
Speaker 3:  and all the cars are so gigantic, like I think pendulum just swing back and
Speaker 3:  forth. There's like tax stuff where you like buy a car for your small business.
Speaker 3:  You can write off the fold depreciation that is pushed like the Dentist of
Speaker 3:  America buying giant SUVs that I think that stuff is coming
Speaker 3:  to an end or, or changing in some way. And So, I just think like
Speaker 3:  between a market, the regulatory pressure and then just the reality of you
Speaker 3:  get in a car that's so big, you need cameras to drive it.
Speaker 4:  That's too much.
Speaker 3:  It's getting weird, right? Yeah. Like when the solution to
Speaker 3:  we, you can't see children as we put cameras all around the truck that can
Speaker 3:  see the children for you, you're just, you're just in a weird spot.
Speaker 3:  So I, I think I look at like, I thoroughly enjoyed
Speaker 3:  owning or after it was very fun, but I lived near no one. And every time
Speaker 3:  I drove that thing into New York City, I encourage, if
Speaker 3:  If, you ever have the opportunity to drive a Ford Raptor through the West
Speaker 3:  Village at night during dinner time when everyone's eating outside listening
Speaker 3:  to the Cure with open windows, take it. That was just a weird
Speaker 3:  experience all the way around for everyone. Everyone was like, what is
Speaker 3:  happening right now? The the car is just incompatible the city. It's
Speaker 3:  incompatible with the suburb I live in now. It's just too big, which is why
Speaker 3:  I got rid of it. And I just see a push, particularly like the Rivian R three.
Speaker 3:  That's a smallish car. Yeah. Yeah. The Ionic five, the Hyundai Ionic five.
Speaker 3:  It's a, it's actually big, but they designed it to look like a small car.
Speaker 3:  Like it's SU Vish proportions, but it's designed to look like a
Speaker 3:  classic hatchback. And I think people are attracted to it's selling really
Speaker 3:  well because it feels small, even though it isn't technically as small as
Speaker 3:  it looks. So I. Just think there's more interest in
Speaker 3:  smaller stuff as opposed to just like full on
Speaker 3:  ucon,
Speaker 4:  You have to f crawl into them. I was in a friend got up one of the big Ram
Speaker 4:  35 hundreds and I was like, hold on, do I have, do you have like a step
Speaker 4:  or something? How do I get into this thing? It was just nightmarish.
Speaker 3:  I do miss her after very much. I'm just, just saying it one more time. I
Speaker 3:  I I think about it all the time. The car ruled. I was
Speaker 5:  Gonna go home, start asking Becky If. you can buy a big truck before it's
Speaker 5:  illegal to have a big truck.
Speaker 3:  No, it's fine. We have a very cranky Mustang inside. It's a good time. All
Speaker 3:  right, David, what you got?
Speaker 5:  So mine is news that actually happened like right after The Vergecast last
Speaker 5:  week, but I have been thinking about ever since, which is that meta
Speaker 5:  finally sort of showed off what WhatsApp and
Speaker 5:  Messenger are gonna look like now that they're being forced to interoperate
Speaker 5:  with other chat networks. This is one of those things that has been sort
Speaker 5:  of burbling forever. We've known that this is gonna
Speaker 5:  happen because of some EU regulation that basically says any sufficiently
Speaker 5:  large messaging platform has to interoperate with other messaging
Speaker 5:  systems. But there's just a couple of screenshots that they showed off.
Speaker 5:  One, they look great. You're gonna be able to either have separate or
Speaker 5:  combined inboxes the way you can have like multiple email accounts in one
Speaker 5:  email client like, seems like obviously how this should work. Excited that
Speaker 5:  it's gonna work that way. I always kind of thought they were gonna do like
Speaker 5:  you have an inbox and then the like Facebook side inbox
Speaker 5:  thing that you have to like go way out of your way to do. But there actually
Speaker 5:  seem to make it a sort of first party messaging system, which is very cool.
Speaker 5:  And then also there's a screenshot that shows
Speaker 5:  basically how you will set it up in each app. And
Speaker 5:  Meta invented two messaging apps just for the sake of these
Speaker 5:  screenshots. One is called Spruce and one is called Blurb. And I
Speaker 5:  just have, I have been, I have been designing and product managing Spruce
Speaker 5:  and Blurb all week and I have a lot of thoughts about them as messaging apps.
Speaker 3:  Which one do you think is better? Spruce or Blurb?
Speaker 5:  Spruce is like businessy. It's like Spruce is is is kind
Speaker 5:  of like where you go to to like LinkedIn Vibe blurb is like,
Speaker 5:  yo, where it's just like, it's just down to clown on blurb time. You just
Speaker 3:  Blurbing all day.
Speaker 5:  We're just Blurbing baby. Yeah, yeah. Are you just like, yo, you, you wanna
Speaker 5:  blurb later? Like, that has connotations. You know what I mean?
Speaker 3:  Well, no, in yo, you could only, yo
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Well, okay. You're right. Blurb is more than yo.
Speaker 3:  Got it. Okay. Just be clear. But
Speaker 5:  You can, you can, yo in blurb to be clear, yo is a feature of Blurb
Speaker 5:  and two super yos equals one blurb. It's important to understand that
Speaker 3:  I I got it. Yeah. I have a, I have an app in my phone called Bonk. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  yeah, yeah. Is there
Speaker 5:  Casey Newton got really excited about Bonk for a minute.
Speaker 3:  Bonk was Yo with Bons.
Speaker 5:  Bonk was Yo with Bonks. Bonk was like, bonk was like real time
Speaker 5:  collaborative. Yo.
Speaker 3:  All right. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But I, I just think this is very cool and as, as far as
Speaker 5:  we can tell, all of this is just coming to the eu
Speaker 5:  again, this fascinating schism happening between
Speaker 5:  the experience of technology in the United States and the eu. And in many
Speaker 5:  ways the EU is going to be much cooler and more open and more interesting.
Speaker 5:  But just the way this looks and the way this works has me like actually
Speaker 5:  sort of excited about what messaging might look like. So I thought that was
Speaker 5:  cool. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  By the way, the EU thing that you mentioned is I think is gonna be part of
Speaker 3:  my solution to how to review the iPhones and talk about them. 'cause
Speaker 3:  Apple intelligence isn't coming to Europe. Oh. So we're just gonna make like
Speaker 3:  European iPhone content,
Speaker 3:  continental iPhone content. I love this. And then we'll, we'll make like
Speaker 3:  Freedom Loving American content Bald eagles everywhere. Yeah. Where
Speaker 3:  the iPhone is just constantly summarizing everything. It's like text
Speaker 3:  Summarized America.
Speaker 5:  All right, NELI, what's yours?
Speaker 3:  Mine is, you know, more, more AI doism. Mm. Okay. But
Speaker 3:  in a fun way. This is legitimately I think the most interesting AI
Speaker 3:  product I've seen yet
Speaker 5:  Do tell.
Speaker 3:  So Google has this thing called Notebook ml. They've actually, that's two
Speaker 3:  different versions of this, this core idea. So Google has
Speaker 3:  this idea, they've settled on this idea. They're gonna take all of their
Speaker 3:  AI stuff where they can take a bunch of data. They have big context windows
Speaker 3:  for their model. They can understand a bunch of documents. They have good
Speaker 3:  voice synthesis. They own YouTube.
Speaker 3:  Here's their idea. We're gonna take a bunch of documents, we're gonna turn
Speaker 3:  'em into a podcast with voices talking to each other.
Speaker 3:  And so they, they have one for scientific papers, which I believe we have
Speaker 3:  access to, but we haven't really tested very much. So inside of Notebook,
Speaker 3:  lm, which is their AI powered notes app that they announced
Speaker 3:  last year. David, you're my notes.
Speaker 5:  It was, it was last year. And it's like, if it, imagine a feature
Speaker 5:  that should be in either Google Keep or Google Docs, but isn't, and that's
Speaker 5:  what Notebook L is.
Speaker 3:  But it's in blurb from what I understand,
Speaker 5:  It's, it is, you can blurb to Notebook L for sure. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Anyway, so in this app you can give it a bunch of documents and it will just
Speaker 3:  generate a podcast like two hosts
Speaker 3:  talking about your documents. And it is kind of remarkably
Speaker 3:  convincing.
Speaker 5:  I'm sorry, I've been reading a bunch about this and it's like, I can sort
Speaker 5:  of understand it, but just hearing you say that sentence, you, you give it
Speaker 5:  a bunch of documents and it can generate a podcast. I just want to like throw
Speaker 5:  myself out of a window.
Speaker 3:  It's like a, and like people have been using it, it, the
Speaker 3:  podcast host uses phrases like messy as heck. Like they
Speaker 3:  use idioms. It's just weird. And it's like
Speaker 3:  Google has had this idea twice now, like, you know, that thing where creatures
Speaker 3:  evolved to become crabs. It's like Google's AI
Speaker 3:  efforts evolved to make podcasts out of documents, like
Speaker 3:  simultaneously evolved twice inside of Google.
Speaker 3:  I think it's utterly fascinating. You can use it now in notebook. The
Speaker 3:  weirdest one I've seen is Robert Stevens,
Speaker 3:  who is the founder of the Geek Squad. The actual Geek Squad in Best Buy,
Speaker 3:  the founder of the Geek Squad. Robert Stevens appears to
Speaker 3:  be a member of the Bennett Valley Community Association in Sonoma
Speaker 3:  County, California. Apparently the Bennett Valley Community Association
Speaker 3:  has been having a lot of fights about whether to allow
Speaker 3:  weed to be grown on farms there like commercial
Speaker 3:  cannabis growing. And so he says he uploaded a bunch of docks and
Speaker 3:  like meeting notes and PDFs into this tool. And it just
Speaker 3:  generated a podcast about this fight
Speaker 3:  that for all the world sounds like a true crime podcast about whether or
Speaker 3:  not they should grow weed in Snow County.
Speaker 3:  Can I just play you the beginning of it, please? Yes,
Speaker 5:  Please.
Speaker 9:  Alright, ready to dive into another pile of documents.
Speaker 9:  Always. What do we have this time? Well, today we're headed out west
Speaker 9:  to Sonoma County, California. Oh, nice. Wine country
Speaker 9:  for a vacation. Not so fast. This isn't about a relaxing
Speaker 9:  getaway. It's actually about a pretty heated controversy brewing in
Speaker 9:  Bennett Valley. Bennett Valley. Okay. I'm intrigued. Tell me more.
Speaker 9:  So it all centers around commercial cannabis cultivation. Seems like
Speaker 9:  a lot of places have been grappling with this since legalization. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Right. It's just like he didn't write that script. Wine country, here's just
Speaker 3:  a bunch of weird minutes from board meetings and it made
Speaker 3:  a true. Now is, is it accurate? Did it hallucinate that the
Speaker 3:  heatedness of this controversy, I don't know, did
Speaker 5:  It hallucinate that the AI needs a vacation? Yeah, super did.
Speaker 3:  Super duper did.
Speaker 3:  God, there's a part in here where it notes correctly If, you
Speaker 3:  listen to it for longer. It notes correctly that
Speaker 3:  the board's lawyers told it that its first attempt to ban
Speaker 3:  cannabis cultivation would not work. So the board backed down and tried a
Speaker 3:  new legal avenue and it issue the AI issues that as a
Speaker 3:  criticism of the board, which is fascinating for a guy on the board to publish.
Speaker 3:  But like that's, to me, this is one of the most interesting uses of this
Speaker 3:  tech that I've seen. No one is making podcasts about
Speaker 3:  Sonoma County weed controversy. It doesn't seem
Speaker 3:  like there are only four subscribers to
Speaker 4:  Check. Well, well technically someone did make the podcast,
Speaker 3:  But Right. But no one and no one
Speaker 4:  Listens.
Speaker 3:  I, I'm interested in generally can you make people more
Speaker 3:  interested in the things that are happening in their community? Yeah. Right.
Speaker 3:  Every day, wherever you live, there is some board or
Speaker 3:  HOA or town council that is doing stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And there's a desert of local news throughout this country.
Speaker 3:  It's not being covered. If, you can turn it into weird true Crime podcasts.
Speaker 3:  Is that a, is that actually useful service of ai? I
Speaker 3:  I, I don't know the answer to that question, but this is the most interesting
Speaker 3:  thing that I've seen out of it yet. Yeah. All the same problems. Are there,
Speaker 3:  is it gonna hallucinate? Is it telling the truth? Can it be manipulated by
Speaker 3:  the people who are making it to be favorable to one side or another? Is it
Speaker 3:  accountable? These are people interesting to listen to. Is it feels like
Speaker 3:  an important question
Speaker 4:  Wine country.
Speaker 3:  Well, so what I found, I think the reason that this sparks such interest
Speaker 3:  to me is not the wine country. They actually were telling a
Speaker 3:  story. Yeah, no, they, as you go into it, they're like, here are the stakes.
Speaker 3:  Here's the back and forth. Here's a thing that happened. Here's the next
Speaker 3:  thing that happened.
Speaker 4:  This is legitimately like, they, they constantly do this tell a story thing
Speaker 4:  where they're like, you're just driving in your car and your kid's sad in
Speaker 4:  the back. And you just have the AI tell it a story. And that's always stupid.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. This is actually like an interesting use case of it,
Speaker 3:  Right? 'cause there's, there's things that actually happened. Yeah. Again,
Speaker 3:  do I know if the AI's, I, I'm not deep in, I'm not deep
Speaker 3:  in Bennett Valley's weed controversy. Not yet if
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna be, but it's just interesting that one like Google announced it.
Speaker 3:  This is again, they've come up with this idea twice now instead of Google,
Speaker 3:  and then two people are, are actually using it, right? Like, this
Speaker 3:  is someone who is on this board who is dealing with this controversy, who
Speaker 3:  is like, I tried this out. This is good enough to share. Right? This is,
Speaker 3:  to me he thinks it's good enough to share. I think other people are gonna
Speaker 3:  use this in other ways. Is this gonna make good podcasts? I don't know. Is
Speaker 3:  this the most interesting sort of, how do you get people
Speaker 3:  to consider things in their like local community
Speaker 3:  that they would not have otherwise considered attempt That I've seen in quite
Speaker 3:  some time. It sure is. Now, do I think that this works for every case?
Speaker 3:  'cause notebook alone? Well, you just do anything. You can put any random
Speaker 3:  assortment of documents in there. I'm very excited to put
Speaker 3:  like any one of our legal decisions in there, like the Google antitrust
Speaker 3:  decision. I wanna make Google make a podcast on,
Speaker 3:  right? Like, I'm very, do they, are they gonna do a better job than we do?
Speaker 3:  But there's just something about all of the LLM stuff
Speaker 3:  where all it's ever really doing is playing with language, right? We've enabled
Speaker 3:  natural language input, we've enabled computers to use language in ways they
Speaker 3:  couldn't do before, where it's actually this kind of thing that feels like
Speaker 3:  the most interesting use case. I don't know that this use case can support
Speaker 3:  the hype or the investment,
Speaker 3:  but actually like we can make your local politics somewhat more
Speaker 3:  digestible to you. It's the first time I've ever been like, all right,
Speaker 3:  there's, there's something going on here that seems interesting, that doesn't
Speaker 3:  seem like massive copyright theft in the end of reality,
Speaker 3:  which is how I usually evaluate these things.
Speaker 5:  Well, the challenge there is can you have this use case without all that
Speaker 5:  other stuff? Yeah. I dunno. But, but I, I agree. It is an interesting use
Speaker 5:  case. And I also, like, I, the, the other news kind of, of this
Speaker 5:  ilk that came out this week was OpenAI released oh one, it's new
Speaker 5:  like reasoning capable model.
Speaker 4:  It looks like an emoji,
Speaker 5:  First of all, terrible name OpenAI said to Kylie Robinson who wrote the story
Speaker 5:  for us, they were like, oh, we think our names are bad. We try to reboot
Speaker 5:  it. Like, you, you, you did that again, sorry. Open AI oh
Speaker 5:  one is nothing.
Speaker 5:  But one of the things that it does is you ask it a question and
Speaker 5:  because it's a quote unquote reasoning model, it takes longer to answer
Speaker 5:  because it's just doing more steps at a time. But it will walk you through
Speaker 5:  the steps that it's taking. And, and Kylie
Speaker 5:  included this screenshot in which it's saying things like, this is
Speaker 5:  the, the model reporting back as it's talking, as
Speaker 5:  it's thinking aloud. I'm curious about defining variables to translate the
Speaker 5:  problem into algebra. And then a minute later I'm thinking through a new
Speaker 5:  variable to measure time and establishing clear definitions for years in
Speaker 5:  the past. And like, we're, we're still down this road of making these things
Speaker 5:  seem sort of human. It's like when you talk to Siri
Speaker 5:  and it goes, Hmm. Or and it's like, is this, is this what we
Speaker 5:  want?
Speaker 4:  It's the most irritating thing in the world. Yeah. And like, you're fake.
Speaker 5:  Like, do I want the AI to pretend to be a person?
Speaker 5:  No, because, and I feel that same way listening to this podcast. I'm like,
Speaker 5:  are you, what are you, what are you here for?
Speaker 4:  I want all of them to go and watch like a whole
Speaker 4:  one of the Star Trek series because they, they actually do interact
Speaker 4:  with computer. Like the computer's not irritating in it. It's like, hold
Speaker 4:  on, let me process that
Speaker 5:  Tea. Earl Gray Hot.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Done.
Speaker 5:  The tea machine is not like, Hmm. I'm thinking about which blend you might
Speaker 5:  be. I've
Speaker 3:  Always wanted to just communicate only in nouns and adjectives. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Very good. I will say just to, you know, the people are gonna
Speaker 3:  yell at me 'cause I said something nice about ai. I'll say something dor
Speaker 3:  about ai, which is meta has taken the AI labels off of Instagram.
Speaker 3:  Mm. Or they're hiding them in a menu because none of that
Speaker 3:  was ready. None of it worked. No one has any point of view. And
Speaker 3:  LOL nothing matters. They just gave up. We have just given up on this.
Speaker 3:  We're we're doing AI generated images of, of Elon Musk and
Speaker 3:  Taylor Swift having a cat baby. That's a real picture that I saw this week.
Speaker 3:  Why? Why the end?
Speaker 3:  There you go. You said it all. This is like the real, the real
Speaker 3:  plus and minus of it right now. Like, oh, maybe this will help people engage
Speaker 3:  in local communities. I will have to see this picture and there will be no
Speaker 3:  label on it because no one figured out how any of that works. And maybe it
Speaker 3:  never will. That's it. That's the RB has everybody. Yay.
Speaker 3:  Fold your phone in half. Any phone. It doesn't have to actually be a fold.
Speaker 3:  Just get out there and start folding phones in half Bridge, strength, rock
Speaker 3:  and roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Verge Cast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one. One. The Vergecast is the
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.