# Transcript
ID: a167fe2a-1ef1-47f8-8f70-60310163b753
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-3223812947774791888/-5014429950039402306/s93290-US-4130s-1717977611.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of audio over Wi-Fi:
03:02 - The Verge’s Chris Welch shares his review of Sonos's Ace headphones.
Sonos Ace review: was it worth it?
Sonos CEO Patrick Spence addresses the company’s divisive app redesign
28:58 - MoviePass, MovieCrash director Muta’Ali and MoviePass CEO Stacy Spikes discuss what went wrong with the MoviePass subscription service and how that story was documented in the film.
MoviePass, MovieCrash review: a damning account of corporate greed
MoviePass is using you to ruin the movies
56:47 - Jennifer Pattison Tuohy answers a question from The Vergecast Hotline about smart home gadgets for renters.
Home Assistant: Setting up the Aqara FP2 Presence Sensor - Derek Seaman's Tech Blog
Yale launches its first retrofit smart lock — the Yale Approach with Wi-Fi
The new Yale Keypad Touch brings fingerprint unlocking to August smart locks
Aqara kick-starts its first Matter-over-Thread smart lock with a promise of Home Key support
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (43 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Audio over wifi.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend David Pierce and I am currently waiting on my breakfast order.
Speaker 2:  That doesn't sound like big news, but as I've mentioned on the show before,
Speaker 2:  whenever I get to a new city, I immediately go looking for like a handful
Speaker 2:  of staples, really great cup of coffee, really great donut, really great
Speaker 2:  pizza is I think one I forgot to mention the last time. And a really great
Speaker 2:  bacon, egg and cheese. I haven't really found one in this neighborhood, but
Speaker 2:  there's this place that I'm at right now that is on the way to daycare
Speaker 2:  for me, which means I walk by it like 40,000 times a week and they just
Speaker 2:  got a new name, a new owner, a new chef, and a new menu including a
Speaker 2:  breakfast sandwich. I keep hearing good things. This would be huge for me.
Speaker 2:  This is where I'm at in life as a breakfast sandwich would, would change
Speaker 2:  things for me. So I ordered it. It was $8, which is a little high
Speaker 2:  but manageable and we're gonna see how we do. Anyway, we have an awesome
Speaker 2:  show coming up for you today. We're gonna do two things. The first thing
Speaker 2:  we're gonna do is we're gonna talk about Sonos. There's a bunch of new Sonos
Speaker 2:  here. Chris Welch reviewed it all. I have been wondering about the Sonos
Speaker 2:  ace headphones forever and Chris has them. He's used them. He's tested
Speaker 2:  them, he's reviewed them. We're gonna talk to him about it and maybe if we're
Speaker 2:  lucky, hear how it went. We're also gonna talk about the new documentary
Speaker 2:  about MoviePass. It's called MoviePass Movie Crashed and it tells the story
Speaker 2:  of one of the fastest growing tech companies of all time and also one of
Speaker 2:  the fastest dying tech companies of all time. It's a really interesting story
Speaker 2:  because it is kind of every tech story all rolled into
Speaker 2:  one bundle of total chaos. We're gonna talk to the director and the
Speaker 2:  CEO get the whole story. Super fun episode. We're also gonna do a hotline
Speaker 2:  question. Lots to do. All that is coming up in just a sec, but first I
Speaker 2:  hear my sandwich coming. I can smell my sandwich coming. I'm very excited.
Speaker 2:  This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  will be going there between, you know, six and
Speaker 2:  So the new Sonos ace headphones are out there, $450.
Speaker 2:  Chris Welch has been using them. There's also the Rome Bluetooth speaker,
Speaker 2:  which I wanna talk about, but I'm particularly curious about the ace because
Speaker 2:  there's just something really hard about doing a pair of headphones like
Speaker 2:  this correctly. You look at something like the AirPods Max
Speaker 2:  or the Bose Quiet Comfort headphones and what you see over and over is
Speaker 2:  that the combination of weight, battery life, overall
Speaker 2:  comfort, sound quality, noise cancellation,
Speaker 2:  easy connectivity, it's really hard to do all of those things simultaneously
Speaker 2:  correctly at any price. Four $50 is a lot to spend on a pair of
Speaker 2:  headphones, but a really great pair of headphones that does all of those
Speaker 2:  things well is like the white whale and a lot of companies are getting
Speaker 2:  closer and closer. This space is really exciting actually, but we
Speaker 2:  haven't quite gotten there so I've been fascinated to know are the Sonos
Speaker 2:  ace the ones, did they get there? Are they Sonos C and are they
Speaker 2:  just an awesome pair of headphones? Chris Welch has reviewed them, he knows
Speaker 2:  this stuff better than anybody else. I know time to talk about it. Chris
Speaker 2:  Welch, welcome back.
Speaker 5:  Hello. Hello.
Speaker 2:  Sonos just continues to take up your whole life
Speaker 2:  and existence.
Speaker 5:  Yes. How you feeling? Good. We just got the review up of the new Ace,
Speaker 5:  as did many other publications and seems like it's a fairly positive vibe
Speaker 5:  so far. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  People seem to, people seem to like the thing. Yeah, I'm very curious how
Speaker 2:  you review a pair of headphones. I wanna get into the ace in particular,
Speaker 2:  but like walk me through a a a day in the life of a Chris
Speaker 2:  Welch headphone review.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I've got my playlist of songs that I know so, so well
Speaker 5:  and then I just, you know, write the subway, walk around New York, see how
Speaker 5:  hot they get, yada yada. It's like very warm in New York City right now.
Speaker 5:  So that's been fun. But you know, comfort, I try and wear 'em all day here
Speaker 5:  at the office once or twice just to see how they wear over time, you know,
Speaker 5:  like I've got glasses so I want to see how those do as far as like comfort
Speaker 5:  goes. But yeah, nothing too crazy, you know?
Speaker 2:  What are your favorite test songs? Like what's, what's at the top of that?
Speaker 2:  Tester goes,
Speaker 5:  Oh God. I mean I'm like a big Dave Matthews band guy, so nice.
Speaker 5:  Gotta go back to those albums.
Speaker 2:  Which of the many jammy guitar parts can I hear? Yes, most clearly here.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I love
Speaker 5:  It. Exactly. So that's on there, but you know, yeah, there's Beatles,
Speaker 5:  there's all sorts of stuff that I kind of just go through in cycle Between,
Speaker 5:  but Okay. But yeah, these sound quite nice. I think they're kinda like in
Speaker 5:  between the Sonys and the AirPods Max. There is some base to them,
Speaker 5:  but yeah, they sound nice and warm and detailed and I don't really have any
Speaker 5:  complaints on that front. Is
Speaker 2:  There I, I'm realizing I've never really known the answer to this question.
Speaker 2:  Is there like a sono sound in the way that I feel like there is sort of a
Speaker 2:  beat sound and to some extent there's kind of a Bose sound. Is
Speaker 2:  there a sono sound with the ace or with just Sono stuff in general?
Speaker 5:  I don't know. You know, they always like talk about how they have this like
Speaker 5:  board of like sound experts who they like go to for every speaker and product
Speaker 5:  that like gives them advice on how it should sound and the yada yada. So
Speaker 5:  these are pretty clean, crisp, they're not like super base forward. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  they're fairly balanced. Like there's no like profile that I can really like
Speaker 5:  tell so it's just, yeah, they're a good sounding pair of headphones. Okay.
Speaker 5:  But they're comfortable as hell. That's like the main thing about these.
Speaker 5:  It's like, so the weight is like in between the AirPods Max and the Sonys,
Speaker 5:  but yeah, they just wear so much lighter than the AirPods Max, you know,
Speaker 5:  there's more plastic, which is fine for headphones I think, you know,
Speaker 5:  you certainly can't overdo it when it comes to metal and I think that's what
Speaker 5:  we had for the AirPods Max. But yeah, they feel great on your head over
Speaker 5:  long timeframes. Yeah, I think the AirPods Max, one thing I like about those
Speaker 5:  better is the fabric ear cushions. These were a bit hotter because they're
Speaker 5:  like pleather. So in the summer and the spring, you know, you start to sweat
Speaker 5:  and that makes a difference. But on the whole they are just way, way more
Speaker 5:  comfortable.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I was surprised actually by how comfortable you found them given that
Speaker 2:  they are not like wildly heavier than say the
Speaker 2:  the Bose quiet comforts but meaningfully heavier and I think
Speaker 2:  the AirPods max for me in particular feel heavy on my head
Speaker 2:  in a way that like the Bose ones, you never don't know you're wearing
Speaker 2:  headphones, but I don't sort of feel them like the gravity of them pulling
Speaker 2:  down on my head with the AirPods Max, I very much do. Yeah. And I was worried
Speaker 2:  this was gonna skew closer to that, but it sounds like at least in the way
Speaker 2:  that they wear, they don't feel like that at all.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, not at all. Super comfortable. The battery life is like 30 hours, so
Speaker 5:  they last a long, long, long time say like on the hardware front they got
Speaker 5:  it all right. Honestly. So for our first time out it's pretty impressive
Speaker 5:  and the software features, you know, half of them work, which is why I gave
Speaker 5:  them a seven. I think some other publications were a bit a bit
Speaker 5:  kinder
Speaker 2:  While we're on the hardware. I wanna talk about just the controls for a second
Speaker 2:  in part because from the way you describe it, it sounds like Sonos got the,
Speaker 2:  how you use these headphones while they're on your head thing almost
Speaker 2:  Exactly right. Like this idea of there being one button that does everything
Speaker 2:  and then I think you, you slide the button to change the volume.
Speaker 2:  I love that, that that seems fantastic. Like is that, is that as good as
Speaker 2:  it seems to be in terms of actually like putting your hands up and using
Speaker 2:  the thing? 'cause for me it's like I have the bows and it's just a bunch
Speaker 2:  of sort of samey feeling buttons and I've gotten pretty good at
Speaker 2:  knowing which one is which. But I'm still, every time I put my hand up I
Speaker 2:  kind of like slide it down the cup to find the right hit and it seems like
Speaker 2:  Sonos just like figured it out from the jump.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no it's very good. The content key as it's called, I'm not sure about
Speaker 5:  the name. Yeah, it's a bad name, you know, bad name but it's great like,
Speaker 5:  so it takes some time to get used to just like finding it and like sliding
Speaker 5:  it and like that difference, you don't wanna press when you slide that takes
Speaker 5:  like one day to get used to. But on the whole, yeah it's very good. Like
Speaker 5:  compared to swipes on all these like Sony headphones and stuff and like the
Speaker 5:  tab gestures, once you have gloves on, forget about it. So this kind of stuff
Speaker 5:  works a lot better in my experience. So there's that button, there's a button
Speaker 5:  for the noise cancellation mode and a power button and that's pretty much
Speaker 5:  it. So
Speaker 2:  That feels right. I will say I am just adamantly against touch
Speaker 2:  pads on headphones. I just don't think they work, I just, it's just a bad
Speaker 2:  user experience. I'm not, I'm, I'm out on it everywhere it exists. So I'm
Speaker 2:  very glad Sonos didn't do that.
Speaker 5:  I'm with you. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so let's, let's talk about the TV audio swap thing because there are
Speaker 2:  a bunch of other interesting features that sort of are and are not here,
Speaker 2:  but TV audio swap was the thing, right? Like if Sonos is going to
Speaker 2:  convince you to buy these headphones, one is it's a Sonos product. Sonos
Speaker 2:  tends to make very good sounding products, but the TV audio swap is the thing.
Speaker 2:  Tell me about your experience with this.
Speaker 5:  It's been mostly good. I had a few hiccups where it just like didn't work
Speaker 5:  and someone just tells me it's a bug. Of course that'll be fixed soon, like
Speaker 5:  so many other things that are coming soon. But on the whole, yeah like so
Speaker 5:  you have an arc, you just go home, you come home, you turn in your tv, start
Speaker 5:  watching something and you hold down the content key for like two seconds
Speaker 5:  and then it just beams it right over to your headphones and there's head
Speaker 5:  tracking if you want that. So you can like, you know, move around and feel
Speaker 5:  more immersed in your content. So it works for like anything plugged into
Speaker 5:  your tv, be like a gaming console which works super well, like surprisingly
Speaker 5:  so. And it's just, yeah, a nice little private wave of watching TV
Speaker 5:  and whatever else you want.
Speaker 2:  Sonos seems to have this idea that it's for more than just
Speaker 2:  watching something quietly while someone else doesn't want to
Speaker 2:  watch it. Like right. For me, I, I used private listening on
Speaker 2:  Roku for months after I had a kid because you know, I have a, I have a kid
Speaker 2:  in my arm and I'm wearing headphones and that is a way to
Speaker 2:  listen to things quietly. But I get the sense Sonos thinks of this as like
Speaker 2:  a, like a lifestyle feature or as like an audio feature
Speaker 2:  more than just, you can hear the audio but others can't. Like what,
Speaker 2:  what is the big sort of Galaxy Brain case for audio swap and
Speaker 2:  why you would wear headphones to watch tv?
Speaker 5:  I think it can be more immersive. Like there's spatial audio, a surround
Speaker 5:  sound, like they up convert stereo if you want that as well. So it does sound
Speaker 5:  really good
Speaker 2:  I guess That's true. It's like a 5.1 system on your head. Yeah, that's fair.
Speaker 2:  That's something
Speaker 5:  And so there's that and then this fall there's a new feature called True
Speaker 5:  Cinema that's gonna like map your room using both the sound bar and the headphones.
Speaker 5:  So it sounds like more real, the surround sound effect, it'll like trick
Speaker 5:  your brain into like actually thinking they're actually speakers around you
Speaker 5:  Right now it's not quite that level but they say sometime this, this year
Speaker 5:  that'll be there and Bose is also working on like similar ideas to like pair
Speaker 5:  soundbars and headphones and earbuds together for like super immersion.
Speaker 5:  So once that rolls out, if it you know, works as advertised, that'll be
Speaker 5:  interesting. But yeah, it's like very immersive. It sounds very nice. You
Speaker 5:  don't have to like sacrifice audio quality just to not have your soundbar
Speaker 5:  blurring away at night, which is nice and you can game on it. Like I said,
Speaker 5:  that's what what I've done a ton and it's great. What's
Speaker 2:  Been your experience so far in terms of actually sitting down and doing it?
Speaker 2:  Like obviously when you're reviewing the product you're gonna go through
Speaker 2:  the work to sit down on the couch, grab the remote, grab your headphones,
Speaker 2:  do the whole thing. Do you think it as just a normal person in normal life
Speaker 2:  you you're gonna add headphones to the flop down on the couch mix?
Speaker 5:  I think so. I've got roommates so that's the main thing. Like what's that
Speaker 5:  real really late at night, I'm not gonna like have my arc going full blast
Speaker 5:  while watching, you know, a top gun maverick. It's not
Speaker 5:  super considerate. So that's there, that's a use case, you know, late night
Speaker 5:  gaming, yada yada past a certain point of night. It's like a super handy
Speaker 5:  thing to have and it sounds very nice for sure. So is it worth the cost of
Speaker 5:  the headphones and an arc? You know, that's a pricey thing
Speaker 2:  I think in that case the key is to try and convince everyone in the house
Speaker 2:  to split it. Yeah and it's like listen this is not for me, this is for all
Speaker 2:  of us. It, it will be mine and I will own it and you can't use it but it
Speaker 2:  is for all of us and so this like what $1,100
Speaker 2:  purchase, we're just gonna split it together, it's gonna be no problem.
Speaker 5:  Yeah but it should, should be coming to the Ray and the beam pretty soon
Speaker 5:  and it's cool for the Ray 'cause like the rays just like a basic like stereo
Speaker 5:  soundbar but now you're gonna get like Dolby atmos like res surround sound
Speaker 5:  through your headphones, which is nice to, nice to see. But yeah, like once
Speaker 5:  they roll out that support, once TV audio swap works on Android at all, that'll
Speaker 5:  be a nice thing. So I think I'm gonna like go back and like readdress the
Speaker 5:  score once some of these software updates go out for more people.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  So it's the once it works thing that is killing me here. Right, because the,
Speaker 2:  this is, this is the story of Sonos these last few weeks is
Speaker 2:  it rolled out this half finished app
Speaker 2:  supposedly in order to support these headphones which themselves don't
Speaker 2:  feel finished from a software perspective. And on the one hand if you want
Speaker 2:  to pick a weakness of Sonos, it has always been its software. So I guess
Speaker 2:  on the, I I shouldn't be totally shocked that it seems like it nailed the
Speaker 2:  hardware and didn't finish the software. Like that is kind of a Sonos story.
Speaker 2:  But on the other hand I just can't stop thinking like wh why why
Speaker 2:  ship any of this A now and B in this order
Speaker 2:  when it doesn't seem like there was any real like rhyme or reason
Speaker 2:  and none of it's done. I
Speaker 5:  Don't understand the whole June timeframe thing. Yeah I think maybe like
Speaker 5:  there like thinking like Apple's gonna have new AirPods in the fall that
Speaker 5:  would just drown out this if they waited until you know September. But even
Speaker 5:  like waiting until August would've given them like precious weeks to just
Speaker 5:  polish everything a little bit more and get it out the door as a fuller
Speaker 5:  thing. Yeah it's just a big rush and it's not clear why, I mean people
Speaker 5:  aren't like buying speakers and sound bars like they were during the pandemic.
Speaker 5:  So that's the main like impetus for these coming out in the first place.
Speaker 5:  Is
Speaker 2:  Sonos a little peloton in that way? Do you think that like
Speaker 2:  it's a great product that is always going to be kind of a niche
Speaker 2:  thing just by virtue of A what it is and B, what it costs and
Speaker 2:  everybody who was gonna get one got one which is great
Speaker 2:  but now puts you in a position of like there, there probably aren't many
Speaker 2:  people out there right now shopping for Sonos upgrades because everybody
Speaker 2:  upgraded in 2020 and 2021. So now if I'm Sonos
Speaker 2:  like is the whole headphones push just we need a
Speaker 2:  whole new thing to give people so that they're not upgrading, they're
Speaker 2:  actually buying like a net new object.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, for sure. Okay. That's the main reason behind this. They've also got
Speaker 5:  services, you know they, they've got Sonos radio, hd, other Sonos Pro for
Speaker 5:  businesses or they like manage all your speakers so they're all trying to
Speaker 5:  branch out and find like new ways of more income. But yeah like you said
Speaker 5:  like you know, I've had an arc it would take a lot for me to like upgrade
Speaker 5:  a soundbar. Like there's not much this, this thing doesn't do that I would
Speaker 5:  need from some new version, you know, same goes for the play five which has
Speaker 5:  been around forever. So these are first and you can see like a world where
Speaker 5:  they do you know like not just headphones but also ear buds and kinda like
Speaker 5:  you know, do the full thing and this is a good start. There are four 50 bucks
Speaker 5:  which is, that's a lot of money but people, people spend a lot on this stuff.
Speaker 5:  So Sony and Bose and everybody else, you know they're all in the same territory
Speaker 5:  but yeah for a first time out, you know, super impressive. I think they've
Speaker 5:  got a lot of bugs to work out. The app is still a causing chaos.
Speaker 5:  I mean the Sonos subreddit is just, I've never seen anything like it just
Speaker 5:  every day still still people venting, which I understand, you know, people
Speaker 5:  lose features. I'd be upset too, like I'm with Neli and you and I don't
Speaker 5:  really use my Sona system that way or I've noticed much different but yeah
Speaker 5:  they should have just waited one or two more months, put all this stuff out
Speaker 5:  in the fall and had a way smoother experience that like didn't cause
Speaker 5:  cause the huge outcry.
Speaker 2:  Yeah I think to some extent Sonos is lucky it got the hardware as right as
Speaker 2:  it did because it'll, it'll buy it a chance to do that. Like I think
Speaker 2:  if if there had been even one kind of big
Speaker 2:  flaw in the hardware on top of all the stuff with the app, yeah
Speaker 2:  this would feel almost dead on arrival. Whereas now it's like okay
Speaker 2:  I think there's a reasonable chance that come this fall or like this holiday
Speaker 2:  when a lot of people are Christmas shopping, this is going to be a damn good
Speaker 2:  pair of headphones. Yeah, absolutely. That is actually gonna make a lot of
Speaker 2:  sense for a lot of people. I will say the thing about it that kills me, the
Speaker 2:  sort of dream that I think a lot of people have had for a Sonos pair of headphones
Speaker 2:  and what I'm seeing a lot of in our comments too on your review is this
Speaker 2:  idea that it should fit perfectly into my whole Sonos
Speaker 2:  ecosystem, right? That I should I, I want to listen to music on
Speaker 2:  the speaker in my kitchen while I make dinner and then pop on headphones
Speaker 2:  and just boom the music switches, everything works great and
Speaker 2:  then I can play from you know, my, my record player and the
Speaker 2:  TV in my living room and the TV upstairs and everything that is in
Speaker 2:  the Sonos ecosystem just sort of beautifully flows around and this has been
Speaker 2:  the promise of Sonos for forever. Yeah and the ace just doesn't
Speaker 2:  feel like it comes anywhere close to that. Like the the content key
Speaker 2:  thing you're describing where it sits down and it works at the Ace, I am
Speaker 2:  confident that will eventually work very well. I could be wrong about that,
Speaker 2:  but it seems like that that is the sort of thing Sonos will eventually get
Speaker 2:  right because it usually eventually gets that kind of stuff right. But it
Speaker 2:  doesn't seem like there's any indication that this is going to be the like
Speaker 2:  magical addition to my whole Sonos system that
Speaker 2:  I wanted it to be.
Speaker 5:  It's funny you should say that last week they had like a Reddit ask me anything
Speaker 5:  where people have asked about this a ton and so they, they kind of said like
Speaker 5:  we're just not there yet as far as the tech goes. So in terms of like CPU
Speaker 5:  power, these have a fraction of even like the Sonos room, oh like it's a
Speaker 5:  small processor in there, then there's wifi to worry about battery
Speaker 5:  worries and so they're like, we tried it like we prototyped those wifi
Speaker 5:  headphones that everybody wants and they sucked so like we're just not there
Speaker 5:  yet as far as like being able to do that and like have it be viable. Like
Speaker 5:  they were like we, they were like we tried it and it's just not the right
Speaker 5:  time right now. So this is like a first step I think and it makes sense,
Speaker 5:  it's like a, you know, halfway point between full on like Sonos integration
Speaker 5:  and what we have now with the TV audio swap. So it's a good starting point
Speaker 5:  but I can see the point of like, you know, do you really want like a short
Speaker 5:  battery life just for wifi audio? I mean I would sometimes but you know give
Speaker 5:  it like two or three, four years maybe we'll see that kind of product eventually.
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 2:  Fair. And I will say to Sonos is credit making a thing that is fundamentally
Speaker 2:  just a very good pair of Bluetooth headphones is the right thing and not
Speaker 2:  something Sonos historically always does. So like making a thing that
Speaker 2:  actually easily works with all of your non Sonos stuff is a victory.
Speaker 2:  So I think if you, if you're forcing me to choose, I will take what they
Speaker 2:  did but it does it, it just feels like there's that little piece of sort
Speaker 2:  of Sonos magic that nothing else can get to that it didn't
Speaker 2:  quite hit and that bummed me out. Yeah, from an audio perspective,
Speaker 2:  does the wifi thing matter? I I just like sincerely don't know how much I
Speaker 2:  should care that I can't do wifi audio versus just having the, you
Speaker 2:  know, Bluetooth codec support from my phone. There
Speaker 5:  Are always gonna be people who like swear they can tell the difference between
Speaker 5:  lossless audio and you know like all these codecs. I can tell maybe
Speaker 5:  sometimes it's just one of those things people just like want to have 'cause
Speaker 5:  they're spending all that money, I think they just want the best thing and
Speaker 5:  so it makes sense to want that doesn't really matter. It's gonna really come
Speaker 5:  down to like each person individually I can see like why you would want it
Speaker 5:  as far as like a turntable in your system and like an amp and like having
Speaker 5:  like play that through your headphones. That'd be awesome. But unfortunately
Speaker 5:  we're not there quite yet. But like yeah these sound very good. They're good
Speaker 5:  headphones. So they've got several features that like all these high-end
Speaker 5:  headphones usually do. There's like on head detection so you can like take
Speaker 5:  'em off, it'll pause all those like you know like the small quality of life
Speaker 5:  things and there's multi points. You compare them with two devices at once
Speaker 5:  and so they've covered a lot of ground. There's like wired USBC listening,
Speaker 5:  so if you want lossless audio there's your answer. So yeah, they've covered
Speaker 5:  a lot of ground but now we're in this like weird game of wait and see for
Speaker 5:  like the Android support and the Beam and the ray and, but that
Speaker 5:  stuff should shake out like Sonas promises, software fixes and they usually
Speaker 5:  do make good on actually you know, putting them out. So yeah, we'll see how
Speaker 5:  long it takes hopefully this month for some of this stuff but there's no
Speaker 5:  firm timetable just yet. So yeah
Speaker 2:  It does seem like audio quality wise I feel like the, the gold standard is
Speaker 2:  like whatever new Sony hexa decimal
Speaker 2:  thing, I can't remember the name of thing. The new Bose Quiet
Speaker 2:  Comforts and the AirPods Max. I feel like that's kind of like the trio everybody
Speaker 2:  thinks of.
Speaker 5:  There are some others and there you know there's the Asen Heiser, momentum
Speaker 5:  fours, those sound great. Those are probably my favorite sound quality headphones.
Speaker 5:  Besides these at the moment there's that and I call these brands like Bowers
Speaker 5:  and Wilkins for like that true like audio file segment. But like by and large,
Speaker 5:  like you said like for most consumers it's Sony, it's Bose, it's Apple,
Speaker 5:  and now hopefully Sonos is what they want to happen.
Speaker 2:  Well and it seems like from a sort of what it's like to wear
Speaker 2:  and use and listen to them, yeah Sonos belongs there
Speaker 2:  but I feel like the one other piece of that we haven't talked about is the
Speaker 2:  noise cancellation, which to me I think is like maybe the most important
Speaker 2:  feature for me, like this is where I out myself as somebody who is like by
Speaker 2:  no means an audio quality expert. Yeah. But somebody who is constantly on
Speaker 2:  planes, the A NC really matters to me, which is why I've been a, a real
Speaker 2:  like Bose loyalist over the years because Bose is just better at this than
Speaker 2:  everybody else. How do the ace shape up there?
Speaker 5:  Bose is still better than everybody else, but these are good, you know, they're
Speaker 5:  not like top tier level but they're good enough for a plane ride or the train.
Speaker 5:  You know, I've, I've had 'em on the past two weeks and they're good for the
Speaker 5:  subway. My coffee shop, I can still hear like a little bit of racket when
Speaker 5:  I work from the coffee shop on my block, but, so they're not like BS level
Speaker 5:  of like a total cocoon of silence but for most like everyday
Speaker 5:  situations where you just wanna like have some peace and quiet, it'll do
Speaker 5:  the job just fine. What
Speaker 2:  About the flip side? The, what is it called? The, the like audio pass through
Speaker 2:  thing where it tries to pump in the outside noise? How is that?
Speaker 5:  That sounds actually very, very good. Okay. That's like the AirPods max have
Speaker 5:  the best pass through mode of all and these are like not too far behind that
Speaker 5:  honestly. Oh
Speaker 2:  Wow, okay.
Speaker 5:  It's like that's where someone else really came through and kind of surprised
Speaker 5:  me because
Speaker 2:  The Air Budds Maxs are drastically better than the Bose. Yeah
Speaker 5:  Those are great. These are, you know, like a stones throw away pretty close
Speaker 5:  and then BS and the Sony are not, not so hot when it comes to the pass through
Speaker 5:  mode. But yeah, so it's not world class A NC but it's close on on the
Speaker 5:  transparency mode front. So pretty good All in all. So it
Speaker 2:  Seems like even if you're not a Sonos person and you're just
Speaker 2:  wanting to buy a really good pair of headphones to pair with your
Speaker 2:  computer and phone and whatever, if you don't have any other Sonos gear,
Speaker 2:  this is probably like a hundred dollars more than you wanna spend on this
Speaker 2:  pair of headphones, right? But like absolutely belongs on the poke
Speaker 2:  around the Amazon listing. Yeah. Set. Is that, is that a fair
Speaker 2:  characterization? Yeah
Speaker 5:  For surely. I don't know who's gonna start their Sonos journey with headphones
Speaker 5:  that cost this much, but I'm sure some people will, you know, there'll be
Speaker 5:  a person who just buys these and then thinks these are great and buys a,
Speaker 5:  you know, the whole, the arc obviously you would get first if you wanna actually
Speaker 5:  use the core feature. But yeah, I mean they're great. Like they belong the
Speaker 5:  same conversation as everybody else as far as like sound quality fit
Speaker 5:  and finish and comfort, like I said, the comfort is really, you know, go
Speaker 5:  to your local Best Buy and trys and you're gonna be pretty surprised by how
Speaker 5:  good they feel. I think
Speaker 2:  It's a big win for Sonos honestly. Especially if you go back to that like
Speaker 2:  Sonos has to find the thing to sell people who don't want sono skier. Right.
Speaker 2:  That's a big win And I, I would bet I could be totally wrong, but I would
Speaker 2:  bet that we're gonna get to like Black Friday and this thing is gonna be
Speaker 2:  $349.
Speaker 5:  That'd be nice. That would help for sure. But even now they're great. I think
Speaker 5:  the white one are my, my favorite compared to the black and the black is
Speaker 5:  fine, but the
Speaker 2:  White one's are really nice looking. Yeah, they're really nice looking.
Speaker 5:  So that's the way I would go if someone wants advice,
Speaker 2:  Which ones have you been testing the most? The white ones I worry would get
Speaker 2:  sort of a like gross patina on them after wearing 'em for a
Speaker 2:  while. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  So far they still look good. Okay. The case is getting pretty, pretty dirty,
Speaker 5:  the white case, but it's got a nice green interior so you know, the black
Speaker 5:  ones get all smudgy, they've got like an anti fingerprint coating on them
Speaker 5:  to help with that a little bit, but they still pick up smudges and stuff
Speaker 5:  like all black plastic gadgets tend to do, but personal preference
Speaker 5:  as always. Yeah
Speaker 2:  I will say for, for all of the kind of missing
Speaker 2:  Sonos stuff, I'm very impressed that Sonos did as well as it did here. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Just to make this good a pair of headphones just absent all the other stuff,
Speaker 2:  just this good a pair of headphones on its first try outta the gate gives
Speaker 2:  me great hope for what Sonos might be able to do here. Pretty
Speaker 5:  Good. I think Patrick Spence's job is safe for now after Just
Speaker 2:  Kidding. I mean gimme a couple app updates until I feel very confident about
Speaker 2:  that, but I, I, I like the thought so far. I also forgot
Speaker 2:  one other ace question that I forgot to ask. We're gonna come on and we're
Speaker 2:  gonna do a full fancy headphone mic test at some point because that's a thing
Speaker 2:  we need to do. The people love when we put horrible sounding audio on The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast, we, and we haven't done it in a while Chris, and we're gonna have
Speaker 2:  to do it, but give the, gimme the quick feeling of how the
Speaker 2:  microphone is on the ace.
Speaker 5:  Pretty good, pretty good. If you go to the review, there's an embed of me
Speaker 5:  testing them that I put out today. We've
Speaker 6:  Got the Sonos Save here in New York trying to give you a sense of
Speaker 6:  how they sound, how clear they are and whether they're suitable for
Speaker 6:  phone calls on the go. So let me know what you think.
Speaker 5:  They're clear. I'm not one to like really take calls outside, I just don't
Speaker 5:  enjoy it for myself or the other person on the line, so I try to avoid it,
Speaker 5:  but sometimes, you know, you're at the coffee shop on a Zoom call and these
Speaker 5:  seem like they'll work just fine. They do a decent job of like canceling
Speaker 5:  out background noise and all that and you come through clearly. So I'm not
Speaker 5:  sure what else you would really ask for beyond that. So
Speaker 2:  Before I let you go, you also have the new Rome, the new Bluetooth speaker.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. You haven't published your review. That's coming later this week. Gimme
Speaker 2:  a preview. How do you feel so far?
Speaker 5:  They added a button that's really the, that's really what it comes down to.
Speaker 5:  Yes, so the first Jerome had a combined power and Bluetooth pairing button
Speaker 5:  and you had to set it up at home first before you could use it as a portable
Speaker 5:  speaker, which never made any sense. So they fixed that. You can use it outta
Speaker 5:  the box now. Whoops. You do. But yeah, there's a new button. It sounds the
Speaker 5:  exact same, so if you've heard it before, you've heard this one. Battery
Speaker 5:  life is the same, some people haven't like had the best time with the room
Speaker 5:  over time. I guess the battery ages not so well. So someone has told me that
Speaker 5:  they've done some work there to make it last longer, but yeah, it's the same
Speaker 5:  speaker as before, same price, just a new button comes in colors. It's
Speaker 5:  small, it's a good bathroom speaker. That's how I use mine for the shower.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, it's not my top tier favorite Sono Skagit
Speaker 2:  Fair. But it, I mean buttons are good. We here on the Vergecast, we believe
Speaker 2:  in buttons. You know this so I I will take it.
Speaker 5:  Love buttons. Yes.
Speaker 2:  All right, well it's very upsetting that I wanna buy one of these now and
Speaker 2:  I will not forgive you for that. I also wanna buy an ace now I like don't
Speaker 2:  have a sound bar and all of a sudden I'm like, oh, $1,200 is a
Speaker 2:  perfectly rational amount of money to spend upgrading my TV audio today.
Speaker 2:  Like what? What could possibly go wrong? There's
Speaker 5:  The arc and there's an arc too coming and even like a higher end sound. They're
Speaker 5:  working on so many, I don't, don't tell me this so much down the pipeline,
Speaker 5:  Chris, this is not helpful. All right,
Speaker 2:  We gotta take a break and then we're gonna be right back to talk about MoviePass.
Speaker 2:  Chris, thank you as always.
Speaker 2:  7 0 9 9. Just in case you're
Speaker 2:  day. That was it. Those were all the rules, at least for a while. It was
Speaker 2:  a great product for anyone who likes watching movies and it was a
Speaker 2:  truly horrific business. It took less than two years
Speaker 2:  for the company to burn through $250 million and shut down
Speaker 2:  the product entirely, which is honestly in a certain way, kind of
Speaker 2:  impressive. Anyway, there's a new documentary out now on Max
Speaker 2:  called MoviePass Movie Crash and it tells the story of
Speaker 2:  MoviePass. No, it was
Speaker 8:  The greatest thing ever. MoviePass MoviePass MoviePass,
Speaker 8:  the popular movie ticket app, MoviePass, we remember them.
Speaker 8:  Whatever happened to those guys?
Speaker 2:  It's a story about wild corporate greed, about a lot of
Speaker 2:  bad decisions and I think at its core it's about how two black
Speaker 2:  founders found themselves ousted from their own company and really their
Speaker 2:  own story. By a couple of fast talking wheeling and dealing
Speaker 2:  white dudes,
Speaker 9:  I was like, we need to pump the brakes a little bit.
Speaker 10:  I just thought that it would be better if he wasn't a part of the team.
Speaker 9:  It's like the heart of MoviePass.
Speaker 8:  The deeper you got in, the more you realize
Speaker 9:  All of this was part of a bigger story.
Speaker 2:  The doc is fascinating. I really recommend everyone watch it. Whether or
Speaker 2:  not you still have your Red MoviePass card lying around. A couple of days
Speaker 2:  after I watched the doc, I got on a call with two people to talk about it.
Speaker 9:  Stacey Spikes co-founder and CEO of MoviePass.
Speaker 9:  My
Speaker 11:  Name is Muta Ali and I'm a film director.
Speaker 2:  I should point out by the way that Muta Ali is the director of this film
Speaker 2:  also, just in case that wasn't clear, this is sort of a spoiler
Speaker 2:  I guess, but the bones of the early MoviePass story is this.
Speaker 2:  Stacey and his co-founder Hamme Watt started MoviePass in 2011
Speaker 2:  and it's more expensive than it turned out to be. It's doing okay. They have
Speaker 2:  about 20,000 subscribers not taking over the world, but coming along,
Speaker 2:  they hired this guy, Mitch Lowe, who says he was a co-founder of Netflix,
Speaker 2:  but that turns out to not really be the case for interesting reasons, who
Speaker 2:  then links MoviePass up with a company called Helios and Matheson and
Speaker 2:  its CEO Ted Farnsworth who injects a bunch of marketing money
Speaker 2:  into MoviePass in order to help it grow. And along the way,
Speaker 2:  Mitch Lowe and Ted Farnsworth start testing ideas to see how
Speaker 2:  they might help the thing grow into the stratosphere.
Speaker 9:  We had grown to 20,000 subs and if you go and you look at
Speaker 9:  the Netflix growth curve it has is long slow
Speaker 9:  arc, and then there's this hockey puck, it just starts to take off.
Speaker 9:  And we had a very similar trajectory in that we were a
Speaker 9:  multimillion dollar revenue company. We weren't that far from
Speaker 9:  profitability, we were at a $30 price point. We
Speaker 9:  knew we were in the ballpark, but we got there with no advertising
Speaker 9:  was only word of mouth. And so we had never had an ad
Speaker 9:  budget. And so really it was, we had figured out what
Speaker 9:  our customer acquisition cost was. We wanted to
Speaker 9:  do the deal just to get ad budget but still grow with the
Speaker 9:  right per month subscription price. And so
Speaker 9:  that's what you wanted to do. You you needed to leave the garage
Speaker 9:  and you had a a really hardcore fan base that people
Speaker 9:  that just loved the service and it was break even. And
Speaker 9:  so now great add that. Well, it broke apart
Speaker 9:  when HMMY, they were coming in and they secretly
Speaker 9:  ran a test and Mitch had given them access
Speaker 9:  to our login page and they went
Speaker 9:  online and they put the new price point up and tested it.
Speaker 9:  We thought our site had been hacked and we were like, Hey,
Speaker 9:  our site's been hacked. Somebody just put up a landing page for 10 bucks
Speaker 9:  and and they were like, no, no, no. Mitch gave Ted and his
Speaker 9:  team access to the website landing page and no one ever
Speaker 9:  told us or the engineering team. And so when you clicked on the button,
Speaker 9:  it didn't let you sign up. They were just using it to gauge interest
Speaker 9:  and they were like, we've got a hit. And I said, well, if you wanna make
Speaker 9:  it even bigger, make it five bucks a month. If you want to make it bigger
Speaker 9:  than that, make it $1 a month. I said, make it 99 cents.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, giving money away is pretty easy, right? I kept thinking that, watching
Speaker 2:  this, that like, oh, if you just give people money, they'll take it. Of course,
Speaker 2:  course. And you'll be very successful at giving people money
Speaker 9:  And it's a race to the bottom when they, you have no competitors like, well,
Speaker 9:  but why? Why don't you walk your way down in price?
Speaker 2:  10 bucks a month for all the movies you can watch was just never going to
Speaker 2:  work. To be clear, it was awesome for moviegoers and one of my favorite
Speaker 2:  things about the doc is all the folks in it who saw hundreds of movies
Speaker 2:  for a fraction of the price. I love that for moviegoers, but it was never
Speaker 2:  sustainable Low. And Farnsworth had this big idea about
Speaker 2:  collecting data about those moviegoers and then selling it back to
Speaker 2:  theater chains. And eventually they seemed to think MoviePass would get
Speaker 2:  so big and so powerful that they'd be able to negotiate a piece of
Speaker 2:  ticket sales and even concessions from those theater chains. That
Speaker 2:  didn't happen even at the time. We all kind of knew it wasn't gonna happen.
Speaker 2:  And just in case you think that's 2020 hindsight, here is a clip from a
Speaker 2:  VERGE video in July of 2018.
Speaker 12:  I mean, look, the whole thing really is a mess. And it comes down to the
Speaker 12:  fact that VPA doesn't make money. The company hopes that when it hits a
Speaker 12:  certain subscriber base size, all the math will magically work out, but
Speaker 12:  in the meantime, it's burning through cash, causing the stock price of its
Speaker 12:  parent company to plummet. The fix apparently seems to be to get its customers
Speaker 12:  to just stop going to movies or if they do to pay up.
Speaker 2:  That last point is a good one, by the way. At one point to stop the money
Speaker 2:  bleeding, MoviePass started to create weird new rules for what you
Speaker 2:  can see and when. And its executives are actually under investigation
Speaker 2:  for even doing worse things like allegedly breaking the
Speaker 2:  product on purpose so that people would stop using it at big movies. The
Speaker 2:  whole thing was just a mess. And a big part of the MoviePass movie crash
Speaker 2:  story is Stacey saying that aloud internally and getting
Speaker 2:  pushed out of the door for it.
Speaker 9:  You had the founder who built the plane saying it can't
Speaker 9:  handle these G-forces. There's no way the math is gonna work.
Speaker 9:  What made it worse to me is you had
Speaker 9:  customers saying, I am willing to pay more to
Speaker 9:  help you be solvent. Like when your customer base
Speaker 9:  is saying that, that's crazy, right? If people are like, this
Speaker 9:  is so awesome. I went to 400 movies last year,
Speaker 9:  please charge me more because I know I'm saving a lot of money and
Speaker 9:  I'm still, I've got so much upside, I'll pay you a hundred bucks a month
Speaker 9:  and I'm still saving money. And when your customer base is
Speaker 9:  saying that and your founder is saying that, then the
Speaker 9:  writing's on the wall and that's part of the plan. You figure
Speaker 9:  it out, you experiment and you find the right place. Great. You
Speaker 9:  found an entry point that consumers love it now find
Speaker 9:  a profitable place to be at. And if that's 30 bucks
Speaker 9:  a month, yeah, you might lose a third of these people, but you're still the
Speaker 9:  biggest subscription company in the world. So for theatrical, so
Speaker 9:  I, that was the hard part was just adjust your pricing.
Speaker 9:  It's like, what's wrong with that? Yeah, you're fired. Get out.
Speaker 2:  Part of the reason I've always been interested in the MoviePass story is
Speaker 2:  that the rough shape of that arc is something we've seen
Speaker 2:  so many times in tech. You prioritize growth at all
Speaker 2:  costs, you lose a giant amount of money and then something,
Speaker 2:  something you'll become so big and so powerful that you can either raise
Speaker 2:  prices or find new ways to make money. That's the Uber story,
Speaker 2:  that's the Lyft story, that's the bird story, that's the Instacart story,
Speaker 2:  that's the TikTok story. On and on and on. Sometimes it works,
Speaker 2:  usually it doesn't. It definitely didn't for MoviePass. And in fact I
Speaker 2:  think MoviePass might have sort of speed run that whole story
Speaker 2:  quicker than just about anybody. The other kind of tech
Speaker 2:  trope about MoviePass that kept jumping out to me was the whole fast talking
Speaker 2:  founder with big ideas who might be full of crap, but everybody keeps listening
Speaker 2:  to anyway thing, which is obviously a staple of Silicon
Speaker 2:  Valley. And for Mu Ali poking at that idea, and
Speaker 2:  in this case who played that part for MoviePass was a big part of the
Speaker 2:  MoviePass documentary.
Speaker 11:  When I was doing research, a lot of people in social media who were
Speaker 11:  trying to discover what's the real story behind MoviePass, some of them
Speaker 11:  were speaking with the understanding that Mitch Low
Speaker 11:  and Ted Farnsworth were really the founders. They were speaking and
Speaker 11:  having these deep dives into MoviePass and not even mentioning Stacy.
Speaker 11:  And I felt that they might need to
Speaker 11:  enter the story through their perspective. It serves us in a couple ways
Speaker 11:  because it's a little bit of a reveal for people who don't know. It
Speaker 11:  might make some people uncomfortable who do know and maybe, oh, do these
Speaker 11:  filmmakers even know who the real founders of MoviePass are? And they question
Speaker 11:  that and hopefully keep watching and not assume the work. But
Speaker 11:  it also plays into part of the premise which kind of revealed
Speaker 11:  itself in a more crystallized form once we were later on in
Speaker 11:  production, is it has to do with racial bias and people's assumptions about
Speaker 11:  who plays what role, especially in a tech company. And maybe if you did
Speaker 11:  enter this story, assuming that, okay, yeah, yeah, Mitch is
Speaker 11:  the leader and Stacey's just kind of complaining and maybe he doesn't know
Speaker 11:  how to ride this rocket ship like Mitch does. You know, because Mitch
Speaker 11:  is the founder of Netflix and all of a sudden your biases
Speaker 11:  played against you and then you're like, oh, maybe I need to rethink how
Speaker 11:  I was thinking about this. And, and so that little pivot in in terms
Speaker 11:  of the plot structure or that little inverse order helps play
Speaker 11:  into that. I will say that it was a battle internally. You know, I didn't,
Speaker 11:  you know, this is a collaborative thing and so I at first
Speaker 11:  didn't want to start the story that way, but then there's an actual
Speaker 11:  arguable point someone could make that we need to start with the excitement.
Speaker 11:  We need to start with the millions of people coming into MoviePass.
Speaker 11:  And in my mind, part of me is like, well, you can't look over
Speaker 11:  Stacey and I amazing, like all these 10 years of development they did before
Speaker 11:  that. And so it was a lot of back and forth and, and I actually needed to
Speaker 11:  see it done both ways before I actually
Speaker 11:  was on board with this little trick because I think it was Archie
Speaker 11:  Gibs who suggested it to me that, oh, maybe we should trick people at the
Speaker 11:  very beginning. And I was like, I don't know exactly what that would do
Speaker 11:  to me in terms of how I feel about this story. And I didn't like
Speaker 11:  it until I decided to like roll it out the way that
Speaker 11:  we did, you know, and like roll it out so that it really
Speaker 11:  emphasizes that Stacey and Jaime were in a position
Speaker 11:  of vulnerability, a position where they weren't in control of the ship
Speaker 11:  and okay, that's normal. They're not the founders. And then you realize,
Speaker 11:  oh, they are the founders and they're not in position to drive this thing.
Speaker 11:  And then you might feel a little bit more concerned about them. And so it,
Speaker 11:  it was a lot involved. It was a lot involved and I'm glad we ended up doing
Speaker 11:  that the way, 'cause it's kind of fun.
Speaker 2:  It really does work. It's, it's quite a, it's quite a twist, whatever, 17
Speaker 2:  and a half minutes into the movie. Yeah. Stacy, how did that part of the
Speaker 2:  process feel? I don't know how involved you were kind of with the, the overall
Speaker 2:  production, but like watching a lot of the sort of twists and turns of it
Speaker 2:  play out again all these years later. Obviously it, it hasn't gone away.
Speaker 2:  You've, you've been involved, this is the thing you lived through, but how
Speaker 2:  does it feel to see all of it sort of put into one place in order?
Speaker 9:  I mean, I think it was what Mutali did. So I've seen,
Speaker 9:  you know, WeWork and Theranos and all of them, I think we
Speaker 9:  all kinda travel in a pack and we watch these things. And
Speaker 9:  I think what he did was closer to the
Speaker 9:  Steve Jobs Apple story because it's the only thing, you know, they had a
Speaker 9:  lot more airtime on CNBC or
Speaker 9:  M-S-N-B-C or all of the different shows that they were on Yahoo Finance
Speaker 9:  where they were being presented as that and called themselves the founders.
Speaker 9:  So whoever thought of it, or whichever way it is a master
Speaker 9:  stroke in storytelling, 'cause it's not straight linear and
Speaker 9:  you know, a third of the way through it's then brings you back
Speaker 9:  to the beginning to the origin story. I thought it was a master stroke. He
Speaker 9:  did make me nervous the first 15 minutes.
Speaker 9:  I was like, he was sitting next to me in the theater when I was seeing it
Speaker 9:  the first time and he got a couple the side eye glances
Speaker 9:  like, and he and he literally said, just wait for it. Wait for it.
Speaker 9:  'cause I didn't know what was happening. And he literally had to tell me,
Speaker 9:  hang on, because I wanted to pause the film and
Speaker 9:  go have a conversation
Speaker 2:  In the first cut. He should have just cut you out entirely just as a, just
Speaker 2:  as a big, just really make you sweat for a while.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. He, my wife was there with me and she, she goes, did they know you
Speaker 9:  were the founder? And I go, yes. I said, yes, hang on.
Speaker 11:  He waited until the end. We were at almost, I think picture lock by the
Speaker 11:  time Stacey saw it. So it wasn't like he had a big chance to change
Speaker 11:  much. So it was, it was do or die at that point. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  One thing I've always wondered about MoviePass is could it have worked
Speaker 2:  if they hadn't grown too fast, burned money at unprecedented rates, made
Speaker 2:  a series of ridiculous bad decisions. Is there a
Speaker 2:  stable idea underneath here? Both Mutali and Stacey
Speaker 2:  agreed that the $10 a month thing killed MoviePass. But
Speaker 2:  both seemed to think that it didn't necessarily have to,
Speaker 11:  I think there were a series of, of failures that took place that allowed
Speaker 11:  MoviePass to, to crash in a way that it did. The biggest though,
Speaker 11:  I think is having 9 95 as that price point for promotional
Speaker 11:  purposes turning into this is our price point forever.
Speaker 11:  And I wonder, Stacy, you know, I think you said it was 48 hours
Speaker 11:  when you had the price at 9 95 and then you gained
Speaker 11:  175,000 new subscribers in two days. If you had
Speaker 11:  cut it off, then maybe that would've been the secret to
Speaker 11:  success. 'cause you would've gotten that marketing boost. Or, or or what
Speaker 11:  do you think? Yeah,
Speaker 9:  I, I think, and we talked about it, we said great, turn that off.
Speaker 9:  Tell everyone this is a promotional price point and
Speaker 9:  just give 'em a heads up. This is a promotional price point. You're all month
Speaker 9:  to month. At some point this will normalize but enjoy it
Speaker 9:  for now, right? Yeah. And then I would take certain
Speaker 9:  segments and I would've said, these people are going up to 30, like test
Speaker 9:  different zones and different things. Test your different price points,
Speaker 9:  see what elasticity you have. If we go up to
Speaker 9:  $50, how high is the churn? If we're at $30 or if
Speaker 9:  we're at 25, but what's the lowest we can go based on the behavior
Speaker 9:  we're seeing? And then you move your price and you're gonna get some churn.
Speaker 9:  But you got so many people excited off the original idea
Speaker 9:  that they keep going and that's all you had to do. And you,
Speaker 9:  and we would be sitting here talking about a really big
Speaker 9:  company, a big global company. That was
Speaker 9:  way 'cause in a MC or Regal would never have been able to catch up
Speaker 9:  to you.
Speaker 2:  To be fair. Of course Stacey believes all of that. He's actually the CEO
Speaker 2:  of MoviePass again, after being ousted from the company in 2018,
Speaker 2:  it went through all of its disasters. He bought the company back in
Speaker 2:  2021 and actually relaunched it last year. There were a bunch of
Speaker 2:  new things about it, some Web3 stuff that I thought
Speaker 2:  was kind of weird at the time, but doesn't really seem to have come to anything.
Speaker 2:  But it operates very differently
Speaker 9:  From a technology standpoint. We had some of the innovation, so we
Speaker 9:  had our first year back and we were profitable and we added
Speaker 9:  a credit system where we knew we needed a governor
Speaker 9:  to be between the consumer, the product,
Speaker 9:  and the marketplace. And in any marketplace you
Speaker 9:  need to show value to the consumer so that the consumer
Speaker 9:  can have alignment with the company. And in version one,
Speaker 9:  whether you went to say an A MC
Speaker 9:  where there maybe wasn't a partnership or you went to A, B and
Speaker 9:  B where there was in the app, you couldn't see the
Speaker 9:  difference. And though we were getting wholesale pricing from
Speaker 9:  someone else, there was no display of that. So this version
Speaker 9:  we simply said let's use a credit system to show
Speaker 9:  alignment when the price is cheaper and say
Speaker 9:  let's motivate them by giving them a certain number of credits
Speaker 9:  so that now they are aligned with saving money the way we are aligned
Speaker 9:  with saving money. That didn't exist in V one, but we knew
Speaker 9:  that was the pathway because we were beginning to test that in 2016.
Speaker 9:  And so when I said, guys, let me tell you how to get there A
Speaker 9:  raise the price B, we have this variable pricing capability,
Speaker 9:  they were like, no, this $10 price point is so awesome. We're
Speaker 9:  adding a quarter of a million. I'm like, you're losing $30 per person per
Speaker 9:  month. So I think that the technology,
Speaker 9:  it's subscription. This isn't, this isn't new. Since newspapers
Speaker 9:  were born, we've had subscription businesses. So a lot
Speaker 9:  of, it's not new, but the way to use the tech is
Speaker 9:  new. So now we built it with machine learning and AI engines,
Speaker 9:  which is very different. So I think the technology was there, it's just
Speaker 9:  stupid, was driving the bus and that's all that happened.
Speaker 2:  The problem with that theory though is that the movie theater industry looks
Speaker 2:  really different now than it did in 2018 or 2011
Speaker 2:  for that matter when they first started working on this. We're in the midst
Speaker 2:  of one of the worst box office runs in a long time.
Speaker 2:  We just had the worst memorial day at the movie theater in three decades.
Speaker 2:  And by at least one measure that I saw, ticket sales are 22%
Speaker 2:  below where they were at this point a year ago. And a full
Speaker 2:  41% down from 2019. It's kind of like the
Speaker 2:  pandemic happened and movie theaters just never came back, which makes
Speaker 2:  sense, right? We're streaming more, we're on Netflix more, we're home more.
Speaker 2:  Maybe movie theaters are just over. This is not remotely
Speaker 2:  surprising to anyone who is like living life and watching TV more
Speaker 2:  often, but Stacey doesn't think it's the case. This guy loves the
Speaker 2:  movies.
Speaker 9:  I'm not a filmmaker, but I love and respect
Speaker 9:  what people like Mutali will spend
Speaker 9:  3, 4, 5, 6, 7 years on bringing
Speaker 9:  a 90 minute story to screens and telling
Speaker 9:  this they are our prophets, they are
Speaker 9:  our freedom fighters. They bring stories that
Speaker 9:  otherwise would never get seen. It's such an important
Speaker 9:  art form that is under attack that if you know you
Speaker 9:  have the burden of responsibility, that you have technologies that can
Speaker 9:  double the attendance of movie going and you
Speaker 9:  can create efficiencies in a, in a sector that
Speaker 9:  doesn't work with itself. When you see a Netflix, they can go
Speaker 9:  into a space, dominate that space from top to bottom
Speaker 9:  because they have the direct to consumer relationship and no one
Speaker 9:  ever built anything from the consumer point of view and
Speaker 9:  empowering the consumer. So I think it's a beautiful moment in time
Speaker 9:  because I don't want that cinema died on my watch, you know
Speaker 9:  that it was a simple technology upgrade. I want the
Speaker 9:  Mutali of the world to forever be able to tell stories
Speaker 9:  in such a powerful medium. And theaters
Speaker 9:  shouldn't be these things on their last legs. It's just
Speaker 9:  stupidity and arrogance and pride that's preventing
Speaker 9:  technology from unlocking such great opportunities.
Speaker 9:  We are in such a beautiful moment that if we can get out of the way,
Speaker 9:  I think that storytelling will go to the next level. 'cause
Speaker 9:  I think we're on The Verge of a new golden age of cinema
Speaker 9:  from we see how storytelling
Speaker 9:  creation is just mind blowingly changing
Speaker 9:  and you see how even the sight and sound experience in the theater is
Speaker 9:  changing, but what it takes to get people there
Speaker 9:  isn't changing. And that's the part that we are focused on and I feel blessed
Speaker 9:  to be able to have the privilege to be able to do that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, basically. Other than Dune, it's been a disaster at theaters
Speaker 2:  this year. And I'm curious from both of your perspectives, like what do we
Speaker 2:  do next with movie theaters? I agree it could be easier. I agree buying it
Speaker 2:  should, it could be cheaper, all this stuff. But I do wonder, does something
Speaker 2:  fundamental in the movie going experience need to change
Speaker 2:  here?
Speaker 9:  Cinema has a PR problem, it doesn't have an attendance problem.
Speaker 9:  You notice that this past weekend, okay,
Speaker 9:  more people went in four days to the movies
Speaker 9:  than everyone who will attend in NFL game
Speaker 9:  in an entire year in four days. That's how many
Speaker 9:  people went to the movies. Okay, you don't get at a football
Speaker 9:  game. They don't tell you how many tickets are sold at every
Speaker 9:  single game. I think that we need to stop reporting
Speaker 9:  box office numbers because we're focused on the wrong things. We're not focused
Speaker 9:  on movie making, we're focused on movie going. And it
Speaker 9:  doesn't matter how great the movie was because most really
Speaker 9:  big films didn't gross at the box office,
Speaker 9:  over time they became part of our culture. And so we
Speaker 9:  are focused on the wrong thing because everything is determined by
Speaker 9:  one number. What was the gross of the box office this
Speaker 9:  weekend compared to last year or the year before? We need to stop
Speaker 9:  reporting those numbers and get back to the days. When I was a kid,
Speaker 9:  you didn't report grosses of Star Wars. It wasn't until
Speaker 9:  IMDB and certain other things came online that my
Speaker 9:  mom would call up and go, oh you know what's such and such gross this weekend?
Speaker 9:  We became obsessed with that and you'll hear even with YouTube
Speaker 9:  and a lot of creators, they say, I stopped watching
Speaker 9:  my view number, I started focusing on content and I
Speaker 9:  started focusing on doing the right content and it will
Speaker 9:  take care of itself. Movie going is healthy when you
Speaker 9:  stop comparing it to these numbers that every Monday morning
Speaker 9:  you have a report card that you failed. No sports do this,
Speaker 9:  no other industry, the travel industry, they report
Speaker 9:  quarterly where some single companies, but you do not
Speaker 9:  get group wide grosses every weekend on a
Speaker 9:  business you don't have it. So I think that's detrimental to us. It gives
Speaker 9:  us a very big PR problem.
Speaker 11:  Definitely.
Speaker 2:  Definitely. That's a good take. I have not heard that before. I actually
Speaker 2:  really agree with that. Mus Ali, what do you think are movie theaters? You're,
Speaker 2:  you're making stuff for the internet, who cares about movie theaters, right?
Speaker 11:  No, I care about movie theaters. I the most fun I've had out this year
Speaker 11:  has been at movie theaters, but it was screening MoviePass movie crash.
Speaker 11:  So I think that's probably why. But that in-person experience is
Speaker 11:  something that will always be better than watching it at
Speaker 11:  home. And speaking of Dune, I just watched Dune two for the first time
Speaker 11:  with my brother and we watched it on a TV and
Speaker 11:  I wish that we had watched it in the theater. Maybe the second time I felt
Speaker 11:  that way, like oh this movie was so great. I wish that I'd seen it in
Speaker 11:  the theater out with other people. That sort of glow that happens
Speaker 11:  when you go and that that communal experience that Stacy was
Speaker 11:  referring to is something special that
Speaker 11:  culturally I think we're going turn back toward after
Speaker 11:  we get enough of sort of the convenience of watching movies on our phone.
Speaker 11:  And I think movie going is still gonna thrive and I think maybe it's just
Speaker 11:  time for us to be reminded of how special it's,
Speaker 2:  I like it. I will say Dune two ripped in theaters. No. Like it's one of
Speaker 2:  the maybe the best theater going experience, not to make you feel bad. One
Speaker 2:  of the best movie theater experiences I've had in a very long time. The movie
Speaker 2:  is just so
Speaker 9:  Loud, it's still playing some places. See it in Dolby Atmos.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, because the sound design in there is just insane.
Speaker 9:  I haven't seen anybody's house that can do Dolby Atmos.
Speaker 2:  He's right about that I think. And I agree that there is still something
Speaker 2:  to be said for going to the movies. I certainly
Speaker 15:  non-starter kind of spot for renters. Am I wrong in that? Let me
Speaker 15:  know 'cause I would love to be proven wrong in that. Like please I would
Speaker 15:  desperately love that, but I don't know. You let me know. Thanks. Bye.
Speaker 2:  All right, well ask and you shall receive Gen Tui. How are you?
Speaker 16:  I'm good thanks. Hi Chris too. Very excited to answer this question 'cause
Speaker 16:  it's a topic I get asked a lot. So yeah, lots to dive
Speaker 16:  into in your question there. The first one I'm gonna say
Speaker 16:  renters. Yes, there is lots of great stuff you can do,
Speaker 16:  especially if you have Home Assistant. I mean Chris, you're already set
Speaker 16:  up pretty well for doing some cool stuff. I'd actually say there's sort
Speaker 16:  of two answers here. Like if you are a renter, there are options.
Speaker 16:  If you're a renter with Home Assistant, there are way more options.
Speaker 2:  Oh, interesting. Okay. Just
Speaker 16:  Because you know, it sounds like Chris is maybe, you know, quite technically
Speaker 16:  advanced.
Speaker 2:  I mean if you have Home Assistant, I think that's, we're safe to assume on
Speaker 16:  A raspberry pie. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Safe to assume. Yeah, you're
Speaker 16:  Doing well, you know what you're doing. And then also he mentioned Apple
Speaker 16:  Home, so I'm assuming that's his main platform that does narrow
Speaker 16:  your choices down. But then Home Assistant widens them back up again.
Speaker 16:  But just to answer that overall question about renters, I do think there
Speaker 16:  are more and more options for renters. And you mentioned door locks. Door
Speaker 16:  locks actually are in a better space for renters and they have been for
Speaker 16:  a long time. There's the August wifi smart lock, which has been sort of
Speaker 16:  our number one choice for renters because it's retrofit. So you are not
Speaker 16:  having to replace your door lock, which your landlord may not like,
Speaker 16:  but you still get to control the lock in a way that is useful
Speaker 16:  for, for a smart home perspective.
Speaker 2:  That's the one that just goes like on over top of the existing lock, right?
Speaker 16:  Right of the back of your deadbolt. Yeah, you actually, you do have to remove
Speaker 16:  the thumb term, but everything else stays as is. That
Speaker 2:  Is pretty clever.
Speaker 16:  Which makes it very easy. Also means you can take it with you when you,
Speaker 16:  if you move to another apartment and also they've just, Yale has just come
Speaker 16:  out with a new retrofit smart lock, so there's another good
Speaker 16:  option there. And they both, both Yale and August who are owned by the same
Speaker 16:  company and their sister brands, they have come out with a new keypad
Speaker 16:  that has a touch fingerprint reader in it. So you can now
Speaker 16:  use a fingerprint to unlock your August wifi smart lock.
Speaker 2:  That is the thing about the smart home that feels the most sci-fi to me by
Speaker 2:  the way. The fingerprint thing, it just, yeah, it's, it's the most like mission
Speaker 2:  impossible thing that I have tried in the smart home and I, I cannot recommend
Speaker 2:  it enough
Speaker 16:  And that, well they've now got facial recognition for smart locks. So
Speaker 16:  I haven't tried that yet, but that came out at CES. But yes, the F and the
Speaker 16:  fingerprint is great. It's really easy. It's my favorite way of unlocking
Speaker 16:  the door. Apple Home Key is also a really useful way if you use Apple
Speaker 16:  Home. Unfortunately there are not any retrofit door locks that work with
Speaker 16:  Apple Home Key right now because it's all inside the house. So
Speaker 16:  there's nothing to do the NFC. Right. Although these new
Speaker 16:  keypads do have NFC in them. So it is potential, we may see Home
Speaker 16:  Key come to some of these retrofit locks. And that brings me to the second
Speaker 16:  retrofit lock I would recommend, which is actually coming out this month.
Speaker 16:  And when I say recommend, I haven't tested it yet, but I have tested some
Speaker 16:  of their past products and they've been good. A carer is coming out with
Speaker 16:  a retrofit smart lock. So the same concept, you can
Speaker 16:  just replace the thumb term on your deadbolt and then you put
Speaker 16:  a, you can put a keypad out in the front of your house so that you can access
Speaker 16:  it. That also has a fingerprint reader that does have NFC in.
Speaker 16:  And I would not be surprised if at some point in future that could
Speaker 16:  support Home Key. 'cause a Cara already does support Home Key in some of
Speaker 16:  its products. So there's lots of options now they didn't use to be. So
Speaker 16:  that's nice for Home Kit, apple Home compatible
Speaker 16:  retrofit Smart locks. Do
Speaker 2:  You think that's a good, like third place to start the lock thing?
Speaker 16:  I do. I think locks are actually my favorite smart home device.
Speaker 16:  Most useful, easiest for everyone to use. Not complicated
Speaker 16:  mostly, and provide real value. You know, being
Speaker 16:  able to unlock and lock your door remotely if there's a problem. There's
Speaker 16:  so much value I think in smart locks and the safety issue.
Speaker 16:  It's just as easy. I think if you're concerned about someone hacking your
Speaker 16:  smart door lock don't be, it's just, just as easy for someone to break a
Speaker 16:  window. It's easier, much easier, sorry to break a window
Speaker 16:  than it is to hack your smart lock. And in terms of whether someone's gonna
Speaker 16:  knock your door down again, regular door lock, smart lock, not a big difference.
Speaker 16:  So yeah, I I, I would not worry about the safety side unless you have someone
Speaker 16:  who's really smart, a big hacker who's after you, in which case maybe
Speaker 16:  fair. But in terms of the third thing, I mean it, it differs I think
Speaker 16:  for renters perhaps from people that own their homes because you
Speaker 16:  know, a smart thermostat is a big one, right? Energy management, you know,
Speaker 16:  bringing that into your smart home. I would say if a smart thermostat is,
Speaker 16:  the research shows that the top three devices people use
Speaker 16:  in their smart homes as smart video doorbells, smart cameras, which
Speaker 16:  are kind of the same smart thermostats and then robot vacuums.
Speaker 16:  Oh, interesting, okay. As well as smart light bulbs are in there at number
Speaker 16:  four than the robot vacuums. So you've already got the smart light. I mean,
Speaker 16:  a video doorbell is, you can do a battery powered one as a renter, so
Speaker 16:  that's a good option. Yep. Door locks actually, you know, aren't in the
Speaker 16:  top categories. I think it's just still, still a bit
Speaker 16:  of a niche. But I do find it, like I said, one of the most useful
Speaker 16:  smart devices in my home and you use it every day and yeah, there's a
Speaker 16:  lot of innovation in this space too. But for Chris,
Speaker 16:  who has, I think, you know, that is probably an more advanced smart home
Speaker 16:  user, what I would recommend as like the third thing based on what he
Speaker 16:  has is more automation. Mm. So that is using
Speaker 16:  sensors, making your home smart, not just having a few smart devices in
Speaker 16:  it. And because he has Home Assistant, you know, using devices
Speaker 16:  like motion sensors, contact sensors, smart plugs, smart
Speaker 16:  buttons to kind of bring everything together and work more
Speaker 16:  seamlessly. Going back to a carer who I mentioned at the beginning, that's
Speaker 16:  a really good option for someone that's using Apple Home and Home Assistant
Speaker 16:  because you can actually, the most of their ZigBee devices will pair directly
Speaker 16:  to Home Assistant and they have great inexpensive motion sensors, smart
Speaker 16:  buttons. So things like he can have his lights turn on when he
Speaker 16:  opens his front door. Or what would be really fun for him to try actually
Speaker 16:  is the FP two Presence Sensor, which is in a car device. And
Speaker 16:  that in I think works really well in apartment setting because I've
Speaker 16:  struggled to get it to work in my home because I have so many people in
Speaker 16:  my home fair. But it uses millimeter wave sensing, which is a really
Speaker 16:  interesting development in smart home sensing, radar sensing to
Speaker 16:  use presence detection versus motion detection. So if he's sitting in his
Speaker 16:  living room watching TV or your lights won't turn off because you haven't
Speaker 16:  moved. Right. So, and I, I find that that that's a really interesting
Speaker 16:  sort of development in the smart home. And for Chris, the FP two does
Speaker 16:  work with Home Assistant, we can include in the show notes as this great
Speaker 16:  blog that this one guy wrote exactly about how to integrate it with Home
Speaker 16:  Assistant and what benefits there are. So, you know, for,
Speaker 16:  for Chris, I think more automation, you know, making your home smarter
Speaker 16:  because things like sensors, contact sensors, you can take 'em with you
Speaker 16:  when you leave too. But yeah, so there's lots. And then the one, the
Speaker 16:  final thing I would say that a lot of people are interested in and works
Speaker 16:  for both renters and homeowners is a smart security system.
Speaker 16:  There's a lot of benefit there, especially 'cause if you can integrate with
Speaker 16:  say your door lock and your video doorbell if you want a video doorbell.
Speaker 16:  So there's a lot the smart home has to offer for renters.
Speaker 2:  And it does seem like, I, I think the stigma that anything beyond
Speaker 2:  the very basics requires opening up your walls, I think is so much less
Speaker 2:  true than it was even just a couple of years ago that a lot of the stuff
Speaker 2:  you're describing used to be a lot of work and now it's a lot of
Speaker 2:  like battery maintenance. And that's kind of it in a lot of these cases,
Speaker 2:  especially like I think about Ring has done a really good job of this, of
Speaker 2:  making it basically that you can just hang a doorbell on your wall
Speaker 2:  and like I have a lot of feelings about people in, especially like apartment
Speaker 2:  buildings and condo buildings who have video doorbells that just go
Speaker 2:  out into the hallway. Yeah. I have a lot of like moral quandaries with
Speaker 2:  that. But the idea of what it can accomplish for you, this stuff in general
Speaker 2:  is a lot simpler than it gets credit for for people. I think now, especially
Speaker 2:  if you've gone through the work to set up a raspberry pie running Home Assistant,
Speaker 2:  like you have the chops to do most of the smart home stuff that is available
Speaker 2:  to you at this point.
Speaker 16:  For sure. Yeah. And there is, there's a lot. And in terms of the doorbell,
Speaker 16:  actually I just, this actually happened last week, so this is news for you
Speaker 16:  on the, the Vergecast. Arlo has some good battery powered
Speaker 16:  doorbells and their first generation one just became
Speaker 16:  HomeKit compatible. Oh, cool. There was only one battery powered doorbell
Speaker 16:  that worked with Apple Home before. That was the A Cara. Now the
Speaker 16:  Arlo essential first gen battery powered doorbell will work
Speaker 16:  with home kits. So not home kit secure video, but with home kits. So Chris,
Speaker 16:  if you were thinking about a video doorbell, those two would be a good option.
Speaker 16:  Cameras are a whole different thing and as you say, especially if you are
Speaker 16:  recording your neighbors walk past your house every morning, but if that's
Speaker 16:  something you're interested in, those are two good options. And a door lock
Speaker 16:  and then motion, get some sensors, get get your house to be really smart.
Speaker 16:  And that's really fun.
Speaker 2:  I think especially if, if you're the type who wants to sort of experiment
Speaker 2:  and play, just adding sensors and smart plugs to everything you can think
Speaker 2:  of opens up so many things. And for me it's like most of the stuff that I've
Speaker 2:  tried ends up being sort of useless, but just the, it's just fun to
Speaker 2:  play with and be like, okay, whenever I get to like the fourth
Speaker 2:  step to the basement, what should turn on? I don't even know. Let's just
Speaker 2:  have some stuff happen and it's just, yeah, just that And, and the sensors
Speaker 2:  are cheap and they're everywhere and they're easy to pick up and move around
Speaker 2:  and I think, I think that's a good call. Just like buy some sensors,
Speaker 2:  spend a Saturday playing with them and and see what works for you. I like
Speaker 2:  that a lot. See
Speaker 16:  What happens.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Awesome. All right Chris, I hope that helps, Jen. Thank you as always.
Speaker 2:  Thank
Speaker 16:  You.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everyone who is
Speaker 2:  on the show and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on everything
Speaker 2:  we talked about at The Verge dot com. We have Chris's Sonos reviews, we have
Speaker 2:  a MoviePass MovieCrash review, everything you want, plus again, lots going
Speaker 2:  on in tech. It's WWDC next week. There's lots to see. Check out The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com and as always, if you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or headphones
Speaker 2:  you think we should buy instead of the ace, email us at vergecast at The
Speaker 2:  Verge dot com. Call the hotline eight six six VERGE one one. I particularly
Speaker 2:  want to hear what you're excited about at WW DC. We have a bunch of WW
Speaker 2:  DC stuff coming, lots of AI stuff. Presumed for next week, a few of us
Speaker 2:  will be on the ground, really wanna know what you think is coming and whether
Speaker 2:  you're excited about what we're gonna see from Apple in this next year. So
Speaker 2:  hit us up Vergecast at The Verge dot com. 8 6 6 VERGE one one. we love
Speaker 2:  hearing from you. This show is produced by Andrew Marino, Liam James,