# Transcript
ID: 2106f450-7883-49b6-8ecf-44b4a08c0fbf
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8975917554762748280/-5716198595045912385/s93290-US-4751s-1721737163.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of configuration changes:
The Verge's Tom Warren joins the show to to talk about the story and legacy of the CrowdStrike crash.
CrowdStrike and Microsoft: all the latest news on the global IT outage
Major Windows BSOD issue hits banks, airlines, and TV broadcasters
What is CrowdStrike, and what happened?
CrowdStrike’s faulty update crashed 8.5 million Windows devices, says Microsoft
CrowdStrike outage: Photos, videos, and tales of IT workers fixing BSODs
Then we talk with The Verge's Victoria Song and Zombies, Run creator Adrian Hon about making exercising fun without making it competitive and awful.
Zombies, Run
Adrian Hon’s Substack
Finally, the Apple Watch will let you rest
This walking app let me whack my co-workers with a baseball bat
Ignore your fitness tracker and walk to Mordor instead
Finally, we answer a hotline question about handheld gadgets for new parents — because there's a lot of time to kill when there's a baby around.
Backbone One review: the best mobile gaming controller yet
Handheld consoles are the future of gaming
Holedown
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (18 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To, The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Configuration Changes.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend David Pierce and I am in my basement as always
Speaker 2:  doing a shipping day. So I'm going on vacation at the end of this week. I'm
Speaker 2:  gonna spend two weeks in the outdoors just like staring at trees
Speaker 2:  and not screens. It's gonna be amazing. Can't wait. But what I always try
Speaker 2:  to do before I go on vacation is just like kind of get stuff together. There's
Speaker 2:  nothing worse than coming home to like mess. So trying to
Speaker 2:  get everything cleaned off. And mostly what that means in my particular line
Speaker 2:  of work is just shipping things. One of the great things about this
Speaker 2:  job is you accumulate a lot of gadgets and one of the annoying things about
Speaker 2:  this job is you have to ship them all back. So right now I have like, I have
Speaker 2:  a bunch of tablets on my desk. I have a case for a thing.
Speaker 2:  I don't even know what the thing is. I have, I have a bunch of watch boxes
Speaker 2:  that I have to go back. I see
Speaker 2:  one, two, three, four, five phones that I have
Speaker 2:  to do something with. I have some AR glasses, I have these Amazon
Speaker 2:  Echo frames. I have a camera and I have a Vision Pro
Speaker 2:  and I have, oh, that's another phone. So that's six phones. I have the humane
Speaker 2:  AI pin that I keep meaning to send back. I have two rabbits. They sent me
Speaker 2:  two for some reason. I don't know why. I don't want either one of them. So
Speaker 2:  basically what has going to happen here is I have a very carefully organized
Speaker 2:  thing of packing tape in the utility room over there and I'm going
Speaker 2:  to spend all day shoving things into boxes and then I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  load my car and as I do four or five times a year, I'm going to
Speaker 2:  dump thousands of things into the UPS office
Speaker 2:  all at once. And then it's going to feel like a gigantic weight has lifted
Speaker 2:  off my shoulders. I both hate this and kind of love how it feels at the
Speaker 2:  very end. Anyway, lots to do on The Vergecast. Today
Speaker 2:  we are gonna talk about the crazy thing that happened on Friday when
Speaker 2:  thanks to something happening with CrowdStrike and Windows
Speaker 2:  computers all over the world just went down and broke and it felt
Speaker 2:  like everything from airlines to banks just fell apart all at once. We're
Speaker 2:  gonna talk about what happened, what it means that that can happen, and where
Speaker 2:  we go from here. We're also gonna talk about one of my all time favorite
Speaker 2:  apps called Zombies Run. And we're gonna talk about what that app means
Speaker 2:  for fitness and what it gets right about how we think about
Speaker 2:  quantifying ourselves and tracking things and gamification and
Speaker 2:  everything that feels toxic and wrong with the
Speaker 2:  way that our devices work. Now, why that app feels like
Speaker 2:  none of it, we had a super fun time talking to one of the creators. It's
Speaker 2:  a really good interview. We also have a fun hotline question about handheld
Speaker 2:  gaming, which we've been talking a lot about on this show recently. So lots
Speaker 2:  to get to. All that is coming up in just a second. But I just this
Speaker 2:  second realized that I don't have anywhere near enough actual boxes,
Speaker 2:  which means I have to go, I think to like Home Depot and pay a bunch
Speaker 2:  of money for a bunch of boxes to then pay a bunch of money to ship
Speaker 2:  to someone else. It's a process. Anyway, this is The Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  We'll be right
Speaker 2:  computers that didn't work. Banks were having trouble, airlines were having
Speaker 2:  trouble. It felt like all at once, the whole world just kind of
Speaker 2:  crashed. and it turns out this was something that happened because of a company
Speaker 2:  called CrowdStrike on Windows computers. and it, it has made a lot
Speaker 2:  of people feel a lot of feelings about what it means that
Speaker 2:  we are so reliant on technology and not just technology, but very
Speaker 2:  specific things from very specific companies. And all of it
Speaker 2:  feels so important and infrastructural, but it all also feels fragile.
Speaker 2:  So I wanna talk about what has happened over the last few days, what we've
Speaker 2:  learned and where we might go forward in how we think about
Speaker 2:  computers and how we use them for the most important things going on in the
Speaker 2:  world. Tom Warren on our team has been covering all of this all weekend,
Speaker 2:  I think didn't have a weekend by the sounds of things, so we're gonna get
Speaker 2:  into it. Hi Tom.
Speaker 4:  Hey, good to be back. So
Speaker 2:  You have like an ITish background a little bit. Is this like the confluence
Speaker 2:  of all of your interests these last few days?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, this, this is like, I'm so glad I got out of it more
Speaker 4:  than a decade ago, kind of a incident. Yeah, definitely.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It seems right. So let's rewind back to Friday morning. You're in the
Speaker 2:  uk, I'm in the us So you woke up a few hours earlier
Speaker 2:  than I did and got online. Like describe to me the scenes
Speaker 2:  of Friday morning as you were getting up and getting online
Speaker 4:  Chaos. No, so I woke up late around about 7:00 AM and I
Speaker 4:  had like a couple of people, one I used to work with and then just a good
Speaker 4:  friend who's like very technical messaged me saying, have you seen this
Speaker 4:  in Australia? Like, what, what's going on out there? And I was like, huh,
Speaker 4:  we'll all this. And I, I looked at like the Reddit thread. There was like
Speaker 4:  loads of cis admins complaining and usually that's a good sign of, of
Speaker 4:  any sort of major sort of Windows outages or, or anything
Speaker 4:  related to that is is Reddit, people getting angry essentially.
Speaker 4:  It's a good flags. Yeah. So I saw that. And then there's
Speaker 4:  some like media reports out of Australia about banks being
Speaker 4:  affected, the supermarkets, airlines, you know, all the us the stuff that
Speaker 4:  we've seen. But then it started to spread, right? So I turned
Speaker 4:  on like the tv, you know, quarter past seven to watch like Sky News and,
Speaker 4:  and they weren't running the news and I was like, Hmm, this is weird,
Speaker 4:  huh. And then it came like one of their tech persons had tweeted saying
Speaker 4:  they were offline because some tech issues and then it started to like escalate.
Speaker 4:  It was like some of the airports warning of the initial flights that started
Speaker 4:  around about that time of the day, like 7:00 AM is kinda like the early flights
Speaker 4:  of delays and stuff. And I was like, okay, right, I've gotta figure out what's
Speaker 4:  going on here. And then obviously we saw the CrowdStrike thing and then it
Speaker 4:  all kind of just started spiraling, like you just saw more
Speaker 4:  and more. But at the same time there was a Microsoft Azure
Speaker 4:  cloud outage going on. Oh God, I didn't even know that. It wasn't a huge
Speaker 4:  one. Yeah, it wasn't a huge one, but it was kind of small. So it started
Speaker 4:  out with like everyone blaming Microsoft basically for this outage
Speaker 4:  to start off. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  How quickly did, by the time I was online,
Speaker 2:  CrowdStrike was kind of already in the conversation. It was, yeah, there
Speaker 2:  was a lot of like, right when I became aware of the story, it was kind of
Speaker 2:  at that moment where it was like, okay, this is, this is a CrowdStrike thing.
Speaker 2:  We hadn't quite gotten to, here's what's going on yet. But how did, how did
Speaker 2:  folks figure out that CrowdStrike was the issue here?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think mainly because on Reddit, the people that were posting there,
Speaker 4:  the CIS admins were posting the stuff from CrowdStrike's support,
Speaker 4:  which obviously had to be a CrowdStrike customer to access. It wasn't available
Speaker 4:  publicly. So then it was like, okay, this is what's actually caused it. It's
Speaker 4:  obviously not a Windows problem because not everyone's waking up with this,
Speaker 4:  it's like a select amount of machines, but enough to obviously be
Speaker 4:  causing a problem. and it obviously they issued this update, I think
Speaker 4:  it was like around about like 5:00 AM UK time and then I think it was like
Speaker 4:  an hour and 20 minutes or so near enough when they pulled it.
Speaker 4:  But that was that time when it was like middle of the afternoon or something
Speaker 4:  in Australia, like the peak time for people to all have their machines on
Speaker 4:  with CrowdStrike installed. And they obviously have a quite a big install
Speaker 4:  base there, I guess in Australia. So they got hit the hardest, like initially.
Speaker 4:  I,
Speaker 2:  I think about that with like you, you see the companies that do maintenance
Speaker 2:  or software updates or whatever and they always do them. It's, it's almost
Speaker 2:  always overnight in the us right? So the thing you're describing like 5:00 AM
Speaker 2:  UK time, that's middle of the night in the us Yeah. I
Speaker 2:  I, it had never occurred to me before this, but that's gotta suck if you
Speaker 2:  live in one of these timelines that is like opposite the US and all of these
Speaker 2:  things are happening in the middle of your workday. Yeah. All the time over
Speaker 2:  and over again. So like Australia just getting screwed by software updates
Speaker 2:  left and right here. I never really thought about that for, I'm sorry, Australia,
Speaker 4:  I think they got hit the hardest because I think just all the machines were
Speaker 4:  online right. To, to get this update. So if, and then obviously the
Speaker 4:  European machines a a lot of these machines will be just, you know, people
Speaker 4:  leave the office, they don't turn 'em off for example. These are also
Speaker 4:  critical systems that this is usually installed on. So they're probably pretty
Speaker 4:  much always online. So that's why there was like 8.5 million
Speaker 4:  machines in total affected. We saw some, I feel like there was less in
Speaker 4:  the US affected in terms of like the stuff that we saw in Australia, like
Speaker 4:  the supermarkets and people not being able to get groceries and you know,
Speaker 4:  all those like affecting hospital appointments and stuff. I think there was
Speaker 4:  a little bit less of that in the us The
Speaker 2:  Biggest thing that happened in the US at least anecdotally was the airline
Speaker 2:  stuff.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. And then
Speaker 2:  There was, and that's still ongoing. The graphs that you could see of the
Speaker 2:  planes in the sky was pretty Yeah. Incredible for a few hours,
Speaker 4:  Which usually only happens like they grind. Yeah, they ground, sorry, that
Speaker 4:  many flights usually when it's less something terrible happens, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But that's still ongoing. I think Delta actually said
Speaker 4:  yesterday they're still canceling flights Oh wow. And canceling some today.
Speaker 4:  So that's, I think they've been particularly like worse hit than, than
Speaker 4:  the other major sort of airlines in the US but Okay. Yeah. So that's still,
Speaker 4:  there's still a bit of a fallout going on there. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So with a few days of hindsight, it seems like we have a pretty clear sense
Speaker 2:  of what happened. So just back all the way up, like what, what happened here?
Speaker 2:  What broke? And I guess start with who is CrowdStrike because I think most
Speaker 2:  people reasonably do not and should not have to know Yeah, sure. Who
Speaker 2:  CrowdStrike is. So like start all the way at the beginning, what went wrong
Speaker 2:  here?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They're probably, the only time you've ever heard of CrowdStrike is,
Speaker 4:  is that they sponsor Mercedes s like you watch Formula One then
Speaker 4:  maybe, wait,
Speaker 2:  I knew I had heard that name before. That's so funny. Okay. That's right.
Speaker 2:  That, yeah,
Speaker 4:  Go. and it was that picture of the, the Windows machines that had crashed
Speaker 4:  at the Mercedes F1 garage. Yep. When they, when they're doing the testing
Speaker 4:  and they had CrowdStrike on the T-shirts, it's like, it's just perfect. But
Speaker 4:  yeah, on Friday morning CrowdStrike issued what they call
Speaker 4:  like a content update to their protection system. And CrowdStrike is
Speaker 4:  a third party security firm that just think of it
Speaker 4:  basically as antivirus essentially. It's a lot more sophisticated than that
Speaker 4:  because obviously cybersecurity these days is, is advanced further, but it's,
Speaker 4:  it's a cloud-based solution that pushes updates to machines
Speaker 4:  that pay for this software. And I think it's around about 50 bucks a machine.
Speaker 4:  So it's not cheap like to, to protect your, your system with, with this stuff.
Speaker 4:  So it's usually on critical systems. So that's why
Speaker 4:  you saw such an impact, but yeah. And do you mean
Speaker 2:  Critical systems in the sense of like super secure government
Speaker 2:  computers or just like computers that can't afford to go down or I guess
Speaker 2:  both.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. More, more, more computers that can't really afford to go down. Okay.
Speaker 4:  Like you see in the, all the airport screens were all Windows machines and
Speaker 4:  they're kind of critical for communications to passengers and stuff. So it's
Speaker 4:  not, not critical in the security side potentially, but
Speaker 4:  more the infrastructure side. Got it. Of of things. Yeah. So
Speaker 4:  yeah, they issued a, a regular update, I think it was about 5:00 AM
Speaker 4:  UK time around about then, which is about midnight eastern.
Speaker 4:  And then all the machines started collecting that update because
Speaker 4:  that is the way that this system is designed so that you get these
Speaker 4:  updates so you are protected against any emerging threats. Right. Like
Speaker 4:  you'll get Right.
Speaker 2:  And it's not like a button you have to click on the computer to update. Like,
Speaker 2:  this is one thing I think I've, I've heard some folks having trouble understanding
Speaker 2:  like, this is not an update that appears and you click a thing and
Speaker 2:  your computer reboots No, this is like, and it's designed to happen in the
Speaker 2:  background all the time, right? Yeah. Like this is the kind of update CrowdStrike
Speaker 2:  does constantly, if I understand. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It does these like if not hourly, like daily. Okay. You know, like
Speaker 4:  these are pre frequent updates. So the way that the system works,
Speaker 4:  let's explain that first is that it runs at the very like highest level
Speaker 4:  of windows. So basically in the kernel, which is like a privileged area of
Speaker 4:  Windows that most apps don't touch or, or go near, it's like your
Speaker 4:  anti sheet systems for PC games or, or see this
Speaker 4:  sort of security scanning software is allowed in there. And, and
Speaker 4:  Microsoft allows that. And so they have a driver that
Speaker 4:  runs at the boot of Windows to protect the system.
Speaker 4:  And then they have these content delivery updates that are sort of like the
Speaker 4:  rules and regulations around how this driver functions and
Speaker 4:  how it detects stuff. And it's that sort of update, not the driver
Speaker 4:  that caused the issues. and it was basically a corruption in the update.
Speaker 4:  And then the, the driver's obviously gone, oh no, what's happening? Crashed.
Speaker 4:  And then Windows has gone, oh no, what's happening Blue screen and then
Speaker 4:  reboot. And then it keeps doing that every time because it keeps reading
Speaker 4:  that the latest content update. And so they, they, they've managed to fix
Speaker 4:  it on some machines because You can keep rebooting the machine and
Speaker 4:  if you're lucky the network stack will initialize in Windows before
Speaker 4:  CrowdStrike does. And then you get the update or CrowdStrike starts, its
Speaker 4:  like scanning. So you get the update the latest like dictionary
Speaker 4:  definitions essentially before it crashes. So,
Speaker 4:  so some have been able to recover from that. I'm not, I'm not sure what the
Speaker 4:  percentage is 'cause CrowdStrike haven't really sort of detailed that and
Speaker 4:  they're also working on some sort of other remediation, some mysterious
Speaker 4:  remediation that they've been testing apparently over the last 24 hours.
Speaker 4:  So may maybe we get some more details about that. But that's essentially
Speaker 4:  what happened. It was like 78 minutes of
Speaker 4:  push this faulty update out to machines and obviously there was a bunch of
Speaker 4:  them that are virtual machines. There's servers, there's just machines that
Speaker 4:  are always on, like we were talking about the airport and stuff. So they
Speaker 4:  were just sort of grabbed it. If you obviously had a machine that you turned
Speaker 4:  on once they pulled the bad update, you wouldn't have been affected. But
Speaker 4:  it still hit 8.5 million devices, which sounds like a lot as well.
Speaker 4:  and it is, but Microsoft's point is like, it's one less than 1%
Speaker 4:  of Windows machines. But but it's the, it's the important part of
Speaker 4:  Windows machines. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Let's let's talk through that. Yeah. That's the thing, right? I think it's
Speaker 2:  like the percentage of Microsoft
Speaker 2:  computers that have CrowdStrike is by definition going to be a very low important
Speaker 2:  percentage of Microsoft PCs. Right. And those matter
Speaker 2:  a lot that they keep running. So this idea that like, you know, the the surface
Speaker 2:  laptop my wife has in her office upstairs didn't crash. It's like, I
Speaker 2:  don't know if that's the victory for Microsoft that we're hoping for. No,
Speaker 2:  but it is useful perspective. It didn't Yeah. And I think Microsoft is trying
Speaker 2:  desperately to say like, this isn't Windows. Like we didn't, this is not
Speaker 2:  a Windows problem. We didn't do it. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Definitely. But can you imagine if it had been 10%, like
Speaker 2:  I know
Speaker 4:  It, it could have been like even like a lot, a lot, lot worse. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  it was obviously very bad, but yeah, I'm just, yeah, it's,
Speaker 4:  it, it could have been really bad. So, and it just kind of shows you
Speaker 4:  like the reliance on this stuff. So
Speaker 2:  You've been tracking kind of the different versions of the fix that have
Speaker 2:  been going on here because I think Yes. Walk me through kind of where we've
Speaker 2:  been. 'cause at the very beginning, if I remember right, one of the big problems
Speaker 2:  was the fix was super manual. You had to like go into every
Speaker 2:  airport, kiosk, computer, reboot it in safe mode,
Speaker 2:  do a thing, do another thing, and then it would work again. And it's like,
Speaker 2:  fine for your computer at home, but that doesn't work for every
Speaker 2:  airline and airport and bank around the world. Like that's just not a good,
Speaker 2:  yeah. So, but it seems like it, even just a few days later, there's a much
Speaker 2:  better track for getting this stuff fixed. So walk me through that a little
Speaker 2:  bit.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Kind of yes and no because obviously we talked about the reboot thing
Speaker 4:  is what CrowdStrike's been recommended and that's, that's, that's working
Speaker 4:  on some,
Speaker 2:  What were you saying up to 15 times you wrote? Right. Just basically keep
Speaker 2:  turning it off and on again until
Speaker 4:  Something it happens. Apparently you just keep rebooting and that's, that's
Speaker 4:  working for some people. It's not working for everyone. So there's still
Speaker 4:  a lot of manual intervention going on. So you still have the option
Speaker 4:  of doing it manually where you, you'd have to start the machine in safe mode,
Speaker 4:  which requires physical access and a keyboard to to, to, you know, get this
Speaker 4:  machine to, to go in safe mode and then you need admin rights to actually
Speaker 4:  delete the 40 file. So there's quite a lot of, you know, a
Speaker 4:  lot of intervention there. It's not like just send an update, click, click
Speaker 4:  a button and update is, is there. The other option is Microsoft
Speaker 4:  create a recovery tool which can sort of automate that process.
Speaker 4:  But the only problem is a lot of these machines, 'cause they're critical
Speaker 4:  and, and, and they're out sort of in airports and stuff, they, they,
Speaker 4:  they might be locked, locked down by BitLocker, which is disc encryption.
Speaker 4:  So then that tool can't do that without you having a recovery key,
Speaker 4:  which are unique for every machine. And then you have to type this long,
Speaker 4:  it's long, it's like a Windows key
Speaker 4:  product key that you put in that sort of length to then allow
Speaker 4:  you access. So there's a lot of, there's still a lot of manual intervention
Speaker 4:  going along. We, we've seen videos and pictures of like people
Speaker 4:  scaling ladders in airports and stuff just to literally plug
Speaker 4:  USBs into like these machines. It's just like, it's, yeah,
Speaker 4:  there's a lot that's still going on. So I didn't, I, I'd love to know what
Speaker 4:  the percentage of ones that were fixed by rebooting multiple times
Speaker 4:  versus, you know, man manual intervention and also just
Speaker 4:  do ITM means just go and just blast this thing away and, and
Speaker 4:  make sure that machine's fixed moved on to next. You know, like it's a choice
Speaker 4:  isn't it, for, for every business as well. Do you wanna sit there trying
Speaker 4:  to reboot it or do you just wanna fix it in the amount of time that you could
Speaker 4:  have sat there rebooting it sort of 20 times? So I think it's a choice, but
Speaker 4:  yeah, there's some more tools and in like we said, CrowdStrike's potentially
Speaker 4:  doing something that, I can't remember the exact wording they've put on it,
Speaker 4:  but it's like some cloud-based solution
Speaker 4:  that they think they might have got this fixed somehow, but
Speaker 4:  I'm not sure how that's gonna work.
Speaker 2:  You cover Microsoft for us. Yes. I feel like over the last 72
Speaker 2:  hours this has gone from being a Microsoft disaster
Speaker 2:  to not really being a Microsoft disaster. This is, it's kind of a Microsoft
Speaker 2:  adjacent disaster I would say. Yeah. But what is your sense of, of
Speaker 2:  what a, kind of how this looks for Microsoft and B like if
Speaker 2:  you're Microsoft and you're, you're a company that obviously is responsible
Speaker 2:  in some ways for Yeah. These kinds of crucial machines and the
Speaker 2:  way that these systems work. Is your sense that anything, anything changes
Speaker 2:  here? Is this just like a bad thing that happened and we all recover and
Speaker 2:  move on? Or does this feel like it might change things?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I feel like it might change things. I mean, because there, there's
Speaker 4:  a lot going on here. It is obviously CrowdStrike, which is a third party
Speaker 4:  vendor, they get privileged access to, to be able to, to
Speaker 4:  run this software in the way they do. Right. Which
Speaker 2:  Is not normal, we should say. Like it's a pretty, it's normal, it's a big
Speaker 2:  thing to give somebody essentially that kind of access. Yeah. It's it's like
Speaker 2:  being inside of your computer in a very real way.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And Microsoft allows it. And I
Speaker 4:  think that there was a statement where Microsoft said that essentially
Speaker 4:  that they have to give this access because of a ruling by the European Commission
Speaker 4:  in 2009, which I think is like yes,
Speaker 4:  true. But also, you know, they, they could, they could
Speaker 4:  possibly do what Apple have done and and create, create an architecture where
Speaker 4:  they have their own API set and then vendors plug into that.
Speaker 4:  But yeah, I, I don't know, I need to look into that more fully to see that,
Speaker 4:  the legalities on that. But yes, they do have to keep their kernel open
Speaker 4:  and it's essentially, it's not necessarily that they have to keep the kernel
Speaker 4:  open, it's just that they can't privilege their own security software over
Speaker 4:  other vendors seen as anti-competitive. And they've tried to lock down Windows
Speaker 4:  a bunch over the years Got it. To sort of secure things up. And they always
Speaker 4:  do get accused of being, you know, anti-competitive, whether it's like through
Speaker 4:  really dumb ways like ESS mode for sure. Or you know, some
Speaker 4:  more ways like TPM chips on Windows 11. Like there's always,
Speaker 4:  there's always gonna be a pushback because people see Windows
Speaker 4:  as this open system and they do not like it when Microsoft tries to lock
Speaker 4:  it down for whatever reasons they might be doing it. But I feel like this
Speaker 4:  might trigger some sort of change. The only thing is that
Speaker 4:  the Mac like way of doing it, it hasn't been perfect. It actually, sometimes
Speaker 4:  the security software that runs there does cause panic errors on,
Speaker 4:  on Macs. So there's no like perfect way
Speaker 4:  of doing this. And I think Microsoft was kind of stuck in this weird situation
Speaker 4:  where it's like they kind of should take some of the blame here because
Speaker 4:  should we say if there's a driver that's faulty and it's
Speaker 4:  stopping windows from booting or or crashing it at boot, why does Windows
Speaker 4:  not unload that after it's done that, like five times or whatever, however
Speaker 4:  long you wanna say. But it should be intelligent enough to be like
Speaker 4:  something weird's going on here, right? because there as a human, if something
Speaker 4:  was crashing, you just stop it, wouldn't you? And be like, let's see what's
Speaker 4:  going on here. Right? But it just allows that behavior to to happen.
Speaker 4:  So I feel like they need to address some of that to, to stop this sort
Speaker 4:  of thing happening in the future as well. But again, it's not their update
Speaker 4:  so that it wasn't their fault, but they couldn't help
Speaker 4:  if you know what I mean? So Yeah. But I think it's, it's gonna trigger a
Speaker 4:  lot of conversations around this and it's just interesting because
Speaker 4:  CrowdStrike obviously competes with Microsoft and Microsoft has its own endpoint
Speaker 4:  stuff like Intune that it sells to customers and competes with CrowdStrike
Speaker 4:  on the sales teams and the CEO of CrowdStrike regularly goes on
Speaker 4:  TV broadcasts and interviews and bashes Microsoft security record,
Speaker 4:  which obviously has not been great Yeah. Over the past few years. So
Speaker 4:  it's all, there's a lot of stuff going on here and, and I think there was
Speaker 4:  something about how, there was an incident that happened, I think it was
Speaker 4:  in 2010 when McAfee sent out an update similar to this and it
Speaker 4:  crashed a bunch of Windows XP machines and the CrowdStrike CEO was
Speaker 4:  the CTO at McAfee at the time. So it's like, yeah, there's, there's,
Speaker 4:  there's a lot of history between security vendors and Microsoft and
Speaker 4:  all this stuff where they, they want it to be open. Microsoft's like, yeah,
Speaker 4:  but you should trust us. I mean, everyone's like, well look what's happened,
Speaker 4:  we've trust trusted you for the past couple of decades. You know, like, so
Speaker 4:  I think there's gonna be a lot of conversations around that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean it's such an interesting microcosm of
Speaker 2:  both sides of the debate here, right? Because like, if you wanna argue for
Speaker 2:  the closed ecosystem, it's so that things like this don't happen
Speaker 2:  And if you wanna argue for the open ecosystem, it's that mostly things like
Speaker 2:  this don't happen, right? Like Yeah. Part of what's so interesting about
Speaker 2:  this to me is it's, it is on the one hand sort of
Speaker 2:  remarkable that like the McAfee thing was in 2010 and this is this year.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And these things don't actually happen all that often, and yet when
Speaker 2:  they do,
Speaker 2:  they literally like set the world on fire, right? Like
Speaker 2:  it
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's, it's catastrophic,
Speaker 2:  Right? And we're, we're so reliant on this stuff now, and I
Speaker 2:  think it, it comes to a point where, and like you said, nobody is perfect.
Speaker 2:  I don't think there is a version of this that is perfect and it just makes
Speaker 2:  you wonder like, okay, how do we, how do we even think about
Speaker 2:  our reliance on this stuff as people, as
Speaker 2:  businesses, as like society? Like the fact that a a what it
Speaker 2:  amounts to like a security update to your computer could prevent you from
Speaker 2:  flying to your vacation is just like a weird thing nobody
Speaker 2:  thinks about. And I, I, I have spent now a lot of time thinking about it
Speaker 2:  and I still don't know how to sort through it because it's not like, get
Speaker 2:  rid of all the computers, pen and paper will fix it. It's like that's clearly
Speaker 2:  not the answer.
Speaker 4:  But yeah. And I've seen seen some people tweet like
Speaker 4:  maybe people should, should use end points in, in like point of
Speaker 4:  sales devices in supermarkets should be iPads. You know, it's like
Speaker 4:  Yeah, but that's, that's expensive for supermarkets. They, they can't afford
Speaker 4:  that.
Speaker 2:  Well, and I, I dunno that iPads are like famously perfect technology.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like there's, there's so many different solutions, but I think,
Speaker 4:  I think really what it should highlight is that these companies like CrowdStrike
Speaker 4:  and Microsoft need to definitely work a lot closer together
Speaker 4:  rather than be in this competitive force against each other because
Speaker 4:  it's no good going on TV and bashing your competitors and stuff. And they
Speaker 4:  both do it. So it's like that, I think in cybersecurity in general at the
Speaker 4:  moment, there needs to just def definitely be a larger focus on the joint
Speaker 4:  customers. Who knows whether that happened, but yeah, the, the fact
Speaker 4:  that this sort of stuff can take down so much stuff and it was only less
Speaker 4:  than 1% of Windows machines, that that should be a major red flag. Like
Speaker 4:  if this was 10% upwards, it, it'd be, you know,
Speaker 4:  who knows, like if if it was a Windows update they'd done this as well. Like
Speaker 4:  Yeah, well
Speaker 2:  I was just gonna say, like you, you talk about nobody's security record is
Speaker 2:  perfect. Like if, if this is something Microsoft had pushed
Speaker 2:  and, and there's not necessarily a good reason, it couldn't have been
Speaker 2:  Microsoft that pushed it. No, the scale would've been dramatically
Speaker 2:  different. Like part of what I, I think, and you, you've probably seen more
Speaker 2:  of this than I have, but to me at least it seems like the question of what
Speaker 2:  went wrong at CrowdStrike that allowed this to happen is gonna be
Speaker 2:  the big question.
Speaker 4:  Why wasn't it tested right. Like that,
Speaker 2:  Right? Or like, was this the kind of thing that they do
Speaker 2:  a million times a day and so somebody got sloppy, was this a failure of process?
Speaker 2:  Was this, did it follow the process? And you know, sometimes bad things happen.
Speaker 2:  Like that to me feels like the kind of core piece of this that we still
Speaker 2:  haven't really seen is like what, what or who
Speaker 2:  screwed up that this could happen and is it a thing we can fix or is this
Speaker 2:  just like a thing that's gonna happen every once in a while and we have to
Speaker 2:  figure out how to live with it?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think what it, what it created was like a, a basically a sort of
Speaker 4:  memory panic. So it was like this file calls the
Speaker 4:  driver to be like, try to write to a part of memory that it shouldn't be.
Speaker 4:  And then Windows is obviously like, no, you can't do that. Let's kill
Speaker 4:  this driver. Or, or the driver crashed and killed Windows with it.
Speaker 4:  I think when it comes to like, there's gonna be obviously a lot of pointing
Speaker 4:  fingers and who, who takes the blame for it. But I think there's definitely
Speaker 4:  Windows should do a better job at this, but there's also, CrowdStrike should
Speaker 4:  do a better job at testing its update. Like how has that gone out to
Speaker 4:  8.5 million devices and not being spotted?
Speaker 4:  Like why, why don't they automate that testing or something like short,
Speaker 4:  there's gonna be questions about how that actually happened. But yeah, like
Speaker 4:  they, I think Microsoft takes probably like, I dunno, 10 to
Speaker 4:  20% of the blame here or something. And I just hope that they both look at
Speaker 4:  it and come up with a solution that stops this from ever happening again,
Speaker 4:  because I don't think the solution is rip these guys out the kernel because
Speaker 4:  Microsoft doesn't do a ton of innovative stuff with Windows at the moment.
Speaker 4:  So allowing people to have kernel access allows for some of that innovation
Speaker 4:  and some like CrowdStrike pushes that security innovation where Microsoft
Speaker 4:  might not take it like Internet Explorer back in the day, if we just let
Speaker 4:  Microsoft define the web, we wouldn't have had Chrome, we wouldn't have had
Speaker 4:  all that competition. So it's like, I don't wanna see it swing one way or
Speaker 4:  the other. I just wanna see cooperation. Really. Yeah. This never
Speaker 4:  happens again.
Speaker 2:  Well and especially in these moments where these things are
Speaker 2:  not allowed to fail. Right. I think part of what was so
Speaker 2:  eyeopening, I think about this whole thing was just realizing how much of
Speaker 2:  the world runs on Windows computers. Yeah. And not,
Speaker 2:  not even different Windows computers, just Windows computers that like
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The, the signs you see at the mall are just Windows computers
Speaker 2:  and, and I think you
Speaker 4:  Go to an ATM and take out cash, it's probably Windows. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And so I think to me the this question of, okay,
Speaker 2:  we have, we have these operating systems, we have this software,
Speaker 2:  do we need to think really differently about the ones that are like modern
Speaker 2:  infrastructure in a way that isn't just
Speaker 2:  functionally a Windows computer? Like, I don't know, it just the fact that
Speaker 2:  it's basically just a bunch of like crappy little PC boxes that keep our
Speaker 2:  banks running is one of those things I think a lot of people sort of intellectually
Speaker 2:  know, but it's actually probably not how it should work. And I don't know,
Speaker 2:  this is where I get in like way over my head on how all the technology of
Speaker 2:  this actually works, but it does feel like we are at a point where there
Speaker 2:  is a set of computers in the world that just cannot fail. Yeah. And that
Speaker 2:  maybe having them be just computers is not the
Speaker 2:  right way to think
Speaker 4:  About it. Yeah. I dunno what the alternative is, but that's
Speaker 2:  The thing. I don't either,
Speaker 4:  That's the thing is that it, they're just cheap, right? It's, it's cheaper
Speaker 4:  for them to, what is the alternative really? Like they're not gonna go Mac
Speaker 4:  os they, they could do Linux, but then that could be complicated. Like it's
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That has its own mess. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So it's like, I, I don't know. There's no, I think that's the biggest problem
Speaker 4:  is that there is actually a monopoly here right? At play with, with Windows.
Speaker 4:  and it was has been, and it's like there isn't really a good
Speaker 4:  alternative and the alternative to securities things are now causing
Speaker 4:  issues. It's like, yeah, like where do you,
Speaker 4:  where do you stop at this? But I mean, maybe the alternative is Microsoft
Speaker 4:  creates a lockdown version windows for these sort of devices. I think they've
Speaker 4:  done similar sort of stuff in the past, but
Speaker 4:  the, the problem there is that then you get complicated apps that wanna do
Speaker 4:  stuff on these and then you have that, the same thing
Speaker 4:  is like, okay, well we just need to give them windows. So,
Speaker 2:  And you get to the point where there's only two people on earth and one vendor
Speaker 2:  that know how to service these things and that causes its own problems. And
Speaker 2:  it's, it's a tough thing, but it feels like, I, I wonder
Speaker 2:  if this moment ends up being a kind of a blip on the radar or if
Speaker 2:  people start to talk seriously about like, okay, how do we make these things
Speaker 2:  work the way that we need them to going forward? And I have no idea what
Speaker 2:  that'll look like, but I think it'll be fascinating to watch. And,
Speaker 4:  And the fragility of this situation just reminds me of like, when I used
Speaker 4:  to be an IT admin, we, we literally had like a ticker that would go
Speaker 4:  around in, in Canary Wolf and it was powered by spreadsheet, an Excel
Speaker 4:  spreadsheet, and I'd input data into it myself and maintain it. And if I
Speaker 4:  put in something wrong, it would crash the whole ticket. It'd be like flashing
Speaker 4:  and going crazy. Like that's just, you know, that's just like
Speaker 4:  the perfect example of how you see this stuff out in the world, like the
Speaker 4:  screens at airports and you just don't realize that usually it's some
Speaker 4:  crappy software. Just the most basic stuff
Speaker 4:  powering that thing. Yeah. Probably from like 10, 20 years ago.
Speaker 2:  I ju I keep thinking about for whatever reason the, I think it was when
Speaker 2:  Oppenheimer was out and there was that picture of somebody posted of the
Speaker 2:  IMAX theater with a, with a palm pilot powering it.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah. And we went and found somebody who ran the theater and they were
Speaker 2:  like, look, it works. Nobody touches it. It's been there for years. Like
Speaker 2:  no one understands it. It's just this weird little thing that keeps the plate
Speaker 2:  spinning. So we, we, we keep it running and I feel like yeah, that's good.
Speaker 2:  More of the world works like that than any of us would like
Speaker 4:  To do. Definitely. Oh yeah. It's all like held to give it by string and that,
Speaker 4:  that strings started going apart on Friday.
Speaker 2:  Exactly. So it seems like most of the worst of
Speaker 2:  this is if not over then kind of on the way to recovery.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think so. I think 'cause it, if you're an it TM and in a business,
Speaker 4:  you're gonna prioritize your, the people and systems that matter the most
Speaker 4:  first of all, and get those back up and running and
Speaker 2:  Stuff. Yeah. There are a lot of people who worked all weekend, I suspect.
Speaker 2:  Yes. So to to all of you it folks listening, we, we we love you.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's the, that's, that's a tough one, especially when on Friday when
Speaker 4:  you think, ah, nice chill Friday, did you feel to the weekend
Speaker 2:  What fallout is left here? What are you keeping an eye on this week?
Speaker 4:  I'm definitely keeping an eye on the Delta situation because they seem to
Speaker 4:  be the most impacted by this in terms of airlines,
Speaker 4:  hospitals, because we've seen people like not being able to get their
Speaker 4:  appointments and stuff to see 'cause in schools, I guess
Speaker 4:  as well though in, certainly in Europe and the uk like a lot of kids are
Speaker 4:  outta school now for the summer holidays. So we will see it is
Speaker 4:  where there's typically less investment
Speaker 4:  in infrastructure where, where it kind of matters like schools and, and,
Speaker 4:  and hospitals and stuff where they just don't have the budget. So it'd be
Speaker 4:  interesting to see where those go and, and where there's still some sort
Speaker 4:  of lingering issues to today and tomorrow, but I feel like we'll hear
Speaker 4:  less about this as as the week goes on for sure. It's it's definitely,
Speaker 4:  yeah. It's getting better out
Speaker 2:  There in some sense. Like thank God it happened on a Friday and not on like
Speaker 2:  a Tuesday morning. Yeah. And we would've felt the full effects of this for
Speaker 2:  like a couple of days in the middle of the week. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  We'll see. Yeah. Yeah, that's good. It's on its way to being, being fixed
Speaker 4:  now anyway. That's good.
Speaker 2:  Well, yeah, here as always, computers are
Speaker 2:  terrifying, fragile things.
Speaker 4:  The funniest thing about it though was like one, one of Microsoft's fixes
Speaker 4:  was like literally have you turned it off and on 15 times.
Speaker 2:  Unreal.
Speaker 4:  It's like, it's the meme coming
Speaker 2:  True. It really, like, it is astounding how much of the world is just unplug
Speaker 2:  it and plug it back in again. And it's, I mean it goes back to the same thing,
Speaker 2:  right? Like the these things are are fragile and simple
Speaker 2:  in, in so, so many ways that we would Yeah. Like maybe it's scary that they're
Speaker 2:  that fragile and that simple. But that is, that is where we are. It definitely
Speaker 2:  is. Yeah. Yeah. All right, Tom, thank you as always.
Speaker 2:  No worries. Thanks for having me. All right, we gotta take a break and then
Speaker 2:  we're gonna come back, talk about fitness, but like in a, in a fun way,
Speaker 2:  we'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  to exercise more, do better, get in better shape, keep
Speaker 2:  track of how you're doing without all of the stuff that feels
Speaker 2:  gamified and toxic and like it's always pushing you to do more and
Speaker 2:  incentivizing you to go do crazy things when it might hurt you or you're
Speaker 2:  sick. Or like, if I just have the Apple Watch yell at me
Speaker 2:  for not closing my rings when I'm sick one more time, I'm gonna lose my
Speaker 2:  mind. You know what I mean? So to kick off our discussions about the
Speaker 2:  Super Chill exercise system, real name pending, we'll see,
Speaker 2:  I wanted to talk to the person who made Zombies Run. So v and I called up
Speaker 2:  Adrian Hanh, who is a writer and developer and
Speaker 2:  storyteller and worked on Zombies Run from the very beginning until
Speaker 2:  very recently. He spent more than a decade writing this game.
Speaker 2:  And Zombies Run if you've never Played It is, I don't know how
Speaker 2:  to describe it exactly, it's an exercise fitness app
Speaker 2:  that is also narrative. So when you're running,
Speaker 2:  it's tracking you and it's aware of what you're doing, but it weaves a story
Speaker 2:  in, basically it's a zombie apocalypse. You're in a place called Able
Speaker 2:  Township and you are a runner. That's your job, right? You,
Speaker 2:  you go out into the barren wasteland of the post
Speaker 2:  apocalyptic world and you do quests, you have to go find something or
Speaker 2:  you have to go rescue somebody or you have to go to another place and learn
Speaker 2:  about something. And it's all incentivizing you to run
Speaker 2:  and be active and be out. But the idea is to make
Speaker 2:  it fun with story, right? You're, you're picking it up every morning to see
Speaker 2:  what happens next. Not to not break some streak.
Speaker 2:  This app worked really well for me. Just having a thing that
Speaker 2:  pushed me out, that gave me something fun to do while I was running. Sometimes
Speaker 2:  it'll just be like, oh no zombies and you have to run faster. It was awesome.
Speaker 2:  Like, I've always been a a person who likes sports more than I like
Speaker 2:  just running because in sports, like there's something to do. I have a purpose
Speaker 2:  for why I'm moving fast. This felt like that. and it,
Speaker 2:  it's kind of like immersive in the way that listening to podcasts is
Speaker 2:  immersive. It sort of distracts you from running while also having you run
Speaker 2:  The story is great. You get to know the characters, there's just something
Speaker 2:  terrific about this game, but I haven't really seen replicated elsewhere.
Speaker 2:  And Adrian was one of the people who built this thing from the very beginning.
Speaker 2:  So v and I called up Adrian to get a sense of how a game
Speaker 2:  like this comes together, why it's hard to do and
Speaker 2:  what it took to really pull it off. And we just started at the beginning.
Speaker 2:  We asked him basically, you know, over a decade ago,
Speaker 2:  you're thinking about building a fitness game. This is like in the early
Speaker 2:  days of the iPhone. Where do you even start?
Speaker 5:  I'm Adrian Hahn. I ran Six Start and
Speaker 5:  Co-founded it for 17 years. And so we made Zombies Run.
Speaker 5:  I left about three months ago, four months ago. So that's
Speaker 5:  probably the most well-known thing that I've done,
Speaker 5:  made Zombies Run and also wrote a book critiquing gamification
Speaker 5:  called You've Been Played. So that's fun. So
Speaker 5:  you know, when we came up with the idea for Zombies Run, it was myself and
Speaker 5:  novelist, Naomi Alderman. And I had just
Speaker 5:  kind of like really gotten into running at that time. And I had a
Speaker 5:  Garmin Forerunner 2 0 5, 2 0 1. So if, if you
Speaker 5:  remember this, this is a massive, like chunky, it's not a watch. I mean it's
Speaker 5:  like a forearm bracelet and it could
Speaker 5:  track you by GPS. And I got this as a kind of way to
Speaker 5:  make myself run more. and it actually did work because it was cool
Speaker 5:  to see like numbers and to see that I was getting better every,
Speaker 5:  every day, every time I ran. And it had this thing called,
Speaker 5:  I think it was like the virtual racer or virtual runner, which is like
Speaker 5:  what it sounds like, it's like ghost racing in, in Mario Kart where you're
Speaker 5:  racing against yourself. So You can go and go out for a run and it will
Speaker 5:  show you yourself versus yesterday's self.
Speaker 5:  and it was kind of really cool to see myself like in this very
Speaker 5:  proto gamification thing, getting better each time. But
Speaker 5:  then there was a moment where I stopped getting better and I started getting
Speaker 5:  worse and like my past self started beating myself. And I
Speaker 5:  was like, this sucks. Like this is not motivating anymore because
Speaker 5:  that only works on the way up. Like it, it doesn't work on the way down or
Speaker 5:  when you plateau or if you're ill. And so then
Speaker 5:  the iPhone came out and then the app store came out and we had Runkeeper,
Speaker 5:  there were even some smartphone running games, actually there was one
Speaker 5:  called Cash and Seek made by Korean
Speaker 5:  developer, I think. And the ideas that you'd run around your neighborhood
Speaker 5:  and you'd see a map and there'd be like little treasure there and it was
Speaker 5:  actually like multiplayer 'cause other people could leave treasure for you.
Speaker 5:  And I started playing that and I was like, I actually just don't want to
Speaker 5:  run to these places. It's telling me to run to 'cause it's like not very
Speaker 5:  safe or it, it doesn't look nice.
Speaker 5:  And so we started thinking about like, well how could we make
Speaker 5:  a good running game because people are trying to make these running
Speaker 5:  games. I mean, one of the problems of a lot of them actually
Speaker 5:  was you have to look at the screen when you're running, which I think
Speaker 5:  for people who have not run before, that
Speaker 5:  sounds cool. Like, that sounds like a good idea. And if you've ever run
Speaker 5:  then you, you're like, this is not just terrible from a kind of safety point
Speaker 5:  of view, but also if you stop every like two minutes to look at your phone
Speaker 5:  and then start running again, like, how are you really gonna do that? Like
Speaker 5:  that, that's not really practical. So the idea kind
Speaker 5:  of came from, look, we have this amazing piece of technology, which is like
Speaker 5:  a sort of like handheld computer, which is brand new really. It's got
Speaker 5:  internet connection, it's got GPS, it's got sound, people
Speaker 5:  are used to using their headphones. What can we do of this to make a
Speaker 5:  game? And so that's a lot of constraints, but it was also like really interesting
Speaker 5:  from a game design point of view.
Speaker 2:  Well, and I think somewhere in there you're also having to make a lot of
Speaker 2:  decisions about like the mechanics of the game, right? Because you're, you're
Speaker 2:  talking about like, I think about all those early games and there were, or
Speaker 2:  all those early running apps and a lot of them were just like, track your
Speaker 2:  run, right? Like there's a, there's a subset of people who just like wanna
Speaker 2:  know how far they run. But then like you're saying, there were others that
Speaker 2:  were starting to play with this. Like, how do we get you
Speaker 2:  to run more? And this is when everybody was starting to experiment with all
Speaker 2:  these new ways of, ways of gamification and leaderboards and all these different
Speaker 2:  things. And I feel like from the very beginning you kind of went the other
Speaker 2:  direction of a lot of that
Speaker 5:  Stuff. Yeah, the, the, there was a lot of, you know, to the extent that
Speaker 5:  they really thought about motivation, I think it was basically competition,
Speaker 5:  right? So it was like, we have a leaderboard and can you get to the top
Speaker 5:  of the leaderboard? So like I was using the Fitbit at the time and everyone
Speaker 5:  was trying to get to the top of the leaderboard and then the leaderboard
Speaker 5:  would never move each week because you'd have the people who like are in
Speaker 5:  Europe and they walk everywhere and you'd have the people in America at the
Speaker 5:  bottom who drive everywhere and, and they don't, they don't climb. And so
Speaker 5:  it's just like, this is not really motivating anyone. Actually,
Speaker 5:  another aspect of that kind of parallel to that, there'd be these
Speaker 5:  territory capture games where you'd have like, you divide the world up into
Speaker 5:  hexagons or squares and it'd be like, can you go and capture enough
Speaker 5:  space? And that's kind of like a leaderboard where it's just whoever runs
Speaker 5:  the most, you know, or has the most free time wins.
Speaker 5:  And again, for some people that's really motivating. I don't really
Speaker 5:  think there was anything beyond that, not even kind of exploration.
Speaker 5:  And so we want to do something completely different, which was
Speaker 5:  storytelling basically. It was like role play, which I didn't think had been
Speaker 5:  done before in, in that aspect, but it really came
Speaker 5:  from the idea that people were already like listening to podcasts and
Speaker 5:  audiobooks when they're running. So we weren't asking people to do anything
Speaker 5:  new. And I think I still have this idea for a game,
Speaker 5:  so feel free to steal it if you want. Which was, there's a, the
Speaker 5:  bit in the born ultimatum when Jason Bourne
Speaker 5:  is guiding this person through Waterloo Station and
Speaker 5:  he's like, okay, turn right now, turn left here. Okay, pause for five seconds
Speaker 5:  and Bne goes and murders him. And I'm like, oh, that's kind of like a really,
Speaker 5:  that's a, that's a very like interesting like dramatic thing, which
Speaker 5:  is just entirely voice-based basically. And it's like, oh,
Speaker 5:  we could do something like that where, where you have this audio story, which
Speaker 5:  is telling you basically to run. And when you're
Speaker 5:  running crucially, you don't look at the screen, you don't tap on anything.
Speaker 5:  So it's not, it's not really interactive game. You're
Speaker 5:  just choosing or, or able to run fast or slower. And the
Speaker 5:  story and the game kind of adapts to that. The zombies came into
Speaker 5:  it because
Speaker 5:  Naomi, my co-creator, she had just joined this running club
Speaker 5:  and they'd said, why do you want to run? And some people wanted to lose weight
Speaker 5:  and other people wanted to get fit. And one woman said she
Speaker 5:  wanted to survive the zombie apocalypse. And
Speaker 5:  and I was like, oh yeah, that's funny. But then I was kind of like sick of
Speaker 5:  zombies at that point. This was like 2011, 2012, and
Speaker 5:  we had the Walking Dead and we had, you know,
Speaker 5:  28 days later and I kind of thought zombies were over, which, which was
Speaker 5:  wrong. They're, they're still here. But from a
Speaker 5:  storytelling point of view and from a gameplay point of view, especially
Speaker 5:  for a running game, that there's actually really nothing better that we found
Speaker 5:  because zombies, everyone knows how they work. You, you
Speaker 5:  just have to kind of move faster than 'em. But also the great thing about
Speaker 5:  zombies is that they, most zombies don't actually run. So,
Speaker 5:  you know, your classic zombies, your non 28 days later zombies,
Speaker 5:  they just walk or they shamble. And so that was kind of a
Speaker 5:  really clear thing for us, which was you don't actually have to run in
Speaker 5:  zombies run, You can just walk if you want and the game will
Speaker 5:  not give you a hard time for that. Like there is nothing gated in
Speaker 5:  zombies run based on your distance or your pace.
Speaker 5:  So if you even want to do it sitting on a couch, You can do that. Like,
Speaker 5:  and some people do it like doing chores or whatever, and then most people
Speaker 5:  do run or jog. And so the crucial thing there was
Speaker 5:  we're not measuring your performance. Like You can measure your performance.
Speaker 5:  We give you stats and things like that, but actually we're not rewarding
Speaker 5:  that in a way what we're doing is we're saying we're just gonna make
Speaker 5:  it more fun. Like, you know, we don't wanna make it like we, we don't wanna
Speaker 5:  reward you for doing a run. We want you to be rewarded while running,
Speaker 5:  which is a really important difference. And I think gets
Speaker 5:  to like what makes for good gamification. Like good gamification
Speaker 5:  means where you are having fun while you're doing it, not after you've done
Speaker 5:  it, which is really hard to do.
Speaker 6:  I actually, this is my, my running journey began with
Speaker 6:  Zombies Run. Oh wow. 'cause I, I, you know, I've been running for a
Speaker 6:  long time, but I was not a natural runner in
Speaker 6:  any form. I was the person who is very much like my natural
Speaker 6:  form is a couch potato. You could, you would have to be chasing
Speaker 6:  me basically for me to run. But it was a, it was a type of thing where
Speaker 6:  I was like, oh, I have like a metabolic thing I need to actually
Speaker 6:  run. Running is one of the cheapest ways that You can exercise, but it is
Speaker 6:  quite miserable when you're starting out. Yeah. So
Speaker 6:  like, I think the thing that really resonates with me here in terms of like,
Speaker 6:  just talking about the chillness of things is like actually having fun
Speaker 6:  while you exercise. Because I think with fitness tech and like with the
Speaker 6:  gamification of it, I don't know why, but we just decide to
Speaker 6:  invite so much anxiety into the process. Like leaderboard,
Speaker 6:  oh, well I feel terrible about myself because I'm not number one. And then
Speaker 6:  if I am number one, I have this intense pressure to stay number one.
Speaker 6:  And so then that's, that's not fun anymore. I've turned the, the exercise
Speaker 6:  into work. And then also just as you said, like it really kind of
Speaker 6:  resonated with the whole idea of the virtual runner and you're
Speaker 6:  running against your past self who is better than you? I am at that stage
Speaker 6:  because if you do it long enough, if you do it long enough, you are going
Speaker 6:  to plateau. You are gonna have a slump. You're just not, you're just
Speaker 6:  you age, you know, as you get older, you're not gonna be quite as fast
Speaker 6:  as you were when you were younger. So I think with the game
Speaker 6:  you want people to keep playing. So how, how, like what were some of the
Speaker 6:  things that you tried that you just realized was like, oh,
Speaker 6:  this is actually making the game less fun, or Oh this is making the game
Speaker 6:  more fun?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean, you know, people come into it with different like motivations
Speaker 5:  and different expectations. So we did this Kickstarter right
Speaker 5:  at the beginning and there were kind of two strands to it. One was there's
Speaker 5:  gonna be an amazing story by an amazing storyteller. And
Speaker 5:  for a lot of people, possibly even most people, that's like the big motivation,
Speaker 5:  which is I go out for a run. It, it's kind of told like in
Speaker 5:  first person. So they're talking to you as if you are like, you know, a real
Speaker 5:  person. It's not like an audio book. and it has amazing characters.
Speaker 5:  It's got like cliffhangers at the end of every mission. So, so you kind of
Speaker 5:  want to know what happens next. And for us that's a big thing
Speaker 5:  where it was always, you know, we want you to get up on a rainy
Speaker 5:  Sunday morning and actually be excited to find out what's gonna happen next
Speaker 5:  rather than be like, is there any excuse I can use not to go to rock.
Speaker 2:  So I just, I just wanna push back on one piece of that that I think is really
Speaker 2:  interesting that you said, which is the, the idea that You can like, it,
Speaker 2:  it, you could just sit on your couch and play the game and it would still
Speaker 2:  be very fun, right? Yeah. I think that there's, there's probably some truth
Speaker 2:  to that, but also if, if that were true, you would've just made a game
Speaker 2:  that You can play sitting on your couch, right? Yeah. So, and, and part of
Speaker 2:  the reason I think this is the thing v and I keep talking about is like gamification.
Speaker 2:  When it's like monopoly go trying to get your money. I have pretty
Speaker 2:  unconflicted problematic feelings about, but this one is so different, right?
Speaker 2:  Because the thing that you're doing, creepy things to incentivize
Speaker 2:  people to do is like ostensibly a good and healthy thing. And so
Speaker 2:  you're in a position of saying like, okay, we built this cool game that people
Speaker 2:  like because it's a game, but they also like it because it makes them exercise
Speaker 2:  and because it makes them do a thing that is good for them and it makes that
Speaker 2:  thing more bearable. Like, does that change the balance of just
Speaker 2:  like if the goal was to just get more micro transactions from people,
Speaker 2:  you would play it one way, but when it's like, okay, we actually want to
Speaker 2:  have you do something that in moderation even at greater
Speaker 2:  intervals than you're currently doing, it is a good thing. Like does that
Speaker 2:  change the way you think about that balance?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean I, I think that, you know, by, by trying to
Speaker 5:  design it in the way we did, we left money on the table. Like, you know,
Speaker 5:  we could have had more engagement if we sent people notifications saying,
Speaker 5:  you're gonna, everyone in your base is gonna die if you don't give a run
Speaker 5:  tomorrow, right? I mean, that, that's what like most games that have done,
Speaker 5:  you know, or we would say like if you go and do like a three mile run now,
Speaker 5:  then you'll get double like, you know, supplies, right? Duolingo style
Speaker 5:  stuff and, and that all this stuff is like really well documented and it
Speaker 5:  does work like in terms of increasing engagement and, and
Speaker 5:  conversions. But I think that that's the
Speaker 5:  nice thing about owning your company and having, having a small company is
Speaker 5:  that You can just say, we're not gonna do that because we don't think that's
Speaker 5:  gonna be a good experience for people in the long term. So we
Speaker 5:  would get people saying, oh, but like, can't people just cheat? And it's
Speaker 5:  like, yeah, people can cheat about anything. Like people can cheat in dance,
Speaker 5:  dance revolution, right? You can cheat a guitar hero, You can cheat all these
Speaker 5:  things. And it's like, if you're gonna cheat a dance dance revolution, don't
Speaker 5:  play dance dance revolution. Like no one's making you do that. It doesn't
Speaker 5:  really bother me as a designer because it just shows
Speaker 5:  that you, you kind of need to do it a little bit differently. And, and I
Speaker 5:  think that, you know, the other thing is I see it as a kind of accessibility
Speaker 5:  mode mostly, rather than like, people cheating. So,
Speaker 5:  you know, we don't know what situations people are in in terms of their ability
Speaker 5:  to move. We call it like simulate running when we do this.
Speaker 5:  It might be that you
Speaker 5:  can't use your legs, you know, then you're going to do another exercise while
Speaker 5:  you're doing this. And so we've had, you know, people
Speaker 5:  say, you know, they'd like it that we offer these options. So having
Speaker 5:  said that, like most people do actually run. So, so, so it's fine.
Speaker 6:  It's a, it's a really interesting thing to me because I,
Speaker 6:  it really just hits home with the whole one size does not fit all, but
Speaker 6:  especially with fitness, because we all have different capabilities, as you
Speaker 6:  mentioned with our bodies. We have different skill levels, different circumstances,
Speaker 6:  but I find a lot of times I burn out when testing
Speaker 6:  wearables and fitness tech because they are just
Speaker 6:  kind of pushing you towards more. and it sometimes does feel
Speaker 6:  like part of this is late stage capitalism. Yeah. Because they need to make
Speaker 6:  money off of this thing and they need to keep user bases. So they need to
Speaker 6:  get us addicted to these platforms, like keep your streaks going. Sometimes
Speaker 6:  it really does feel like streaks can be insidious just
Speaker 6:  because like, oh, I know you're getting me addicted to this, but actually
Speaker 6:  what my body is saying is I need to rest. I actually,
Speaker 6:  so like, it's a tricky thing, right? Because if you wanna stay
Speaker 6:  injury free, you can't constantly do more. You do have to
Speaker 6:  take days off and that's good for you as well.
Speaker 6:  So I think the big metric with
Speaker 6:  gamification and fitness is streaks. And
Speaker 6:  I was just curious like what your thought process was
Speaker 6:  towards streaks and like, do you have feelings towards it? I hate them
Speaker 6:  personally.
Speaker 5:  Just look, I, I hate them. I don't like them. I, I
Speaker 5:  mean, you know, you, you will see people talk about how it
Speaker 5:  motivates 'em to sort of go and ha if they're doing like nano rmo national,
Speaker 5:  you know, novel writing month, it, it's like nice to have a streak where
Speaker 5:  you're writing for 30 days in a row, right? Or you've got
Speaker 5:  like a calendar and you like mark it with an X every time you, you know,
Speaker 5:  do something useful. And so I always kind of think it's about
Speaker 5:  like, how can you get the incentives aligned
Speaker 5:  correctly, right? And so I think that
Speaker 5:  the issue with like fitness is that, you know, you see this
Speaker 5:  with the Apple watch, you see it with Peloton in particular. There are a
Speaker 5:  lot of stories about Peloton where people were just completely burning out
Speaker 5:  and like really injuring themselves. I just don't think this is like
Speaker 5:  the way to like good health and fitness actually a lot of
Speaker 5:  these companies along with like, trying to get you addicted, they're trying
Speaker 5:  to sell this idea of you becoming a, like an a literal elite athlete.
Speaker 5:  Like, as if like, that is like a good thing to be, like, if you want to be
Speaker 5:  elite athlete, that that's fine. But like, it's not really
Speaker 5:  a good idea frankly for, for, for most people. Like, you know, most people
Speaker 5:  have got jobs and they've got families and, and it's very hard to like maintain
Speaker 5:  that, you know, it can be, it can actually be quite, quite damaging. And
Speaker 5:  I see that with a lot of the marketing. I mean they've changed it a bit now,
Speaker 5:  but like Nike and a lot of these other apps were like made by people who
Speaker 5:  used to be athletes or, or who, who just like incredibly fit, right? And
Speaker 5:  so they'd be like, wow, you've gotta go and break through the pain barrier.
Speaker 5:  You've gotta go and do all this stuff. It's like, you don't, you don't actually
Speaker 5:  need to do that. Like you are just saying you have to do that. So I don't,
Speaker 5:  I don't like streaks. It can be done in a way that's like less
Speaker 5:  bad, right? But I think that when I look at the
Speaker 5:  best games and the best apps out there, like a Nintendo doesn't like,
Speaker 5:  I mean, Nintendo does actually have streaks and animal crossing, but like,
Speaker 5:  it's very small. It's really small stuff and it, it doesn't, it's not punishing
Speaker 5:  at all if you don't, if you don't match it. Like, you know, there are streaks
Speaker 5:  in some video games, but like you play elder ring or you play, you know,
Speaker 5:  like legends as elder, that's not like a streak for playing it two days in
Speaker 5:  a row. They don't need that because it's a really good game, right? And so
Speaker 5:  I think it's just, it, you know, it it's an excuse it for
Speaker 5:  not making something that is as targeted or is interesting for
Speaker 5:  people. It's very difficult because, you know, if you're running a company,
Speaker 5:  like I do have a lot of sympathy for people. Like we, we didn't take investment
Speaker 5:  when we started and so like, or we have very little investment, so they were
Speaker 5:  like really patient and they were not giving us a hard time. You know, people
Speaker 5:  would call us like a lifestyle business I guess. But it does mean
Speaker 5:  that if you take investment and you kind of have to take
Speaker 5:  investment if you're a startup. 'cause otherwise you'll just be outgunned
Speaker 5:  by all the other startups who take investment, right? You don't really have
Speaker 5:  a choice. They need to see the line go up. And one of the easiest ways of
Speaker 5:  getting the line to go up is by adding in streaks, is by adding in notifications
Speaker 5:  and, and making people feel bad about not using it. So,
Speaker 5:  you know, I I can blame individual like, you know, designers here, but it's,
Speaker 5:  it's like they're in an arm's race.
Speaker 2:  It does feel like a much harder bar to set for yourself though, because essentially
Speaker 2:  what you're describing is that instead of punishing me for not doing the
Speaker 2:  thing that you've already given me, you have to keep giving me new things,
Speaker 2:  which is a lot of work for you. Yes. Like it's, it's much easier to
Speaker 2:  just yell at me for not closing my rings than it is to like, like you, you,
Speaker 2:  you mentioned Elden ring, like people play Elden ring because it's a great
Speaker 2:  game. Like it's really hard to make a great game and it's much easier
Speaker 2:  to build a mechanic that requires me to open the app every day or my
Speaker 2:  little character dies than it is to keep building a great game for 11 years.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That, that's, that's really true. Yeah. It, it's
Speaker 5:  definitely not easy. I mean, when you make a a a a fitness game
Speaker 5:  that's based around like narrative, you just need to keep on making more
Speaker 5:  narrative, right? And so we turn from being
Speaker 5:  a, a sort of tech company almost into like a content company, And, if you
Speaker 5:  open up like Zombies Run or ZX now it kind of looks a bit like Netflix, like
Speaker 5:  it has these carousels of Rose and you know, You can like, choose different
Speaker 5:  stories, which is shows how the
Speaker 5:  company kind of evolved over time from like triangle, all these different
Speaker 5:  like gameplay mechanics, some of which worked and some of which didn't into
Speaker 5:  like, okay, what we are doing is we're creating a
Speaker 5:  process to try and make as many like consistently
Speaker 5:  good stories as possible. Like every week, multiple, multiple stories a week.
Speaker 5:  And so you, we ended up with like writer's rooms and, and just
Speaker 5:  sound designers and you know, like it's games as a service, as
Speaker 5:  software, as a service. And a lot of companies try and transition from
Speaker 5:  making like a one-off game or one-off tech product into making constant,
Speaker 5:  you know, content and it's just really difficult to do, especially when you're
Speaker 5:  making like specialized stories that are like about you running,
Speaker 5:  you know, like that's, that's a different kind of storytelling
Speaker 5:  and you know, the team did it really well, but I think that
Speaker 5:  that's actually not something that tech companies are really set up to do.
Speaker 6:  It reminds me of Peloton because they too have become a media
Speaker 6:  company without I think necessarily intending that. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So, you know, is, is this just then the challenge of
Speaker 6:  gamifying fitness because I, I don't know, like I
Speaker 6:  don't have an answer, but it's just like I constantly have to find
Speaker 6:  new ways to motivate myself or sometimes just like
Speaker 6:  let myself have permission to be bad at fitness,
Speaker 6:  which is opposite to what all these devices
Speaker 6:  are doing, which is to optimize yourself to be the best version
Speaker 6:  of yourself. I feel like there's conflicting narratives here where like,
Speaker 6:  I think David and I just wanna like be slightly healthier and
Speaker 6:  not beat ourselves while doing it. But then, you know, these
Speaker 6:  watches, these rings, these games, not yours, but
Speaker 6:  some of these games are just like, here's how to be the best version of yourself
Speaker 6:  with metrics and numbers and get you addicted to it. So how do you like,
Speaker 5:  I mean they're sort of creating goals for you that maybe you didn't have
Speaker 5:  when you began, right? Which is like, you know, the, the longest I've ever
Speaker 5:  run is a half marathon and everyone's like, oh, so why, why didn't you do
Speaker 5:  like a marathon? I'm like, why would I do a marathon? I I don't want to do
Speaker 5:  a marathon. Yes. That, that seems like You can reach that. That seems like
Speaker 5:  a bad time for me. I'm I love it. I'm glad for you if you've done a
Speaker 5:  marathon, you know, I know someone who did like an ultra marathon, you know,
Speaker 5:  she's great, but like it's, it's not for me. And so
Speaker 5:  I think when you start, you know, these applications, it's all games. It's
Speaker 5:  always like, so what's your goal? And you've just got these like massive
Speaker 5:  goals, right? You know, and like, oh, do I really wanna do that or do I just
Speaker 5:  want to do something else? Just be a little bit healthier. So
Speaker 5:  a big part of it is, you know, again, I just
Speaker 5:  come back to like, how can we make it fun? How can we make it a little bit
Speaker 5:  more bearable? You know, you mentioned the, like when you start out running,
Speaker 5:  you know, it was the same for me. It's just horrible. It like, it's so painful,
Speaker 5:  like sweaty, it's just like, you know, you get a stitch, I just can't
Speaker 5:  like bear it. But then, you know, the thing is when you've done
Speaker 5:  it a lot, you get good at running and now I don't need like a
Speaker 5:  game to go running. Like I just go out running to music or
Speaker 5:  podcasts and it's actually pretty easy for me, right? And so like,
Speaker 5:  can we get people into that situation where they
Speaker 5:  don't need us anymore? Of course, like from a business point of view, you
Speaker 5:  know, you, you want people to keep on paying and, and hopefully you're fun
Speaker 5:  enough, but that's where you want to get people to because it's the same
Speaker 5:  with like a lot of stuff. When you get to a good enough point, it actually
Speaker 5:  becomes way easier to, to maintain it. I do think
Speaker 5:  it's gonna be a challenge for a lot of gamified fitness apps. Like, because
Speaker 5:  you, you just need to keep on providing the content. Like some of
Speaker 5:  them, you know, will just become basically gym instructor classes
Speaker 5:  like, like Peloton, you know, or like a lot of VR staff,
Speaker 5:  you know, some of them will just be constant competition, like the
Speaker 5:  cycling, you know, things and Strava and that's fine. You know, they, if
Speaker 5:  you like that sort of thing, you should do it. I do think there's still more
Speaker 5:  room for companies especially there's ar like becomes more of a thing
Speaker 5:  to do. Like even more fun ways of making
Speaker 5:  like sports and like competitive sports and cooperative sports. I, I really
Speaker 5:  wanna make like a cooperative fitness game. I think it'd be like so fun to
Speaker 5:  do that. So yeah, like I think there's a lot we can do there. Like the kind
Speaker 5:  of original gamified fitness is just playing like soccer, so like,
Speaker 5:  you know, maybe we just do more of that, but I can make it bit more convenient.
Speaker 6:  Are there any fitness apps or just like services
Speaker 6:  out there that you see and you're like, oh, I kind of dig what they're
Speaker 6:  doing then because we have seen so many of them just kind of take the
Speaker 6:  same leaderboard and competition approach to it. So is there
Speaker 6:  anyone out there that's doing it in a way that you're like, oh, that,
Speaker 6:  that actually seems like that's a cool way for us
Speaker 6:  anxious people out here? I have my list, but like us
Speaker 6:  anxious people out here to actually take a step back and like build
Speaker 6:  the foundational habits and get to the point where you're saying like, you
Speaker 6:  actually don't need it. Because I too am at the place where I'm like, oh,
Speaker 6:  I'm a week without a run. I feel bad I need to like actually
Speaker 6:  go out and do it.
Speaker 5:  I actually just use like the apple like fitness app and the health app a
Speaker 5:  lot to go and track my stuff, you know, like particularly things like sleep
Speaker 5:  and like heart rate recovery. So these are like more, more kind of technical
Speaker 5:  like things I, I don't like have like a third party app that I
Speaker 5:  use to track that. But it, it is useful because I've noticed it does
Speaker 5:  correlate actually with like when I've got more energy and I
Speaker 5:  do use, I use like the platform stuff because it just like
Speaker 5:  integrates the best. So if I'm going for a run or for a swim, I just use
Speaker 5:  whatever's on the Apple watch, which is boring, but I, I
Speaker 5:  kind of don't want to, I've sort of seen
Speaker 5:  pass a curtain I guess for a lot of the stuff and I kind of a bit, I'm a
Speaker 5:  bit worried about what people would try and do to my experience if
Speaker 5:  I let them, you know, I, I'm quite vulnerable to gamification.
Speaker 5:  I like, I like extended streaks, you know, if you, if you'd let me do it,
Speaker 5:  but even though I know it's not good for me and so I try and actually stay
Speaker 5:  away from, from a lot of that stuff. So going for the more vanilla
Speaker 5:  Apple watch stuff is, is what I tend to stay on.
Speaker 2:  Do you think about things like sleep tracking and we're getting
Speaker 2:  to these smart rings and all this stuff and we're, we're getting to a point
Speaker 2:  where there is this kind of like second by second 24
Speaker 2:  hour long ability to understand how you're doing and I'm like, somebody is
Speaker 2:  gonna make the next version of Zombies Run that is not like an episodic thing
Speaker 2:  that you put on headphones and listen to while you go exercise. It's going
Speaker 2:  to be like a lifestyle game. And part of me wonders if that is
Speaker 2:  super cool or totally dystopian and, and the idea
Speaker 2:  of like, I'm gonna get a thing at, you know, 2:00 AM that's just like zombies
Speaker 2:  because it it understood that I'm like in the right sleep zone for it
Speaker 2:  and like this is coming, we have the data to do this now and it, it feels
Speaker 2:  like it's coming and I can't decide if that's good or bad.
Speaker 5:  People keep on trying to do this and we, we tried to do it with a, with a
Speaker 5:  game called the Walk, which was kinda like a all day like, you know, walking
Speaker 5:  pedometer kind of thing. And I think
Speaker 5:  in practice it's quite hard to do because
Speaker 5:  people we found don't really like to be interrupted with like
Speaker 5:  gameplay and story. It, it, it's kind of annoying and, and so
Speaker 5:  the issue is that like third party developers generally do not have enough
Speaker 5:  contextual information about like what the person is doing
Speaker 5:  to like make sure that the interruptions work. But of course you want to
Speaker 5:  interrupt people. Like if you are like a line goes up business person, so,
Speaker 5:  so, but then that usually gets too annoying. So we did
Speaker 5:  try and and make like two or three times to go and make these these games
Speaker 5:  which would be kind of ambient. And I think at the point
Speaker 5:  at which using AI or using just more sensors, devs
Speaker 5:  have that ability then you will see more of that stuff and I think it will
Speaker 5:  actually end up looking really interesting and looking more
Speaker 5:  almost like role playing, right? It'll be like an even richer experience
Speaker 5:  and I know that people actually want to play these sorts of games where they're
Speaker 5:  kind of more into it at the same time. I think people probably be a little
Speaker 5:  bit like nervous about what that means. 'cause you know that if it's really
Speaker 5:  good it just actually takes over your life, right? And so do people really
Speaker 5:  want that just to get fit? I don't know.
Speaker 2:  As you look around this space right now, do you see any other things that,
Speaker 2:  that feel kind of spiritually similar to Zombie's Run? I think about
Speaker 2:  like we, we've all at the Virgin using this app called Stompers, which is
Speaker 2:  basically, it's like a, it's a sort of silly pedometer game and I think it
Speaker 2:  has hooked a lot of people in the same way that it's, it's not
Speaker 2:  even accurate, but being accurate is not the point. Like do you, do you
Speaker 2:  see anything that feels like it's sort of doing the same thing that the a
Speaker 2:  similar way,
Speaker 5:  I mean like one of the other things which I know vis written about w was
Speaker 5:  a whole fantasy hike thing where oh, and, and like, you know, and and like
Speaker 5:  before that it, it was just a direct rip off, you know, Lord of the Rings
Speaker 5:  where you're like walking from the Shire to like Moreor and I think
Speaker 5:  actually at the start you would just type in like how far you'd walked into
Speaker 5:  like a webpage and then it work it out and it got slowly more, more interesting
Speaker 5:  and that's cool. Like that's a fun thing. People have done various things
Speaker 5:  like that. There's a, a website or or an app called The Beautiful
Speaker 5:  Walk, which was kind of synced up to, to your,
Speaker 5:  you know, fitness apps and, and would do that like spiritually,
Speaker 5:  like a lot of the VR staff and ar stuff I
Speaker 5:  think is interesting in the sense of, you know, I
Speaker 5:  I come back to I want people to be having fun when they exercise. And
Speaker 5:  so I used to play like Hollow Point a lot,
Speaker 5:  which was this old
Speaker 5:  steam like five game and it was like an archery game
Speaker 5:  and basically you, you were just shooting, you're just using at, you know,
Speaker 5:  enemies in virtual reality, you know, arena with archery.
Speaker 5:  And the core thing was because the arrows
Speaker 5:  kind of like move slowly then you could dodge them. Like you can't dodge
Speaker 5:  bullets in real life, right? But like in super hot with other games you You
Speaker 5:  can dodge these and so you're always just like rolling around the floor and
Speaker 5:  jumping up and down and, and like it's just so energetic in a way
Speaker 5:  that like you could never get me to do that in real life. Like if you told
Speaker 5:  me, okay, go and go and fall over sideways and then go and scramble and roll
Speaker 5:  back and jump up. It's like I, no, I'm not doing that. But like you go and
Speaker 5:  put me in VR and there's like arrows coming at me and I'm like shooting people
Speaker 5:  of arrows. I'm like, this is the most fun I've ever had, but I don't
Speaker 5:  have room for it so I can't play that anymore. So that's kind of the problem,
Speaker 5:  like what I, I think and I, and I do see like the, you know, beat Saber
Speaker 5:  and Fit XR and things like that and I'm like, seems a bit boring
Speaker 5:  to me, you know, I want something a bit more involved than that. So
Speaker 2:  First of all, how dare you? Super
Speaker 5:  Is amazing.
Speaker 2:  Yes. This is, that's that was outrageous. But no, I I I'm glad you actually
Speaker 2:  mentioned super hot because Super Hot is one of those games that I found
Speaker 2:  to be like accidentally a surprisingly good workout. It's
Speaker 2:  like time only moves when you do. So I'm doing a ton of like very
Speaker 2:  deliberate, intense movement and I'm like, I'm sweating at the end and it's
Speaker 2:  like, all right, this is what I'm going for. This is like a fun thing that
Speaker 2:  made me sweat. Not a thing that bullied me into exercising,
Speaker 2:  which feels very different
Speaker 5:  I think when we get the glasses, you know, which we all want and not the
Speaker 5:  head, you know, the the VR headset, this is gonna be the way people exercise.
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be amazing. Like it's so cool but like it's just not there
Speaker 5:  at the moment. Like it's just too like, I don't know, it's like sweaty, like
Speaker 5:  I know people do use these things, but it, it's, it's for like for
Speaker 5:  most people it's it, you know, it doesn't seem to be a good experience. So
Speaker 5:  I think that's gonna be great. I think, you know, make believe and like role
Speaker 5:  play and sports, like that's one of the best ways of getting fit.
Speaker 6:  I think giving my per self permission to do the fantasy stuff, fantasy hike
Speaker 6:  to whack my editors with baseball bats and Stompers
Speaker 6:  has really just kind of made it easier to be like, oh
Speaker 6:  it's okay if I'm not so fast. It's okay, you know what, just give
Speaker 6:  yourself the participation trophy. That's the only real badge that you need.
Speaker 6:  It's okay, maybe it's 'cause I'm a millennial, but the participation trophy
Speaker 6:  is good enough.
Speaker 5:  Well it, I mean, you know, the way we put it in Zombies Run is as
Speaker 5:  long as You can boo faster than a slow shamble, then you know you're good
Speaker 5:  with us. So keep on trying things until you find
Speaker 5:  something that's fun and, and if it's
Speaker 7:  an advantage to having a handheld over that situation if I've already got
Speaker 7:  something like a game pass subscription? Thanks, appreciate it.
Speaker 7:  Bye.
Speaker 2:  I should say by the way, before we get started, thank you to everybody who
Speaker 2:  responded about our segment last week about gaming handhelds. I got
Speaker 2:  a ton of good ideas from people. I got a lot of people who just like felt
Speaker 2:  my pain about wanting to play FIFA and
Speaker 2:  not having a good device to do it on. People are mad at ea, I'm also mad
Speaker 2:  at ea thank you to everybody who reached out. I have a lot of gadgets to
Speaker 2:  try. I haven't bought anything yet, but I'm committed to answering this question
Speaker 2:  for real at some point very soon and I'll get back in touch. But thank you
Speaker 2:  to everybody who reached out with suggestions and ideas and commiseration,
Speaker 2:  I appreciate it. My answer for this question is actually
Speaker 2:  pretty simple. I just went through this recently and I
Speaker 2:  initially, I just went through this recently. My kid is about a year and
Speaker 2:  a half old at the beginning of 2023. I was in that like
Speaker 2:  sitting up at night for four hours while a small child
Speaker 2:  sleeps on my lap vibes and you're like, what do I do with myself? I tried
Speaker 2:  all the things for a while. I was carrying a switch around with me that
Speaker 2:  I would use in those moments. I had a couple of like tester
Speaker 2:  things. I got one of the slightly sketchy things from
Speaker 2:  Amazon that You can buy that have a million retro games on them.
Speaker 2:  I think the answer is just your phone. And I
Speaker 2:  think this for a couple of reasons. One, and this is the key one,
Speaker 2:  your phone is just there with you all the time. One of the things that happens
Speaker 2:  when you're a new parent is that you just suddenly find yourself frozen to
Speaker 2:  a place because your child just fell asleep. And You can
Speaker 2:  plan ahead to some extent and say like, okay, I'm gonna leave the switch
Speaker 2:  in the room with the chair where I'm probably gonna be while the kid is sleeping
Speaker 2:  or whatever. But your phone is just dramatically more likely
Speaker 2:  to be in your pocket, right? and it also has a lot
Speaker 2:  of retro games now especially, which are really great to play
Speaker 2:  A on silent and B for a couple of minutes at a time. When you're in those
Speaker 2:  moments where you're like, I don't know how long I'm gonna have to do this.
Speaker 2:  You can just quickly fire up Delta or one of the other emulators. And I
Speaker 2:  played, I would say maybe an alarming amount of like
Speaker 2:  old Mario games, a few minutes at a time with one thumb on
Speaker 2:  the joystick and one thumb on the buttons kind of wrapped
Speaker 2:  my arms around the, it was, it's, it's a, it's a scene but it works.
Speaker 2:  The other thing is it's really malleable, which I like, right? So I have
Speaker 2:  a backbone controller, which I like very much and when I was able to
Speaker 2:  sort of plan for it, I would use the backbone, I would bring the backbone
Speaker 2:  with me, I would plug it in, I would have the full better controller. And
Speaker 2:  that worked great. Works really well with a lot of games on
Speaker 2:  iOS and Android. Highly recommend a backbone as a sort of addition
Speaker 2:  to all of this. But when you don't have that, You can just use your phone,
Speaker 2:  right? And so having something that you're not stuck
Speaker 2:  because you forgot one piece of it is really helpful.
Speaker 2:  The other piece of it is that you will find yourself needing your phone for
Speaker 2:  all kinds of other things, right? Maybe you're gonna be one of those parents
Speaker 2:  like I was who has a spreadsheet of like every time your kid eats and sleeps
Speaker 2:  and goes to the bathroom and having that with you at the same time
Speaker 2:  that you have your like thing you wanna play games on. Super helpful.
Speaker 2:  If you are the type of parent who is going to be like texting your partner
Speaker 2:  or taking lots of pictures or whatever, again your phone just
Speaker 2:  becomes like the center of your baby universe in a very real way. And
Speaker 2:  so not adding another device to the equation is
Speaker 2:  sort of useful. There are good reasons to get a dedicated
Speaker 2:  device. Like I've, I've talked to a lot of people who bought a switch,
Speaker 2:  put like Zelda on it and then left it in the baby's room
Speaker 2:  and that becomes the like I am in the baby's room, this is the thing I'm
Speaker 2:  gonna play. There's something to that. But I think for me having fewer
Speaker 2:  batteries to worry about having the thing that's probably in my pocket be
Speaker 2:  the thing that works and having kind of the one device to rule them all
Speaker 2:  wound up being really helpful. Also, there are
Speaker 2:  a lot of games that I played that I would call like deeply
Speaker 2:  boring, repetitive games that are actually perfect for mobile. 'cause
Speaker 2:  you're in this headspace when you have a newborn where you're just exhausted
Speaker 2:  and you're like, okay, I wanna play a game. I don't wanna use my brain at
Speaker 2:  all and I'm gonna need to play this game for somewhere between one minute
Speaker 2:  and five hours. Games like hole down, which is basically a, it's, it's
Speaker 2:  like reverse snoo. You shoot a ball downward and you try to
Speaker 2:  remove all the stuff down at the bottom and the further you go down, the
Speaker 2:  more points you get endlessly repeatable games. I
Speaker 2:  probably played a hundred hours of that game and it's a perfect little mobile
Speaker 2:  game. You can play it with one hand, which is another victory given
Speaker 2:  baby's sleep situations. Having something You can do with one hand is pretty
Speaker 2:  helpful. I did a lot of like cross wordy kinds of
Speaker 2:  things when I was like, okay, I actually need to use my brain a little bit.
Speaker 2:  I did a lot of those like Temple
Speaker 2:  Run kind of endless runner games because again, super easy, super
Speaker 2:  repetitive, doesn't require any brain power. Those are the kinds of games
Speaker 2:  that I ended up playing way more than I expected. I was like, oh, I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  play a lot of like fun old PS two
Speaker 2:  games because now I have all this time to kill and I ended up playing like
Speaker 2:  infinite hours of hold down because it's just what happens in those
Speaker 2:  moments. You're tired, you have one hand des spare while there's a human
Speaker 2:  sleeping on top of you and that just is what it's, so I think the
Speaker 2:  answer is probably either a switch for the games or
Speaker 2:  your phone with a backbone or some other kind of controller. But
Speaker 2:  I would, I would start with your phone because there's a lot of games. It's
Speaker 2:  super easy, it's super accessible and odds are it's gonna be right there
Speaker 2:  with you, which is pretty important. I hope that helps. Let me know. And
Speaker 2:  again, I've gotten tons of really good handheld recommendations over the
Speaker 2:  last couple of weeks. And, if you have good ones for me or for Keaton here,
Speaker 2:  please let me know. Alright, that's it for The Verge Cast today. Thank you
Speaker 2:  to everyone who's on the show and thank you as always for listening. There's
Speaker 2:  lots more on everything we talked about from the Microsoft CrowdStrike chaos
Speaker 2:  to V's. Great reporting on wearables and rest days in the Apple Watch
Speaker 2:  to lots of stuff on gaming handhelds on The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  I'll put some links in the show notes, but also read The Verge dot com. There
Speaker 2:  is a shocking amount going on right now for it being like late July.
Speaker 2:  So keep an eye on the website and as always, if you have thoughts, questions,
Speaker 2:  feelings or gaming handheld you think I should buy, email us at vergecast
Speaker 2:  at The Verge dot com or call the hotline eight six six Verge one one. Keep
Speaker 2:  sending us questions. We've got lots more stuff to talk about this summer.
Speaker 2:  Please keep all of your questions coming. And like I mentioned last week,
Speaker 2:  I want more like teeny tiny weird tech mysteries. So if you have a
Speaker 2:  teeny tiny weird tech mystery, send it to us. Can't wait to hear it.
Speaker 2:  This show is produced by Andrew Marino,