# Transcript
ID: 8410c20d-1478-49cf-8739-254b879e68a0
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7345323237920002529/-8525728869536755130/s93290-US-5015s-1707212605.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of anti-glare coatings:
03:58 - Josh Miller, CEO The Browser Company, joins the show to chat about the Arc Search mobile browser.
Arc Search: a new iPhone app combining browser, search, and AI
The Arc browser is the Chrome replacement I've been waiting for
48:34 - Allison Johnson shares her review of the flagship Samsung Galaxy S24 phones.
Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra review: all that and AI
Samsung Galaxy S24 and S24 Plus review: smart choices
1:18:54- David Pierce answers a question from The Vergecast Hotline about the Apple Vision Pro.
Apple Vision Pro review: magic, until it’s not
Meta’s Quest headsets add spatial video and pinch controls to compete with Vision Pr
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (8 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Anti glare
Speaker 2:  coatings. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am doing my taxes.
Speaker 2:  It's that time of year, my friends, the one time a year I need a
Speaker 2:  printer. Mine is currently broken and suddenly I have to pretend that I understand
Speaker 2:  a lot more than I actually do about like complicated financial
Speaker 2:  documents. And honestly, most of all, this is the time of year that I
Speaker 2:  most wish I were more organized during the rest of the year so
Speaker 2:  that this wasn't such a painful process. I have this like beautiful filing
Speaker 2:  system that I never touch until right about now, and then I
Speaker 2:  regret all of my life choices over the past 12 months, but I don't really
Speaker 2:  see that dynamic changing anytime soon. So here we are. Anyway, we have
Speaker 2:  an awesome show for you today, but some quick housekeeping stuff before we
Speaker 2:  get to that. First thing you'll notice, it's Tuesday and this episode is
Speaker 2:  publishing. We are from now on going to be publishing The Vergecast on
Speaker 2:  Tuesdays and Fridays. There are a bunch of reasons for that, but mostly
Speaker 2:  it just lets us cover more stuff more quickly when we had to wait
Speaker 2:  until Wednesdays, it felt like we were doing a show and then really quickly
Speaker 2:  doing another show and then not doing a show for a bunch of days. So this
Speaker 2:  just kind of evenly spaces The Vergecast a little better. It'll let us be
Speaker 2:  more on top of the news. It'll let us do all kinds of stories and it won't,
Speaker 2:  you know, bunch our episodes up quite so much in your feed. Hope it's gonna
Speaker 2:  be great. Hope it doesn't screw up any of your routines. Please let us know
Speaker 2:  what you think. Also, we are gonna start having a full post on
Speaker 2:  The Verge dot com with all of our show notes, a whole bunch of links, lots
Speaker 2:  of information about every single episode we've heard all of you asking for
Speaker 2:  better show notes and more links to stuff you can read about that we talk
Speaker 2:  on the show. So we're just gonna start doing that at The Verge dot com slash
Speaker 2:  Vergecast. You'll be able to find all of that every single time we publish
Speaker 2:  an episode. That's a great place to leave comments, tell us what you think
Speaker 2:  of the episode. We're gonna try to do a good job of being in the comments
Speaker 2:  and talking to you and we want to hear all the dumb things we say and all
Speaker 2:  the times that you agree with me and not Eli, put it in the comments, tell
Speaker 2:  us everything. We have lots more changes coming soon actually,
Speaker 2:  especially on YouTube. So stay tuned. The Vergecast as a thing
Speaker 2:  is not changing so don't worry. But we have little ways we think we can do
Speaker 2:  everything a little better and make it all more fun to watch
Speaker 2:  and listen to and download and all that good stuff. So lots more coming.
Speaker 2:  Stay tuned. Alright, enough of that. Let's get to the show. The first thing
Speaker 2:  we're gonna do today is we're gonna talk to Josh Miller, who is the CEO of
Speaker 2:  a startup called the Browser Company, which is trying to basically nothing
Speaker 2:  short of reinvent the web browser and do some big
Speaker 2:  AI stuff and generally maybe change the internet forever. That
Speaker 2:  all sounds big and ambitious, but it is big and ambitious and it's fascinating.
Speaker 2:  Then we're gonna dig into all things Galaxy S 24 with Allison
Speaker 2:  Johnson because it's only February and we might have already
Speaker 2:  seen the most important Android phone of the year. All of that is coming
Speaker 2:  up in just a second. But first I have to go finish this one thing on this
Speaker 2:  tax form, which is literally a form I've never heard of before.
Speaker 2:  Hopefully this only takes a a minute. This is To Vergecast. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back over the last couple of years, this browser called Arc
Speaker 2:  has become super popular. It's available on Mac and iOS, it's coming to Windows
Speaker 2:  soon. People are super into it, which is weird honestly. I
Speaker 2:  mean when was the last time people got excited about a web browser, the
Speaker 5:  New Netscape power and ease of use. It's
Speaker 5:  free@netscape.com
Speaker 2:  But Arc has some cool unusual ideas about how
Speaker 2:  browsers should work and it's just so much nicer to use than Chrome
Speaker 2:  or Edge. It's just caught on for a lot of people. As a result,
Speaker 2:  last week, the Browser company, which is the company that makes Arc released
Speaker 2:  a new mobile app called Arc Search. It's a mobile browser and a pretty good
Speaker 2:  one, but it's way more than that. It's also an AI tool called
Speaker 2:  Browse. For me that is like a combination of search engine
Speaker 2:  ai, chat bot, webpage maker and a bunch of other things.
Speaker 2:  It's confusing to explain and frankly kind of hard. So let me just give you
Speaker 2:  an example. Let's see the Grammys were the other day, So, I go into
Speaker 2:  Arc Search on my phone and I say what happened at
Speaker 2:  the Grammys on Sunday? And then I type that in and then I hit
Speaker 2:  browse for me in Arc and it takes a second, it says it's reading
Speaker 2:  six webpage, CBS news, New York Times, stuff like that. And then it pops
Speaker 2:  up this page that says highlights of the 2024 Grammy Awards. This
Speaker 2:  is a completely AI generated webpage. It has a bunch of things at
Speaker 2:  the top like Killer Mike, the rapper was arrested,
Speaker 2:  Taylor Swift won her fourth album of the year award Women
Speaker 2:  Dominated. There was a physical altercation apparently it just says that
Speaker 2:  at the top. And then it has some search results and then it has
Speaker 2:  more information about Killer Mike being arrested. More information about
Speaker 2:  Taylor Swift's wins, more notable wins including
Speaker 2:  Tracy Chapman who didn't win but performed a duet. This is the thing about
Speaker 2:  ai, right? None of this is perfect, but anyway, it's this big long list of
Speaker 2:  information and links and media and videos to watch that is
Speaker 2:  all completely AI generated. It is building a webpage for me
Speaker 2:  every single time I search. It's neat and it doesn't always work as you can
Speaker 2:  see and it's weird, like a lot of AI stuff is weird, but it also points
Speaker 2:  at something really big about how the internet is changing. What does it
Speaker 2:  mean for the web that I can just get information like this? Arc
Speaker 2:  is essentially just Googling for me, which is handy, but it kind of
Speaker 2:  changes the whole dynamic of the internet. So I grabbed Josh Miller, the
Speaker 2:  Browser company's CEO to talk all of that through what Arc wants to
Speaker 2:  be, how it's gonna break the web apart and lots more. I've been talking to
Speaker 2:  Josh for years. I find Arc really fascinating honestly, and
Speaker 2:  he's always had these really big ideas about what a browser could
Speaker 2:  be and also why he thinks a browser is worth building in the first place.
Speaker 2:  And If you rewind four or five years ago, we're in this age back then
Speaker 2:  where a couple of operating systems rule the world, right? Android, iOS,
Speaker 2:  windows, Mac, you wanna do anything interesting. You have to reckon with
Speaker 2:  those oss and they are the ones that have the real control over how things
Speaker 2:  work. But Josh had this inkling at the time that the web and
Speaker 2:  specifically web-based apps were making a comeback.
Speaker 6:  Figma notion, slack, even discord. These are all
Speaker 6:  just secretly web apps running in web browsers pretending they're not
Speaker 6:  web browsers. And so the foundational observation of the browser
Speaker 6:  company was, oh my goodness, the next operating system
Speaker 6:  is right in front of our eyes. It's gonna look more like
Speaker 6:  a web Browser, it's gonna be a web browser design for the web because
Speaker 6:  essentially to use a Wall Street term, the cloud
Speaker 6:  is underestimated and the shift to the cloud is underestimated. It is a
Speaker 6:  fundamental shift that we take for granted that all of the things
Speaker 6:  in our life related technology are actually not in our lives anymore. They're
Speaker 6:  out on a server or many servers somewhere. And so the bet of the browser
Speaker 6:  company was If. you reimagine the interface to those things, to
Speaker 6:  the internet that would effectively become the most important operating system
Speaker 6:  in our lives. And to be totally self-aware, that was kind of all we
Speaker 6:  had at the time.
Speaker 2:  So that's the frame here, right? The web is the thing. It's as if the app
Speaker 2:  store was already around in 2004 or 2005 or
Speaker 2:  whatever and Apple went, huh, somebody should build an iPhone to run all
Speaker 2:  these things that might be cool. It's exactly backwards in the most
Speaker 2:  interesting way. That's ARC's big plan. And now with ai,
Speaker 2:  Arc can do that more and bigger and faster, but
Speaker 2:  what is it trying to do and is what it's trying to do what we
Speaker 2:  want both as users and like people on the internet. So that's where
Speaker 2:  Josh and I really got into it. I asked him, you know, you've been shouting
Speaker 2:  all this nonsense about web browsers for years now and this new app,
Speaker 2:  Arc Search feels like the closest thing yet to getting to that
Speaker 2:  idea about what an operating system can do to the web.
Speaker 2:  So does this feel like you've finished, like you've done the thing?
Speaker 6:  The first thing I'll say is now I know you thought I was spewing nonsense
Speaker 6:  for these past few years that we've been friends.
Speaker 2:  Listen, we're all spewing nonsense most of the time. It's okay,
Speaker 6:  We're all spewing nonsense. That's true. Another thing people don't tell
Speaker 6:  you when you're younger. Yes, but not for reasons. You may
Speaker 6:  think, okay, the reason that this new iPhone app,
Speaker 6:  Arc Search feels like the truest representation of what we've been saying
Speaker 6:  for many years. My dad has this phrase that he told me way too
Speaker 6:  many times growing up, which is disregard the words. And the idea
Speaker 6:  of this phrase is that we, we add these labels to things, these
Speaker 6:  nouns and they gain all this cultural meaning to the point where
Speaker 6:  we almost forget that they were made up. They don't actually mean they don't
Speaker 6:  represent the natural law. Yeah. And what we've been saying from
Speaker 6:  the beginning and the reason that we use these phrases, the internet, computer
Speaker 6:  and operating system for the web as imperfect as they were and as ambiguous
Speaker 6:  as they were, is that we were trying to say is that If you approach
Speaker 6:  software and interface it to the internet from a human perspective,
Speaker 6:  what does David need to do today? What does David's wife have to get
Speaker 6:  done today? Why are they turning to their computer? And you work backwards
Speaker 6:  from that. You probably don't need a thing called a web browser or
Speaker 6:  a search engine or a webpage 'cause those are random nouns that
Speaker 6:  were invented 25 years ago. The
Speaker 6:  reason that Arc Search represents in its purest form to date, our big
Speaker 6:  idea is that it's something different. It's something new,
Speaker 6:  it's kind of hard to put a label on it. You struggled with it in your review.
Speaker 6:  Is it a browser, is it a search engine? Is it ai, is it
Speaker 6:  something else? And that makes me really excited because that
Speaker 6:  is what we were trying to do. We were trying to start with what does David
Speaker 6:  need to do when he is at the restaurant with a bunch of friends and they
Speaker 6:  have a random question about something that comes up in conversation. Find
Speaker 6:  the answer to that as quickly as possible and we should employ whatever tools
Speaker 6:  and nouns and technologies we need to do that as quickly as possible.
Speaker 6:  And yeah, turns out, ends up looking a little different than web browsers
Speaker 6:  of 25 years ago and search engines of 25 years ago and web pages of
Speaker 6:  yesteryear. So that's what makes me so excited about Arc searches.
Speaker 6:  It's a reminder to ourselves and everybody that hey, we can invent new
Speaker 6:  nouns. And in fact if those new nouns are invented to solve
Speaker 6:  problems and realize goals that we have, they might even
Speaker 6:  be better than the old nouns. That's why I'm so excited about it and I'm,
Speaker 6:  one of our principles has always been the idea of a general purposed
Speaker 6:  web browser is deeply flawed.
Speaker 2:  So you just brought up a bunch of things that I wanna talk about, but we've
Speaker 2:  started to talk about the internet in a really different way than we used
Speaker 2:  to. Where I think you could make the case that we
Speaker 2:  got the internet that we got, which I think by and large is a
Speaker 2:  good version of the internet based on this like overall value
Speaker 2:  exchange that everyone agreed on, right? Like Google came up because
Speaker 2:  Google made a bet that what was good for the web would also be good for Google
Speaker 2:  and set itself up as a company that would worked that way. And it worked
Speaker 2:  that way for a really long time and it went super well for Google and I think
Speaker 2:  largely went well for the internet. Facebook built on some of the same premises,
Speaker 2:  right? Like there's this idea that I as a person on the internet am going
Speaker 2:  to get value out of something. The people who make the tools that I use are
Speaker 2:  also gonna get value that like everywhere along the way, if we can all find
Speaker 2:  win-wins the, it's gonna make the internet better. And I think with the
Speaker 2:  advent of ai, what it has come to is, okay, the internet exists,
Speaker 2:  it is now a thing to be mined for your benefit. And I think
Speaker 2:  the, the people who are mad at open AI and chat GPT and
Speaker 2:  the the New York Times suing over the training data, there's this idea that
Speaker 2:  like, well we made things and you used to take those things but you would
Speaker 2:  deliver value back to us and now you're just taking
Speaker 2:  them because the, the idea is that the internet is just out there and everything
Speaker 2:  that's out there is out there and you can just have it. And I think one of
Speaker 2:  the things that I thought was really interesting about Arc Search is not
Speaker 2:  only are you doing the LLM stuff, which I think is is interesting we should
Speaker 2:  talk about, but you're also, you're blocking ads by default. You're blocking
Speaker 2:  trackers by default, you're blocking the cookie popups by default. That's
Speaker 2:  a big series of I would say
Speaker 2:  potentially user-centric and maybe internet hostile
Speaker 2:  set of things to do. You rely on the internet to work
Speaker 2:  but you also are sort of tacitly agreeing that the way the internet works
Speaker 2:  doesn't really work. Like how do you do both of those at the same time?
Speaker 6:  I think If, you look back at maybe what some people would say were
Speaker 6:  the glory times for the early web when as you're alluding
Speaker 6:  to maybe the incentives were better aligned and the value exchange was better
Speaker 6:  aligned. I personally remember Craigslist decimating the
Speaker 6:  business models of the offline media companies and Yep. And especially in
Speaker 6:  newspapers because of the innovations at this moment in time when we're talking
Speaker 6:  about the value exchange being great, I actually order remember a lot
Speaker 6:  of second order negative externalities that came from the web at this glorious
Speaker 6:  moment. Yeah, that's
Speaker 2:  A good point.
Speaker 6:  My belief is that having worked at Facebook after selling my
Speaker 6:  first company there is that anything that transforms
Speaker 6:  our world, again sociology major has very positive things
Speaker 6:  that happen and has very negative things that happen, right? Airbnb is one
Speaker 6:  of my favorite products and experiences. It's ruining a lot of cities.
Speaker 6:  The same is true for almost everything that changes how we
Speaker 6:  live our lives as it relates to LLMs and AI and what
Speaker 6:  you're alluding to in terms of its relationship to the exchange of value.
Speaker 6:  I think the same is true here. I think it is absolutely
Speaker 6:  true that Arc Search and the fact that we remove the
Speaker 6:  clutter and BS and make you faster and get you what you need with
Speaker 6:  a lot less time is objectively good for
Speaker 6:  the vast majority of people. And it is also true.
Speaker 6:  It breaks something, it breaks a bit of the value exchange and not just Arc
Speaker 6:  Search but all of these tools, yeah it's, it's at one level higher than Arc
Speaker 6:  Search or chat GBT. We are grappling with a revolution
Speaker 6:  in how software works and computers work and
Speaker 6:  that's gonna mess some stuff up. And I totally agree with the premise
Speaker 6:  of the question which is hey, something's breaking and it is really gonna
Speaker 6:  break soon. I a hundred percent agree So I think the answer is
Speaker 6:  I think it will do more positive than negative. And I think it's kind of
Speaker 6:  unbelievable how much of humanity's time has been wasted by how atrocious
Speaker 6:  the mobile web is in support of the search ad business
Speaker 6:  model. And we gotta figure out a better way to get content creators and
Speaker 6:  publishers paid because it it, it's not gonna work and it's not
Speaker 6:  been working and it's not been working since Craigslist. So that is
Speaker 6:  definitely a challenge for us all to grapple with.
Speaker 2:  I do think the one difference, and don don't wanna like dwell on philosophies
Speaker 2:  of ai, but I think the one difference between the like Craigslist example,
Speaker 2:  which is a really good one and this is that Craigslist built a better
Speaker 2:  product than all of those things, right? Like and and I think what we're
Speaker 2:  learning about the media industry in particular is that the media industry
Speaker 2:  spent a long time build building really crappy products and got eaten alive
Speaker 2:  by better products. That just is what it is. And the next
Speaker 2:  reckoning is going to be like what does it look like for a media company
Speaker 2:  to build product? It's a thing we talk about all the time at The Verge. It's
Speaker 2:  like why we did the redesign of our website the way we did. It's like as
Speaker 2:  we think about all of our future, it's as much about product as it is about
Speaker 2:  anything else. And the difference between that and
Speaker 2:  what's happening now is that what's happening now with a lot of LLMs, one
Speaker 2:  way to look at it is it's as if Craigslist had taken
Speaker 2:  all of the classifieds out of all of the existing newspapers and just posted
Speaker 2:  them on the internet. And I think people would be like, well that's not a
Speaker 2:  better product that's you stealing from me and repackaging it in a new way.
Speaker 2:  And I think that would've been a very different version of the conversation.
Speaker 2:  And again, I think there is a lot of like society wide reckoning to do
Speaker 2:  about ai. There are a lot of people who are like, well the upside is so
Speaker 2:  high that it's worth the, you know, investment
Speaker 2:  of all of our stuff into it because we'll get more utility out of it.
Speaker 2:  But I just think like that fundamental question I don't think has precedent
Speaker 2:  on the internet because it's just never worked like this before and don don't
Speaker 2:  think we have answers to it, which is gonna be fascinating and now you're
Speaker 2:  right in the middle of it. So congratulations.
Speaker 6:  It's really exciting to think about from a media company perspective,
Speaker 6:  what is the superior product? What is that next evolution of
Speaker 6:  media? And what I would say is candidly I have a
Speaker 6:  deeper relationship with The Verge than I ever have before.
Speaker 6:  I've been reading The Verge for over a decade now. I have never spent
Speaker 6:  that much time and had that much depth with your, with your publication.
Speaker 6:  Now I'm not saying that the economic incentives of your ad model with podcasts
Speaker 6:  are working out, but that's all to say that in the same way that
Speaker 6:  Arc can rethink our interface to the internet in
Speaker 6:  a new way thanks to this technology, I think the answer probably lies
Speaker 6:  in the media industry and media companies rethinking what they do as well.
Speaker 6:  Sure.
Speaker 2:  And I will say to your credit, one thing you have said to me many times over
Speaker 2:  the years is that there is a big phase of this for Arc
Speaker 2:  that is figurine out how to like be a good citizen of all of those things.
Speaker 6:  You see this in Arc Search by the way, which is here's what we could have
Speaker 6:  done. You could have typed in a question to Arc Search and we could have
Speaker 6:  answered it and given ourselves all of the credit, right? Look
Speaker 6:  at how smart Arc is. It's the smartest thing that ever existed.
Speaker 6:  In fact what we do is we say extremely prominently
Speaker 6:  we don't, we actually don't even let you do anything else until you read
Speaker 6:  the fact that hey we are your browser.
Speaker 6:  We are gonna go read these six websites, these six
Speaker 6:  websites and then we are gonna summarize a little bit about what each of
Speaker 6:  those said and then we're gonna link to all of them. We're gonna link to
Speaker 6:  them multiple times, we're even gonna verify a pull quote from them. And
Speaker 6:  so I think again, this change is inevitable. I
Speaker 6:  think it's good for most people. I do think they're second order
Speaker 6:  externalities. I think it is the responsibility of folks like us to do
Speaker 6:  our best with the role that we have to be good
Speaker 6:  citizens and that's what we try to do here relative to other competing products
Speaker 6:  which I shouldn't name because I got Pr training but I don't think
Speaker 6:  it's enough. And I think the answer to this question is one level higher
Speaker 6:  than the browser company or Verge or anyone else. but it is absolutely something
Speaker 6:  we need to grapple with.
Speaker 2:  So, I'm glad you brought up the UX of it all because I think how is an
Speaker 2:  AI tool supposed to look is my favorite question in the world right now.
Speaker 2:  And I think people on this podcast are tired of hearing me rant about it.
Speaker 2:  But the one thing I believe for sure is that a text box is not The future
Speaker 2:  of the internet. But I'm curious, like the one thing I know about the browser
Speaker 2:  companies, you spend a lot of time prototyping, you spend a lot of time experimenting
Speaker 2:  and building stuff and you landed on Arc Search
Speaker 2:  the way it is, which is an interesting mix of kind of what I would call,
Speaker 2:  like there's media stuff at the top and then there's kind of a like
Speaker 2:  bulleted summary and then there's a bunch of links and then there's more
Speaker 2:  summary and then there's more links. Is that a, is that a fair description
Speaker 2:  of, of the situation? The
Speaker 6:  Two things that you're missing that I'm especially proud of is we embed YouTube
Speaker 6:  videos. True. So you can watch videos in line and then we embed
Speaker 6:  verified quotes where we pull a quote from one of the articles and
Speaker 6:  then we use AI and we say Hey ai, you
Speaker 6:  actually make stuff up a lot so do us a favor this pull quote you told
Speaker 6:  us you pulled, just go double check to make sure it's actually there. And
Speaker 6:  then if it is, then we say hey, this quote's verified, we can show it. So
Speaker 6:  those are two other interface innovations I'm especially proud of.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So of all of the things you tried and thought about and played with,
Speaker 2:  why did that feel like the right setup? I think we're, we're still
Speaker 2:  in this phase again of there are a million ways AI can
Speaker 2:  present itself to you. Most of them right now are chatbots. What about this
Speaker 2:  one stuck out to you as feeling right for Arc Search?
Speaker 6:  So as you mentioned we prototype a lot so we tried
Speaker 6:  50 variations of that experience before we landed on the exact
Speaker 6:  one you see in Arc Search today. And in fact down to the tiniest details
Speaker 6:  like do we show emojis as bullet points or do we just show bullet points?
Speaker 2:  You landed on emojis, which was the right call by the way.
Speaker 6:  Thank you. Thank you. I take no credit for it. Shout out to Nate. The way
Speaker 6:  that we landed on it is I agree with what you said
Speaker 6:  which is why does everyone think text boxes are like The future,
Speaker 6:  there's gotta be something better. But I think the way that we approached
Speaker 6:  it was not, you know, hey should it be this or should it be that?
Speaker 6:  We really try to approach it as hey let's write down
Speaker 6:  throughout the week what are the things we look up on the go on our phone?
Speaker 6:  Just quickly make a note of it and then let's go through all that stuff that
Speaker 6:  we turn to our computer in our pocket and our internet for
Speaker 6:  on the go. What are the commonalities, what are the sort of things we wonder
Speaker 6:  about? Okay, great. Looks like I'm really bad at cooking and at the age
Speaker 6:  of 33 I still don't know how to make couscous. That's
Speaker 6:  problematic for a bunch of reasons. But if I need to know how to make couscous
Speaker 6:  and I've got one hand 'cause my other hand is dirty and the water's
Speaker 6:  boiling and I got other stuff to do, what is the fastest way we can
Speaker 6:  get you the information for that job to be done and the others?
Speaker 6:  And what you end up finding is it's not just a wall of text,
Speaker 6:  it's not just photos, it's not just video, it's sort of a mixture of things
Speaker 6:  but it's all grounded in not, hey let's go make a product that is a webpage
Speaker 6:  or a text box or a a photo gallery. But we really try to do ground it in
Speaker 6:  what do you, what are you turning to this rectangle in your pocket for every
Speaker 6:  day and how can we craft a dynamic interface that
Speaker 6:  as best as possible tries to shapeshift itself to answer
Speaker 6:  exactly what you want. So what you'll notice is If, you ask Arc
Speaker 6:  Search for how to cook couscous, you're actually gonna get back a a
Speaker 6:  very different experience than If. you asked it what is the meaning of
Speaker 6:  life for example. Sure, sure.
Speaker 2:  It's very telling to me that the phone was the centerpiece of that. 'cause
Speaker 2:  one of the things I was gonna ask you is does this same paradigm make
Speaker 2:  sense on a desktop browser? And I almost
Speaker 2:  don't think that it does. one of the things you, you've always said to me,
Speaker 2:  which I think I mostly agree with is that most people don't want to use
Speaker 2:  technology. They have a thing they'd like to get done and they use technology
Speaker 2:  in service of that. They're not just like goofing around on their phone,
Speaker 2:  they mostly have like a a thing they'd like to do. And so your job is to
Speaker 2:  help them do it faster. And I think if that's how you think about it, the
Speaker 2:  way you put Arc Search together makes a lot of sense. But in in a world of
Speaker 2:  like I am just sitting here and I wanna like
Speaker 2:  learn as much about Machu Picchu as I can, the idea of
Speaker 2:  delivering me what Arc Search is, which is sort of like a finished product
Speaker 2:  thing makes a lot less sense but that's also not what people do on their
Speaker 2:  phone. So like does this feel like a sort of truly mobile
Speaker 2:  centric and even maybe mobile specific way of solving this problem?
Speaker 6:  So three things. The first is you're absolutely right that which
Speaker 6:  device you're on will radically change what it should and will
Speaker 6:  look like in Arc. Okay. And so the sort of questions you're wondering at
Speaker 6:  the bar when you're talking to your friend are different than when you're
Speaker 6:  at your desktop on a Sunday trying to do some big research project
Speaker 6:  for a big purchase. You and your wife are about to make fair. And so yes
Speaker 6:  it will look very different on desktop because what you're trying to do is
Speaker 6:  very different. The second thing is the principle behind
Speaker 6:  Arc Search, which is these artists formerly known as
Speaker 6:  the web browser, the search engine and webpages are archaic
Speaker 6:  ideas that should be merged and blended together into a
Speaker 6:  new dynamic interface. Definitely applies on desktop and
Speaker 6:  definitely applies on mobile in other ways. Okay? And an example
Speaker 6:  of that is on desktop, one of the features we just launched
Speaker 6:  is something we call instant links. And instant links you can
Speaker 6:  type in, you can hit new tab and on desktop in Arc
Speaker 6:  type videos of Steve Jobs unveiling the
Speaker 6:  iPhone iPod Macintosh and
Speaker 6:  iPad and hit enter and Arc will go out and it'll
Speaker 6:  grab a video of each of those Steve Jobs
Speaker 6:  unveiling events and put it right in your browser. You skip the search engine
Speaker 6:  altogether, right? That's the same idea, that's the exact same idea
Speaker 6:  but tailor to the thing you were trying to do on that device in
Speaker 6:  that moment. So that foundational principle of there's a new type of
Speaker 6:  software, a browser that browses for you, that merges these three things.
Speaker 6:  Is there, I think the final thing I'll note, which I think is more broadly
Speaker 6:  applicable is If, you were to really reduce down
Speaker 6:  this phrase ai, which also means kind of nothing correct and you
Speaker 6:  were to ruse down, reduce down even large language models, which also
Speaker 6:  kind of doesn't mean anything just sounds fancier. Yeah this sounds really
Speaker 6:  fancy and smart but don't ask me what So If you were to reduce
Speaker 6:  AI and LLMs down to their essence and explain it to a five-year-old.
Speaker 6:  The thing you would say is for the first time computers can read
Speaker 6:  and if computers can read then they can understand,
Speaker 6:  truly understand what you're asking them. And So I think really
Speaker 6:  the underlying principle of what Arc is doing
Speaker 6:  with this new category of software on mobile and desktop
Speaker 6:  is not actually even the output. That's not what's new.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, sure it will be new and that it'll be dynamic and it'll look and feel
Speaker 6:  a little different. It's the idea that you can go to Arc on mobile or desktop
Speaker 6:  and tell Arc what you're looking for and what you're trying to do.
Speaker 6:  And thanks to these large language models we can understand that for
Speaker 6:  the first time and route you to the right place and route
Speaker 6:  you to different things in different ways that wouldn't have been possible
Speaker 6:  before. That's really what's the most different to me. And I think people
Speaker 6:  fail to talk about that 'cause they tend to focus on, oh my god, it
Speaker 6:  just wrote me a haiku about computers even that why would I need a haiku
Speaker 6:  about, I mean it is wild, but that is not, that's not really what's fundamentally
Speaker 6:  new. It's the fact that our computers can read and think with us for the
Speaker 6:  first time. OpenAI has this product or this part of their API
Speaker 6:  called function calling and function calling is remarkable. What function
Speaker 6:  calling is able to do is it's able to allow us to
Speaker 6:  take an input from a person like you saying what are the best
Speaker 6:  iPhone chargers and then not only understand
Speaker 6:  what you're asking, but then based on its understanding, route it to
Speaker 6:  specific places and to specific things that actually have nothing to do with
Speaker 6:  ai. So one of the reasons that people including me many months ago
Speaker 6:  were a little bit bearish in all this AI hype was I was just seeing
Speaker 6:  these blobs of text outputted and assume that was ai.
Speaker 6:  No, no, no. That was just one output. But thanks to function calling
Speaker 6:  you can say, okay, if David is asking for videos
Speaker 6:  of Steve Jobs unveiling the iPod, iPhone Macintosh, great. He's
Speaker 6:  looking for these three videos. So go to YouTube and grab those videos. Hmm.
Speaker 6:  There's no hallucinating there. I mean again, it's gonna get it wrong. It's
Speaker 6:  technology, it's as imperfect as we are. But that's actually
Speaker 6:  wildly valuable and pretty unreal. Why isn't everyone talking about that?
Speaker 6:  And it's 'cause we get caught up in these memes and these words that just
Speaker 6:  mean everything and nothing to us. So function calling,
Speaker 6:  it's where it's at and there'll be more of those in The future.
Speaker 2:  That's super interesting. Well and that's also just like
Speaker 2:  straightforwardly the thing that comes after search engines, right? Like
Speaker 2:  you're in a certain way all that's doing is taking
Speaker 2:  what would be a Google results page with a bunch of ads at the top and just
Speaker 2:  skipping all of that. It's just saying, instead of me having to go
Speaker 2:  say, where's this video and then click on the video and then watch the video
Speaker 2:  and then save it to my sidebar, it's just putting those things in
Speaker 2:  my sidebar, which in a funny way to me is like actually way more understandable
Speaker 2:  than a lot of the AI stuff because one of the reactions to all of
Speaker 2:  these things is basically like actually Google's very good and
Speaker 2:  it's very good at finding information and maybe we don't need to just completely
Speaker 2:  reinvent this wheel with chatbots. And to a large extent, I'm actually really
Speaker 2:  receptive to that argument. I think Google is a lot less good than it used
Speaker 2:  to be, but it's still If. you wanna find a piece of information on the internet,
Speaker 2:  Google's pretty damn good. But then the next step
Speaker 2:  after Google alerting you to the existence of that information
Speaker 2:  is awful. And it's because web browsers suck. And this is like why I've always
Speaker 2:  thought Arc is interesting. So you've just sort of backed your way towards
Speaker 2:  the search engine and now you're, you're just like dis intermediating it
Speaker 2:  entirely. I
Speaker 6:  Agree. I think Google doesn't get enough credit for how it's innovated and
Speaker 6:  pushed search forward and how actually wondrous search is, and
Speaker 6:  I would push back on the idea that Google search gets us what we're looking
Speaker 6:  for because if aliens arrive tomorrow and they're like, look, I just read
Speaker 6:  this great book, God Saved Texas by Lawrence Wright on the Spaceship Write
Speaker 6:  over and I'm looking for a new book. And you went to Google and you
Speaker 6:  typed in books similar to Gods Safe Texas by Lawrence Wright
Speaker 6:  and then wow, magically so fast Google brought you what
Speaker 6:  you wanted. Alien's like, oh wow. Are those books, well no, not quite.
Speaker 6:  Those are called links and those links, yeah, yeah. Click on the
Speaker 6:  link, the book's gonna be in there. Oh no. So these aren't books either.
Speaker 6:  These are listicles and in the listicles are books and then If, you click
Speaker 6:  on this other thing, those are books. So the truth is that
Speaker 6:  there are these abstractions that we forget about, but
Speaker 6:  Google doesn't really bring on one hand to make it simple.
Speaker 6:  Google brings you what you're asking for in the sense that it brings back
Speaker 6:  a bunch of links and on the other hand, it doesn't bring you what you're
Speaker 6:  asking for and that it makes you stop at Google first. And oftentimes the
Speaker 6:  thing you're looking for are buried in a bunch of links in a bunch of links
Speaker 6:  behind that. And now we have the technology to say, let's just go straight
Speaker 6:  to bringing you what you want and bring it right to you. That's a, that's
Speaker 6:  a pretty big idea. And that's exactly how a human being wants it to
Speaker 6:  work.
Speaker 2:  I agree and disagree with that and the, I like, I'm glad you put it that
Speaker 2:  way because I think one of the fun things we're going through right now because
Speaker 2:  of AI is trying to figure out which
Speaker 2:  new ideas are better enough to be worth unlearning decades
Speaker 2:  worth of habits and which aren't, right? Like I think about don don't
Speaker 2:  know Siri and Google Assistant and Alexa, right? And the idea that voice
Speaker 2:  is a much more natural interface for asking for information than typing on
Speaker 2:  a keyboard unequivocally true. The tech wasn't very good and
Speaker 2:  also people are not used to it. And so we all kind of were just like, well
Speaker 2:  it's pretty easy to type on my phone, I'll just do that. Instead, I just
Speaker 2:  was interviewing somebody for a future episode of the show about keyboard
Speaker 2:  layouts and like, you know, what's better than wordy keyboard layouts is
Speaker 2:  everything else, but good luck trying to convince people to not use Krty
Speaker 2:  keyboards, right? So I think that question of can you build something that
Speaker 2:  is so much better that it will actually make people
Speaker 2:  make real behavioral change versus like, no it's,
Speaker 2:  it's not the most human natural thing in the world that we all sort of learned
Speaker 2:  how to type in what Google calls keyword ease. But I'm pretty
Speaker 2:  good at it now. Like I, I can get what I want out of Google pretty
Speaker 2:  successfully and so, you know, screw the aliens, what's it gonna take for
Speaker 2:  me to switch, I think is is very much the open question and this like path
Speaker 2:  of AI over the next two years I think is really where we're gonna start to
Speaker 2:  see where it does and doesn't clear the bar. And I think it's gonna be fascinating.
Speaker 6:  I agree with you unless you're a web browser. Okay, and this is
Speaker 6:  exactly why we built a web browser. This is exactly why operating systems
Speaker 6:  have so much leverage in how we use technology in that if I were to make
Speaker 6:  an AI chat bot app called Chatty and it got really
Speaker 6:  popular and wanted to radically change the way we get information,
Speaker 6:  you gotta remember to go to that tab and as you said, you have this great
Speaker 6:  muscle memory. you know, it may be chatty is better than Google, but
Speaker 6:  you have to remember to instead of hitting new tab or command t, go
Speaker 6:  to that chatty tab. Yep. That's really hard to your, it really is.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's really hard if in fact you are the web
Speaker 6:  Browser and you are the text box that people type into
Speaker 6:  to go to Google, you don't need to change your behavior. Mm. Your behavior
Speaker 6:  actually doesn't happen in Google. Google's just a tab two. Everyone forgets
Speaker 6:  that it's actually the browser that is your interface to the web and is the
Speaker 6:  Browser where your muscle memory is and then you might say, yeah, well If,
Speaker 6:  you send me to Chatty instead of Google. I'm still gonna be mad because I
Speaker 6:  wanted Google because Chatty's not as good at all the searches. Well great
Speaker 6:  thanks to function calling and thanks to ai we can know if you're
Speaker 6:  asking us something that really Google's the best at or should what
Speaker 6:  you send send you to Chatty or should we not send you anywhere? Should we
Speaker 6:  just bring it to you? So one of the other features that we're launching on
Speaker 6:  Arc for Mac is, I hate to admit it, I have
Speaker 6:  an alert set up and not even alert at some regular
Speaker 6:  interval. I go to Google and I type news about the Browser company or news
Speaker 6:  about Arc Browser and I do that a lot. We have a new feature called live
Speaker 6:  folders where whenever there's a new press story hopefully written by David
Speaker 6:  Pierce and hopefully glowing about Arc, it'll just pop up in my
Speaker 6:  sidebar. don don't even need to go to search. So again, because we're the
Speaker 6:  web browser, you don't have to change ingrained behavior. We're just gonna
Speaker 6:  pop it up right in your sidebar. So yes, I think people underestimate
Speaker 6:  how ingrained behaviors are and how hard it is to get people to change anything
Speaker 6:  because at the end of the day they don't really care about technology and
Speaker 6:  that is exactly why we built a web Browser. Everyone thought we,
Speaker 6:  why would you work on a desktop web browser? It could not be more boring.
Speaker 6:  Well it's actually in, in fact because it's so boring that we wanna work
Speaker 6:  on it because you happen to use it for eight hours a day and so If, you use
Speaker 6:  it for eight hours a day and you're all over this rectangle. If we place
Speaker 6:  things in this rectangle or if we change where you go in the rectangle, when
Speaker 6:  you type in something that's actually a great place to be to change
Speaker 6:  entrench behavior without you having to change anything yourself, just
Speaker 6:  abstracting that complexity. All we're proposing with Arc and this idea of
Speaker 6:  a browser that browses for you is that we can then do
Speaker 6:  to Google what Google did to the web, Google and all these other applications
Speaker 6:  we use, which is wow, there are now so many web apps open and
Speaker 6:  tabs and Google Docs and all of these things. It's too much to reason
Speaker 6:  about, I have to do 10 search queries just to find what I'm looking for.
Speaker 6:  It's time for a layer that sits above that which says, you tell us what you're
Speaker 6:  trying to do and we'll go use the search engines and web apps and read the
Speaker 6:  articles for you. So that's the other thing that feels so exciting is it
Speaker 6:  feels like a natural kind of march of progress toward
Speaker 6:  making it your day easier and easier until one day you can
Speaker 6:  really just tell Arc or whatever software comes next what
Speaker 6:  you're trying to do and it will go figure out what on the internet you want
Speaker 6:  to use.
Speaker 2:  If you're right, two companies come to mind that are sort
Speaker 2:  of perfectly set up to do the vertically integrated thing
Speaker 2:  you're describing, which are Google and Microsoft, like they're sitting on
Speaker 2:  the whole tech stack more so than you are to do all of
Speaker 2:  the things that you just described. Google has Google, Google has
Speaker 2:  Chrome, Google has Gemini and all of its like all it has to do is like
Speaker 2:  put three project managers in a room together and they could start to build
Speaker 2:  something similar to what you're describing. Microsoft's the same with Bing
Speaker 2:  and all the open AI stuff and what's to prevent them from
Speaker 2:  doing this too. I think there's real energy in the browser space
Speaker 2:  because of this for the first time and right now so much of it is just like
Speaker 2:  we stick a chat bot or sidebar or some of the little
Speaker 2:  organizational stuff like Google just launched a bunch of stuff in Chrome
Speaker 2:  that is basically like less interesting feature rips of what
Speaker 2:  Arc Max was doing a few months ago. But they with real
Speaker 2:  energy and resources, they could out muscle you in pretty much every direction
Speaker 2:  here if they chose to, right?
Speaker 6:  You are absolutely right that I view our true competition
Speaker 6:  as Microsoft, Google, and Apple. Sure. I actually
Speaker 6:  think Apple is the one that is in the best position to do this and
Speaker 6:  they're all trillion dollar companies with everything.
Speaker 6:  Of course that is terrifying. And of course that is gonna be
Speaker 6:  a big challenge. you know there's this famous story about Google Chrome
Speaker 6:  where when you open a new tab, you see the new tab page,
Speaker 6:  it shows you a tile of your most frequently visited sites
Speaker 6:  and the way that they used to show those tiles were with screenshots, you
Speaker 6:  know, a picture of the webpage and then this PM had this idea, you know,
Speaker 6:  it's actually much easier and faster to just show the logo
Speaker 6:  of the website because people can more quickly identify, oh that
Speaker 6:  tile is Twitter than it is to identify the screenshot. And that
Speaker 6:  PM was right. It made it so much easier for people to quickly
Speaker 6:  find what they were looking for by clicking on one of those tiles. There
Speaker 6:  was a major freak out at Google because overnight
Speaker 6:  ad revenue search ad revenue dropped by 5%, which is a
Speaker 6:  huge deal at Google scale. Yeah, 5% red alert. What
Speaker 6:  happened, what did we change? And it turned out that this pm making it easier
Speaker 6:  for people to get what they needed faster in the web browser tanked
Speaker 6:  Google's global ad revenue because when you click on a
Speaker 6:  tile, you're not doing a Google search. So on paper, do
Speaker 6:  Google and Microsoft have everything it takes? Yes.
Speaker 6:  Is there a lot of structural challenges to big public companies with shareholder
Speaker 6:  pressures not to hurt the cash cow that is search ads? Yes,
Speaker 6:  sure Can I remember the last time that Google and
Speaker 6:  Microsoft invented something wildly new that
Speaker 6:  revolutionized a category where nothing had come before it?
Speaker 6:  No. Is this time different? Potentially we're gonna pretend like we're
Speaker 6:  competing with them in a really big way. Yeah, but I think that we're just
Speaker 6:  gonna keep doing our thing and hope that they keep loving search ads. Fair
Speaker 2:  Enough. So the the reason I would think in that way of thinking to be
Speaker 2:  most curious about what Apple is up to is that it seems to have a lot of
Speaker 2:  those same capabilities and less to lose
Speaker 2:  as a search business essentially like safari. I
Speaker 2:  mean the whole Google antitrust thing makes this very interesting with the
Speaker 2:  safari ads deal that could get very complicated over time, but Apple
Speaker 2:  seems to have a big, very successful, very popular browser that makes it
Speaker 2:  a lot less, is a lot less important to its future as a company
Speaker 2:  than say Chrome is to Google.
Speaker 6:  I actually think you're putting a little too much emphasis on search. I think
Speaker 6:  it's one or two levels higher than that. Okay. What we're really talking
Speaker 6:  about is this idea, which by the way is not original to us, but the idea
Speaker 6:  is you tell Arc or you tell your interface to your computer or the internet
Speaker 6:  what you're trying to do and then in this new world it will go
Speaker 6:  use whatever tools and any information it needs to do it for you and bring
Speaker 6:  it back to you. There's almost universal agreement that's how it's gonna
Speaker 6:  work. And in order for that to work, you need three things. First
Speaker 6:  you need a really rich data set about each individual,
Speaker 6:  everything that's going on in their personal life, professional life, what
Speaker 6:  they type in text boxes, what they read on webpage, the documents that matter
Speaker 6:  to their work. So you need, you need a unique data set about each individual.
Speaker 6:  The second thing you need is you need the ability to manipulate
Speaker 6:  all of the tools and the applications that people rely on to do what they
Speaker 6:  do on their computers and on the internet said differently. You need them
Speaker 6:  to be logged into the apps. Sure. The third thing that you need
Speaker 6:  is you need an interface. To your point about behavior change that
Speaker 6:  people use all the time, all day, every day, they don't need to change anything
Speaker 6:  they do, they just keep doing their thing and you can then
Speaker 6:  go put The future in those places. You need those three things.
Speaker 6:  There are only two types of software that have
Speaker 6:  those three things. The first are operating systems, the second
Speaker 6:  are web browsers. I promise you there is no way that The future
Speaker 6:  powered by AI will exist in anything other than an
Speaker 6:  operating system or a web. Browser, So, I. The only thing that keeps me
Speaker 6:  up at night are web browser companies and operating system companies because
Speaker 6:  I think those are the only two type of companies that have a shot at reimagining
Speaker 6:  our interface to the internet. So
Speaker 2:  Last thing, and this is a question I've been meaning to ask you for several
Speaker 2:  weeks now. Did you see the rabbit launch at CES? This little
Speaker 2:  AI gadget thing? I saw that thing and I, after
Speaker 2:  talking about a lot of the stuff that you and I have been talking about for
Speaker 2:  a while and a lot of stuff you've been talking about now, I looked at that
Speaker 2:  and I was like, okay, if, if Josh and the browser company had become a hardware
Speaker 2:  company, this is roughly what they would've gone after. The same idea
Speaker 2:  of like, okay, if the goal is to have these tools accomplish
Speaker 2:  something on your behalf, instead of building me like a nice web browser
Speaker 2:  that I'm in all day, you would've built me like a fun teenage engineering
Speaker 2:  gadget that I can press a button and talk to all day. Does that feel right
Speaker 2:  to you? What did you make of what rabbit's up to?
Speaker 6:  First of all, I love anyone that dares to dream
Speaker 6:  and anyone that just goes for it and I love that energy.
Speaker 2:  They are nothing if not going for it. That team,
Speaker 6:  I love anyone that stands up on a metaphorical stage and says, I'm
Speaker 6:  excited. I think The future should work like this and I'm gonna dedicate
Speaker 6:  my life to doing something really bold and different than what we're used
Speaker 6:  to. So, I have a lot of respect for that. I also totally agree that
Speaker 6:  The future is going to work like you telling your computer whether it's
Speaker 6:  Arc or Rabbit, what you wanna do and it should go do it for you and abstract
Speaker 6:  that complexity. I think the one place where I personally
Speaker 6:  see a slightly different future is I don't want
Speaker 6:  more gadgets in my life. Okay? I don't want more devices.
Speaker 6:  I think the secular trend to the cloud and the secular
Speaker 6:  trend toward our stuff, our digital stuff, being out on a server
Speaker 6:  somewhere, whether it's an application or our data, is that we can actually
Speaker 6:  kind of free ourselves from the machines. We can free ourself from the devices
Speaker 6:  because they're everywhere. I was on a united flight last night, I was like,
Speaker 6:  I'm not sure if the this, for the first time this seat in front of me could
Speaker 6:  probably run the Vision Pro. It's like it's the computers are going everywhere
Speaker 6:  and so what I'm really excited about is a world in which the computer
Speaker 6:  and air quotes that you talk to, the place it has all of your data and stuff
Speaker 6:  is not another new box I gotta put somewhere on my
Speaker 6:  body, whether that's on my face or in my pocket or another button
Speaker 6:  I gotta remember to press instead of that other button. But oh wait, that's
Speaker 6:  not the action button. That's the volume and screenshot. What I'm really
Speaker 6:  excited about is the idea that your computing life just goes with you
Speaker 6:  everywhere to every device. But I do think the rabbit is
Speaker 6:  fascinating from a vision perspective and a boldness perspective and I probably
Speaker 6:  have a lot more in common with whoever started that company than I do
Speaker 6:  with someone else that I shouldn't name.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. So what you just made me realize is that I've been talking about
Speaker 2:  Arc in terms of Chrome for a really long time and I should have been talking
Speaker 2:  about it in terms of Chrome OS for a really long time
Speaker 6:  Internet computer operating system for the web.
Speaker 2:  But what you're describing, and you know one of the things you announced
Speaker 2:  last week was this thing. Was it Arc anywhere the new syncing service
Speaker 2:  that becomes very important, right? Because what you're essentially building
Speaker 2:  me is not a piece of software that lives on my computer. You're building
Speaker 2:  me a piece of software that lives everywhere that I can just sort of
Speaker 2:  tap into in whatever way I need to, whenever I need to. And all
Speaker 2:  of a sudden like Arc anywhere becomes the thing as much as
Speaker 2:  whatever it is on my device becomes the thing.
Speaker 6:  Arc anywhere is the product. Arc anywhere is the computer. Okay,
Speaker 2:  This all just clicked in my brain as you were talking. This is
Speaker 6:  Why we have to talk more. It isn't today, I'm not don, don't wanna over promise.
Speaker 6:  It is a cross platform sinking mechanism for getting your tabs wherever you
Speaker 6:  need them. But right behind you on this recording you have a tv, it looks
Speaker 6:  like a TV sitting up on a little nightstand. It's a
Speaker 2:  Piece of crap. Never buy a Roku TV people. Well
Speaker 6:  One day that piece of crap computer in five years will actually be a very
Speaker 6:  powerful computer. Just like the phone in our pocket is
Speaker 6:  a much more powerful computer than it was a decade ago. And so the idea of
Speaker 6:  Arc and Arc anywhere is that one day when you're sitting on that couch behind
Speaker 6:  you, looking at that screen you're looking at, which is now as powerful as
Speaker 6:  the iPhone in your pocket, you should just be able to toss at
Speaker 6:  a glance and authenticate that it's you. And then you're in air
Speaker 6:  quotes, computer, all of your apps and data and conversations and people
Speaker 6:  should appear on that screen. That is the whole idea of Arc.
Speaker 6:  That is the idea of this next wave is that your computer is just an
Speaker 6:  old noun for saying the stuff that matters in your digital life
Speaker 6:  that is yours. And that should go with you anywhere, on any screen, on any
Speaker 6:  device and the way that you, it should interface with it in The future is
Speaker 6:  not opening seven applications and 19 search query tabs and 27
Speaker 6:  listicles. You should just tell the device in your life through Arc,
Speaker 6:  here's what I'm trying to do and it should bring it to you. It should be
Speaker 6:  a a browser that browses for you or a better tagline. 'cause I don't love
Speaker 6:  that tagline, but it feels weird to invent your own noun.
Speaker 7:  Alright, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna
Speaker 8:  Talk Samsung and we're gonna talk galaxies.
Speaker 7:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. It's been a couple of weeks now since Samsung launched.
Speaker 2:  Its new devices, the Galaxy, S 24, S 24 plus, and S 24
Speaker 2:  Ultra, which means the Verges Allison. Johnson has had time to put
Speaker 2:  all three of those phones through their paces and she's published their reviews.
Speaker 2:  They're on The Verge dot com. Put 'em in the show notes and like I said,
Speaker 2:  post on the site with all the links you need. It's wild to think that it
Speaker 2:  is only the first week of February and we might have already seen the
Speaker 2:  best Android phone of 2024, but I think that might be the case.
Speaker 2:  Samsung as always, has done some of its usual upgrades here with
Speaker 2:  better screens and some design tweaks and a little bit of new camera hardware.
Speaker 2:  But most of what's new here is ai. There is so,
Speaker 2:  so, so much AI in these phones, it's nuts. But
Speaker 2:  does it add up to anything or is it all just another gimmick in
Speaker 2:  Samsung's long, long line of phone gimmicks. Like I said,
Speaker 2:  Allison has tried it all and she's here to answer that for us. Hi Allison.
Speaker 2:  Hello. Welcome out of Samsung Chaos. This is very exciting for
Speaker 2:  you.
Speaker 13:  Thank you. It was a recent development so I'm happy to be here.
Speaker 2:  This is a tough time because you basically had to take three different phones
Speaker 2:  that are the same phone but different phones and try to figure out how to
Speaker 2:  like make them make sense and also write something that is interesting to
Speaker 2:  read about all of them, which is a difficult challenge.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. And the same challenge as like most phones lately
Speaker 13:  where the updates are just pretty incremental.
Speaker 13:  Aside from Galaxy ai, which is a whole thing that you know we'll get
Speaker 13:  into, but it's just an interesting dynamic looking at it this year.
Speaker 13:  Like the Ultra has always been the like we're just gonna throw everything
Speaker 13:  in a phone. And for the past couple years that has been like,
Speaker 13:  this is great, like you guys are killing it. And then the
Speaker 13:  the regular ones, the s and S plus just sort of felt like
Speaker 13:  they're good. They're a good alternative if you're like okay with
Speaker 13:  Samsung's take on things and you want a really good Android phone.
Speaker 13:  Right. And that's sort of the case this year, but it's like slightly different.
Speaker 2:  Okay. We're, we're about to spoil where I was going with all this, but I
Speaker 2:  kind of think it's the opposite this year. Oh really? Like so the Ultra is
Speaker 2:  still very much the kitchen sink phone. Like it is the Samsung
Speaker 2:  iest of Samsung phones and I mean that both as a compliment and an insult
Speaker 2:  as always with Samsung, but to me I got to the end of all
Speaker 2:  your reviews and I was like okay, for the first time in a few years, I actually
Speaker 2:  think the base Galaxy S 24 is the best
Speaker 2:  Galaxy phone. Yeah. For most people right now. Which I don't feel like has
Speaker 2:  been true for don. Don't know at least the last few years I feel like I would've
Speaker 2:  always tried to talk people up and now I'm kind of like you
Speaker 2:  get almost all the stuff in a slightly better size
Speaker 2:  for $799 instead of $1,299. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  With the base model like big win for the base model this year. It
Speaker 13:  Is, it's a big win for people who like smaller big phones
Speaker 13:  'cause they're all big. They're
Speaker 2:  All big.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, no that sums up how I feel about them and I guess I
Speaker 13:  think of like the Ultra just always kind of feels like it's
Speaker 13:  in its own little atmosphere. It's like what
Speaker 13:  phone do you compare it to that has an spen and 12 cameras, you know?
Speaker 13:  That's
Speaker 2:  Very true.
Speaker 13:  It's kind of always felt to me like you sort of know if
Speaker 13:  that's the thing you want and you want all that extra.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. What feels different this year is that nothing on the
Speaker 13:  Ultra just feels like, oh yeah, I totally see why this is worth the
Speaker 13:  extra money because it is more money this year. It's 1299,
Speaker 13:  which is a hundred dollars more than last year. And yeah,
Speaker 13:  all of the exciting new features like air quotes,
Speaker 13:  that's Samsung's words, the AI are on all
Speaker 13:  three phones, like with no differences in how they
Speaker 13:  perform or any of that. And this little phone, the regular S
Speaker 13:  24 just feels like a good size and I'm happy it's here.
Speaker 13:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So, okay, let, let's talk through this a little bit because I think the first
Speaker 2:  thing you pointed out to me right before we started recording is the actual
Speaker 2:  physical object itself, which is again a thing I think that is sort of
Speaker 2:  carried through all three versions of the phone. Correct me if
Speaker 2:  I'm wrong, but they made this thing what seems to be a little, it's a little
Speaker 2:  nicer. It's, it's nicer to hold in the hand. Samsung has a long history
Speaker 2:  of making just the slipperiest phones on the face of the earth and and
Speaker 2:  it seems like they solve some of that this time.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, well Google took that crown away. Like pixel
Speaker 13:  is the most slippery. It really is. Object. It should be studied by
Speaker 13:  scientists. I don't understand it. Yeah, no like Samsung,
Speaker 13:  the Ultra still has, it has the flat screen this year which like,
Speaker 13:  yay you have an spen, you want a flat screen, you're like running the pen
Speaker 13:  over the edge that stinks. Still has a little bit of that
Speaker 13:  like note design, the S 24, the S 24
Speaker 13:  plus they, I'm just gonna say it like they are just straight up
Speaker 13:  iPhones and that's fine. Like they have the,
Speaker 13:  the flat edges. The S 23 was still kind of a
Speaker 13:  curved edge, still had kind of a, I don't really wanna call
Speaker 13:  it a Samsung look, it had a different look to it. It's not like a
Speaker 13:  drastically different change, but I find it more
Speaker 13:  comfortable to hold when I go to pick it up off of the table. It doesn't
Speaker 13:  like fly outta my hands. They look great, they feel great and I
Speaker 13:  think like why reinvent the shape of a phone? Just
Speaker 13:  go with what works.
Speaker 2:  I agree. I feel like the two things that have always driven me crazy about
Speaker 2:  some of these designs are either I'm holding it in my hand and it kind of
Speaker 2:  digs into your palm in a way that feels bad or,
Speaker 2:  and this is really my true slipperiness test. I'm holding the phone in my
Speaker 2:  hand and I go to put it in my pocket and there have been phones that
Speaker 2:  in the motion of like moving it down to put it in my pocket, I have just
Speaker 2:  thrown it onto the ground. Yeah. Like I don't even drop it. Like I slingshot
Speaker 2:  it out of my hand onto the ground. Yeah.
Speaker 13:  With prejudice. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 2:  And yeah and the pixel is maybe the worst at that. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  In history. But that is like the, the iPhone is they, they found the right
Speaker 2:  mix of like the flat edges and the sort of rounded corners and it just like,
Speaker 2:  it feels like an object in a nice way And I, I'm, I'm glad that Samsung
Speaker 2:  has landed in that same place.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. My Galaxy brain take is that phones over the next year
Speaker 13:  are just gonna converge on that design. Like the pixel nine leaks,
Speaker 13:  have the flat edges like this is fine, let's just do it.
Speaker 13:  Let's embrace it. We're gonna go there.
Speaker 2:  I think that's for the best honestly. Yeah. It's like there was that phase
Speaker 2:  with laptops where everybody was like, what if they did weird stuff
Speaker 2:  and they flipped around and moved to the left and we just moved the track
Speaker 2:  pad over here and everybody was like, oh no, what if it just looked like
Speaker 2:  a laptop and we worried about other things And that is, that is the correct
Speaker 2:  answer.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. Nobody's like, oh I wish my refrigerator looked cooler
Speaker 13:  and different than other different, it was like you just wanna know where
Speaker 13:  stuff is.
Speaker 2:  A hundred percent. So my first question with all Samsung phones is
Speaker 2:  how Samsung are these Samsung phones? And I will say too,
Speaker 2:  Samsung's credit, it used to be horrific. Yeah. I used to tell people do
Speaker 2:  not buy a Samsung phone because it will torture you with popups and
Speaker 2:  duplicate apps and things you'll hate. And I no longer feel
Speaker 2:  quite that strongly, but I still think one UI is a mess in
Speaker 2:  certain ways. So how, how Samsung are these phones this year?
Speaker 13:  They're like tolerably. Samsung. Okay. You do, there
Speaker 13:  is the like list of stuff I go through when I'm setting up a Samsung phone
Speaker 13:  and it is much longer than any other phone I use.
Speaker 13:  You have to sort the app drawer. So apps
Speaker 13:  are alphabetical instead of just like nonsense order
Speaker 2:  Sounds right.
Speaker 13:  There's 10 million things in the quick menu
Speaker 13:  settings. All that is still a reality. It's it's just like, and this is
Speaker 13:  kind of where I keep landing with like Pixel versus Samsung is that
Speaker 13:  you just kind of have to work for it a little harder with the Samsung. You
Speaker 13:  put in the work ahead of time, you disable the popup notification
Speaker 13:  like sell me a new Galaxy S series phone. Like I don't
Speaker 13:  need that. I'm using the new Galaxy S series phone.
Speaker 2:  That was one of your best lines in the review is opening up a Galaxy S 24
Speaker 2:  setting it up and getting a popup saying, have you heard about the new Galaxy
Speaker 2:  S 24 every year It's like guys we're doing something wrong here every
Speaker 13:  Year. I I treasure that popup. I'm like oh there it is.
Speaker 13:  Yeah you can disable it. It's just If you
Speaker 13:  don't it it comes for you. Yeah. You can get
Speaker 13:  to a place where you can just live totally peacefully with it. Yeah. And
Speaker 13:  it, it has very good things going for it. Another iPhone
Speaker 13:  feature that they wisely stole
Speaker 13:  is the always on display that the wallpaper just kind of dims.
Speaker 13:  So you see that all the time but you get those widgets too. So you
Speaker 13:  have like your little calendar widget or the battery indicator
Speaker 13:  or is it gonna rain in the next hour is like I love that I should gimme
Speaker 13:  all the information.
Speaker 2:  I think this is the thing about these phones that you are most
Speaker 2:  wrong about. No, but that's okay. No, this is just personal purpose. I think
Speaker 2:  the iPhones always on display is bad. Yeah. And just makes me
Speaker 2:  think my phone is on and that's stupid.
Speaker 13:  You're not alone. I hear that a lot. I'm gonna die on that hill. It's
Speaker 2:  Listen, you know to each their own you're wrong and so is Samsung and
Speaker 2:  that's fine. Okay. And so is Apple. I think the pixel got it right where
Speaker 2:  it's just like I wanna know the time and like the little thing where the
Speaker 2:  song is playing into that love that don't need any more than that and just
Speaker 2:  the thing where it kind of seems like I turned the brightness all the way
Speaker 2:  down on my phone is not an always on display
Speaker 13:  And naturally there's a setting in the Samsung phone you can turn that right
Speaker 13:  off with just the wallpaper parts so you can have a normal always on
Speaker 13:  display. But I think that is kind of the basic difference between like
Speaker 13:  Samsung's philosophy and Googles is like on the pixel you
Speaker 13:  have at a glance and you don't, you don't need to go in and
Speaker 13:  set up a bunch of widgets. It's just gonna tell you something on
Speaker 13:  your home screen or on the lock screen like hey you got a calendar appointment
Speaker 13:  coming up. Or it doesn't always nail it. Sometimes I'm like oh that
Speaker 13:  would've been a useful thing to know but it's just kind of gonna do those
Speaker 13:  things for you. And Samsung's like here are 10,000 settings
Speaker 13:  you can mess with and you can get to a place where you get all
Speaker 2:  That. I wish Samsung would dial in the balance of
Speaker 2:  the defaults there a little more. But I've come to really appreciate over
Speaker 2:  time, especially as Google has kind of worked down
Speaker 2:  towards giving you less to do. Like part of the reason people like Android
Speaker 2:  is because it is so much more customizable and Samsung to its credit
Speaker 2:  is like listen, everything there is to do, we are going to give you
Speaker 2:  a way to do. And I actually think to some extent that's the right approach.
Speaker 2:  I wish it made better choices about how it initially sets up the
Speaker 2:  phone. And I wish there were some things that were less duplicative. Like
Speaker 2:  I think you mentioned that there are basically like three different augmented
Speaker 2:  reality search products on this phone. Like that's bad. That's just bad user
Speaker 2:  experience. Yeah. But I do appreciate the thing that Samsung is like, look,
Speaker 2:  do you want there to be 650 things in the settings that you can touch?
Speaker 2:  We have that for you. I seriously, I think it's, it's a good thing people
Speaker 2:  like that about Android. I think it's the right thing.
Speaker 13:  They deliver
Speaker 2:  It. Yeah. There should just be a version of Samsung phones that is like when
Speaker 2:  you set it up it's like do you wanna do this the easy way or the hard way?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And and you can pick either one
Speaker 13:  Like the easy button right? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So the thing on the Ultra that really jumped out to me, I have basically
Speaker 2:  two Ultra specific questions. The first is the screen. And it seems like
Speaker 2:  of the specs in the whole series, the biggest
Speaker 2:  upgrade from the 24 and the 24 plus to the 24
Speaker 2:  Ultra might be this new display. Was that your takeaway?
Speaker 2:  If
Speaker 13:  I was putting my money down on these phones, that's what
Speaker 13:  I would pay for. Okay. For the Ultra it has a new
Speaker 13:  gorilla glass that is supposedly much more
Speaker 13:  scratch resistant. I put my phone next to my keys. It's bad.
Speaker 13:  I always get those little like hairline scratches without fail don
Speaker 13:  don't have a single one on the Ultra and it's only been, it's a
Speaker 13:  small sample size but so far so good. But
Speaker 2:  You're pretty brutal on phones like your, your review period is not
Speaker 2:  easy. Yeah,
Speaker 13:  I don don't have a case. My kid will touch it. He's got like, you know,
Speaker 13:  peanut butter on his fingers the works. So yeah, there's that
Speaker 13:  which is promising and the anti glare coating
Speaker 13:  which is just, it's a little bit like magic. Like it's not like some
Speaker 13:  brand new technology. It's just literally an anti glare coating on the
Speaker 13:  phone screen. But you hold it up against another phone outside
Speaker 13:  and a the Ultra gets really bright so you have
Speaker 13:  that working for you and it just cuts the glare
Speaker 13:  way down and you can, you sort of prepare yourself to like
Speaker 13:  squint at the phone. When you look at it outside you're like, oh I can see
Speaker 13:  this just flying. Like it's almost as good as just in my house.
Speaker 13:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That's huge. And I think glare is one of those things we've all gotten used
Speaker 2:  to on our phones. Like I was thinking about this reading your reviews that
Speaker 2:  I've gotten used to the thing now where you kind of learn how to block the
Speaker 2:  sun with your body as you're using your phone. Yeah. And you, you sort of
Speaker 2:  keep it down here and you like le hunch over it. Yeah. To not have glare
Speaker 2:  but once you don't notice it and like once it's gone
Speaker 2:  that's a huge change. And it's like for especially things like taking pictures
Speaker 2:  and If, you have to hold it at an angle and you, you're sort of looking down
Speaker 2:  off axis at your phone. Like anti glare is a bigger deal than it
Speaker 2:  seems in a lot of ways I think. Which is pretty cool. Yeah.
Speaker 13:  I liked it better than most of the AI features
Speaker 2:  Honestly. We're gonna get to those in in one second. Yeah. But the other
Speaker 2:  thing that I'm curious about with the Ultra specifically is this Zoom
Speaker 2:  trade off that Samsung made. They went from 10 x zoom
Speaker 2:  on the lens and then it was digital zoom in between. So If you wanted it
Speaker 2:  like five x it was digital zoom to the opposite where now it's a five x lens
Speaker 2:  but you can digital zoom to 10 x. I'm deeply suspicious
Speaker 2:  of this change because digital zoom is a lie that we tell
Speaker 2:  ourselves it's just cropping. What did you find? Is this, is the, was this
Speaker 2:  the right trade? Was this the wrong trade?
Speaker 13:  Well the slightly less evil version of digital zoom
Speaker 13:  is this like actual crop into the middle of the sensor that they're doing
Speaker 13:  and that's what's happening now at 10 XI
Speaker 13:  was a big fan of the 10 x lens. I thought it was great. It was so much fun.
Speaker 13:  So I was really kind of bummed to see it go. But the more I kind of
Speaker 13:  sat with it, the more I get it, like five x is more,
Speaker 13:  there's just more utility kind of in every day you can kind of take
Speaker 13:  a portrait of someone if they're across the room, you're not taking
Speaker 13:  a portrait with a 10 x lens. Like that's
Speaker 2:  True. 10 x is kind of a party trick in a way that five x is like a
Speaker 2:  thing you might do anyway.
Speaker 13:  Exactly.
Speaker 2:  That's interesting.
Speaker 13:  And it's a higher resolution sensor. It's actually a little bigger
Speaker 13:  than the old telephoto. All these things going for it. Samsung
Speaker 13:  is like so don't worry that the quality at 10 x is like
Speaker 13:  actually just fine And that's like kind of true If, you
Speaker 13:  don't like iix peep. It's kind of a pointless
Speaker 13:  exercise. But I, I go there and I think the detail
Speaker 13:  captures about the same but you just see the where the little tiny
Speaker 13:  lens falls apart. You're like ah that's there's a little chromatic
Speaker 13:  aberration. It's like that's in the 1% of like what
Speaker 13:  anybody should care about. It is totally fine for just about
Speaker 13:  anything else. So, and
Speaker 2:  I suppose I can get behind the idea that you're trading really good 10 x
Speaker 2:  zoom and mediocre five x zoom for really good five x zoom and
Speaker 2:  mediocre 10 x zoom. Yeah. In real life that is probably a decent trade
Speaker 2:  I suppose
Speaker 13:  It makes sense. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I just, they said they were like oh even at 10 x it'll look better
Speaker 2:  'cause it has more megapixels. And I was like I bet that's a lie. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  I'm happy to know that it wasn't no
Speaker 13:  It wasn't quite just me to a better, yeah.
Speaker 2:  So okay let's talk about the AI stuff 'cause I think that's kind of the point
Speaker 2:  of these phones, right? And I think my sense of your
Speaker 2:  review was basically there's a ton of AI stuff here. You tested a
Speaker 2:  lot of it, but I'm curious like for you, not as a phone reviewer but
Speaker 2:  just as like a person who has a phone, what of these AI features
Speaker 2:  feels like it would actually be a thing you would use in everyday life? And
Speaker 2:  leave the camera out. We'll come back to the camera in a sec. Yeah. But of
Speaker 2:  the like there's the translation on a phone call, there's the recorder stuff,
Speaker 2:  there's a bunch of other stuff like what feels like it actually could insert
Speaker 2:  itself into your life.
Speaker 13:  The thing I see as the most useful that I don't, don don't
Speaker 13:  currently have a use for it but it's kind of nice to know it was there is
Speaker 13:  the translation stuff. So that's where you call someone and you
Speaker 13:  can turn on this live translator and it'll just,
Speaker 13:  you talk and it speaks for you and the other person and it translates back
Speaker 13:  and forth. I called the song our, our
Speaker 13:  wearables reviewer and she speaks Japanese and
Speaker 13:  her take on it was like, it gets the gist of it right? If your conversation
Speaker 13:  is like kind of transactional or you like I need to make a reservation or
Speaker 13:  whatever, sure gonna do those things fine. She tried to tell me her cat
Speaker 13:  was eating her chair and it said that she was eating the chair. It was
Speaker 13:  confusing. Very funny. But I think that's kind of
Speaker 13:  where a lot of these AI features are. You're like, it's actually
Speaker 13:  more useful than not to have that there. As long as
Speaker 13:  you're not relying on it as like yeah this is gonna perfectly translate,
Speaker 13:  you know, whatever I wanna say to this other person. Or you're not expecting,
Speaker 13:  like I want you to summarize a page of notes and you're just gonna
Speaker 13:  blindly be like, well my notes summary, my AI summary said this
Speaker 13:  so it must be true. Right. It's just kind of like a good starting point.
Speaker 13:  That's where I see it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah and I think with a lot of this stuff, the the sort of don't rely
Speaker 2:  on this too much. Footnote is a useful one but
Speaker 2:  I think you, you said at one point I, one of interview is like there's no
Speaker 2:  way in which this is worse than not having it. So So I'll take
Speaker 2:  it. Yeah. Which is fair. And I think the challenge with some of these phones
Speaker 2:  for me now is Samsung wants you to buy these phones for the AI
Speaker 2:  features, right? And Google increasingly wants you to buy these phones for
Speaker 2:  the AI features. And I think on the camera, which we're gonna get to in just
Speaker 2:  a second, there are compelling cases to be made there that AI is letting
Speaker 2:  you do genuinely cool new, like worth getting this
Speaker 2:  phone over another phone sets of things. I don't know that I see any of that
Speaker 2:  here that it's like none of these strike me as
Speaker 2:  a tiebreaker over another device, if that makes sense. Like
Speaker 2:  nice to have. You'll probably use them if you're there. Like the, the recorder
Speaker 2:  is a cool thing and I've always loved a pixel recorder but I've never bought
Speaker 2:  a pixel because of the pixel recorder. Do you know what I mean? Does any
Speaker 2:  of the AI stuff feel like it clears that like this is why you would buy this
Speaker 2:  over something else bar?
Speaker 13:  I don't, I don't know if we're quite there. Okay. I think the, maybe with
Speaker 13:  a small asterisk for the pixel on the like face swap stuff, which
Speaker 13:  we all have, you know, feelings about. But that's the one that
Speaker 13:  people I talk to who are like not online, you know, are like,
Speaker 13:  oh I saw this pixel phone does this thing. I'm like, yeah actually
Speaker 13:  it's, it's really useful and like people see the utility for it. Yeah. There's
Speaker 13:  a lot of AI like camera and on-camera that I just sort of feel like,
Speaker 13:  is this helping it? Like is anyone gonna use this? Like the, especially
Speaker 13:  the chat assist stuff where it's like I'll write
Speaker 13:  something but you know, put some emoji in it or make it sound
Speaker 13:  professional or casual. Like I, I'll like write a text and
Speaker 13:  think to myself like should I use this? I'm like no
Speaker 13:  I have no reason to try it. Right. But the photo stuff is interesting.
Speaker 13:  I think it's, it's at a place where it's a little more compelling to people.
Speaker 13:  And Samsung's take on generative ai photo
Speaker 13:  editing is interesting.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. How compare and contrast it a bit to what the Pixel is doing. 'cause
Speaker 2:  the underlying models are, are mostly Googles, right? So in theory
Speaker 2:  it's, it's dealing with the same underlying technology but what is Samsung
Speaker 2:  doing differently from what we've seen on the pixels?
Speaker 13:  Yeah. So you kind of have the interface for the tools and
Speaker 13:  they're like very similar. You go into this separate kind of
Speaker 13:  editing pane of like you're doing AI and you can select
Speaker 13:  an object and move it or erase it. That's kind of the same
Speaker 13:  on Pixel and Samsung. I
Speaker 2:  Will say though, by the way, for anyone who has not yet read Allison's review
Speaker 2:  of the S 24 and S 24 plus, the funniest thing
Speaker 2:  in that whole review is a picture that you took, I think one of your, of
Speaker 2:  your husband's arm draped over a couch that you tried to remove. What, what
Speaker 2:  happened when you tried to remove this?
Speaker 13:  So yeah, I, I selected it and I hit, you know, take it out of the
Speaker 13:  scene. I did this on the pixel in the Samsung and the Pixel J
Speaker 13:  just kind of tried to like fill in the background. It was like there's a
Speaker 13:  couch here. Samsung was like, you want a new arm made out of pillows
Speaker 13:  and it just like creepiest frigging thing I've ever seen. Yeah.
Speaker 13:  And it's so cursed and it's now on the webs. It's on The Verge dot com forever.
Speaker 13:  It's
Speaker 2:  Good stuff. That's what we're here for. But anyway I derailed you. Sorry
Speaker 2:  keep going.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, no that kind of sums it up. 'cause like I think the pixel in like
Speaker 13:  what it'll actually generate and they are running on same
Speaker 13:  Google models, the pixel's a little more prone to be like, okay, you wanna
Speaker 13:  fill in the background here. It doesn't always look super great. Sometimes
Speaker 13:  it's really good, sometimes it's not. But the Samsung phone for
Speaker 13:  whatever reason is very eager to just like throw something else in there
Speaker 2:  That's such Samsung energy. I love it. It
Speaker 13:  Really is. Yeah. Like you, I selected a lamp on a
Speaker 13:  a table and I tried to take it out and it put a different lamp in. Like
Speaker 13:  that's not what I wanted at all. Like
Speaker 2:  It's like what's behind this in another lamp probably. Yeah. Let's see.
Speaker 13:  Just infinite layups like it's so strange.
Speaker 13:  That's so good. Yeah, it's Samsung energy.
Speaker 2:  The one we talked a bunch about on To Vergecast when this launched was the
Speaker 2:  a ability to take any video and make it into a slow motion video and NELI
Speaker 2:  got like very in his feelings about how this is creating frames that don't
Speaker 2:  exist. What was your experience of actually using this thing in,
Speaker 2:  in life? How did it feel?
Speaker 13:  So I don't quite have the same philosophical hangup with it.
Speaker 13:  I'm like, okay sure. Let's, this is fun. I can slow down a video of my kid
Speaker 13:  on a swing. I think
Speaker 2:  That's where most people are. It's great. That's based on the emails we got
Speaker 2:  after that episode. I think most people agree with you
Speaker 13:  There. All that's the consensus. Yeah. When, so when we
Speaker 13:  tried it out just initially in the kind of product demo time, both vi
Speaker 13:  vi Veen and I were like, this is really impressive. Like it looks pretty
Speaker 13:  convincing and then you kind of throw more
Speaker 13:  complexity at it and it falls apart a lot of, a little bit. You can see
Speaker 13:  where it's like things sort of look jerky and the one I did was
Speaker 13:  like my kid on a swing and you know, he, he pulls him back and
Speaker 13:  lets him go and it's like so cute and he is just like
Speaker 13:  overjoyed but then his like the chains of the swing are just kind of like
Speaker 13:  flickering in and out of existence. Oh,
Speaker 2:  Interesting.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. And like it's trying to decide what the, the mulch on the
Speaker 13:  playground should look like in every one of those frames where it doesn't
Speaker 13:  exist. So it just kinda like looks real warped and kind of,
Speaker 13:  it's a little distracting. Like
Speaker 2:  It makes the mulch looks like it's moving. Looking at the video. Yeah like,
Speaker 2:  like have you ever seen the thing where there's, there's just like a billion
Speaker 2:  ants altogether. It looks like sort of a solid thing but it's just like churning.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's what it makes the mulch look like. It's a little unsettling
Speaker 2:  honestly.
Speaker 13:  It is. Yeah. It's, it's like take something very cute
Speaker 13:  and fun and makes it just a little like cursed.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The one AI thing I forgot to ask you about was the circle to search
Speaker 2:  thing. And this is something that is not technically a Samsung only feature,
Speaker 2:  it's also on the pixel now and it's kind of, you can like hack your way
Speaker 2:  into something very similar just using Google's overall multi search stuff.
Speaker 2:  But I think this is very cool and strikes me as the kind of thing in general
Speaker 2:  that is like just a good feature. It's also a good reason to have an spen
Speaker 2:  like yay for the Ultra. Yeah. But you've tested this a bunch. I have not
Speaker 2:  been able to use it at all. What's been the, the verdict on circle of search?
Speaker 13:  Yeah, I think it's something that I am gonna miss when I don't have it.
Speaker 13:  It's not, it's not like you're constantly, I'm like oh I'm gonna circle
Speaker 13:  everything, search it in this Instagram post. But when you do need it
Speaker 13:  and you kind of have to unlearn the old way of doing things. Like I was
Speaker 13:  texting with a friend and they mentioned the name of the restaurant where
Speaker 13:  you're gonna meet at and my instinct was like go open Google
Speaker 13:  Maps and type it in and search it. And I had to backtrack. I was like,
Speaker 13:  no, no, no I can, I can just like highlight this in it.
Speaker 13:  you know you don't have to leave the app you're in just pops up with your
Speaker 13:  everything you were gonna look for in Google Maps. Yeah. I'm like oh this
Speaker 13:  is how we should have been using our phones. Like this feels so much
Speaker 13:  more intuitive and I think I'm gonna miss it when it's not an option.
Speaker 2:  Yeah it's, it's the kind of thing that seems weird
Speaker 2:  until you do it about four times and then it's like oh this makes sense.
Speaker 2:  Yeah it is insane that I have to copy text in a
Speaker 2:  text message, close this app, open another app, go to the search bar, type
Speaker 2:  on that and hit search just to get the map for the direction that this person
Speaker 2:  sent me. Like that's a bad user experience that we're just all used to like
Speaker 2:  this is the thing about AI in general that I think is kind of exciting. It's
Speaker 2:  just finding ways to shortcut all of that stuff because it can start to figure
Speaker 2:  out, oh this is an address, there's really only one thing you wanna do with
Speaker 2:  an address. Let's just do that for you. I think that's very cool.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, like don't write me an email like Shakespeare wrote it. Just
Speaker 13:  like give those shortcuts like totally do the grant work
Speaker 13:  for me please. Exactly.
Speaker 2:  Okay, last thing and then I'm gonna let you go. one of the big promises Samsung
Speaker 2:  made here is seven years of software support, which I think in the abstract
Speaker 2:  is very cool. Google also said seven years, right? So that's we, this is
Speaker 2:  now like the gold standard. I think that's very cool. Is it realistic if
Speaker 2:  I'm buying an S 24 to assume that I'm still going to want this phone in seven
Speaker 2:  years. Like the big spec missing for me is the Q2 charging, which I think
Speaker 2:  is whatever seven years from now you'll probably want better wireless charging
Speaker 2:  than this phone gives you. But even looking past that, like is it realistic
Speaker 2:  for this phone or really any phone to say I am feasibly going
Speaker 2:  to keep this thing and it's gonna be useful to me for seven years.
Speaker 13:  For the vast majority of people they're gonna be trading in their phone
Speaker 13:  before that. Especially with the Ultra sort of feels like people who
Speaker 13:  buy that phone are on a quicker upgrade cycle 'cause they want the
Speaker 13:  next big thing with all the Yeah, with all this stuff.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The Venn diagram of Spen users and people who only upgrade every seven
Speaker 2:  years I don't think is huge.
Speaker 13:  Not a big one there. But you know, I look at like my parents
Speaker 13:  or like bless his heart, my husband with his iPhone 10 R.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. They just want to not shop for a phone. They're like, I hate that.
Speaker 13:  I don't wanna deal with Verizon doing a whole bunch of
Speaker 13:  things. Jedi mind tricks, like I just want my phone and I
Speaker 13:  want it to work for a long time. And I think that's fair. I think Samsung
Speaker 13:  has a good track record in that respect. They've sort of been pushing
Speaker 13:  forward with more years of support and they were doing
Speaker 13:  better than Google for a hot second. But Google caught wise,
Speaker 13:  so I'm glad to see it. I think it's, it's probably gonna make a difference
Speaker 13:  for a minority, but I think it's important.
Speaker 2:  Yeah and I guess I, I do like the idea that you should be able to decide
Speaker 2:  to upgrade your phone before your phone forces you to upgrade it. Right?
Speaker 2:  Right. Like I, I think that's a good thing and I think seven years
Speaker 2:  is probably two years longer than even
Speaker 2:  most sort of normal people will keep their phones partly just because of
Speaker 2:  like battery health, right? Like it's, yeah, it's just gonna get to the point
Speaker 2:  where your phone doesn't charge for very long. Right. Anymore. But yeah,
Speaker 2:  then at least I'm in a position where I get to say I want a new phone rather
Speaker 2:  than my phone being like I'm dead.
Speaker 13:  Exactly.
Speaker 2:  Get a new phone. Yeah. So S 24 Samsung
Speaker 2:  usually is like the default Android phone. Does it stay
Speaker 2:  there this year do you think? Like is this the phone of 2024 in the Android
Speaker 2:  world? I
Speaker 13:  Think so. And I, when I reviewed the Pixel eight in the eight Pro,
Speaker 13:  I was really impressed and I was kind of like, Samsung's gonna have to really
Speaker 13:  come up with something. And I think they did. There's an asterisk,
Speaker 13:  there's, you know, if Samsung software is very
Speaker 13:  unappealing to you, you just want something a little more turnkey.
Speaker 13:  You don't ever want to think about whether Bixby exists
Speaker 13:  or not. The Pixel is a great option and, and there
Speaker 13:  are things I think that are compelling about it. you know, If, you
Speaker 13:  do like the face swap that's there for
Speaker 13:  you. The way the assistant like processes natural
Speaker 13:  language is a little better than on the assistant
Speaker 13:  on the Samsung Galaxy phones. So there are still reasons to look at the
Speaker 13:  Pixel, but I think, yeah, I think Samsung keeps, keeps the Crown
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. All right, we're gonna do this many more times but I'm
Speaker 2:  especially, I'm gonna play you that clip when we do the pixel nine, whenever
Speaker 2:  that comes out this year. Okay. And we're gonna see how it holds up, but
Speaker 2:  I appreciate it. Thanks Allison.
Speaker 14:  Thank you.
Speaker 15:  Alright,
Speaker 2:  We gotta take one more break and then we'll be back to answer a question
Speaker 2:  for To Vergecast Hotline. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back, let's get to the Hotline as always. The number is
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 Verge one one and the email is Vergecast at The
Speaker 2:  Verge dot com. We love all of your questions. It's been so fun hearing about
Speaker 2:  everybody's Vision Pro experiences and we're gonna try to keep putting
Speaker 2:  that stuff on the show as much as we can. We don't wanna overload you with
Speaker 2:  Vision Pro stuff, but we think this thing is fascinating this week. Surprise.
Speaker 2:  We have a Vision Pro question. We're gonna get to a bunch more of these,
Speaker 2:  like I said, including your experiences, which I loved hearing about
Speaker 2:  on Friday, but I thought this one was interesting and actually made me think
Speaker 2:  a lot. It comes from Dan, I think maybe Stan. I think
Speaker 2:  it's Dan either way. If I got your name wrong, I'm sorry. Here it's,
Speaker 17:  Hey there. This is Dan from San Francisco. I got a Vision Pro
Speaker 17:  icon in my iPhone camera app today and I think
Speaker 17:  that it wants me to start shooting in spatial video. Should I do
Speaker 17:  that? even that I might not buy a Vision Pro ever. Can I
Speaker 17:  shoot everything in Spatial Pro already or should I wait and shoot
Speaker 17:  normal video now? Only help me out. Thank you.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so I've gone back and forth on this question a bunch since I first
Speaker 2:  heard it and I think the answer is no. I think at this
Speaker 2:  point, If, you have no particular intention of getting a headset.
Speaker 2:  The answer's kind of no spatial video has some really neat stuff going on,
Speaker 2:  especially the way it's integrated with the headset If. you just shoot it
Speaker 2:  on your iPhone. You're kind of just capturing 3D video and that's all well
Speaker 2:  and good. The Vision Pro has that neat way of presenting it where it has
Speaker 2:  those kind of misty borders around it. So it looks a little like you're looking
Speaker 2:  through a portal rather than just looking at a video. But the other thing
Speaker 2:  about the Vision Pro is that actually it's a great way to just watch regular
Speaker 2:  video and you can get 4K video off of the iPhone. You
Speaker 2:  can't get 4K spatial video. Spatial video is huge. It's
Speaker 2:  about twice the size of a normal 10 80 p video So I think at this
Speaker 2:  point, if you're not anticipating getting this soon If, you wanna use spatial
Speaker 2:  video as like the second thing you shoot, right? You're like, I'm gonna take
Speaker 2:  a video of my kid's baseball game. Take the regular video first and take
Speaker 2:  it in the highest quality you can and then go back and get the spatial video.
Speaker 2:  It's a fun sort of neat thing, but I wouldn't treat that as your
Speaker 2:  main media capture situation. That said,
Speaker 2:  I do think spatial video is coming in the sense that
Speaker 2:  I think everyone agrees that this is a format that is going to be around
Speaker 2:  for a long time. Meta is now supporting spatial video on the Quest headsets.
Speaker 2:  Apple is obviously all in on the Vision Pro, both as a capture
Speaker 2:  thing for spatial video and as a way to watch it back. I think this format
Speaker 2:  is real, so it's a fun thing to start playing around with. I don't think
Speaker 2:  it's like the 3D video of eight years ago that
Speaker 2:  kind of went nowhere and now You don't really even have a way to play it.
Speaker 2:  I don't think spatial video is going to die, but I also don't think it's
Speaker 2:  gonna be the main way you consume media anytime
Speaker 2:  particularly soon. Especially if you're not going to be a headset person.
Speaker 2:  So I would say start goofing around with it, have some fun, but don't feel
Speaker 2:  the need to like switch your default settings and start shooting everything
Speaker 2:  in spatial because 4K video will do pretty well even
Speaker 2:  in a headset. Alright, that's it for The Vergecast today. Thank you
Speaker 2:  to everyone who is on the show, and thank you as always for listening. There's
Speaker 2:  a whole lot more from this conversation at The Verge dot com. We'll put some
Speaker 2:  links in the show notes. All the links you need are gonna be on The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com, The Verge dot com slash Vergecast. That's where you can find everything
Speaker 2:  and there's tons of news going on Verge dot com. It's a good website. As
Speaker 2:  always. If you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or S Pen uses you really
Speaker 2:  want to tell me about. You can always email us at Vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com or call the Hotline eight six six Verge one one. Tell
Speaker 2:  us your Vision Pro experiences. Tell us which Galaxy phone you bought. Tell
Speaker 2:  us all of your feelings about everything happening in tech right now. We
Speaker 2:  do a Hotline question on this episode every week, which again is now on Tuesdays,
Speaker 2:  so keep 'em all coming. This show is produced by Andrew Marino, Liam James,
Speaker 2:  and Will Poor The. Vergecast is Verge production and part of the Vox Media
Speaker 2:  podcast network. Neil, I Alex and I'll be back on Friday to talk about Google
Speaker 2:  Chaos, all the AI stuff going on and lots more. We'll see
Speaker 2:  you then. Rock and roll.