# Transcript
ID: d20efea0-677e-4414-8939-bc8fd6e865cf
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1688123310602129525/6439686922485118198/s93290-US-4175s-1705062597.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz follow up on all the rest of the gadgets and tech seen at CES 2024.
Speaker 2:  Hello and welcome to Our Chest, the flagship podcast of Affectionate
Speaker 2:  Intelligence.
Speaker 4:  Aw. Aw. Yeah. That's so nice. It's really cute. That's how I describe you
Speaker 4:  most of the time.
Speaker 2:  It's an all-knowing kind of cobbly intelligence. The affectionate intelligence
Speaker 2:  is how LG is branding. Its AI washing machines.
Speaker 5:  Uhoh.
Speaker 2:  Huh? So they don't have, you know, you go to the LG booth. Yeah. LG makes
Speaker 2:  everything. Yes. So here's our washing machines. Here's our little
Speaker 2:  robot guy. And all the AI stuff is affectionate intelligence.
Speaker 4:  Okay. 'cause it's ai. Because it's ai it's also ai.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's like pers instead of personal
Speaker 2:  Intelligence. It's not like chat GBT, which will lie to you and then try
Speaker 2:  to bang you. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's,
Speaker 2:  This is much more, it's just gonna
Speaker 5:  Make sure your, your sweaters are dry.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I've given, LG has
Speaker 2:  A little robot, so we, we should, LG and Samsung both have little robots.
Speaker 2:  We'll talk about Bali 'cause David, and I'm gonna have to see Bali in action.
Speaker 2:  The LG robot is so silly. Like they're not even
Speaker 2:  pretending that this will be a real product. It
Speaker 5:  Doesn't even have arms.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Just like, it's just like a little thing that walks around and and
Speaker 2:  makes squeaky noise about you. It's cute. It is Very cute. So it's day
Speaker 2:  two of Vergecast at CES. We're sitting here at the Kia connected home right
Speaker 2:  in front of the show floor at css. I'm your friend NELI. David Pierce is
Speaker 2:  here. Hello. Alex Fran is here. Hey. The. Verge team is everywhere across
Speaker 2:  the show floor. Yes. If you are on our site or you're on TikTok or whatever
Speaker 2:  you've seen, we've got reporters everywhere. They're making themselves
Speaker 2:  sick at laser shows. It has been quite an experience here at cs. I would
Speaker 2:  say. It's been a good show.
Speaker 4:  It has been a good show. It's been, I would say not as like
Speaker 4:  full of wildness as CES sometimes is.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like there are very few sort of bonkers off the
Speaker 4:  wall new things as there sometimes are.
Speaker 4:  But in terms of like actual cool things that might be actually cool in
Speaker 4:  the actual world, like Yeah, it's been pretty good. Then there's more here
Speaker 4:  than I expected actually. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  There's, and it's a lot of iteration has occurred, right? Yeah. And then
Speaker 2:  you can like slap chap GPT on it. And the test I
Speaker 2:  always use at CS is the local news test. Like, how ridiculous is
Speaker 2:  CSS by how many things break through the barrier of local
Speaker 2:  news programming? Oh, that's good. Mm. And that one that I always remember,
Speaker 2:  the, the baseline product for this test is the year there
Speaker 2:  was the Smart Fork. And it would tell you if you were eating
Speaker 2:  too fast. Yep. It didn't actually work. But poor
Speaker 2:  Joanna Stern was at a BC at the time. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And so she was just like on every local news broadcast in America being like,
Speaker 2:  it's a smart fork. There's not a lot of smart fork at css.
Speaker 4:  There was so much enthusiasm for the smart fork. There was like, it was,
Speaker 4:  it was such earnest belief that this was a good
Speaker 4:  idea. That just these were simpler times.
Speaker 2:  But that's how you, that's how I measure CSS is like what's, is there garbage
Speaker 2:  that breaks through to the local news or is there meaningful
Speaker 2:  technology that is, and like there's a lot of meaningful technology. There's
Speaker 2:  a little bit of local news garbage
Speaker 4:  This year. It's the, it's the e Ink toilet, right? I
Speaker 2:  Think it's the, the e ink toilet. The sort of transparent display situation.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But there is, gee should watch the video. Jen Tuy went and looked at
Speaker 2:  an ink toilet from Kohler. You get the feeling to Kohler
Speaker 2:  has like maybe more r and d money than it knows what to do with Kohler.
Speaker 4:  Have you been to Kohler's booth?
Speaker 2:  I have not yet.
Speaker 4:  Kohler's Booth has all kinds of stuff and then don
Speaker 4:  don't know. 15 just running showers. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  All going into like a pond. There's just a pond. but it's
Speaker 5:  Soothing. It's very soothing. Like you walk into it and you're like, I'm
Speaker 5:  in a little garden.
Speaker 2:  Take bath. Look. I'm from Wisconsin. Kohler literally owns a company town
Speaker 2:  called Kohler, Wisconsin. I wish Kohler nothing but the best. You know,
Speaker 2:  pump some of that water back into the local economy, if you know what I'm
Speaker 2:  saying. Every year Kohler's, like this time the toilet has more
Speaker 2:  technology in it. Yes. It's pretty great. Okay. So I. Think we're gonna break
Speaker 2:  the show up into three segments. If you watched our earlier show this week,
Speaker 2:  David's Gambit was, that was the Screens show. And this is meant
Speaker 2:  to be the not screen show
Speaker 4:  In, despite the fact that many of the things we're gonna talk about have
Speaker 2:  Screening. Almost everything we're gonna talk about has screens here.
Speaker 4:  My methodology is not to be questioned, but
Speaker 2:  It's products that are screen products.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That are like about the screens. And then
Speaker 2:  Now, and then this show is all the products that are products
Speaker 2:  that have screens. I
Speaker 4:  Mean, we have e ink toilets now. Like everything has screens. There were,
Speaker 4:  we've, we wrote stories about headphone cases that have screens on them now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like you just cannot avoid screens anymore. But they're like,
Speaker 4:  not the point of the thing. Right. They're just like, one of the gadgets
Speaker 4:  we're gonna talk about, they're literally
Speaker 2:  Gonna show you ads. Literally
Speaker 4:  The question was, why did you put a screen on this? And his answer
Speaker 4:  was, eh, screens are cheap. That's literally what it was. And so it's like,
Speaker 4:  that's just, screens are cheap and they're everywhere.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So we're gonna talk about some gadgets then. We should talk about a
Speaker 2:  bunch of standards that hit pretty important moments at the show. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Which
Speaker 4:  Actually kind of is the story Yeah. Of CES this year. It's like there
Speaker 4:  are big standards that are gonna start to be everywhere that are like here
Speaker 4:  in a really meaningful way. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like wifi seven had a moment. Thunderbolt five is here. This was a
Speaker 2:  smart home stuff. Alex had an A TSC 3.0 adventure, which is pretty
Speaker 2:  good. It was wonderful. It's a magic. And then we should talk about some
Speaker 2:  cars. 'cause there's tons of Cs always has tons and tons of cars at it. And
Speaker 2:  we'll just go through all the Carney. Well let's start with gadgets. And
Speaker 2:  I wanna start David, with what is undeniably the breakout gadget hit of
Speaker 2:  the show, which you have seen? Yes. And talk to the founder of The Rabbit.
Speaker 2:  R one.
Speaker 4:  This thing came out of absolutely nowhere. Yeah. And I think probably has
Speaker 4:  been the most talked about single device
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Of the show. It's either that or the transparent TVs. Yeah. But so
Speaker 4:  this thing is basically, it's just dedicated AI
Speaker 4:  hardware, right? It's like, if you've ever seen the, the panic play date,
Speaker 4:  that little console with the, the, yeah. Crank the crank.
Speaker 4:  It's feels just like that. It's like colorful and orange. It has a button
Speaker 4:  on the side and a camera and a scroll wheel. And it was made by teenage
Speaker 4:  engineering. And so it's like lovely. And all the buttons feel really good.
Speaker 4:  But the shtick is, it's an AI gadget. And this company Rabbit, which
Speaker 4:  has kind of an interesting history, its founder has worked on AI stuff
Speaker 4:  for a really long time. He's on the board of teenage engineering. So he's
Speaker 4:  like connected to this world. They built this whole big new
Speaker 4:  thing where instead of a large language model like chat GPT, which is fundamentally
Speaker 4:  about, like you input something and you get text back, this is
Speaker 4:  about like doing stuff, right? So their idea is you should be able to say,
Speaker 4:  I want to accomplish any goal. I want to listen to music. I need a ride
Speaker 4:  here. Order me something, book me flights on something, whatever.
Speaker 4:  And have it all be like accomplishable with all of the services
Speaker 4:  you use. But inside of what amounts to an assistant,
Speaker 4:  1 million, billion unanswered questions about that. So many. But it's
Speaker 4:  $199. It's a like adorable little gadget. And the
Speaker 4:  two reactions that everybody seems to have are either this
Speaker 4:  thing doesn't do anything that my phone doesn't do, why on earth would I
Speaker 4:  want it? And this thing doesn't do anything my phone doesn't do. And
Speaker 4:  oh my God, I want it so bad.
Speaker 2:  That's me. Yeah. It is very cute. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I think people are just reacting to the idea that they could purchase a gadget.
Speaker 2:  The questions are just in infinite. Yes. Yes.
Speaker 2:  Or like, for example, it's $200.
Speaker 2:  There's no recurring fee. Right. There's no subscription service. Right.
Speaker 2:  They, they, this thing can't be making money. Like just from the jump. It's
Speaker 2:  like,
Speaker 4:  It seems impossible. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  They have to run a cloud service. There's no way that they're making enough
Speaker 2:  money on the upfront sale to run the cloud service.
Speaker 5:  They had to pay like teenage engineering to do all the design work. Like,
Speaker 2:  Right. Yeah. Another question I have, and I encourage everyone to go watch
Speaker 2:  this. They put it out in what is a, can only be described
Speaker 2:  as a fake Apple keynote.
Speaker 4:  Oh, very much so. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  He's, he's standing there on a stage. don don't know if there's an
Speaker 2:  audience, but it doesn't appear there.
Speaker 4:  So I. Can I actually describe the scene to you? 'cause it's very funny. So
Speaker 4:  this wasn't on the show floor, it was kind of a secret thing.
Speaker 4:  Like I found out about it from like a relatively
Speaker 4:  sketchy email that was just like, we're launching the future of everything.
Speaker 4:  And I, I was like, well, all right. Like, I gotta, we'll just find out. It
Speaker 4:  was deep. I mean deep like it, like a mile and a half
Speaker 4:  walk from the front door of the wind to this like tiny little meeting
Speaker 4:  room in the back of the wind where this keynote was. And
Speaker 4:  it was set up. It was like in a ballroom. And you know, on the one side you
Speaker 4:  have tables for people to stand out and coffee and stuff. And on the other
Speaker 4:  side, maybe four rows of seats. And then this
Speaker 4:  big screen, and Jesse Lou, the founder standing in front of that, and
Speaker 4:  that's where they shot the whole thing. And it looks so polished and so
Speaker 4:  professional. And it's literally just him standing in a casino ballroom
Speaker 4:  talking in front of a screen. Yeah. It was very impressive.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But you were in that audience.
Speaker 4:  I was in that audience.
Speaker 2:  So that was live. I thought that was a production, but no, you were there.
Speaker 2:  It was live. All right. So that's the experience you had. Yeah. The experience
Speaker 2:  I had was what appears to be a pre-produced
Speaker 2:  version of the presentation you were given, which
Speaker 4:  Now that I'm looking at it is even more aply than the thing. Right.
Speaker 2:  It looks like a fake Apple keynote. That's the introducing R one video on
Speaker 2:  their channel. Right. And the thing about this that caught me, and I'm wondering
Speaker 2:  if you saw this inaction is in the video,
Speaker 2:  he's like, asks it to do something and you look at the animation of
Speaker 2:  the Rabbit jumping, which is adorable. Yeah. But you never actually see
Speaker 2:  it do the thing. Right. He's like, success. And you're like,
Speaker 2:  what happened? But you like held it and got to use it.
Speaker 2:  Did it, did it work?
Speaker 4:  Y yes and no. Oh.
Speaker 2:  Oh,
Speaker 4:  Well, I did get to hold it, it did work. But we were
Speaker 4:  on horrible hotel wifi, which I can vouch for being horrible.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So it kind of came and went in terms of actually being able to do anything
Speaker 4:  at all. And obviously a device like this can't do much offline period, because
Speaker 4:  everything it's doing is happening in the cloud. So after about
Speaker 4:  10 minutes of everybody's sort of playing with it, getting to try stuff,
Speaker 4:  he literally like disconnected it and just was handing it around to
Speaker 4:  people. But at one point it, Rick rolled somebody, somebody was holding in
Speaker 4:  their hand, that's pretty good. And, and never gonna give you up started
Speaker 4:  playing. That's pretty good. I think that might've been when they took it
Speaker 4:  offline for good. They're
Speaker 2:  Like, no, we're done. That's how it reacts to losing its connection. It's
Speaker 2:  like he was, you're gonna like this. So again, like
Speaker 4:  Added to the list of unanswered questions about this
Speaker 4:  thing is like, does it actually work? Because I think you're,
Speaker 4:  you're right. And a bunch of people had this reaction of like, you see him
Speaker 4:  talk into it Clever cut. You see it work
Speaker 4:  and it's like, well, yeah. And
Speaker 2:  What does it
Speaker 5:  Do? Like, like Who knows. I hate trying to understand that.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So, I I have. Okay. I'm just gonna say my ideas. Okay. And then David
Speaker 2:  can tell me if I'm okay. Yeah. How's that? That's how we'll structured this
Speaker 2:  because I, I don't think David actually knows either. Yeah. I
Speaker 4:  Think I, I bet I know slightly more than you, but only slightly.
Speaker 2:  So my understanding of this is that it is using
Speaker 2:  the apps for you. Right. And this is not a new idea.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. If you are a decoder listener, we've had like
Speaker 2:  robotic process automation episodes or big enterprises
Speaker 2:  basically bring in computers to use their old computers for them.
Speaker 2:  And like, these are big companies that do this work. And that's at the corporate
Speaker 2:  level. It's enterprise that this is a, a known thing. Yeah. We're gonna use
Speaker 2:  some machine learning and some computer vision, and we're gonna use Windows
Speaker 2:  3.1 instead of updating the hospital building system. Right. There's a real
Speaker 2:  thing that happens. There is a company called Cavo that I loved ages ago.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Were, yeah, we talked about it last week. And they were gonna do machine
Speaker 2:  vision to like click around on your TV interface for you. Right.
Speaker 2:  They, they failed it. It didn't go well as we talked about last week. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But not because you can't do it technically, like it is a possible thing
Speaker 4:  to do. It is
Speaker 2:  A thing you can do. Yeah. So this gadget, the
Speaker 2:  hardware seems less important than whatever is happening in the cloud.
Speaker 4:  Yes. Oh, very much so. The
Speaker 2:  The hardware is just like a little bitty cute thing you can ask questions
Speaker 2:  of. Yeah. And then somewhere in the cloud it appears they're spinning up
Speaker 2:  like Android virtual machines that have your Spotify
Speaker 2:  app or whatever on it. Right. And then it's clicking around on a little
Speaker 2:  Android phone, like a virtual Android phone in the cloud and then delivering
Speaker 2:  you the result
Speaker 5:  Onto the little
Speaker 2:  Guy onto the
Speaker 4:  Little thing. So that is also, I think my
Speaker 4:  understanding of like the most likely way for it to work. What that doesn't
Speaker 4:  do is jive at all with what Rabbit says about
Speaker 4:  privacy, which is that it doesn't store your credentials. Yeah. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  so there's, there's like a total disconnect there that I just don't understand.
Speaker 4:  And what I do know is they have this training mode where you can like teach
Speaker 4:  Rabbit how to do something for you. Like one of the examples, Jesse, the
Speaker 4:  CEO gives is how to remove a watermark from Photoshop. And the way that you
Speaker 4:  do it is you literally go into Rabbit Hole, which is like their adorably
Speaker 4:  named portal for getting all your apps. Really. It's very good. Good name.
Speaker 4:  Like the, the whole branding of this is excellent. You go into
Speaker 4:  it and you, like you said, you boot up a virtual Windows machine, you load
Speaker 4:  Photoshop and this is all like rabbit's, computers not yours,
Speaker 4:  right? Yeah. So you're, you load up Photoshop and then you narrate aloud
Speaker 4:  what you're doing as you're teaching the model how to do it. So you go through
Speaker 4:  the process and you say, and then you, you go over here and you select the
Speaker 4:  lasso, and then you select you, you lasso around the watermark, and then
Speaker 4:  you click this and that and that, and you remove the watermark and that's
Speaker 4:  how you train the model. So in terms of like how to actually
Speaker 4:  interact with the underlying model, your metaphor is exactly right.
Speaker 4:  Then what happens after that? Yeah. I do not know because like once I
Speaker 4:  give it my Spotify credentials, Rabbit says unambiguously
Speaker 4:  that it does not then keep my Spotify credentials and I have no idea.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. How it cannot be.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. At some point it just has to have a token to log into Spotify on your
Speaker 2:  behalf. Right? Right.
Speaker 5:  Are we sure it's absolutely gonna be in the cloud or is it gonna be in
Speaker 5:  the cloud than talking to your phone and in the cloud talking to your
Speaker 2:  Laptop?
Speaker 4:  It's not talking to your devices. That I know for sure. But
Speaker 2:  Do they have a rack of like mid-range Android phones? Yeah. Maybe
Speaker 2:  like hot dog fingers just banging away on 'em. Like
Speaker 4:  Beepers thing with the Mac Minis getting into your iMessages. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 2:  There, this is just a big question I have about this whole product. Right.
Speaker 2:  Which is, it sounds really cool. What if you had an assistant that could
Speaker 2:  use a computer for you? Right? Yeah. Very good. Yeah. Right. And You don't,
Speaker 2:  and you don't have to re-architect all these apps and services. You don't
Speaker 2:  need Adobe's permission. Maybe I Yeah. Big question
Speaker 2:  mark there. But you have a computer in the cloud, it's loaded up with
Speaker 2:  legal apps and services. Who knows
Speaker 2:  it's not Alex's Plex server. It's a computer in the cloud and a
Speaker 2:  robot's gonna click around on it for you and then do the work for
Speaker 5:  You. And that just means that the pri like, that just can't work with,
Speaker 5:  with the privacy claims.
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. It's, it's very difficult to, and they
Speaker 4:  Also very clear about the privacy claims. Like it's, they're either just
Speaker 2:  Boldly
Speaker 4:  Lying or there is some clever turn that we don't know
Speaker 4:  yet and they're not really talking about yet. Yeah, yeah. But, but it's not,
Speaker 4:  they're not doing the like, you know, sketchy, you know, deflect when
Speaker 4:  you ask questions of the like No, they're, they're
Speaker 2:  Just very
Speaker 4:  Straightforward about like, we do not store your stuff. So, and I'm like,
Speaker 4:  how
Speaker 2:  I'll do the same sort of exercise as we did with the humane AI pin. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Right. You're like, here's the demo. So one of the demos was Spotify music,
Speaker 2:  right? Yeah. Okay. To make that work, they need your Spotify credentials.
Speaker 2:  Then they've got log into Spotify somewhere somehow.
Speaker 2:  We don't know where or how, we don't know if they have a virtual Android
Speaker 2:  computer or virtual Windows computer. We don't know how your
Speaker 2:  $200 one-time payment is paying for that server cost. Right.
Speaker 2:  That's just the beginning. Yeah. Then they've logged into Spotify,
Speaker 2:  their large action model has clicked around Spotify and
Speaker 2:  found the song you want from the artist you want, which even
Speaker 2:  Spotify search is not great at. Correct. So that's
Speaker 2:  the, there's a whole problem there, right. It's gonna navigate the Spotify
Speaker 2:  interface, which is more and more geared towards like
Speaker 2:  what if you listen to a podcast. Yeah. Right? So like two different
Speaker 2:  computers are gonna be hostile to each other in that specific way.
Speaker 2:  Then it's gonna stream the audio from Spotify.
Speaker 2:  Spotify's audio is DRM to hell and back because it's a streaming
Speaker 2:  service. So now it's accepting a DRM audio stream, and then
Speaker 2:  it's gonna send it to your Rabbit,
Speaker 2:  it's gonna send it to your headphones. That little
Speaker 2:  transcoding step where it re-broadcast the DRM audio
Speaker 2:  is, I would call it a pickle. Yeah, yeah. If you will.
Speaker 2:  I think
Speaker 5:  There's just like a vague whiff of vapor you think So to
Speaker 5:  this, this thing. Like, it just, there's, there's too many things where it's
Speaker 5:  like, no, that doesn't compute. That's not how computers, that's good. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's good. Yeah. There's, there, this is just not how computers work. This
Speaker 5:  is just not how like any of these services work.
Speaker 5:  How, and the fact that they're not saying how, but they do have this really
Speaker 5:  gorgeous hardware. Like, well,
Speaker 2:  So I do think the, how it's not such a leap. The how.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Right. Because machine vision to operate a computer interface
Speaker 2:  has been deployed in other contexts. Right. The thing that gets me is the
Speaker 2:  cost.
Speaker 5:  Right? No, it's, it's the cost. Like
Speaker 2:  If you call Microsoft to come do a big RPA integration in your healthcare
Speaker 2:  system, that is millions of dollars. Yes. It is.
Speaker 2:  Not $200. Yes.
Speaker 5:  One time payment of $200
Speaker 2:  A one time payment of $200. Like that. I, I'm just dying to know. And then
Speaker 2:  they sold, which is to their credit, they sold vastly more than they thought
Speaker 2:  they were gonna sell. They sold out of their first run of 10,000 units in
Speaker 2:  a day, maybe hours even. Yeah. So they, they've just signed up to
Speaker 2:  run a pretty large set of what, 10,000 virtual machines at
Speaker 2:  least.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And you know, we used to see that a lot in the
Speaker 5:  Kickstarter days. Yeah. And then eventually you'd get an email saying, my
Speaker 5:  bad. Yeah. And, and, and I like this has that
Speaker 5:  kind of feeling to me because the privacy situation and like, and the cost
Speaker 5:  are two things. Like you need to explain, there's, there's a big
Speaker 5:  missing piece here and you haven't disclosed it. And I kind of need
Speaker 5:  to understand that. Yeah. even that I do, I would a hundred percent have
Speaker 5:  spent $200 on it if I'd gotten in, like
Speaker 2:  They're gonna open up another wrap. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Seem hardware seem very confident itself. I'm like, I just wanna play with
Speaker 2:  That. Yeah. I love a teenage engineering device.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Like that's pretty cheap for, for us teenage
Speaker 4:  Engineering like to everybody in March. Like this is Right by all
Speaker 4:  accounts, their version of this thing is like ready.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And, and again, I think that to Alex's point, like the how of it,
Speaker 2:  it's not like other people couldn't have come up with this idea. I think
Speaker 2:  their challenges are can you, because it actually work, is it brittle or
Speaker 2:  does it really flexible? Right. Spotify changes the interface.
Speaker 2:  Will it actually survive that Photoshop moves some buttons around, will it
Speaker 2:  survive that? That's got a run on Windows. By the way, you're not, they're
Speaker 2:  running Photoshop on like an Android phone, like a mid-range Android phone
Speaker 2:  with a hotdog finger Your
Speaker 5:  Hands. Well I, I mean they could be using like Azure or they could be using
Speaker 5:  AWS Right. Just
Speaker 2:  Put all just cost after cost after cost. Right. Totally.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'm just like, can I just read you a few sentences from their privacy
Speaker 4:  webpage, which is actually like a useful summary of everything we've been
Speaker 4:  talking about. So it says, when you interact with Rabbit oss, you'll be assigned
Speaker 4:  a dedicated and isolated environment on our cloud for your own large
Speaker 4:  action model. Which more or less Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Jives about machine. When our rabbits perform tasks for you,
Speaker 4:  they will use your own accounts that you have securely granted as control
Speaker 4:  over through our Rabbit hole web portal. We do not store your passwords for
Speaker 4:  these services. I literally don't see how those two sentences can both be
Speaker 4:  true. Because
Speaker 2:  You don't need the password persistently. Yeah. You need it for like a, a
Speaker 2:  second to get the off, off token.
Speaker 4:  True. If you're running Spotify's API, not if
Speaker 4:  you're logging in on a new machine that I'm spinning up every single time.
Speaker 4:  No,
Speaker 2:  But it says you have access to a machine, they're you, they're giving you
Speaker 2:  a little cloud computer that is yours.
Speaker 4:  So for these 10,000 people who bought $200 Rabbit
Speaker 4:  R ones, they also bought a computer. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's, this is what I'm asking. Yeah. It
Speaker 4:  Doesn't make any sense. I
Speaker 5:  Mean that's what it sounds like, like it sounds like they're saying we personally
Speaker 5:  aren't gonna have like your code everywhere. Instead our
Speaker 5:  cloud, like your little cloud computer that we manage is gonna have
Speaker 5:  it. Right. And it little splitting cares there a Rabbit
Speaker 5:  joke.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well and this is, this is why if you're a lot of these companies, you
Speaker 4:  try to build a thing where you can tap into APIs. Like there are lots of
Speaker 4:  ways to interact with Spotify, not through Spotify, right? Yeah, yeah. Because
Speaker 4:  Spotify has open APIs for this stuff and you can plug in and they do a good
Speaker 4:  job of the authentication tokens. Rabbit is explicitly going a different
Speaker 4:  direction.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So Spotify's a good example because it, it's a very simple, you
Speaker 2:  could put the Spotify API on this device, run it right locally.
Speaker 4:  Spotify will happily let you do this thing that is
Speaker 2:  Describing, here's a next computer, it's going ping Spotify and Stream. Right.
Speaker 2:  May and maybe that's what they're doing.
Speaker 4:  Every smart speaker, is that
Speaker 2:  Right? And they're cheap. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. You go to the second most
Speaker 2:  complicated example and like I said, I'm just running this down the way that
Speaker 2:  we ran down Humane, because obviously Humane is a thing that people are gonna
Speaker 2:  compare this to Humane, by the way, which laid off 4% of its staff this week.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And tried to play some games with Alex Heath when he broke that
Speaker 2:  story. Pretty shady. Humane anyway. Not
Speaker 4:  Great.
Speaker 2:  Not great. So the other example
Speaker 2:  was booking a flight. Yep. Which is easily the most complicated
Speaker 2:  thing you can do with computer. Yes. And when I talk about hostile interfaces
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah. Which the interfaces to book a flight are openly hostile to you.
Speaker 2:  Like all over the place all the time. Prices are changing, it's unclear
Speaker 2:  what you're buying. The door might fall off the plane. It's just a real,
Speaker 2:  the hard time in air travel, this thing has to go. You say like, book
Speaker 2:  me a flight to Seattle. This thing has to go find
Speaker 2:  a website to do that on. Then it
Speaker 4:  Has to, it has to understand a vast amount about your preferences and what
Speaker 4:  you want and what you fly and what seats, like the amount it have to know
Speaker 4:  about you before it even starts the rest of this process. Right. Is really
Speaker 4:  complicated.
Speaker 2:  If you are a United person and I'm a Delta person and you are American. American,
Speaker 2:  yeah. It's rough.
Speaker 2:  And that's three entirely different websites for the large action model
Speaker 2:  to understand and be able to navigate. And then it has to condense those
Speaker 2:  into a coherent response that works on the interface
Speaker 2:  of the Rabbit. Yeah. And the airlines by the way, hate this and
Speaker 2:  always have. Yes. Like they just don't want there to be a,
Speaker 2:  a layer of abstraction over their websites. They don't like it.
Speaker 2:  That's, and then, and then it has to actually do a good job of booking you
Speaker 2:  a flight. Right. And it has to have your credit card So I can pay
Speaker 5:  And your frequent flyer miles your like preferred seat area. Like
Speaker 5:  do you want first class? It's a lot that's gotta do. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I don know. I like, I love this thing. I'm, it seems like we're gonna get
Speaker 2:  one soon. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I think sooner rather than later we'll start to get a real idea of what this
Speaker 4:  thing actually is.
Speaker 2:  But I'm just like, if you just like run the examples, just how would you
Speaker 2:  do this? Yeah. Just step by step. You know, a funny way,
Speaker 4:  I would be more bullish on this thing if it was $400 than I am at
Speaker 4:  $200.
Speaker 2:  I'd be more bullish on it if it was $200 and it was 30 bucks a month. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  But at least I would understand. Okay. Like, I understand how this company
Speaker 2:  can persist. Yeah. The way it's structured now is like we make a big splash.
Speaker 2:  There's a part of me who believes that they started this company, they got
Speaker 2:  all this interest, and then we're right. We're sitting right next to the
Speaker 2:  Google booth here at the Kia connected home. They're gonna sell it to Google
Speaker 2:  in a year. 'cause there's so much interest in ai and then Google will shut
Speaker 2:  it down in two years. This thing running
Speaker 4:  Bard would be so much less exciting
Speaker 2:  Like that. I just don't, don don't understand the economics of this service.
Speaker 2:  but it is very exciting. It looks very cool. I understand people are excited
Speaker 2:  and it is
Speaker 4:  Like a whole thought about ai. Yeah. Which I appreciate. Yeah. Like they,
Speaker 4:  they, they built a thing that is like a full vision and I think that's cool.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  It is bringing some tech that we have seen in the enterprise context to consumers.
Speaker 2:  So, I have more, I think I have more faith that's It's not a hundred percent
Speaker 2:  faith, it's maybe 5% more faith than you Alex.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Like the hardware is so, and the the, the
Speaker 5:  concept is so, so good execution. I'm just like,
Speaker 5:  no.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And I wanna, I wanna, I wanna, I want it to work. I want this all to work.
Speaker 5:  I would love a $200, no additional fees, just
Speaker 5:  like does everything for me. That's magic. That sounds great. But that's
Speaker 5:  magic. And generally magic is not real. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So, well I went to the sphere last night. Oh,
Speaker 5:  Sorry. Sorry.
Speaker 2:  David. David and I went to the sphere.
Speaker 2:  Boy, I was just, I'm in love with the sphere. Yeah. We should
Speaker 2:  be a sphere in every town in America. We can
Speaker 5:  See it from here. It's beautiful.
Speaker 2:  It is. It it is better farther away than up close. Oh
Speaker 4:  Yes. Oh absolutely.
Speaker 2:  And then even inside in the screen you can see lines and like,
Speaker 5:  You're
Speaker 2:  Like, eh, I was like, there's dead pics.
Speaker 5:  It's not imax.
Speaker 2:  And then also we did not see two we saw Yeah. Darren Aronofsky's postcard
Speaker 2:  from Earth, which is just the weirdest thing you can see if you are
Speaker 2:  sober.
Speaker 5:  Oh, you,
Speaker 2:  Oh there are people there who are not sober, who are like, yes.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That feels like a shrooms event. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That's real. Adam and Eve Rie. Yeah. Like at the end of it, like they get
Speaker 2:  off, I'm, I'm gonna spoil postcard from That's fine.
Speaker 2:  It's mostly a reason to show you like videos of elephants. It's gonna be
Speaker 2:  fine. At the end of it, they, the Adam and Eve get off their spaceship and
Speaker 2:  the voices are like, you are here for a reason. The reason is
Speaker 2:  obviously to bang and populate the planet around. Like, it's like very
Speaker 2:  obvious. Get to it. What the reason is, it's good.
Speaker 2:  I I it's a love story. You should go to earth,
Speaker 2:  which humanity has left in this. Okay. Liam is telling me. Gotta wrap this
Speaker 2:  up. I love the sphere there. You know, like the water tower
Speaker 2:  in your town. If you're in a town in America with a water tower, go to your
Speaker 2:  local town meeting and be like, we should turn our water tower into a sphere.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Just a huge,
Speaker 4:  It's only gonna cost $2.3 billion
Speaker 2:  Probably.
Speaker 5:  Don't worry about hail. You'll be fine.
Speaker 2:  You gonna say it was not full last night? Oh it was
Speaker 2:  in fact mostly empty. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Oh.
Speaker 2:  But it is that because people like, I was just like
Speaker 2:  magnetically drawn to the screen regardless of what was on the screen. I
Speaker 2:  would've been happy. Postcard from Earth I think is not drawn a crowd. No.
Speaker 2:  Anyhow. Alright, we gotta take a break. We're gonna come back. We're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk about some gadgets. We talk about some standards. css, stay tuned at
Speaker 2:  The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  more details.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Vergecast day two at css, the Kia connected home.
Speaker 2:  It's actually like CSS day four. It's just the second Vergecast. Yeah. I've
Speaker 2:  been doing this for 15 years and I still have no idea how to number any of
Speaker 2:  these things. No, yeah. We've
Speaker 4:  Been here for eight days. It's CES day three. Yeah. None of it makes any
Speaker 4:  sense.
Speaker 5:  I spent the whole day thinking it was Friday.
Speaker 2:  The only thing that makes sense is the fear. David Giant.
Speaker 2:  Ridiculous.
Speaker 2:  When you walk into the sphere, we, oh my God.
Speaker 2:  Like the lobby of the sphere is like bathed in blue light. There's like bad
Speaker 2:  robots talking about the future at you and you're like, oh, you just made
Speaker 2:  like a, like an Epcot center. Yeah. Like you went to the, the warehouse
Speaker 2:  of old Epcot technologies. Do
Speaker 5:  You ride on a little train and get to see like the cave thing?
Speaker 2:  No, they ran outta money well before that happened.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's what the, the postcard from Earth is supposed to be, I guess.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, right. The spaceship Earth where you go up. Yeah. Right. No, there's
Speaker 2:  a definite vibe at the sphere where you're like, well this is where they
Speaker 2:  ran outta money. They built the screen and they're like, Hmm, this carpet
Speaker 5:  Just porta-potties everywhere.
Speaker 2:  If you are in Vegas, please, if you're listening to this and you ever come
Speaker 2:  to Vegas, you just go look at the screen. It's insane screen.
Speaker 2:  Don't look at postcard from Earth, I think is
Speaker 4:  What I would say. Yeah, that's right. Yeah. I think Phish is coming like
Speaker 4:  in April, go see Phish. That's,
Speaker 2:  That's the move that's appropriate. Yeah. Oh, that's
Speaker 5:  Very good.
Speaker 2:  Actually speaking, we, we gotta talk about standards. There's a bunch of
Speaker 2:  standards news here at css, but speaking of just screen
Speaker 2:  mishaps, you and I both saw Samsung, Bali demos,
Speaker 4:  Poor
Speaker 2:  Bali, and we saw different, had a tough week, different mishaps. What was
Speaker 2:  yours? Okay. From I first tell people at Bali, so
Speaker 4:  Bali is the sort of little rolling home
Speaker 4:  robot that Samsung is making. We saw it last year. Yeah. And we saw a new
Speaker 4:  version of it this year. And its new thing is basically it's a, it's a
Speaker 4:  robot assistant projector. Yeah. So
Speaker 2:  It like, so last year had no projector, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Okay. And this year the demo is actually sort of convincing.
Speaker 4:  It's like this little thing that will follow you around and you're like,
Speaker 4:  oh, I'm doing a workout and it'll project your workout on the wall. And then
Speaker 4:  he went to do sit ups and so it started projecting on the ceiling the, the
Speaker 4:  workout on the ceiling. And I was like, that's awesome. And it's, it can
Speaker 4:  make calls for you. It knows your schedule. It's just like, it's a little
Speaker 4:  adorable smart speaker that just kind of like ambles around your house. Like
Speaker 4:  I'm into it. I look. Yeah. The demo I saw. So they were doing these as
Speaker 4:  shows like once an hour? Yeah. It was like Bali will appear
Speaker 4:  and Bali comes out. They do the first half of the demo, it's going fine.
Speaker 4:  And then Bali is supposed to, I believe the first time
Speaker 4:  it went wrong, Bali was supposed to make a phone call. And what Bali is supposed
Speaker 4:  to do is project the phone call like up on the wall so you can see who you're
Speaker 4:  talking to, whatever Bali projected it upside down
Speaker 4:  and about three inches off the ground. So all you could see was the word
Speaker 4:  like flower shop upside down on the wall.
Speaker 4:  And then Bali went around to try and, you know, help him see his calendar
Speaker 4:  upside down and teeny tiny. And then for the last part of the demo,
Speaker 4:  rolls it back over to the wall. And the guy's like, oh, show me what's in
Speaker 4:  my fridge. So I can decide what to make. Leaving aside that his fridge is
Speaker 4:  literally white,
Speaker 2:  He was standing in front of the, the fridge
Speaker 4:  Next to him. Yeah. Like he could've reached out with his left hand and opened
Speaker 4:  the fridge and said, he's like, Bali, what's inside the fridge? Bali projects.
Speaker 4:  Nothing on the wall.
Speaker 2:  Just
Speaker 4:  Nothing. And this poor guy who clearly has a script to follow stands there
Speaker 4:  and he goes, Hmm, So, I have some apples.
Speaker 4:  And and that was the moment that like the panic level among all the Samsung
Speaker 4:  employees just started to display. And the demo ended very quickly after
Speaker 4:  that. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's over. I saw the same Bali show.
Speaker 2:  I thought the call the flower shop demo was very funny. It just, in the same
Speaker 2:  way we were talking about the Rabbit, he's like, what's on my calendar? And
Speaker 2:  Bali was, show's a calendar. It's like, it's your anniversary. And he is
Speaker 2:  like, okay, call the flower shop. And he just says, call the flower shop
Speaker 2:  you. And if you've ever done a search in your life, you know Yeah. That is
Speaker 2:  not a thing you can just instruct any assistant to do. There's not
Speaker 4:  A thing on Google Maps called the flower shop. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's like 10,000 sponsored listings later. And
Speaker 2:  he calls the flower shop, he makes a phone and like this is, you know, it's,
Speaker 2:  yeah, it's a demo. It's fake, but whatever. But he is like, I need a dozen
Speaker 2:  roses. And like, come in Right your way and hang up. Oh. I was like, that's
Speaker 2:  not how that works. No. At all. And then he's like, I'm gonna make dinner.
Speaker 2:  He does the apple thing. And then in mine, the mishap was he went to go watch
Speaker 2:  a cooking video and Bali was supposed to, oh, I didn't even
Speaker 4:  Get that far.
Speaker 2:  He shut yours down Mine. He was like, I'm gonna do some cooking.
Speaker 2:  And they, it was supposed to project it above the kitchen sink,
Speaker 2:  but Bali missed and presented it teeny tiny in the side of the cabinet
Speaker 2:  and it just kept going as though that wasn't happening. Just keep,
Speaker 5:  Like looking down, double checking all your, your
Speaker 2:  Instructions. It was very, it's very good. I love the idea of boli. I think
Speaker 2:  it's, it's, it would be very fun. Yeah. To have a little projector that follows
Speaker 2:  you around showing you things. Yeah. My
Speaker 4:  Favorite thing about it was every time he would ask it a question, it would
Speaker 4:  project little arrows on the ground. Yeah. As telling you like, follow me
Speaker 4:  over to this wall. So I can show you. And it was great. And he's just like
Speaker 4:  chasing this little ball around the living room. The whole, it was so
Speaker 2:  Good. There's a real, the workout demo. Yeah. Did this happen?
Speaker 2:  It sounds like your demo was much higher stakes than mine. Mine mostly went
Speaker 2:  fine. The workout demo is like, it's time for my workout and he is like stretching
Speaker 2:  and he's standing in front of a television. Yeah. And, and said Bali rolled
Speaker 2:  to the left of the television, projected the workout video on the wall next
Speaker 2:  to tv, which everyone has just a wide blank wall next to tv. Yeah, same.
Speaker 2:  And then just insisted on making us watch Meghan Trainor video on the
Speaker 2:  television. So I think this isn't what I want at all.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I don't want this experience. Yeah. It's very good. All right. So that's
Speaker 2:  Bali. It was good. It's cute. Yeah, it's cute.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. All right. We should talk about some, some standards. So lots of smart
Speaker 2:  home stuff happening at css. Eating toilets, you know,
Speaker 2:  clumsy projector, robots, what have you.
Speaker 2:  Let's start with just some smart home stuff. So Jen Tuy is here, our smart
Speaker 2:  home reviewer. She's killing it as always. Yep. Basic stuff.
Speaker 2:  So matter and Thread are always a big deal. It's css. We're into what year?
Speaker 2:  35 of trying to make matter or thing. It's gonna happen this year, this
Speaker 5:  Year's for
Speaker 2:  Sure. The big news around matter is that
Speaker 2:  Matter is supposed to work with a wireless standard called Thread.
Speaker 2:  Thread is built into all kinds of things. Now the iPhone 15 Pro has
Speaker 2:  a Thread radio in it for totally mysterious reasons. But the Apple TV has
Speaker 2:  it, nest tubs have it. The issue is that Thread is
Speaker 2:  supposed to form a low power mesh network in your house.
Speaker 2:  So you get an Apple tv, you've got a Thread device, you get a Nest Hub, you
Speaker 2:  get an arrow. They all sort of form one pretty good resilient
Speaker 2:  Thread network. And up until yesterday
Speaker 2:  the specification did not allow that to happen. Right? Yes. So instead they
Speaker 2:  would all create their competing little networks. Yeah. Yeah. And you would
Speaker 2:  have like this fight, like my Arrow has a different Thread network running
Speaker 2:  in my house Right. Than my Apple tv. And I just shut the Thread radios off
Speaker 2:  my arrow. 'cause this is useless. Yeah. That is bad because there's more
Speaker 2:  arrows in my house than Apple TVs.
Speaker 2:  And so they should, that should just be the good network. Right. But you
Speaker 2:  can't pass the credential. It's like all just a mess. So the news here at
Speaker 2:  TSS is that Thread, the Thread group, which definitely
Speaker 2:  sounds like a consulting company that Jason born works for.
Speaker 2:  They've, they've murdered a number of high value targets and they've also
Speaker 2:  released a specification that lets all of those devices pass
Speaker 2:  credentials to one another. Which Jen specifically has been saying is the
Speaker 2:  thing that needs to happen. Yeah. Nothing has shipped with it yet. It's a
Speaker 2:  software update. They've all gotta do it. But this is some like baseline
Speaker 2:  spec news at CSS that I think is very important. 'cause it's gonna get you
Speaker 2:  to the place where you, in your house, you have a wifi network for high
Speaker 2:  power usage, high data usage, and a Thread network
Speaker 2:  for smart locks and light switches. We'll see.
Speaker 5:  Fingers crossed. As someone who relies on a Thread network.
Speaker 2:  What's the other Thread Network Fingers?
Speaker 5:  The light for the entryway. So I can climb up the stairs at night. Whoa.
Speaker 5:  At my apartment, I like to be able to see.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it seems reasonable. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Sometimes it doesn't work. And I'm like, okay,
Speaker 2:  Cool. I've got the Schlagg door locks on the Thread network with the Apple
Speaker 2:  tv. Yeah. don don't know why. Yeah. I just like knowing it's on a
Speaker 2:  different network than the wifi feels. Yeah. Like these batteries last 30%
Speaker 2:  longer. Nailed it. These were more expensive than the other smart robot.
Speaker 2:  Then there's a bunch of just sort of like basic stuff standards wise as it
Speaker 2:  comes to smart homes. So with Matter, matter is extending, it's
Speaker 2:  gonna do robot vacuums this year. It just keeps getting bigger.
Speaker 2:  Yes. And then Deere Suite, Amazon announced that instead of
Speaker 2:  using Chromecast or Airplay, it will now support
Speaker 2:  casting content from Prime Video with Matter,
Speaker 2:  which no one else supports it. It's
Speaker 4:  One of those things that it's like if we had all decided to do this a long
Speaker 4:  time ago, yeah. The world would be a better place. Yeah. Like this, it
Speaker 4:  is patently absurd that you have 11 different
Speaker 4:  technologies just to send a thing from your phone to your television. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But like the, we're out on that one. Yeah. And so now we're in the like,
Speaker 4:  it's
Speaker 2:  Like people are like, Dora keyboards are better than K. And it's like, that's
Speaker 2:  great for you.
Speaker 4:  It's irrelevant. Yeah. Yeah. I don't care anymore. That's
Speaker 2:  Cool. That's cool. Yeah. Yeah. We should put the accelerator on the left.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. don don't know. Maybe. Maybe we should have done that in 1915.
Speaker 2:  Right. But we didn't. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, exactly. And so now you have yet another way to send Prime
Speaker 4:  video to things. Yeah. Which I'm sure tons of people do all
Speaker 2:  The time. Right. So Amazon makes its own TVs.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  They can insist on it.
Speaker 5:  Really popular set top box too.
Speaker 2:  Really? Yeah. The Fire TV is popular. Like
Speaker 5:  I wanna joke about this thing a lot. But also Amazon's like right behind
Speaker 5:  Roku with one of the most popular. Yeah. Like set top situations.
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 2:  I excited for Andy Jassy to have a meeting with Tim Cook where he is like,
Speaker 2:  we'd love for you to support Matter casting and the iOS So
Speaker 2:  I don't think that's gonna happen. I just
Speaker 5:  Assume he'll close his laptop.
Speaker 2:  Tim Cook just nope. Puts on his Vision Pro. He's like, I am on the top
Speaker 2:  of a volcano now, sir.
Speaker 4:  He just puts on the screensaver thing on the outside.
Speaker 2:  It's like, I'm done. This
Speaker 4:  Meeting's over just,
Speaker 2:  Just looking at Tim Cook's dead
Speaker 4:  Virtual eyes while
Speaker 2:  He just disassociate from this conversation. That's
Speaker 5:  Exactly what's
Speaker 2:  Gonna happen. That sounds about right. So similar note, LG is
Speaker 2:  supporting Google Cast. This is a big announcement. Samsung is not,
Speaker 2:  this is very good. This the
Speaker 4:  Silliest thing. Yeah. Like so Google has
Speaker 4:  nearby share. I'm like, there's a 100% chance I'm gonna get all these names
Speaker 4:  wrong. Google has nearby share, Samsung has quick share. Google is
Speaker 4:  now renaming nearby Share to Quick Share and just giving it to Samsung. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  They're just gonna put 'em together.
Speaker 4:  And then LG is just off to the side being like, we don't have any of this
Speaker 4:  anymore. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  We don't make phones, but we're gonna use Google Cast and I, our TVs Samsung
Speaker 2:  is like, we're partnering with Google on Quick Share, but we're not gonna
Speaker 2:  put Google cast on. It's just a mess. Like this whole thing is a mess.
Speaker 2:  Which is why basically Airplay two continues to
Speaker 2:  be the thing that people like gravitate to. And then Google Cast is
Speaker 2:  a thing that on Android thing, people gravitate to. Yep. Except for Amazon
Speaker 2:  Prime video. And then lastly, just on, on Smart Home
Speaker 2:  gadgets. We still live in a world of hubs and bridges. They're
Speaker 2:  inescapable, but the thing that's happening is they're all kind of
Speaker 2:  converging. And you, the idea that you'll have just one kind of main Hub,
Speaker 5:  Thank God
Speaker 2:  In your house, it's not quite there yet. But Aqara, which is sort of an
Speaker 2:  upstart smart home company. I've got Aqara, a Smart lock as in
Speaker 2:  addition to my, my Sage. Super expensive Thread ones
Speaker 2:  for no reason. They're very good. They go on sale every
Speaker 2:  constantly
Speaker 5:  On sale. Are you They're motion sensors. They're great.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And they're a really interesting company. They've got an interesting
Speaker 2:  proximity sensor, but they've got a new Hub. The Hub M three. We've been
Speaker 2:  talking about it for a year or more. It's a ZigBee Hub. So
Speaker 2:  for all of Aqara ZigBee devices, it's also a Thread border router. And it
Speaker 2:  is a matter controller if you wanna be a matter thing. So this is the thing
Speaker 2:  that should be able to control like queue lights and eve shades
Speaker 2:  and work with your Nest thermostat and
Speaker 5:  Not require you to use Home Assistant. 'cause Home Assistant has a similar
Speaker 5:  Hub, but it requires you to use home assistant. And a lot of
Speaker 5:  people aren't as nerdy as
Speaker 2:  Myself. A lot of home assistant stands are about to get real mad at you.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I mean I, I'm one of you. I, I use home assistant. I I love it. I have the
Speaker 5:  home assistant yellow, but like a lot of people don't want that.
Speaker 5:  Something a little more turnkey. This is
Speaker 4:  Non sick hacker version. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  If It works, if it It works, I just wanna point out threat didn matter. Like
Speaker 2:  every year at TSS we track like, okay, there's a bunch of smart home products.
Speaker 2:  These standards are growing, the big companies are still all
Speaker 2:  over the place with things like as simple as like I'm watching a video on
Speaker 2:  my phone, I want on tv still a mess. Right? Like still fundamentally
Speaker 2:  a mess. Unless you are pretty firmly in the Apple ecosystem, which is Apple's
Speaker 2:  argument. Right. To be fair, this is app like stay in this prison
Speaker 2:  and we will care for you three hots of caught and consistent,
Speaker 2:  reliable video casting. That's the Apple way,
Speaker 2:  but it's getting better. And some of these products are interesting. Okay.
Speaker 2:  So that's the smart home stuff. You wanna talk about wifi seven? Or actually
Speaker 2:  you wanna talk about atsc?
Speaker 5:  I'll talk about ATSC 3.0 forever.
Speaker 2:  This is, I mean, this is Alex's baby. Yeah. You saw a pretty cool demo. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I saw a really cool demo. A TSC 3.0 famously came out many, many years ago
Speaker 5:  and nothing happened because no one wanted to spend the money
Speaker 5:  to upgrade all of their broadcast towers to a TSC 3.0
Speaker 5:  because it's expensive. And all you would get was like slightly higher quality.
Speaker 5:  And they're like, well, why would I wanna do that? That's dumb. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  so this company Roxy thinks it's figured out a way, which is
Speaker 5:  that it's
Speaker 2:  Roxy with an I by the
Speaker 5:  Way. Yeah. It's Roxy with an I. Very important,
Speaker 2:  Very important.
Speaker 5:  ROXI. So it's, it's good. Yeah. They also do like a music app. And
Speaker 5:  so they're bringing that music app as a channel. And so right now, as we're
Speaker 5:  recording, if you're in Vegas and you happen to have an A TSC 3.0
Speaker 5:  tuner on your tv,
Speaker 4:  You almost certainly don't,
Speaker 5:  You could if you recently bought an lg, but not this year's, just last year.
Speaker 4:  Right. If you're one of three people in Vegas, to whom this applies,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You can go and you can, you can watch this channel and, and then you
Speaker 5:  can pause the music on the channel. You can skip tracks, you can choose other
Speaker 5:  like stations within the channel itself, all in the channel,
Speaker 5:  all broadcast. And I was like, okay, well do you need wifi? And they
Speaker 5:  said wifi will like increase the quality, the visual quality. But otherwise,
Speaker 5:  like the interactivity, no, You don't need it. Really. It's all broadcast.
Speaker 5:  So I. Like
Speaker 2:  That was just not how I'd expect that to work. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And I was like, oh, cool. They're, they're claiming that they basically put,
Speaker 5:  they called it a transitory app, just a little tiny app
Speaker 5:  that goes onto the TV and operates on the TV while you're on the
Speaker 5:  channel. And then it, it leaves the short term memory once you leave the
Speaker 5:  channel.
Speaker 2:  So at 3.0 increases the bandwidth. Yeah. It's a digital signal spec inside
Speaker 2:  the digital signal. The spec has the storage in there. They can send you
Speaker 2:  the bits to run a little baby app. Yeah. That's pretty neat. How does it
Speaker 2:  send a signal back to the TV station if you wanna like buy So like
Speaker 5:  It, so they're, they're having to use AWS they're going through servers.
Speaker 5:  So, so that all is happening. And the money side of it was
Speaker 5:  my other question there. They figured out instead of using broadcast ads,
Speaker 5:  which I guess don't make as much money, they can use streaming TV ads. Okay.
Speaker 5:  So, so they can use a more lucrative ad on it. And they're partnering with
Speaker 5:  Sinclair who has like 40% of broadcast standard. Like they own
Speaker 5:  40% of broadcast stations in the United States they can't own anymore because
Speaker 5:  then they'd be a monopoly. So that's the only reason they haven't
Speaker 5:  purchased more. They're partnering with it, they're super excited about
Speaker 5:  it and they're insisting that it's gonna be on all, in
Speaker 5:  every market that has a TSC 3.0 Wow. By the end of
Speaker 5:  this quarter. Wow. I'm really curious about that. Because there's a 60% of
Speaker 5:  markets that don't, that aren't completely owned by Sinclair. So, but
Speaker 5:  they're like, no, no, no, we got this. So the guy was like very, very emphatic
Speaker 5:  about that. So we'll see if that actually happens. But like,
Speaker 5:  this is cool. I would love to be able to, you know, you could think about
Speaker 5:  it like Max could theoretically not your child, but
Speaker 2:  Because I mean I love her dearly and every now and again, I regret naming
Speaker 2:  her Max, but go ahead.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. She could become a new broadcast channel, but like theoretically
Speaker 5:  Max could like be on this, their, their examples were QVC or something like
Speaker 5:  that. Of course. Like yeah, you could,
Speaker 2:  There's always, there's always transactions buy stuff.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Transaction, buy stuff, choose the weather, skip skip to your, your
Speaker 5:  actual weather on the station while still watching the news, that sort of
Speaker 5:  thing. So, so like this has been a promise for a very long time and
Speaker 5:  nobody's actually like shipped it. And so that's why this is really, really
Speaker 5:  exciting. So
Speaker 2:  This is like over-the-Air Interactive television
Speaker 5:  Over-the-Air Interactive television.
Speaker 2:  No internet required.
Speaker 5:  No internet required. And that's I think super crucial because there's so
Speaker 5:  many people in the United States who don't have easy, cheap access to internet.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So like, they don't get to go watch all the cool stuff we get to watch.
Speaker 5:  And this would theoretically, if everybody adopted it would
Speaker 5:  give them more opportunities.
Speaker 4:  It is super cool. I think all of the interactive stuff though, I wonder about
Speaker 4:  because like on the streaming side of it, there's
Speaker 4:  no reason that hasn't been possible for forever. Yeah. And still
Speaker 4:  nobody has to, like, Amazon cannot figure out how to do a good job of letting
Speaker 4:  you be like, I would like to buy the chips in this ad. Please. Yeah. Like,
Speaker 4:  you're showing me a commercial for Fritos, please allow me to buy these Fritos.
Speaker 4:  Amazon doesn't know how to do that yet. And so the idea that they're all
Speaker 4:  gonna figure this out on,
Speaker 2:  They're doing that with Prime video. They're getting there. They're
Speaker 5:  Getting slowly.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I I, I suspect that one. Like, like, but this is my point right now. It's
Speaker 5:  just gonna be this Roxy Mu music app. That's all we're gonnas or the Roxy
Speaker 5:  Music Channel. That's all we're we're gonna see. You
Speaker 5:  know, maybe they could work with QVC and QVC and them could put their heads
Speaker 5:  together and, and, and figure this out.
Speaker 2:  Okay. But here's my question. Yeah. It's, it's always QVC. It's always shopping,
Speaker 5:  It's always QVC. Right.
Speaker 2:  The other thing you do with at T three Bruno is improve the picture quality.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Well and that's the part I think is exciting.
Speaker 2:  Please someone
Speaker 4:  Improve
Speaker 2:  The,
Speaker 4:  To your point about the broadband stuff, the idea that just a, you're gonna
Speaker 4:  be able to send what amounts to streaming services over broadband
Speaker 4:  is really exciting for all the reasons we're talking about. Broadcast over
Speaker 4:  broadcast, sorry. Yeah. Is super exciting. And then also the fact that the
Speaker 4:  picture quality could be better. But I just wonder if any of the stakeholders
Speaker 4:  involved in this care enough about ATSC three anymore to pick this fight.
Speaker 4:  It's like the matter casting. Like we should have done this a decade ago
Speaker 4:  and everything would be better.
Speaker 5:  Sinclair needs it. Like if Sinclair doesn't figure this out. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Broad. Like they're done, you know, 10 years from now broadcast TV is
Speaker 5:  dead. Like last year we, we did a lot of reporting about how people were
Speaker 5:  watching less broadcast tv. Right. So I, it's, it's on its last legs. It
Speaker 5:  needs something. And if this can, can get those companies and a lot of
Speaker 5:  these streaming companies own broadcast networks. Right? Like, like a, B,
Speaker 5:  C True. Or Disney does. Yeah. Paramount does. I think believe Max owns a
Speaker 5:  lot of cable channels. Like there is certainly opportunity for these people
Speaker 5:  and the fact that this company is figured out Yeah, just tech,
Speaker 2:  This is lucrative spectrum. Yeah. You should be able to do something good
Speaker 2:  with it, right? Yeah. Ideally you increase the picture quality and stop broadcasting
Speaker 2:  football in seven.
Speaker 5:  Instead you're gonna buy.
Speaker 2:  But instead we're doing Qvs. Yeah. It's great. Alright, let's talk about
Speaker 2:  some other standards. By the way, you should go watch just the Glee on Alex's
Speaker 2:  face. That's the Best's a video. Just watch the video. The way that
Speaker 2:  I felt at the sphere, Alex felt demoing ATTs three
Speaker 5:  On our activity. I had such stopped to watch 'cause I think I was just that
Speaker 5:  excited. Yeah. People are like coming
Speaker 2:  Into a bit later today. I'm gonna go look at some party speakers. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  I feel like I'm gonna be the most excited person to go through the party
Speaker 2:  speaker tour. They're gonna
Speaker 5:  Just join you. People are just gonna follow you, feel your enthusiasm.
Speaker 2:  And they're like, why?
Speaker 2:  Just some other quick standards to talk about Q2. That's the magnetic
Speaker 2:  wireless standard. That is basically mag safe. It's here. There's some
Speaker 2:  products.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, there's a lot of it. It's, it's the good news is less about like a
Speaker 4:  specific product and more about, it just feels like everybody has decided
Speaker 4:  to embrace QE two, which is awesome. Yeah. And it's gonna be good.
Speaker 2:  Including Apple, which is like the big one,
Speaker 4:  Right? Including Apple. Like we're gonna start to see a lot of Android phones
Speaker 4:  with it this year everybody thinks that new Pixel is gonna have it. Like
Speaker 4:  the, the momentum on this is super real and happening
Speaker 4:  fast to the point where I think like, and we've talked a lot on this show
Speaker 4:  about how cool it will be when we have a bunch of unified systems for
Speaker 4:  accessories. Yeah. And we're getting it with USBC. We're getting it with
Speaker 4:  Q2. Like it's, it's gonna be good things. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So we've got some photos of docs from Satechi and other companies. There's
Speaker 2:  a Belkin thing that works with Apple's new DO kit. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And So I absolutely forgot Doc Kit was a thing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I know. Apple is like, we made an accessory standard and you're so
Speaker 2:  used to being like, and that'll be, yeah. One company will try it, but now
Speaker 2:  because of USBC and G two companies are free to try it. It's like
Speaker 2:  less costly in a way. Yeah. So Belkin made a doc,
Speaker 2:  a camera doc, you put it on it and Doc hit Motorize is
Speaker 2:  the doc while you're in FaceTime mode. So it like follow you around
Speaker 2:  I don dunno if that's cool. I think it's cool that it, the people made a
Speaker 2:  thing. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That part's really cool.
Speaker 2:  Is this funny thing that's David is,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Is this anything I will say I hate, I hate the
Speaker 4:  webcams that automatically move to keep you in the center of the frame. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It is the worst experience to be on a call with somebody while their camera
Speaker 4:  is constantly moving every time they move their head. But
Speaker 5:  It's like, it's just panning zoom. No.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Or pan and scan. Right. But like, if
Speaker 4:  You watch something that is constantly panning and scanning,
Speaker 2:  Hey, it sucks. Hey Bella porch built an entire TikTok career off that
Speaker 2:  effect man. Whatcha doing? Fair enough. Alright.
Speaker 2:  Alex, what is going on with wifi seven? It's, it's everywhere. It's like
Speaker 2:  having a moment. It
Speaker 5:  It's having a moment. It's, it's faster. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 2:  but it, it's faster because you can like do a thing, right? Like,
Speaker 2:  like it can like use multiple radio channels at the same time.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's faster. It can use multiple radio channels. And the big thing
Speaker 5:  is that
Speaker 2:  Like I don know what you, what other feature you want from wifi other than
Speaker 2:  faster. No
Speaker 5:  One wants anything else from wifi, but
Speaker 2:  It's also a delivery service. Go fast.
Speaker 5:  It's now interactive. You can connect to QVC with it and buy all
Speaker 5:  sorts of things.
Speaker 4:  You can look at Max on it now.
Speaker 2:  Which one?
Speaker 5:  All of them. But yeah, I think the big thing is is that it's gonna
Speaker 5:  be smarter about how it handles your, your traffic. Yeah. So if
Speaker 5:  you're on the five gigahertz and it's, it's getting jammed with stuff, it'll
Speaker 5:  switch you over automatically to six. And this is just like, like the,
Speaker 5:  but the main thing is it's just, it's faster. It, it's, it's getting a lot
Speaker 5:  faster. It's getting smarter about how it handles all those packets. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And you can prob like, you're gonna find laptops with it now
Speaker 5:  because a bunch of the laptops announced it to the point where I was like,
Speaker 5:  oh, I guess it's just everywhere now. It's the cheaper laptops don't have
Speaker 5:  it. But anything like, like the XPS line has it. Yeah. A lot. All,
Speaker 5:  almost all of the gaming laptops that were announced have it. So is
Speaker 4:  It just all the stuff with the new Intel stuff happen?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It seems like primarily all the new Intel, but you still have to have
Speaker 5:  like the wifi chip and, and that's expensive. Right. And so like sometimes
Speaker 5:  they're like, no, we're not gonna put the new wifi in. Yeah, that's fair.
Speaker 5:  But but yeah. So, so it's gonna be available this year. I'm
Speaker 5:  hesitant to tell people to go out and buy those wifi seven routers. I think
Speaker 5:  you can still, you can still,
Speaker 2:  Well they've only just started certifying. Yeah. So you can buy them now.
Speaker 2:  But they're uncertified and the promises that a software update will certify
Speaker 2:  that.
Speaker 5:  Right. We just got, what's it? Wifi six E. Yeah. Like last year or
Speaker 5:  something. I only know that because I bought a wifi six router and
Speaker 5:  then it was immediately then out six E and I was very bitter about it.
Speaker 4:  That's how I feel too. I just bought new arrows and their wifi six because
Speaker 4:  I was like, who needs six E? Like that's barely
Speaker 5:  Anything. Yeah. Now they're seven and
Speaker 4:  I'm seven. I'm like, I'm two generations behind now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So this is all just, this is like the wifi companies are
Speaker 5:  are doing what the TV companies did where they just wanna make you jealous
Speaker 5:  every year. Yeah. So you're like, okay, I guess I better go spend $3,000
Speaker 5:  on a new router.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I would wait until there's the second generation routers
Speaker 2:  when things calm down. Yeah. The last thing you want is for there to be software
Speaker 2:  instability in your network infrastructure fair. So like, unless
Speaker 2:  you need for some reason like a two gigabit per second
Speaker 2:  wifi link.
Speaker 5:  If you live like in an apartment, which we all do by yourself, really small.
Speaker 5:  Your routers old. You see one of these like giant 'cause
Speaker 5:  it's always gonna be all like the giant gaming routers. Yeah. You wanna spend
Speaker 5:  five or four or $500 on that thing. You know, I'm not gonna
Speaker 5:  judge you. I've done that not for seven, but I've definitely done that. But
Speaker 5:  otherwise probably, probably wait
Speaker 2:  Year zero, max seven is not four or $500. It's like,
Speaker 5:  Oh no, I'm thinking like the gaming, the gaming ones are also like, they
Speaker 5:  usually start at four or 500 but then they immediately go up.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The a single Euro max seven is $600 and the three pack is
Speaker 2:  $1,700. That's a region.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Wait, just, just wait.
Speaker 4:  Don't spend that much money on row. Like
Speaker 5:  It's fast. But is it that much faster than six As
Speaker 5:  particularly because you're still gonna be like hampered by the fact that
Speaker 5:  you have to pay your ISP who probably is gonna give you garbage
Speaker 5:  internet. So unless you're just moving a lot of big files on your Plex server,
Speaker 5:  you're probably fine.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. My local network is,
Speaker 2:  Is like I'm pre-ordering a 1700. All right. I haven't
Speaker 5:  Pre-ordered it,
Speaker 2:  I swear. but it, it's wifi seven is here. It seems like it's gonna be the
Speaker 2:  next Yep. Yep. Like six E seems very transitory. Yes. I also have a six E
Speaker 2:  network and I feel very annoyed. Yeah, yeah. Whatever. Next year. Next
Speaker 2:  year. And then lastly, on the standards front, I'll say
Speaker 2:  The Verge team was the most irrationally excited about this.
Speaker 2:  I don't know why, but Thunderbolt five is here and we have
Speaker 2:  a lot of pictures of US PC ports. Ports with stickers on
Speaker 2:  them that indicate they support Thunderbolt five. They're just
Speaker 2:  pictures of US PC ports. Now, I'm not saying we shouldn't run pictures of
Speaker 2:  USPC ports here at The Verge, I am perhaps the most guilty
Speaker 2:  of publishing photo supports on our website and excitedly telling people
Speaker 2:  that the future is here. I've done it a lot, but I'm just telling you it,
Speaker 2:  it's not even a different shape of port. Yeah. It's
Speaker 2:  A-U-S-B-C port with a sticker on it. Their Thunderbolt five, Thunderbolt
Speaker 2:  five offers 240 watt charging, 120 gigabit
Speaker 2:  per second data transfer and up to it will support monitors up to 540
Speaker 2:  hertz refresh rates on the new versions.
Speaker 5:  Can you bring a 200? It's a good 40 watt charger on a plane. That's like
Speaker 5:  past FAA rules, right?
Speaker 2:  No, that's the battery size. You can't bring more than a hundred watt, hundred
Speaker 2:  watt hour battery. Okay.
Speaker 5:  So this is fine.
Speaker 2:  But yeah, you can put two of those together,
Speaker 2:  but you need it for some of the GPUs that you need to support 540 hertz
Speaker 2:  refresh rates. Yeah. So this is just the next standard. There are some laptops
Speaker 2:  here. Again, you can look at the photos of the ports with the stickers on
Speaker 2:  'em on the website. But Thunderbolt five is here
Speaker 2:  and Sean talked to the person Intel responsible for Mr. Thunderbolt,
Speaker 2:  who he referred to in print on our website as Mr. Thunderbolt. Wow. Sick.
Speaker 2:  And I refuse to learn his real name. Intel's Mr. Thunderbolt, when asked
Speaker 2:  of Apple would support Thunderbolt five simply said to Sean, well they support
Speaker 2:  every other one.
Speaker 2:  That's all you need to know. Yeah. We also have a photo of a Thunderbolt
Speaker 2:  five cable. It looks like a Thunderbolt cable. I,
Speaker 2:  I'm telling you like our whole team is so excited. Like there was like a
Speaker 2:  hunt to get that first picture of a Thunderbolt five like our
Speaker 4:  Weeks ago. We made a whole virtual episode about how stupid USBC is.
Speaker 4:  This is not stupid. USBC. This is the good USBC. Yeah. So
Speaker 4:  like we should be excited about this. It
Speaker 2:  Goes fast. I'm excited about it. It's very good. Yeah. All right, we gotta
Speaker 2:  take a break. That was the standards lightning round here at The. Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  Episode two, CES day four. Still
Speaker 4:  Unsponsored. Still
Speaker 2:  Unsponsored. Well no, we're here at the Kia connected home.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's true. Very good. We'll be back. We got another car lightning
Speaker 2:  round to come in. David's rubric of things that are not screens
Speaker 2:  cars is next.
Speaker 2:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  E nine for more details.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we're back. CES Vergecast
Speaker 2:  two day four. Month
Speaker 2:  one. Our 12 year
Speaker 3:  2024.
Speaker 2:  Last little lightning round of CSS coverage. This show over the
Speaker 2:  years has become a car show. There's just cars everywhere. We're literally
Speaker 2:  sitting in the Kia connected home. There's cars all around us.
Speaker 2:  Every kind of car tech that you can think of is being demoed here. I saw
Speaker 2:  a power steering pump on the show floor the other day. The Bosch booth. Wow.
Speaker 2:  Sure. They're like, here's a thing. And I was like, that's consumer technology
Speaker 2:  I suppose, I guess. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Consumers love steering wheels. It's,
Speaker 2:  yeah, literally every piece of the car is being re-contextualized
Speaker 2:  to be connected, to be smart, to be an EV. David, run us through some of
Speaker 2:  the highlights here. So the, that
Speaker 4:  Thing you said is actually kind of why I think the car stuff is really interesting
Speaker 4:  because it feels like we got a bunch of cars. There's like
Speaker 4:  new versions of existing cars, right. There's a lot of that at CES every
Speaker 4:  year. There's a lot of that this year. This year felt unusually also.
Speaker 4:  Like we got a bunch of things that are shaped like
Speaker 4:  cars that are barely cars. Yes.
Speaker 2:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  And I think like the, the Sony Afeela, which is probably the first one we
Speaker 4:  should talk about, is to me the closest version of that thing. This is like
Speaker 4:  borderline not a car, it just looks like a car, but it's like a,
Speaker 4:  it's like a lounge area that runs
Speaker 4:  places theoretically. But the car part seems to be the least important
Speaker 4:  and least fleshed out part of this car. They've spent a lot of time thinking
Speaker 4:  about the seats.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And that's about it. And I just think that's weird. We're in this like strange
Speaker 4:  time with cars where like Honda has this very cool
Speaker 4:  new concept series called Honda. Zero. Hyundai and
Speaker 4:  Kia are doing interesting stuff there all over the place. There's just like
Speaker 4:  a Bugatti chilling on the floor. Yeah. For reasons that I don't totally understand.
Speaker 4:  but it just feels like a lot of the cars here aren't cars.
Speaker 4:  It's a
Speaker 2:  Tank. My just a tank. You saw a tank. There's
Speaker 5:  Like a little like tiny tank over,
Speaker 2:  There's a company here called Dodge Brothers with e-bikes, but they've bought
Speaker 2:  a Dodge Challenger and everyone's like, what's this for? And they're like,
Speaker 2:  we just brought it to get attention. It's like, it's a very good, just a
Speaker 2:  good comment. So, the way I always thought about this for years, was it css?
Speaker 2:  We saw the future of the inside of cars and then the Detroit auto shows in
Speaker 2:  a few weeks here and won't, that's where we'll see the outside of cars. Oh,
Speaker 2:  I like that. The thing that is, I think not the case anymore.
Speaker 2:  'cause I think what is happening in a big way is the outside
Speaker 2:  cars are going retro. There's cool design stuff like these Honda concepts
Speaker 2:  are really cool. The inside of cars. That
Speaker 2:  is what is selling the cars now. So if you just think like, I love watching
Speaker 2:  car reviews on YouTube. You watch Doug Deira, you watch Forest Auto reviews.
Speaker 2:  Miles Summerall is on the Mkb HT team. I saw him the other day. He makes
Speaker 2:  great TikTok car reviews. Everyone's like flipping buttons and counting cup
Speaker 2:  holders and like pushing. Right. Like quirks and future because that's where
Speaker 2:  you spend your time because you're inside the car. Yeah. So that whole thing
Speaker 2:  has moved to the Detroit. 'cause that's how you're gonna sell cars now. Right?
Speaker 2:  It's like And is
Speaker 4:  That just because Es especially as things go
Speaker 4:  EV, like the the experience of what it's gonna be like to drive this thing
Speaker 4:  just compresses to the point where like driving an EV is gonna be like driving
Speaker 4:  an EV is gonna be their driving
Speaker 2:  EV and you see how a car companies called talk about mobility. Yeah. 'cause
Speaker 2:  they're like, you're gonna get in the car, it's gonna drive you where you
Speaker 2:  wanna go. And in the meantime you'll be a wash and a sea of Sony IP
Speaker 2:  just transacting. You'll be
Speaker 5:  Spider-Man just flipping a car spider across
Speaker 2:  The car. Spider Man's flying around the car and you're gonna be watching
Speaker 2:  our streaming service. If you could put Bravia Co in the Sony Feela Fila
Speaker 2:  I'll, I'll buy it. Yeah. I 80 megabits per second in the So
Speaker 4:  I guarantee you that's a thing.
Speaker 2:  Do you think it, because I'm in css, I've been wondering this all week.
Speaker 2:  Braco usage has to have dropped by like 200% because I'm not at home
Speaker 4:  Who's watching Spiderman? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Anyhow, so the feel is really interesting 'cause I kind of get
Speaker 2:  what Sony needs from Honda. Can you make us a car? Right. And what I've been
Speaker 2:  wondering is like what does Honda get from Sony? And the answer is a universe
Speaker 2:  of screens and content. But that is, it just doesn't
Speaker 2:  feel like enough to sell me a car. I mean,
Speaker 5:  But also most of the car makers, most not all are garbage
Speaker 5:  at like the software side of things. So, right.
Speaker 2:  So that you see why Honda would turn to noted software? Oh yeah. Experience
Speaker 2:  provider Sony.
Speaker 5:  I mean if you're garbage edit it makes sense.
Speaker 2:  Can you imagine if the, like the interface of the Sony feel has the same
Speaker 2:  menu structure as like any Sony camera.
Speaker 5:  You just spend 45 minutes every time you get in your car where you even go
Speaker 2:  Anywhere. Terrific image quality you have to
Speaker 4:  Format before you go into drive.
Speaker 5:  You brought the wrong format card. Sorry. No
Speaker 2:  Driving. It's, it's actually memory. No driving. We're doing, we're doing
Speaker 2:  weird Sony memory formats. So that's a Fila, which is interesting. You look
Speaker 2:  at the pictures, but it is very much, it's less about the car and more about
Speaker 2:  will you watch a bunch of Sony content on these Sony screens?
Speaker 2:  And I think the answer is, well I have a phone, so
Speaker 2:  no. And it will just, it's not, it's the most vaporware with vapor
Speaker 2:  cars. Like this year instead of a picture of it. You can like look at one
Speaker 2:  that's,
Speaker 4:  Yeah you can, you can sit in the passenger seat now.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. but it, but it's not
Speaker 4:  Anywhere close. but it's still, I guess that's part of what is like leaving
Speaker 4:  me cold with lot stuff is it doesn't really feel like any of this is getting
Speaker 4:  more real year after year. Like I think we're in
Speaker 4:  a phase with car design that I think is not gonna last forever. Where everybody
Speaker 4:  is just designing cars that are like the capital F future.
Speaker 4:  You know what I mean? Like everything looks like a Blade runner prop now.
Speaker 4:  And that's fun. But eventually we'll like start making EVs that look like
Speaker 4:  cars again. Like that will, that will happen. We'll come back to it. We'll
Speaker 4:  see. Fingers don't think so. You think we're just gonna stay in this like
Speaker 2:  Air 3000? All depends on autonomy. I think right now we're, we're on the
Speaker 2:  cusp of what feels like a really fun design renaissance and cars. Cars are
Speaker 2:  real ugly for a long time. Oh yeah. Like the angry
Speaker 2:  robot car was just everywhere for a minute. Yeah. And now
Speaker 2:  there's like some very cool like smoothed out ture designs are EV all over
Speaker 2:  the place. The Honda ones. You're talking about Hyundai and Kia
Speaker 2:  that what's, there's that Hyundai N concept that kinda looks like Laureate.
Speaker 2:  Like that stuff is really cool.
Speaker 2:  You know we're sitting above an E nine. People keep coming in looking at
Speaker 2:  the E nine. You can just see like car companies are getting the new
Speaker 2:  Prius. Yeah. Yeah. It's like a surprisingly cool looking car. Yeah. Finally
Speaker 2:  it's dog slow and surprisingly cool looking car. We were just on the
Speaker 2:  cusp of what I think is a good moment for car design. And it's because you
Speaker 2:  can re, the EV stuff lets you repackage cars and think about them in a different
Speaker 2:  way. Right. And they want them to look different from what came before. 'cause
Speaker 2:  they wanna signal to consumers like these aren't just cars. And then on top
Speaker 2:  of that you might get to autonomy, which is a real coin flip and one that
Speaker 2:  will happen. And then you get to really repackage the car into the thing
Speaker 2:  that looks nothing like a car. So,
Speaker 4:  I. I totally agree with that. But like this Honda
Speaker 4:  concept is just the Batmobile, like they just made the
Speaker 4:  Batmobile.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. There's a lot of that going around
Speaker 4:  Here. I think. I just think we might have swung the pendulum a little far.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  I mean it's a, a concept like,
Speaker 4:  But now I'm looking at the picture of this and this thing's hot. So like
Speaker 4:  it's hot. Maybe I'm wrong. It's hot.
Speaker 5:  It's a hot, I I had that on my wall when I was like eight. Right,
Speaker 2:  Right. Yeah. But but those are, these are all concepts. They're all like
Speaker 2:  out in the world and you look at what's actually being asked css, it's like
Speaker 2:  BMW put an L Lmm in the voice assistant. Okay. There's a bunch of
Speaker 2:  AR features and then you BMWs it's like why? Yeah. Right.
Speaker 2:  Volkswagen is letting you talk to chat GBT inside the car, which I am told
Speaker 2:  people have just been doing anyway on like the streets of
Speaker 2:  San Francisco. Alarming.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna try it. My road trip,
Speaker 2:  Like someone told me yesterday, like more people, more tech people in
Speaker 2:  San Francisco are driving around just chatting to
Speaker 2:  chat GPT instead of listening to podcasts, then you think,
Speaker 5:  Don't they have like siblings, parents
Speaker 5:  loved ones?
Speaker 4:  This makes me think of like every once in a while there's like an app that
Speaker 4:  comes out that's like, turn all of your emails into a daily podcast. And
Speaker 4:  I'm like, who wants that? And then it's it's these people it turns out Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Where we are. I just love the idea that people are getting outta the car
Speaker 2:  is just woefully misinformed. Yeah. Just utterly be like,
Speaker 2:  I know a lot of facts. This robot may, but none of the numbers are Right.
Speaker 5:  Whole list of books that don't exist that they're gonna read.
Speaker 2:  Exactly. They're like ready to read books that have never been written.
Speaker 2:  On the flip side of that, there is a lot of just infrastructure here at
Speaker 2:  CSS Intel. I, I think this can only be read as
Speaker 2:  a threat. Intel had a whole keynote where they announced a bunch of AI stuff
Speaker 2:  and then the quote is, we are bringing the A IPC to the car.
Speaker 5:  Right.
Speaker 2:  Whether you like it or not. And Intel wants this to be a big market
Speaker 2:  for them. You can see that they would like to bring a car makers
Speaker 2:  to use their chips. They're so, they're very late. Nvidia is very dominant
Speaker 2:  and all over the cars. But this notion that the car should be one sort of
Speaker 2:  unified computer from the body control module all the way infotainment stack,
Speaker 2:  I think Intel sees as an opportunity. And then
Speaker 2:  let's just end here. We should just talk about Will I am
Speaker 2:  the Mercedes?
Speaker 4:  Do we have to
Speaker 2:  So I was sent a video by a good friend of the Mercedes event, which
Speaker 2:  I'm told was very expensive to produce and Will I am comes out and he
Speaker 2:  wrapped a song about cars.
Speaker 2:  It he just did it. Yeah. I love this for you. And the feature they announced
Speaker 2:  is that this is actually cool. I dunno if you've seen this video or any demos
Speaker 2:  of it. It's an interactive musical experience in the car. So it's
Speaker 2:  like playing a track and Will I am obviously chosen all the samples and if
Speaker 2:  you speed up the track, it's more exciting.
Speaker 5:  Oh, I don't want that.
Speaker 2:  And it, it feels like it's just gonna make you drive really fast.
Speaker 5:  I was, I was like, my car just screaming at me as I drive down the road.
Speaker 4:  Have you ever, have you seen the movie Baby Driver? Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like
Speaker 4:  The, the thing in that movie that's so cool is the music is matched up to
Speaker 4:  what's going on. So like he's, he's steering on beat and drifting on beat
Speaker 4:  and it just, it rips dude. Yeah. Like it's so fun the whole time. I'm
Speaker 4:  like, I could do that. Imagine
Speaker 5:  You watch that, you watch Fast and Furious, you get in this car
Speaker 5:  immediate accident, like you're going a hundred miles per hour
Speaker 5:  straight out. You're like, I can drift around this corner in my neighborhood
Speaker 5:  and
Speaker 4:  It's just where I am yelling at you the whole way home.
Speaker 2:  So it's the MBUX sound drive or Mbu sound drive.
Speaker 2:  It links the music that you're listening to is driving. So it's a bunch of
Speaker 2:  tracks, bunch of samples and things like energy
Speaker 2:  recuperation, acceleration, steering, braking and turning all
Speaker 2:  linked to what is being played. And
Speaker 2:  will I am refer to this as the automotive orchestra. Cool.
Speaker 4:  Okay. I love it. There was a thing a bunch of years ago, and it's possible,
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna get all of the details of this wrong, where I think it was Spotify
Speaker 4:  did a thing with Tiesto that had basically like adaptive
Speaker 4:  Tiesto songs to your workout so that like the, the faster you were
Speaker 4:  moving, the faster Tiesto would go. Yeah. And I tried it out and it was like,
Speaker 4:  it was pretty cool 'cause it like keeps up with the beat as you're running
Speaker 4:  and you like you, it kinda, you fall into the right pace.
Speaker 4:  A hundred percent. Everyone is gonna crash their cars as soon as they start
Speaker 4:  you. Well,
Speaker 2:  So there's other things that happen too. For example, if it's raining and
Speaker 2:  you turn on your windshield wipers, it'll play lo-fi beats at you so
Speaker 2:  you can drive home sadly in the rain.
Speaker 5:  So you drive
Speaker 2:  Slow. I was in loved ones. My Mercedes Benz. If you get
Speaker 2:  in the
Speaker 4:  Car and you like roll into the McDonald's, drive through, like what does
Speaker 4:  it start
Speaker 2:  Playing? Mercedes wants sound drive to be an open music platform so that
Speaker 2:  any musician create their own auditory soundscape for driving,
Speaker 2:  using the Mbu operating system. Can you, this is like why I
Speaker 2:  am at CES. Yeah. I want to be very clear, this specific
Speaker 2:  nonsensical idea with Will I am just mash it all. I'm
Speaker 2:  surprised to have him put the words AI in this in any way, shape or form.
Speaker 5:  I'm just imagining being a kid in this car. You know when you'd sit in the
Speaker 5:  back and you'd like, when it's raining on your car, you're just thinking
Speaker 5:  really heavy thoughts in the back of the car as a little kid. But now you'll
Speaker 5:  have this soundtrack going with it. Yeah. Like the lo-fi soundtrack.
Speaker 4:  I just wanted to like play me depressing music while I like
Speaker 4:  shove Taco Bell in my face on a long road trip. Like what's, what's the vibe
Speaker 4:  there? One hand
Speaker 5:  On the wheel. Exactly. Tacos
Speaker 4:  In the
Speaker 2:  Other hand like Yeah, the one where will I am is like you got broken up with
Speaker 2:  dude.
Speaker 2:  You can, you can buy a taco and a burrito. You know what I'm saying?
Speaker 2:  Like that crunch wrap alone. Ain't gonna, ain't gonna take this home.
Speaker 2:  We've all been there. Alright, that's the Vergecast Day
Speaker 2:  two, episode two, day four
Speaker 2:  at CES 2024, right? Yeah. Seems good. It was a good
Speaker 2:  css. Yeah. Yeah. I will say it was good. Good. And I got to go sit in this
Speaker 2:  sphere. A almost religious experience capped off by
Speaker 2:  an almost religious movie.
Speaker 2:  Thank you for joining us. Thank you to Kia for letting us use our Space studio
Speaker 2:  shows. Thank you. The whole Verge team has just been killing it this week.
Speaker 2:  Please read the site. Check
Speaker 4:  Out our best of CES stuff. The best is up
Speaker 2:  As you're hearing this. It's coming right now. It's going up. TikTok channel
Speaker 2:  is full of really fun videos. CSS is really fun every year. It's like a great
Speaker 2:  way to start the year. It's just a bunch of tech. So it's been really fun.
Speaker 2:  Thanks for listening. Thanks for watching. See you next week. Bye.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The. Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The, Verge and V Media Podcast Network. The show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. This episode was mixed and edited by
Speaker 1:  Xander Adams. And that's it. We'll see you next
Speaker 1:  e nine for more details.