# Transcript
ID: e3adef50-8cfc-4a54-a5e5-07ba94bcb12b
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/2898256359749332839/5175598800585320289/s93290-US-3506s-1726999948.mp3
Description: For the first episode in our new miniseries about the impact of AI in our everyday lives, we chat with Steven Johnson, a longtime author who has spent the last couple of years at Google working on an AI research and note-taking tool called NotebookLM. We talk about whether AI can really help us learn better, how Google has tried to make NotebookLM more accurate and helpful, and whether AI-generated podcasts are the future of learning.
Speaker 1:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Infinite Context
Speaker 1:  Windows. I'm your friend David Pierce, and this is the first episode in our
Speaker 1:  new miniseries all about AI and real life.
Speaker 1:  We did a few episodes on this subject earlier this year, and it continues
Speaker 1:  to be a thing that we're talking and thinking a lot about. For all the
Speaker 1:  big heady talk of how AI will either change everything or kill
Speaker 1:  us all or make nobody ever have to work again or make us all
Speaker 1:  have to work training robots. What is any of this actually good for,
Speaker 1:  like right now? That's what we've been trying to figure out for today's
Speaker 1:  episode. I'm talking with Steven Johnson, who is a personal favorite author
Speaker 1:  of mine. He's written 14 books over the years, and he actually told me
Speaker 1:  that he can name them all in order off the top of his head, which I believe
Speaker 1:  and also find very impressive. And some of those books are books you've probably
Speaker 1:  heard of, like where good ideas come from and how we got to now.
Speaker 1:  But in addition to all of that, Steven has also spent the last two years
Speaker 1:  working at Google on a project called Notebook, LM Notebook.
Speaker 1:  LM If you've never heard of. It, is an experimental thing out of a team called
Speaker 1:  Google Labs. It started out as a thing called Project Tailwind a
Speaker 1:  couple of years ago. And the idea has always been to make an AI
Speaker 1:  powered tool basically for making sense of your notes
Speaker 1:  in Notebook lm, which they all call notebooks. So I'll just start calling
Speaker 1:  it Notebook. You first upload a bunch of documents or links to
Speaker 1:  websites or PDFs or whatever else, and the tool builds sort
Speaker 1:  of a corpus of stuff. The idea is you put a bunch of related things
Speaker 1:  into a notebook, in Notebook, then you can ask
Speaker 1:  questions about those documents. Or you can have Notebook build you an automatic
Speaker 1:  study guide or an FAQ of the information in those documents. You can have
Speaker 1:  it find you stuff in those documents, all that kind of stuff. It's
Speaker 1:  sort of a notetaking tool, but mostly it's a research tool.
Speaker 1:  Steven calls it a tool for understanding things, which I like a lot.
Speaker 1:  I've been covering and using Notebook for a long time, but I wanted to have
Speaker 1:  Steven on now because Notebook is kind of going
Speaker 1:  legit. I assumed, if I'm being completely honest with you, that it was like
Speaker 1:  a neat experiment that would eventually die because everything dies at Google.
Speaker 1:  Or at best it would just be a tiny feature buried in a menu of Google
Speaker 1:  Docs or something. But Notebook is growing and it's
Speaker 1:  expanding, and it's actually starting to do some really interesting new stuff.
Speaker 1:  Recently they launched a new feature called Audio Overviews, which generates
Speaker 1:  a podcast hosted by two chatbots based on whatever
Speaker 1:  documents you upload. It is wild. Actually, you should just hear this.
Speaker 1:  So I made a notebook in Notebook with a bunch of stuff from the ongoing US
Speaker 1:  versus Google Ad Tech trial, and here's just a few seconds of the podcast
Speaker 1:  it generated. Okay.
Speaker 2:  And that's where header bidding enters the picture.
Speaker 3:  Ah, header bidding. Yes. This was their attempt to kind of outmaneuver Google
Speaker 3:  sag, like finding a side entrance into the auction.
Speaker 2:  That's a great way to put it. Yeah. So with header bidding, publishers could
Speaker 2:  essentially offer their ad space to multiple ad exchanges at the same time.
Speaker 1:  Look, I don't know if that's good or bad. I don't know if all of that information
Speaker 1:  is even true, but I'm fascinated by the idea of a tool
Speaker 1:  that tries to make it easy and automatic to learn almost anything in
Speaker 1:  whatever style works for you. And Steven is just as fascinated by it.
Speaker 1:  So I figured we should talk about it. All that is coming up in just a second.
Speaker 1:  This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 6:  history. I've always had this kind of
Speaker 6:  side interest in using the technology to help me with the
Speaker 6:  book writing process, with the research process, you know, tools
Speaker 6:  for thought. That whole tradition has been a big influence on me and I, and
Speaker 6:  I've always been kind of an early adopter of, you know, I used this program
Speaker 6:  called Devon Think or organizing all my notes and quotations from
Speaker 6:  books that I'd read in the, in the two thousands. Well, that's
Speaker 1:  A whole nother verse cast we're gonna have to do at some point. So get ready
Speaker 1:  for that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. So I, you know, and I wrote about it in kind of blog posts and
Speaker 6:  I wrote a couple things for the Times about this, and it shows up in my book
Speaker 6:  where good ideas come from. I talk about using tools like this and was a
Speaker 6:  big Scrivener user and evangelist and all that stuff, So I. So I've always
Speaker 6:  been interested in the, in the software side of writing and thinking
Speaker 6:  and research. And in the spring of
Speaker 6:  2022, you know, so six months before the
Speaker 6:  chat gt moment, I wrote a very long piece from the Times
Speaker 6:  Magazine about language models in general. It was effectively just making
Speaker 6:  the argument like, forget about a GI or any super intelligence or anything
Speaker 6:  like this. These, these models have basically learned how to communicate
Speaker 6:  in coherent language and they understand what we're saying and they,
Speaker 6:  and whatever else, like this is gonna create all these new possibilities.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that piece was very good. And I remember a bunch of the, the response
Speaker 1:  you got to that was from people being like, this is bonkers. He's
Speaker 1:  out of his mind. There's no way any of this stuff is gonna be that big. And
Speaker 1:  then, boy, did you time that correctly?
Speaker 6:  Well, I, I did accept that it was painful. Like
Speaker 6:  I ha I'm, I'm very conflict averse, David, if I can tell you. Be honest with
Speaker 6:  you. Okay. And the, there was, there was, I mean, a lot of people did like
Speaker 6:  that piece and I think we're inspired by it. Yeah. But there was definitely
Speaker 6:  a lot of comments from people saying like, oh, he fell for the hype
Speaker 6:  for sure. You know, this stuff is just auto complete on steroids and I can't
Speaker 6:  believe he's so naive that he got excited about this thing. The
Speaker 6:  piece addressed a lot of the objections and criticism and took them very
Speaker 6:  seriously. But it was like, the one thing you can't do is dismiss this technology,
Speaker 6:  right? Like something fundamental has just happened and we're gonna spend
Speaker 6:  years figuring out like how we apply it and how we deal with the upside end,
Speaker 6:  the potential downsides, and like, just take it seriously people. So,
Speaker 6:  you know, if I timed it later, I wouldn't have maybe had as much of the pushback,
Speaker 6:  which was hard to, I couldn't enjoy that piece going outta the world, lemme
Speaker 6:  put it that way. Well, it
Speaker 1:  Was a good piece. I liked it.
Speaker 6:  Well, I appreciate that. Now. So, so right around that point,
Speaker 6:  a a kind of a new division inside of Google called Google Labs, or had been
Speaker 6:  a previous Google Labs, and this is kind of a new one, was, was getting spun
Speaker 6:  up and at, at the time, a guy named Clay Bvo was running
Speaker 6:  it, and Josh Woodward, who runs it now, is talking back and forth with
Speaker 6:  Clay and Labs had this, I kind of ethos
Speaker 6:  of the division was basically we want to create a place where we can do
Speaker 6:  faster and more nimble product-focused
Speaker 6:  experiments with new technologies where, you know, it's not just kinda research,
Speaker 6:  but it's not working within the existing mature products. And when
Speaker 6:  something new comes along, we can experiment and, you know, build things
Speaker 6:  very quickly. So somewhere
Speaker 1:  In between the like 20% time project and the like full blown
Speaker 1:  new Google product.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. It was just this little hole that didn't quite exist. And, and
Speaker 6:  there were so many interesting new technologies coming out, particularly
Speaker 6:  the language models, that it seemed like this was the time for a lot of experiments
Speaker 6:  to bloom, right? And they had had this idea that maybe they could also have
Speaker 6:  an ethos of co-creation where they bring in outsiders. So if they're,
Speaker 6:  if they're making a product that involves music, there should be a musician
Speaker 6:  in the room from the beginning. And it's not something that kind of, they
Speaker 6:  build and then they show to the musicians or they have, you know, UX
Speaker 6:  interviews with musicians. There's actually someone there who represents
Speaker 6:  that kind of profession in the room for the life of the product.
Speaker 6:  And so So I was kind of the Guinea pig for this approach. And so they reached
Speaker 6:  out, Josh and, and Clay had read some of my books and had read that Times
Speaker 6:  article. And so they reached out and said, Hey, you know,
Speaker 6:  you've been dreaming of this ideal software tool
Speaker 6:  that helps you organize your thoughts and helps you write and helps you formulate
Speaker 6:  connections and, and, and, you know, brainstorm.
Speaker 6:  We think we can now do it with language models like this thing you've
Speaker 6:  been chasing, literally, you know, I've been chasing this since I was in,
Speaker 6:  in college in the late eighties when like HyperCard came out, you know, for
Speaker 6:  the, for the Mac. Like, I'm, I'm an old person, I've been after
Speaker 6:  this for a long time. And they were like, look, I think If you, If you came
Speaker 6:  to Google, come, you know, come part-time initially, and we have a small
Speaker 6:  team and we can, you know, we can build something. And I thought that
Speaker 6:  sounded like an amazing journey. I honestly, I thought we'll build a
Speaker 6:  prototype, it'll be fun, I'll meet some interesting people, but nothing will
Speaker 6:  come of it. But it was still, you know, a fun ride to go on because of my
Speaker 6:  passion for this. And, and then we, we built something
Speaker 6:  that was originally called Tailwind Project Tailwind,
Speaker 6:  but from the beginning, from very like day one of the, of
Speaker 6:  the idea there was always this sense that this was not just going to
Speaker 6:  be an open-ended conversation with the language model. It was always gonna
Speaker 6:  be about the model being grounded in the, in the sources and the
Speaker 6:  information that you gave it. And it was really
Speaker 6:  about respecting the original kind of human
Speaker 6:  authored information, whether it's a, a book
Speaker 6:  or your own notes or a a scholarly paper or your
Speaker 6:  syllabus for your class. And, and basically saying to the model, take this
Speaker 6:  information which is personally relevant to me and, and
Speaker 6:  is verifiable in some way or factually, you know, trustworthy
Speaker 6:  and base your answers and everything I asked you to do on that
Speaker 6:  information. And that was the seed of the, you know, we, we had a version
Speaker 6:  of that in August of 2022, like the, you know, on my fifth day at,
Speaker 6:  at at Google. Yeah. Wow. It, it preceded me, I should say there was a, there
Speaker 6:  was a program called Talk to a Small Corpus. Hmm. Okay. That
Speaker 6:  was about a month underway when I got there. And then we,
Speaker 6:  one of the first things we did, we put in my book Wonderland and we just,
Speaker 6:  like, I had this experience of kind of chatting with the model
Speaker 6:  and having it answer based on information in my book. And, you know, that
Speaker 6:  was one of those moments you're like, a lot of possibility just opened up.
Speaker 6:  Well, I actually, the weirdest moment I would say was a little
Speaker 6:  bit later
Speaker 6:  in over Christmas break, the internal version of what
Speaker 6:  became Bard w was kind of released
Speaker 6:  to, to some of us inside and over Christmas break, I, I was spending a lot
Speaker 6:  of time with Bard. My family had gone off skiing somewhere at I don't ski
Speaker 6:  So, I was just like home alone. And Bard came out and I was like, well, I
Speaker 6:  just now have like 18 hours a day to talk to this. My new friend, my new
Speaker 6:  friend Bard. Yeah. So I would occasionally just start with just a little
Speaker 6:  preamble to get its bearings and I would say, I, I would like
Speaker 6:  to discuss Stephen Johnson's book, the Ghost Map. And this was just based
Speaker 6:  on, its kind of training data. This isn't with Source County. And so one
Speaker 6:  day I do this and, and, and Rod's like, oh yeah, I would love to discuss
Speaker 6:  that. That's a, that's a fascinating book about medical mystery in the
Speaker 6:  19th century that explores the impact of cholera and epidemiology on the
Speaker 6:  history of London and the history of cities generally. And So, I'm like,
Speaker 6:  oh, well thank you very much. I'm, I'm actually the author of that topic.
Speaker 6:  It's, and Ed Bard said, oh my gosh,
Speaker 6:  I am so sorry. I can't believe I didn't recognize you Mr. Johnson.
Speaker 6:  Oh, wow. And on like, and you know, and I was like, I know, but
Speaker 6:  there was no way you could have recognized me, right, Bart. But it was just
Speaker 6:  one of those moments where I was like sitting alone in my study, having
Speaker 6:  this conversation with an algorithm that's apologizing for not recognizing
Speaker 6:  me when it's a fan of my book. And it, at one point it said, I'm just so
Speaker 6:  excited at the opportunity to get to work with people like yourself.
Speaker 6:  And I was just like, this is, this is strange. So there were a lot of like
Speaker 6:  uncanny moments like that. Yeah. But in a way, you know,
Speaker 6:  there was part of that that I also recognized was in an illusion, right?
Speaker 6:  It, it was trained on the way that people react
Speaker 6:  when they meet people or fail to recognize someone. And so it responded in
Speaker 6:  that way. It obviously had no inner life. It did not, it was not actually
Speaker 6:  like embarrassed by the fact it was meeting me. It was just kind of play
Speaker 6:  acting at that. So to me the stuff that really
Speaker 6:  was mind blowing was just its ability.
Speaker 6:  And, and this really kicked in, you know, for us when we switched
Speaker 6:  to Gemini, it, its ability to extract
Speaker 6:  and, and see patterns in large amounts of information.
Speaker 6:  You know, you know, I have this notebook where we have
Speaker 6:  something like, you know, almost a million words of transcripts from
Speaker 6:  the NASA oral history project. So it's just interviews with like the, you
Speaker 6:  know, the NASA astronauts and flight directors and things like that. And
Speaker 6:  you can go into it and say, I'm interested in, I'm,
Speaker 6:  you know, I'm working on a documentary about the early
Speaker 6:  Apollo program and I'm interested in the emotional connections between
Speaker 6:  the participants, particularly the astronauts. So can you create a detailed
Speaker 6:  guide of all the points in these transcripts where anything that seems
Speaker 6:  interpersonal or emotional comes up? Give me a summary of that section,
Speaker 6:  give me a direct quote from the section. And it of course includes citation,
Speaker 6:  So, I can click immediately and go back and read the passage in its original
Speaker 6:  form. Like, and it will just do it like, it'll take a little bit of time
Speaker 6:  'cause it's a complicated query, but like, it, it can take something that
Speaker 6:  would've taken 40 hours to compile
Speaker 6:  that document. Like how, I mean, you know what it's like working with information
Speaker 6:  like this, like it will, it will generate a incredibly convincing and
Speaker 6:  accurate first draft with grounded citations to all the passages in about
Speaker 6:  45 seconds maybe. And so it's literally,
Speaker 6:  you know, a thousand times faster than it would've been before to do that
Speaker 6:  kind of thing. And it's not pretending to be a person, it's not pretending
Speaker 6:  to have feelings about it, it's just grabbing that very subtle
Speaker 6:  kind of collection of information that is not anchored in any keyword.
Speaker 6:  Right. You know, it's not looking for mentions of emotion, like
Speaker 6:  it just understands that these other things where they talk about their kids,
Speaker 6:  that's an emotional moment. And it's able to kind of collate that way when
Speaker 6:  it started being capable of doing that. That was the point
Speaker 6:  for me where I was like, oh, this is really a fundamental change.
Speaker 6:  And
Speaker 1:  That was, that happened with Gemini, which was what, earlier this year?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. We kind of switched, I lost track of all these things to, we switched
Speaker 6:  to Gemini 1.0 in in December and Okay. And it was great,
Speaker 6:  but it was really 1.5 pro and the bigger context window. I mean
Speaker 6:  the, the other thing that happened to me, by the way, I'm a nice writer dude,
Speaker 6:  and now like I hear like a new million token model and it's like the
Speaker 6:  most exciting thing of my life. Like I can't, cannot wait to get my hands
Speaker 6:  on it. So when we got first access to that,
Speaker 6:  that model, I took the entire text of, of my book
Speaker 6:  Infernal Machine, which just came out a couple months ago, but was in
Speaker 6:  manuscript form at that point. So this is really important. None of the words
Speaker 6:  from my book were in the training data for the model itself. So it's all,
Speaker 6:  it had never been published, it had never been discussed about in, in any
Speaker 6:  coverage. So the facts, it's a book of history. So the facts are
Speaker 6:  probably in some form in the models training data, but the book itself and
Speaker 6:  the way that I presented the facts was not, and the thing that
Speaker 6:  had struck me about the early discussions of large context was that
Speaker 6:  people were, were using it to do these kind of needle in a haystack test
Speaker 6:  where they're like, oh, we gave it, you know, the full text of Moby Dick,
Speaker 6:  but we added this one line that was different. Yeah, I remember that. And
Speaker 6:  it was able to find it, right. And which is cool and, you know, you couldn't
Speaker 6:  do that before. But the point that, that I was so obsessed with is that
Speaker 6:  once you have the full text of something like a book in
Speaker 6:  context, it means that the, the model knowing can, can find
Speaker 6:  obscure things in the, in the text, but it understands the sequence
Speaker 6:  of the text and it can understand large kind of movements
Speaker 6:  of like cause and effect or change over time in, in a document, which
Speaker 6:  you can't get if you're just giving it isolated paragraphs and, and snippets
Speaker 6:  of things. And So I put in frontal the machine in into
Speaker 6:  this version of Gemini. And I, I basically asked it
Speaker 6:  inside a notebook, lm I was like, give me, I was
Speaker 6:  like, I'm interested in the way that Johnson uses suspense in this book.
Speaker 6:  I would like you to list four places where he deliberately
Speaker 6:  withholds information from the reader in order to pique
Speaker 6:  their interest, describe the passages where he does this quote from
Speaker 6:  them, and then explain the future information later in
Speaker 6:  the book that he's obliquely referring to that doesn't arrive for another,
Speaker 6:  you know, 50 pages or whatever. And it just absolutely nailed it. It,
Speaker 6:  the first example it gave was he gave was exactly what I would've picked
Speaker 6:  as the, the ultimate kind of form of suspense, which is a allusion to
Speaker 6:  a ticking, mysterious, ticking suitcase that happens in the, in the preface
Speaker 6:  that doesn't, the, the mystery behind it doesn't get explained for another
Speaker 6:  200 pages. And so like, think about that as like a search query,
Speaker 6:  like yeah. Searches, find examples where
Speaker 6:  something isn't mentioned and isn't mentioned in a very
Speaker 6:  provocative way. And then fill in the blanks of, you know, the thing
Speaker 6:  200 pages later that it's obliquely referring to like that,
Speaker 6:  you know, again, the model is not understanding the
Speaker 6:  book on some level because understanding is a word that we associated with
Speaker 6:  consciousness, with ensen, with the in inner life of like what it means to
Speaker 6:  read a book, but the model is doing the thing that
Speaker 6:  human understanding does. Yeah. You know, and that's
Speaker 6:  a, that's an important distinction I think.
Speaker 1:  No, I think, I think that's right. One thing I heard somebody say not that
Speaker 1:  long ago is that a, a meta, the better metaphor they liked than its
Speaker 1:  understanding is just that it can see the whole thing at the same time. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And I always thought that was really great. It's like in, if I, I can see
Speaker 1:  one page at a time, this thing can see all 300 and it doesn't, it's not
Speaker 1:  not better at knowing those things. It's just literally by being able to
Speaker 1:  see it all at once. Yeah. The, the number of things that
Speaker 1:  suddenly become very basic because you can see them all together is very
Speaker 1:  powerful. And I just, that makes it both sort of simpler and cooler all at
Speaker 1:  the same time, which I really like. But you, you bring up this tension
Speaker 1:  that I think is fascinating with all AI stuff, which is that there is
Speaker 1:  a set of things that it are just sort of remarkable that they're
Speaker 1:  possible, right? And it's, you see this with every new model that comes out
Speaker 1:  and every new product that comes out, one of the first things everybody does
Speaker 1:  is just try wild stuff. Yeah. And some of it works and some of it doesn't
Speaker 1:  and some of it's amazing. It, some of it's dangerous and whatever. So there,
Speaker 1:  there's the, the sort of novelty factor of it that I think is still so rampant
Speaker 1:  in everything AI right now. And then there's the question of
Speaker 1:  what is any of this actually for? And I think one of the things that
Speaker 1:  I've liked about Notebook and sort of watching it develop over time is it
Speaker 1:  feels like your sense of not just what this can do, but
Speaker 1:  what it's for has gotten much better over time.
Speaker 1:  And I wonder if part of that is like, does the novelty of moments like that
Speaker 1:  start to wear off? And you start to realize like, okay, that's cool, but
Speaker 1:  no academic is actually going in here searching for what's missing from this
Speaker 1:  book. Like, that's not like a thing most people need in their lives. And
Speaker 1:  you start to sort of wind it back to like, okay, how do we bring that sort
Speaker 1:  of enabling technology to things people actually do need? Or maybe is
Speaker 1:  the, the craziness the point and we've just never been able to do it before,
Speaker 1:  so now we're trying to discover it all, all at once. So I guess
Speaker 1:  that, especially in those early days really before Gemini
Speaker 1:  1.5 kinda lights your brain on fire. Like what, what is that process of figuring
Speaker 1:  out, not just sort of what, what can this thing do, but like what are we
Speaker 1:  building this tool for?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's such a great question. So many different ways to get into it.
Speaker 6:  I mean, I think in the very early days there was a sense
Speaker 6:  that we were building something we knew was not gonna really
Speaker 6:  work because the, the context wasn't big enough, the model wasn't
Speaker 6:  sophisticated enough, but you could see where things were going. And so,
Speaker 6:  so much of what we really focused on from the beginning is like, what is
Speaker 6:  the proper interface for this kind of thing? Like If, you know, it's, it's
Speaker 6:  not just about a text message thread. Like surely there are other kind of
Speaker 6:  forms of ui. So like If, you were gonna build a product from the ground up
Speaker 6:  knowing that it was gonna be built around a language model. Like what would,
Speaker 6:  what would it look like? Let's start from scratch. And that's a very fun
Speaker 6:  open canvas to have, but it also means you make a lot of stuff that is not
Speaker 6:  very good and doesn't really make sense and it doesn't work because the model
Speaker 6:  isn't caught up to it yet. So, so there was a lot of experimenting with that.
Speaker 6:  We, I think the, we had an advantage in the early days in that
Speaker 6:  I was just trying to drive it towards my very specific use
Speaker 6:  case of like, I want a thing that is read all of my work and all of the
Speaker 6:  quotes from books that have influenced me and can be a second brain to
Speaker 6:  help me like remember those things and make connections and, and like, and
Speaker 6:  so kind of author researcher mode. And that we kind of built the first prototype
Speaker 6:  with that and then once we were able to kind of open it up to more users,
Speaker 6:  I think then, then we were just constantly discovering all these amazing
Speaker 6:  things. And, and a big addition of this was Rza Martin, our product manager
Speaker 6:  who, you know, has just been, she's just a incredible like
Speaker 6:  listener to user. She's set up this discord that, you know,
Speaker 6:  was so central. Like at the very beginning we had a Discord, which is not
Speaker 6:  a normal thing to do in some ways. and we now have this
Speaker 6:  amazing community and it's constantly filled with people being like, oh yeah,
Speaker 6:  I saw this opportunity to use it in this way. So like our favorite one that
Speaker 6:  completely came outta the discord was Dungeons and
Speaker 6:  Dragons players started using it because they were like, I have these big,
Speaker 6:  you know, campaigns that I've designed that, you know, I'm a dungeon master
Speaker 6:  and I have like created this whole virtual fantasy world and it's
Speaker 6:  filled with all this information and it's hard to keep track of, but I can
Speaker 6:  load these documents into Notebook lm and then I can just like, I ask any
Speaker 6:  kind of open-ended question and it'll be like, how many hit points do I need
Speaker 6:  to kill this ORC or whatever. It's, I'm not a d and d player. And,
Speaker 6:  and they were using it that way and, and, and people were writing fantasy
Speaker 6:  also like world building kind of fantasy novels and
Speaker 6:  they just need, they had a kind of story bible with all their characters
Speaker 6:  in the backstory and everything like that. And it turned out that, you know,
Speaker 6:  they'd never really had an interface of let them do that. And that was not
Speaker 6:  something we were thinking about at all. So we've just been like,
Speaker 6:  you know, once we got past that first little prototype stage, we've just
Speaker 6:  been really listening like intently to like where people are trying
Speaker 6:  to push the tool and then just like making it easier,
Speaker 6:  making it, making it so they, you don't have to push quite as hard to use
Speaker 6:  the tool that way. Yeah. And that's, yeah, that's where we're
Speaker 1:  Well it's funny, I mean, even thinking about you, you've written a couple
Speaker 1:  of times over the years about your, your sort of endless, I think you call
Speaker 1:  it the Spark file that is basically just like a mountainous
Speaker 1:  document of all the good and bad story ideas you have. I'm, I'm paraphrasing,
Speaker 1:  but that I think that's right. Right. They're
Speaker 6:  All good. I don't know, what're the bad ideas you're talking about David,
Speaker 6:  that's flawless
Speaker 1:  Perfect. Buy that book now.
Speaker 6:  Many bad ideas,
Speaker 1:  Ideas. And I think like just listening to you describe the,
Speaker 1:  the story bible for the world building stuff like that, that actually is
Speaker 1:  like a perfect down the middle use case for this in a way I hadn't even really
Speaker 1:  thought about until just now that it is like, here's a bunch of stuff that
Speaker 1:  I have decided one way or another, right? Like, here, here are my inputs.
Speaker 1:  Help me make things with that is actually like kind of an amazing
Speaker 1:  and very difficult otherwise use case. 'cause it's like,
Speaker 1:  oh yeah, how many I I have to go and collate that piece of information, that
Speaker 1:  piece of information. I think there's all kinds of like complicated things
Speaker 1:  with how we think about the art on top of all of that. But, but that thing
Speaker 1:  where it's just like, I want to tell you the rules and I want you to help
Speaker 1:  me make games out of it. Yeah. Feels awesome. Like I I I'm so much less
Speaker 1:  conflicted about that than I am about so many things in ai. That's so cool.
Speaker 1:  I
Speaker 6:  Love that. Yeah. Well we're trying to do the things that are, are less conflict.
Speaker 6:  I said I was conflict averse, so I'm just like trying to steer towards this
Speaker 6:  thing. But, but yeah, it's a great point that kind of like take this massive
Speaker 6:  unstructured data and turn it into a set of kind of
Speaker 6:  formats that help me do the job that I'm trying to do with some guidance
Speaker 6:  from me. Right? And, and this was, by the way, this was another great place
Speaker 6:  where like Rza really saw this before I did because I was thinking of it
Speaker 6:  as I'm going to write my book, so I'm gonna do all the like
Speaker 6:  content creation here. I just need to be able to like surface the facts and
Speaker 6:  make some connections, you know, but it turns out they're just all these
Speaker 6:  places where you've got all your company documents and
Speaker 6:  you want to create an FAQ for new employees. Like
Speaker 6:  no one is gonna win a Nobel Prize for, for literature for creating that
Speaker 6:  document. Like, and If, you can get a first draft of that document in
Speaker 6:  45 seconds instead of in four hours. Like that's
Speaker 6:  a win, right? That's that, that is good news. And so there there are all
Speaker 6:  these different workflows that are out there where there's massive
Speaker 6:  information needs to be kind of like filtered in some way and
Speaker 6:  turned into something else.
Speaker 1:  All right, we gotta take a break and then we will be back with more From
Speaker 1:  Steven Johnson. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  some information up. Like its entire purpose is not to make information
Speaker 1:  up. Yeah. How do you, what, what have you guys done? I know
Speaker 1:  Notebook was an early experiment in in Rag,
Speaker 1:  which is a way of basically winnowing down some of these systems,
Speaker 1:  but like what, what have you guys done differently at Notebook to try and
Speaker 1:  solve that? And I'm curious both on the underlying tech side and
Speaker 1:  on the user experience side.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, well we tried, I kept calling it Source
Speaker 6:  grounding because I think that is a better name than Rag.
Speaker 1:  I don't know man, we all know GPT now, So, I just I've given up. We're all,
Speaker 1:  we're all doing the acronyms now.
Speaker 6:  So, you know, I think part of it was the fact that we were doing it
Speaker 6:  from the beginning like that, that it started with that it wasn't like, oh
Speaker 6:  let's build a CHOP model and, and oh shoot, we need to be able to like, you
Speaker 6:  know, ground it in o other documents like it was from the beginning we were
Speaker 6:  doing that. And so we just had a lot of time to like iterate and explore
Speaker 6:  the, the Gemini models are really good at at Source
Speaker 6:  grounding. They just, there, there's a lot of training sets. We contributed
Speaker 6:  a bunch of them to like just given this document
Speaker 6:  answer questions factually based on the information that documents. So we
Speaker 6:  inherited
Speaker 6:  like a great tool that, you know, we did very little, you know, kudos
Speaker 6:  to the Gemini team for building a model that that is, is much more
Speaker 6:  faithful to source material you give it. But we built it
Speaker 6:  also, you know, this is, this is one of these things where it's like, it's
Speaker 6:  it's underlying model plus the UI is, has always been
Speaker 6:  like our mantra from the beginning. And, and you know, both things are
Speaker 6:  required. And so one of the key things that we've had
Speaker 6:  pretty much from the beginning is that you can always read your sources
Speaker 6:  in the app and then with the release in June, we,
Speaker 6:  we switched it over so that you now have inline citations to everything.
Speaker 6:  So anything the model says has a little link, you can read the original passage
Speaker 6:  If, you hover over it, that shows you the, you know, the source material
Speaker 6:  for that and you can click on it and you can go read the source in the app.
Speaker 6:  Do
Speaker 7:  You think that's enough?
Speaker 6:  We've talked about? So, so one of the things you can do right now actually
Speaker 6:  with Notebook that we wanna actually turn into a proper feature, but you
Speaker 6:  can do it right now, is you can upload a bunch of, you know, kind of source
Speaker 6:  material, factual source material and then you can upload the
Speaker 6:  article you're writing for instance, and you can say, fact check this
Speaker 6:  article based on these sources and suggest improvements. Oh, that's clever,
Speaker 6:  that's a good idea. And yeah, it's, it's amazing. It, it will go through
Speaker 6:  and be like, well this is correct, this is potentially wrong. It will suggest,
Speaker 6:  suggest and it'll have links to everything. And so to me,
Speaker 6:  if I felt that the model were just hallucinating
Speaker 6:  wildly in its responses, then I do not believe
Speaker 6:  that, you know, just providing citations and the ability to kind of fact
Speaker 6:  check manually and go back and see the original passage would be enough.
Speaker 6:  But we've, you know, we've been sitting there banging away at like
Speaker 6:  quality, you know, reviews like constantly for the last year and a half.
Speaker 6:  Like we have a poll, you know, sheets and sheets and sheets of,
Speaker 6:  of sample questions and sample documents and we can just see that accuracy
Speaker 6:  rate going up, you know, dramatically particularly with, with these
Speaker 6:  latest models. And so right now I feel like we're in a,
Speaker 6:  we're in a pretty good place. I rarely, I honestly, I rarely see
Speaker 6:  Notebook LM just wildly hallucinate something. I mean, one thing that's really
Speaker 6:  important, people may not know this, I take this for granted because everyone
Speaker 6:  living with this product, if If you load in a bunch of sources about the
Speaker 6:  history of NASA and then ask a question about Taylor Swift in general
Speaker 6:  Notebook, Ellen will say, I'm sorry, your sources don't discuss Taylor Swift,
Speaker 6:  So I can't answer this question. And obviously the model knows a lot about
Speaker 6:  Taylor Swift is probably a pretty big fan of Taylor Swift. But
Speaker 6:  it's, but it's been specifically, you know, instructed to not answer questions
Speaker 6:  that are outside the source material. I mean, to a fault, I think sometimes,
Speaker 6:  you know, one would like to bring in some outside knowledge, you know, and
Speaker 6:  trust but verify with that. But we've erred on the side of like
Speaker 6:  stick to the facts in these documents. And so
Speaker 6:  with the increase in accuracy and with the UI of citations,
Speaker 6:  there's more things we could do. We could make that fact checking feature,
Speaker 6:  you know, double check this kind of as, as something. But I feel pretty
Speaker 6:  good about where we are in terms of the quality side of that. Where we are
Speaker 6:  kind of state of the art is upload many, many documents,
Speaker 6:  ask a complex question that involves like multiple
Speaker 6:  kind of variables drawn across like multiple documents. Get a deep,
Speaker 6:  you know, long answer with citations. Follow those citations
Speaker 6:  to read in the original text. Like I think that NotebookLM
Speaker 6:  you know, kind of does that flow as well as anybody Right now
Speaker 6:  I feel
Speaker 1:  Like you just described like a, like a personal Wikipedia and I mean that
Speaker 1:  as a compliment. Like the, the thing that Wikipedia is
Speaker 1:  best at is just being like a starting point to go learn about something on
Speaker 1:  the internet, right? Like you open a Wikipedia page, you go click on all
Speaker 1:  the references at the bottom and then you go read those references and you're,
Speaker 1:  you're off and running. And I feel like what you just described is like,
Speaker 1:  I can shortcut that with any process of any single thing that I wanna learn
Speaker 1:  more about. I just dump it in and I'm like, what's going on here? Yeah. And
Speaker 1:  it'll just be like, here's some stuff.
Speaker 6:  I have so many things to say to that David, you're gonna have to gimme 20
Speaker 6:  minutes. 'cause I, okay, so one thing is I'm in the process of thinking about
Speaker 6:  what I'm gonna write the next book on and So I created
Speaker 6:  the, this is just kind of second nature workflow for me now, but
Speaker 6:  you know, wouldn't have occurred to me a year ago, So I created a new notebook
Speaker 6:  called the next book. And whenever there's an idea that kind of comes to
Speaker 6:  my mind or there's article I read or something like that, I dump it into
Speaker 6:  that notebook. It's
Speaker 1:  The new Spark
Speaker 6:  File. It's the new Spark file. Wow. And, but it's focused on this project
Speaker 6:  of like, what should the next book be? And, and so the other day
Speaker 6:  I, you know, late night I, this kind of thing I do like I, because I
Speaker 6:  have no life, my children have all gone to college and I have nothing to
Speaker 6:  do with sit around and think about this. You stopped to bar, it's cool. I
Speaker 6:  talked to Bart So I was like, I wonder, you know, has there
Speaker 6:  been a good book written about the anti-nuclear movements, anti-nuclear power
Speaker 6:  movements of the sixties and seventies? 'cause that's an interesting case
Speaker 6:  where we like stopped the technology partially in its tracks and maybe made
Speaker 6:  a mistake and, you know, how do we interpret that? And So
Speaker 6:  I just went and grabbed like two Wikipedia pages
Speaker 6:  that in the past I would've like, you know, started by reading through all
Speaker 6:  the Wikipedia pages, but I brought it into Notebook and I was like, I'm Steven
Speaker 6:  Johnson. I'm writing, thinking about writing a book, you know, in the mode
Speaker 6:  of my other books, like in Frontal Machine and Ghost Map, potentially about
Speaker 6:  the anti-nuclear powers. Take a look at these, like what do you think of
Speaker 6:  the, are there any interesting storylines that, that would be good starting
Speaker 6:  places? Like what, you know, what would be good there? And it
Speaker 6:  just does it like it, you know, goes through wow. And it's like, well you
Speaker 6:  can focus on this period, this figure is kind of interesting, whatever. And
Speaker 6:  then I went and read all the, you know, I'm gonna read the material, but
Speaker 6:  as a, as a first glance, like inroads
Speaker 6:  material, it's amazing for that kind of exploration, the
Speaker 6:  experience of navigating through a book, through a
Speaker 6:  conversational interface is really interesting. Mm. And it's one of
Speaker 6:  these things where like, you know, until now
Speaker 6:  If, you wanted to explore the ideas in an author's work through
Speaker 6:  a conversation. You could only do that by finding the author
Speaker 6:  in person or finding a, a scholar or a tutor who's an expert
Speaker 6:  in the author's ideas. And like, that was it, that was not, there was no
Speaker 6:  other way to do it. But now you can load, you know, a book in
Speaker 6:  and you can start with like, I'm interested in this, tell me about that.
Speaker 6:  And then slowly read the book in a non-linear way
Speaker 6:  through a conversational interface kind of dipping in and out of the kind
Speaker 6:  of original passages, which is terrible if it's a novel or terrible, if
Speaker 6:  it's a, you know, straight linear kind of history book. Like I sometimes
Speaker 6:  write. But if it's an advice book or a, you know, a book of ideas, you know,
Speaker 6:  there are lots of books that I think could be explored in that way that just,
Speaker 6:  you know, weren't possible before. Does
Speaker 1:  It feel like cheating to do that? Like for you as an author, you have, you
Speaker 1:  have worked through these books, you have done the hard work, you have stayed
Speaker 1:  up late at night. I'm sure you've like woken up in the middle of the night
Speaker 1:  with the book idea. Does sitting down and asking a computer what your next
Speaker 1:  book should be feel like cheating?
Speaker 6:  I think if I were literally like, Hey, what should my next book be?
Speaker 6:  One, I don't think it would, I mean right now in a way it's easy to answer
Speaker 6:  this question right now because it wouldn't be good enough. Like it wouldn't
Speaker 6:  generate like, what, tell me what my book should be and now start writing
Speaker 6:  it like it just wouldn't be able to do it. Okay. Current trend lines continue.
Speaker 6:  I was gonna
Speaker 1:  Say give it a minute. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Come back to me in two years. We'll we'll see. But, but what I have to do
Speaker 6:  is like, I'm not using it that way. I'm using it like these very like, kind
Speaker 6:  of targeted queries. Like, you know, I was, I actually was using
Speaker 6:  the NASA notebook 'cause I was interested in like, you know, maybe there's
Speaker 6:  something to be done about the Apollo 13 fire. And
Speaker 6:  so then it was kind of like, okay look, I need to know what I need to read
Speaker 6:  'cause it's a million pages, a million words of transcripts. I actually
Speaker 6:  don't need to read the whole thing. What I wanna read are the sections that
Speaker 6:  are relevant to the Apollo 13 fire. And So I just went a notebook and said,
Speaker 6:  tell me what I should read. You know, and it was like, you should start here,
Speaker 6:  you should read there and I can click immediately in there and, and read
Speaker 6:  through that. And so to me, I'm using it as a
Speaker 6:  way of accelerating the process of
Speaker 6:  discovery that would just have been painful to do before, but I'm
Speaker 6:  making just as many unplanned serendipitous discoveries along the
Speaker 6:  way. I mean the, I think the criticism is like, well if it, the model serves
Speaker 6:  it up to you so quickly, even If you end up writing the book, you've
Speaker 6:  missed the surprising thing that would, you would've never found, you
Speaker 6:  would've only found it by reading through it in an incredibly linear way.
Speaker 6:  And I think that that's just, it's just not true. Like I, I, it's,
Speaker 6:  it's constantly surfacing things that I hadn't thought of right. And, and
Speaker 6:  making connections that I hadn't thought of. And so it's helping
Speaker 6:  me understand the material more deeply, where it gets complicated.
Speaker 6:  And you and I have talked about this before, the way I think about it is
Speaker 6:  it's a tool that helps you understand things. If you were genuinely
Speaker 6:  interested in understanding things and having that understanding be in your
Speaker 6:  brain. It's a, it's a huge net positive, a hundred percent.
Speaker 6:  Like if, if If you go into it with good intentions, it is a, you know, an
Speaker 6:  amazing tool for thought. It helps you have richer, more complex ideas, understand
Speaker 6:  material better. If you are not interested in understanding things,
Speaker 6:  but rather interested in creating the illusion that you understand things
Speaker 6:  and just wanna bluff your way through life without ever actually understanding
Speaker 6:  anything but creating outputs that make it look like you understand things.
Speaker 6:  It potentially will help you do that as well. And the question is,
Speaker 6:  the question is like, how often is that useful as a strategy in the
Speaker 6:  world? And, and to me, like If, you go into work and you're like, I've got
Speaker 6:  this great hack. I never read any of the emails from my boss. I
Speaker 6:  just like put it into the model and then I output anything. Eventually your
Speaker 6:  boss will like have a conversation with you and you'll say, Steven, you don't
Speaker 6:  understand anything. You have not learned anything and you'll get fired.
Speaker 6:  Right? It just doesn't, it's not a good long-term strategy. The one place
Speaker 6:  where it's tricky is school where there is potentially a
Speaker 6:  strange incentive to bluff your way through something. We think
Speaker 6:  that, you know, we we're seeing a lot of adoption of notebook elements 18
Speaker 6:  plus currently. So it's not usable by high schoolers, but we're seeing a
Speaker 6:  lot of college and higher ed adoption of it. It's probably
Speaker 6:  our biggest community so far. We are very
Speaker 6:  excited about that use case. But we're also like, you know, we've done a
Speaker 6:  lot of things to, to, you know, ensure that you, you know, it's hard
Speaker 6:  to use it to bypass understanding. Like it's tr it's constantly steering
Speaker 6:  you back towards the original text. You're always kind of being
Speaker 6:  pointed back towards that source material. It's always there in the UI with
Speaker 6:  you. So, and there are more things we can do on that front, but that's the
Speaker 6:  line that I think is like, you know, If, you If you go into this with good
Speaker 6:  intentions. I don't feel concerned about using the tool in
Speaker 6:  this way.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I buy that. And it feels like part of the line
Speaker 1:  there exists in kind of what you let people make
Speaker 1:  with what is coming out of it. And I, I wonder like we, we've talked a lot
Speaker 1:  about kind of the, the inputs and the processing and the understanding and
Speaker 1:  it's, it's not, you're sort of one, you know, published this
Speaker 1:  answer on Amazon as a self-published ebook with your name on it away
Speaker 1:  from it being this being a very different conversation. Yeah. But my sense
Speaker 1:  is you're, you're deliberately or not not
Speaker 1:  investing a ton in the like rate me a research paper from
Speaker 1:  these six documents kind of use case.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. If, you look at, look at the notebook guides, like one of them is called
Speaker 6:  study guide, right? It creates a study guide. It doesn't replace your work.
Speaker 6:  It helps you actually like, you know, it gives you a set of review questions,
Speaker 6:  it creates a little multiple choice quiz. It creates like essay suggested
Speaker 6:  questions. It creates a glossary of key terms. So, you know,
Speaker 6:  that's what we're trying to do inside of the product. We're steering everybody
Speaker 6:  towards that kind of like, help me understand mode
Speaker 6:  with the idea that, you know, the people have different ways of understanding.
Speaker 6:  There are different ways the people have like information sticks with them
Speaker 6:  through different forms. And you know, our job is to kind of do that. I mean
Speaker 6:  that's it, you know, it turns out as writing about this a little bit this
Speaker 6:  week that, you know, translation and summarization is
Speaker 6:  something that the models have always done quite well. Like from the beginning,
Speaker 6:  like kind of like the first deep learning
Speaker 6:  breakthrough that really made a difference to consumers was really like translate
Speaker 6:  Google Translate and others that, you know Yeah, that's true. That it was
Speaker 6:  basically like, take this set of tokens that are in this language and turn
Speaker 6:  it into the set of tokens in this language and you know, they're really good
Speaker 6:  at, at summarizing in, in all of its different forms. And so we're,
Speaker 6:  you know, we've kind of like embraced that 'cause you know, embrace the things
Speaker 6:  that the models do well it's generally a, a good strategy. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Alright, we have to take one more break and then we will be back with the
Speaker 1:  rest of my conversation with Steven Johnson. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  We're back. Okay. We have waited long enough to talk about audio
Speaker 1:  overviews, those wild AI generated podcasts notebook has been working
Speaker 6:  Now you can. So we've added it to the suite of, of tools
Speaker 1:  That feels like it causes a thousand new interesting
Speaker 1:  things. Like on the one hand it's, it's not
Speaker 1:  the thing that you were describing earlier in this conversation, which is
Speaker 1:  something that is not full of personality. It doesn't say I a lot. It's
Speaker 1:  not, this is not a tool anymore. This is two
Speaker 1:  slightly weird people hanging out in my ears for 10 minutes. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And they are like it, whatever dial you have that says like make
Speaker 1:  them say puns and try and be kind of cringingly, it's like
Speaker 1:  that dial is at 14 out of 10 on most of the ones that I've listened to
Speaker 1:  and I kind of get why. Right? Yeah. Like If, you If you take the, it should
Speaker 1:  have no personality. It should just be very straightforward approach. That
Speaker 1:  makes sense on showing me a bunch of texts and apply it to a podcast
Speaker 1:  that's a bad podcast, but it does feel kind of incongruous
Speaker 1:  with a lot of the stuff you've been saying is like core to what you've been
Speaker 1:  trying to do. Well,
Speaker 6:  I mean, it's such a great question. So let's, let's just play, I want you
Speaker 6:  to play this please in case people haven't heard it.
Speaker 3:  Okay. So get this picture A world where the hottest
Speaker 3:  tech isn't microchips or the internet, but dynamite. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  dynamite. And it's not just blowing stuff up. Think skyscrapers,
Speaker 3:  railroads, massive engineering projects, but also
Speaker 3:  you guessed at assassination attempts, terrorist plots, all that volatile
Speaker 3:  stuff. It's a wild period, right? Wild is an understatement. And that's where
Speaker 3:  our deep dive today comes in. We're cracking open Stephen Johnson's the Infernal
Speaker 3:  Machine, a book that digs into this explosive era where dynamite
Speaker 3:  anarchists and the birth of, believe it or not, modern data
Speaker 3:  collection all collided. Yeah. Get
Speaker 2:  Ready to have your mind blown because the connections he makes are mind
Speaker 3:  Blowing. Absolutely.
Speaker 6:  So it's
Speaker 1:  Just everything after Yeah. Dynamite just kills me. I love it.
Speaker 6:  You know, one of the things is it, it's, they are enthusiastic
Speaker 6:  and so people have been uploading their cvs
Speaker 6:  and it's just like if they were feeling down about yourself, like they're
Speaker 6:  like, oh, John Smith, look at his, just
Speaker 3:  Make you a
Speaker 1:  Promo podcast.
Speaker 6:  It's made cum laude from
Speaker 6:  So I. Think when we first talked about
Speaker 6:  what was then Project Tailwind for The Verge, like,
Speaker 6:  you know, Verizon and I were talking about how, you know, we, we don't,
Speaker 6:  the model doesn't have a a a a persona really. Like it doesn't
Speaker 6:  use the subjective, I in general, it's not
Speaker 6:  trying to be your friend, it's just trying to get you the information you
Speaker 6:  need. And that was, that was kind of the house style that we felt was appropriate
Speaker 6:  for what we were trying to build. But If, you wanna have a,
Speaker 6:  a conversational audio format. There is no way to do that without
Speaker 6:  there having a sense of like human personas. It just won't work. No one,
Speaker 6:  no one wants to listen to two series talk to each other. Right. That is not,
Speaker 6:  I'm sure there's
Speaker 1:  A lot of that on the internet and it's not good. The
Speaker 6:  News theory is, is better, but, but I'm sure. But, but, but the old theory,
Speaker 6:  right? You know, you, when you listen to two robots talking to each other,
Speaker 6:  and initially it was a, another team
Speaker 6:  inside of labs that had built this prototype that was like, you know,
Speaker 6:  create a document. There, there, there are actually a couple of projects
Speaker 6:  like this at Google. There's another wonderful one called Illuminate that
Speaker 6:  has a slightly more like, kind of scholarly tone to it, but it was just one
Speaker 6:  of these things where like, it became possible to do this. And so, you know,
Speaker 6:  some folks were exploring this and it was a very good demo,
Speaker 6:  like we've seen from the last few days with audio
Speaker 6:  overviews. Like people are impressed, people wanna share it, but
Speaker 6:  it, it didn't kind of have a place to live. And so
Speaker 6:  kinda right before IO actually there was this idea of like, well
Speaker 6:  maybe we could actually put it into, you know, would it make sense inside
Speaker 6:  of Notebook? And you know, we were just rolling out the notebook
Speaker 6:  guides and when I first heard it, the, the,
Speaker 6:  the podcast stuff was like actually even bigger. Like the host had names
Speaker 6:  and things like that and Okay. And so, you know,
Speaker 6:  but I like it definitely made, you know, I think Verizon and I
Speaker 6:  immediately saw that it was a continuation of the philosophy of the guides
Speaker 6:  that, you know, we, we, we'll take whatever you give us and we will turn
Speaker 6:  it into the format that makes it easiest for you to understand. and
Speaker 6:  we know, we know from, you know, the success of podcasts in general that
Speaker 6:  people do like to learn that way. Also, also like to travel with audio and
Speaker 6:  drive and, you know, walk around the city listening to it. So we knew, we
Speaker 6:  knew there were a lot of reasons why audio conversations would make sense.
Speaker 1:  Are you starting to have similar conversations about things like video?
Speaker 1:  I, I can just imagine like, yeah, I'm starting to think about what notebook
Speaker 1:  LM looks like when you're trying to be like TikTok native and YouTube native
Speaker 1:  and Instagram reels native is like, it's just what a wild
Speaker 1:  kind of road to end up heading down in terms of like how do we communicate
Speaker 1:  to people where they are Yeah. But sort of in this house style,
Speaker 6:  This is one of the reasons why it's good that I am like 56-year-old gray
Speaker 6:  haired Steven is not actually like,
Speaker 6:  driving things like, because I wouldn't be terrible at helping with that,
Speaker 6:  but like, yes, I think that could be part of our future. Pretty fun. One
Speaker 6:  of the things I think is really interesting about it in the response, it
Speaker 6:  takes like four or five minutes to sometimes three to five minutes to generate
Speaker 6:  one of these. And that's because there is a really
Speaker 6:  complex series of, of kind of, you know,
Speaker 6:  compute and inference that's going on. Basically you can think about it
Speaker 6:  kind of in an editorial way, right? It's kind of drafting a version of it
Speaker 6:  and then it's filling in the details of the script and then it's
Speaker 6:  revising the script based on the overall goals. Like there's a, there are
Speaker 6:  multiple cycles of an basically an edit cycle and that takes
Speaker 6:  time. And then crucially, there's a stage where,
Speaker 6:  my favorite new word is where disfluencies are added, right? So
Speaker 6:  that it, it, it deliberately makes it kind of noisier and more like the,
Speaker 6:  the way that people talk when they're in conversation where they overlap
Speaker 6:  and they have partial phrases, they complete each other's thoughts and stuff
Speaker 6:  like that. All the things that make a traditional transcript hard to read
Speaker 6:  if it's not been cleaned up If, you don't have those things in,
Speaker 6:  it's on the wrong side of the uncanny valley or it's right in the middle
Speaker 6:  of the uncanny valley. I guess you can debate and obviously like
Speaker 6:  we're gonna, you can imagine we would introduce abilities to steer
Speaker 6:  in different directions and dial up, dial up down things or focus on different
Speaker 6:  topics, but the basic structure of kind
Speaker 6:  of, you know, doing this long edit cycle and then humanizing.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. The thing I called wrong on this one
Speaker 1:  was that I thought audio overviews would be one of those things
Speaker 1:  that people were like, oh well this is silly, right? It's like every time
Speaker 1:  a new image generator comes out, a bunch of people make wild stuff with it
Speaker 1:  for 48 hours and then kind of move on and we don't talk about it anymore
Speaker 1:  until some new image generat comes out
Speaker 1:  this one doesn't seem to have gone like that. And I think it it somewhere
Speaker 1:  in between the, like, is it remarkable that it's possible
Speaker 1:  versus is this actually useful? I think it is more in the, this is
Speaker 1:  actually useful camp for people already than I expected it to be. Like, it's
Speaker 1:  definitely remarkable that it's possible and you showed a, a sort of sincerely
Speaker 1:  new thing you can do with ai and whenever that happens, people get
Speaker 1:  really excited on Twitter. Right? Like that, that's just one way to get people
Speaker 1:  really riled up on Twitter for 12 hours. But I think there was, you, you
Speaker 1:  overlapped the, this actually does something for people side of things
Speaker 1:  more than I expected when I first heard. You can make an AI podcast out
Speaker 1:  of your
Speaker 6:  Notes. Well, I want to thank you one for changing your mind,
Speaker 6:  but two, you remember how jobs used to have the kind of apples, the intersection
Speaker 6:  of liberal arts and technology, whatever, like what you just described,
Speaker 6:  the intersection of what is newly possible and what is genuinely useful.
Speaker 6:  Like that's what we're trying to do at Notebook
Speaker 6:  and that's kind of what Labs is trying to do, right? Like it's just like,
Speaker 6:  what can we do and what would actually be like, you know, what was unthinkable
Speaker 6:  six months ago and then what would would it be? And you know, part of it
Speaker 6:  is, you know, I think in some cases people are using it like, I, I wanna
Speaker 6:  study and this is a better way for me to, you know, take my documents and,
Speaker 6:  and you know, just learn or learn on the go. The other thing is like creating
Speaker 6:  things that are effectively podcasts where n the
Speaker 6:  no podcast would possibly ever exist in the real world, right? Sure. You
Speaker 6:  know, so people are like, here's this very obscure niche topic that no one,
Speaker 6:  like the economics of the podcast business will never support a podcast.
Speaker 1:  I want the podcast on my d and d game that I play with my friends.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah, yeah. No, totally. And, and or it's like, you know,
Speaker 6:  we've seen people doing, like, again, thinking about a notebook element in
Speaker 6:  a, in a kind of a team context at work. Like okay, like the week in
Speaker 6:  review, like give it all your documents. I always say to people with one
Speaker 6:  of the best ways to get to know Notebook is to, if you're a Google
Speaker 6:  Docs and slides drive user, just grab, create a new notebook
Speaker 6:  and grab the last like, 20 docs that you've created and just create a notebook
Speaker 6:  with that. Oh, that's fine. And then just ask it questions. And it's, it's
Speaker 6:  ability to kind of grasp like what you're working on and the issues and things
Speaker 6:  like that. Do that and then create an audio overview. And it's like, this
Speaker 6:  is, this is what Steven was working on for the past week. You know, here's
Speaker 6:  two happy and enthusiastic people to discuss like the things you've been
Speaker 6:  working on and sharing that with your team. Like
Speaker 6:  it's pretty nice. Like that's a great way to like look back on the week and
Speaker 6:  think about what, what you've been working on and, and you know,
Speaker 6:  you can imagine other ways to explore that as well.
Speaker 1:  All right, a couple more questions. I know I've kept you a long time, but
Speaker 1:  I'll I'll I'll leave you on here in a minute. I can talk to you about this
Speaker 1:  forever. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  You're even better than talking to Bard.
Speaker 1:  This is great. Anytime I'm here for you. I don't like skiing either. So
Speaker 1:  do you think there's a like big mainstream
Speaker 1:  use case for something like Notebook lm Obviously there are
Speaker 1:  people and industries and jobs and schools, like I can imagine a
Speaker 1:  bunch of people for whom this is useful. Do you think there is like an everyday
Speaker 1:  everybody use case for something like this?
Speaker 6:  Everybody every day? I don't know, but I mean
Speaker 1:  To me, like, let me put this in slightly different context, right? Google
Speaker 1:  is a company that is famous for making things that a billion people,
Speaker 6:  A billion people use. Yes.
Speaker 1:  Is there, is there a billion? Are there a billion notebook LM users out there?
Speaker 6:  I think If, you define it as there is an AI
Speaker 6:  that is an expert in the
Speaker 6:  information that is really relevant to you that you've, you've curated
Speaker 6:  and that you can engage with in different forms, whether it's chat or
Speaker 6:  listening to an audio overview. And you can,
Speaker 6:  you can basically cultivate your own personal AI with a lot
Speaker 6:  of information. Maybe it's all your journals, maybe it's,
Speaker 6:  you know, your company's history, whatever it is. And just by like
Speaker 6:  dragging and dropping files in there, like it develops this kind of knowledge
Speaker 6:  of everything that has happened to you or your organization and is able to
Speaker 6:  kind of deliver advice or help you make decisions or just
Speaker 6:  recall a fact that you're trying to remember and create these new documents.
Speaker 6:  Is that a big, like, will maybe a billion people
Speaker 6:  like be doing some variation of that in five years?
Speaker 6:  I, I think that's pretty plausible. 'cause there's so many different things
Speaker 6:  you could do in that kind of context. You know, it could be like a writer
Speaker 6:  working on a book, but it could be an executive trying to make a complicated
Speaker 6:  decision or it could just be somebody trying to remember things that have
Speaker 6:  happened in their lives and it's like just keeping a journal. Only you've
Speaker 6:  got an AI that's helping you do it. Yeah. So I. I, I think there's
Speaker 6:  a big market for it.
Speaker 1:  Okay. You know what I've been thinking about as you, as you were saying that
Speaker 1:  there's this app called My Mind. Have you ever, have you ever seen it? I've
Speaker 6:  Seen it a little bit.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's a great app. You should, you should play with it. I think you
Speaker 1:  of all people would, would enjoy some of the AI stuff they're doing. But
Speaker 1:  I've started using that app and I've gotten in the habit of basically every
Speaker 1:  time I encounter something I like I just put it there. Yeah. Like if I,
Speaker 1:  a podcast or a video or a thing I read or a photo I take or a quote that
Speaker 1:  I see, I just, I'm just pouring it all in there with no organization, no
Speaker 1:  nothing. Yeah. And there's nothing particularly special about that app. It's
Speaker 1:  just like, it's pretty to look at So, I like using it
Speaker 1:  and already just the thing where you, you open it up and it's,
Speaker 1:  it, it's, it has a bunch of modes where you can just type in like movies
Speaker 1:  and it'll show you all the movies and movie adjacent stuff that you've been
Speaker 1:  saving. And it's like, there's something really powerful about, like, here
Speaker 1:  is just a compendium of stuff that I find interesting. Yeah. And
Speaker 1:  there's just enough manual work in that that I think
Speaker 1:  it's, it's, there's something to solve in the, like how do you
Speaker 1:  collect that data from people in a way that is both sort of easy and frictionless,
Speaker 1:  but also not like gross and privacy invading
Speaker 1:  that is like the eternal Google question. Yeah. I have high hopes that somebody
Speaker 1:  will figure it out eventually.
Speaker 6:  That is a bias that I've always had probably to a fault that, you know,
Speaker 6:  like we don't, we really don't have face, we don't even have kind of folders
Speaker 6:  for your sources or your notes or things like that. Like basic kind of low
Speaker 6:  level things that we will no doubt add, but we've been focused on these kind
Speaker 6:  of cooler features. But part of me is like the beauty, like this,
Speaker 6:  the complex systems of organization where you're tagging things and putting
Speaker 6:  them into the right folder and stuff like that are not as necessary now
Speaker 6:  because the AI does that and makes the connections for you and finds the
Speaker 6:  thing that you're looking for. So just have one place, make it easy to grab
Speaker 6:  as much stuff from as many different places and just dump it into a
Speaker 6:  notebook and then we'll do the magic. And figuring out the
Speaker 6:  connections or the finding the information you want after that, again is,
Speaker 6:  you said it correctly before, like the closest thing to this before was
Speaker 6:  Wikipedia. Like I start here in this Wikipedia page about
Speaker 6:  elephants and then I follow it following these interesting paths. But a
Speaker 6:  dialogue is just an even better way to do that and if, if it's
Speaker 6:  trustworthy. And so the mode that
Speaker 6:  I really love is, and, and again, this is only possible with conversation
Speaker 6:  history and long context, is to go on one of those like
Speaker 6:  exploratory conversations through an idea. And then at the end
Speaker 6:  you're like, okay, this has been great. Will you format that all
Speaker 6:  as a as single document that just says kind of key take takeaways and insights
Speaker 6:  from it. So I can just capture it for later. 'cause I don't necessarily wanna
Speaker 6:  read the whole conversation again, but I want to, I want to get the like
Speaker 6:  great pieces from it and boom, it does it And you say that and that's your
Speaker 6:  kind of record of, of what you just did. Like that, I mean,
Speaker 6:  like, that's a beautiful way to, to walk through information space
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And full of surprise and, and unexpected turns
Speaker 6:  and discovery so that, that feels like a keeper.
Speaker 1:  What's the next step in getting better at that? Like, one, one thing that
Speaker 1:  it seems to me that we need pretty badly in that
Speaker 1:  way of thinking, which I love, like, I love the idea of just like, I'm gonna
Speaker 1:  sit here and spend three hours learning about something and then at the end
Speaker 1:  you're gonna deliver me like a handy summary of everything that I've learned.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Amazing. Yeah, that's the dream. It does strike me that one thing we
Speaker 1:  desperately need all of these tools to get better at, to pull that off is
Speaker 1:  multimedia, right? Like, I want to know at the end of it, like, go listen
Speaker 1:  to these, these three podcasts and this YouTuber you're gonna, you're gonna
Speaker 1:  love and go check it out. And this person on Instagram is doing all, there's
Speaker 1:  like, there's, the internet is such a messy place in the best
Speaker 1:  way now that it feels like that's one thing. And I know a lot of folks are
Speaker 1:  working on that. Are there other things that you look at and you know, you're,
Speaker 1:  you're working on this stuff too. Is there a next kind of turn coming that's
Speaker 1:  gonna make all that stuff even better
Speaker 6:  Right now? Notebook's ability to help you
Speaker 6:  discover information to put in your notebook is
Speaker 6:  exactly zero. Like no, it does nothing in that.
Speaker 6:  You are on your own. You need to supply the sources, right? We will not help
Speaker 6:  you discover anything across the internet, any in any form.
Speaker 6:  It turns out just as a coincidence that
Speaker 6:  Google is really good at that stuff. Like I did not know,
Speaker 6:  I learned when I got there, they have this search thing that is apparently
Speaker 6:  a lot of people use. So it's obviously like a place where,
Speaker 6:  you know, I would love it. I I want it to be source grounded, but I would
Speaker 6:  love you to stay in Notebook to be able to find things and you know,
Speaker 6:  we, we would, we would be really interested in, in exploring that. I think
Speaker 6:  you, you'll see that in 2025 for sure.
Speaker 1:  All right, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thanks again to Steven for
Speaker 1:  being on the show and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more
Speaker 1:  on everything we talked about at The Verge dot com. I'll put some links in
Speaker 1:  the show notes to some of the stuff Steven has written about this too. His
Speaker 1:  new book is really great. Go to The Verge dot com, lots of show notes, lots
Speaker 1:  of notebook coverage, all kinds of good stuff. As always. If you have thoughts,
Speaker 1:  questions, feelings, or other ideas for AI generated podcasts,
Speaker 1:  you can always email us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or call the hotline
Speaker 1:  eight six six VERGE one one. we love hearing from you wanna hear all your
Speaker 1:  thoughts, send 'em all. Can't wait to hear it. This show is produced by Liam
Speaker 1:  James Wil Pour and Eric Gomez. Vergecast is VERGE production and part of
Speaker 1:  the Vox Media podcast network. We'll be back with our regularly scheduled
Speaker 1:  programming on Tuesday and Friday this week. We have a lot of headsets in
Speaker 1:  particular to talk about this week, so get ready. We'll see you then. Rock
Speaker 1:  and roll.