# Transcript
ID: ea0a0cb9-cd25-46fc-9ed0-9f057a038aac
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-6502887084526400668/3424120342131868000/s93290-US-4374s-1714462819.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of dedicated AI hardware:
The Verge’s David Pierce and Allison Johnson debate whether the emergence of standalone AI gadgets like the Humane Pin and the Rabbit R1 are better off as apps or should exist as its own hardware.
Humane AI Pin review: not even close
The Humane AI Pin worked better than I expected — until it didn’t
A morning with the Rabbit R1: a fun, funky, unfinished AI gadget
Can Rabbit’s R1 outsmart the smartphone assistants? Let’s find out!
The future of AI gadgets is just phones
The Ray-Ban Meta smart glasses actually make the future look cool
The Verge’s Alex Heath joins the show to discuss Meta’s big move into AI with its multimodal AI smart glasses and a new AI model called Llama 3.
Q&amp;A: Mark Zuckerberg on winning the AI race
Meta wants to be the Microsoft of headsets
Zuckerberg says it will take Meta years to make money from generative AI
Nilay Patel answers a question from The Vergecast Hotline about Microsoft and antitrust.
Microsoft splits Teams from Office as antitrust pressure ramps up
Microsoft and OpenAI deal may face anti-trust investigations in the EU.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (11 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of dedicated
Speaker 2:  AI hardware. I'm your friend David Pierce and I have a label
Speaker 2:  maker. One of the things I've learned about myself is that I
Speaker 2:  procrastinate by organizing, which mostly means I just like take a thing
Speaker 2:  that's over here and put it sort of arbitrarily over here.
Speaker 2:  Although it improves nothing but it like scratches my brain in a very
Speaker 2:  helpful way that makes me feel like I'm accomplishing things even when I'm
Speaker 2:  mostly not. But now that I have a label maker, I'm actually gonna get
Speaker 2:  stuff done. There's the spice rack over there. I'm gonna label all the
Speaker 2:  spices. So I stop using paprika instead of cinnamon accidentally.
Speaker 2:  I have a bunch of tea up here. I'm gonna label all of that. So I stop drinking
Speaker 2:  caffeinated tea at night and staying up all night. I'm gonna label the
Speaker 2:  baby bottles over here so I know what he's supposed to be drinking out of
Speaker 2:  and what we're not supposed to be drinking out of anymore. I'm gonna label
Speaker 2:  the milk with the word milk, which we'll accomplish nothing but will make
Speaker 2:  me laugh every time I pull the milk outta the fridge. I'm just gonna label
Speaker 2:  everything and then my wife is gonna come home from work and have a lot of
Speaker 2:  feelings about what happens. So we'll see. Anyway, we are not here to
Speaker 2:  talk about label makers. We are here to talk tech and we have a lot to do
Speaker 2:  on the show. Today we're gonna talk to Allison Johnson about AI
Speaker 2:  gadgets. She's been testing some, I've been testing some and she has a
Speaker 2:  theory that maybe none of them need to exist and that maybe a phone is the
Speaker 2:  answer. I have some thoughts. We're gonna talk about that. And then we're
Speaker 2:  gonna talk about meta and AI because meta has been on a huge
Speaker 2:  run of new AI products and there's a big story in there somewhere. So
Speaker 2:  Alex Heath is gonna come on and help us figure it out. Then we're gonna do
Speaker 2:  the hotline. Lots of talk about this week. All that is coming up in just
Speaker 2:  a second. But first, I'm not kidding, I have a fresh roll of label tape.
Speaker 2:  The battery is charged. I have work to do. This is The Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  We'll be right
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. All right. I believe I have labeled everything in my
Speaker 2:  house that there is to be labeled and then some. We'll see how my wife
Speaker 2:  responds when she gets home. Let's get into it. For the last few weeks I've
Speaker 2:  been immersing myself in AI gadgets, the humane AI pin, the
Speaker 2:  rabbit R one, the Meta Smart Glasses, this voice recorder I have
Speaker 2:  called plot, a bunch of apps, everything I can get my hands
Speaker 2:  on that is like a way to use ai. And the number one
Speaker 2:  question in front of all of these devices in particular, I think is the same
Speaker 2:  thing. Why isn't this just an app on your phone? Actually, that might be
Speaker 2:  the number two question. Number one is just, is this thing any good? And
Speaker 2:  a lot of them aren't, but let's focus on the phone thing for right now. The
Speaker 2:  VIRs, Allison Johnson wrote a piece last week arguing essentially that a
Speaker 2:  smartphone is the perfect AI gadget, that we don't need dedicated
Speaker 2:  devices, we have the dedicated devices. And she ran an experiment
Speaker 2:  to prove it. So of course I had to ask her to come on and tell us how it
Speaker 2:  went. Allison, welcome back.
Speaker 4:  Thank you.
Speaker 2:  We usually talk about phones when you come on the show and this time we're
Speaker 2:  gonna talk about phones, but maybe in the weirdest way that we've ever talked
Speaker 2:  about phones, which I'm very excited about.
Speaker 4:  I'm here for it.
Speaker 2:  So let's just start at the beginning here. Tell me about this wearable
Speaker 2:  phone experiment that you devised for yourself.
Speaker 4:  Oh my gosh, I have never been so glad that I just work in my own house
Speaker 4:  alone. I was just sort of ranting about how, you know,
Speaker 4:  the humane pin reviews came out and I was like, this thing is just an
Speaker 4:  Android phone, like a mid-range Android phone. And I was like, I have
Speaker 4:  so many mid-range Android phones. So I just kind of set out to like
Speaker 4:  recreate the capabilities with what I had. And
Speaker 4:  it was surprisingly hard. I tried a flip phone, I had the Motorola Razor
Speaker 4:  Plus, and I had it like kind of clamped over the collar of my shirt,
Speaker 4:  you know, like you do. And I got like so far with that,
Speaker 4:  like I could kind of talk to Google assistant.
Speaker 2:  So wait, so you, you dangle it over with like what The front screen facing
Speaker 2:  out? Yeah. And you just, and then you just sort of like, Hey g it
Speaker 2:  from Yeah, there.
Speaker 4:  And I figure, 'cause then you have cameras facing forward. You could do Google
Speaker 4:  lens. That was the, the thought. It's not very easy to
Speaker 4:  do any of that kind of out of the box. Like the flip phones
Speaker 4:  won't let you download the Gemini assistant, which is strange. So you kind
Speaker 4:  of have to, that's weird. Like side load it, if you try and and
Speaker 4:  trigger the Google assistant with the phone closed and
Speaker 4:  the cover, just using the cover screen, it tells you to open up the phone.
Speaker 4:  So it kind of like, I was already not off to a great start.
Speaker 2:  So did you ever find an actual solution
Speaker 2:  with the phone itself? We're gonna get to headphones in a minute. Yeah. Foreshadowing.
Speaker 2:  But did you ever find a version of like a wearable phone that actually kind
Speaker 2:  of worked?
Speaker 4:  I did not really. Okay. I had, I just ran chat GPT
Speaker 4:  in the kind of like talking mode where the conversation mode
Speaker 4:  and I had that on my shirt and just, but it's just always listening and like
Speaker 4:  waiting for you to say something so you can't just like go about your day
Speaker 4:  and Right. We had a very pleasant conversation about like the weather,
Speaker 4:  whatever. But yeah, nothing, nothing really worked the way I thought it would.
Speaker 2:  Well this is why I wanted to talk about this because I think you and I have
Speaker 2:  been talking about this for months now and the question everybody brings
Speaker 2:  up about every single AI gadget is like, why isn't this just an app
Speaker 2:  on my phone? And my thoughts on the subject and
Speaker 2:  why it shouldn't just be an app on your phone are actually becoming increasingly
Speaker 2:  strong and intense. And I feel like I'm more right than I was before. But
Speaker 2:  I am curious like at a, at a broad level, do you buy that
Speaker 2:  argument? Like are you also one of the people who is just like, this is all
Speaker 2:  ridiculous, this should just be an app on my phone. I think
Speaker 4:  I'm, I'm like 20% rooting for like a
Speaker 4:  gadget that does these things and 80% just, it just feels like
Speaker 4:  realism. Like phones have already solved
Speaker 4:  so many of these problems. Like these little gadgets get
Speaker 4:  hot, they have to connect to the internet, they
Speaker 4:  need cameras like check mark on all
Speaker 4:  of those for phones, right? Like they did it battery life, you know,
Speaker 4:  regular software updates. They got it. And I'm just like, I'm having
Speaker 4:  flashbacks of covering compact digital cameras for
Speaker 4:  years where it was like, you know, oh these are
Speaker 4:  so much better than your phone. And which is like not even true
Speaker 4:  anymore. But it was like, no, the phone is good enough for
Speaker 4:  most people and people do not wanna carry around two things.
Speaker 4:  That is, that is what we learned from that experiment is if you can carry
Speaker 4:  one thing instead of two things, you will carry one thing.
Speaker 2:  I do agree with that. And that that is a, I think maybe the most
Speaker 2:  convincing argument against the AI gadget is just,
Speaker 2:  it's, it's the good enough hypothesis, right? That it's like I don't need
Speaker 2:  it to be as good. I just don't wanna carry and charge and worry about two
Speaker 2:  things. But I think my most strident opinion on this subject
Speaker 2:  is that I think we all have forgotten how annoying it is to
Speaker 2:  use your phone. Hmm. Like we've just been doing it for so long that
Speaker 2:  I think it's why I believe in flip phones for the same reason. It's like
Speaker 2:  our phones are these big chunky things that you balance on top of
Speaker 2:  your pinky to the point where most of us have like divots in our fingers
Speaker 2:  now from trying to hold these things. You have to sort of like worm your
Speaker 2:  thumb around this gigantic screen in order to touch anything. Like
Speaker 2:  from a pure, in a vacuum user experience, it's not good.
Speaker 2:  And if your hands are full, you can't do anything. And I spend like an
Speaker 2:  alarming amount of my time with like dog and stroller
Speaker 2:  in one arm and phone in the other. Like it's just bad. And I
Speaker 2:  this idea that, okay, every time I wanna do anything, the right user experience
Speaker 2:  is for me to dig into my purse, pull out my phone, unlock
Speaker 2:  it, swipe, swipe pipe, open an app, tap on the app, log in,
Speaker 2:  do a thing. Like that's bad. And the idea that you can
Speaker 2:  shortcut all of this by just yelling a thing is good. I believe in that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And this is why I like your experiment so much because it's like, okay,
Speaker 2:  can I make my phone that thing? which I think is where we get to
Speaker 2:  earbuds. Yeah. The longer we do this, the more I'm coming to the answer of
Speaker 2:  like, maybe headphones are the problem solver in all of this.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And this is something that our colleague V song has
Speaker 4:  written about is like with wearable tech, it's so
Speaker 4:  important that it's just like something you want to put
Speaker 4:  on your body and is comfortable and is kind of like socially accepted.
Speaker 4:  And I just come back to earbuds like we're just, people just
Speaker 4:  walk around with them. I feel like such an old person being like these kids,
Speaker 4:  they just walk around with their earbuds all the time. But like you have
Speaker 4:  a good transparency mode, you know? And those things could get
Speaker 4:  smarter about the sounds they let in and the sounds they keep
Speaker 4:  about. And then you have this connection to your phone that you can just
Speaker 4:  like summon it when you want it and keep it in your pocket and
Speaker 4:  not have to do the whole dance of like tapping on things. 'cause I think
Speaker 4:  we've come, we're sort of blind to that. Like we are just so
Speaker 4:  conditioned to like, this is how you get things done on a phone. You take
Speaker 4:  it out, you do all this, you get distracted. And yeah. Once you start kind
Speaker 4:  of like conceptualizing not having to do that,
Speaker 4:  it's like, oh yeah, I, I buy into that vision and I, but I
Speaker 4:  think we're just gonna be able to do it without touching our
Speaker 4:  phone. Right. But it's still gonna be phone.
Speaker 2:  Yes. And well, and that turned out to be sort of the second half of your
Speaker 2:  experience with, with this phone AI gadget thing,
Speaker 2:  right? You you basically went like full pixel.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I did. Like I downloaded the Gemini assistant and
Speaker 4:  switched into it and there's still like weird workarounds you have to do
Speaker 4:  because you can have Gemini assistant running on the phone. The
Speaker 4:  earbuds are not going to trigger Gemini 'cause
Speaker 4:  they're, they don't talk yet.
Speaker 2:  This is the most Google thing you've ever said. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Seriously. Well like the pixel watch you, you can't have Gemini on
Speaker 4:  it yet. So you're like talking to one assistant here, you're talking to a
Speaker 4:  different assistant on the phone. The Google home in my kitchen is constantly
Speaker 4:  being like, what? So I had to like unplug that
Speaker 4:  and I kept Gemini like open and running on the phone, which is not an
Speaker 4:  ideal user experience, but had the earbuds in and my like
Speaker 4:  light bulb moment was, I took a picture of this recipe
Speaker 4:  I was making and I was like, look at this and remember it. And
Speaker 4:  I just walked around my kitchen doing things and I would ask it questions
Speaker 4:  like how long do I put the fish in? How do I chop the vegetables? Just kind
Speaker 4:  of out of order. And like as I was doing things and it,
Speaker 4:  it got it right all the time and it was like, oh this is super helpful.
Speaker 4:  I would be running back to this recipe with like stuff
Speaker 4:  on my fingers trying to figure it out. And it's like man, those
Speaker 4:  earbuds,
Speaker 2:  That is maybe the single coolest use of AI I've ever heard by
Speaker 2:  the way, to take a picture of a recipe and then just pepper
Speaker 2:  the assistant with questions Yeah. About that recipe as you go. That's very
Speaker 2:  cool.
Speaker 4:  I was super into it and it's that kind of thing of like I run outta things
Speaker 4:  to talk about with chat JBT I'm like, there's only so many like business
Speaker 4:  proposals you can brainstorm. But I'm like, if you give it a little data
Speaker 4:  set of like I'm doing this thing help me out.
Speaker 4:  Like it makes so much more sense to me that way. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Are you a voice assistant person in your day to day?
Speaker 4:  Not at all. I set timers and I asked the weather and like trying
Speaker 4:  to get myself, I'm starting to like realize I can use
Speaker 4:  it a little more. Especially if I am using a phone with
Speaker 4:  Gemini on it. Hmm. Like I asked but you just, man you gotta keep an
Speaker 4:  eye on it 'cause it'll make up a word. Or like I was asking
Speaker 4:  it if the bridge they were working on in my neighborhood had reopened
Speaker 4:  and, and it like got the days backwards. It was like, yes
Speaker 4:  it's open but it's opening tomorrow so
Speaker 2:  You
Speaker 4:  Just have to keep an eye on it. But it's, it's like converting me a little
Speaker 4:  bit to more of a voice assistant person I think. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think one of the big questions I have about this space right now
Speaker 2:  is did voice assistance work because they were a bad idea?
Speaker 2:  Or rather did voice assistance not work because they were a bad idea? Or
Speaker 2:  did they not work because they weren't very good? And I think they definitely
Speaker 2:  aren't very good. Right. And I think that the Siri experience
Speaker 2:  sort of proves that yes, for a lot of people and I think a lot of people's
Speaker 2:  first experience with these things was Siri. And you ask it to do something
Speaker 2:  and it just fails or it's like, here's what I found on the web. And you're
Speaker 2:  like, well this is useless and then you never really try again. And so the
Speaker 2:  first attempt, we all had to build that habit, it failed
Speaker 2:  spectacularly and there are a lot of like kids
Speaker 2:  who grew up asking Alexa silly questions and getting silly responses and
Speaker 2:  that was the thing that worked. So I think the attach rate there has actually
Speaker 2:  been better as a result. But then I come around to, okay,
Speaker 2:  we all bet on this a decade ago. Like the tech industry was like,
Speaker 2:  this is the thing, conversational interfaces, they're gonna change everything.
Speaker 2:  And they super didn't. And now to some extent we're back in that exact
Speaker 2:  same thing and the promise is no, it was the right
Speaker 2:  idea with the wrong underlying technology. And at least
Speaker 2:  my experience so far has been, I still see the theory of it,
Speaker 2:  but even as I use all these things, I'm not, I'm using it more.
Speaker 2:  I, I agree with you. I've definitely found more reasons to do this stuff.
Speaker 2:  Particularly with like I really like to use an AI voice notes
Speaker 2:  app to like say my to-do list out loud. And they're actually getting pretty
Speaker 2:  good at turning that into just a structured list of stuff I have to do today.
Speaker 2:  I feel like a doctor who's like saying all of my charts into my voice
Speaker 2:  recorder and then like something magical happens, it's great, but I still
Speaker 2:  don't feel like I have hit the thing where it just sort of, that becomes
Speaker 2:  the main way I use my phone and what people say when I say that to
Speaker 2:  them is, oh it's just an interface question. It's because once you have your
Speaker 2:  phone out, why not just use your phone the way that you're used to? Which
Speaker 2:  is why they're all excited about these new gadgets. And so I just, I don't
Speaker 2:  know, I spin in circles about like what is the actual sort of roadblock
Speaker 2:  here to this actually becoming real? 'cause it seems like there are a lot
Speaker 2:  of them.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. There's just sort of like a pain versus reward,
Speaker 4:  you know, ratio of like, it, I feel like it's starting to even
Speaker 4:  out a little bit with the voice assistants, but you still get burned
Speaker 4:  where you're like, yeah there's nothing worse than like being at the grocery
Speaker 4:  store and being like, I'm gonna use the voice assistant. And then it's, it
Speaker 4:  just fails and you have to like either keep talking to it or like
Speaker 4:  take your phone out. I think once you had that experience you're like, oh
Speaker 4:  just use my phone for this. Yeah. But yeah, I think, I think it's something
Speaker 4:  we can adjust to and it, it really has to like that
Speaker 4:  threshold of public embarrassment or just like
Speaker 4:  frustration has to change and there's like signals that
Speaker 4:  that will happen I think. But yeah, it's, it's not proven.
Speaker 4:  I wouldn't say.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. One of my developing theories is that
Speaker 2:  headphones are gonna be where a lot of this goes for that reason. It's
Speaker 2:  like, it's a thing you can wear one of in the grocery store and
Speaker 2:  no one will look twice at you. Like we have solved the public weirdness
Speaker 2:  problem of headphones. Sony did that for us 45 years ago. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  thank you Sony. But what I wonder now is like
Speaker 2:  should you have the AI system that is just purely baked into
Speaker 2:  your headphones? Like one of, one of the conspiracy theories that I have
Speaker 2:  no evidence for but believe to my soul is that the next AirPods
Speaker 2:  maxes are going to be local AI devices because they're big
Speaker 2:  and they're heavy and they have a big battery and they can do stuff. But
Speaker 2:  like if you try to run some of that stuff on AirPods or the Pixel
Speaker 2:  buds or it's just the battery's gonna die in one minute and there's just,
Speaker 2:  there's literally no place to put d AI stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  But maybe it's, maybe that's okay. Maybe Bluetooth headphones and your phone
Speaker 2:  in your pocket or purse is enough interface. And it does seem like in your
Speaker 2:  experiment that's kind of where you landed.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That, that kind of proved out in, that didn't solve
Speaker 4:  the camera thing, which is also like an intriguing related,
Speaker 4:  you know, like feature which the humane pin has the camera
Speaker 4:  and you we're both like, wanna look at something and ask a
Speaker 4:  question about it. Or if you want a hands-free way to take pictures, which
Speaker 4:  both are kind of intriguing to me. So I mean everybody keeps
Speaker 4:  bringing up the meta ray bands and man that kind of solves
Speaker 4:  a couple of those problems and doesn't look stupid.
Speaker 2:  True. Do you wear glasses normally?
Speaker 4:  I wear contacts. Okay. So I'm, I'm so close to buying
Speaker 4:  these things. I don't know really. Yeah. I, it'd be so good for
Speaker 4:  just like taking picture of a kid running around and I
Speaker 4:  don't know, but another gadget, do I want another gadget?
Speaker 2:  I dunno. I I hear you. I've been, I've been debating this with some of the
Speaker 2:  folks on our team for a while 'cause I think they're definitely a huge
Speaker 2:  leap better than like having a headset on your face to
Speaker 2:  have the, the metas smartt glasses and meta is leaning into the fact that
Speaker 2:  we've also solved, having glasses on your face is not weird. And I don't
Speaker 2:  know what your experience has been, but when I wear the meta glasses, no
Speaker 2:  one ever looks at me sideways. Yeah. Like I got more public
Speaker 2:  notice, more sort of weird double takes wearing the humane pin
Speaker 2:  than I ever have wearing the meta glasses by a mile. Yeah. So that's,
Speaker 2:  that's a huge victory. But I also don't wear glasses normally and I don't
Speaker 2:  wanna start wearing glasses. Like I wear sunglasses when I'm
Speaker 2:  outside and I have mostly replaced my sunglasses with the meta glasses, which
Speaker 2:  I like a lot. But in terms of a sort of always on assistant like I'm not
Speaker 2:  gonna get to work and keep wearing glasses I don't need
Speaker 2:  just to use my assistant.
Speaker 4:  It's a different vibe. Yeah. You have to be ready for that shift.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like I are, if we can normalize sunglasses indoors just in
Speaker 2:  order to make AI happen Yeah, I'm here for it. This, this works.
Speaker 4:  We'll work on that.
Speaker 2:  But yeah, I do think I have definitely come around to the idea in testing
Speaker 2:  the humane pin and now the rabbit and some of the other stuff that's out
Speaker 2:  there now that actually what we need to figure out is how to put AI into
Speaker 2:  other socially acceptable things that already exist before we try and
Speaker 2:  invent some who new thing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like the humane pin kind of tries to hide it, but
Speaker 4:  it's sort of like, look at this, this is kind of a cool gadget. I appreciate
Speaker 4:  that. The rabbit is just like, this is a thing. It is bright orange.
Speaker 4:  It like practically glows in the dark. I don't know if you had this
Speaker 4:  experience where I walk into a dark room and I'm like,
Speaker 4:  there's the rabbit art.
Speaker 2:  It really does it, it sort of screams at you from wherever it is. What do
Speaker 2:  you think about the rabbit, speaking of experiments you've been doing, you've
Speaker 2:  been, you've been testing rabbit's, AI stuff with some of the other stuff
Speaker 2:  that's out there. How's that gone? It
Speaker 4:  It, boy
Speaker 4:  that's a tough, that sounds right. It's a tough one. The, the battery
Speaker 4:  life is just god awful. Which you know, as it turns
Speaker 4:  out is important. 'cause I don't, if I just have it in my bag and I go
Speaker 4:  somewhere, I'm like, I'm gonna leave it off because the minute I turn it
Speaker 4:  on it's gonna be like draining the battery. So like
Speaker 4:  a, if there's no battery it doesn't help you do anything. It's just a cool
Speaker 4:  orange thing. I've seen a couple of moments when
Speaker 4:  I'm like, okay, this is maybe doing a little more than a Gemini. I
Speaker 4:  took a picture of my plant on my desk and it, it did the typical thing of
Speaker 4:  like, this is a POTOs plant, blah blah blah. And it, it kind of
Speaker 4:  like went into the care instructions and it was like, your plant looks
Speaker 4:  happy in its current pot. And I'm like, you know, great job. I don't, I don't
Speaker 4:  get that assessment from Gemini. It just sort of spits out a bunch of stuff
Speaker 4:  that you like, don't overwater it, don't underwater it. So I don't know there's,
Speaker 4:  there's like something that is a little more like
Speaker 4:  could tune itself to like what you're actually doing or looking at
Speaker 4:  that feels like not just googling something. Hmm. But I don't
Speaker 4:  wanna give this thing too much credit. It is not done that
Speaker 4:  very often and it, it kind of feels that basic stuff.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's bad. Like I think yeah, we're gonna have, we're gonna have more
Speaker 2:  to say about it both on the site and on this podcast, but the, the, the rabbit
Speaker 2:  R one is not good is is a pretty easy takeaway. But I'm curious, you've been
Speaker 2:  testing it against Chad GPT in particular pretty
Speaker 2:  strenuously, right? Are they, my assumption would be that most of these things
Speaker 2:  should come out relatively the same because it's all kind of pulling from
Speaker 2:  the same backend infrastructure. Have you noticed anything interesting poking
Speaker 2:  at all this stuff?
Speaker 4:  Well I think that something you mentioned I think is that it's running
Speaker 4:  perplexity so you get a little more like real
Speaker 4:  time info than a chat GPT that or the
Speaker 4:  free chat GPTI used that was trained whenever ago. Right.
Speaker 4:  So I can ask it like, is that bridge open that was closed over
Speaker 4:  the weekend and I get a real response. So
Speaker 4:  that's interesting. But it's, it's such a strange little
Speaker 2:  Strange
Speaker 4:  Little creature. It's like very adorable. I think there's an
Speaker 4:  adorable factor. It perks up its little ears when it's listening
Speaker 4:  to you. But TBD on that,
Speaker 2:  Does that do anything for you actually? 'cause I think I, I have, I've definitely
Speaker 2:  had the same experience that I like that it, the little rabbit on the screen
Speaker 2:  sort of bounces waiting for you to talk and then you ask it a question and
Speaker 2:  it perks up its ears and stops bouncing. And when you're playing music it,
Speaker 2:  it wears headphones and there's a lot of sort of charming little things about
Speaker 2:  it I think. And I can't decide if that's what I
Speaker 2:  want or is totally the opposite of what I want from a device like this because
Speaker 2:  you, you use Gemini or chat GPT or Siri or
Speaker 2:  whatever and it's all very matter of fact, right? Like they are, they are
Speaker 2:  tools to do a job and actually every time we've seen these things exhibit
Speaker 2:  personality, it's been in really bad ugly problematic ways mostly.
Speaker 2:  And so they've all learned to just sort of shut all that down and just be
Speaker 2:  there to execute whatever they're required to execute and then move on. And
Speaker 2:  part of me is sort of endeared to rabbit for trying something else and part
Speaker 2:  of me is also like, well maybe if it worked but was less cute, I would like
Speaker 2:  it better. Yeah. And maybe that's what actually matters here.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like there's a cute little animation of the rabbit
Speaker 4:  in a hamster wheel or something when you, when you need to charge it.
Speaker 4:  I'm like, this is adorable, but I am annoyed that I need to charge
Speaker 4:  this thing again. Like cute only gets you so far I think.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Do you think there's gonna be ways to put more of this
Speaker 2:  stuff onto phones in interesting ways? Like is is the next round of flip
Speaker 2:  phones and foldable phones and smartphone gonna have some of the stuff we're
Speaker 2:  seeing in these gadgets? Or are we just gonna keep getting phones because
Speaker 2:  like I I just keep thinking about the razor as you're talking about it and
Speaker 2:  it's like what if the external screen of the razor could run an assistant
Speaker 2:  and could have that outward facing camera. Like it kind of has all the hardware
Speaker 2:  it needs to do that. Are we gonna get that do
Speaker 4:  You think? I I would like it. I mean it would be an ideal
Speaker 4:  world where you could kind of choose from your AI assistant and you
Speaker 4:  don't just have to use the one that you're operating system baked in fair.
Speaker 4:  But yeah, then you get into like the tech company's gonna
Speaker 4:  let the app makers in, you know like get into
Speaker 4:  the system the way it would have to where you don't run into a wall like
Speaker 4:  chat GPT can't change settings on my phone or like
Speaker 4:  put something on my calendar. You know? So I feel like there is a pretty
Speaker 4:  like firm wall on that right now. And and that would be
Speaker 4:  interesting. I think that's kind of like rabbit's, you know,
Speaker 4:  ethos is like how do we get around that? And it, the answer is a weird
Speaker 4:  system where you log into stuff and Right on,
Speaker 4:  I don't know, a virtual computer.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The answer is largely you can't right now. Yeah. It turns out
Speaker 4:  That that seems to be not working also. So, but
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's, it's an interesting question and and my sense would be that's
Speaker 2:  only happening if regulators make it happen, right? It seems, it seems to
Speaker 2:  some extent like more powerful than setting your default browser,
Speaker 2:  which you can do even more powerful than setting your default search engine,
Speaker 2:  which has only become a thing because of regulatory pressure
Speaker 2:  and essentially you could kind of argue it's like allowing you to install
Speaker 2:  another operating system on top of your operating system. Like if you were
Speaker 2:  allowed to let chat GPT run your phone, that's a pretty big thing for any
Speaker 2:  of these companies to be able to do. I kind of agree that that's how it should
Speaker 2:  shake out. If this tech is gonna get better in the way that everybody says
Speaker 2:  it's gonna get better, it'll be cool to have options and not just be forced
Speaker 2:  to use better Siri or better Gemini or
Speaker 2:  better CHATT or whatever. I don't know that I would bet on that ever being
Speaker 2:  a possibility.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that does seem like a big question mark. And then you get
Speaker 4:  back to just like, well what if you could just talk to
Speaker 4:  your operating system while you're walking around the kitchen and
Speaker 4:  it's like not the ideal future that I want. I think I
Speaker 4:  want a future where there's weird gadgets or you can download
Speaker 4:  a, a, a virtual assistant that can actually do things for
Speaker 4:  you. Yeah. I think that's why I am, I am on like team phones
Speaker 4:  'cause it's the realist in me is like, oh, they're not gonna let
Speaker 4:  this stuff happen.
Speaker 2:  I think that's probably right. But I do also remember somebody, I forget
Speaker 2:  who it was, somebody at one of the phone makers years ago was like, we're
Speaker 2:  gonna get to a point where the phone in your pocket is basically just a cellular
Speaker 2:  modem and all the accessories around are
Speaker 2:  going to be connected to that in some way. Your wearable is gonna use that
Speaker 2:  to connect to the internet. Your headphones, you gonna use that to connect
Speaker 2:  to the internet. Your laptop is gonna use that to connect to the internet,
Speaker 2:  but it is, it's going to be less the device you use for everything and
Speaker 2:  more the device that just lets you use everything everywhere. Yeah. And I
Speaker 2:  think that's a really interesting version of the future and is kind of what
Speaker 2:  you discovered with this is like I can just use my phone as a
Speaker 2:  go-between to all these services that exist and with headphones that I already
Speaker 2:  own. I actually don't need to invent a completely new pipeline
Speaker 2:  for that stuff. I just need a new way to kind of get at that pipeline.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I've become just an addict for this smartwatch.
Speaker 4:  Like I over the past couple years, like I never used one before
Speaker 4:  and now I cannot live without one. It's just like, it's the
Speaker 4:  right kind of light interface for when I need to do stuff. Like I'm out on
Speaker 4:  a walk and I need to pause music or just check a
Speaker 4:  quick notification or a text and it's like you run into the
Speaker 4:  wall very quickly of like, you can't really respond to a text very well
Speaker 4:  or you can thumbs up emoji something. Right. But
Speaker 4:  boy has that been like, that is the point where I'm like, I am
Speaker 4:  so willing to charge this extra thing and it has its own special
Speaker 4:  charger that I have to bring along when I travel. And like
Speaker 4:  it crosses that threshold of like, yes, I will do all of that because
Speaker 4:  I find it so useful.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I I think smartwatch is probably land in the, the
Speaker 2:  earbuds category of that kind of light input system
Speaker 2:  that really works. Like when I wrote, when I wrote the humane pin review,
Speaker 2:  the overwhelming response was what you're describing is just a better Apple
Speaker 2:  watch. Yeah. And I think other than the camera stuff, which is left
Speaker 2:  to be solved, but right now is only kind of somewhat
Speaker 2:  useful anyway. That is true. Like my big
Speaker 2:  regret right now is that I didn't buy a cell connected Apple watch. Right.
Speaker 2:  I know. And I wish, I wish that I had because then I could do all that sort
Speaker 2:  of lightweight stuff you're talking about without needing my phone in my
Speaker 2:  pocket. Yeah, that'd
Speaker 4:  Be awesome. You just leave the house. Can you imagine?
Speaker 2:  I mean, first of all no, no, but also it sounds wonderful.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  The idea of your phone as a thing that lives in your pocket that it lets
Speaker 2:  everything else connect to the internet strikes me as much more the sort
Speaker 2:  of AI gadget future than like these all encompassing
Speaker 2:  new ideas about gadgets.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I know it's kind of depressing, but
Speaker 4:  it's also I think
Speaker 2:  True.
Speaker 4:  It's a little bit,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And it means like all these other companies, humane Rabbit, everybody
Speaker 2:  else is like desperately trying to get around your phone, just like you said
Speaker 2:  and it's like, oh, this maybe keeps the world the way that it is if
Speaker 2:  that's how we do it more than I would like. But it also just
Speaker 2:  might be inevitable.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And it's an interesting moment at least. Yeah. Boy is
Speaker 4:  it not dull right now.
Speaker 2:  I know and I'm I'm still thinking about the, the camera comparison and cameras
Speaker 2:  never came back. No. They just like mid-range. We found a lot of
Speaker 2:  interesting stuff to do at like the high end and I think about like the Fuji
Speaker 2:  series that people really love. Like I feel like if you want like a good
Speaker 2:  camera, your options have never been better. But if you want a pretty
Speaker 2:  good camera, they don't exist because you have a smartphone.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You already have it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I wonder maybe that's where we're gonna go with AI stuff and we're
Speaker 2:  ways away from the ai, ai gadgets being any good. So
Speaker 2:  maybe we're, we're gonna be in a real sort of valley with that stuff for
Speaker 2:  a little while it feels like.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We're gonna find out,
Speaker 2:  But luckily phones are getting better, so I'll take
Speaker 4:  To that. Yeah, yeah. Phones are sticking around I think.
Speaker 2:  And you've given me yet another reason to buy a flip phone, which oh man
Speaker 2:  is all I really needed from you was more recent.
Speaker 4:  I took that Motorola out of the closet and I was like, this is so nice.
Speaker 4:  Ugh. Just shutting it. Just shutting. It feels good. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna start buying t-shirts with the pocket on the, on the breast. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  exactly. I'm gonna, I'm gonna fold it out and just stick it right there and
Speaker 2:  chat with it all day. It's gonna be amazing. Yeah, it
Speaker 4:  Looks super cool.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I I I believe that, I bet you made a lot of friends and everybody thought
Speaker 2:  you were super normal and cool all the time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I was taking pictures of it for the article and my husband walked into
Speaker 4:  the kitchen and just slowly backed away. Like, I don't
Speaker 4:  understand what's happening here and I'm not gonna question it.
Speaker 2:  That's, that's the correct way to react to AI of all sorts. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Probably just back away.
Speaker 2:  All right Allison, thank you as always. Thank you. We gotta take a break
Speaker 2:  and then we're gonna talk that
Speaker 2:  We're back while we're on the subject of ai, there's one company that we
Speaker 2:  don't talk about much as an AI powerhouse and we probably
Speaker 2:  should. That company is meta and it's been on a tear with new AI
Speaker 2:  products recently it added multimodal AI to the smart glasses that it
Speaker 2:  makes with RayBan. It launched a new model called LAMA three that it says
Speaker 2:  can keep up with Gemini and Jet GPT and the rest. It added meta AI
Speaker 2:  to like every one of its apps if you use any meta product
Speaker 2:  and statistically if you are a person on earth, you do, you basically
Speaker 2:  can't avoid Meta's AI anymore. There's a big
Speaker 2:  company-wide move happening here and it feels like meta, which
Speaker 2:  was all in on the Metaverse not that long ago, might be all in on
Speaker 2:  something else. Now Alex Heath on our team knows this situation better than
Speaker 2:  anybody and so he's here to help make sense of all of it for us.
Speaker 2:  Alex Heath, welcome back.
Speaker 5:  It's good to be back on the People's podcast, David.
Speaker 2:  Yes, we who cares what the judges think Alex, I don't, I don't care about
Speaker 2:  them. That's
Speaker 5:  A webby reference.
Speaker 2:  So there's a lot of stuff going on at Meta and basically you've been reporting
Speaker 2:  out a bunch of like puzzle pieces over the last few weeks of what's going
Speaker 2:  on there and I wanna see if we can like make sense of them all together.
Speaker 2:  But let's start with last week with the Big Horizon os
Speaker 2:  announcement. Explain to me what Meta is up to with Horizon Os and
Speaker 2:  trying to like open up the Quest universe to other people.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, so Meta's been doing headsets since before it was meta for a very
Speaker 5:  long time, 10 years actually when they bought the Oculus startup,
Speaker 5:  that then became Quest later. And what they
Speaker 5:  did recently, which I think it actually makes a lot of sense in the bigger
Speaker 5:  picture of Meadow, which I know we'll get into, is that they decided that
Speaker 5:  the OS that they built for the Quest, which they've now called Horizon,
Speaker 5:  and we are approaching Google level naming confusion here. It truly
Speaker 5:  David insane. So ask me to to explain if, if it's confusing at
Speaker 5:  any point. But they are taking the OS that they've
Speaker 5:  built over time for the Quest and starting to license it out to
Speaker 5:  OEMs. So basically replicating the Android playbook that
Speaker 5:  Google used to become the number one player by user base
Speaker 5:  and mobile and they think a similar thing could happen with headsets. It's
Speaker 5:  very early. So all they've announced is that Lenovo is gonna work on
Speaker 5:  a custom headset using their Horizon OS and
Speaker 5:  Asus is also doing something and then there's gonna be less custom,
Speaker 5:  but I think more just special edition with some, you know,
Speaker 5:  bundled controllers, Xbox themed Quest. And I think
Speaker 5:  what they've decided is that they want to be the general purpose headset
Speaker 5:  maker. So making kind of the state-of-the-art thing that could be used for
Speaker 5:  a lot of different tasks on your face. And they want a wide network of
Speaker 5:  OEMs to basically invent all of these more niche narrow headset
Speaker 5:  use cases. Whether that's something for work, something for gaming, something
Speaker 5:  for who knows, construction, whatever the idea is, just let
Speaker 5:  a million flowers bloom here.
Speaker 2:  That's really interesting. So yeah, my, my next question is gonna be what
Speaker 2:  do you think this means for Meta's hardware plans? But that's a really interesting
Speaker 2:  way to think about it, that actually this is meta saying we want to
Speaker 2:  build this sort of all purpose headset but then let
Speaker 2:  lots of people build lots of other kinds of headsets which I think actually
Speaker 2:  makes sense. Like we, we certainly have not arrived at the perfect hardware
Speaker 2:  for a headset, so you might as well let lots of people try lots of things.
Speaker 5:  No, and the quest is still pretty small. I mean it's approaching
Speaker 5:  console level yearly volume in terms of sales. I think they've sold
Speaker 5:  a little over 20 million quests to date now how many people actually use
Speaker 5:  those quests on a regular basis is a whole nother story. Right, fair. They
Speaker 5:  were giving them away basically for a little while. But yeah, I think even
Speaker 5:  with this market being so young, they see the potential for
Speaker 5:  others to come in and help them grow it. And I think crucially for meta here
Speaker 5:  with the OS is that it comes with Horizon, the social
Speaker 5:  network. So yes, horizon Os also has what has been called
Speaker 5:  Horizon, the 3D kind of Sims meets Roblox
Speaker 5:  social network that we have relentlessly made fun of here on The
Speaker 5:  Verge.
Speaker 2:  I was gonna say, which sucks
Speaker 5:  To be fair, they have squashed a lot of the bugs and
Speaker 5:  the avatars look better. But yeah it's still pretty rough. But
Speaker 5:  that comes bundled with this os it kind of reminds me of when
Speaker 5:  Google was licensing Android. I mean it's, that's still how they do it. That
Speaker 5:  really to get the best experience you've got to have Google services
Speaker 5:  baked into Android and this has actually gotten 'em into some anti-competitive,
Speaker 5:  you know, regulation trouble over the years with how they bundled things.
Speaker 5:  But Meta is kind of kind of doing the same thing here. They're bundling what
Speaker 5:  is their actual way that they see monetizing all this metaverse stuff over
Speaker 5:  time, which is their social network which will be monetized with ads of
Speaker 5:  course and commerce assuming that enough people eventually
Speaker 5:  start using it.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. So I've been trying to think what is in this
Speaker 2:  for meta because on the one hand I think Meta's assumption would be that
Speaker 2:  the more people use any kind of immersive headset
Speaker 2:  stuff, the better, right? Like we're still very much in a sort of rising
Speaker 2:  tide lift all boats world then if you're meta you're like, okay, do
Speaker 2:  we want to be the ones who run the store and we just take a commission on
Speaker 2:  everything? Everybody buys on every headset And that's something, do we want
Speaker 2:  to be the ones who like charge? Do we wanna charge a licensing fee and go
Speaker 2:  like the Windows way and make all of our money that way? But you, you think
Speaker 2:  it's actually the big Galaxy brain play here is actually a social networking
Speaker 2:  play.
Speaker 5:  I just think that's how they're gonna make money off of it. Okay. They've
Speaker 5:  decided that they won't be making money on a hardware margin
Speaker 5:  like Apple and you know, they're leaning into what they're inherently good
Speaker 5:  at, which is like scaled ad-based attention services
Speaker 5:  and I think they think that they can translate that to headsets over time.
Speaker 5:  And so that's why Horizon, the social network is in Horizon the os
Speaker 5:  I'm sure they're gonna get paid also just for someone to license the os,
Speaker 5:  but I don't think they see that as a key moneymaker. And I
Speaker 5:  know I've been mentioning Android and Google already a lot, but I would say
Speaker 5:  that if you were to talk to, to Mark Zuckerberg like I have, he would really
Speaker 5:  rather be me making a comparison to Microsoft because, oh interesting.
Speaker 5:  Microsoft when they, you know, began licensing Windows OEMs really
Speaker 5:  wanted it, it was actually the leading desktop PC software platform
Speaker 5:  because Microsoft had invented the most useful productivity software at the
Speaker 5:  time, right? Whereas Android was very clearly a reaction to the iPhone.
Speaker 5:  It wasn't so much something that OEMs were seeking out because of
Speaker 5:  how good it was. It was more of a defensive play. And to
Speaker 5:  meta's credit, they invested in this category before anyone else at the level
Speaker 5:  that they have. It hasn't gotten them a lot yet, but I think with this opening
Speaker 5:  up play that they're doing, it positions them better long term,
Speaker 5:  especially with Apple getting into the picture with the Vision Pro.
Speaker 2:  I mean it, it is a funny time because there was just this report that Apple
Speaker 2:  is scaling back its Vision Pro plans because it hasn't been
Speaker 2:  selling the way that it hoped. It kind of feels like everything you just
Speaker 2:  described makes quite a bit of sense to me, right, actually for like both
Speaker 2:  what Meta is good at and also where this space is headed. Building
Speaker 2:  an operating system makes a lot of sense and Meta has done this really well,
Speaker 2:  but I feel like the, there's it, it all still assumes that eventually there
Speaker 2:  will be a real market for headsets and I don't know that I'm less
Speaker 2:  confident in that thesis than I would've been a couple years ago, but I certainly
Speaker 2:  don't feel like I'm more confident in that thesis. But you've been talking
Speaker 2:  to Mark, where do you feel like his head is with how
Speaker 2:  this market is going in general right now?
Speaker 5:  I think they still see these headsets that fully immerse yourself in
Speaker 5:  virtual environments as akin to like the future
Speaker 5:  PC market in terms of volume and scale. So you're not
Speaker 5:  talking hundreds of millions of devices a year. You're probably just looking
Speaker 5:  at, you know, low to med, tens of millions. And this is
Speaker 5:  over a period of the next several years. I think the industry is in single
Speaker 5:  digit millions right now, the AR side, so where
Speaker 5:  the Meta Ray Band glasses are now, but eventually where they want to get
Speaker 5:  to with displays in them. I think they see that by the end of this
Speaker 5:  decade, early 2030 as something that could be approaching mobile
Speaker 5:  in terms of its just widespread usage and adoption. So there's
Speaker 5:  kind of two parts of the same play and a lot of the headset
Speaker 5:  technology eventually makes its way into the AR technology. It goes back
Speaker 5:  and forth and you know, we saw that with the Quest three, right? It has the
Speaker 5:  mixed reality component that you're also seeing in a lot of AR
Speaker 5:  devices.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I guess that also makes the social emphasis make
Speaker 2:  sense because if you're trying to build sort of from both directions,
Speaker 2:  one thing that will will flow kind of across that whole spectrum, all the
Speaker 2:  way up from smart glasses to like really high end headsets is just people
Speaker 2:  want to talk to each other and hang out. And so if, if Meta can build that
Speaker 2:  stuff for that whole spectrum, it can sort of win no matter how long it takes
Speaker 2:  us to get to the final thing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean they see this hardware naturally as like an inherently social
Speaker 5:  medium. I think that's a bit of a dichotomy when you think about strapping
Speaker 5:  something to your face. There's something inherently antisocial and putting
Speaker 5:  something on your face between you and other people. But it's a pretty
Speaker 5:  different approach to what we've seen at least Apple do to date with the
Speaker 5:  Vision Pro, right? They're really treating it as more of a general purpose
Speaker 5:  computing platform. They're not leaning into social the only social thing
Speaker 5:  they have. The FaceTime personas are pretty creepy based on my experience.
Speaker 5:  They're so creepy. Yeah. So I think Meta recognizes where it
Speaker 5:  can play to its strengths and that's in building social experiences at scale
Speaker 5:  and being this kind of quasi open player that is
Speaker 5:  the Microsoft to Apple's apple.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Let's talk about the open player thing because there was also, you
Speaker 2:  know, this, this push to Llama three, the new large language model and there
Speaker 2:  meta's trying to be open about how it approaches a lot of the big language
Speaker 2:  model stuff. It's very strange to me that the company that built
Speaker 2:  Facebook, which you had to be logged into in order to see anything
Speaker 2:  and was so famously like its own walled garden and made a ton of money by
Speaker 2:  being that walled garden that people came into and spent all of their time
Speaker 2:  into, has now made this grand pivot into being like
Speaker 2:  a, a good citizen of the internet and an open player working with everybody.
Speaker 2:  And they're talking about this with Federating threads, they're talking about
Speaker 2:  this with the AI stuff, they're talking about it with the horizon stuff like
Speaker 2:  what happened here? Is it like Mark Zuckerberg got like really into fighting
Speaker 2:  and was just like, I love the world now. Like what, what happened here?
Speaker 5:  I don't know if fighting would get you into being like embracing open source.
Speaker 5:  That's an interesting theory.
Speaker 2:  He, he just has somewhere else to put all of his rage, so now he's happy
Speaker 2:  at work. I don't
Speaker 5:  Know. I would challenge a little bit of your, your history retelling there.
Speaker 5:  I mean you remember the Farmville era? Sure. They actually made a huge
Speaker 5:  bet very early to become a developer platform. So yeah, they've been a walled
Speaker 5:  garden in the sense that they've pretty tightly controlled the, the walls
Speaker 5:  around their apps. So it's not like, you know, the code to Instagram is open
Speaker 5:  source and I it never will be. But I would say they have
Speaker 5:  historically, actually even on the hardware side, thinking about very
Speaker 5:  early, you know, Oculus, rifs were done with companies like
Speaker 5:  xmi, Samsung, Lenovo, so
Speaker 5:  they have a history of this. I really think that meta is
Speaker 5:  becoming a kind of new Microsoft. Hmm. And
Speaker 5:  it makes sense because Zuckerberg has seen Bill Gates as a, as
Speaker 5:  a kind of a business idol and mentor personally for a very long time.
Speaker 5:  And I, I've heard him talk about Microsoft's influence on his thinking
Speaker 5:  over the years and he is talked about it with me recently. In
Speaker 2:  What sense? Like what, what about Microsoft do you feel like sticks out to
Speaker 2:  him is
Speaker 5:  Appealing? I think the way they leveraged their expertise
Speaker 5:  in software and then licensing that software
Speaker 5:  across different players to really just build a
Speaker 5:  true platform. There's this old Bill Gates quote and I'm gonna butcher
Speaker 5:  it, but essentially he said, you know, you know, you've built a true platform
Speaker 5:  when the total value of what has been built on top of your platform
Speaker 5:  is greater than the platform itself. Right? Right. And I think that's what
Speaker 5:  Met is hoping for on the headset side and especially on the AI side.
Speaker 5:  You know, with Lama for example, I just interviewed Mark for
Speaker 5:  the LAMA three release. It's interesting what they're doing because they're
Speaker 5:  spending billions of dollars on compute to build these cutting edge models
Speaker 5:  that compete with open ai, Andro and others. And they're just giving them
Speaker 5:  away. And that seems counterintuitive for a company like Meta to do,
Speaker 5:  but when you think about where they're kind of strategically positioned relative
Speaker 5:  to the rest of the players here, they don't have their own cloud
Speaker 5:  business, right? So they're not selling access to their servers and
Speaker 5:  their business is building consumer social products that
Speaker 5:  monetize attention and rather than boil the ocean, I
Speaker 5:  think they're realizing that's where they're, they can play to their strengths.
Speaker 5:  And the history with Open source is if you get a bunch of people
Speaker 5:  to build on your frameworks that you've open sourced,
Speaker 5:  guess what? It makes the technology you build more pervasive
Speaker 5:  and value flows back to you in the sense that the community helps
Speaker 5:  improve it. Right? And Zuckerberg said something on a podcast
Speaker 5:  recently where if the developers using LAMA three
Speaker 5:  can help them lower their costs on inference, which is the cost of like
Speaker 5:  running these models over time, even just slightly, it
Speaker 5:  will make up for the entirety that they've spent on training all future
Speaker 5:  versions of Llama just in terms of the cost of what they need to, to run
Speaker 5:  this stuff in the cloud, in their cloud. So it's a pure
Speaker 5:  infrastructure play that I think Mark has correctly
Speaker 5:  identified. They're in a unique position to make and it creates more
Speaker 5:  competition because LAMA three can be used by other developers. It forces
Speaker 5:  open AI and others I think to do more in open source, which I think we'll
Speaker 5:  see over the course of this year. And you know, meta has a long history of
Speaker 5:  doing open source actually on the kind of just regular coding
Speaker 5:  side. That's
Speaker 2:  True. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It, it makes sense for them and it's, again, I just think we're seeing kind
Speaker 5:  of like the rise of perhaps the next Microsoft in terms of how they're
Speaker 5:  attacking each of these new technologies.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it seems smart too because right now most of those other companies
Speaker 2:  you just named are all desperately trying to be the next Apple. Hmm. Like
Speaker 2:  OpenAI is very much trying to sort of build a universe inside of
Speaker 2:  OpenAI. They like license some of this stuff out, but like it's clear that
Speaker 2:  the thing that they want to do is like, they want to build, they want to
Speaker 2:  make custom gpt and have you use their stuff inside of their stuff and
Speaker 2:  so many, and like Google is desperately trying to like pull the whole ecosystem
Speaker 2:  in around itself with ai and you get the sense everybody sees this
Speaker 2:  as a chance to sort of own the whole experience and Meta is going the other
Speaker 2:  way, being like, this is a chance for us to like own the whole experience
Speaker 2:  everywhere, which actually strikes me as very smart in this moment.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, and you know, it's, yeah, I mean Meta should maybe be called open AI
Speaker 5:  and OpenAI should probably find a new name at this point. I mean, OpenAI
Speaker 5:  isn't open at all really. Yeah, it's, it's interesting. I, I agree with you.
Speaker 5:  I think for a while Meadow was trying to have its cake and eat it too on
Speaker 5:  the reality labs Quest side. And I kept pushing them on this that like they
Speaker 5:  were trying to be too much like Apple in the sense that they were doing all
Speaker 5:  of the hardware fully vertically integrated and the
Speaker 5:  software. And I was like, when are you gonna, if you wanna be the open player,
Speaker 5:  you've gotta start licensing some of this stuff because Apple, you can't
Speaker 5:  compete with Apple at its own game, right? Like Apple is the best at this
Speaker 5:  and I think they finally realized that and are embracing it and
Speaker 5:  it's what Microsoft did and it's smart.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no, I, I I think, I think that's right and it also seems like it's
Speaker 2:  given meta real momentum. Like my, my sense is this,
Speaker 2:  the, the LAMA relaunch and just the sort of meta AI
Speaker 2:  percolation around all of Meta's different apps really worked
Speaker 2:  very quickly. Like, it, it it kind of, it became a big player pretty
Speaker 2:  fast in, in this space and I think in part because it has been
Speaker 2:  sort of out in the ecosystem much more rather than just saying, you know,
Speaker 2:  here is an AI you can talk to inside of Instagram, which I think everybody
Speaker 2:  would've kind of just sniffed at and moved on. It feels like Meta is able
Speaker 2:  to make these big plays by playing this game differently.
Speaker 5:  They are, I have a framework for evaluating companies, which is like, are
Speaker 5:  you in the show me or tell me phase? And I think Meta's been doing a lot
Speaker 5:  of tell me stuff with ai, like the assistant is gonna be everywhere. Right?
Speaker 5:  That was the recent news. They're putting it in the search box of Instagram,
Speaker 5:  which I hate
Speaker 2:  By the way. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So that's where I'm going like yeah, they're putting it everywhere. And now
Speaker 5:  the real test is do people actually want this? Does it make sense to have
Speaker 5:  a chat GPT like experience in your Instagram or your WhatsApp where
Speaker 5:  you're used to just talking with people and Zuckerberg really thinks we're
Speaker 5:  all gonna be interacting with synthetic AI type personas. Like people
Speaker 5:  in conversations with people, you know, like you can add the meta AI to a
Speaker 5:  WhatsApp thread with other people to give recommendations or something. So
Speaker 5:  they've gotta prove that people actually want that, that running joke inside
Speaker 5:  Meta before they put the AI everywhere was that like no one was using
Speaker 5:  this, it was something you had to kind of find. It was pretty buried and
Speaker 5:  not even like people at Meta were using it. So now that it's got Lama three
Speaker 5:  under it, which is pretty competitive as a model and they've got Google results
Speaker 5:  in there and Bing results in there, which are the only chat bot that does
Speaker 5:  realtime search from both those, it's got a good shot at at
Speaker 5:  capturing a lot of the attention from people who have maybe never tried
Speaker 5:  Chatt PT or Anthropics Claude. Because you know, for people who listen
Speaker 5:  to the show, they know all these names, but you gotta think the, the boomers
Speaker 5:  sharing, you know, spaghetti Jesus viral generative
Speaker 5:  AI memes on Facebook, they've probably never used a chat bot
Speaker 5:  before. There's, there's millions, hundreds of millions of people who have
Speaker 5:  never used one of these things. And I think Zuckerberg's bet is just like
Speaker 5:  he did with stories and Snapchat and reels with TikTok, he's gonna
Speaker 5:  introduce this new format, this new way of interacting with the internet
Speaker 5:  to more people than anyone else possibly could because his
Speaker 5:  true inherent leverage and competitive edge
Speaker 5:  is over 3 billion daily users.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think that all strategically makes a lot of sense to me. And I think
Speaker 2:  as a product, it works in some places. Like I actually think putting the
Speaker 2:  generative AI stuff inside of Facebook has terrifying
Speaker 2:  implications, but as a product makes some sense. I hate that they have
Speaker 2:  replaced the Instagram search bar with meta ai. I just wanna find a
Speaker 2:  video. I don't wanna talk to the ai, I wanna search for a video. Like it's
Speaker 2:  this idea that we have decided AI and search are the same thing, just drives
Speaker 2:  me insane. And I wish Meta would stop doing it.
Speaker 5:  They might, you know, if there's enough uproar, they might, they did this
Speaker 5:  like overnight Meta is notorious, they invented the kind of ruthless
Speaker 5:  AB testing in Silicon Valley. So in a normal situation they would've tested
Speaker 5:  this with some, you know, in different markets for weeks and on
Speaker 5:  end, months on end figured out if people actually wanted, they just flipped
Speaker 5:  it on for everyone overnight, which means it's a Zuck level top down.
Speaker 5:  We are betting the farm on this as a modality
Speaker 5:  and now he's gotta be proven right or wrong.
Speaker 2:  So that was actually one of the things I wanted to ask you about is like
Speaker 2:  connect the AI push to that sort of big picture meta
Speaker 2:  idea for me because I think I saw AI for
Speaker 2:  a while at Meta as kind of an end around Metaverse play. Like
Speaker 2:  AI got really cool right as the Metaverse stopped being cool and they could
Speaker 2:  build AI stuff that was actually Metaverse stuff, but they just had to call
Speaker 2:  it AI stuff. But now it seems like there is this idea that
Speaker 2:  some part of that like engagement based
Speaker 2:  community stuff going on inside of Meta's products, they also seem to think
Speaker 2:  AI is part of that in a way that I can't quite wrap my head
Speaker 2:  around. Like as you talk to people like Zuckerberg, like
Speaker 2:  what is the sort of Galaxy brand vision for AI right now?
Speaker 5:  It's this kind of scary vision that I, frankly I can't
Speaker 5:  decide how dystopian it is, but it's this idea that there are just going
Speaker 5:  to be thousands if not millions of ais that we chat
Speaker 5:  and interact with in our feeds and our messaging threads
Speaker 5:  that are indistinguishable from people and that
Speaker 5:  creators that Kylie Jenner on Instagram will have an AI version of herself
Speaker 5:  that she's trained with certain parameters that means that all her
Speaker 5:  fans can interact with quote unquote Kylie Jenner, right? And
Speaker 5:  they're doing some, I think, kind of clever early engagement
Speaker 5:  hacks with meta ai. There was an example of I think 4 0 4 media
Speaker 5:  where it was really cringe, but it was an interesting way to kind of juice
Speaker 5:  human engagement on Facebook. There was this group
Speaker 5:  full of parents with special needs kids and
Speaker 5:  there's this new feature that Meta is trying in a, in a group where if someone
Speaker 5:  doesn't comment under a group post for I think like more than an hour
Speaker 5:  meta AI will comment with its own just prompt to try to Oh wow.
Speaker 5:  Spark conversation with the actual human beings. And in this example,
Speaker 5:  Medi made up that it had a kid or a couple of kids with special
Speaker 5:  needs and it was pretty creepy and hallucinating and all that.
Speaker 5:  But you look at the thread, it got a lot of humans commenting underneath
Speaker 5:  it, right? So it's like you're using AI as the beginning
Speaker 5:  flame to get a bunch of people to actually talk to each other. I
Speaker 2:  Like the idea that the AI's job is to just say some wild insane
Speaker 2:  stuff on every post on the internet just to just to get the fire.
Speaker 2:  I
Speaker 5:  Mean we can all just rage at it. Yeah. And yeah, I think that's
Speaker 5:  part of it. But yeah, it's, it's all of these things and it's also the, the
Speaker 5:  the visual generation stuff, there's gonna be multimodality. So
Speaker 5:  generating video you can already generate images. They upgraded it where
Speaker 5:  it like generates the image as you type. Have you played with this?
Speaker 2:  It's really cool. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's cool. And you know, obviously they're, they're still figuring out the
Speaker 5:  like things that will and won't do that are cringe, you know, the Gemini
Speaker 5:  type diversity scandal stuff. Yeah. But I think we're still in the very early
Speaker 5:  innings of this. It's the, and now it's the show me like I was saying, they've
Speaker 5:  gotta show that people actually want all this stuff.
Speaker 2:  That's a very broad way of thinking about it. 'cause like the, the way you
Speaker 2:  were describing it earlier right, is that there is that sort of unifying
Speaker 2:  sense of what Meta is very good at, which is, which is basically building
Speaker 2:  products that people engage with at scale, right? Like you, you can boil
Speaker 2:  a lot of the things that Meta does down to that. And the
Speaker 2:  AI seems like it's partly that, but it could also be lots of stuff.
Speaker 2:  And I get the sense that Meta is maybe just gonna explore that
Speaker 2:  stuff to see what happens. But also I think like a lot of companies is going
Speaker 2:  to be prone to being distracted by whatever shiny thing you can do
Speaker 2:  with a language model and just shove it inside of apps and think people
Speaker 2:  will use it. And I feel like meta more than most might have a chance
Speaker 2:  to like really ruin some of its products by overextending AI
Speaker 2:  into it.
Speaker 5:  The thing is, they're a large mature publicly traded company. They won't
Speaker 5:  torch everything for this. Like if they see that it's tanking key metrics
Speaker 5:  that will impact, you know, the next earnings, they'll roll this stuff back.
Speaker 2:  I mean, I would point out they torched a lot of things in the name of the
Speaker 2:  metaverse for a while there. Like this wouldn't be totally unheard of.
Speaker 5:  Well, kind of. I mean it was all, it's all still separate, right? Like yeah.
Speaker 5:  So it's a lot of sunken money into it, but nothing they've done
Speaker 5:  on the Quest has like impacted your experience as an average Instagram
Speaker 5:  user.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. They're not fighting Facebook. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's what's different about me AI is that they're literally putting it
Speaker 5:  everywhere. So they're in the, like, like you said, shove it everywhere and
Speaker 5:  find out phase and we're all about to find out. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's, yeah. So what, what's your sense from talking to Mark
Speaker 2:  about this Google stuff, by the way, this is, this is the like small detail
Speaker 2:  of, of your most recent story with him and this whole meta
Speaker 2:  AI rollout that I found the most fascinating. They're very excited about
Speaker 2:  having Google integrated into meta AI search results. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Which just seems bizarre to me that that is a thing that exists. What, what,
Speaker 2:  what do you know about what's going on there? I
Speaker 5:  Thought it was interesting too, reading between the lines. You know, I asked
Speaker 5:  him what is the deal here because Google has not licensed
Speaker 5:  its realtime search results to any of these chat bots yet. And
Speaker 5:  I was like, are you paying them? Are they paying you? He basically said
Speaker 5:  that Meta is paying Google, but it's not quote a ton. I don't
Speaker 5:  know if a ton is billionaire who owns half of Kauai a
Speaker 5:  ton or normal a ton. I'm sure that will come out. But
Speaker 5:  yeah, it's smart because that's one of the main problems with
Speaker 5:  these chatbots, right? Is their recency isn't very good. They make up
Speaker 5:  events. I was using meta AI without the Google
Speaker 5:  integration and it like used last year's Coachella lineup
Speaker 5:  when I asked it, who was just performing at Coachella last weekend. So
Speaker 5:  you've gotta fix that realtime search can do that. Zuckerberg hinted to me
Speaker 5:  that Google's building a model, and I don't mean AI model, but I think a
Speaker 5:  business model around this, around licensing search to these chatbots.
Speaker 5:  So it makes sense because that is Google's bread and butter
Speaker 5:  still, I thought that Google would keep that for Gemini,
Speaker 5:  that that would make their chat bot experience, you know, more
Speaker 5:  unique and their leverage there. But I think this means that we
Speaker 5:  may start seeing them license it elsewhere as well.
Speaker 2:  That's fascinating. A sucks for perplexity. You had a good
Speaker 2:  run, perplexity great job. But b, the, the tension there
Speaker 2:  just for Google, this is a total aside, but the tension there for Google
Speaker 2:  between like search has made it all of the money in the known universe and
Speaker 2:  also they're betting a lot of that search money on AI working. But then you
Speaker 2:  look at this and there is just a giant money faucet licensing this data to
Speaker 2:  chat bots all of whom would want it and pay for it. Fascinating. The
Speaker 2:  like the, the business machinations between those two things are
Speaker 2:  going to be really interesting to watch in the next couple of years.
Speaker 5:  I agree. I I'm eager to hear Google maybe talk about that more at IO
Speaker 5:  soon.
Speaker 2:  So big picture as, as the person who broke the story of
Speaker 2:  Facebook renaming to Meta, I'm curious how you feel about Meta as a metaverse
Speaker 2:  company at this moment in time. Like there is part of me that is like rewind
Speaker 2:  whatever, five years and knowing what he knows now, mark would've renamed
Speaker 2:  the company like artificial or something instead of meta. Like is
Speaker 2:  the Metaverse still the thing when you talk to Meta and Mark?
Speaker 5:  No, I mean it's not the thing they want to talk about the most, but I
Speaker 5:  don't know man, I, I think you can walk on chew gum at the same time and
Speaker 5:  I still think 10 years out they see more of their
Speaker 5:  optionality on the future being on the Metaverse stuff because okay,
Speaker 5:  they've hit a plateau with Facebook, it's not getting young people back
Speaker 5:  eventually and they talk about this pretty frankly internally, literally
Speaker 5:  everyone's just gonna die, right? Because like if you're not getting new
Speaker 5:  users on your platform, your platform's in terminal decline,
Speaker 5:  Instagram is their next Facebook, right? It will be,
Speaker 5:  we're all gonna be on there in probably 10 years and it's gonna feel just
Speaker 5:  like Facebook does now to the younger generation, whether they can buy the
Speaker 5:  next thing to keep that whole cycle going 40 years from now, TBD
Speaker 5:  unlikely, but this whole push to control the next computing
Speaker 5:  platform and or at least have more say in it so that Apple just doesn't
Speaker 5:  invent the whole next, you know, headset modality. I think it still makes
Speaker 5:  sense. I mean, I don't know, I've been playing with the The Ray band smart
Speaker 5:  classes with multimodal AI on them. You have it too, right?
Speaker 5:  And you know, it's not great. It's wrong
Speaker 5:  half of the time. I will say I'm impressed with the speed of it, but you
Speaker 5:  know, it's just makes stuff up still a lot. Yeah. But you can see when they
Speaker 5:  iron out these kinks like, oh the, the basis of this makes sense. Like
Speaker 5:  I actually do see over time as the tech gets figured out, a lot of people
Speaker 5:  wanting to use technology more through their eyes
Speaker 5:  and through their kind of egocentric view of the world. And you're covering
Speaker 5:  this a lot in the wearable AI side with you know, humane and rabbit and all
Speaker 5:  that. But this is all kind of converging over time. This generative AI
Speaker 5:  meets wearables into what I think is a pretty compelling next
Speaker 5:  computing platform. And if anything I think meta feels like
Speaker 5:  AI has only kind of made that more apparent and
Speaker 5:  actually pushed off the need to have the whole display stuff that we
Speaker 5:  always hear about that we're gonna have all these holograms around us and
Speaker 5:  it just keeps getting pushed out and out and out. And now maybe they think
Speaker 5:  like, oh maybe all we really need for the next five-ish years or so is
Speaker 5:  compelling AI in a wearable form factor. So yeah, I mean all these big tech
Speaker 5:  companies, they over rotate on the topic de jour and that's generative AI
Speaker 5:  right now. I don't think they're changing the company name again, I think
Speaker 5:  they're still investing a lot of money in reality labs and will have, yeah,
Speaker 5:  a pretty wild product next year that I've scooped, which is The Ray bands
Speaker 5:  with a display and a bracelet that does right EMG kind of neural
Speaker 5:  interface control. So imagine like typing and clicking and
Speaker 5:  pointing with I guess just basically thinking. So we're about to hit
Speaker 5:  a lot of really interesting new stuff there. It's,
Speaker 5:  it's definitely like they, they over rotated on it like way too early, but
Speaker 5:  that's like the story of meta they, they spent, you know, whatever they spent
Speaker 5:  on Oculus 10 years ago and whereas it really gotten them in terms of ROI
Speaker 5:  even now, so them like going too hard too early
Speaker 5:  is nothing new.
Speaker 2:  That is fair. That is what they do. And I will say to their credit, they,
Speaker 2:  they both like built the way too early thing
Speaker 2:  and the kind of right on time thing. Like the, I think the smart glasses
Speaker 2:  were the correct move for now. The big push after the
Speaker 2:  headset and the metaverse is like way too early, which is a classic Microsoft
Speaker 2:  move, so good job again Z. But they're doing a surprisingly good job
Speaker 2:  of both sort of running those in parallel and pushing them towards each other.
Speaker 2:  And I think that is like, if you can keep that up and you can afford to keep
Speaker 2:  that up until they actually hit each other, that's it. That ends up being
Speaker 2:  a pretty powerful place to be. As opposed to somebody like Apple who now
Speaker 2:  has this massively overpowered thing that it's gonna have to
Speaker 2:  figure out how to like pull back into actual mainstream
Speaker 2:  interests over
Speaker 7:  browser is kind of like popping up constantly, even if you've selected it
Speaker 7:  not as your default browser. Same thing with the cloud
Speaker 7:  storage. And I wanted to know, number one, why do they think they can get
Speaker 7:  away with doing the exact same thing that got them in trouble in the nineties?
Speaker 7:  I mean, I understand the market share for their browser has dropped, but
Speaker 7:  it's still the same anti-competitive practice. And two, why
Speaker 7:  aren't we putting a stop to it legally? Anyway, thanks.
Speaker 7:  Hope you can answer the question.
Speaker 2:  All right. You ask for a Eli rant, you get a Eli rant, NELI Patel. Hello.
Speaker 8:  Hi, how's it going?
Speaker 2:  So we, we've talked sort of obliquely about Microsoft as part of all
Speaker 2:  of these big antitrust things, so I figured this is useful and to just hit
Speaker 2:  head on, what are your thoughts? What do you make of this question?
Speaker 8:  I dunno if you're gonna get so much. A legal rant from me is just a rant
Speaker 8:  about the fact that nothing can displace Chrome.
Speaker 8:  Like governments around the world have been trying to displace Chrome for
Speaker 8:  10 years more and, and nothing. They try works and I think they're
Speaker 8:  kind of at a point where they're like, I don't know, maybe Microsoft can
Speaker 8:  do some stuff and it doesn't work. And I, I think that
Speaker 8:  specifically with the Edge browser and the prompts to make edge the default
Speaker 8:  and all that stuff, I think the market is very clear that it hates it.
Speaker 8:  People don't like it whenever we write about it, people are like, I hate
Speaker 8:  this. This is stupid. And then it doesn't work anyway. And I suspect
Speaker 8:  that regulators in Europe and the United States are kinda looking at that
Speaker 8:  and being like, fine, it's just not working. Right? If you want to destroy
Speaker 8:  your own reputation, try to make this work. Like have at it. When I interviewed
Speaker 8:  Jonathan Cantor on decoder, the head of antitrust at Department of Justice,
Speaker 8:  he said his framework for decisions was hips. He's called it
Speaker 8:  hands on Hips. Okay, high impact programmatically significant, huh?
Speaker 8:  And I think you just look at that equation and you're like, this is low impact,
Speaker 8:  right? Because it's not working. Anyway, that said, Microsoft is not
Speaker 8:  getting away with it. Totally. They rolled out teams, they bundled teams
Speaker 8:  into office that basically put a ton of pressure on Slack. It forced
Speaker 8:  Slack into selling itself into Salesforce. The European regulators
Speaker 8:  looked at that very sternly and Microsoft
Speaker 8:  Unbundled teams from office and they have now done that
Speaker 8:  globally because I think they saw the pressure was rising globally. So there,
Speaker 8:  I think there is, I think there are some places where Microsoft is responding
Speaker 8:  to the pressure, but specifically when it comes to irritating
Speaker 8:  everyone around Edge, I think regulators are like, yeah, that shit doesn't
Speaker 8:  work.
Speaker 2:  Right. Yeah. My, my read on this was that there are interesting Microsoft
Speaker 2:  Antit trucks questions probably around Windows and
Speaker 2:  probably around office and especially as it shoves
Speaker 2:  copilot AI stuff into all of that, there might be interesting questions to
Speaker 2:  come up there, but you just cannot make the case that Edge is
Speaker 2:  powerful. Like you just, you just can't. And I, I think you're
Speaker 2:  right that everyone has been desperate for there to be a meaningful
Speaker 2:  competitor to Chrome for a really long time. Mozilla has been running around
Speaker 2:  saying, you know, Firefox is the thing, we're gonna do everything differently.
Speaker 2:  Do all these browsers now even run chromium. Like Mozilla is one of the few
Speaker 2:  companies that isn't using the blink engine with the Chromium project
Speaker 2:  underneath all of the browser stuff. Like Edge is just another
Speaker 2:  skin on the same stuff that Chrome runs. And so it's all
Speaker 2:  really mely and weird, but for everything that Microsoft is doing, edge
Speaker 2:  still has like teeny tiny market share. And I feel like if I'm a regulator,
Speaker 2:  I'm like, Aw, you're trying so hard this it, this would be sketchy if only
Speaker 2:  it were working.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I mean the regulators in Europe basically imposed the same thing that
Speaker 8:  Microsoft is doing, which is like, would you like to try another browser?
Speaker 8:  And everyone was like, no. Yeah. And so Microsoft is Welcome To try
Speaker 8:  to decrease the market share of Chrome, which is the problem that those regulators
Speaker 8:  have been focused on. They're just not doing a good job. The other thing
Speaker 8:  that I think is interesting and kind of Vir Chasity is the reason Microsoft
Speaker 8:  was terrified of Netscape back then was they were very
Speaker 8:  worried that the application model for desktop computing would
Speaker 8:  leave the Wintel monopoly. So they were doing
Speaker 8:  anti-competitive stuff to protect that monopoly, protect the dominance of
Speaker 8:  Windows, make sure Windows was the place where all applications were
Speaker 8:  deployed and they saw correctly that deploying applications to
Speaker 8:  the web would break that model and that 100% happened.
Speaker 8:  Yes. So the fact that Edge runs chromium is because
Speaker 8:  if you want web apps to run well, it is better to standardize the
Speaker 8:  browser engines. They all work in the same place in the same way. And that's
Speaker 8:  how all apps are deployed now. And so I, it's just weird that like
Speaker 8:  we've come full circle, but actually the thing Microsoft was the most
Speaker 8:  worried about absolutely happened. And what the browser Chrome is
Speaker 8:  like the, the way the browser looks and works and what default
Speaker 8:  search service it uses versus what is the browser engine like that war is
Speaker 8:  lost.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I think, I mean it's, it's a weird place to be in because my next
Speaker 2:  question for you is gonna be, should we be talking more about Microsoft in
Speaker 2:  an antitrust way? Because again, it's either the first or second biggest
Speaker 2:  company on Earth. It is, it is clearly as powerful as anybody. It's just
Speaker 2:  so much more diversified in that way that it doesn't, it doesn't
Speaker 2:  have kind of the one thing that feels like it's thing the same way, but I
Speaker 2:  guess it would be Windows. But Windows has been completely commoditized.
Speaker 2:  Like I think desktop operating systems in general have been made totally
Speaker 2:  irrelevant by web browsers essentially. And the internet, like
Speaker 2:  most people, you buy a laptop, you download a browser, and that is, that
Speaker 2:  is your portal to everything else. And so maybe if I'm an antitrust regulator,
Speaker 2:  there's just no upside in caring about desktop operating systems anymore,
Speaker 2:  even though Microsoft is like by a mile the dominant player.
Speaker 8:  But there's a handful of things that are worth considering. But
Speaker 8:  even there you can see there's enough competition. So the one I would just
Speaker 8:  throw right back at your example is games. Sure. If you want to play video
Speaker 8:  games on a pc, you're gonna buy a Windows pc. Yeah. And you are really
Speaker 8:  reliant on Windows and all of its graphic support and the ecosystem of
Speaker 8:  graphics cards available for Windows. There
Speaker 2:  Are like three people with Steam running on their Macs who are like really
Speaker 2:  upset that you said that, but
Speaker 8:  Yeah, and they're, you're correct. They're running it at very low frameworks
Speaker 8:  compared to any anyone pc, right? Like, and so there's a little
Speaker 8:  market there that feels very tightly controlled, but then you look around
Speaker 8:  and you're like, oh, there's all these like cool handhelds that run
Speaker 8:  Linux and Steam, and you can just see, okay, there's like
Speaker 8:  meaningful, like the game developers themselves know they don't wanna
Speaker 8:  be totally stuck here forever. So they're creating new markets and
Speaker 8:  there's new distribution and Windows itself is not even Microsoft. Some
Speaker 8:  particular advantage in gaming Xbox, it's other big consumer gaming brand.
Speaker 8:  It's is not the winner. Like Phil Spencer will happily tell you they're not
Speaker 8:  the winner all day and all night. So I I, I think it's
Speaker 8:  hard for a regulator to point at some big consumer harm in gaming.
Speaker 8:  Like they couldn't even make the case to keep Microsoft from my Activision.
Speaker 8:  So, so I think that's challenging and plus you, you know, that space does
Speaker 8:  feel competitive and then everything else kind of doesn't touch consumers
Speaker 8:  that Microsoft does Slack and teams and it
Speaker 8:  got the scrutiny and they had to stop bundling teams. What else is there?
Speaker 8:  Everything else, all of Microsoft's other business is a bunch of enterprise
Speaker 8:  business. It's Azure, it's cloud computing services, it's
Speaker 8:  security to some shaky extent, like that's competitive now. Yeah. I think
Speaker 8:  it's hard to put together the political case. Like here's a real
Speaker 8:  problem that people are complaining about unless it's something a can consumer
Speaker 8:  can see, or like lots of people can see
Speaker 2:  In the way that like blue and green bubbles is like, it has that like visceral
Speaker 2:  thing that you can point to. Microsoft doesn't have any of those. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And then when it does it, it's so blatantly annoying. Like, would you like
Speaker 8:  to try Edge that? Like the market just sort of corrects for it? Yeah. By
Speaker 8:  being like, no, I will now I will never do this.
Speaker 8:  And that's fine.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So you don't, you don't necessarily think any of this is even necessarily
Speaker 2:  coming for Microsoft. Like I think the, the two I've been waiting for are
Speaker 2:  YouTube scrutiny and Microsoft scrutiny and I think YouTube scrutiny is probably
Speaker 2:  still coming.
Speaker 8:  I'll, I'll take the opposite. I'll take the other end of that bet. Oh,
Speaker 2:  Okay. I,
Speaker 8:  YouTube is just a blind spot for everyone. We, we treat it like the ocean.
Speaker 8:  Like there it is
Speaker 8:  forever changing and always the same. Powerful.
Speaker 2:  It will be there long after we're all dead. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  It's like there, there lies the ocean. It's like who knows
Speaker 8:  what, what vast mysteries exist in the deep, it's an
Speaker 8:  absolute blind spot for everyone. It, no one treats like a business. Microsoft,
Speaker 8:  I think their deal with OpenAI, how they will integrate those
Speaker 8:  products, the exclusivity around that deal, whether it's a, whether
Speaker 8:  they sort of like acquired OpenAI without acquiring it. I think
Speaker 8:  there's a lot of scrutiny left to come there, particularly as that market
Speaker 8:  heats up. But I, I dunno what shape it will take, but I think people will
Speaker 8:  understand that that's weird and there's money in power and characters over
Speaker 8:  there before anyone even tries
Speaker 8:  to understand YouTube.
Speaker 2:  Hmm. That's fair. And that is to your point, that like directly
Speaker 2:  regular human relevant thing. Like yeah. If, if you want, if you
Speaker 2:  wanna start talking about what happens to chat GPT, like now you're back
Speaker 2:  squarely in regular consumer territory, which is where that goes.
Speaker 8:  Yes. Did Microsoft illegally invest in whatever, blah, blah, blah with
Speaker 8:  open AI to make these guys rich? Sure
Speaker 8:  you can tell that story. It's, I think it's very hard to be like, we're gonna
Speaker 8:  mess with YouTube.
Speaker 2:  It's just the ocean. That, that might be the best metaphor for YouTube I've
Speaker 2:  ever heard. I, I very much enjoy that. That's not what we came here to do.
Speaker 2:  But I'm glad that's really went
Speaker 8:  I one day someone's gonna be like, huh, YouTube's a company and
Speaker 8:  we'll see what happens after that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Fair enough. Alright, Josh, I hope that helps, Eli. Thank you.
Speaker 3:  Thanks.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that's it for The Vergecast today. Thanks to everybody who came
Speaker 2:  on the show, and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on
Speaker 2:  everything we talked about from Rabbit to Allison's experiment, to
Speaker 2:  Alex's coverage of all things going on at Meta at The Verge dot com. We'll
Speaker 2:  put lots of links in the show notes. But as always, read The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  It's a good website. If you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or other
Speaker 2:  AI gadgets you want me to try, you can always email us at Vergecast at The
Speaker 2:  Verge dot com. Call the hotline, eight six six VERGE one, one. Thanks again
Speaker 2:  to everybody who voted for us for the webs. We're still riding high on the
Speaker 2:  victory there, thrilled that you all listen to and like this show. It means
Speaker 2:  the world to us. Send us all your thoughts and questions, ideas, everything.
Speaker 2:  We wanna hear them all. Call the hotline, send an email. we love hearing
Speaker 2:  from you. This show is produced by Angel Marino, Liam James, and Will Poor
Speaker 2:  The. Vergecast is VERGE production part of the Vox Media podcast network.
Speaker 2:  Neli, Alex and I will be back on Friday to talk about presumably more AI
Speaker 2:  gadgets, some iPads coming up next week and everything else going on in tech.
Speaker 2:  We'll see you then. Rock and roll.