# Transcript
ID: 60028001-4969-4941-ac12-05fed5cec7d8
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6275216506023703371/-913261400835456250/s93290-US-5608s-1719564615.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel and David Pierce chat with Switched on Pop's Charlie Harding about the RIAA lawsuit against AI music startups Udio and Suno. Later, Nilay and David discuss the rest of this week's tech and gadget news.
Speaker 5:  That one track needs
Speaker 5:  of the world. There's a bunch of new phone events coming that just got announced.
Speaker 5:  We shock about, there are new party speakers from ultimate years. That's
Speaker 5:  very important to me. And we got a lightning around. We got a, we got a full
Speaker 5:  show before, before the 4th of July. This is America's
Speaker 5:  technology podcast. But before we begin, I have
Speaker 5:  to issue a correction.
Speaker 5:  There are some words that I only read and I never
Speaker 5:  say out loud.
Speaker 3:  Ooh. Which
Speaker 5:  One is that? There are lots of those words. Tons of 'em. I was a, I was a
Speaker 5:  small nerdy child in the middle of Wisconsin who read a
Speaker 5:  lot of books that the other children in Wisconsin were not interested in
Speaker 5:  this. Just a whole universe of vocabulary words.
Speaker 6:  What is like your main one from when you were a kid that you, you were like
Speaker 6:  26 and all of a I feel like chameleon is like the classic of genre.
Speaker 6:  Oh, that's a good one. Right. Where like half the people in the world grew
Speaker 6:  up thinking it was Chama Leon. For me it was learning that Hermione name
Speaker 6:  is Hermione and not Hermien as I called her. Oh,
Speaker 5:  That's good.
Speaker 6:  However many books I read before I saw the movies. Did you guys have these
Speaker 6:  that you grew up with?
Speaker 5:  I still,
Speaker 6:  And you discovered way late.
Speaker 5:  I still don't know whether it's Dearth or Darth
Speaker 5:  and I don't want to find out.
Speaker 6:  Fair enough. Don't email us about it. Don't ruin this for any lie.
Speaker 5:  Don't tell me. Don't. I don't. And I don't know if it means a lot or not
Speaker 5:  enough
Speaker 7:  On switch on Pop. We have in ongoing uncertainty about whether it
Speaker 7:  is homage or homage. That's good. And we have been written many
Speaker 7:  emails that it's both. And so we've refused to use the word from now
Speaker 5:  On out. Niche and niche. Very confusing. Mm.
Speaker 7:  Both
Speaker 5:  Acceptable also have been told it's both. So there's a lot of these. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  One of them in recent times is
Speaker 5:  risk five, which is, I would say not a thing
Speaker 5:  that comes up in casual conversation for anyone. Even the people who are
Speaker 5:  working on risk. Five Bryant just walking around the office saying Risk five.
Speaker 5:  I I said it was risk V the other day. All right. I'm sorry. I mean, this
Speaker 5:  is your correction. You got one on me. I, I apologize.
Speaker 5:  I don't know what kind of slash shot nerds are reading it out loud.
Speaker 5:  I mean, you're my people and you're listening and you know, like we have
Speaker 5:  a bond here. You're listening to a podcast in which the word is said out
Speaker 5:  loud. And you, the audience know that I've
Speaker 5:  mispronounced there's something special there. Precious. I I want to protect
Speaker 5:  it. I'm just saying we are the only people who
Speaker 5:  know
Speaker 7:  How do you know they're right and that you aren't now
Speaker 5:  Also spreading the truth also. Good question, Charlie. Am I being gaslit
Speaker 5:  by an internet conspiracy?
Speaker 6:  I would also like to posit that with all Roman
Speaker 6:  numerals. The, the letter and the number are both
Speaker 6:  correct. Like when the iPhone 10 came out and it was the iPhone X,
Speaker 6:  it was the iPhone X. I don't care what anyone said, I got a lot
Speaker 6:  of crap for that. and it was the iPhone X because it was, it was the iPhone
Speaker 6:  and then the letter X you call whatever you want. I, I submit that
Speaker 6:  both should be allowed at all times.
Speaker 5:  So I would, I I I support this. In theory it's Superbowl Excel.
Speaker 6:  Unless it's more than one letter, then well, no,
Speaker 5:  But Super Bowl xl. Like they ob they were like hype for it,
Speaker 6:  Right? Yeah. They did a thing.
Speaker 5:  That's your moment. But I was one of those slash do nerds who was like,
Speaker 5:  it's me was 10, so I'm sorry. Like I, you
Speaker 6:  Know, even though it's not, it's OSX.
Speaker 5:  We got fun. Anyway, that's your correction. I'm just telling you what we,
Speaker 5:  what we share as a group is special and I'm, I'm sorry that I pushed the
Speaker 5:  boundary of it, but I'm also saying no one says these words out loud.
Speaker 5:  It's just not a thing bad and I feel nothing. Charlie
Speaker 7:  XCX has entered the chat.
Speaker 5:  What is the, what is XC, X in numbers?
Speaker 7:  It isn't a real one
Speaker 5:  Isn't C and Roman numeral
Speaker 6:  C is a hundred. So that would be a hundred. It would be 90 and then 10 more.
Speaker 6:  and
Speaker 5:  It allows you to put them in this order.
Speaker 6:  It's just Charlie CI think.
Speaker 5:  I don't know how Roman work.
Speaker 5:  Speaking of things that are bad at math ai,
Speaker 6:  That's true. That's
Speaker 5:  Good. That's good. Big week in the AI landscape.
Speaker 5:  A weird week for me emotionally. I'll explain why in a second. The major
Speaker 5:  labels have sued two AI companies that you may or may not have heard of.
Speaker 5:  UDO and Suno. These are classic Silicon Valley names. We should all be proud.
Speaker 5:  They're music companies, AI music companies. UDO is the company
Speaker 5:  whose tool was used to make B BBL Drizzy. We'll have Charlie explain
Speaker 5:  that entire chain of events. And then Suno has a deal with
Speaker 5:  Microsoft. It's in copilot and You can ask it to giant music in copilot.
Speaker 5:  How would you train an AI tool to make music? You might ask, as
Speaker 5:  did the lawyers at the Recording Industry Association of America. And the
Speaker 5:  answer is you just put a bunch of music in them and you train the
Speaker 5:  model on a bunch of music, including what appears to be and a a
Speaker 5:  remarkable amount of the recording industries music, not just music
Speaker 5:  that's out in the world. The companies are sued. There's a lawsuit.
Speaker 5:  The RAA is mad. The RA is already mad. They
Speaker 5:  say that they asked the companies what was used to train the models. The
Speaker 5:  companies Suno deflected and said their training data was confidential. Business
Speaker 5:  information.
Speaker 5:  Fine. UDO made the same statements. And then Suno also
Speaker 5:  said, our stuff is transformative and designed to generate completely new
Speaker 5:  outputs. Not memorize and regurgitate pre preexisting content.
Speaker 5:  We'll get to that in a second. 'cause that is actually a very funny claim
Speaker 5:  based on what You can do. The Rwa put tracks in lawsuit, which we will
Speaker 5:  listen to. It straightforwardly can just make Johnny be good
Speaker 5:  in a song called Prancing Queen, which is my favorite, which is deeply hilarious.
Speaker 5:  There's just a part of this where these companies knew
Speaker 5:  that what they were doing was training on copyright work and they kind of
Speaker 5:  assumed that they would get away with it or at least be able to like pay
Speaker 5:  the money and move on.
Speaker 6:  Can I ask a, can I ask a very possibly dumb framing question
Speaker 6:  about this? Because I, I want, we're gonna get into the weeds of like a very
Speaker 6:  specific music case, but a lot of what you just described,
Speaker 6:  the sort of basic outlines of like how these companies trained their data
Speaker 6:  and what they're being accused of doing and who's mad
Speaker 6:  feels identical to me to every other conversation we've had about these AI
Speaker 6:  models, right? Like it seems to me that if you change Johnny B. Good
Speaker 6:  and Suno to the New York Times and Chat
Speaker 6:  GPT, we're functionally talking about the same thing. So like, I want to
Speaker 6:  get into the deep into this in, in weird ways, but like, is there something
Speaker 6:  different about the fact that we're doing this with music than the fact the
Speaker 6:  way we've been doing this with like the web for the last year or so?
Speaker 5:  Yes. And it's that The music industry is organized and
Speaker 5:  aggressive when it comes to protecting its rights.
Speaker 6:  So the difference is lawyers,
Speaker 5:  The difference is lawyers and also the, the history of music and the internet
Speaker 5:  is lawyers. Like, the reason I'm so conflicted
Speaker 5:  about this is that I went and became a copyright lawyer because
Speaker 5:  Napster came out when I was in college and I was
Speaker 5:  radicalized because I thought everyone was stupid, which is what
Speaker 5:  should happen when software comes out when you're in college. Yeah. That
Speaker 5:  I, I'm assuming there are some kids out there today who are radicalized by
Speaker 5:  the presence of new software, but that wouldn't, it wasn't for me. It was
Speaker 5:  Napster. I went off and became a copyright attorney. I sucked at it. I don't
Speaker 5:  ever want anyone to think I was good at this as a practicing attorney. I
Speaker 5:  was garbage. But the thing I did was I worked at a law firm that defended
Speaker 5:  other college kids who got sued for using kaza against the RAA
Speaker 5:  and the RIAA was suing college kids and actually
Speaker 5:  suing the universities to get the IP address of the college kids on their
Speaker 5:  networks who were using the tools and then identifying the college students
Speaker 5:  and suing the college students. It was my roommate's computer. It wasn't
Speaker 5:  me. Yeah. I swear this is like a lot, right? That's a lot
Speaker 5:  that, that's just a lot to like the universities are caving and not protecting
Speaker 5:  their, all this stuff is happening and they were running this program at
Speaker 5:  breakeven. They just wanted $5,000 settlements so everyone would be scared
Speaker 5:  and stop doing it. And they won that. That worked sort of,
Speaker 5:  now we're back to it, right? But like the movie industry is
Speaker 5:  not quite as good. It's stopping the Piy as The music industry was. And they
Speaker 5:  ran that program to kind of like shut it down and chill. Napster
Speaker 5:  and Ster and Kaza and all the other ones, they ran Grokster all the way up
Speaker 5:  to the Supreme Court. That decision was, is 20 years old now. The
Speaker 5:  RAA versus ter
Speaker 5:  great. Then they did the iTunes store and they got deals
Speaker 5:  with Steve Jobs and then other music stores and then they did Spotify and
Speaker 5:  Apple Music and streaming. And all along the way they have
Speaker 5:  been extraordinarily litigious and extraordinarily protective of their copyrights
Speaker 5:  because people have an emotional connection to music that they can trade
Speaker 5:  on. This is true in a way that even Hollywood doesn't, like when
Speaker 5:  Disney's like, we must protect the copyright to the Avengers. People are
Speaker 5:  like, go fuck yourself. Like right In a way that The music industry, when
Speaker 5:  it's like you are stealing music, you are making it so artists don't get
Speaker 5:  paid. There's an emotional resonance. That argument tends to have.
Speaker 5:  Charlie, I'm curious how you, how you see that changing over time. But they've
Speaker 5:  been good at it and they've run the playbook over and over and over again.
Speaker 5:  Music is also a closed ecosystem of like four big
Speaker 5:  companies. And so you see things like interpolation where
Speaker 5:  an artist uses a bit of a song from another artist and fans get mad
Speaker 5:  and then writing credits get distributed and money flows inside of a
Speaker 5:  closed ecosystem. None of that is true about the web. None of that is true
Speaker 5:  about the media. So if you are like, are a writer at a media company,
Speaker 5:  nothing like no one cares. Like there's not some big apparatus
Speaker 5:  designed to make it as seem like your work is emotionally resonant and should
Speaker 5:  be protected in the way that The music industry does. So I think that's a
Speaker 5:  huge difference here. The other difference, and this is where I, I really
Speaker 5:  try, I'm very curious for your take here,
Speaker 5:  is that the outputs of these systems are just the
Speaker 5:  songs, right? And they're, the lawsuits are about
Speaker 5:  training, right? All copyright lawsuit. All copyright is dumb. Like
Speaker 5:  it's a dumb legal system because it, it just regulates copies.
Speaker 5:  And so they're like, you made a copy to do this thing and you didn't have
Speaker 5:  the permission to do the thing with the copy that you made. So copyright
Speaker 5:  infringement weird. All computers do is make copies.
Speaker 5:  We've talked about this so many times in the show, so they're not talking
Speaker 5:  about the outputs, but I think the outputs are so convincing.
Speaker 5:  Like in order to get to the thing can just make Johnny be good. It is
Speaker 5:  obvious that you made a copy of Johnny be good. Charlie, what do you
Speaker 5:  think? Man,
Speaker 7:  I feel like The music industry is the one place that copyright becomes part
Speaker 7:  of public conversation in a very frequent way.
Speaker 7:  People talk about when Pharrell is
Speaker 7:  borrowing from Marvin Gaye, people talk about when
Speaker 7:  Steroid to Heaven might be of, might have been copied by another song. People
Speaker 7:  constantly are debating in social media, Hey, you kind of sound like
Speaker 7:  you borrowed this other person's thing. They should get a credit on it.
Speaker 7:  There's no thing in journalism where someone's like, Hey, you know, NELI
Speaker 7:  kind of used someone else's text. Maybe we should give David some extra credit
Speaker 7:  on that piece. That Neli plagiarized. I'm sorry, I'm obviously not accusing
Speaker 7:  you. I
Speaker 5:  Do that all the time. This
Speaker 7:  Is Hypothe. I don't
Speaker 5:  Think you
Speaker 6:  Specifically Neli does that all.
Speaker 5:  I have God mode Google Docs access and I just lift everybody's copy
Speaker 5:  left and right.
Speaker 7:  There's just no other creative industry that where there's this like level
Speaker 7:  of actual infringement that happens that then there is this internal
Speaker 7:  litigious system where these major players are constantly trading credits
Speaker 7:  back and forth and the public is in on it often
Speaker 7:  debating whether or not they're the artists that they
Speaker 7:  stand is making original work. This is part of popular discourse and it happens
Speaker 7:  in music. So it's really different when The music industry
Speaker 7:  is going after AI than if the New York Times is because I've just never
Speaker 7:  been in a circumstance where I'm talking about, that article was completely
Speaker 7:  lifted from this other article, but we constantly talk about is so-and-so
Speaker 7:  writing their own songs.
Speaker 5:  Right. I'll give you a a dumb example from movies. The movie, the
Speaker 5:  Dark Night is basically an interpolation of the movie Heat
Speaker 5:  except with Batman. Yeah. Right. Like many of the shots are the same.
Speaker 5:  Christopher Nolan is out there being like, heat is the greatest cops and
Speaker 5:  robbers movie ever made. Like, I just wanted to make Heat. But with Batman
Speaker 5:  and then you like watch both movies, you're like, oh shit. Like dude just
Speaker 5:  made heat with Batman. Yeah. And that's great. And I think everyone's like,
Speaker 5:  this is the best. Like this is so cool. And then you get to, I don't know,
Speaker 5:  Miley Cyrus is writing flowers, which the lyrics just reference
Speaker 7:  Bruno Mars,
Speaker 5:  Bruno Mars. And people are like, should she have to pay Bruno Mars? It's
Speaker 5:  like, why? Like why like the melodies aren't like they she's just
Speaker 5:  saying some of the same words. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Right. But the expectation
Speaker 5:  is that there, there should be some economic exchange of value. Well,
Speaker 6:  And I, I would, I would think then that the existence of
Speaker 6:  that exchange of value is also how you get to something like this, right?
Speaker 6:  Where it's, it's not just everybody's sort of yelling and then nothing
Speaker 6:  ever happens. It's that we actually have a system by which this
Speaker 6:  gets solved, right? Where, where we have people get songwriting credits and
Speaker 6:  then they get paid for it. And there's like The music industry has built
Speaker 6:  ways for all of this to work and like you said, is
Speaker 6:  very good at picking fights with those who do not play inside of that system.
Speaker 6:  And so like now I'm just thinking, okay, the difference between The music
Speaker 6:  industry and the, the others who are fighting against
Speaker 6:  open AI and others like just groups of authors or whatever, is
Speaker 6:  not only does The music industry have a system by which it understands
Speaker 6:  how everybody is supposed to get paid. That has existed for a long time and
Speaker 6:  everybody kind of sort of understands, but also is
Speaker 6:  able to marshal that whole system against anyone who wants to exist
Speaker 6:  outside of that. And part of what we've been saying forever is like all the
Speaker 6:  money is on the side of the AI companies. Like who, who is going to be able
Speaker 6:  to run a lawsuit against Google all the way to the end
Speaker 6:  and probably aren't that many creative industries other than The music
Speaker 6:  industry that might be able to do it.
Speaker 7:  They've done it before. Yeah. And they have won major concessions. Right?
Speaker 7:  We wouldn't have content id if not for music labels going after YouTube.
Speaker 7:  Right.
Speaker 5:  And they and the music labels have gone after YouTube, right? Universal,
Speaker 5:  this is where Drake gets involved. There's fake Drake that we've, we've talked
Speaker 5:  about endlessly on the show. Shout out to Laser Bong a song that has been
Speaker 5:  just aggressively censored from ev every major platform.
Speaker 5:  Boyd, does TikTok not want electronic music about bongs on its platform?
Speaker 6:  Sue about that. Record labels. Like
Speaker 5:  You want to talk about government censorship? Yeah. All right. The Chinese
Speaker 5:  government is like no bongs for American teens. Just saying it.
Speaker 5:  The piece of that puzzle that's super interesting to me is
Speaker 5:  Universal was mad about fake Drake. They went to Spotify, apple,
Speaker 5:  they said, don't have these, don't have this song. And Spotify and Apple
Speaker 5:  Control the catalogs in their music service, they can pull down YouTube is
Speaker 5:  open access, right? So anyone can upload anything. And then there is continuity
Speaker 5:  and they have these other copyright management systems on YouTube, but it's
Speaker 5:  not the same catalog control where You can just delete the song the way that
Speaker 5:  Spotify and Apple Music could just delete the song. So they had to come up
Speaker 5:  with some other system and YouTube did give the concessions, right? They
Speaker 5:  put out a list of like AI principles that they would work on about safety,
Speaker 5:  about this other stuff. And a lot of it was we are gonna work directly with
Speaker 5:  Universal and the rest of The music industry to figure out what tools are
Speaker 5:  valuable and what tools aren't. And even to allow some creators to like do
Speaker 5:  some of this AI music generation. 'cause we think it's cool and then we'll
Speaker 5:  obviously we'll figure out how to pay them. This is implicit if you're like
Speaker 5:  co announcing that tool with universal music, universal music is gonna
Speaker 5:  get paid. Yes. Like the, the heat death of the universe could occur
Speaker 5:  in Lucian Grange, the CEO of Universal Music would get paid. Like he's good
Speaker 5:  at it. Yes. These two companies did not do that. There's a quote from one
Speaker 5:  of the CEEs and Suno, a Rolling Stone profile from March,
Speaker 5:  and he, he's, he just says to Rolling Stone, if we had deals with the labels
Speaker 5:  when the company got started, I probably wouldn't have invested in it. I
Speaker 5:  think they needed to make this product without the constraints.
Speaker 6:  Wild thing to say out loud. Incredible
Speaker 5:  Thing to say out loud.
Speaker 7:  They said the quiet thing out loud because Yeah. Behind all of this, they
Speaker 7:  haven't ever really quite publicly emitted that they are using copyrighted
Speaker 7:  works. They've talked around that in every way they possibly can without
Speaker 7:  denying it. And this is sort of like the big Yeah, this is the, this is the
Speaker 7:  smoking gun.
Speaker 5:  Right? And then the other smoking gun, and this is the part we should just
Speaker 5:  listen to some of this music is the output of the models themselves. Right.
Speaker 5:  Which is, I mean, let's listen
Speaker 5:  to it and we can talk about it. David, take us through it. Okay.
Speaker 6:  I have, I have brought some sound thank you to Andrew and Liam for getting
Speaker 6:  all of this together. We have three examples
Speaker 6:  and I, I will just roll through all three. Stop me when you have
Speaker 6:  feelings about this. The first thing we'll do is this
Speaker 6:  is just titled Real Chuck Berry in Riverside. So
Speaker 6:  let's just listen to this for a second, by
Speaker 5:  The way, and this is all fair use, no copyright infringement intended. All
Speaker 5:  right. YouTube. All right, go ahead.
Speaker 8:  But he could play a guitar just like a ringing a bell. Go go. Sure.
Speaker 8:  Go,
Speaker 8:  go, go
Speaker 5:  Try. That's enough. Stop it before the robot sensors arrive. Great
Speaker 6:  Song I. love it. Right? I can confirm
Speaker 5:  I love it. If you don't know that song one, go watch Back to the Future.
Speaker 5:  Incredible movie that you should just watch. Yes. And two like Stop, go get
Speaker 5:  cultured. Know what you're
Speaker 7:  Doing. Johnny B. Good. Chuck Berry, founder. Yeah, that's founder. Rock and
Speaker 7:  roll one of them. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And now we have a song from uio, which
Speaker 6:  is not called Johnny B. Good, but just listen
Speaker 8:  Power. Just like a ring. Go, go
Speaker 8:  go, Johnny. Go. Go go. Johnny.
Speaker 8:  Go. Go Johnny. Go.
Speaker 8:  Go.
Speaker 6:  So I mean, it's,
Speaker 5:  So that one is non copyright infringement just on its face. Yeah. Because
Speaker 7:  You can't,
Speaker 5:  You can't, nobody owns this. You can't copyright the AI work.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Okay, so that's one. Next we have a
Speaker 6:  James Brown.
Speaker 5:  Wait, brown. Wait, can we just, I just wanna ask Charlie like a hard question.
Speaker 5:  Charlie's a professor of music at NYUI believe, right? Yes.
Speaker 5:  All right, professor, let's say you didn't have
Speaker 5:  Johnny B. Good in the training data. Yes. But then you had the entire
Speaker 5:  architecture of rock and roll that is built on Johnny B. Good. That's a good
Speaker 5:  question. Yeah. Could you back your way into Johnny B. Good
Speaker 6:  Monkeys and typewriters and Shakespeare, right? Like that's the, is that
Speaker 6:  the, the theory,
Speaker 5:  But like you, you don't need, do you need the seed crystal when you have
Speaker 5:  the whole diamond mine of rock and roll?
Speaker 7:  That's a really good question because, you know, if you look at this era
Speaker 7:  of, of music where r and b rock and roll
Speaker 7:  be are sort of like rockabilly are all kind of one entity. The music is drawing
Speaker 7:  on 12 bar blues, a very standard song structure.
Speaker 7:  They're often in the same keys that play well on guitar. They're using a
Speaker 7:  lot of the same kind of guitar licks. They're mostly using pentatonic scales.
Speaker 7:  They're using a lot of the same language. And you might think, yeah, you
Speaker 7:  could just sort of back into that. But the precise rhythms, the
Speaker 7:  exact words, let's be clear. The copy is worse.
Speaker 7:  It does not sound nearly as good as the real Johnny B. Good. You
Speaker 7:  could never get to that same place without having heard that Johnny B. Good.
Speaker 7:  I feel confident. And if these two songs, one
Speaker 7:  being a real song and the other being nobody owns the copyright and it's
Speaker 7:  made by an ai, if, if there were a copyright case made
Speaker 7:  against the copy, it would definitively lose.
Speaker 7:  I I have many of these cases, many of these music copyright cases are
Speaker 7:  not clear. They're often fought over eight notes,
Speaker 7:  sometimes six notes, sometimes a general feel in the case
Speaker 7:  of blurred lines and got to give it up. This is a
Speaker 7:  direct copy of the Rhythm and the words and most
Speaker 7:  of the melodies. So no, you had to have heard this song in order to
Speaker 7:  make Johnny be good twice.
Speaker 5:  By the way, if you want more on eight notes and how complicated it is. Charlie
Speaker 5:  and I did an entire episode of Decoder pulling that Apart. We'll link that
Speaker 5:  in the show notes somewhere, but let's move on. Let's listen to the next
Speaker 5:  one.
Speaker 6:  It's very good. All right, next up we have James Brown, first Real,
Speaker 6:  James Brown. Wow.
Speaker 8:  How Big Good
Speaker 8:  knew that I
Speaker 8:  knew that I, I mean the classic
Speaker 5:  An A timer, another one where if you're listening to the ver chest And, if
Speaker 5:  you've never heard this song, like, I don't know what you're doing. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Go listen to Switch song. Go it. Exactly. You need it very badly. You're
Speaker 6:  right.
Speaker 5:  Go to school and then come on, come
Speaker 6:  On home. And now we have AI James Brown.
Speaker 8:  Wow. I feel good. I knew
Speaker 5:  Spicy.
Speaker 8:  I feel good.
Speaker 8:  I knew that.
Speaker 8:  So good.
Speaker 6:  Okay, so this one I actually think is very fun because it, it is a little,
Speaker 6:  it's like a little tiny bit further away from it in the way that the first
Speaker 6:  one just is Johnny be good but worse. This one is like one tiny
Speaker 6:  tick. Yeah. This is a further away from being just the thing.
Speaker 5:  This is a lounge band with pretension where everyone's like, just play, just
Speaker 5:  play it the way that, can you stop it? All right. Like, we get it. You,
Speaker 5:  you, you thought you had something. I have one question about this. and it,
Speaker 5:  it actually felt the same way about Johnny B. Good. The way these models
Speaker 5:  work, right? Is you ingest a bunch of data into them. They set a
Speaker 5:  bunch of model weights, and then they like statistically make the next bit,
Speaker 5:  right? They're just sort of like assembling the thing around the prompt,
Speaker 5:  which means they're kind of just assembling ones and zeros to make a sound
Speaker 5:  wave here, which is pretty wild if you think about it. Like that makes sense
Speaker 5:  with words, right? What is statistically the next word in the sentence around
Speaker 5:  this prompt? When you get to like, what are the ones and zeros of a sound
Speaker 5:  file and you get to statistically hear the next ones and zeros. That's pretty
Speaker 5:  weird. It's actually a pretty weird way to, to make an audio recording.
Speaker 5:  And the thing that strikes me about these, this one in particular,
Speaker 5:  but the other one a little bit, the instruments don't sound real at all.
Speaker 5:  To me. Those horns sound so fake. Not like synthesizer fake.
Speaker 5:  No, but almost exactly like what you would expect if you asked a computer
Speaker 5:  to statistically produce a horn section. Mm. Like it's
Speaker 5:  almost played again. You're like, just listen to it. It's so weird.
Speaker 8:  Wow. I feel good. I knew that. I
Speaker 5:  Do you hear how like weird and thin it is? I
Speaker 8:  Knew that I not
Speaker 8:  so good. So good.
Speaker 7:  It doesn't sound like an ensemble of form. It sounds like this weird
Speaker 7:  synthesized thing where the, the beginning of the sound or the end of the
Speaker 7:  sound is exactly lined up. The sound is there's this
Speaker 7:  artifacting quality to it. This is like the pope's jacket version
Speaker 7:  of sound. Yes. Where it's like you got it close, but all the
Speaker 7:  lines are wrong. Why does he have seven fingers? Right. It's
Speaker 5:  A, it's it's a statistical approximation of a hand, right? Yeah. But as expressed
Speaker 5:  as a horn section, which is really weird to like just on its face and You
Speaker 5:  can, you know, people are like, it'll get better and blah, blah blah. But
Speaker 5:  like You can act, to me, You can hear a meaningful difference
Speaker 5:  once you know what you're listening for and it's like, oh, this is
Speaker 5:  a fake instrument. It's not a and it's not a fake instrument. The way it's
Speaker 5:  synthesizer is a fake instrument. Right. It's just fake. Like it doesn't,
Speaker 5:  it doesn't make any sense over
Speaker 7:  The top all of all of it. Right? Now, I don't know if this is a solvable
Speaker 7:  problem. I imagine it probably is is that everything sounds kind of
Speaker 7:  grainy. There's like, there's this top level hiss kind of over the entire
Speaker 7:  recording of any AI output. It sounds maybe equivalent
Speaker 7:  to neli those Fios that you were not downloading
Speaker 7:  in college, but like the really low bit rate MP
Speaker 7:  threes when mp threes were actually noticeably worse. Yeah. That's what these
Speaker 7:  sound like. All of them have this artificial sheen on top
Speaker 7:  that sound very lo-fi. Yeah. In addition to artificial instruments.
Speaker 5:  Just a side note, I can't listen to the song in between days by the Cure
Speaker 5:  without mentally inserting the weird
Speaker 5:  compression artifacts at the high end. 'cause I listened to a shit MP three
Speaker 5:  of that song so many times that the symbols are just forever distorted in
Speaker 5:  my brain.
Speaker 7:  There there's literally a plugin and guitar pedal called Lossy
Speaker 7:  that is made to recreate the sound of early
Speaker 7:  two thousands MP threes. That's
Speaker 5:  Very good. So if you
Speaker 7:  Need it, I can run it for philosophy.
Speaker 5:  It's the older millennial button basically. Exactly. Yeah. So that's the
Speaker 5:  sound. Yeah. Talk about the actual music here. Is this right?
Speaker 5:  Would trying to be good? You're like, that's straight copy infringement.
Speaker 5:  This is weird, right? It's like slant rhyme. Yeah. What do you think?
Speaker 7:  I think that it's the exact same rhythms.
Speaker 7:  I'd have to look at the notes. I think they're quite close. They're the exact,
Speaker 7:  if they're in, maybe they're in a different key, but they're like the same
Speaker 7:  intervals moving in the same direction at the exact same time. That
Speaker 7:  would almost certainly lose in court if these
Speaker 7:  were, again, if I should be clear, the AI companies are not
Speaker 7:  being sued for the output. Yep. But these outputs, if you were to try to
Speaker 7:  make a case, I'm sure a judge would rule in favor of the
Speaker 7:  James Brown estate because it is the same line.
Speaker 7:  Well, it's more or less the same line. It's an interpolation of the line.
Speaker 7:  There's slightly different words, but it's the same rhythms, same melody
Speaker 7:  that almost always is going to, that's always gonna win. And
Speaker 5:  Here the the output is proof of the input. Right.
Speaker 6:  They're, they're not suing for the output. That's right. But the output seems
Speaker 6:  unusually important here in that respect. That it's, it's like
Speaker 6:  if, if UDO is doing the thing that it claimed to be doing,
Speaker 6:  which is, which is transforming stuff into other stuff,
Speaker 6:  we have a very different kind of fair use case. But reading through the RA's
Speaker 6:  lawsuit, like the thing they did over and over and over was just go reproduce
Speaker 6:  songs that exist in the world. Yeah. And that's how we're fighting about
Speaker 6:  training. Yeah. Like I, I went through and pulled a bunch of the prompts
Speaker 6:  that they used to get songs. We did the
Speaker 7:  Same
Speaker 6:  Thing. They're they're so funny. They're so funny. Like to
Speaker 6:  get to get the Green Day song, I think it was American Idiot. The
Speaker 6:  prompt is Pop punk, American Alternative Rock, California 2004, Rob
Speaker 6:  cyo. Perfect.
Speaker 5:  To get and the, and that produced a Pastiche of American idiot.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  Amazing.
Speaker 6:  To Get My Girl By The Temptations. It was my tempting 1964 girl
Speaker 6:  Smokey Sing Hitsville Soul Pop Got My Girl by the Temptations.
Speaker 6:  This one you'll enjoy Neli to get All I want for Christmas is you by Mariah
Speaker 6:  Carey, my girl. The prompt is Mariah Carey. But with
Speaker 6:  a space between each letter so that it's not, 'cause presumably these things
Speaker 5:  Are trained because it's pronouns, artist
Speaker 6:  Names. So it's m space, a space all the way through the name Contemporary.
Speaker 6:  That's
Speaker 5:  I spell Holiday
Speaker 6:  A Grammy Award-winning American singer songwriter, remarkable vocal range
Speaker 6:  that produced all in What for Christmas is you. I mean, there's,
Speaker 5:  There's of, so it's what they're proving is that it's instead by the way,
Speaker 5:  the argument in response that I'm sure we're gonna hear, because this is
Speaker 5:  the argument opening AI made about the Times lawsuit was one, no human
Speaker 5:  prompts like this and B, these prompts are so weird. They represent a hack
Speaker 5:  of our system, which is remarkable. But I'm
Speaker 5:  confident based on how open AI replied to the times that that is what these
Speaker 5:  companies
Speaker 6:  Were reply to. There is one very good one that the prompt was create
Speaker 6:  a song by an artist that rhymes with truce string bean that produced a Bruce
Speaker 6:  Springsteen song. That's
Speaker 5:  Very good. It's fantastic. So, so that question I asked Charlie about the,
Speaker 5:  do you, if you have the entire history of rock and roll, do you need the
Speaker 5:  first song right Or do you need Chuck Berry? Okay, maybe you don't,
Speaker 5:  maybe you do. Right? Like I think this third example is the
Speaker 5:  funniest example because I can't figure how you would get to this
Speaker 5:  without specifically one thing. Go ahead, David.
Speaker 6:  I'm glad you agree because I left this for last for precisely this reason.
Speaker 6:  So here is, I won't even spoil it. Here's the real one.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, okay. Right.
Speaker 5:  Everybody's
Speaker 6:  Heard it a million times. That's our boy, that's our boy jd
Speaker 7:  The longest lasting digital career that I never expected to happen.
Speaker 5:  No.
Speaker 5:  And
Speaker 6:  And here, here is the ai, I I just wanna say this was created by a
Speaker 6:  prompt on UDO. This is in theory a completely synthetic
Speaker 6:  new work of art.
Speaker 6:  Oh, it's so good.
Speaker 5:  It does sound like a Jason Derulo song. Like my critique of Yes. Does this
Speaker 5:  sound like real music aside?
Speaker 6:  It's even got the little like vocal riff at the end. Like it's, it's it's
Speaker 6:  red.
Speaker 5:  Like does Jason Derulo sound like sympathetic music?
Speaker 5:  That's your problem.
Speaker 7:  This one's interesting though because you know, Nila, you've talked a lot
Speaker 7:  about the issue that likeness is not copyrightable, right? Yeah. And so
Speaker 7:  there there's a question of like, if, you know, we we're going back to this
Speaker 7:  hypothetical, there is no suit that's suing over this particular Jason
Speaker 7:  Derulo riff. Someone could just, I could say Jason Doo on a
Speaker 7:  song probably, and it's not, you can't copyright that.
Speaker 5:  So you Wait, hold on, hold on. Oh, this is weird. So these tags, did
Speaker 6:  We, we have this fight the last time with the Metro Boomin tag
Speaker 5:  Yes. With the Metro Boomin song. So Metro Boomin's producer tag was the
Speaker 5:  copyrightable expression in the fake Drake song.
Speaker 7:  If it's exactly, if it's exactly the recording of the tag though,
Speaker 7:  right? Because it's, it's, it was, the issue was that they actually kept
Speaker 7:  in the sample of the producer tag and
Speaker 7:  and reproducing a recording. You can copyright that. So
Speaker 6:  We could start every episode of The Vergecast with Neli singing Jason Derule,
Speaker 6:  Jason
Speaker 7:  Daro and get away
Speaker 5:  With, and we'll,
Speaker 7:  I think he probably would have a lot of issues, a lot of nasty letters
Speaker 5:  Into you. I'm saying in terms of ways to boost this podcast profile after
Speaker 5:  13 years, Jason Daro suing us is high on my list.
Speaker 7:  That's wonderful. But, but this definitely proves that like you had to have
Speaker 7:  had access. There is no monkeys in the back writing Shakespeare that ends
Speaker 7:  up on Jason Daro. It just doesn't happen. It's not possible.
Speaker 5:  Actually, I don't know. I think if you, if you took the worst impulses of
Speaker 5:  The music industry and fed them into an ai, you might produce Jason
Speaker 5:  Daro.
Speaker 7:  This one's also important though because everything else we've heard has
Speaker 7:  been written by artists pre Copyright
Speaker 7:  Act of 1974 and probably also reflects some of maybe who
Speaker 7:  the lawyers are writing these, you know, these cases because
Speaker 7:  you know, we're talking about the cases reference Frank Sinatra.
Speaker 7:  Right. And to bring in Bruce Springsteen actually
Speaker 7:  that's
Speaker 5:  Like 74, right? It's like Springsteen, Maria, Mariah Carey, green Day Johnny
Speaker 5:  or Chuck Berry.
Speaker 7:  The early ones are all Chuck Berry like the Temptations.
Speaker 7:  Right.
Speaker 5:  Are you getting it? Judges are
Speaker 7:  Old. I'm seeing everyone. Yeah. And, and that's actually potentially very
Speaker 7:  advantageous and knowing the judge and who you might go in front of, but
Speaker 7:  then to show that also they're taking all the latest music as well. Sure.
Speaker 7:  We're we're bringing in Jason Dillo. Yes. Like,
Speaker 5:  Judge, have you heard Your Honor, are you familiar with Jason Dillo?
Speaker 7:  I wanna bring Jason Dillo into the courtroom. Jason Dillo,
Speaker 5:  By the way, another total side note. There's an incredible Katie and Apollos
Speaker 5:  piece about hardcore Jason Duro stands and what their
Speaker 5:  stand culture is like that I will dig up and put in the show notes.
Speaker 7:  Oh my gosh, that sounds fun.
Speaker 5:  It's truly one of the funniest things I've ever read on the internet. Just
Speaker 5:  because A, it exists and B, because Katie is good at finding things like
Speaker 5:  that, that exist.
Speaker 7:  Have you all tried running these prompts by the way?
Speaker 5:  No. Have you?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. You can go to uio and to Suno and You can run the prompts that
Speaker 7:  the, that these lawsuits are alleging. And you don't get the
Speaker 7:  same songs obviously. But like if you write Make a jazz crooner song
Speaker 7:  about New York baritone voice, you will definitely get it's Frank
Speaker 7:  Sinatra. There's just like, there's no other song with Frank Sin. I don't
Speaker 7:  think that that really is hacking the systems. It, it's really
Speaker 7:  easy. The other thing I get a lot, by the way are
Speaker 7:  random prompt, Hey, that sounds strangely like Crazy
Speaker 7:  Town by Butterfly. My prompt was actually, I
Speaker 7:  tried to make a rap about American founder Thomas Jefferson
Speaker 5:  Butterfly by Crazy Town. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Crazy. Yeah. Sorry. Thank you. Butterfly by Crazy.
Speaker 5:  If there's a band called Butterfly that had a song called Crazy Town that
Speaker 5:  would be perfect
Speaker 7:  In another universe. So I a ud
Speaker 5:  I'm sure there is.
Speaker 7:  I tried to, I tried, I did try to hack these systems a little bit
Speaker 7:  and I wrote, I want you to write a rap about American founder
Speaker 7:  Thomas Jefferson about not throwing away his shot nasal male
Speaker 7:  rapper Boom Bap. And what I got was basically Butterfly by Crazy Town.
Speaker 5:  Just like total random.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But
Speaker 5:  Tom,
Speaker 9:  Jeff never slept Constitution slave on
Speaker 9:  hip.
Speaker 9:  Oh God.
Speaker 5:  I'm so, I'm I'm sorry Ted, I'm sorry for listening to this. And we
Speaker 5:  suggest you
Speaker 7:  Really is Butterfly by Crazy Town. I think it's also a little bit of a, what
Speaker 7:  was that song? Superman?
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 9:  Oh
Speaker 7:  Wow. Who, who's Superman by
Speaker 5:  Three Doors Down. I'll be Your Kryptonite or whatever. kp. That was horrible
Speaker 7:  Kryptonite. Yeah, kryptonite. Three doors down. Is that who? It's by three
Speaker 7:  doors down. It
Speaker 5:  Is by three doors
Speaker 7:  Down. Oh's got a little bit of that. It's just You can so easily
Speaker 7:  hear references that are not even the thing that you prompt. And I just,
Speaker 7:  I have to say that if you, right now, if you go to the homepage
Speaker 7:  of UDO, the two most popular tracks are exact
Speaker 7:  sound alikes of Eminem and Snoop Dogg. So people are doing this
Speaker 7:  like people are trying to make sound alikes.
Speaker 5:  So the argument from all these companies is, look, training is fair use.
Speaker 5:  And that's the argument for open ai. That's the argument for Google. It's
Speaker 5:  the argument for Suno and UDO, the
Speaker 5:  organization of these cases is different because the plaintiffs are different.
Speaker 5:  Right. The New York Times is situated differently than the major labels.
Speaker 5:  People have different emotional relationships with different kinds of work.
Speaker 5:  But this is the argument, like when Google eventually goes and Sues opening
Speaker 5:  eye for training on YouTube, the weirdness of that argument is Google
Speaker 5:  telling open ai, the training on YouTube is not fair. Like that's
Speaker 5:  what's gonna happen here. Mm. It's all the same argument and it's all kind
Speaker 5:  of in a circle.
Speaker 7:  Wait. So Google can do it in its fair use, but Suno and UIO cannot
Speaker 7:  do it because it's not fair use. This is,
Speaker 5:  This is the trap the industry has set for itself
Speaker 7:  And our giant, what's
Speaker 5:  That line consolidated? Yeah. Right. It's like it's all the same VCs and
Speaker 5:  all in all different directions kind
Speaker 7:  Of like the music business.
Speaker 5:  That's true. There's that line though that's like, you have to be perfect
Speaker 5:  every time and I just have to get through once. Mm.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's like I can't, I don't remember exactly what it's, that's what, it's
Speaker 5:  the
Speaker 6:  Hacker creed, right? Like, you have to stop me every time. All I have to
Speaker 6:  do is I just have to get through once. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And that is, that feels like the copyright situation for
Speaker 5:  AI right now. This is a house of cards and
Speaker 5:  maybe, maybe the Times will win, maybe the
Speaker 5:  record labels will win Mary, maybe Sarah Silverman will win. Like
Speaker 5:  there are so many of these, maybe Google and Open Eye reach
Speaker 5:  an agreement about training on YouTube and then a bunch of YouTube creators
Speaker 5:  sue and maybe they win. Like You can just game it out a hundred
Speaker 5:  different ways. The at some point someone is gonna win a lawsuit that says
Speaker 5:  training is not fair use. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  The fair use argument here, I feel like is notable, I feel like
Speaker 7:  is quite different than what the New York Times can claim. Because
Speaker 7:  part of fair use is for example, the effect on the potential market.
Speaker 7:  Right. And with New York Times, they're gonna have to argue, well,
Speaker 7:  you know, you're using our articles and other people are taking
Speaker 7:  that and creating texts and putting it on other pseudo journalistic sites.
Speaker 7:  Right.
Speaker 5:  I I, I'm, I'm pretty sure the time's assuming for both the output and the
Speaker 5:  training.
Speaker 7:  I see. Okay.
Speaker 5:  So I I I think these cases are all different. This is what I mean, like the,
Speaker 5:  the strategy for one doesn't work for all of them in the same way. Right?
Speaker 7:  Right. In the case of music, the marketplace argument like does is it
Speaker 7:  going to affect the marketplace? Is I I think they have a very strong argument
Speaker 7:  here. I think the RIA has a very strong argument. They're basically saying
Speaker 7:  Suno, nio, you are charging users money to make songs
Speaker 7:  that you are allowing them to upload to the exact same place where we
Speaker 7:  also have all of our songs and to Spotify, apple Music, et cetera. And so
Speaker 7:  you are actually changing the marketplace for music,
Speaker 7:  having used all of this output. But is that, is that not part of the argument
Speaker 7:  you're saying?
Speaker 5:  I I think we have to find out how that shakes out.
Speaker 7:  Right?
Speaker 5:  Like I, I don't know. They gotta get assigned a judge, right?
Speaker 5:  Like Right, right now what they've done is they've put out a complaint and
Speaker 5:  a press release. There hasn't been a reply to that complaint or an answer.
Speaker 5:  They haven't been assigned a judge. Like they haven't done any discovery.
Speaker 5:  Like we just don't know a bunch of stuff. And we certainly don't know where
Speaker 5:  they're gonna put their focus. But that part where copyright law
Speaker 5:  is just about making copies and in the history of computing, every single
Speaker 5:  copy has been litigated down to, again, I bring it up, I think I
Speaker 5:  bring it up every time. MAI versus peak systems. You go look it up. This
Speaker 5:  is, are you a third party software seller
Speaker 5:  allowed to load software into a computer's memory without permission?
Speaker 5:  Crazy. A co a crazy court case. Yeah. Can you put a disc in a computer
Speaker 5:  and load software from the disc to the hard drive without my permission got
Speaker 5:  litigated and they lost crazy. And they lost. And then we had to get all
Speaker 5:  the way through caching our ephemeral copies on your
Speaker 5:  ISPs network equipment or those copies that should be
Speaker 5:  litigated. This is copyright, it's dumb. Like it is a very
Speaker 5:  dumb rationale, but it litigates the creation of copies. So
Speaker 5:  here it's did you have permission to make a
Speaker 5:  copy to train your model of all these songs and e
Speaker 5:  every time you didn't have permission. By the way, we want the statutory
Speaker 5:  maximum of $150,000, which essentially ends up being a
Speaker 5:  pretend amount of money. It
Speaker 7:  It's gotta be bigger than the US GDP.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's like crazy, right? Like, did you have permission to copy every
Speaker 5:  song in the world, And if you didn't, every song in the world times $150,000.
Speaker 5:  What we're asking for,
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna run this
Speaker 5:  If you didn't have that permission, can we do an analysis that says that
Speaker 5:  use is fair use? Right. So fair use is what's called an affirmative
Speaker 5:  defense to copyright infringement. Where you, you, you admit it like I did,
Speaker 5:  I did it. But under this other rationale, it's That's fine. And
Speaker 5:  so that's like the winding path here is,
Speaker 5:  well first they won't even cop to having made the copies, which
Speaker 5:  is why The music industry is putting out, well here's just Johnny be good.
Speaker 5:  Like you can't output Johnny be good unless you copy Johnny be good on the,
Speaker 5:  on the front end. Right. Okay. So first we gotta get them to cop to making
Speaker 5:  the copies at all, which they claim is proprietary business information.
Speaker 5:  Sure. Then it's was that copy allowed,
Speaker 5:  they obviously didn't have permission. This is why they're in a lawsuit.
Speaker 5:  And then it, and then it's, is it fair use? And then we run the analysis
Speaker 5:  and the analysis is like the purpose and character of the use, the amount
Speaker 5:  of the use, the nature of the use, the, and then the last
Speaker 5:  factor is the effect on the market. Right? On the output side. I think the
Speaker 5:  market argument is really strong.
Speaker 7:  Right? Right. So the question is, 'cause this case, this is something I actually
Speaker 7:  don't understand, maybe You can explain with your copyright law degree.
Speaker 7:  Can, can, is there like some wall between the input and the
Speaker 7:  output in, in this argument that says, well, there's no
Speaker 7:  marketplace for, you
Speaker 5:  Know, that emoji, it's like this with the hands. Yeah, it's the hands are
Speaker 5:  up. Like I'm just that emoji right now. I
Speaker 7:  Don't know because, because I was trying to say, oh, well if there's a clear
Speaker 7:  change in the marketplace for songs, which are all outputs, but it sounds
Speaker 7:  like, you know, we don't know what the responses are gonna be, but they could
Speaker 7:  say, well there isn't currently a marketplace for training data in this kind
Speaker 7:  of way. And so it's not affecting that marketplace. But
Speaker 5:  If you, there will never be a market if you just set the rate at zero.
Speaker 5:  Right? Right. So if you're like, I want really high quality
Speaker 5:  music for my high quality music AI program,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna go pay a bunch of artists, but then these guys come along and
Speaker 5:  steal it. Like you've just, you've actually preemptively destroyed the market.
Speaker 5:  Sure. You've never allowed that market to set some rates. And I've heard
Speaker 5:  from publishers who are taking the deals with opening AI disclosure of Vox
Speaker 5:  Media has a content licensing deal with opening ai.
Speaker 5:  I've heard from other publishers, not our company, that one of the reasons
Speaker 5:  they've taken these deals is to create that market, right? Hmm.
Speaker 5:  So that the times can go to court and say, this has an effect on the market.
Speaker 5:  Look at this market. Hmm. Look at the money that's moving around.
Speaker 5:  And so some of these publishers are, are playing kind of a strategic game
Speaker 5:  to say we should create a market to help that factor along. I think that's
Speaker 5:  fascinating. Hmm. The, but I don't think that the AI company,
Speaker 5:  I think they thought they could just buy forgiveness. And what's crazy
Speaker 5:  to me is when it was Napster or YouTube or Google search,
Speaker 5:  even buying forgiveness worked because people liked the companies,
Speaker 5:  they liked the products, they liked the experiences they were having. And
Speaker 5:  here people, I mean I'm con you, if you're listening to
Speaker 5:  this and you have a, a very different view of this, lemme know, but our audience
Speaker 5:  is pretty loud with us that they don't like these companies and they don't,
Speaker 5:  they, they perceive this as a moral problem. And I,
Speaker 5:  I think that's just a very different position for them all to be in.
Speaker 7:  Which brings us to your moral quandary. It seems like you flipped sides from
Speaker 7:  20 years ago.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The idea that I'm sitting here being like the RIA has a point is crazy.
Speaker 5:  Like I, it's bananas and Sarah j and I have been like all day,
Speaker 5:  every day like slacking or like who have we become, you know, this
Speaker 5:  is like the horseshoe theory of copyright law, politics.
Speaker 5:  It's weird, man. And I, I think one of the pieces of the puzzle, and
Speaker 5:  I'm curious how you see this in The music industry itself, Charlie, one of
Speaker 5:  the pieces of the puzzle here is that the internet just blew the
Speaker 5:  bottom outta The music industry. Like there's no, there's no
Speaker 5:  way to be like a middle class musician anymore. There's no guaranteed way
Speaker 5:  to make money. You're like, you're playing the same algorithmic game as everyone
Speaker 5:  else. You're beholden to some labels. You don't have any power as an individual
Speaker 5:  against these platforms. So now this next group of people who's
Speaker 5:  come and taking your work for free and is gonna extract value
Speaker 5:  from you, well sure. Like the enemy of my enemy
Speaker 5:  is my friend. It's, it's kind of the vibe. But I'm wondering if you see that
Speaker 5:  reflected in the actual music industry.
Speaker 7:  Absolutely. I mean, the public perception here is so different than what
Speaker 7:  was happening back in the Napster era. Back in the Napster era, the labels
Speaker 7:  were enemy number one. Selling out to labels was, was a big, you know,
Speaker 7:  they were, they were, they were the worst players Today. I actually think
Speaker 7:  they've done a very effective job of using their proxy Spotify and let
Speaker 7:  Spotify be the enemy. And everyone's like Sony Music. Who are they? Like
Speaker 7:  Warner, UMG. Like they labeled deal, but they are not, they, they're not
Speaker 7:  the topic of conversation of who's really screwing who now they basically
Speaker 7:  help set the rates of what gets paid out in streaming. and it's the
Speaker 7:  distributors now that really are taking all the heat. And so they're actually
Speaker 7:  in a better, I think, place of public perception in terms of within The music
Speaker 7:  industry. I, I see songwriters, producers,
Speaker 7:  fans totally freaked out about what's going on. When you go and
Speaker 7:  scan through a lot of the, the YouTube comments of some of these
Speaker 7:  AI songs. The, the sentiment is we are
Speaker 7:  screwed. Music is over. I give up. I am not learning an
Speaker 7:  instrument. Like it's, it's sort of, it, it is not, the future is
Speaker 7:  bright. We're gonna create new beautiful music. Like my creativity is
Speaker 7:  going to blossom. I think that there is a, a real existential fear
Speaker 7:  that is exists within all of the, you know, the AI world. But you're, you're
Speaker 7:  getting into like our human emotions and the beautiful creative output, hopefully
Speaker 7:  beautiful. I mean, listen how you feel about pop music,
Speaker 5:  Whatever Jason Deru
Speaker 7:  Don't bring Jason into this.
Speaker 5:  We gotta get Dar on the po I
Speaker 7:  Don't really do,
Speaker 6:  That's obviously like reading through the RIAs lawsuit like that is, they
Speaker 6:  talk about the creativity and, and human emotion of it all. Yes.
Speaker 6:  But is the, is the end of this just they're trying to get
Speaker 6:  checks in the same way that there are absolutely lot, lot of folks out there
Speaker 6:  just trying to get checks. Like, well, 'cause part of me, like I I think
Speaker 6:  obviously that's the answer. But also part of me wonders if the labels are
Speaker 6:  feeling the same way that you do, which is that, oh, this is not just a thing
Speaker 6:  we need to make money off of tomorrow. This is like an existential crisis
Speaker 6:  for our business down the road. Or if they're like, whatever, this is just
Speaker 6:  a new turn, we have to make sure we get paid.
Speaker 7:  This is an existential crisis because they are already losing market share
Speaker 7:  to, you know, people who are not on major labels. But major label
Speaker 7:  listening is down. Hmm. Right. As an overall share of all
Speaker 7:  listening. It's still a lot of it, still the majority of listening. But
Speaker 7:  so they recognize that flooding the streamers with more and more
Speaker 7:  independent music has not necessarily been good for their business. And with
Speaker 7:  more flooding, it's just going to bring everything down to everything as
Speaker 7:  valueless entirely. If you own music and it gets played a lot on
Speaker 7:  streaming, there's a lot of money in it. Like there's
Speaker 7:  billions and billions and billions of dollars in streaming. How it's distributed
Speaker 7:  is not always fair. And people get upset about this, but they very much need
Speaker 7:  to figure out how to, how, how, how to enter and participate in this marketplace.
Speaker 7:  And I think kind of like a content ID system, they want to figure out how
Speaker 7:  to properly license. You wanna use Jason Daros voice? Jason Daro says yes
Speaker 7:  and it costs this and now we've got Jason Dollo copies and that's okay by
Speaker 5:  The way, of all of the artists who would let his voice go deepfake to make
Speaker 5:  like commercials. Jason
Speaker 7:  Dillo. Yeah. Jason
Speaker 5:  Dollo. Look, I, it's, I'm not, I'm not even saying I've, I've talked a lot
Speaker 5:  of Jason Dillo related ish on this episode. I'm aware of it. I just
Speaker 5:  know that he is a commercial mastermind.
Speaker 7:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  Like that man's gonna make a bag no matter what happens. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Friend of the pod, Blake Reed, he is a professor at Colorado Law, teaches
Speaker 5:  copyright, telecom, all this stuff. He wrote me a note
Speaker 5:  last week or the week before and he sent me really smart that I've been thinking
Speaker 5:  about. And it's related to what you're saying, David, copyright
Speaker 5:  law is like a economic system, right? We create
Speaker 5:  scarcity and then we can like charge money for things. 'cause you're not
Speaker 5:  allowed to just like freely copy them. So if you do something bad in the
Speaker 5:  world of copyright law, the answer is you pay money and you
Speaker 5:  fix it. And you, you even out the economic problem that you've created,
Speaker 5:  right? Olivia Rodrigo might have sung four
Speaker 5:  notes of a Taylor Swift song. The answer is Taylor Swift gets a writing credit
Speaker 5:  and then some money flows to Taylor Swift. And that is the end of that story.
Speaker 5:  Right? And it's just an economic problem that you've solved by redistributing
Speaker 5:  money. AI is a moral problem. This is the thing Blake pointed out to me is
Speaker 5:  like, the money doesn't solve the perceived moral issue here. So the labels
Speaker 5:  might get paid, they might find some business model that lets some license
Speaker 5:  the music into perpetuity or whatever. But the thing you're seeing in the
Speaker 5:  YouTube comments, the thing our audience is feeling, the thing I think a
Speaker 5:  lot of artists are feeling does not get solved by money. Right? It
Speaker 5:  it, it's like another problem. And so like you, you see these deals come
Speaker 5:  up and get signed and whatever, and everyone's like, eh, it's still pretty
Speaker 5:  icky. Right? And there, there's something there that I think is important.
Speaker 5:  I haven't quite puzzled it out. I actually want to do something with
Speaker 5:  that idea. If you have further thoughts, let me know what you think about
Speaker 5:  it. But that gap is the gap, right? We can move
Speaker 5:  a bunch of money around like the VCs in Hollywood and
Speaker 5:  the recording in in Streets Association of America. God bless them, they
Speaker 5:  will move the money around. Lucian Grange will get paid.
Speaker 5:  Is that gonna solve the other problem? Right? Like and that's, I think that's
Speaker 5:  really hard. Well,
Speaker 7:  There's two things that musicians need to not fear. One is that because
Speaker 7:  the output of all of these models cannot be copywritten, this
Speaker 7:  music is kind of in this weird limbo space. Like maybe it's gonna def
Speaker 7:  it will definitely find some streams, but it probably won't be synced on
Speaker 7:  television and film because no TV producer is gonna wanna
Speaker 7:  have a song where they like, don't really understand the rights associated
Speaker 7:  with that song. And if they have the right to it. And does it also secretly
Speaker 7:  contain a vocal sample of James Brown that has been stolen. Like
Speaker 7:  so nobody wants to, any rights holder doesn't want to use this music that
Speaker 7:  can't be used in a weird way. So I think composers and people who are putting
Speaker 7:  stuff on TV, in film, I think that they're still very much a business for
Speaker 7:  them until these much bigger legal issues get sorted out
Speaker 7:  the other places that music is about human connection. And I don't say this
Speaker 7:  in some like wishy-washy way. It's like there is no fandom
Speaker 7:  for Olivia Rodrigo without an Olivia Rodrigo. Like you need the person. The
Speaker 7:  time that The music industry tried to create like an avatar
Speaker 7:  racially strangely coded, what
Speaker 7:  was that guy's name? It was terrible. They tried to do like their NFT
Speaker 7:  avatar pop star and it was an utter failure both because it
Speaker 7:  was completely racist and because why would we develop a relationship to
Speaker 7:  this thing? And so the the fandom side, the pop stardom side of pop
Speaker 7:  music, I don't think is ever gonna go away. What
Speaker 5:  About uni miko, right? Isn't that she's, she's like the cartoon
Speaker 5:  character. I just learned that she's officially code named
Speaker 5:  CVO one.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. There are the, there are these avatar characters that are finding some
Speaker 7:  fandoms online. Yes, that's gonna happen. I'd still just like that doesn't,
Speaker 7:  that's not Olivia, that's not Taylor, that's not Gaga. I'm sorry.
Speaker 7:  It's just different. All
Speaker 5:  Right, we gotta end it. They're not Jason Deo. They're
Speaker 7:  Not Jason Deo.
Speaker 5:  Like the bar is like, can your cartoon character defeat Jason Derulo?
Speaker 5:  I'll take it. That's a good place to end it. Charlie, thank you so much for
Speaker 5:  joining the show. I suspect you're gonna be back on the show quite a bit
Speaker 5:  as these cases wind their way through the courts. Anytime. All
Speaker 6:  Obviously I would say
Speaker 6:  copies it, Arthur gets a little bit less solid.
Speaker 5:  All right, we gotta do a lightning round. There's a lot of gadgets. There's
Speaker 5:  basically two gadget lightning rounds. Yeah, let's start three
Speaker 5:  phone events announced in quick succession here. So Samsung announced
Speaker 5:  unpacked, it's looking like July July 10th. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Weeks. We expecting some foldables surprise pixel
Speaker 5:  nine announcement from Google in August and then Motorola just had an event
Speaker 5:  and announced the 2024 razors. So
Speaker 6:  Lot knows it doesn't get to announce an event, it just has to tell you what
Speaker 6:  phones there're at.
Speaker 5:  Well it had like a big influencer like I don't think we went 'cause we already
Speaker 5:  had the phones, but like it had like a big influencer
Speaker 5:  launch event with some of the funniest photos of like very cool
Speaker 5:  influencers looking extremely bored with like very
Speaker 5:  colorful razor phones. We can get to that in a minute.
Speaker 6:  Sounds right.
Speaker 5:  This is pretty early in the cycle for a bunch of phone launches.
Speaker 6:  It is weird. I've been trying to figure out what's going on and it's very
Speaker 6:  clear that the, the AI race is now
Speaker 6:  happening to everybody else. Where I think the thing that is happening
Speaker 6:  is everybody is just announcing like the same set of 12 features
Speaker 6:  and the same new hardware that does the same new stuff. Like
Speaker 6:  Apple is copying, Google is copying, Samsung is copying Apple. And so now
Speaker 6:  there's this incredible race to just be the first one to say it out loud.
Speaker 6:  And I think especially on Android there, there's just
Speaker 6:  going to be so much like AI sameness over the next 12
Speaker 6:  months as they all rush to do everything they can think of. So the goal I
Speaker 6:  think especially is to beat Apple. Like to me this Google thing
Speaker 6:  is so transparently just doing this sooner
Speaker 6:  in order to say all the words out loud about what your camera can do before
Speaker 6:  Apple says those same words out loud about what its camera can do.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, what what, so what's interesting, well let's start with Google. What's
Speaker 5:  fascinating to me about Google is they just shook up those
Speaker 5:  teams. So Rick Oslow who had all of hardware
Speaker 5:  now has all of it including Android.
Speaker 5:  That's a complicated switch up, right?
Speaker 5:  So it like the Pixel team, their boss now runs Android
Speaker 5:  or their old boss now on Android, they got a new boss. And the big question
Speaker 5:  for Google this whole time has been are you gonna do, are you gonna try?
Speaker 5:  Are you gonna try hard? And like the thing that has kept them from trying
Speaker 5:  hard is they have to maintain the Android ecosystem in the United States.
Speaker 5:  That's mostly expressed to Samsung. Like you just gotta keep Samsung happy
Speaker 5:  around the world or many more players. And Android is expressed very
Speaker 5:  differently, but if like the Pixel guy like Rick
Speaker 5:  is like, I'm doing it with the Pixel and that's his first move
Speaker 5:  is the boss of Android. Weird. It is just weird I think. I think
Speaker 5:  that's weird. It's like that shakeup is weird. And then on top of that,
Speaker 5:  I think Google really wants AI to be the differentiator for Pixel. Oh yeah,
Speaker 5:  right. That big vertically integrated, like only Google can do all this stuff
Speaker 5:  at every layer of the stack. We build our own chips like da da, like all
Speaker 5:  the way you want to do that with Pixel so You can body up against the fund.
Speaker 5:  So a really just weird spot for Google to be in
Speaker 6:  It is, and it feels like Google is
Speaker 6:  trying to do the same thing to both Samsung and Apple, but can only
Speaker 6:  say that it's trying to do it to Apple, which is basically like I, I think
Speaker 6:  Google very clearly and they, they've kind of said this out loud, sees this
Speaker 6:  as its chance to win in hardware, right? That like if they can be the ones
Speaker 6:  to make AI happen and do it well and do it first and do it
Speaker 6:  in the biggest, most interesting, most differentiated ways that all of a
Speaker 6:  sudden this is the best new reason to buy a phone that we've had in a really
Speaker 6:  long time. Yeah. I don't know if that's true. I don't know that there's a
Speaker 6:  ton of evidence yet that it is true. But if it's true And, if you believe
Speaker 6:  it's true, everything Google has done sort of makes sense. Right.
Speaker 5:  I will remind you that my response to all AI announcements right now are,
Speaker 5:  it's probably broken. I don't believe you including Apple. I wanna be very
Speaker 5:  clear about this. Apple has not announced a date for anything yet
Speaker 5:  for any of the Apple intelligence features. And no one has ever seen those
Speaker 5:  features in anything but a totally controlled demo. So
Speaker 6:  Yeah, there's an increasingly angry rant inside of me
Speaker 6:  about how AI is actually nothing and we all need to stop it,
Speaker 6:  but I'm, I'm waiting a while for that to come out.
Speaker 5:  I mean, look, we can get a computer to produce in a pitch. Perfect. Jason
Speaker 5:  Dillo tech, right? It's something Yeah. I'm not sure what it is, but it's
Speaker 5:  something. It
Speaker 6:  Is, it is something. I'll give
Speaker 5:  You that. So I, I just think that that one for Google, how they talk about
Speaker 5:  the Pixel, how they talk about the pixel in relation to Google's AI
Speaker 5:  capabilities. Yep. How much of those AI capabilities come to Android
Speaker 5:  versus just the Pixel. There is some kind of shakeup going
Speaker 5:  on over there and I, I'm kind of cur, I'm kind of curious how they handle
Speaker 5:  it. Especially if they can ship this stuff before Apple.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Yeah. If they do this and they're like, oh, shipping in October, that's
Speaker 6:  a unbelievable width. Yes. But if they can do it and I think especially,
Speaker 6:  well
Speaker 5:  No, 'cause Apple's gonna announce new iPhones and it's not gonna have Apple
Speaker 5:  Intelligence until like next year. So even if Google's like shipping in January,
Speaker 5:  they're gonna get to market with an AI iPhone before Apple
Speaker 6:  Probably. Yeah. But I don't know that anybody is sitting around waiting for
Speaker 6:  an iPhone. Right. I think fair enough. Think we're, we're still at this point,
Speaker 6:  and this is part of what I'm really excited about is I think there are two
Speaker 6:  simultaneous things happening here where we're gonna see in rapid succession,
Speaker 6:  I think Samsung and Google both try really hard to make the case for Foldables.
Speaker 6:  Like it's very clear that Samsung is all in on that train. I think one
Speaker 6:  of the things Google is probably going to do is push the new
Speaker 6:  pixel fold or whatever it's gonna be called. I've heard rumors
Speaker 6:  it's gonna be called the Pixel nine XL fold, which sucks of course. Perfect.
Speaker 6:  Just call it the pixel fold too. Everybody, it'll be fine But anyway.
Speaker 6:  They're gonna try to make this case for this like new kind of phone.
Speaker 6:  I think especially as we get to ai, like You can start to see what you do
Speaker 6:  with the extra screen, what you do with the extra power, all this different
Speaker 6:  stuff. Again, in the hopes that Apple is just going to announce like a Sam
Speaker 6:  e iPhone that does Sam e iPhone things and looks less interesting compared
Speaker 6:  to the Android stuff. I don't know if it'll work, but I think that is the
Speaker 6:  gambit and I think it's gonna be really interesting. But then at the same
Speaker 6:  time, everybody is trying to make yeah, these AI cases and
Speaker 6:  no one has those yet. I don't think like you and even throw Motorola
Speaker 6:  into that, right? There's this question about like what is the form factor
Speaker 6:  and it's gonna be like the summer of Foldables and Flippable and whatever
Speaker 6:  else. And then at the end of it we'll have Apple and
Speaker 6:  whether anyone can do anything that is better than last year's iPhone
Speaker 6:  feels extremely up in the air still, which is kinda wild.
Speaker 5:  Let's talk about the Motorola phone for a second. The Razor Plus actually
Speaker 5:  looks great. It does because they put a four inch screen on the front.
Speaker 5:  It's huge. Which is the size of the original iPhone. Like they, it's bigger
Speaker 5:  than the original iPhone I think. Yeah. It's just a full phone. Yeah. You
Speaker 5:  front
Speaker 6:  Phone, you just have two phones now instead of one phone. It's to, the problem
Speaker 6:  is
Speaker 5:  And and they, they went with saturated colors. Like honestly, this is the
Speaker 5:  thing I like about this phone the most. The colors are hot. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  They really are.
Speaker 5:  But they refined this design, right? This is like the third one of these,
Speaker 5:  the fourth one of these. It's expensive, it's a thousand dollars.
Speaker 5:  But I'm looking at it and I'm like, you know what, if AI can actually do
Speaker 5:  any of the things people say can do, which I don't believe,
Speaker 5:  and I believe that it's mostly broken actually maybe this is the time to
Speaker 5:  get a smaller phone, right? If I just talk to the phone and have it do a
Speaker 5:  bunch of stuff for me, like I don't need all this screen. I, I'm not looking
Speaker 5:  for another laptop, which is basically where my phone is going right now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's like very quickly becoming another laptop.
Speaker 6:  I got so much shit last year for writing that everybody should start making
Speaker 6:  flip phones and history will prove me. Right. I firmly
Speaker 6:  believe it. Motorola
Speaker 5:  Doesn't have any of the AI features and they swap and the plus they swapped
Speaker 5:  out the ultra wide for a telephoto, which is just the wrong approach. Like
Speaker 5:  everyone loves these ultra wides and whatever, but I, these phones
Speaker 5:  are great. And then on top of it, you know, Apple's supporting RCS now,
Speaker 5:  so the iMessage stickiness, like, I'm like, ah, maybe I could just like try
Speaker 5:  one of these for a while and like not everyone will be mad at me once everyone
Speaker 5:  upgrades. Like there's something there that is super
Speaker 5:  interesting. But it's not because the ai, it's because of the form factor
Speaker 5:  and honestly the colors like I just like things that look different. The
Speaker 6:  Orange razor is, is sick, I'm very into it.
Speaker 5:  But then you look at Samsung, Samsung is basically just like moving down
Speaker 5:  the line, right? It's like we're gonna get a new Z flip and a new Z fold
Speaker 5:  and like big spiel be marginally smarter, but
Speaker 5:  who cares? Yeah. And they've gotta deal to use some Google stuff, but not
Speaker 5:  all of it. And like lots and lots and lots of questions about how Samsung
Speaker 5:  pulls this off in a way that's differentiated from Google.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. To me the big question for Samsung is if it can, if it can make the
Speaker 6:  ring a desirable thing.
Speaker 5:  Right? We're we're expecting the Galaxy ring
Speaker 6:  In the next year. Yeah. Like and, and we've been hearing sort of bits and
Speaker 6:  pieces about it for a while. It seems to look good. We got to try a prototype
Speaker 6:  a while back. Like I have reasonably high expectations for this thing
Speaker 6:  and if it's great or even pretty good,
Speaker 6:  that's a pretty solid ecosystem play for
Speaker 6:  Samsung to make that at least I think might convince some
Speaker 6:  people who have Galaxy phones to keep their Galaxy funds. Which is something.
Speaker 6:  But I, I do agree. I think there's this bet coming
Speaker 6:  from all of these companies that AI is going to sort of throw the
Speaker 6:  industry up in the air again and everybody has a chance to win it. And to
Speaker 6:  me, I actually think it that that may be true, but I think this like
Speaker 6:  flippable foldable different form factor change your relationship
Speaker 6:  with your gadget thing might end up being more important. Yes. And AI is
Speaker 6:  part of that, right? Like better Siri makes it so that you have to look at
Speaker 6:  your phone less, which makes it so that you use your phone differently.
Speaker 5:  If AI makes it so that we have smaller phones, that will be good.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Agreed. I, I would take that. By the way, Liam is reminding me that the iPhone
Speaker 5:  one was 3.5 inches. It's the iPhone five that had a four inch screen.
Speaker 5:  So they straight up put an iPhone five size screen on the front of the
Speaker 6:  Razor.
Speaker 5:  It's fantastic. It's incredible. But if we can get to a place where the phone
Speaker 5:  is more useful because of ai, so now I can carry a
Speaker 5:  smaller, less distracting phone, that would be good. I don't think any of
Speaker 5:  these companies have put those ideas together yet. No,
Speaker 6:  But they're all going to come out. What's gonna happen is they're all gonna
Speaker 6:  talk about the camera. This is gonna be the summer of AI features in your
Speaker 6:  camera and they're all going to be the same features on the same kinds of
Speaker 6:  devices across every single surface You can possibly think of.
Speaker 6:  And I'm already sort of bored of
Speaker 5:  It. Yeah. Here's what I can tell you. I was out with some teens, you
Speaker 5:  know, like family graduation party. They all had little crappy a hundred
Speaker 5:  dollar point and shoots. And then I'm out with the parents running
Speaker 5:  around around Max's kindergarten graduation and they're all asking me about
Speaker 5:  my Arc X 100. Mm. Because everyone kind of thinks iPhone photos look like
Speaker 5:  crap.
Speaker 5:  Do I, as AI kind of creeps in and everything that's brighter and weirder,
Speaker 5:  it's, it's weird to see where people are going instead. And I,
Speaker 5:  I suspect as soon as Samsung Samsung's like more saturation,
Speaker 5:  like I don't, I think it's gonna be weird. I, I think the AI photo trend
Speaker 5:  is going to, I think people have enough more taste than these companies are
Speaker 5:  assuming. I think that's right. All right, let's run through just some other
Speaker 5:  gadget stuff. We should talk about Rabbit really quickly.
Speaker 5:  This company is a disaster. What's going on with Rabbit?
Speaker 6:  I just do. We have to. So I, again,
Speaker 6:  I'm just this, this podcast is just me doing a victory lap. I said a while
Speaker 6:  back that I think that like if, if you made me
Speaker 6:  forecast whether Humane or Rabbit was closer to being kind of on a right
Speaker 6:  path to do good things, I would say Humane. I was right. Rabbit
Speaker 6:  just continues to be a, a massive disaster. Basically what happened here
Speaker 6:  is a group of developers and security researchers, I think they called
Speaker 6:  themselves Rabbit two, which is very good. Yeah. Found
Speaker 6:  Hardcoded API Keys that basically long story short
Speaker 6:  like governed rabbits access to, I think it was 11
Speaker 6:  labs who did all their text to speech stuff. And by
Speaker 6:  having those API keys, those API keys are supposed to rotate all the time
Speaker 6:  so that someone else can't get them and use them to get access to that same
Speaker 6:  data. Rabbit wasn't doing that and so the researchers were able to just use
Speaker 6:  that API key to get into and apparently see every response ever
Speaker 6:  given by a rabbit device,
Speaker 6:  which is absurd and, and has had the attitude
Speaker 6:  apparently said they've had access to these keys for, I think it was more
Speaker 6:  than a month. And Rabbit hadn't done anything, hadn't changed the
Speaker 6:  keys to make them outdated. Just it, it's basically like handing somebody
Speaker 6:  your password and saying, here go, go
Speaker 6:  nuts, do whatever you want. And it's like, well are you gonna change your
Speaker 6:  password? And you're like, nah, I'm cool.
Speaker 5:  That company is ever since your
Speaker 5:  review and then sort of response, it's like you're just
Speaker 5:  waiting, you're just waiting for the next shoe to drop that. Like there never
Speaker 5:  was a lang large action model and there never will be. Like it's still
Speaker 5:  too hard to make. Yes. On the humane side at least, you know, they're
Speaker 5:  trying to like sell it to h hp.
Speaker 6:  Well and they've like, they've shipped a bunch of updates. It has gotten
Speaker 6:  noticeably better. It's still not good and you still shouldn't buy it, but
Speaker 6:  it is, it is a better product than it was. But I think the, the rabbit thing
Speaker 6:  has been so interesting to me these last few months because there is like
Speaker 6:  this running is rabbit a scam thing happening
Speaker 6:  and I think it, it all amounts to basically like
Speaker 6:  they did nfts.dot do
Speaker 6:  feel about that however you want. And really I think,
Speaker 6:  what is the, the old saying like never ascribed to malice, what can be described
Speaker 6:  by incompetence. This is just gross incompetence all the way down. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And it's like, it's just, it's just brutal to watch.
Speaker 6:  And I like, I wanted this thing to be cool, I wanted this company to work.
Speaker 6:  I was pro the idea of this goofy little orange Handel
Speaker 6:  gadget and this thing just sucks. Yeah. Like I, mine is in a drawer and I
Speaker 6:  don't intend on ever touching it again.
Speaker 5:  That's basically how everyone I know who bought a rabbit feels about it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like the that cool rabbit animation was worth $300.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I'm betting that in 10 years it'll be like a fun story to have on the table
Speaker 6:  behind me while we vergecast. But until then I let its battery
Speaker 6:  die And that is the correct
Speaker 5:  Way for it to be. You're like I finally a teenage engineering product that
Speaker 5:  costs less than $4,000. I bought it my habit.
Speaker 6:  Exactly.
Speaker 5:  And we're good.
Speaker 5:  I wanna call this one out. Sean Ster got to sit in the
Speaker 5:  Sony Aila car, what they made with Honda and then he played
Speaker 5:  Grand Smo on the screens inside as the car,
Speaker 5:  which is per like perfect in its way. Which
Speaker 6:  Still seems to be the realist version of this car that exists. Right, right.
Speaker 6:  He is
Speaker 5:  The one in, right. He's the stuff I learned about the car and he is like,
Speaker 5:  the car isn't real, like it's mostly a fake car
Speaker 5:  and there there's no guarantee that it will actually have a PS five in it.
Speaker 5:  But Sony's trying to make a car and I, God, God bless them. Yeah. I hope
Speaker 5:  it has ULT power sound in it. Speaking of ULT power
Speaker 5:  sound, I, I am I think legally now required to call out party speakers.
Speaker 5:  So ultimately E has announced a whole new lineup including
Speaker 5:  a new mega Boom and a Wonder Boom. Yep. And they now have a feature called
Speaker 5:  Megaphone where You can just hold up your phone, talk in your phone and broadcast
Speaker 5:  sound to people, which is incredible. I also on the party speaker update,
Speaker 5:  ludicrous was supposed to play a show in Milwaukee recently and
Speaker 5:  he got called off because of the heat. So he just paired two JBL party
Speaker 5:  speakers, wore them with shoulder straps and did a free concert
Speaker 5:  in a mall.
Speaker 6:  No way
Speaker 5:  Was singing into a microphone. I've yet to confirm whether he used a proprietary
Speaker 5:  protocol to pair the speakers or one of the new open protocols like
Speaker 5:  Aura Cast, which is very cool. But just know there's
Speaker 5:  video of ludicrous wearing a party speaker
Speaker 5:  with a shoulder strap. That's amazing.
Speaker 6:  They do it for the people
Speaker 5:  Ing in the mall, which is great.
Speaker 5:  I propose that we write about it to our team and they're like, Neil, you
Speaker 5:  You can.
Speaker 5:  That's more or less the
Speaker 6:  Response. So that's what we're here for. I love this.
Speaker 5:  And then real quickly David, people can go listen to it, but you spent some
Speaker 5:  time on Tuesday talking about service laptops, windows and arm. What's the
Speaker 5:  vibe?
Speaker 6:  They seem to be very good there. There's like a surprising amount
Speaker 6:  of positivity and enthusiasm that
Speaker 6:  Microsoft actually like pulled this thing off. Tom published his review of
Speaker 6:  the Surface laptop when we talked on Tuesday. He was like mid draft of the
Speaker 6:  review, published it. He called it Microsoft's best MacBook Air competitor
Speaker 6:  yet, which I suspect if you're a Microsoft and knowing everything that we
Speaker 6:  know about how they have talked about these things is exactly what you would
Speaker 6:  hope for. Yeah. It still seems like Microsoft like
Speaker 6:  almost finished the job. There's still some like wonky
Speaker 6:  emulation stuff. If you run an emulated app, it seems like it just
Speaker 6:  decimate your battery. Like if anything Thomas talking this on Tuesday. But
Speaker 6:  if anything like understated the extent to which running
Speaker 6:  an app that is not prepared for emulation will just set your computer on
Speaker 6:  fire and kill your battery. But like he got good battery life,
Speaker 6:  one of his pros in the review says 16 gigs of Ram for the base
Speaker 6:  model, which I take as a personal attack, but we'll leave that aside.
Speaker 6:  But it seems like it, it seems like this new line of laptops is gonna
Speaker 6:  be really good. Microsoft stuff is coming out, Dell's stuff is coming out.
Speaker 6:  A seus reviews are coming out. Like the, the general vibe around this
Speaker 6:  generation of PCs seems to be pretty good.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think that the how good Prism the emulator,
Speaker 5:  how good Prism is over time is gonna be the thing. Yeah. In a way that Rosetta
Speaker 5:  is an not the thing on the Mac. Rosetta is the emulator that lets old
Speaker 5:  like Intel apps run on the new arm ships on a Mac
Speaker 5:  and like Rosetta was like so good no one even thought about it. And now it's
Speaker 5:  not even pre-installed on these machines, right? Like if you open an X 86
Speaker 5:  app on a Mac, it asks you if you wanna download Rosetta. Whereas I
Speaker 5:  think Prism on the Windows side, you're in it like you have a
Speaker 6:  Relationship. Yeah. It's gonna prim more important for much longer and it
Speaker 5:  Doesn't seem to be as good. So I think that's, that's the thing I'm keeping
Speaker 5:  on.
Speaker 6:  It's also just a much harder task, right? Like there's a, there are like
Speaker 6:  centuries of Windows apps that you have to figure out how to run in a way
Speaker 6:  that on a Mac, the Mac doesn't bill
Speaker 5:  Quite same has a stone tablet with a win 32 app app on it. It's true
Speaker 5:  but it's also if you wanna compete, that's the game, right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So we'll see. All right, we gotta take a break we'll back with the
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back with lightning round. David has two,
Speaker 5:  I have three, but one of them is a joke. You have three. Oh my god I picked
Speaker 5:  three first. Oh that I know what your joke is. Wait, can I guess what your
Speaker 5:  joke is? Can we do it first? What is it? Do you wanna talk about the new
Speaker 5:  Verizon logo? I wanna talk about the new Verizon logo so much. If you haven't
Speaker 5:  seen a Verizon redesign its logo, it's the same text that the
Speaker 5:  Tica Verizon or whatever it is, they got rid of the check mark. But now the
Speaker 5:  text is red on a black background and then the V
Speaker 5:  has like a fire gradient in it. It is nuts.
Speaker 5:  Like nuts like all the way around. Like
Speaker 5:  it just, have you ever seen putting a gradient in a logo is such a strong
Speaker 5:  move because it will never get reproduced correctly. Like every time we do
Speaker 5:  a logo I'm like let's do gradients. And everyone's like, no. Like no. And
Speaker 5:  Verizon's like, screw it. We're doing gradients but then
Speaker 5:  doing red on black I actually think is a great move
Speaker 5:  because every carrier should be like, here's what we are. We are the
Speaker 5:  demon spawn reconstruction of at t that the United States government tried
Speaker 5:  to kill and was not able to kill, which is what Verizon is. And I think
Speaker 5:  leaning into the fact that it it's from hell is
Speaker 5:  like good. Like let's just be who you are. Now that you point that out, it
Speaker 5:  even like you could argue it is kind of like the glow from hell coming outta
Speaker 5:  the bottom of the V. That's what I'm saying like that really it's, it's the
Speaker 5:  most goth telecom logo I've ever seen in my entire life.
Speaker 5:  and it's like here's what happened. The United States government tried to
Speaker 5:  kill at and t and instead we got two zombie at ts
Speaker 5:  and like just be from hell. Like that's good. Like
Speaker 5:  a I'm at and t, I'm looking for your Satanic logo redesign any minute now
Speaker 5:  by the way, this is true. Verizon is one half of the old baby bells and at
Speaker 5:  and t is the other half of the old baby bells.
Speaker 5:  And you just know they wanna merge. Like you just know that their
Speaker 5:  CEOs wake up every morning and they probably look out across the golf course
Speaker 5:  at each other and they're like, one day buddy at
Speaker 5:  and t's coming back. This look sucks too to my X and
Speaker 5:  Ferris
Speaker 6:  Once again. I would like to offer my services as the person who will walk
Speaker 6:  into your boardroom say That's the dumbest idea I've ever heard in my life
Speaker 6:  and leave for $50,000. And I would've done that for this because they took
Speaker 6:  like this. This just reminds me of the gap when they're like, oh we have
Speaker 6:  this great logo that everybody really likes and doesn't feel dated at all.
Speaker 6:  What if we changed it to something so stupid? That'd be so fun. Right?
Speaker 6:  And then we did
Speaker 5:  It. Wait, no one feels anything about the Verizon logo. That's true. If you
Speaker 5:  have an emotional attachment to any version of Verizon logo over time, let
Speaker 5:  me know. I'm just saying I'm super down with Verizon being like,
Speaker 5:  this one reminds you of literal hell. The
Speaker 6:  V just makes me think of like, I don't know why this is where my brain goes,
Speaker 6:  but like you know how Logan Paul has that sports drink that I can never remember.
Speaker 6:  Like I think it's Prime or something like that. Prime. This is like if a,
Speaker 6:  if a YouTuber with like a 10th as many subscribers as Logan Paul
Speaker 6:  wanted to make a sports drink, this is what the V would
Speaker 6:  look like to me. Yes. That's all I get is like knock knockoff sports drink.
Speaker 5:  That was mine. What's yours?
Speaker 6:  My first one is some Fedi verse news because
Speaker 6:  we are obligated to talk about it. Yes. Some new stuff on threads where now
Speaker 6:  if you have federated your account and you post on threads,
Speaker 6:  not only can people on other activity pub
Speaker 6:  platforms see your post, they can actually like and reply and you will see
Speaker 6:  the likes and replies. Like the way it's worked in threads has been kind
Speaker 6:  of weird before. Yeah. And now there's at least sort of one step of two way
Speaker 6:  stuff. If you reply to their reply it gets wacky. But
Speaker 6:  again, like any inkling that meta is
Speaker 6:  continuing to push into actually opening this stuff up, I find very
Speaker 6:  exciting and it seems to still be happening that Meta cares about this and
Speaker 6:  wants to federate and make all of this stuff interoperate. And
Speaker 6:  I just think that's very cool.
Speaker 5:  Whether Meta is a company Cares weird
Speaker 5:  like Meta has, which is weird ideas about all of its platforms right now.
Speaker 5:  Yes. They had a half the controversy scandal this
Speaker 5:  week where they just keep limiting the political content.
Speaker 5:  Even if you ask it to show you politics content, it just reverts every
Speaker 6:  Time you close the app, it turns the setting off to show you political content.
Speaker 5:  It's like, yeah we know you guys don't want news. It's like, it's weird how
Speaker 5:  all of your bugs are in support of you not wanting to show news. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 5:  The thing that you keep denying so I don't meta the company is weird. The
Speaker 5:  people who are working on this at Meta super sincere about it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like they're communicating about it, they're posting along threads about
Speaker 5:  it. They've talked to us about it. So at least on that
Speaker 5:  front, the energy of that company is
Speaker 5:  sincerely pointed at can you make Metaverse work? Yeah. And I think
Speaker 5:  that Alone is bringing a bunch of other companies along. So like
Speaker 5:  Ghost the newsletter platform, very sincere about
Speaker 5:  making Federation work. The blog post that their product manager is writing
Speaker 5:  about figuring out how to do federation and activity pub, some of the funniest
Speaker 5:  technical blog posts you will ever read in your entire
Speaker 6:  Life. They, it's very good.
Speaker 5:  And this stuff
Speaker 6:  Is complicated. It's actually, if you wanna like understand what it takes
Speaker 6:  to make all this work, those blog posts are actually pretty good. Yeah. Because
Speaker 6:  this stuff is messy.
Speaker 5:  Super. I mean we wanna do it and yeah like, you know like sending stuff
Speaker 5:  out for media company is like in our DNA, like we have RSS,
Speaker 5:  we syndicate to Apple s like we, we have feeds of content going to all these
Speaker 5:  places like out is super great, right? All day long. What do media
Speaker 5:  companies love doing? Sending their shit out for free.
Speaker 6:  Right? Like
Speaker 5:  Work for free by all means. Like every media company is like let's do it.
Speaker 5:  Inbox is really hard. Right? The part where I post a quick post to
Speaker 5:  The Verge, it gets federated, you hit like on it and then it comes back to
Speaker 5:  us super hard. And then making
Speaker 5:  that two-way in turn. So you've replied to my post on some asset on server
Speaker 5:  and then I reply to you and that goes back out to you and then everyone else
Speaker 5:  can see it all. That's really complicated. And then if you're meta or any
Speaker 5:  of these other companies, you have to like be legally compliant in Europe
Speaker 5:  and da da da. So it's going slow 'cause it's complicated. But You can just
Speaker 5:  see there's movement and there's still a bunch of energy there.
Speaker 5:  It's not like it hasn't broken Twitter yet. You know, like
Speaker 5:  Right. All that stuff is happening. But I can see how complicated it is,
Speaker 5:  but I can see people are just consistently plugging away at it, which I think
Speaker 5:  is great.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. I agree. The, the just the sheer existence of
Speaker 6:  new features on this front goes a long way. And You can see it like in the
Speaker 6:  fedi verse space. Every time meta announces anything, all of my like
Speaker 6:  Fedi verse bros on Mastodon are like, let's
Speaker 5:  Go. It's great I. love
Speaker 6:  It. What's your next one?
Speaker 5:  Big Supreme Court. Weak Scott has actually not released a bunch of
Speaker 5:  big decisions that we wanna cover. Some very complicated ones,
Speaker 5:  but they released one big one that I think is really important to talk about.
Speaker 5:  Just briefly, there was a group of basically Covid
Speaker 5:  deniers who sued the Biden administration for
Speaker 5:  like First Amendment violations. 'cause the Biden administration had been
Speaker 5:  talking to social media platforms about vaccine information
Speaker 5:  and misinformation and they basically said this is impermissible censorship.
Speaker 5:  and it got all the way to Supreme Court by way of the Fifth Circuit, which
Speaker 5:  is crazy. The Fifth Circuit basically wrote like a fever dream, like,
Speaker 5:  you know, if the Fever dreams of YouTube
Speaker 5:  swamp kind of written judicial opinion, like that was the fifth Circuit opinion.
Speaker 5:  Like the, I think they called it like the largest coordinated government
Speaker 5:  censorship campaign in history of course. and it got to the Supreme Court
Speaker 5:  or six three Supreme Court
Speaker 5:  full of extremely hard right conservatives. And they basically are like,
Speaker 5:  what are you talking about? That's the opinion written by Amy Coney Barrett.
Speaker 5:  And she says like flat out like one you don't have standing to sue here.
Speaker 5:  You cannot prove one set of actions by the government
Speaker 5:  that pulled your post stem. Like there's, there's nothing here in
Speaker 5:  this body of evidence that says the government censored you
Speaker 5:  so like you don't, you shouldn't even be here. And then she, she says this
Speaker 5:  other thing which I think is really important for this whole debate that
Speaker 5:  probably no one will pay attention to, but very important to this whole debate.
Speaker 5:  She's like, you have collapsed the
Speaker 5:  users of the platform, the platform and the government all into
Speaker 5:  one thing. Hmm. Like the plaintiffs, the defendants and you are like, and
Speaker 5:  the platforms in between. It's not just one thing. Like
Speaker 5:  there are some people who got hurt this way who claim that they got censored
Speaker 5:  this way by this agency talking to that platform. There are people who
Speaker 5:  say that a different part of the Biden administration talked to a different
Speaker 5:  platform or suited yet a third person about something else. And that's not
Speaker 5:  all the same thing. So like the idea that there's a mass
Speaker 5:  coordinated government censorship campaign directed at
Speaker 5:  platforms broadly that is directed at the, like, that doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 6:  Well that's, I mean that, that is sort of an animating argument of a corner
Speaker 6:  of the internet. Yeah. And it's, it's, it was nice to see that kind
Speaker 6:  of roundly
Speaker 5:  Refuted. Yeah. Basically she was like, this is nonsense. Yeah. And like our,
Speaker 5:  this Supreme Court telling that
Speaker 5:  swamp like this is nonsense is pretty notable to me.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's not to say, look, I think government's speech regulations are
Speaker 5:  bad. I think everybody knows how I feel about the First Amendment. That's
Speaker 5:  not to say there isn't overreach in weird jawboning, that's what it's called
Speaker 5:  when the government sort of like pressures a platform, they call it jawboning.
Speaker 5:  There's a lot of that going on. For example, conservative Republicans
Speaker 5:  basically just got the Stanford Internet observatory
Speaker 5:  defunded by putting a lot of pressure on Stanford. Is that cool?
Speaker 5:  Is that a thing you want? Is that a speech right there? There's like a lot
Speaker 5:  of that going on on both sides. I, I like
Speaker 5:  Democrats love a speech regulation actually the same way Republicans do.
Speaker 5:  Like all these kids safety bills are basically speech regulations.
Speaker 5:  Just, we think it's, we think it's important to protect kids so we
Speaker 5:  can like shove a speech regulation into, into American political history.
Speaker 5:  Weird. Weird all around. I'm not saying I support them, I'm just saying this
Speaker 5:  case was so stupid and our Supreme Court was like, it's pretty stupid and
Speaker 5:  kicked 'em out. All right. What's yours? What's your next one?
Speaker 6:  My next one is a small one
Speaker 6:  about the the chat GPT Mac app, which is now available to everybody.
Speaker 6:  And I think it's fascinating because
Speaker 6:  a couple of people have pointed out to me very recently that one of the strange
Speaker 6:  things about open AI is it's terrible at making product that it,
Speaker 6:  it has what a lot of people would argue is like best in class, extremely
Speaker 6:  good technology. And I can't stop talking to people whose whole pitch is,
Speaker 6:  we did it better than OpenAI. And I think
Speaker 6:  the Mac app is weirdly important for chat GPT because
Speaker 6:  they've been, OpenAI has been pretty like
Speaker 6:  loudly and clearly working on a search engine. I think they have a lot of
Speaker 6:  other ways they're trying to figure out how to productize this stuff other
Speaker 6:  than just like a weird ugly chatbot in your web browser
Speaker 6:  and this thing where it can, you know, talk to you
Speaker 6:  using supporting documents like You can take screenshots on your computer
Speaker 6:  and upload it and ask questions about it. That's very cool. It has access
Speaker 6:  to different things in your computer. This is like if you want to see what
Speaker 6:  OpenAI is actually trying to do and get you a normal person to be
Speaker 6:  interested in like the Mac app is a pretty big step
Speaker 6:  in that direction. And I just think it's really interesting also all
Speaker 6:  of its most interesting Scarlet Johansen voices still not there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think we know why. I think Scarlet Johansen is like,
Speaker 5:  no, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 6:  She's like, I use Windows. Thank
Speaker 5:  You. I'm super, super gonna sue you very soon. Yeah. All right, last one.
Speaker 5:  And this is I think the most important thing we're gonna talk about this
Speaker 5:  week on the show. As you know, The Verge is America's foremost
Speaker 5:  cyber truck wiper news source. That's correct.
Speaker 5:  We've been very responsible in the show. I I, I think you also know we are
Speaker 5:  very precious, very serious journalists. We take our duty of care
Speaker 5:  very seriously. This is true.
Speaker 6:  I was there when you first got your hand on a cyber truck
Speaker 6:  wiper. Yeah. and it was, and you, you journalism a cyber truck wiper at South
Speaker 6:  by Southwest. It was a big deal.
Speaker 5:  I don't think the owner of that cyber truck enjoyed the practice of journalism.
Speaker 6:  I don't think so.
Speaker 5:  I committed some real acts of journalism with that wiper. So a few
Speaker 5:  weeks ago there was these reports that the Cybert truck wiper was faulty
Speaker 5:  and cybert truck's deliveries were being held back that there were potentially
Speaker 5:  a recall that it was flapping around that it wasn't very
Speaker 5:  effective. And we held back
Speaker 5:  hundreds of tips arrived out of various cyber truck
Speaker 5:  forums and social media posts and we couldn't confirm them. So we,
Speaker 5:  we, you know, we ran reportedly we, we were very calm. Others, other sites,
Speaker 5:  I won't name names, ran with it. Sensational, outrageous
Speaker 5:  click fadey journalism.
Speaker 5:  They
Speaker 6:  Were right wait
Speaker 5:  Click. They were right the whole time to be clear, they were right the whole
Speaker 5:  time. Now there's an official recall of cyber truck wiper,
Speaker 5:  which has motor problems, which just flopping and then the trim on the back
Speaker 5:  is flying off the cars. Which is great. That seems
Speaker 6:  Worse.
Speaker 5:  It's not good. There's a lot of cyber truck owners in the forums now who
Speaker 5:  are like, we just got had like, this is nonsense. Not great for your a hundred
Speaker 5:  thousand dollars triangle. It's the second big recall. The first one that
Speaker 5:  you recall. It's the second big recall. The first one, if you remember was
Speaker 5:  the accelerator pedal was getting stuck. Yep.
Speaker 6:  Which they fixed with like a rivet, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And that's how I would fix it. Sure. I'd be like ah, just get some,
Speaker 5:  just not just rivet it in, just
Speaker 6:  Point your nail gun at it and see what happens.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Yeah. The trim is gonna be fixed
Speaker 5:  with something called ADI promoter, which basically like make the glue work
Speaker 5:  better and pressure sensitive tape or they will replace it
Speaker 5:  if necessary. Free of charge of course. And then except the
Speaker 5:  wiper is excessive electrical current can cause the front windshield wiper
Speaker 5:  motor controller to fail. So they will replace
Speaker 5:  the motor.
Speaker 6:  I'm sure this is not what's happening but that makes it sound like it's,
Speaker 6:  it's getting like too much power and it is just, it's becoming
Speaker 6:  like electrified and going a thousand miles an hour and then it just like
Speaker 6:  launches itself into space and that's the end of your cyber drug waiver.
Speaker 5:  Well look, I can't, I won't draw too many
Speaker 5:  connections here, but you'll recall one of the big innovations of the cyber
Speaker 5:  truck is its new 48 volt control system. Oh right.
Speaker 5:  Whereas the traditional cars are 12
Speaker 5:  and the fact that the
Speaker 5:  God bless Tesla for launching this angry
Speaker 6:  ideas. Can it survive to like, oh this is, it's it's coming
Speaker 6:  now. And even the way that like RJ their CEO talked about it afterwards
Speaker 6:  was like, it's like buckle up, like let's go.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  every 12 months or so until eventually we have like
Speaker 11:  one. One The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast
Speaker 11:  Network. Our show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James.
Speaker 11:  That's it. We'll see you next week
Speaker 13:  With Verizon. You can finally create an internet plan that's made for you.
Speaker 13:  Whatever error you're in with my home now You can choose exactly what
Speaker 13:  goes into your Fios home internet plan and save on the entertainment you
Speaker 13:  love. Say hello to internet your way. Create your Fios home
Speaker 13:  internet plan starting at $35 a month with autopay and any Verizon mobile
Speaker 13:  plan. Call one 800 Verizon to switch today.
Speaker 13:  Availability varies for existing Verizon postpaid mobile customers, excluding
Speaker 13:  prepaid business and data only. Customers who then add and keep a file.
Speaker 13:  300 megabits per second Plan. Mobile and home discount enrollment required
Speaker 13:  autopay and paper free billing required $99 set up and other terms apply.