# Transcript
ID: dcdcfd9c-77e6-4aa3-bb8d-9fbfc5f23295
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/8400258708521634618/9168731759702286858/s93290-US-5801s-1716162641.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss announcements from Google I/O and OpenAI's GPT4o event.
Speaker 4:  Hello And Welcome to rich cast flagship podcast of
Speaker 4:  multimodal search agents. They can kill you in a number of
Speaker 4:  ways. Knives, guns, they're here, they're
Speaker 4:  agents and they can do anything they want. I dunno why the industry has picked
Speaker 4:  word agents. I mean I, I get it historically, but I don't know if you've
Speaker 4:  ever seen the matrix in which the agents relentlessly try to kill
Speaker 4:  Keanu Reeves. Hi, I'm your friend. Neli. It's The. Verge has Alex. Cranz
Speaker 4:  is here.
Speaker 5:  Hi, I am the AI of Alex. Cranz. How are you today?
Speaker 6:  Not enough emotion. Crans. More emotion.
Speaker 1:  Hi.
Speaker 4:  Oh my God. Kranz is gonna flirt with you this entire episode.
Speaker 4:  David Pierce is here.
Speaker 6:  Hi. I will not flirt with anyone this whole episode. I promise
Speaker 4:  We should just turn up the knobs of how flirty our ais are like throughout
Speaker 4:  the episode randomly. There's a lot going on this week. I dunno, If, you
Speaker 4:  can tell from my voice. I am very tired. I just came home on a red eye
Speaker 4:  flight from Google IO on the west coast. So Google had io. It was very exciting.
Speaker 4:  OpenAI had an event launching their own product. We should talk about those
Speaker 4:  two things together 'cause they're kind of in direct competition with each
Speaker 4:  other in actually kind of hilarious ways. And then a bunch of other stuff
Speaker 4:  happened. David reviewed the iPads. A bunch of other emulators have
Speaker 4:  launched for iOS. Continuing to reveal
Speaker 4:  that Apple's application model for iOS. Maybe a little limiting.
Speaker 4:  The CEO of AWS just unexpectedly stepped out. There's just like a lot going
Speaker 4:  on. And then there's like a Windows event next week in which Microsoft
Speaker 4:  is basically being like, we're gonna beat the M series processors. So a lot,
Speaker 4:  just a big week. And I just got off a plane so
Speaker 4:  I'm, you know, who knows who, who knows where this episode of The Vergecast
Speaker 4:  will take us.
Speaker 6:  It's either gonna be the shortest or the longest vergecast in history and
Speaker 6:  no one knows.
Speaker 4:  So, you know, a thing that I've, I have a new theory about red eye flights.
Speaker 4:  So you know, in your twenties you just take 'em 'cause they're cheap. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And you and your body can just take it. And then in your thirties you get
Speaker 4:  a little bit smarter and you're like, I shouldn't do that anymore. Like,
Speaker 4:  like I have a real job still sometimes. Like I wanna buy, I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  buy a real plane ticket and then a thing that happens. And I've only noticed
Speaker 4:  this recently that I'm in my forties now and I have a child and I take the
Speaker 4:  red eyes 'cause I just wanna get home. It's real. Like my goal is to just
Speaker 4:  be back at home. 'cause I'm like, I don't, I've been places at San Francisco,
Speaker 4:  it's Milwaukee with rich people. Like get me outta here. Like going
Speaker 4:  back to New York and then you look at the plane and the plane is like a
Speaker 4:  gradient of like people in their forties going home to people in their twenties
Speaker 4:  who are hungover. And that's a red eye flight.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's about right.
Speaker 4:  It's very good.
Speaker 6:  One of my favorite early neli stories that I still tell is
Speaker 6:  when I think we were in Barcelona for MWC and your
Speaker 6:  Go-to Redeye advice was eat two McDonald's
Speaker 6:  McGriddles right before the flight and you will instantly fall asleep because
Speaker 6:  your body just shuts down and that's how you sleep the whole way home.
Speaker 4:  It's the level of sodium
Speaker 6:  Control. It's been like a decade since you told me that. And I still think
Speaker 6:  about it every single time I get on a plane. It's unbelievable advice.
Speaker 4:  My friends and I used to call it time travel. You just like eat two
Speaker 4:  McDonald's sandwiches. You just wake up wherever you're gonna be.
Speaker 6:  It's like
Speaker 4:  What happened to me? You're like desperately thirsty and extremely puffy,
Speaker 4:  but you are
Speaker 6:  And sweaty and yeah, it's bad, but you get there. Anyway,
Speaker 4:  But I'm back. I'm here. It was a big, it was just a big week in
Speaker 4:  ai. So lemme set a little bit of the just competitive stage
Speaker 4:  here.
Speaker 4:  We have long known when Google io is
Speaker 4:  right, it's, it's around now every year. And they have it at the
Speaker 4:  Shoreline Amphitheater, which is a big outdoor amphitheater at Google Loans
Speaker 4:  right next to Google Campus. And you know, they invite lots of people. Last
Speaker 4:  year was a little bit smaller. They're coming outta pandemic This year is
Speaker 4:  big. Again, we, we just know when it is. Then there's this
Speaker 4:  other company called OpenAI that likes to act like they're just
Speaker 4:  a bunch of kids, even though they're some of the richest and most experienced
Speaker 4:  people in all of tech. And they're like, oh, we should have an event. We're
Speaker 4:  not gonna have an event. And they literally did this move. They, they tried
Speaker 4:  to upstage Google io but maybe leaking, maybe not leaking,
Speaker 4:  maybe just like swirling some rumors. They were gonna launch a search product
Speaker 4:  last week. And then Sam Lin was like, we're not gonna launch a search product.
Speaker 4:  And then they announced a demo and they did a live stream called their
Speaker 4:  spring event, which they announced, I don't know, 20 minutes before
Speaker 4:  it started. They, they just created some anticipation
Speaker 4:  that they were gonna have a big thing before io.
Speaker 6:  Well it was weird because there were, there were rumors that it was gonna
Speaker 6:  be s GPT five, which obviously would've been a huge deal. And then there
Speaker 6:  were rumors that it wasn't gonna be s GPT five, but it was gonna be a search
Speaker 6:  engine, which would also be a huge deal. And then right before the event,
Speaker 6:  Sam Altman, I believe was the one who tweeted like, not s GPT five not a
Speaker 6:  search engine, but we have something to share. So yeah, they are, they're
Speaker 6:  doing this very weird like aw shucks routine about like, it's not
Speaker 6:  a big deal. We're just, and that's so on brand for OpenAI
Speaker 6:  where they're like, they're both convinced that they are doing the biggest
Speaker 6:  thing that has ever happened in the history of humanity. And like, I literally
Speaker 6:  mean that precisely as I said it. Like they
Speaker 6:  actually believe that and also are just these like aw shuck
Speaker 6:  scientists who are like, oh look, we made a thing that will flirt with you.
Speaker 6:  Isn't that fun?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I would, let's hang out again, I'm just pointing out some of the most
Speaker 4:  experienced, richest people in tech. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  They know exactly what they're doing
Speaker 4:  And they are, they are very competitive. I, I guess
Speaker 4:  is the way to put it. Like they're, they're aggressively competitive with
Speaker 4:  Google I think they see that their opportunity is to displace Google
Speaker 4:  whether or not their opportunity to actually build a GI we will come to that,
Speaker 4:  right? Like one way or the other. Open A is gonna make a
Speaker 4:  GI, you know, like, but in the show we will also come to that.
Speaker 4:  And so there was just that little gamesmanship there of are they gonna announce
Speaker 4:  a big thing? Are they an upstage Google? And then so they had their event,
Speaker 4:  they announced their multimodal search. s GPT four oh oh
Speaker 4:  stands for Omni that let's use search with video, with audio, with voice.
Speaker 4:  It is natively multimodal. The, you know, the, the,
Speaker 4:  the feeling at Google io and Alex Heath reported this in command line is
Speaker 4:  that OpenAI did the demos Google was gonna do. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right. So this was the big upstage, like OpenAI saw what Google was gonna
Speaker 4:  do or somehow heard about it and rushed to demo those same
Speaker 4:  capabilities first to make sure that Google was in response to them. I that's
Speaker 4:  true, right? That's, that was just very much the feeling from Google folks.
Speaker 4:  It's very much the feeling that Alex reported. But there is some real
Speaker 4:  gamesmanship there. And I think the important frame for all of the news
Speaker 4:  is it feels like OpenAI and Google have identified some
Speaker 4:  kind of end state of an AI chat bot, AI search
Speaker 4:  product. And now they're in a furious race to get there. First.
Speaker 6:  I would actually frame it slightly differently. I think everyone has known
Speaker 6:  this is the end state for decades. Like the idea
Speaker 6:  that you should have a Star Trek computer as a
Speaker 6:  thing is, is what everyone has been talking about forever. Like
Speaker 6:  you go back to when we, the, the early days of Siri and Alexa and Google
Speaker 6:  Assistant and they were talking about this stuff. But the sense that I've
Speaker 6:  gotten is that I think the thing that has changed, and I think it's changed
Speaker 6:  really recently, is that people think we're close. That there, there is a
Speaker 6:  real sense that like not only is this the dream, but like, oh my God, we
Speaker 6:  can build it now. And I think that was definitely the sense I
Speaker 6:  got talking to Demi s who runs Deep Mind at Google and is in charge of
Speaker 6:  all their ai ai stuff. It was kind of the sense you got watching the OpenAI
Speaker 6:  stuff there. They think it's here now. And, and you
Speaker 6:  get the sense that we've gone from like, oh neat pie in the
Speaker 6:  sky. A dream that someday we'll all get to, which everyone has always known
Speaker 6:  is the goal. Whether or not it's a good goal, still debatable. We've tried
Speaker 6:  it a bunch of times, it hasn't really worked. Here we are. But there is this
Speaker 6:  real sense that like, oh it's it's happening now and and
Speaker 6:  we have to go get it right now. And you like, it just feels like everyone
Speaker 6:  has gone from running as fast as they could to like running even faster
Speaker 6:  because there is a sense that like you can sort of see the finish line now,
Speaker 6:  which is really interesting. Yeah. But
Speaker 5:  They're running faster to a not particularly useful place.
Speaker 5:  Like, like I just watching it, the, particularly the
Speaker 5:  ChatGPT and GPT one was like going to, do you remember at
Speaker 5:  CES, Intel used to have a big booth and they'd always be like, look at the
Speaker 5:  power of what we can do with Intel. We can read your emotions
Speaker 5:  with the camera. And I was like, okay. So when ChatGPT and GPT did it, I
Speaker 5:  was like, cool. I saw that demo from Intel four or five
Speaker 5:  years ago. Oh cool. You, you can like read things when you hold the camera
Speaker 5:  down on it again. I've seen that demo before. Like it felt like a, it it
Speaker 5:  was like a nice demo. It was done very well and like I can appreciate that
Speaker 5:  there was a lot of new technology there but it also didn't feel like it was
Speaker 5:  doing anything new or fantastic.
Speaker 4:  Alex, I think you're under estimating the level to which the billionaires
Speaker 4:  with Silicon Valley believe that people wanna bang an iPad.
Speaker 5:  Oh this is true. This is true. Yeah. You like, where's your David Zs love,
Speaker 5:  love, you've gotta like love people. Not not just devices. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  An FMK with David Zv, an iPad
Speaker 4:  like Sydney Sweeney is like a reel. and it was like, I don't know guys,
Speaker 5:  Beautiful lineup, incredible
Speaker 4:  Lineup, nightmare rotation. It's a tough one.
Speaker 6:  I think Sydney's gonna lose. I'm real like
Speaker 4:  A lot of people are gonna pick the iPad. You feel they're,
Speaker 4:  so that's the frame. And I actually wanna come back to that Alex
Speaker 4:  because it feels like the core technology that we're
Speaker 4:  everyone that has gotten everyone so excited has a fatal flaw with these
Speaker 4:  hallucinations Yeah. That everyone is ignoring. And we should talk about
Speaker 4:  that a lot. But let's go through the news. Yeah. So you know,
Speaker 4:  we covered the hell out of OpenAI event. Kylie Robinson, our new senior AI
Speaker 4:  reporter talked to Mira Mirati, their CTO about some of their technology.
Speaker 4:  We sent an army to Google io like we always do soon. Our was on
Speaker 4:  decoder, which we'll give a little preview of that's gonna come out Monday.
Speaker 4:  So just a lot. We covered all of this stuff. Let's go through the news.
Speaker 4:  OpenAI news, pretty straightforward, right? The s
Speaker 4:  GPT four Oh that's the omni model. It's faster. They changed some of the
Speaker 4:  pricing so you can just get it for free now. you don't have to pay for it
Speaker 4:  like you did with s GPT four. There's a Mac app now, which is very funny
Speaker 4:  because they have a gigantic Microsoft investment by the way. Their answer
Speaker 4:  to why Mac app is that's where the users are, which is both a
Speaker 4:  statement, a true statement, and also the sickest possible burn that you
Speaker 4:  can deliver to Microsoft, your major investor. They are letting
Speaker 4:  people use the s GPT store for free now. So like really it's like a pricing
Speaker 4:  change, this new model and in classic sort of OpenAI fashion,
Speaker 4:  you know, they announced Soro, their video generator, no one can use it.
Speaker 4:  They announced s GPT four Oh it's out. But the thing where you like wave
Speaker 4:  your phone around and look at stuff I don't think has hit yet.
Speaker 6:  No, you can, you can get at the model and like every AI app,
Speaker 6:  AI app on the planet has been integrating that model over the last whatever,
Speaker 6:  96 hours at this point. It's out there and by all accounts is is very good.
Speaker 6:  People like it, it's really fast. But the yeah, the the like super
Speaker 6:  agent stuff that everybody is talking about is as far as I can tell, not
Speaker 6:  anywhere really at this moment.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And so the idea here, and this is where the, the idea that you're gonna
Speaker 4:  bang an iPad comes from is you've got a phone, it talks to you the,
Speaker 4:  the voice is very much like Scarlet Johansen in the movie her Sam Altman
Speaker 4:  tweeted the word her Mira denied that it was Scarlet
Speaker 4:  Johansen voice. But boy is it close. But the idea is you're just like looking
Speaker 4:  at stuff with your phone, you're talking to an an AI
Speaker 4:  that's much more personable, even a bit flirty. It's like telling
Speaker 4:  jokes. It's saying you look nice in that hoodie and it's like more
Speaker 4:  powerful because it's not going from your voice to text into the AI model
Speaker 4:  back out to text, to back out to right text to speech. It's all just
Speaker 4:  happening natively, which is a speed up. But that's
Speaker 4:  like the thing, right? Like that the, the announcement here is very much
Speaker 4:  this model can now talk, can like look at stuff with you and you can talk
Speaker 4:  to it in a much more emotive way. Okay. Right.
Speaker 6:  Can we talk about that actually? Because I was talking to somebody about
Speaker 6:  this yesterday and they just sort of
Speaker 6:  casually made the point that this is a user behavior
Speaker 6:  that does not exist and doesn't make any sense. And I have not been able
Speaker 6:  to stop thinking about it. And like I, I go back to the, when I was at the
Speaker 6:  Rabbit R one launch a couple of weeks ago, one of the demos he did was
Speaker 6:  write a spreadsheet out by hand, just like a table of numbers
Speaker 6:  and then point his R one at it and say, I
Speaker 6:  think it was like, can you invert the rows and the columns and then send
Speaker 6:  this to me? And it's like cool technology. What the hell is that
Speaker 6:  for? And is anyone in the world ever going to actually do this? And
Speaker 6:  so many of these demos that we've seen both from Google and OpenAI this week
Speaker 6:  are basically people walking around a room asking their phone
Speaker 6:  what a thing is. Yep. And, and I just like, and this goes back to Alex your
Speaker 6:  point of like, what is all this technology actually for that's either a user
Speaker 6:  behavior that we just have never developed because we've never had the technology
Speaker 6:  for it or it's just not a thing people want to do. And I'm increasingly
Speaker 6:  leaning towards the second thing.
Speaker 5:  I mean If, you can't see you probably, it would be very useful to the
Speaker 5:  point a phone in a general direction and be like, what's there?
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Granted that's a good one. It's a good extensibility feature. No question.
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent.
Speaker 4:  The demos are
Speaker 4:  weird because they need to create them so that you can
Speaker 4:  verify that the thing is happening in the way that you think it's happening.
Speaker 4:  Like the dumbest one I've seen so far is someone holding up s GPT four oh
Speaker 4:  at like Buckingham Palace and being like, is the king here? and it's like,
Speaker 4:  yes, the flags are raised so the king is here. And it's like, dude, like
Speaker 4:  you don't need all this technology to, to get that. Like they've been answering
Speaker 4:  that question since the 12 hundreds.
Speaker 4:  You know, it's like that's why the, that's the thing. That's the whole thing.
Speaker 4:  and it, there's just a piece of that where it's, you need to construct the
Speaker 4:  demo so it's obvious the computer is doing the thing and the actual use cases
Speaker 4:  are yet to be seen because real people have to get the stuff and try doing
Speaker 4:  things that no one's ever thought of doing. This actually ties in
Speaker 4:  with what Google demoed, right? Which is you have some sort of problem, you
Speaker 4:  point your phone at it, you're like, help me fix this problem. We will come
Speaker 4:  to that because both of their demos were kind of weird for various
Speaker 4:  reasons. But that, it's like that thing where it's like, I don't know what
Speaker 4:  this part is called, but it's rattling, fix it.
Speaker 4:  Right? And then like the computer knows some things
Speaker 4:  and it like helps you get to that answer. Whereas all these demos, I think
Speaker 4:  they're just trading on the fact that people will know the answers already.
Speaker 4:  And what they're proving is that the various ais can, and I think
Speaker 4:  that's what you're getting at David, is like these demos are not compelling
Speaker 4:  because at the end of the day, they're designed so that
Speaker 4:  you can see that it's doing the thing that you already know.
Speaker 6:  Right? Yeah. It was like the person, they, they were in the London
Speaker 6:  Google Office demoing project Astro, which we'll we'll get
Speaker 6:  to, but running around with the same kind of multimodal assistant and they
Speaker 6:  point their phone out the window at King's Cross Station and say, what is
Speaker 6:  this? and it goes King's Cross station. It's like, who did we help here?
Speaker 6:  Like you're in Google's London office and you're like, gosh, what enormous
Speaker 6:  station is that? Just outside? Like, I don't know. And I think
Speaker 6:  to your point, I think as a, as a like search input, it's super interesting.
Speaker 6:  But the idea of that as a sort of ongoing assistant that I'm just
Speaker 6:  gonna like pipe the video of my world into
Speaker 6:  all the time and it's just gonna chat to me about what I see that I am
Speaker 6:  suspicious of. I just don't see that
Speaker 4:  Yet. The funniest thing about that demo in particular is I believe it also
Speaker 4:  asked in the demo, I believe they also asked Astra,
Speaker 4:  what is Kings Trust station known for? And Tom Warren on our team who
Speaker 4:  is British, said, no Londoner would've given such a milk toast answer.
Speaker 4:  They've been like, that's where you get hookers and cocaine.
Speaker 4:  That's actually the answer. If
Speaker 6:  Gemini had said that, I would be more oppressed. Yeah. I'd
Speaker 4:  Be like, all right, straight up you're just like finally billions of dollars
Speaker 4:  of technology later. We're heating the oceans Yeah. With all this GPU
Speaker 4:  usage. But I can finally ask our robot where hookers Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like, hey, hey ChatGPT and GPT, who in this audience is most likely to sell
Speaker 6:  me drugs? Like now we're talking. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So that's like the open eye news and the the big piece of it is this emotion
Speaker 4:  stuff, right? They they, they're made the thing
Speaker 4:  multimodal. But the, I think the thing that was compelling to most people
Speaker 4:  in this demo was that it was flirting
Speaker 4:  with the people who were giving the demos and in a voice that sounded very
Speaker 4:  much like Scarlet Hansen.
Speaker 5:  Was it compelling though? I mean it definitely was flirting, but like
Speaker 5:  was it compelling?
Speaker 4:  So I I I'm just gonna caveat this with two things. One, it's been a long
Speaker 4:  time since I was called upon to flirt with anyone and whenever I try
Speaker 4:  to flirt with Becky, she's like, I don't know what you're doing. Like those
Speaker 4:  days are long gone.
Speaker 4:  And so like I read it as like they, this is
Speaker 4:  what they, this is what a bunch of nerds think flirting is. Yeah. Like you
Speaker 4:  want a flirty female voice to be like, you look good in that
Speaker 4:  hoodie, but it's like maybe you shouldn't be wearing a hoodie.
Speaker 5:  Like, like I don't want a computer to just reinforce all the bad stupid things
Speaker 5:  I do all the time. Yeah. I don't need that kind of hype person in my life.
Speaker 5:  'cause they're not productive.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean there's just an element where you should listen to it. It's,
Speaker 4:  it's hard to talk about it just like away
Speaker 4:  from the actual thing. But If you listen to it. What they've added is a bunch
Speaker 4:  of stutters and pauses and like intonations to what would
Speaker 4:  otherwise be a pretty dry text to speech output.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Okay. Yeah. It sounded the most human. I think that we've heard one
Speaker 5:  of these sound, right. And, and I know that like back to
Speaker 5:  that project Astro demo too, they're actually saying don't talk to them like
Speaker 5:  you talk to Alexa or Siri or any of these other ones. Talk to it more like
Speaker 5:  you would a human. And that's like kind of compelling. But at the same time
Speaker 5:  I go back to I don't want a yes man. Like the yes man is how I ended up with
Speaker 5:  a leather newsboy hat in the two thousands. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  My friend was just like, she wanted to just get out of the store. She was
Speaker 5:  like, yeah, get that hat Alex. I worked for weeks before she admitted
Speaker 5:  it. And that's what like I don't need that from a computer.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no. Our nation's teens during that same period of time was like, swing
Speaker 4:  dancing. That's what we're gonna do. Yeah. Yeah. And like that's just a collective
Speaker 4:  delusion that honestly what you want is an automated system to put a stop
Speaker 4:  to. Yeah. And we just didn't have the technology at the time. And now
Speaker 4:  maybe that technology's pointed in the wrong way. I went through a Brian
Speaker 4:  sets face, like I'm just, I'm, I was, I was a teen during that time. It happened
Speaker 4:  to me. It's great if it's still happening to you. I please,
Speaker 4:  how
Speaker 5:  Many people do you fling over your shoulder and then around your waist?
Speaker 4:  Again, when I when I say that he's no longer interested in
Speaker 4:  these antics, like the thing that's always on my mind is she is a divorce
Speaker 4:  lawyer. Like we just don't play
Speaker 4:  the, the thing about all that right is what people reacting to is the
Speaker 4:  personality and then all the demos at the bottom, it said check your
Speaker 4:  facts. Yeah. Right. The thing they have not improved is, is this thing getting
Speaker 4:  more accurate and more useful or smarter? which I want to put a pin in. 'cause
Speaker 4:  Alex, you wrote a great piece about that. That also comes up in the Google
Speaker 4:  example. But the, the part where
Speaker 4:  everyone's excited about this enabling technology to build these experiences
Speaker 4:  that everyone's always wanted, that David was talking about is like did they,
Speaker 4:  is the thing good enough to do the thing that they want? Or is it just
Speaker 4:  convincing enough? I actually don't know the answer to s GPT four. Oh. 'cause
Speaker 4:  I haven't had a chance to use it very much. And the feature, the big feature
Speaker 4:  isn't actually available to be used.
Speaker 6:  I do think it's becoming increasingly clear that it's getting convincing
Speaker 6:  faster than it's getting good. Yep. which I actually think is sort of scary.
Speaker 6:  Like just, just looking at the reactions that people had to the
Speaker 6:  OpenAI demos this week. Like it made a lot of mistakes. It got a lot of things
Speaker 6:  wrong. The interaction was kind of weird, but it was
Speaker 6:  mind blowing to a lot of people. Just the fact that it sounded
Speaker 6:  passively human and it made jokes and it was sort of silly and flirty and
Speaker 6:  it could dial up and down the emotions. There's one point where the, it was
Speaker 6:  two researchers who were doing this demo and one of them, he's sitting there
Speaker 6:  and he asked a question and she responds and the other guy goes, not enough
Speaker 6:  emotion. Like, give me, give me more, more drama. and it like
Speaker 6:  correctly amps up the drama and like to the point where it's funny like
Speaker 6:  I laughed at the thing and that's remarkable. But
Speaker 6:  I, I I don't know that there's any evidence that it is making fewer
Speaker 6:  mistakes in those moments so far than these things
Speaker 6:  have in the past. Or that it is like meaningfully glister to getting to zero.
Speaker 6:  Which is ultimately the only thing that actually matters. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And zero is a hard place to get. Like people aren't at zero,
Speaker 4:  but at least I you understand the failure mode of another person. Right.
Speaker 4:  You know, like you, you can evaluate whether a person is trustworthy or like
Speaker 4:  you have some history or you can define a number of tiktoks going
Speaker 4:  through someone's entire backstory to tell. Right. Like there's a whole thing
Speaker 4:  you can do to evaluate whether another human being is
Speaker 4:  trustworthy. They're telling you the truth or whether they're experts or
Speaker 4:  whatever in a way that like AI are just like a different
Speaker 4:  kind of thing. Yeah. Yeah. And we don't have the skills as a society or a
Speaker 4:  culture to do it. And also we're gonna come to this, this is
Speaker 4:  Alex's piece. Everyone seems to be just ignoring it 'cause it's fun. Right.
Speaker 4:  and it's like, that's weird.
Speaker 6:  If I'm going to briefly defend ai, I will say there are a lot of things about
Speaker 6:  these tools that are very low stakes that are fine, right? Yeah. Like
Speaker 6:  there's a lot of things for which there's not a right answer that it, and
Speaker 6:  it doesn't matter if it gives you the slightly wrong answer. And again, I
Speaker 6:  think the thing that we're learning is that more of the point
Speaker 6:  is the interaction than we expected. Right. The more you hear
Speaker 6:  about Kevin Ru's girlfriends in the New York Times, I
Speaker 6:  loved that story. Like we've given Kevin a hard time. It is an unbelievable
Speaker 6:  story idea and I'm very jealous of it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I mean his beat is what If you banged an iPad. I just wanna, it's clear,
Speaker 6:  Unbelievable idea. Incredible. And you, you hear about
Speaker 6:  like the the meta celebrity AI things that they have. Like
Speaker 6:  half the point of these things is just to use them. Yeah. And I think
Speaker 6:  I really underestimated that for a long time. I was like, these things are
Speaker 6:  tools and the goal is to accomplish something as quickly and efficiently
Speaker 6:  as possible. And having ums and oz is actually just a waste of
Speaker 6:  everybody's time. And for my own use,
Speaker 6:  I actually still believe that. But I think in general the, the fun of
Speaker 6:  using it, it's a real, like the real friends with the friends we made along
Speaker 6:  the way is like, that's very much, that's very much where we're at with a
Speaker 6:  lot of ai. And I think it, it forgives a lot of the wrong stuff
Speaker 6:  in a way that is a little scary. But also if you're a company like
Speaker 6:  OpenAI really productive because as long as it's fun people will forgive
Speaker 6:  so much and they're making it fun.
Speaker 4:  I mean, but you're kind of getting to the point where it's like, what if
Speaker 4:  your computer was Calvin's dad from Calvin and Hobbes, you know,
Speaker 4:  just like, I don't know, I'm just gonna make some stick go away kid. Like
Speaker 4:  fine, you know that. And that was life before computers, like before Google
Speaker 4:  people would just make stuff up at parties be ah, that's what it feels and
Speaker 4:  fine. Like society made it through many moments
Speaker 4:  without being able to Google stuff on their phone at a party. But it's just
Speaker 4:  weird that we're at a place where we had that facility and now we're like,
Speaker 4:  it's less accurate than before but it's flirtier and the point is the, the
Speaker 4:  interaction that's a change. It's like worth remarking on
Speaker 5:  That kind of mirrors like people's search behavior in general, right? Because
Speaker 5:  everybody's like, I could use Google, which will take me probably to the
Speaker 5:  correct answer. Or I could just go on TikTok and be like, does anybody know
Speaker 5:  why this happens? And take the first answer I get, yeah. From the most charming
Speaker 5:  person
Speaker 4:  And the answer is, your water doesn't have enough hydrogen in it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Just pack full,
Speaker 4:  See the answer open announced all this stuff. Which is interesting. Right?
Speaker 4:  Again, the timing. Then the day of IO they announced that
Speaker 4:  former chief scientist now Ilya Ver is leaving the company after
Speaker 4:  all of the drama about Sam Altman getting fired. Ilya was one of the people
Speaker 4:  that voted to remove Sam. And then he said he made a mistake and he went
Speaker 4:  back and there was the whole thing and now Sam is back with a bigger board,
Speaker 4:  whatever. It always seemed likely that I would leave. And
Speaker 4:  then they announced it on the day of io and I, I only bring this up, you
Speaker 4:  know, it's like the sort of machinations of open eye are very interesting
Speaker 4:  because of Sam getting fired. But it's interesting timing and that
Speaker 4:  they made all this noise about maybe we're doing search, maybe we're doing
Speaker 4:  a thing. It's not, it's but it's magic anyway. And also our chief scientist
Speaker 4:  who led a coup will be leaving the company. Yep. Don't pay
Speaker 4:  attention to that. Pay attention to Google's news. Like weird. It's just
Speaker 4:  a weird Yeah. It that I think OpenAI is in a weird spot where they
Speaker 4:  are, it doesn't feel like this from the product side. I think the product
Speaker 4:  has captured more imagination. But they are, as a company,
Speaker 4:  like pretty reactive to Google. Like they're in, they're weaving
Speaker 4:  their way around Google in a fairly interesting way.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think Google is getting powerful in this
Speaker 6:  space more quickly than anyone gave it credit for not very long ago.
Speaker 5:  I don't think that, I think, do
Speaker 6:  You remember 12 months ago when we were sitting around being like, Google
Speaker 6:  blew it, they blew it. Like where have they been? Google fucked it all up.
Speaker 6:  Like
Speaker 5:  That's not cool. We think Google was like slow. But like, I don't think it's
Speaker 5:  surprising that Google, the one of the largest companies in the
Speaker 5:  world is, is gonna run circles around this company that
Speaker 5:  was originally created to be clear, to protect people from a GI while
Speaker 5:  also creating a GI like, like they're still a startup.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They've got a ton of money for Microsoft and they're, and they're hunting
Speaker 5:  for more investment all the time. But Google has been investing in this space
Speaker 5:  for a very long time and investing in those resources, investing in
Speaker 5:  those people. And I'm like, I'm not surprised that it came
Speaker 5:  up and said, yeah, we're gonna do it and we're gonna crush it. Like of course
Speaker 5:  OpenAI is gonna be on their back foot the entire time. That's why they, they
Speaker 5:  rolled out their store so quickly. That's why they've been moving so fast
Speaker 5:  is 'cause they're like, okay, we beat them to market now we have to keep
Speaker 5:  beating them to market. 'cause that's all we have. We don't have all of the,
Speaker 5:  the infrastructure, we don't have all the resources that Google has. So this
Speaker 5:  is what we can do.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no, I, I I I, I buy that a lot actually. And I think that,
Speaker 4:  you know, what OpenAI is good at is having a product and caring about
Speaker 4:  a product and having the product be existential to the company and making
Speaker 4:  the product good. And Google is not good at that
Speaker 5:  Real bad.
Speaker 4:  Like Google has a product that it cares about for a long time.
Speaker 4:  Not Google's core skillset. It hasn't been for a while.
Speaker 4:  And you know, last year they announced a bunch of stuff and we're like, where
Speaker 4:  is it? You know, like again, they were at Bard last year, like all that's
Speaker 4:  gone, they already wiped out one whole set of products and replaced it with
Speaker 4:  of long list of other products, all of which are named Gemini, which we'll
Speaker 4:  get to. But they had, you know, their announcements at IO were
Speaker 4:  very confident we should go through at least the chat bot stuff here. I did
Speaker 4:  talk to Sundar afterwards, we talked a lot about sort of how
Speaker 4:  people feel about ai, you know, that's coming on coder next week, but
Speaker 4:  it felt like he has a handle on it.
Speaker 4:  You know, like he, he knows that he has to do this stuff and he knows that
Speaker 4:  it's like very much like can't make an omelet without breaking some eggs.
Speaker 4:  And he is like, I'm, I feel bad for the eggs. But he's doing it like they're
Speaker 4:  in an aggressive posture and the thing that they, I think the most
Speaker 4:  aggressive posture on is Project. Astra is
Speaker 4:  some of their search improvements. And it's the idea that they have
Speaker 4:  the infrastructure to scale this stuff and make it cheap.
Speaker 4:  Right? So Sundar said to to Deirdre Bosa and CNBC,
Speaker 4:  our cost of queers are 85% like cheaper than it was a year ago. And
Speaker 4:  that if you're OpenAI is like, oh shit. Like Google can
Speaker 4:  just deploy this stuff to everybody who has Google and it's cheap and they
Speaker 4:  can like figure out their business on the back of search ads and all this
Speaker 4:  other stuff. And we are at, well, 20 bucks a month was a lot of money and
Speaker 4:  people weren't paying for it and now we're giving away the best model we
Speaker 4:  have for free. Right? Like there's a real challenge in there and you can
Speaker 4:  see these companies kind of battling it out each using their own advantage.
Speaker 4:  OpenAI very much their advantage is they can tell a compelling story about
Speaker 4:  a product that everyone believes will be here a year from now. And Google's
Speaker 4:  advantage is that it's huge.
Speaker 5:  Yep.
Speaker 6:  And you also just described basically the whole reason that
Speaker 6:  Microsoft and OpenAI got so tied up because Microsoft promised
Speaker 6:  AI that same level of scale and infrastructure.
Speaker 6:  And I think if we've learned one thing, it's that it's very hard to do that
Speaker 6:  in a partnership. Yeah. In a way that it's much easier to do it inside of
Speaker 6:  your company. And I think like If, you look at what we've seen across Google
Speaker 6:  the last year or so, that company has just like relentlessly
Speaker 6:  consolidated itself to be able to move all of that stuff faster. Yes.
Speaker 6:  And that's like, that was the Rick Oslo story when they, they put him on
Speaker 6:  top of hardware and on Android it's to move AI into
Speaker 6:  Pixel and Android more quickly. And the infrastructure stuff, like, one thing
Speaker 6:  Demi Sava said to me is that the, the fact that
Speaker 6:  Google's infrastructure exists is how you get Astra to be
Speaker 6:  so fast. Like it, he just literally tied those two things together and he
Speaker 6:  is like, that's we, we spent six months taking the tech that we had and making
Speaker 6:  it fast. And what that meant is putting it in the rest of Google's infrastructure,
Speaker 6:  like that becomes the job. And and you're right, cheap and fast are
Speaker 6:  how you win. Yeah. That's, that is the next phase of this is we take all
Speaker 6:  of this stuff and we figure out how to do it. We figure out how to do it
Speaker 6:  in a way that is like economically sustainable and doesn't have latency because
Speaker 6:  latency kills all of these products just as a user. Like if it's slow, it
Speaker 6:  sucks and that's where we are.
Speaker 4:  And Google has known that forever, right? Yeah. I mean Google has always
Speaker 4:  known that speed is the thing. So we should talk about some of Google's news.
Speaker 4:  The main one is Project Astra, which is their natively
Speaker 4:  multimodal. Take a video of a thing, search for it,
Speaker 4:  ask it questions. I did a demo of it with V Song.
Speaker 4:  It was weird. Like there were Google executives there doing
Speaker 4:  demos on their phones. Apparently we, we didn't see that.
Speaker 4:  We went into a booth where we put on like a gaming headset and there was
Speaker 4:  a, you know, it's mounted camera pointing down on a big TV screen and we
Speaker 4:  were asked to take objects out of like bins and like put them
Speaker 4:  on the top, you know, so the top down camera can see 'em and like ask questions
Speaker 4:  about the objects, which to David's point is a completely insane use case.
Speaker 4:  Like you are just never gonna do this. You know what? But like the idea is
Speaker 4:  that it could see the things that could just like innate like instantly sort
Speaker 4:  of latency free chat with you about them. So, you know, v picked three things
Speaker 4:  and like said, tell me a story name this stuffed animal. Great. I I
Speaker 4:  broke it just instantly broke it.
Speaker 4:  I had a spaceship, a pliosaur, like a, like a plastic dinosaur.
Speaker 4:  And
Speaker 6:  Did you know it was a posa or did it tell you it was a pliosaur? I
Speaker 4:  Thought it was an OSA and it told me it was a police or, oh, I dunno, by
Speaker 4:  the way, I don't dunno who was right. I I didn't have any like dinosaur
Speaker 4:  people there with me. You know, the, the one dude from Jurassic Park was
Speaker 4:  not living with me,
Speaker 4:  but Alan, what's his name?
Speaker 7:  Alan Grant.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Alan Grant was not there. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Good pull. There we go.
Speaker 4:  What was the, who's the one who played Ellie? This is what I care about.
Speaker 4:  Laura Dern. Laura Dern. Yeah. Laura
Speaker 7:  Dern. That's with Laura. Oh my god, I wish she'd been there with you. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I just wish
Speaker 7:  She's around's
Speaker 4:  Great. If Google's Google's listening, the next time we do the demo, Laura
Speaker 4:  Dern should be there. And I was like, tell me a story about these three objects
Speaker 4:  we're the Morocco is the winner, which to be fair is like an idea
Speaker 4:  that can only come from my like booze old human
Speaker 4:  brain. Yeah. and it would just, it was like get ready for a story
Speaker 4:  and I was like, I'm ready. and it was like once upon a time and it
Speaker 4:  just stopped it just dead in its tracks. Like could not predict
Speaker 4:  the next word in a sentence that added up to the Morocco will beat
Speaker 4:  this dinosaur in this space. Like it was like, I dunno.
Speaker 6:  And there is nothing more awkward than that specific silence. Yeah. Where
Speaker 6:  you're like, is it, is it about to happen? Is it thinking, did it break?
Speaker 6:  Is it doing like
Speaker 4:  Are, is there an amster on a wheel somewhere? Like there's a data center
Speaker 4:  on fire and the poor guy giving the demo just like hit this space bar. I
Speaker 4:  was like, get outta here. Like he was like, we have other demos to give,
Speaker 4:  like I don't trust you anymore and it's fine. Like that is a weird demo.
Speaker 4:  It's a weird use case. It doesn't make any sense. The point is to show that
Speaker 4:  it can like, see you can like use its camera and
Speaker 4:  do text to speech like all at the same time in the same way. Right. Natively
Speaker 4:  multimodal, but Right. Like you would never walk like If, you asked a normal
Speaker 4:  person tell me a story where the morocco's a winner. They would also be like,
Speaker 4:  get ready
Speaker 4:  and walk away.
Speaker 4:  But I think there's just a part of this where we're, we're asking these things
Speaker 4:  to do like incredibly esoteric things just to see where their limits are
Speaker 4:  obviously. And it, you gotta bring that back to reality.
Speaker 4:  So the one demo they gave, which was, it's coming to Google Lens, it's like
Speaker 4:  an extension of Google lens, a video search, which is sort of
Speaker 4:  related to astro like Astro's a thing over here. But video search is a thing
Speaker 4:  over there and it's, it's weird to pull them apart.
Speaker 4:  So Astro you're just like talking to a computer, you're like waving your
Speaker 4:  phone around looking at stuff and talking to it. Video search and lens is
Speaker 4:  you like take a video. Like you hold down the shutter button of a thing
Speaker 4:  while you're talking and you say like, why is this record player broken?
Speaker 4:  Which is one of their demos or why doesn't the lever on this camera move,
Speaker 4:  which is another one of their demos. and it, they feel to me like the
Speaker 4:  very related ideas, but they're separate and classic Google fashion.
Speaker 4:  Like these are not the same idea. They're different, different names.
Speaker 4:  But the thing about it is the Astro demos, you know, they felt very
Speaker 4:  esoteric. Canna Morocco win the video search
Speaker 4:  demos were very tactile. Like I could see how they would be useful.
Speaker 4:  Yep. Right. This thing is broken. I'm just gonna take a video of it being
Speaker 4:  broken. I don't even know what the parts are called. Help me fix it. So the
Speaker 4:  record player one, which I did a lot of on stage is pretty good, right? They
Speaker 4:  had a people know about record players, there's a weight on the back of the
Speaker 4:  to arm and If, you don't have the weight balance, right? The to arm just
Speaker 4:  like skips around, right? Because you need, you need some weight pushing
Speaker 4:  down on the needle into the record to like hit the whole thing. If, you're
Speaker 4:  a record player nerd. This is like the most exciting demo that you've ever
Speaker 4:  seen. If, you are a normal person. You look at that and it,
Speaker 4:  it just tells you this thing. Go watch the demo. I encourage you to watch
Speaker 4:  the demo. It's like that it identifies the model, the make and model of the
Speaker 4:  turntable. It's like that's an audio technical turntable. And the reason
Speaker 4:  that toner might be moving this way is because it, the, the, it's not counterbalanced
Speaker 4:  correctly and it has a whole list of like things you could do to counterbalance
Speaker 4:  correctly. And it's like, oh, this actually isn't useful.
Speaker 4:  which I thought was fascinating. It's the right answer straightforwardly
Speaker 4:  the right answer. Like that's why it was doing that thing. But If, you don't
Speaker 4:  know what the tone arm is called. You've gone two steps too deep, too
Speaker 4:  fast, right? Right. You're like the the, the
Speaker 4:  information you need is like record players work
Speaker 4:  by putting a needle in a groove and you need to put pressure on that needle.
Speaker 4:  And this round weight at the back is called the counterbalance and
Speaker 4:  you need to spin it so you put enough weight on the thing and the amount
Speaker 4:  of weight you put on it is actually dependent on your needle. You go, it's
Speaker 4:  like you fall down the rabbit hole and suddenly you realize like you own
Speaker 4:  four record players.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Then you're just an audio nerd. It's
Speaker 4:  Just a thing that happens to you. That's fine. But like that was
Speaker 4:  really interesting to me, right? It's the right answer. But sort of in a
Speaker 4:  way that was like too far, too fast.
Speaker 6:  Oh, I think you're totally wrong. I think, I think I think you what you just
Speaker 6:  described as Google search, like which which is the way that it works, right?
Speaker 6:  Which is that it essentially,
Speaker 4:  But I I'm saying like If, you don't know what a tar Mars called. You couldn't
Speaker 4:  follow the directions that were given to you. Right?
Speaker 6:  That's, I mean that's fair. But I think maybe a better example of
Speaker 6:  the the opposite case is one that Liz Reed, the
Speaker 6:  head of search, talked about when she and I were talking, which is your dishwasher
Speaker 6:  is broken and there's a light blinking and you don't know what brand your
Speaker 6:  dishwasher is. You don't know what model it is. you don't know how to describe
Speaker 4:  It's just a baby. You're
Speaker 6:  Just like, my dishwasher's broken like off the top of your head. Do you know
Speaker 6:  the, do you know the model number of your dishwasher?
Speaker 4:  I could make up anything right now.
Speaker 6:  If, you had confidently answered, I would've believed you. You're absolutely
Speaker 6:  just be
Speaker 5:  Confident. Just make up enough. But
Speaker 6:  Like, but, but again, I don't, that's not information most people have. It's
Speaker 6:  not information most people need. It's not information most people should
Speaker 6:  care about. It should just say take out the filter in the bottom,
Speaker 6:  rinse it out and put it back. You'll be fine. Like that. That is the answer.
Speaker 6:  I don't need to learn about dishwashers. I just want mine to work. And it's
Speaker 6:  the, like, I take my car to the mechanic. Some people are like, oh, I'd like
Speaker 6:  to understand cars so that I can, my, I can make sure that my car runs
Speaker 6:  better. Most people come in, they go, my car's going rah, fix it.
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 6:  The end of
Speaker 4:  The interaction. That's great. But if you're asking like, what is this thing
Speaker 4:  and why is it broken? And it's like, here's how to fix it. Telling you what
Speaker 4:  to do is actually important. Right? And here it was just like,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, but that kind of teaching me about it, it just says pull the, do you
Speaker 6:  see the thing there? Pull it down.
Speaker 4:  Fair. I I I just thought that was a particularly jargony. Maybe it's 'cause
Speaker 4:  I just like am a turntable person, but the answer there was like particularly
Speaker 4:  jargony in a way that I thought was interesting. Right? It didn't like, it
Speaker 4:  didn't help you understand the actual answer.
Speaker 5:  Well I think you're also someone who thinks like you wanna understand the
Speaker 5:  thing that you're talking about in the working with like we're all gadget
Speaker 5:  nerds. We, or
Speaker 4:  I just wanna lie to David confidently in this.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah, that too. But like
Speaker 6:  I would've, so
Speaker 5:  Of feedback, we, we wanna know how the thing works, we wanna know all the
Speaker 5:  processes. And it's true, like the reason, you know, when you first used
Speaker 5:  Google search 20 years ago, you would have to be really think about your
Speaker 5:  search prompt, right? Like you'd have to think about what you type in and
Speaker 5:  now you just type in like, my dishwasher doesn't work. Yeah. And,
Speaker 5:  and people just don't care as much. But, but to your point, like
Speaker 5:  yeah, if, if it said, if the dishwasher said, yeah, go replace the filter,
Speaker 5:  I'd be like, where the hell is the filter? What the hell is that? Like I
Speaker 5:  I would still like to your credit, like I would still wanna know all of that
Speaker 5:  and I don't think it would necessarily get me there yet. Well
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying I think that one's interesting 'cause the, it it was the
Speaker 4:  right answer, there's no question it was the right answer. Yeah. That that's
Speaker 4:  the reason the to arm was flying back and forth. It was just, is the,
Speaker 4:  is it a useful answer, right? And I think we can obviously disagree about
Speaker 4:  that and we are, but that's the level that we're at. Like is this actually
Speaker 4:  useful for you to go sort of like spit out an answer like this where
Speaker 4:  it's fix the counterbalance, right? And you need to know some
Speaker 4:  information to like take action on that instruction.
Speaker 6:  Well, and there's a really interesting sort of AI all the way down
Speaker 6:  piece of that too, which is that like, what that indicates is that
Speaker 6:  the, the AI for sort of understanding what's in a video that you're sending
Speaker 6:  to it is capable, right? Yeah. Like it, it did the job, it figured
Speaker 6:  out the question you had by you pointing a video. That's awesome, right?
Speaker 6:  Like I actually think the, the video and lens is a very good idea. And I
Speaker 6:  think pointing your phone at something, being like, what is this thing that's
Speaker 6:  happening is an actually totally normal user behavior. So I'm like all in
Speaker 6:  on that the output thing is actually much harder, right? Because it's like,
Speaker 6:  okay, in this case is the right thing for Google to do
Speaker 6:  to just sort of give me an answer about the tone arm, which is not a term
Speaker 6:  that I know to your point. So if it says pull the thing on the to arm, I'm
Speaker 6:  like, what the hell is the tone arm? And you've lost me. Should it send me
Speaker 6:  a YouTube video? Should it, yeah, send me a compilation of stuff. Should
Speaker 6:  it like super impose ar on top? Like that is just such
Speaker 6:  a different problem from the sort of search query recognition thing.
Speaker 6:  And my sense is Google is getting really good at the search query recognition,
Speaker 6:  right? They did it with voice, they did it with video, they did it with images.
Speaker 6:  Like it, Google is very good at understanding what
Speaker 6:  you're asking almost no matter how you ask it. And then the question of how
Speaker 6:  to answer is so different and so much harder and
Speaker 6:  full of thorns and wildfires.
Speaker 4:  So the, the the, by the way this is kind of exactly what I was getting at
Speaker 4:  is what it presented was like a list of words, like vocab words. And then
Speaker 4:  in the demo she was like, and
Speaker 4:  here's a link to audio technical's manufacturer page, which is more words.
Speaker 4:  And what you actually want is like a YouTube short where someone just does
Speaker 4:  it in five seconds, right?
Speaker 6:  Somebody just reaches down and pokes the thing and it works again,
Speaker 4:  Right? And they're just like, here's this thing, like do this thing until
Speaker 4:  it floats and then like turn the number to whatever number is on. Like that's
Speaker 4:  what you, that's all you need to know. And like the actual answer to that
Speaker 4:  is a video of someone doing it. And that that's again, it just like
Speaker 4:  you, it got it right in one specific way, but it actually got
Speaker 4:  it wrong in like another way, which is like the form of the answer is not
Speaker 4:  the most useful thing. Yeah. Which is really interesting. Then there was
Speaker 4:  the other demo, which it was just wrong, like
Speaker 4:  wrong in a way where I'll just preview it. My, the first question
Speaker 4:  I asked Sundo Phai in the Dakota interview was, is language the same as intelligence?
Speaker 4:  Because the question was that someone was pointing a
Speaker 4:  camera at a broken film, advanced lever on a SLR, like a film SLR
Speaker 4:  camera. And so these cameras are really manual, right? So you take a picture
Speaker 4:  and you gotta move the lever to move the frame of film over in the camera.
Speaker 4:  If you've never seen a film camera, this is like a very
Speaker 4:  satisfying mechanical thing to do, right? You like push the button
Speaker 4:  the big, you know, the shutter goes junk and then, then you like move,
Speaker 4:  you are literally pulling, you know, the notches in the side of film. You're
Speaker 4:  literally like pulling the film over and winding it around. Such a good thing
Speaker 4:  you can expose the next shot, the next frame, when the next time you open
Speaker 4:  the shutter. This is great. I love like I'm a nerd for these things.
Speaker 4:  And the answer, the question was why, why won't I, why can't I advance this
Speaker 4:  thing? Why is this lever not moving all the way to advance the next thing?
Speaker 4:  This is a problem with these cameras. They have them, there's a million reasons
Speaker 4:  you might have this problem. One of like one of them on like old cannons
Speaker 4:  is like, there's a magnet at the bottom of the thing and one of the answers
Speaker 4:  is like get a magnet and like run it over the bottom of the camera. Like
Speaker 4:  there's all these, there's like folk tales and super suspicions like, you
Speaker 4:  know, it's like drink the blood of a goat and like wave at a crystal and
Speaker 4:  like move your film advance lever. It doesn't matter. There's just like a
Speaker 4:  lot of information out on the web of how to do this and
Speaker 4:  the answer that Google delivered in its own video and highlighted
Speaker 4:  is the most wrong answer. Like it's right in one
Speaker 4:  way, which is as a last resort, just open the back of the camera.
Speaker 4:  It will technically work. Yeah it will technically work.
Speaker 4:  But If, you open the back of a film camera, you expose all of the film, you
Speaker 4:  ruin all of your photos, right? So when people do this, when I
Speaker 4:  ask Becca and Veen a bunch of other photographers on our staff, like when
Speaker 4:  you have a broken film events lever, would you ever just open the back of
Speaker 4:  your camera? And Becca was like, no, no, no, no, no. You go into the darkest
Speaker 4:  closet you can find and you pray and then you open it in monkey with it
Speaker 4:  because you don't wanna expose your film, you don't wanna lose your photography.
Speaker 4:  And Vera was like, I've spent a lot of time in that closet, which is like
Speaker 4:  a very funny thing if the most virent thing you can say,
Speaker 4:  right? Like these cameras break, they're, they're finicky mechanical objects,
Speaker 4:  but there's not a place where anyone with even the
Speaker 4:  slightest bit of intelligence about those kinds of cameras would
Speaker 4:  recommend and highlight, just open the door and fix it
Speaker 4:  because necessarily you're gonna ruin all of your photos.
Speaker 4:  So I actually asked about this, I was like, I, this is not a thing. I don't
Speaker 4:  see the intelligence going up. I see the language I see, I see the capability,
Speaker 4:  right? Like David's saying, it can see in the video what's wrong, it can
Speaker 4:  go search the web, it can synthesize some answer, but this answer is
Speaker 4:  wrong. Like this is not the thing you should advise people to do. And he
Speaker 4:  is like, I went and talked to the team and they're like, well in some cases
Speaker 4:  If, you were willing to destroy all of your photos. It's the right answer.
Speaker 4:  Which is correct. Yeah. That that is the correct
Speaker 4:  response. We should just run it. We should just run that clip. Let's run
Speaker 4:  that clip now.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Ironically I was talking to the team as part of making the video.
Speaker 8:  They consulted with a bunch of subject matter experts who all reviewed the
Speaker 8:  answer and thought it was okay. I understand the nuance, I agree with you.
Speaker 8:  Obviously you don't wanna expose your film by taking it outside of a
Speaker 8:  dark room. There are certain context in which it makes sense to do that.
Speaker 8:  If, you don't wanna break the camera and if what you've taken is not that
Speaker 8:  valuable, it makes sense to do that. You know, it's a good example of
Speaker 8:  you are right, there is a lot of nuance in it and part of
Speaker 8:  what I hope search serves to do is to gives you a lot more
Speaker 8:  context and around that answer and allows people to
Speaker 8:  explore it deeply. But I think, you know, these are the kind of things for
Speaker 8:  us to keep getting better at. I do see the capability frontier
Speaker 8:  continuing to move forward. I think we are a bit limited if we were just
Speaker 8:  training on text data. But I think we are all making it more multimodal.
Speaker 8:  So I see more opportunities there.
Speaker 4:  I, to me that answer is like, yeah, we should have probably told you you're
Speaker 4:  gonna destroy all your photos, right? Like that's the answer. Yeah. Yes.
Speaker 4:  But it's also like why, why are we rushing into a world where the
Speaker 4:  products like can't quite do the thing you need them to do and Alex,
Speaker 4:  this was your piece, which is these things are Halluc left and right and
Speaker 4:  everyone's kinda like over it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's, I just keep being baffled by it because people,
Speaker 5:  it, it just screws up constantly. Like If, you give me one of these things,
Speaker 5:  I can probably get it to hallucinate within four to five questions fairly
Speaker 5:  easily, like consistently I can get it to screw up.
Speaker 5:  And it's just because they're not good at it yet. Because they're
Speaker 5:  computers, they're not people, they're not actually, all of the stuff that
Speaker 5:  our brains do is really hard to do and they're not prepared. But these companies
Speaker 5:  are like, well it's really cool we're on our way, so like, enjoy and this
Speaker 5:  is now how we're gonna have everything work. And it's like, well no, stop
Speaker 5:  that. Like I don't, I don't, I need my computer to know how to do my taxes.
Speaker 5:  I don't need it to know like what a nice accountant should
Speaker 5:  sound like.
Speaker 4:  Have you seen the one where people keep asking it how to get a, a man and
Speaker 4:  a goat across the river and literally none of the models can like do it.
Speaker 4:  Like the question is, you have a man, a boat, and a goat, how do you get
Speaker 4:  'em all across the river? And it's like, first you take the goat across,
Speaker 4:  then the man comes back and he takes himself across, and it's like, that's
Speaker 4:  not the answer.
Speaker 5:  This is just a bad answer. Yeah. They, they, they, they don't, they don't,
Speaker 5:  the com like Theis don't think like humans do. They're not meant to.
Speaker 5:  And, and that, that is remarkable. And it's like, it is cool that we're
Speaker 5:  now effectively engaging with like these alien thoughts
Speaker 5:  and things, right? Because it doesn't think the way a human does, but
Speaker 5:  it also doesn't think the way a human does. And we keep asking it to, and
Speaker 5:  we keep putting it in these situations and then we're like, don't worry about
Speaker 5:  it. So it hallucinated a little bit. So it like decided that Neli
Speaker 5:  wasn't the founder of The Verge and that Alex is a man. It's fine. Keep going.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, right, yeah. Materially, those aren't harmful things to say,
Speaker 5:  right? Like, like I, I think we'll both be fine if somebody said that,
Speaker 5:  but it still shouldn't say it. And that's, that's what you want to now be,
Speaker 5:  become the new form of search. Like for me, it really feels like Google has
Speaker 5:  lost the plot for what Google is supposed to do. And Google is supposed to
Speaker 5:  get you to the information. It is not supposed to be the arbiter of the information.
Speaker 5:  And increasingly it feels that it needs to be the arbiter of the information
Speaker 5:  and, and that it's like the whole point behind a lot of its new search products,
Speaker 5:  we're just gonna tell you how to think. And it's like, well no one, your
Speaker 5:  a company, you shouldn't tell me how to think. Two, you don't actually know
Speaker 5:  because you're relying on these ais that don't know, just stop this.
Speaker 5:  Like this is a really bad path for them to go down. And I feel like it's
Speaker 5:  gonna eventually bite them in the ass. But they're so financially incentivized
Speaker 5:  that they just keep doing it.
Speaker 4:  I mean this is the truly the com the competition between OpenAI and
Speaker 4:  Meta and Google is ferocious. Microsoft obviously
Speaker 4:  in the mix there. Apple wants
Speaker 5:  To be
Speaker 4:  What? Apple's just gonna buy some model from the other. Right?
Speaker 4:  At least for this stuff that sir is outside your phone. That, that, that's
Speaker 4:  the rumor. We'll see WWC is coming up, but it just feels like
Speaker 4:  there's that ferocious race to get to this product that everyone has dreamed
Speaker 4:  of for a long time. Whether or not the core technology can do the
Speaker 4:  task reliably. And you know, just go back and think about that film
Speaker 4:  camera example for a minute. But If, you had a friend who was like,
Speaker 4:  my, you were like, for some reason you're like, my film camera is broken.
Speaker 4:  I can't move this lever. And they're like, yeah, just open the back. And
Speaker 4:  then you open the back and it destroyed all the photos you've taken. And
Speaker 4:  by the way, film's not cheap, which is the thing the back reminded me of
Speaker 4:  instantly. Like, film is expensive, so you're gonna ruin all these photos,
Speaker 4:  you're gonna ruin it. Your expensive piece of film, you would be pissed at
Speaker 4:  your friend.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like, just as a matter of course, you'd be like, what dude? Like
Speaker 4:  you could've told me to go to a dark room like I asked you. 'cause I assume
Speaker 4:  you know, this other piece of information and there's none of that accountability
Speaker 4:  with these tools. You can't just be like, be mad at it because you know,
Speaker 4:  in a market you would leave Google and go to OpenAI and it's like, it's gonna
Speaker 4:  lie at you, but in a way that suggests it might also have sex with you. Like
Speaker 4:  yeah, fine. You know, but I, I just, that's the part where
Speaker 4:  it's, it's like everyone's building a really fast car, but they're not telling
Speaker 4:  you that the engine just doesn't work about 20% of the time.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, okay, but is there a path to stopping it?
Speaker 5:  That would be a bad car.
Speaker 6:  I I actually, I would, I would put it slightly differently. I think it's
Speaker 6:  it's they're building a fast car and not telling you how to use it. Right.
Speaker 6:  And I think like the, the camera thing to me is such an interesting example.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Because I I would argue that's not a hallucination, that's a
Speaker 6:  terrible UX mistake. Like, it, it gave you a
Speaker 6:  true answer without the actual bit of information you needed to know what
Speaker 6:  to do with that true answer. You can open the back of your
Speaker 6:  camera to get the film out that that is a true thing. And so in a certain
Speaker 6:  way, the model was successful. And like that's what I hear Snar saying. It's
Speaker 6:  like it didn't get it wrong, it just didn't tell you
Speaker 6:  what you actually needed to know. And, and so now we're in this place
Speaker 6:  where like,
Speaker 4:  I mean that is the, you are dancing on the, the pins, sort of
Speaker 4:  the heads and needles, whatever that thing is. I think, I mean
Speaker 6:  There are, there are things that are wrong. Like Alex, Kranz does not
Speaker 6:  have a beard that is wrong. Right? Like got it nailed.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  By the way, the rest of the answers on that list, that's the one I focus
Speaker 4:  on. 'cause it was the most destructive. The rest of the answers in the list
Speaker 4:  that it generates are bananas. Like one of them is just like nudge the shutter
Speaker 4:  a little bit, which is like,
Speaker 6:  No, yeah, I've already done
Speaker 4:  That. Don't do that. But I think that's not gonna help you.
Speaker 6:  One of the things I think a lot about with Google right now is Google used
Speaker 6:  to make you do a lot of work, right? And that was, that was the job, right?
Speaker 6:  Like when you did Google search, you did most of the work when you were interacting
Speaker 6:  with Google and now Google is trying to do most of the work for you.
Speaker 6:  and it creates this incredibly different version of
Speaker 6:  Google that needs to exist. And what Google thinks is that actually it can
Speaker 6:  just put a paragraph summary at the top and then let you
Speaker 6:  use Google the way you normally would. Because If you wanna know more than
Speaker 6:  just the paragraph. Well here's regular Google. And I think that is like
Speaker 6:  woefully underestimating how differently people are gonna start to use Google
Speaker 6:  as a result. And so to me it's like, it's oh, oh, making
Speaker 6:  these things in such a way that is like weird and different is one thing,
Speaker 6:  but to just push them at people and be like, this is a familiar thing that
Speaker 6:  you totally understand is a disaster. And that's so much
Speaker 6:  of what we're getting is like this thing sounds like a person. Yeah. Talk
Speaker 6:  to it like a person. It works like a person. Like it super doesn't
Speaker 6:  not even close and it all it's gonna do is run you into trouble. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I mean to me, this is the question that like all of these products
Speaker 4:  have to answer, right? Is what are people's expectations and can you change
Speaker 4:  them fast enough? I I truly do not know the answer to
Speaker 4:  that because I think what people are responding to is these
Speaker 4:  computers are talking to them and it turns out people
Speaker 4:  confidently Flirtatiously talking to you, charmingly talking to you
Speaker 4:  is a great way to get a lot of people to believe a lot of lies.
Speaker 6:  That's how you get Alex Kranz in a news boy cap.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, exactly. This is how swing dance happened to America.
Speaker 4:  I know that's true, but like Google knows this because it operates YouTube,
Speaker 4:  it knows this problem intimately, right? There's a lot of charming liars
Speaker 4:  on here. We are, we're on YouTube. But it's interesting that it's
Speaker 4:  like running full force into making the problem and like you said,
Speaker 4:  Alex owning those search results. Like that's Google's fault that they told
Speaker 4:  you that answer. Whether or not you think that it's appropriate to pop open
Speaker 4:  the back of a camera. That's Google's answers. Now. It's not some answer
Speaker 4:  in a Reddit thread. It's not some answer from a friend that you're kind of
Speaker 4:  mad at. It's just Google's problem now. It's gonna
Speaker 4:  Existential crisis about banging an iPad is on pause for
Speaker 4:  the rest of this first cast. I know you wanted more of it.
Speaker 6:  I thought you were gonna say over and I was like well that's a lie. But no
Speaker 6:  on, on pause we can live with
Speaker 4:  No Kevin Ru still wanders these streets David, by the way, we're
Speaker 4:  good friends with both Kevin and Casey at Hart Fork. That's why. Oh yeah,
Speaker 4:  we out of love. Although I do worry out of love.
Speaker 4:  All right.
Speaker 6:  Just not as much as we love our iPads.
Speaker 6:  It's like my wife, my iPad, Kevin Russ is like, I would say that the big
Speaker 6:  three,
Speaker 4:  A dog just got job a child.
Speaker 6:  He's there, he's fine.
Speaker 6:  He doesn't play me any YouTube videos.
Speaker 4:  Fair enough. Look, the OpenAI stuff and the Google stuff, right?
Speaker 4:  These like video multimodal search chat interfaces, those are the main events.
Speaker 4:  Google announced 10 million other things at
Speaker 4:  io, all of which were named Gemini
Speaker 4:  basically, or or variations of it. It's very confusing. David, can you just
Speaker 4:  run us down the stuff?
Speaker 6:  Sure. So basically the, the theme of Google IO
Speaker 6:  is just Gemini in everything. There was
Speaker 6:  Gemini in Google Photos, which powers a feature called Ask Photos that lets
Speaker 6:  you ask questions of the photos in your Google photos. The example they gave
Speaker 6:  was you can just search what's my license plate number and it'll find your
Speaker 6:  license plate number in your license plate in a photo in your Google photos.
Speaker 6:  Which as somebody who only knows my driver's license number because it's
Speaker 6:  in my Google Photos rules all about that feature. Yes,
Speaker 4:  By the way, that might be the single most important thing that they announced
Speaker 4:  was AI search and Google Photos.
Speaker 6:  Oh, it also, as far as I could tell, I wasn't there live but it, it got a
Speaker 6:  big reaction as far as I could tell. Both live on the live stream and
Speaker 6:  just in our office people being like, yes, license plate search.
Speaker 4:  Well, alright, turns out no one
Speaker 4:  knows what their license plate is. You know what I think it is? It's Google
Speaker 4:  Photos is so close to being able to do that now. So is Apple photos and it's
Speaker 4:  why that you start to ask at things it can't do. So If, you ever
Speaker 4:  search your Google photos, you quickly start to ask for things
Speaker 4:  that it can't do because it's so close to being able to do that now.
Speaker 4:  Right? So you can just ask it for like show me all the people wearing
Speaker 4:  a a blue shirt on this day in the past and it like will figure it out,
Speaker 4:  right? Because it has some ability of that knowledge. I
Speaker 4:  personally search for the word truck a lot just to gaze my now to party
Speaker 4:  pickup truck. I needed to know my VIN number for when you, I traded
Speaker 4:  in the truck and I just searched for the words VIN number and it just like
Speaker 4:  found it, right? 'cause I'd taken a, a picture of it. The idea
Speaker 4:  that you can extend that I think people responded to it. 'cause you're, they're
Speaker 4:  already trying. Yeah. So now you're gonna give the people what they want.
Speaker 4:  It's like very good.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. So that was one thing that got a lot of excitement all
Speaker 6:  sort of in the same vein of like things you already kind of wanna do. They
Speaker 6:  announced a bunch of Gemini stuff in workspace. There's a, there's a thing
Speaker 6:  where you can like ask similar questions of your email. The example they
Speaker 6:  gave was If, you have concert tickets or I think it was Nick's tickets was
Speaker 6:  one of the examples they used. You can just say like, what time did the doors
Speaker 6:  open at the next game tonight? And it'll actually look in your email for
Speaker 6:  your ticket to find that information. That kind of stuff is neat.
Speaker 6:  There was a bunch of stuff in just the kind
Speaker 6:  of general model universe. There was a new version of the
Speaker 6:  Imagine Model, which is one of the ones that developers can use for
Speaker 6:  creative tools. There was vo, which is Google's answer to Soro,
Speaker 6:  which is a text to video model, which
Speaker 5:  Seemed really cool by the way. Like yeah
Speaker 4:  It seems good. It seemed
Speaker 5:  Even better than SOA in a lot of ways.
Speaker 6:  It it also debatable whether either of them actually exist
Speaker 6:  in the world. So we'll see. There was a new thing called Gemini
Speaker 6:  Live, which was like a always on voice chatty thing. Basically very
Speaker 6:  similar to the one that OpenAI announced. Project Astra
Speaker 6:  is the big like long-term vision Gemini Live is that just sort of specific
Speaker 6:  voice thing. There were up, there was an update to synth id
Speaker 6:  which is how Google is attempting to figure out a way to
Speaker 6:  watermark AI generated stuff. They're now doing it with text, which I thought
Speaker 6:  was really interesting. But also with videos which goes along with
Speaker 6:  VO and all the stuff they're doing there. Bunch of stuff for
Speaker 6:  Gemini Advanced and Gemini. Nano and Gemini 1.5 flash, which is a
Speaker 6:  new model for all of it to be like it's, the names are insane
Speaker 6:  and I'm sure I've gotten two thirds of them wrong and I don't care because
Speaker 6:  I It's Google's fault you, you've gotten 'em all right so far. The names
Speaker 6:  are dumb. There was a new one, there's a new AI thing in YouTube
Speaker 6:  called Music AI Sandbox, which I confess I don't totally understand because
Speaker 6:  there's been a bunch of kind of overlapping AI music things
Speaker 6:  inside of YouTube and they glossed over it so quickly that I think it
Speaker 6:  might just be kind of an amalgam of some of those things already. But that's
Speaker 6:  a thing that exists. They're working with musicians on that stuff. New
Speaker 6:  Gemma models, which are Google's open sourced AI models.
Speaker 6:  Circle to search is in Android doing more stuff. They
Speaker 6:  had a bunch of little things in Android designed to make
Speaker 6:  kind of Gemini all over the operating system in interesting ways.
Speaker 4:  So the Android piece is really interesting to me like in a big
Speaker 4:  way. I dunno if any of it will come true because
Speaker 4:  Google, but Dave Burke got on stage and
Speaker 4:  started demoing AI features in Android and he's like, this works as we control
Speaker 4:  the operating system. And you put that sort of right next to, we've combined
Speaker 4:  the Android team and the Pixel team under Rick Oslo and you're like, oh,
Speaker 4:  like this is the like If, you make this really good, this
Speaker 4:  is the thing that is actually compelling to switch from a Samsung phone or
Speaker 4:  iPhone.
Speaker 6:  Yes. This is how Google thinks it wins. Yeah, for sure. Both with Pixel
Speaker 6:  specifically and with Android in general. Like I think this is true or
Speaker 6:  false, the thing they have identified as their chance to
Speaker 6:  leapfrog Apple in a really, but they've always thought AI was their way.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But now it's like the user interface for the operating system is ai.
Speaker 4:  Like they built like a super rabbit, you know, it's like that's the thing
Speaker 4:  that they're getting at. Yeah. Is like you can just be on your phone and
Speaker 4:  like circle a thing and like the robot will like go do it for you.
Speaker 4:  Or like you can just talk to it and like use the app for you. And unlike
Speaker 4:  Rabbit, Google has some AI technology.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Well and there was one thing that they talked about where
Speaker 6:  the sort of context awareness where it'll actually understand what's on the
Speaker 6:  screen as you're talking to your phone. That's the kind of thing that you
Speaker 6:  genuinely only can do. If, you control the operating system like no one else
Speaker 6:  has that access. But also Google has been trying to
Speaker 6:  do this for forever. Do you remember Google now? Yeah. Which was just the
Speaker 6:  same damn thing. Like the, the promise of so much
Speaker 6:  of the large language model stuff right now is all this stuff we've been
Speaker 6:  trying to do for 15 years we can do now because the tech is better. Like
Speaker 6:  these ideas are not new. It's so funny. They just think we
Speaker 6:  have the tech to do it now
Speaker 4:  Or the tech to do it convincingly. I just have to keep putting that asterisk
Speaker 4:  there. Right. To do it convincingly. Maybe not to do it. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  That's fair to at least make you want to try it. Yeah. Is is as far as
Speaker 6:  they have to go. There's more, there's a bunch of search stuff that
Speaker 6:  we should talk about, but it was basically like they made all the models
Speaker 6:  better and are starting to introduce some more specific models.
Speaker 6:  Like I think Gemini 1.5 Pro Flash in addition to beginning
Speaker 6:  unbelievably stupid name, horrible name is really interesting because it's
Speaker 6:  just a different version of Gemini that is just designed for speed. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Its whole job is we just paired everything down and made it as fast as we
Speaker 6:  possibly could. And I think you're gonna start to see more little things
Speaker 6:  like that as they tune to these kind of specific use cases over time.
Speaker 6:  So it really top to bottom was just, here's the thing,
Speaker 6:  we gemini it. Is it better now? Do you like it? Yeah. That was the whole
Speaker 6:  vibe.
Speaker 4:  So I will say I think the most important one is Google Photos. It's the one
Speaker 4:  that will hit the, the most people the fastest. I think thats right. And
Speaker 4:  change how people use that application. which I think is cool. Like really
Speaker 4:  cool. Then there's the rest of it. which I, you know, I think the major criticism,
Speaker 4:  I was like, there's too much stuff. It was too unfocused. Like they just
Speaker 4:  said the word Gemini a million. Like If. you just read that list of things
Speaker 4:  named Gemini. Gemini 1.5 Pro Gemini 1.5 slash Gemini Live Gemini
Speaker 4:  now Gemini. Like it's insane. Yeah. They announced the thing where
Speaker 4:  they're like, here's a prototype and idea where you have an AI teammate
Speaker 4:  who has their own Gmail address. No, she just like yell at it. No. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  His name was Chip. That's like, this is a ridiculous like, like this. I forgot
Speaker 4:  about Chip. This is pure vapor. Yeah. Like you are announcing vaporware,
Speaker 4:  there's no reason to do this. Like you're just, why. Right. You
Speaker 4:  could pare it down to like, here's our product and here's all the things
Speaker 4:  it can do and that'd be more focused. But I think Google thinks it has to
Speaker 4:  like cover the waterfront of every idea you might have with AI and be like,
Speaker 4:  we had that idea too. And we have the infrastructure to pull it off and we
Speaker 4:  have Google workspace so we can just deploy a hundred AI teammates to your
Speaker 4:  Google workspace tomorrow. Startups. Don't you dare.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean I, I really like the, the way I've come to think about
Speaker 6:  all of these things is that they used to be kind of half for
Speaker 6:  developers and half for like the general public to sort of show the world
Speaker 6:  what you've been working on Now. It's like a third for Wall
Speaker 6:  Street. Yep. So that you can make sure investors trust that you have
Speaker 6:  a real AI strategy because fundamentally that's what a lot of this is
Speaker 6:  about. Google is still fighting the idea that it got caught off guard by
Speaker 6:  OpenAI and ChatGPT and GPT and is still trying to assert itself
Speaker 6:  to investors specifically as a big player in the AI future,
Speaker 6:  which means trillions of dollars. If, you can convince everybody that
Speaker 6:  that's the case. So it's like it's a third Wall Street, it's like
Speaker 6:  50% developers and then it's just a little teeny tiny
Speaker 6:  slice left for regular people.
Speaker 4:  You almost did the rest of that math and you just, you walked away from s
Speaker 4:  the end
Speaker 6:  17% regular people. There you go.
Speaker 4:  And
Speaker 6:  It's just like you, you could just feel Google getting up
Speaker 6:  there over and over and being like, we are good at ai. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Look at
Speaker 6:  There's so much of it. Yeah. Like we did it
Speaker 4:  Ai, that's how I felt about Apple. The iPad event. Yeah. They were just like
Speaker 4:  the best AI piece. It's like, what are you talking about? Yeah. And it's
Speaker 4:  like this is made for analysts. So the one thing that's really interesting
Speaker 4:  there, specifically in the context of Wall Street is AI overviews and search.
Speaker 4:  Hmm. Which they announced very quickly. So Google
Speaker 4:  has had this thing called search generative experience sort of in testing
Speaker 4:  for a long time now a year where you search for something and
Speaker 4:  there's like an AI answer and it's like here's this stuff and they've been
Speaker 4:  tweaking it and messing with it and like seeing how it works for a while.
Speaker 4:  And what they announced at io, which is a huge deal, is
Speaker 4:  it's rolling out to everyone in the US like this week it's gonna be called
Speaker 4:  AI Overviews and it's, that's it. This is search now.
Speaker 4:  And on earnings calls last year Shar was saying this is the future of search.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like search will be this thing. This is where we're going and here
Speaker 4:  we are where you search for something on Google and depending on the query,
Speaker 4:  Google just reads the web and delivers the answer for you.
Speaker 4:  And next to that they have this thing AI powered like search
Speaker 4:  page, which is basically what Arc browser is doing. Right. Where you
Speaker 4:  like go ask Arc a question and it like reads the web and it like makes a
Speaker 4:  little webpage for you with all the answers in it. Google's gonna do that
Speaker 4:  now. Yep. As the search engine results page. The serp,
Speaker 4:  instead of 10 blue links, it will just like make a little custom webpage
Speaker 4:  of like best anniversary restaurants in Dallas and be like,
Speaker 4:  we've concocted this webpage for you. That's wild. Right. This is like
Speaker 4:  flip the table on how the internet works in a big way.
Speaker 4:  I would say the response from the media industry in particular
Speaker 4:  is apocalyptic. Like that's the word I would use Bear
Speaker 4:  the, the CEO of the News Media Alliance, which I think we have to disclose.
Speaker 4:  Like I think Fox media's in it, I don't know. It's like not my thing but
Speaker 4:  someone's in it. Sure. We are the media. We are in the news media.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We run, we operate in the media business and our executives are in
Speaker 4:  various media business organizations. I dunno that's their side of the house.
Speaker 4:  I just complained, but there's a disclosure. But the CO of the News Media
Speaker 4:  Alliance said to CNN, this is catastrophic to our traffic. Like Google's
Speaker 4:  gonna keep all the traffic and they're not gonna send us any traffic. We've
Speaker 4:  been talking a lot about little sites that are already seeing Google
Speaker 4:  traffic go to zero. I've been talking for years about this thing I called
Speaker 4:  Google Zero, which if you've been listening to VERGE has for a long time,
Speaker 4:  you know that like our first big referer when we started was Yahoo. And we
Speaker 4:  would like write stories about Phish technology because Yahoo algorithm
Speaker 4:  loved Phish. And we would just like do that on Fridays to
Speaker 4:  fuck with Yahoo and it worked. I don't know. That's, that's how I built this
Speaker 4:  business. Like, I'm sorry. Yeah. And then, you know, there's like Facebook
Speaker 4:  traffic for a while and it went away and I'm always like the thing, it will
Speaker 4:  go away. That's like my inherent paranoia after all this time in the media.
Speaker 4:  And I'm like, that number will go down. And that's Google and that's the
Speaker 4:  last refer of note across the entire industry. I've been calling this Google
Speaker 4:  Zero for years. Like, what are you gonna do if your Google traffic goes to
Speaker 4:  zero on decoder? Ask me the executives all this time. And this is the
Speaker 4:  moment where I think it clicked into reality for a lot of those executives
Speaker 4:  that Google is gonna start answering the questions by reading their sites
Speaker 4:  and delivering an AI summary of the answer. And Google's response to this,
Speaker 4:  I, and again this is, we, we move through this quickly. 'cause I talked about
Speaker 4:  this with s decoder quite a bit that's going on Monday, but
Speaker 4:  Google's answer to this, Liz's answer to this Liz reader on search is
Speaker 4:  actually the links in the AI overviews get more clicks.
Speaker 4:  That's, that's their answer. Like straight up. They're like, actually we're
Speaker 4:  gonna send more traffic this way. Hmm. No one knows if that is true. The
Speaker 4:  only people who know who have the data to evaluate that are Sun Shy and Liz
Speaker 4:  Reed. And it's like, well, if that's true, that's great. If it's
Speaker 4:  not true. Or worse, if the haves
Speaker 4:  get bigger, like you send more traffic to the big corporate sites
Speaker 4:  and no traffic at all to anyone else
Speaker 4:  that's bad for the, like, that's bad. Right. That will reshape the internet
Speaker 4:  in particular ways. And maybe you think this is great, like maybe you think
Speaker 4:  that indie media or whatever or small sites should build their
Speaker 4:  own network of traffic and their own, I, this is our belief, right? Like
Speaker 4:  my belief very strongly is we should have our own audience away from platforms.
Speaker 4:  But If, you are just like operating today and you're like, oh, my traffic
Speaker 4:  is gonna go to zero, my Google traffic's gonna go to zero. you don't have
Speaker 4:  the runway to like do the thing.
Speaker 6:  Right. They just turned it on like it's just on now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. Like your, your business is gonna go away. Yeah. And I I, that
Speaker 4:  is the thing that I think the pressure from OpenAI, the competitive
Speaker 4:  pressure from OpenAI and all these other companies, it pushed Google to do
Speaker 4:  a a thing very quickly that's gonna reshape the internet in almost
Speaker 4:  indescribable ways because the traffic flows of search traffic
Speaker 4:  are about to like table flip.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I do think the, the example that most immediately keeps coming to
Speaker 6:  mind for me for this is the what time does the Super Bowl start kind of thing.
Speaker 6:  And that to some extent has already died thanks to the knowledge graph,
Speaker 6:  which now is just like a, it just pops up a thing at the top. But what
Speaker 6:  I, I talked to Liz Reed a few days before IO and one of the things that she
Speaker 6:  said almost in as many words is that
Speaker 6:  there is a type of information on the internet that Google just views as
Speaker 6:  commodity information that I shouldn't need to go to another
Speaker 6:  website to know the answer to. Right? Like before If, you wanted to know
Speaker 6:  the years that Abraham Lincoln was the president. You would search that on
Speaker 6:  Google and then you would click on a link and Google at some point has decided
Speaker 6:  that that is just commoditized information that belongs to
Speaker 6:  no one. And so I should have to go nowhere to get it. And
Speaker 6:  then If, you go all the way down the spectrum, you get down to like
Speaker 6:  human perspectives and original stuff and really beautiful art.
Speaker 6:  Right? And that is the stuff that I think Google earnestly believes should
Speaker 6:  still belong to those people. And that Google's job is still
Speaker 6:  to send you as the user to those places. And I think Google would like you
Speaker 6:  to believe that it is very obvious where one of those things ends and the
Speaker 6:  other begins. And in fact, the whole middle ground, which is most of the
Speaker 6:  internet, is some, is is somewhere in between. And there is just no
Speaker 6:  line that it is possible to draw between what,
Speaker 6:  what is it just sort of out there in the ether that everyone can
Speaker 6:  know. And the idea that you and I both used
Speaker 6:  some of our time to write a story hoping we'd get some clicks and some mad
Speaker 6:  sense that that's actually like a unnecessary thing for
Speaker 6:  the enjoyment of the internet. And maybe that should go away. I'm somewhat
Speaker 6:  receptive to that version of the conversation where that ends and good
Speaker 6:  things that deserve to exist begins is now up to Google. And
Speaker 6:  that is what scares me about this. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And they have not really articulated anything
Speaker 4:  beyond like the cream or rice the top, you know, like Yeah,
Speaker 6:  They say high quality information and human perspectives and a bunch of just
Speaker 6:  like vague buzzwords that don't give anybody anything. Isn't
Speaker 5:  This like just what Ask Geeves was doing for
Speaker 5:  decades? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like with
Speaker 6:  The
Speaker 5:  Better name. And did we all decide that that was a stupid way to interact
Speaker 5:  with the internet? And that's why asked G still exists, but
Speaker 5:  way fewer people use it now. I think it still
Speaker 6:  Exists. It's ask.com now.
Speaker 5:  Sorry,
Speaker 4:  JS was fired,
Speaker 6:  Pleases
Speaker 4:  Can't, some old tweets surfaced and Js is no longer
Speaker 4:  with us. But
Speaker 6:  Again, Alex, that's, that's a perfect example of like, none of these are
Speaker 6:  new ideas, right? The the, the only thing that's new is that
Speaker 6:  everyone has decided it's now possible to do this. Well yeah.
Speaker 5:  S.com does TV show reviews now.
Speaker 4:  Oh my God. Sure.
Speaker 4:  So that's pure, just like Google Day, perfect example, right? Yeah. I mean
Speaker 4:  this is like why we spent a year last year covering the SEO
Speaker 4:  industry because I, I like, I think it's important
Speaker 4:  to describe the thing as it was before you can understand how it changed.
Speaker 4:  So we're like, let's just, these are the la these are the glory days
Speaker 4:  of the SEO industry as it exists today, which is you buy as.com
Speaker 4:  and you search for which TV shows are trending and you shove a bunch of
Speaker 4:  content onto a high ranking domain to collect some pennies. This is happening,
Speaker 4:  by the way, across the media industry and that's happening at like AI scale.
Speaker 4:  Like you buy Sports Illustrated and you shove a bunch of AI content
Speaker 4:  on it is a real thing that has happened. Yep, yep. Right? You you, you buy
Speaker 4:  these like zombie domain names. What's the last one? The
Speaker 6:  All Gizmo.
Speaker 4:  The all gizmo.
Speaker 6:  Oh no. Was it the Hairpin
Speaker 4:  Hair? The Hairpin? It is the Hairpin. Yeah. That's what I'm thinking of.
Speaker 4:  Like this beloved women's blog and you show a bunch of AI content on it,
Speaker 4:  like that's already happening. This should wipe all that
Speaker 4:  out. Right? That's I think what Google would like is to, to wipe all that
Speaker 4:  noise out. That implies by the way that Google can make good
Speaker 4:  determinations about what's good and what's bad, which the current state
Speaker 4:  of Google does not provide a huge amount of evidence for. It also
Speaker 4:  implies that Google will prioritize the beautiful
Speaker 4:  human content over the AI content when a huge part of
Speaker 4:  Google's business is making the AI content weird
Speaker 6:  And monetizing the AI content. Yeah. That actually Google has an incentive
Speaker 6:  for that content to exist at giant scale.
Speaker 5:  It also kind of pulls the curtain back on like Google probably more
Speaker 5:  than Google should want it to, right? Like we, we, we,
Speaker 5:  especially in our industry, we know that Google is an enormously powerful
Speaker 5:  thing that really controls a lot of conversations and stuff simply by
Speaker 5:  virtue of the fact that If, you want to engage in these conversations. You
Speaker 5:  first go search for them and the first place you go search for them is Google.
Speaker 5:  And so Google kind of dictates how you, how you perceive these things if
Speaker 5:  Google just starts answering the questions, it is like the theater of, oh,
Speaker 5:  I search Google to figure this out and I have the agency of finding
Speaker 5:  the answers is gone. It's just Google,
Speaker 4:  Dude. This is the phrase, yeah. They use this on stage. Let Google do the
Speaker 4:  Googling for you. This was the frame for horrible, talked about search.
Speaker 5:  Horrible, horrible way to do it.
Speaker 4:  It's a lot there. We can talk about this forever. Yeah, I mean I
Speaker 4:  personally can talk about this forever entire some ways. And I assure you
Speaker 4:  that If, you work at Vox Media, you have heard me talk about nothing else
Speaker 4:  for four years. Like a lot of The Verge
Speaker 4:  is designed around Google Zero. And the point
Speaker 4:  is, I, I don't think anyone deserves
Speaker 4:  traffic from Google. Right? I, that expectation I think has actually been
Speaker 4:  really unhealthy for the media industry that like you, we are entitled to
Speaker 4:  traffic from platforms, especially for us because we cover the platforms.
Speaker 4:  Like I would like some distance there in a real way. And also just
Speaker 4:  like I'm a brat and I don't wanna be dependent on anyone ever for anything.
Speaker 4:  But this is a pivotal moment like Google
Speaker 4:  waving through, we're gonna do AI overview and search for everyone in the
Speaker 4:  US and then sort of immediately pivoting to, oh, and also you can search
Speaker 4:  your Google photos. That was, they like lit a bomb and they're
Speaker 4:  like, and you can find your license plates. And they spent no time on it.
Speaker 4:  It does not appear that anybody knew they were gonna do this. We'll see how
Speaker 4:  it shakes out. I think the next 12 to 18 months are gonna be an absolutely
Speaker 4:  bananas time in media. I think this is the thing that's gonna, I
Speaker 4:  I would predict that there are some lawsuits filed over this from the various
Speaker 4:  media lobbying groups the same way that they've already started suing OpenAI.
Speaker 4:  There's gonna be a big shakeout from AI
Speaker 4:  overviews and a huge part of it, and this is just what I'll focus on is
Speaker 4:  Google's claim is that it will send more traffic. You cannot measure
Speaker 4:  that claim inside of Google's own tools today or with any
Speaker 4:  data that Google is providing. And if they want to close that loop, they
Speaker 4:  have to make it like testable. Yeah. But this is true,
Speaker 4:  right? That you have to be able to see the data for yourself and say, okay,
Speaker 4:  like we were the one that showed up in the AI overview box and we got way
Speaker 4:  more traffic from it than we when we were getting, like, you cannot measure
Speaker 4:  that today. So we'll see. But I, you listened to
Speaker 4:  Decoders nar 'cause we talked about it a lot that's gonna on Monday, but
Speaker 4:  we're gonna be talking about this I I guarantee you for about 18 months because
Speaker 4:  the internet is gonna reshaped around this particular feature in search
Speaker 6:  And it's gonna change a lot between now and then. Yeah. Like there, there
Speaker 6:  are the, the weirdest thing about this is like SGE changed a ton in
Speaker 6:  a year and I think Google is
Speaker 6:  maybe going to be surprised at how different it looks once you give it
Speaker 6:  to everybody.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's, it's, it's gonna be weird. All right, we should just take a break.
Speaker 4:  We're come back with the lightning round, which as of yet is
Speaker 4:  unsponsored, but the bites they're coming, it's gonna
Speaker 4:  happen one of these days. We'll be right back.
Speaker 16:  It's loud, deafening caco. It's a nightmare oppressive.
Speaker 17:  And just what is it that many people think is pretty
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. It's lightning round. Sponsored by me. Neil a
Speaker 4:  Patel. Thank you. The guy who coined the first, I
Speaker 6:  Didn't get any of that money. I dunno.
Speaker 17:  I was like, you're so generous. Where is it?
Speaker 4:  I'm just moving money around my own house. I'm just doing tax fraud.
Speaker 4:  There's kind of a lot in lightning round. David, do you go first?
Speaker 6:  So there's a Microsoft Surface event on Monday, which
Speaker 6:  there's been a lot of hype for because Qualcomm and Microsoft and others
Speaker 6:  have been kind of quietly ti intimidating that they were about to
Speaker 6:  get a new generation of Snap J and chips that are going to be like as good
Speaker 6:  as the M series Apple chips and the war between Mac and
Speaker 6:  PC is about to go on. And then we got a huge leak from Dell,
Speaker 6:  I think it was a 311 page document detailing
Speaker 6:  the next X-P-X-P-S 13, which is Dell's best laptop.
Speaker 6:  It's like the default, which Windows laptop should most people buy if the
Speaker 6:  XPS 13 And the, the things
Speaker 6:  that they're saying on here are pretty unbelievable.
Speaker 6:  12 hours of battery life, 13 hours of battery life on the lower
Speaker 6:  spec models, local video playback for 29 hours.
Speaker 6:  Tons of power that like, at least according to the marketing copy,
Speaker 6:  the things that we've been thinking might be true of this run of
Speaker 6:  Snapdragon processors might actually be
Speaker 6:  true of these Snapdragon processors.
Speaker 5:  I just wanna highlight that
Speaker 5:  Apple last week, like in kind of a surprising move
Speaker 5:  announced their M four processor in an iPad. And I
Speaker 5:  don't think that's an accident, right? Like, like Nila, you were talking
Speaker 5:  earlier about how a lot of these things are for Wall Street,
Speaker 5:  apple did it for Wall Street. 'cause it is very aware that
Speaker 5:  this is happening right now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, we'll see. We'll see. Yeah. I would be remiss if I didn't note
Speaker 4:  two things. One, boy, we've heard this story before. Oh yeah.
Speaker 4:  So who knows. But two, a lot of what we have on
Speaker 4:  a lot of our coverage is in Tom Warren's new newsletter Notepad by Tom Warren.
Speaker 4:  Yes. Which is his new newsletter about all things. Microsoft's particularly
Speaker 4:  ai, the future of PCs in this particular way and whatever Microsoft is doing
Speaker 4:  in gaming, which I won't even continue to talk about because it will
Speaker 4:  immediately be another hour of the first test. But you can, you can sign
Speaker 4:  up for a notepad now. You can get it in a bundle with command line. We have
Speaker 4:  two paid newsletters where we see, you see our empires
Speaker 4:  growing.
Speaker 5:  I hope there's some like arrows pointing down saying bye now.
Speaker 6:  Subscribe to Tom's newsletter so that he can buy one of these new X Ps thirteens.
Speaker 6:  That's really, that's really what ELA is saying here, that's Tom needs the
Speaker 6:  battery life so he can write his newsletter. Please subscribe to Notepad.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, he's gotta, he's gotta write a lot of those every week now. Okay, Alex,
Speaker 4:  what's first,
Speaker 5:  Have you heard of p?
Speaker 4:  That's a great name. Sorry. What?
Speaker 5:  Otherwise known as
Speaker 5:  PPPS. SPP.
Speaker 5:  You could say it like that. Which is how it's supposed to be because it's,
Speaker 5:  it's PSP.
Speaker 6:  That's how you lure cats, right? You go But
Speaker 5:  It's,
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  You just keep saying it until somebody tells you to shut up and then you're
Speaker 5:  like, yeah, do you wanna play it? It's, it's a new emulation software. It's
Speaker 5:  P the PSP. Do you guys remember the PSP? Oh
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I had a PSP you I one. I had one of the great cartridges of all time.
Speaker 4:  Oh,
Speaker 5:  I broke one of those cartridges. But I loved the game and I was
Speaker 5:  like poor. So I couldn't go get a new one and I'd always have to be like
Speaker 5:  flicking the plastic just to get it just right and then putting it back in.
Speaker 4:  Only Sony invents MiniDisc and then invents another mini disc. Yeah. For
Speaker 4:  the PSP. But
Speaker 5:  Somehow a little worse.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But now this, now you can play it on the iPhone, which is really
Speaker 5:  exciting because it was like a tank game and I really wanna play that tank
Speaker 5:  game. Yeah. And I'm gonna be able to play it on my iPhone now. And also Retro
Speaker 5:  Arch, which is like the emulator software. So Retro Arch
Speaker 5:  lets you basically play just about any kind of, if if somebody
Speaker 5:  out there has created emulation software for a console you have
Speaker 5:  never heard of, you can probably find it in retro arch. Nice.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's real. The software itself is a little,
Speaker 5:  it is not the most user friendly. It is not gonna be as needed. Easy.
Speaker 6:  It's hideous. Just, just say yes ugly. It's the ugliest apple or
Speaker 5:  Ugly. Yeah. But it works. It does the job. I just put it on my
Speaker 5:  my my Apple TV and as almost as soon as
Speaker 5:  we are done recording, I'll be putting a budget games on my Apple TV and
Speaker 5:  testing it for, for work. And definitely just for
Speaker 5:  work. But it's, it's cool and it's just remarkable 'cause
Speaker 5:  like even a couple of years ago you were like trying to figure out how to
Speaker 5:  get all of these emulated games onto your TV and
Speaker 5:  it was really limited and you could do it like a raspberry pie, you could
Speaker 5:  mess around with Android, all of that. And now you can just do
Speaker 5:  it on an Apple TV and it's like, welcome Apple. I've been here for 10 years,
Speaker 5:  but I'm excited you're here because I kind of like my Apple TV more than
Speaker 5:  my Shield tv. I'm so sorry to all the Shield people. I'm sorry
Speaker 4:  Dude, end the show. It's
Speaker 5:  In the guest bedroom now.
Speaker 4:  It's the most Wow. I
Speaker 6:  Have have been stewing on the idea and being increasingly
Speaker 6:  angry about it that the Apple TV is the only good set top box left.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They're all bad. But it is the least bad
Speaker 6:  because it is the one least destroyed by like ads
Speaker 6:  and scams and all kinds of other, I mean mean
Speaker 5:  It's still, I watched Palm Royale because it was like, do you wanna watch
Speaker 5:  Palm Royale? And I was like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  Carol Burnett,
Speaker 4:  No. Apple's figured out that it can just do, it can just be a Roku. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  and it, it's headed there and extra blue. It's
Speaker 6:  Infuriating. But I will say retro in particular, being on the Apple tv,
Speaker 6:  it's like a native Apple TV app and it
Speaker 5:  Just Native is
Speaker 6:  Strong. Yeah. Yeah. It's, but it exists on the Apple tv. Yeah. And some
Speaker 6:  of the others work with like airplay and stuff and are starting to be pretty
Speaker 6:  good. But the Apple TV as a like retro console
Speaker 6:  thing is going to be a big
Speaker 5:  Deal. Yeah. You can just do it now retro. Like there's gonna be a lot more
Speaker 5:  that will probably be much more user friendly. But retro arch is, is is the
Speaker 5:  big one. You can just go play it now. And that's dope.
Speaker 4:  And yeah. I I keep thinking about feel weird saying David said a couple weeks
Speaker 4:  ago, which was all of this regulatory stuff was really like
Speaker 4:  hard to understand and then the emulators happen and now everyone gets it
Speaker 4:  that like a little bit of regulatory pressure opened up the application model
Speaker 4:  on the app and it's like, oh, everyone wants this. Yeah. And it's like,
Speaker 4:  particularly for the Apple tv, apple has insisted
Speaker 4:  that you like do its dumb stuff and has not won, like that
Speaker 4:  product has not won and it's by far the smallest install base.
Speaker 4:  It has the least, like the idea that everyone's gonna be playing games and
Speaker 4:  the Apple TV is like, did not come true. And now it's like, oh shit, everyone's
Speaker 4:  gonna be playing games with their Apple tv.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I have never wanted to actually hook up a, a controller to an Apple
Speaker 5:  TV before today. Yeah. Like every other time people, they'd be like, you
Speaker 5:  wanna play this game on your Apple tv? No. Yeah, it's don't ask me that.
Speaker 5:  I'm not gonna lie to you. Like, no. And now I'm like, okay, I I I wanna do
Speaker 5:  that. I wanna play sugar on my tv.
Speaker 4:  I think I, I honestly think the emulator stuff is just the biggest indictment
Speaker 4:  of apples and like closed fisted ness that you can get. Yep. 'cause it's
Speaker 4:  like the second you let people do good stuff, they're like more excited about
Speaker 4:  these products than they have been in a long time. Totally. I have two in
Speaker 4:  my lightning round. One of them is just telling David to talk about his iPad
Speaker 4:  reviews, which I know you already talked about earlier this week, but
Speaker 4:  I wasn't here so I just, it feels like the, everyone
Speaker 4:  landed in exactly the same place, which is,
Speaker 4:  boy I hope WW C involves an iPad of us update.
Speaker 6:  So yes and no. The conversation around this has actually been really interesting
Speaker 6:  because yeah, the most of the reviews, including mine, basically say that
Speaker 6:  like, it is a, I I actually worried I was going overboard. You
Speaker 6:  were gushing about the hardware. There were others who went much further
Speaker 6:  like the, with the IED Pro in particular, like it is, it is a spectacular
Speaker 6:  piece of engineering and design. But the question forever
Speaker 6:  is like, what is this thing actually for? And I think
Speaker 6:  what has come true this week is there's been a subset of people who are like,
Speaker 6:  yeah, this thing needs to be more like a Mac. Let me run Mac
Speaker 6:  apps, open it up, let me do whatever I want, like give me a Mac
Speaker 6:  in this body and I will be happy. And then there's a much
Speaker 6:  different set of people who are louder than I thought who
Speaker 6:  are like, no, this is, that is not the point I like, maybe I want
Speaker 6:  to touch screen Mac, we'll have that conversation separately, but the iPad
Speaker 6:  is supposed to be different. And one of the things I said in my review is
Speaker 6:  that like after talking to people at Apple and about the iPad, and I've just
Speaker 6:  been covering this a long time, like Apple's running theory is that it can
Speaker 6:  do like whatever the opposite of death by a thousand cuts is
Speaker 6:  that like, rather than have sort of one big thing that
Speaker 6:  makes the iPad for everybody, it can have one that is for you and
Speaker 6:  Eli and one that is for you Alex and one that is for me David. And we'll
Speaker 6:  all buy iPads and we'll use them differently. And that, that for Apple is
Speaker 6:  like the ideal outcome. And there are a lot of people for whom
Speaker 6:  that idea is like really compelling and really romantic. Those people tend
Speaker 6:  to be people who have that specific thing in the iPad already. People
Speaker 6:  who love the pencil or people who like do the insane
Speaker 6:  architect thing of like holding up the iPad and walking around the table
Speaker 6:  to show somebody your designs, which I'm not convinced is real.
Speaker 6:  We
Speaker 4:  Got an email from someone who, I don't remember the email specifically, but
Speaker 4:  they're either they are an interior designer or they're, they're partners,
Speaker 4:  an interior designer and they're like, we just run the iPad to the ground
Speaker 4:  like every day. Yeah. It's a thing. It's like great, great.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But so I think the, the question then for Apple is like,
Speaker 6:  okay, do you try to find the big mainstreaming thing, which I think the obvious
Speaker 6:  answer is make it more laptop or
Speaker 6:  just like open it up so that people can do more stuff on it. Or do
Speaker 6:  you keep just chipping away at this thing like one tiny use case at a time
Speaker 6:  until you've built the magic. And I think like that
Speaker 6:  second approach is way more fun and interesting and leads to something very
Speaker 6:  cool in the long run. We're also 14 years into this. Yes. And Apple has found
Speaker 6:  two.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And to me the the, the thing that I got, I was, you know, like
Speaker 4:  on planes all week, basically just like watching people angrily post each
Speaker 4:  other with the iPad and I was like, I, these are,
Speaker 4:  these are the same iPad reviews we've been writing for years.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's the same iPad.
Speaker 4:  Like I forgot that I wrote this iPad review in 2013 when the first iPad
Speaker 4:  came out, like the same exact review running Iowa seven.
Speaker 4:  Like boy it would be cool if I could do stuff with this. And then I wrote
Speaker 4:  a version of that review in 2018 and then David you wrote a version of that
Speaker 4:  review yesterday and then I just saw Dieter at the Google event and he was
Speaker 4:  like, I wrote these iPad reviews. Like Dieter is the one I believe who co
Speaker 4:  coined the phrase it's an iPad. It's like, so look directly to camera and
Speaker 4:  be like, it's an iPad and you know exactly what that means. Yep. That's,
Speaker 4:  that's us. We did that here. And the thing that gets me about it, the thing
Speaker 4:  that I've, the, the reason I wanna talk about it right after emulators is
Speaker 4:  it's Apple's business model that is holding this computer back. Yes.
Speaker 4:  It is not the capabilities of the iPad or some idealism or
Speaker 4:  blah blah blah blah blah blah blah. It is Apple's business model
Speaker 4:  is preventing application developers from using the full power of the iPad.
Speaker 4:  The fact that this thing cannot actually run a desktop web browser. They
Speaker 4:  say it's si plus it absolutely is not. No. Nope. It just
Speaker 4:  isn't. Also
Speaker 6:  If, you go to docs gut.google.com in the browser
Speaker 6:  on an iPad, it will punt you to the Google Docs app. It is the most try,
Speaker 6:  most miserable
Speaker 4:  Experience in the world. So what's really interesting is the Google Docs
Speaker 4:  app, this is, you know, all our years are in the iPad. We would complain
Speaker 4:  about this and Apple would always be like, yeah, well who cares? Only journalists
Speaker 4:  use Google Docs. And then they realized the journalists who review the iPad
Speaker 4:  use Google Docs. And so they fixed it by faking the user
Speaker 4:  agent in Mobile Safari to tell Google Docs that it's desktop safari.
Speaker 4:  So you can run the good Google Docs in Safari in the iPad. What they
Speaker 4:  did not do was make mobile safari good.
Speaker 6:  Right. Or fix it in Chrome or any of the other browsers that you can run
Speaker 6:  on the iPad.
Speaker 4:  Right. and it that the reason for that is
Speaker 4:  straightforwardly a business model reason. It's not that the thing isn't
Speaker 4:  powerful enough to run No. The regular safari that you can run. It's like
Speaker 4:  stupid this thing. Right? You Yeah. I have an Intel Mac
Speaker 4:  downstairs. I have a 2015 iMac sitting right over there that is
Speaker 4:  one 10th as powerful as the iPad Pro. Yeah. It runs regular
Speaker 4:  Safari just fine. It runs Chrome in a way that suggests that I should
Speaker 4:  buy a new computer but it runs Chrome. Right. The reason
Speaker 4:  Apple doesn't allow that to happen on the iPad is because the web
Speaker 4:  is now the most powerful application distribution mechanism that has
Speaker 4:  ever existed. It is by far the most popular in the world. And If, you bring
Speaker 4:  that to the iPad, the app store goes away because now
Speaker 4:  it's just, now you just have a laptop, you have a Chromebook and
Speaker 6:  Really nice Chromebook
Speaker 4:  Business, a really beautiful Chromebook and Apple's business will not allow
Speaker 4:  that to happen. And so this product is just absolutely held back by a business
Speaker 4:  decision that maybe it's fair, I don't think fine make
Speaker 4:  your business decisions, but we should be honest that this isn't a technical
Speaker 4:  limitation or an idealistic limitation or blah blah. Apple is making a hard
Speaker 4:  business decision about the application models on its products. Regulators
Speaker 4:  are starting to crack that open and people are starting to see, oh, emulators
Speaker 4:  are great. Like all this other stuff that we could do is great. And the last
Speaker 4:  one to fall, I promise you is they will put a desktop class browser on the
Speaker 4:  iPad and it will suddenly become a hundred times more powerful as a computer.
Speaker 4:  And more and more people will be like, I can just use this all time. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's not the file system, although I love a file system, it's literally
Speaker 4:  the application environment is completely neutered.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, no, I I I absolutely agree. And I think the browser solves
Speaker 6:  a much bigger set of problems than like, you know, X
Speaker 6:  86 interoperability Yeah. With the old apps that you wanna use. 'cause like
Speaker 6:  I'm fine, there's going to be a bunch of apps you can never use on the iPad.
Speaker 6:  So be it the web, there's no good excuse
Speaker 6:  for that to not be one of those things that doesn't
Speaker 5:  Even work anymore because all the laptops are ARM-based.
Speaker 6:  Yes. I mean that's true. Like including, including Apples. Yeah. Like this,
Speaker 6:  like the most
Speaker 5:  Powerful laptop processor line is now in the iPad first. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'm just saying like the, the thing about the iPad, the thing that
Speaker 4:  it's been missing to me from the discourse from the beginning is like
Speaker 4:  Apple designs every inch of this product, right. That they
Speaker 4:  are, they make the screen and the input devices and the operating system
Speaker 4:  and they're like, there's not a thing in this that is not an Apple choice
Speaker 4:  and this is the thing that they want.
Speaker 6:  Yes,
Speaker 4:  Fine. But then you have to be like, apple chose to limit this,
Speaker 4:  this specific way. And
Speaker 6:  I think there's a version of that trade that is more palatable at, you know,
Speaker 6:  $349 for the 10th gen iPad than at like, yes.
Speaker 6:  I mean I saw people spending two and $3,000 on the, and I just
Speaker 6:  like, I think the, the argument that this should be a different device, that
Speaker 6:  it, it it's meant for different things. It has does different things well,
Speaker 6:  like no at that price it should do everything well that it is physically
Speaker 6:  capable of doing and it just can't. and it is, it is like you're not
Speaker 6:  letting
Speaker 5:  It, I do need to fight you on one thing, David. 'cause I was one of those
Speaker 5:  people that spent way too much money on an iPad Pro this week. Yeah. Love
Speaker 5:  I, oh yeah. I got the 11 inch. It's the first one I've, that first iPad Pro
Speaker 5:  I've had since the 20 18 1. That magic keyboard case,
Speaker 5:  even though it's the new one and it's all much better, is horrible. Really?
Speaker 5:  It is. It's so thick. It is. So like as soon as you, you
Speaker 5:  drop that iPad into it, all of the magic of it goes away. And I was like,
Speaker 5:  okay, it's so, it's the exact same as my 2018 iPad, but the screen's better.
Speaker 5:  Like that was the immediate feeling I had Interesting in a really like, demoralizing
Speaker 5:  way.
Speaker 6:  There is something, there is something to that. I mean, it, it doubles the
Speaker 6:  size of the iPad. Like the keyboard at this point I think is both thicker
Speaker 6:  and heavier than Yeah. The actual iPad, which is
Speaker 6:  bonkers and probably says more about how thin the iPad is than anything else.
Speaker 6:  But also like if it were a little thinner, it would be flopper
Speaker 6:  even than, yeah. It's just an unsolvable
Speaker 5:  Problem. Things. Yeah. I I mean if it is the same feeling you get when you
Speaker 5:  use like those inexpensive Chrome Chromebooks that are convertible
Speaker 5:  Chromebooks or whatever, right? And it's like, okay, what do you want? And
Speaker 5:  like, yes, realistically having it be feel like a laptop
Speaker 5:  is more satisfying, but also I hate it.
Speaker 6:  I get that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I, I miss the surface. Does it better? I'm gonna play with
Speaker 4:  yours Alex. 'cause I really thought about buying,
Speaker 6:  I'll bring it in for you. The surface, having a built in kickstand and then
Speaker 6:  all you have to do is attach the keyboard is the correct way. Yep. I
Speaker 6:  believe that with every fiber of my being.
Speaker 4:  Man, look, Mac versus PC is back on Subscribe to Notepad by Tom Warren
Speaker 4:  for all the latest on the newly resurgent Mac versus
Speaker 4:  PC battle where everything old is new again. That was my lightning round
Speaker 4:  one. The other one I was gonna point out is Andy Hawkins wrote a great piece
Speaker 4:  about just like self-driving cars have hit a wall. And I was gonna make
Speaker 4:  the same comparison to ai, which is everyone got really excited about technology
Speaker 4:  and then it just didn't do the thing. Yep.
Speaker 4:  And I, I would just caution everyone, like can they actually do the thing?
Speaker 4:  But you should go read that piece by any 'cause. It's very good. I think
Speaker 4:  we were like five hours over. Yeah, we should go. Yeah. Should we talk about
Speaker 4:  search for a little bit longer?
Speaker 4:  All right. There's much more to come on Monday. Again. We had the interview,
Speaker 4:  Sundar, we, he and I got into it. I like talking to Sooner. I've talked to
Speaker 4:  him once a year for a long time now. Basically
Speaker 4:  he, he was fire in this one. So stay tuned for that on Monday. And then it
Speaker 4:  says here on Sunday we're gonna do the five senses of gaming,
Speaker 4:  smell and taste. Oh yeah. I dunno what that means. I'm very worried about
Speaker 4:  what Liam and David are doing with the For Chest, but it sounds great.
Speaker 6:  This face on David is just great. That's
Speaker 4:  You. David
Speaker 6:  Is great. You officially know everything I need you to know. It's gonna be
Speaker 6:  great.
Speaker 4:  All right. That's it. That's where we're chest rock and roll.
Speaker 9:  And that's it for The Verge Cast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 9:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one. The Verge. Vergecast is a
Speaker 9:  production of The, Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 9:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.