# Transcript
ID: effdcd1f-6039-48cc-b320-a6b893c3bc1c
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-25633703622495832/-8498131612271620185/s93290-US-4058s-1728988246.mp3
Description: Before a podcast was a “podcast,” it was… well, it wasn’t really much of anything. It was in 2004, though, that many of the earliest names in on-demand audio began to smush “iPod” and “broadcast” into the word we’ve come to know as the way we all download and listen to shows now. In this episode, we go back two decades to the first days of the podcast. Then we hit the skip button to today and look at where podcasts are headed next.
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of our Ss.
Speaker 2:  Enclosures. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am sitting in my car
Speaker 2:  recording a Podcast So. Our episode today is all about the
Speaker 2:  early days of podcasting. We're doing this whole big package of stories
Speaker 2:  on The Verge all week, all about 2004. The stuff that
Speaker 2:  happened in 2004, the legacy of that year, 20 years later,
Speaker 2:  which is a surprisingly consequential one in tech. it was the year Google
Speaker 2:  went public, it was the year Gmail was created, it was the year Facebook
Speaker 2:  launched, it was the year dig launched. it was the year that Firefox browser
Speaker 2:  became a thing. it was the year of Janet Jackson's wardrobe malfunction,
Speaker 2:  which was a huge deal that changed the streaming and television worlds forever,
Speaker 2:  all kinds of stuff. But for this episode of The Vergecast,
Speaker 2:  we're re gonna talk about the word podcast because the word podcast
Speaker 2:  became a word and came to describe this whole industry.
Speaker 2:  This whole thing we're doing right now back in 2004 So, we're re gonna
Speaker 2:  talk about where that name came from. What it has come to mean and then What
Speaker 2:  might happen in the next 20 years. But the thing I've
Speaker 2:  discovered in doing all this research and in talking to a bunch of people
Speaker 2:  who were around in those early days is that a surprising number of
Speaker 2:  people were just sitting in their car making Podcasts.
Speaker 2:  Back then They were, you know, talking into microphones or had really
Speaker 2:  crude sort of rudimentary cell phone setups that They could call into with
Speaker 2:  a phone number and record a podcast that way. But the acoustics of a car
Speaker 2:  are pretty good. It does a pretty good job of dampening noise and
Speaker 2:  echoes and all kinds of issues. So the car, it doesn't Look great, but
Speaker 2:  it turns out to be a half decent place to make a podcast. So here. I am
Speaker 2:  in the car making a podcast just like our, our good
Speaker 2:  forefathers of the podcast years did So, Anyway, all of that is
Speaker 2:  coming up. We're re gonna talk about the past, the present, and the future
Speaker 2:  of Podcasts on this whole episode. It's very meta, it's a super fun
Speaker 2:  episode. I'm really excited about it. All of that is coming up in just a
Speaker 2:  second, but it's warm out and I had to turn the car off to do this. I
Speaker 2:  don't know how people made Podcasts when like the air conditioning was running
Speaker 2:  and everything was insane, but right now it is too hot in
Speaker 2:  here and it has to stop. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Do you remember when you first heard about
Speaker 2:  Podcasts? If you've been listening to this show, The Vergecast since
Speaker 2:  2011, maybe it was that or If, you were a listener of
Speaker 2:  the End Gadget podcast before even that, maybe that's where you
Speaker 2:  got into it. Or really to be way less self-absorbed and much
Speaker 2:  more realistic about it. Maybe it was Serial in 2014
Speaker 2:  that turned you and frankly millions of other people onto
Speaker 2:  the idea of Radio on Demand. That's when Podcasts
Speaker 2:  became a thing. But I bet that for most people the
Speaker 2:  farthest possible distance back you could go would be this moment.
Speaker 2:  In 2005 when Steve Jobs got on stage at
Speaker 2:  WWDC and before he announced that Apple was switching to using Intel
Speaker 2:  chips and before he said that leopard would be the next version of Mac Os,
Speaker 2:  he explained to a lot of people why They were about to start seeing Podcasts
Speaker 2:  in iTunes.
Speaker 5:  As you know, the podcasting phenomenon is exploding right now,
Speaker 5:  and podcasting of course is a concatenation of iPod and broadcasting
Speaker 5:  and What is podcasting. You know, it's been described a lot of different
Speaker 5:  ways. One way has been TiVo for radio. You
Speaker 5:  can download radio shows and listen to 'em on your computer or put 'em on
Speaker 5:  your iPod anytime you want. So, it's just like television programs on TiVo
Speaker 5:  and that's true. Another way it's been described is Wayne's World for
Speaker 5:  radio, which means that anyone without
Speaker 5:  much capital investment can make a podcast, put it on a server and get a
Speaker 5:  worldwide audience for their radio show. And that's true too.
Speaker 5:  We see it as the hottest thing going in radio.
Speaker 2:  A fun fact from that one, by the way, jobs talked about how There were 8,000
Speaker 2:  Podcasts available at that time in 2005 and that was a huge number. He
Speaker 2:  was really excited about it. Now that number is somewhere between three and
Speaker 2:  5 million. Podcasts lots changed Anyway.
Speaker 2:  A lot of people credit jobs with mainstreaming both the word
Speaker 2:  and the concept of Podcasts, which is probably at least a little true
Speaker 2:  podcast, was the Oxford Dictionary's word of the year in 2005.
Speaker 2:  It beat out in case you're wondering Bird flu, reggaeton,
Speaker 2:  Life, hack, whole bunch of other stuff. But jobs didn't create the
Speaker 2:  concept or the word the concept. I think is
Speaker 2:  the one of those two that is trickiest to figure out. Technically you could
Speaker 2:  argue that the idea of a podcast is just like radio and we've had that around
Speaker 2:  forever, but I think you can make a pretty good case that the
Speaker 2:  thing We now know as a podcast became a thing in about
Speaker 2:  2003 and it involved a guy named Chris Leiden.
Speaker 4:  It was a very exciting coincidence for me. For one thing, I I had
Speaker 4:  been Ignominiously bumped out of a wonderful job in public radio
Speaker 4:  and looking for something new. So. Charlie Nessen at Berkman Center said,
Speaker 4:  come and think with us. Dave Weiner arrived a few
Speaker 4:  weeks later and he said, well, Charlie told me
Speaker 4:  David Weiner was coming.
Speaker 2:  Charles Nessen, by the way, was the creator of the Berkman Klein Center for
Speaker 2:  Internet and Society, which was kind of an early internet think tank at Harvard
Speaker 2:  that actually still does a lot of really interesting digital work. Dave
Speaker 2:  Weiner is one of the Internet's earliest and longest tenured bloggers. His
Speaker 2:  blog just turned 30 last week. He's also a key creator of
Speaker 2:  RSS, which is the technology that spreads feeds of content around the internet
Speaker 2:  and he's just a guy who cares a lot about web publishing standards At the
Speaker 2:  time. If, you wanted to start a blog calling Dave Weiner was like calling
Speaker 2:  Gordon Ramsey for tips on how to open a restaurant and Chris Leiden
Speaker 2:  hit him up.
Speaker 4:  I wrote to Dave Wine saying six months ago, I couldn't spell blog.
Speaker 4:  Now I want a B one. and we went through the blog cycle very, very
Speaker 4:  quickly. But then he said, you know, radio I know
Speaker 4:  programming What the world needs is an MP three file that can
Speaker 4:  go worldwide instantly. I said, sounds good to me and
Speaker 4:  we got to work. It only took oh couple of months let's say,
Speaker 4:  and he said, I, think we got it. I said, now What Day. He said, well that's
Speaker 4:  obvious you're gonna do a conversation with me and we're gonna put it out.
Speaker 4:  and we did
Speaker 2:  Leiden and Weiner ended up publishing that conversation in July of
Speaker 2:  2003 and I just wanna play you the first 30 seconds or So of it,
Speaker 2:  which I found. By the way, thanks to James Cridland
Speaker 2:  over@podnews.net. He did a great whole big
Speaker 2:  thing on The history of the word podcast and we're actually gonna talk to
Speaker 2:  him about the future of Podcasts later in the show. Anyway here it's Dave
Speaker 4:  Weiner I. Feel like a new immigrant in this blogger world where you're a
Speaker 4:  kind of founding father. Walk me around it and I'm
Speaker 4:  not talking about the technology I wanna know What kind of democratic
Speaker 4:  experiment. This blog idea really amounts to,
Speaker 6:  Well gosh, it changes all the time. I mean when we first
Speaker 6:  started doing this, it was just a bunch of people sort of
Speaker 6:  writing hello world and being amazed that
Speaker 6:  it was possible to do that and and then the next
Speaker 6:  step was recognition of other people and say, wow, there's somebody else
Speaker 6:  doing this and learning how to
Speaker 6:  communicate and
Speaker 6:  gosh, I don't know how to answer that question. I mean it is What you make
Speaker 6:  of it. Everybody brings something different to it and different set of expectations
Speaker 6:  and everybody molds it to be whatever it means to them.
Speaker 2:  They don't call What, they're doing There a Podcast, but I mean that's a
Speaker 2:  podcast, right? There like it's two dudes talking tech.
Speaker 2:  It's all very meta. The sound quality is good but kind of messy.
Speaker 2:  That's all the hallmarks of Podcasts all in one place. And
Speaker 2:  I think the thing that whiner says at the very end, it is What you make of
Speaker 2:  it turned out to be more prescient than maybe either of them realized at
Speaker 2:  the time, but still, They weren't calling it a podcast, nobody
Speaker 2:  was. They were calling these things audio blogs if They were calling them
Speaker 2:  anything, There were a handful of them out There, but none of them were Podcasts
Speaker 2:  until Ben Hammersley showed up. Ben I should say right up front
Speaker 2:  is not exactly psyched that he is part of this particular slice of
Speaker 2:  podcast history.
Speaker 7:  It was in fucking bane in my Life because there's absolutely no
Speaker 7:  honor in the origin story, right? That
Speaker 7:  you know, when I die, I want to be remembered for
Speaker 7:  I don't know a 20 year project or something or saving
Speaker 7:  orphans from a burning building or or something,
Speaker 7:  something like that. Rather than a word that was invented in a sort of deadline
Speaker 7:  frenzy that I didn't even realize I was doing until a few
Speaker 7:  months later.
Speaker 2:  In 2004, Ben was working on some early RSS in publishing tech
Speaker 2:  and was also writing about the burgeoning tech industry for The Guardian.
Speaker 2:  And in February of 2004 he published a piece called Audible revolution.
Speaker 2:  All about the cool stuff people were doing online with audio at
Speaker 2:  the time, There were people building software that could automatically record
Speaker 2:  radio streams over the internet and make them available for listening later.
Speaker 2:  The iPod obviously was everywhere and people were also building software
Speaker 2:  to take all those streams that you had downloaded and put them onto your
Speaker 2:  iPod one step at a time. All of this stuff was starting to come together.
Speaker 2:  Ben actually interviewed Chris Leiden for the piece that he wrote and Leiden
Speaker 2:  talked about how audio over the web was gonna change people's relationships
Speaker 2:  with their audience. it was gonna democratize media. They had all these big
Speaker 2:  high-minded ideas about What audio might do,
Speaker 2:  but it's right There in the second paragraph of the story that Ben Hammersley
Speaker 2:  does. The thing, actually, lemme just read you the first two paragraphs
Speaker 2:  with the benefit of hindsight. It all seems quite obvious. MP three players
Speaker 2:  like Apple's, iPod in many pockets, audio production software, cheap or
Speaker 2:  free and web logging an established part of the internet, all the ingredients
Speaker 2:  are There for a new boom in amateur radio, but What to call it
Speaker 2:  audio blogging, podcasting, gorilla Media
Speaker 2:  There, it is that almost everyone agrees is the first published
Speaker 2:  use of the word podcasting. It's a big moment. Of course, Ben
Speaker 2:  had absolutely no idea What he was doing when he wrote that word. The
Speaker 7:  Guardian at the time was a print first paper as in you wrote
Speaker 7:  for the paper and you had a print deadline when the physical printing presses
Speaker 7:  would run at six o'clock and If, you
Speaker 7:  missed that deadline. The the words weren't going to go onto the
Speaker 7:  page and that meant that every
Speaker 7:  day the sort of working rhythm was that There was this big rush to get everything
Speaker 7:  done by quarter to six or whatever. And
Speaker 7:  I'd written this article and about five 30 or So, you know,
Speaker 7:  just before the print deadline I get a an email from my
Speaker 7:  editor saying we've put it on the page and it's very nice but
Speaker 7:  it it is kind of a line short and it doesn't Look very
Speaker 7:  good on the page. You know the, the text hasn't gone green in the typesetting
Speaker 7:  program. Can you write me another sentence just to
Speaker 7:  pad it out, right? Just to make it fit beautifully on the printed page and
Speaker 7:  So I wrote an extra sentence and emailed it over and the sentence is this
Speaker 7:  sort of like mildly meaningless sentence of, but What do we call this
Speaker 7:  new phenomenon. And then I sort of invented three words and put 'em in There
Speaker 7:  and then sent it off and then I went to the pub
Speaker 2:  Look. On the one hand, thank God we call it podcasting and not
Speaker 2:  Gorilla Mediaing, you know, What I mean, but Ben doesn't even
Speaker 2:  remember how he came up with podcast. Everyone now says it's a Port
Speaker 2:  manto of iPod and broadcast, which is What. Steve Jobs said in that clip
Speaker 2:  earlier and Ben basically just said, yeah, that seems reasonable
Speaker 2:  enough, but he doesn't even remember coming up with it. He also at
Speaker 2:  the time had no idea, truly no idea
Speaker 2:  What he had done.
Speaker 7:  And it was only a few months later that I got emails from, from the Oxford
Speaker 7:  English dictionary saying, where, where do you find this word? We, we're
Speaker 7:  trying to find an earlier citation for it than than your piece. And, and
Speaker 7:  we can't, where did you get it? And I, you know,
Speaker 7:  pulled it out the back of my head on a, on a deadline panic. I I had no idea
Speaker 7:  and I looked on all of the RSS related
Speaker 7:  development mailing lists and So on which, which is What the place where
Speaker 7:  it would've been. And I couldn't find any trace of it either.
Speaker 7:  And So I said, well clearly I just must have made it up. And then he said,
Speaker 7:  great, because it's word of the year. And then, you know, and
Speaker 7:  then it became the thing that Apple took on and that's What They called their
Speaker 7:  app and that's What it became known as, and you know, the rest is history.
Speaker 2:  Ben made very clear several times when we talked that he didn't
Speaker 2:  invent the idea of a podcast and nor does he deserve credit for What
Speaker 2:  Podcasts eventually became, but all these years later
Speaker 2:  he does seem to kind of like the word he came up with, it's got that nice
Speaker 2:  plosive p you can use it as a noun or a verb pretty easily.
Speaker 2:  It's a good useful word that way,
Speaker 7:  But also that within it There are context clues that Normies could understand.
Speaker 7:  Hmm, So, you know, the iPod was the biggest thing in the
Speaker 7:  world at that time and that's where the pod bit comes from.
Speaker 7:  And although it was super fiddly at the beginning to, to take these Podcasts
Speaker 7:  and put them onto your iPod pretty rapidly, some software came out
Speaker 7:  There and made that simpler. And then soon after that Apple made it possible
Speaker 7:  within iTunes and to
Speaker 7:  say it's kind of like TiVo for radio
Speaker 7:  that you listen to on your MP three player is a pretty good
Speaker 7:  sentence in 2002, 2003. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 7:  To sort of not, not necessarily to hugely techie circles or, or even like
Speaker 7:  super early adopters, but to sort of, you know, the, the whoever, whoever
Speaker 7:  comes after the early adopters, those people, you know, They They can understand
Speaker 7:  it and So it I think it becomes one of those things where
Speaker 7:  it's a fun word to say but also it kind of has meaning within
Speaker 7:  it that somebody who's used to new
Speaker 7:  technologies can kind of understand straight away
Speaker 7:  and, and So and it becomes a self evidently good idea,
Speaker 7:  right? And then when you have a few years later you have these
Speaker 7:  very successful professionally made Podcasts, which take full advantage or
Speaker 7:  start to take full advantage of the, of the fact that they're at liberty
Speaker 7:  to use as much space or as little space as They need, as much time as
Speaker 7:  little time, different episode lengths, all that sort of thing
Speaker 7:  that people started exploring that and, and being able to self commission
Speaker 7:  and make, make programs that were something you would never, ever
Speaker 7:  have heard before on regular Bull Cross radio then,
Speaker 7:  then suddenly it becomes, it wasn own it was own thing very rapidly and people
Speaker 7:  start to see the value of it hugely tied in with
Speaker 7:  the call it Skagit on the market at the time. So, I think it, it, it,
Speaker 7:  it sort of catches that lightning of all of those different things happening
Speaker 7:  At the same time,
Speaker 2:  Most people do seem to agree that Ben coined the term
Speaker 2:  podcast or at least used it first. But There is one other person in the
Speaker 2:  equation who definitely deserves credit. That's Danny Gregoire who's a
Speaker 2:  software engineer who used the word in an email to a list of folks working
Speaker 2:  on and with an app called iPod. iPod was one of those things that could
Speaker 2:  automatically take recorded audio and put it on your iPod.
Speaker 2:  The list at the time was brand new and iPod was an app started by
Speaker 2:  a guy named Adam Curry who had an audio blog of his own at the time called
Speaker 2:  Daily Source Code. Adam was a long time radio guy, he'd
Speaker 2:  also been an MTV VJ for years and he'd also been an early
Speaker 2:  internet entrepreneur and for years at this point he had been chatting with
Speaker 2:  Dave Weiner and others about the whole concept of putting audio files
Speaker 2:  in RSS. But Adam was one of the very first people to have
Speaker 2:  kind of a whole vision of how this on demand internet radio
Speaker 2:  thing should actually work.
Speaker 8:  Now it was end of 2003
Speaker 8:  when a friend of mine said Look at this cool thing I have I said What, do
Speaker 8:  you have? And it was the iPod and I looked at this iPod
Speaker 8:  and it was like literally like lightning bolts because
Speaker 8:  it looked I don't have any I, it looked exactly like this
Speaker 8:  transistor radio my grandmother had given me when I was seven years old.
Speaker 8:  This little, little Sony transistor radio nine volt battery.
Speaker 8:  I'm like, yeah, you can call this a digital Walkman or you know,
Speaker 8:  whatever you want, but this to me was a radio receiver and right away I'm
Speaker 8:  like, oh, let's hook it up to this RSS thing. So
Speaker 8:  again with my very poor scripting skills. I
Speaker 8:  tried to rig this together with Apple Script and then Kevin Marks
Speaker 8:  who I think worked at I, dunno if he worked at Google, he worked in Silicon
Speaker 8:  Valley somewhere. He basically said, oh here's the script that you need and
Speaker 8:  boom, I was like, okay, it works. So I could create a blog post and then
Speaker 8:  this little script would be looking to to find some, a new item
Speaker 8:  in my blog post with a file attached to it. It would download the file,
Speaker 8:  it would, because you still had to sync your iPod back in the day
Speaker 8:  to your computer and So it would trigger an update and then in the morning
Speaker 8:  you'd walk in and There would be your iPod with as the album
Speaker 8:  would be. Basically, we didn't have the name podcasting yet. It would be,
Speaker 8:  you know, kind of the blog name or the, you know, the the show name and
Speaker 8:  then it would have these episodes under it and I immediately started to just
Speaker 8:  get the word out There because I needed software developers who could create
Speaker 8:  this for real
Speaker 2:  That thing he's describing. That script was iPod, it would watch
Speaker 2:  RSS feeds for audio files, it would download them, sync them to your iPod
Speaker 2:  and you're done. That's just a podcasting app, right?
Speaker 2:  Adam Curry made a podcasting app, that's all it was. And
Speaker 2:  in fact his show Daily Source Code was in part a podcast
Speaker 2:  for it was own sake, you know, entertainment and content and whatever, but
Speaker 2:  it was also in part sort of an ongoing beta test of how
Speaker 2:  all of this podcasting technology stuff might really work.
Speaker 8:  So, I'd like, okay, I have an audience. It's these guys and a
Speaker 8:  couple gals at the time who develop software. How do I
Speaker 8:  keep them engaged in this process? Well I need to give them content
Speaker 8:  every single day and it has to be about the stuff they're doing, which is
Speaker 8:  programming What do you do in programming, you create source
Speaker 8:  code So I did it every single day for a long time and from
Speaker 8:  I I missed one from time to time and it They came became more spaced out
Speaker 8:  over time. But we kept Daily source code and I would literally talk
Speaker 8:  about the developments They had done the previous day. So They needed something
Speaker 8:  to test on. There were no programs So, They needed something daily
Speaker 8:  that sounded like a, you know, a show that They could
Speaker 8:  use. So we could figure out well where did show notes go
Speaker 8:  And you know, when someone first subscribes to a feed, do you
Speaker 8:  give them the most recent one? Do you download all of the archives, all of
Speaker 8:  this stuff and So I know from my radio background,
Speaker 8:  when you talk about people on the radio, it makes them feel good.
Speaker 8:  So, when I was talking about Andrew Grommet and you know the guys at
Speaker 8:  at iPod or X and you know one was in Australia and the other one was
Speaker 8:  in I, know somewhere in Vienna
Speaker 8:  that motivates you and So it was both a feedback loop. 'cause I was
Speaker 8:  the ultimate user both from the content creation side and from the, from
Speaker 8:  the listener side.
Speaker 2:  So, you can hear this flywheel going at this point, the programmers are
Speaker 2:  making Podcasts, they're listening to each other's Podcasts. They're building
Speaker 2:  better software for listening and to and making those Podcasts. They're making
Speaker 2:  new stuff to test it and round and round and round it goes. And
Speaker 2:  a lot of that conversation was happening on the iPod or dev email
Speaker 2:  list, which is where we come back to Danny roi. In
Speaker 2:  September of 2004 he wrote to the iPod or dev list that he could imagine
Speaker 2:  a world in which people would want to be able to subscribe to one of these
Speaker 2:  audio programs and get access to older stuff. He didn't know whether to
Speaker 2:  call that older stuff posts or episodes or shows. He actually
Speaker 2:  suggested calling them POS or sos, which I'm very glad
Speaker 2:  did not catch on. And he though They might want an easier way
Speaker 2:  to go through the archives, but then he wrote this I
Speaker 2:  guess one could argue that this is simply an RSS slash server side issue
Speaker 2:  and that the podcaster, yes, I like making up words, should be
Speaker 2:  responsible enough to offer a page of separate feeds of old SOS by month,
Speaker 2:  year, season, et cetera. He kind of made up Podcasts again
Speaker 2:  Dave Weiner and others have over the years given Gregoire credit for
Speaker 2:  if not making it up, at least making the term podcast a thing.
Speaker 2:  Adam Curry in particular is pretty forceful about it
Speaker 8:  And for my money, Danny Gregoire is the one who showed up with that,
Speaker 8:  with that name I know Ben Hammersley feels he
Speaker 8:  invented it. He used the word a long time before that, but I'd never
Speaker 8:  heard it. So Danny showed up with Podcasts. It made a lot of sense
Speaker 8:  because we were doing this on the, on the iPod and So.
Speaker 8:  it was obvious where it came from,
Speaker 2:  However it came into be Weiner and Curry both bought into the word
Speaker 2:  immediately and did a lot of work promoting the word podcast once
Speaker 2:  it had been sort of unofficially decided on as usual. There is
Speaker 2:  no clear story about who did exactly What, who knew What when, where the
Speaker 2:  word came from. And if anyone is singularly responsible,
Speaker 2:  I don't know that it matters to be honest. But I do know this. After
Speaker 2:  Gregor's email to the iPod group, the word Podcast caught on
Speaker 2:  really fast I think the first podcast to ever refer to itself
Speaker 2:  as a Podcast was probably Dave Slusher on Evil Genius
Speaker 2:  Chronicles, which had been around in blog form for a couple of years and
Speaker 2:  was becoming an audio blog at the time. Three days after Gregor's
Speaker 2:  email in September of 2004. Like all good early
Speaker 2:  Podcasts Slusher spends a long time talking about how all this new
Speaker 2:  fangled technology works for making and downloading audio,
Speaker 2:  talking about his servers and Bit Torrance and Bills and all this
Speaker 2:  stuff. And then he talks about What, he calls it
Speaker 9:  And So I and I I saw somebody, there's
Speaker 9:  somebody has registered podcasting.net and I saw a
Speaker 9:  podcaster or podcaster.net and I saw
Speaker 9:  podcaster as a user agent, you know, hitting my RSS feed and I went and looked
Speaker 9:  at it and right now it's just a coming soon page, but I'm gonna pay attention
Speaker 9:  to that I wanna see who's, who's got that and What they're doing but that
Speaker 9:  term I think they've coined the term So iPod platform just doesn't,
Speaker 9:  you know, spring from the tongue Tongue but What I'm doing right here and
Speaker 9:  What Adam's doing and What Dave Weiner's doing and What it conversations
Speaker 9:  are doing. That's podcasting. I think that is the term
Speaker 9:  I am using that from here on out. You know So, I am a podcaster
Speaker 9:  and They are podcasters and I am podcasting right now and you listen
Speaker 9:  to my podcast fucking A
Speaker 2:  Think about how quickly that changed A few months after Ben
Speaker 2:  Hammersley haphazardly wrote the word in a story a few days after
Speaker 2:  Danny Gregoire brought it up to that super influential mailing list,
Speaker 2:  Podcasts were being called Podcasts. One really
Speaker 2:  fun thing about listening to some of the Podcasts from this era is hearing
Speaker 2:  these Podcast hosts actually reckon with the idea of being
Speaker 2:  Podcast hosts. Like here's a clip from a show called the Dawn and
Speaker 2:  Drew show also from September of 2004. This is their very first episode
Speaker 2:  and you can hear them kind of trying on the term for size.
Speaker 10:  Alright, now
Speaker 11:  Wait, What is podcasting.
Speaker 10:  We're we're broadcasting to pod devices, which
Speaker 10:  what's a pod? An iPod would be We don't have an MP three player,
Speaker 11:  But We don't have an iPod. Well that's why
Speaker 10:  We're pod it's been the term has been coined
Speaker 10:  and
Speaker 11:  Is someone gonna give us one for free I Wish? Dear
Speaker 11:  in Nut, please give me a pod me a because
Speaker 11:  Drew has like a little machine, this little tiny thing that he puts music
Speaker 11:  in and I don't have one, it's a
Speaker 10:  Lira from RCA, but see now that would technically be considered a pod
Speaker 10:  in this regard.
Speaker 11:  I think we should crawl inside a pod to do this. I
Speaker 11:  have some right here, let me unzip it.
Speaker 11:  Get out of my pod. Oh shit, there's someone one in There
Speaker 2:  At this moment. It has still only been a few days since the word Podcast
Speaker 2:  hit that mailing list and already it's just the accepted term. They're
Speaker 2:  broadcasting to pod devices, they're Podcasts. That is how quickly it happened.
Speaker 2:  And now for better or for worse, 20 years later there's still Podcasts.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. All right, we've talked a lot about the history of
Speaker 2:  Podcasts. Let's talk a little bit about the future and kind of where We are
Speaker 2:  now as a way to understand where We might be going 20 years after
Speaker 2:  a podcast became a podcast. Podcasts are bigger than ever, right? Like the
Speaker 2:  Podcast Revolution kind of worked. There are people out doing amazing things.
Speaker 2:  There are whole companies being built around Podcasts. More people are listening
Speaker 2:  to Podcasts than ever, but podcasting hasn't killed radio.
Speaker 2:  It hasn't become the future of the media
Speaker 2:  business or democracy or whatever high-minded stuff those folks were talking
Speaker 2:  about 20 years ago. It's doing really cool work,
Speaker 2:  but how important are Podcasts and how big is this
Speaker 2:  industry going to be and how is it supposed to work even after two decades?
Speaker 2:  So, much of that stuff feels like it hasn't been ironed out yet. So
Speaker 2:  to help me figure out where we are and where we're headed with all of this
Speaker 2:  stuff, I invited James k Credlin from podcast News net
Speaker 2:  back on the show to talk about it. I mentioned James up top. He did a great
Speaker 2:  piece a while back about The history of the word podcast that I got
Speaker 2:  a lot of really great information from. He's also been in and covering the
Speaker 2:  podcast industry for longer than almost anybody and knows this
Speaker 2:  space incredibly well. He's super fun to talk to. So I figured I would
Speaker 2:  just sit here and throw some of my questions slash
Speaker 2:  existential crises about the future of my Life and career and all of my favorite
Speaker 2:  Podcasts at him and see if together we might be able to figure
Speaker 2:  out where all of this audio blogging stuff is headed next.
Speaker 2:  Let's get into it. I think if we had had this conversation a year ago,
Speaker 2:  it was like doom and gloom everywhere. The, yeah, the the golden age of
Speaker 2:  podcasting is over. Everything is a disaster. You know,
Speaker 2:  this was all fun while it lasted. Goodbye to everybody. It feels like we're
Speaker 2:  in a slightly different place in the podcasting universe. Like at the risk
Speaker 2:  of asking a needlessly broad question here, right at the beginning, where
Speaker 2:  do you feel like we are right now?
Speaker 12:  I think we're in a pretty good position. I think What
Speaker 12:  happened between probably 2019 and
Speaker 12:  2022 was that a lot of new money came into the
Speaker 12:  podcasting world. it was new money that was really destined for TV
Speaker 12:  and instead was diverted into the podcasting, you know,
Speaker 12:  existence. And really that was their I,
Speaker 12:  I think a lot of TV execs got into podcasting because They felt that
Speaker 12:  it was an easy win for them. And I think that They didn't properly
Speaker 12:  understand anything about audio and anything about
Speaker 12:  making great shows because
Speaker 12:  it's very different world to tv. Audio is a very
Speaker 12:  habitual thing. You listen to a particular show which you'll listen to every
Speaker 12:  single week. So Limited series shows by and
Speaker 12:  large don't work too well. So I think that we saw a lot of people
Speaker 12:  who were, you know, who were coming at this with a different media understanding
Speaker 12:  of how TV works trying to apply it to the podcasting world and
Speaker 12:  they're not really understanding why it wasn't actually working. And that's
Speaker 12:  really, What stopped happening at the end of 2022, beginning of 2023
Speaker 12:  and why we all of a sudden saw lots of layoffs and lots of,
Speaker 12:  you know, bad things happening. Coinciding of course with
Speaker 12:  whatever's going on in the media industry as a whole. Anyway,
Speaker 12:  right?
Speaker 2:  So does it feel like to a certain extent we're, we're
Speaker 2:  back to where we were with Podcasts I Don't know
Speaker 2:  Pres Serial, like There There was a moment where it was like serial happened
Speaker 2:  and then it was like, okay, podcast is gonna go through it. wasn it was peak
Speaker 2:  TV era and maybe 10 years later we're at the end of the
Speaker 2:  peak TV era in the way that in the TV world we're at the end of the peak
Speaker 2:  TV era. And we're gonna go back to I don't know the, the like
Speaker 2:  sitcoms and reality TV version of the
Speaker 2:  podcasting universe.
Speaker 12:  Well, So I think, you know, podcasting has always had two
Speaker 12:  kind of separate industries. You've got the industry
Speaker 12:  of, you know, the serials of this world, big high
Speaker 12:  budget shows with a lot of people working on them and
Speaker 12:  you know, that has been always a part of podcasting and then
Speaker 12:  you've had, you know, a show which is put together by, you
Speaker 12:  know, two people and a computer program and that's it.
Speaker 12:  And those shows seem to have weathered the storm
Speaker 12:  obviously, because the costs for making those shows are much, much lower.
Speaker 12:  But those shows are typically around sort of I would say
Speaker 12:  18 90% of all shows out There are things that
Speaker 12:  are put together, you know, at relatively low cost.
Speaker 12:  It isn't a massive staffing thing of, you know, 20 people involved in
Speaker 12:  one particular show as some of these shows are. And I think
Speaker 12:  podcasting is always done very well because of that. Because it
Speaker 12:  is a, because it's an open medium that anybody can
Speaker 12:  actually get into. I think that's been the real benefit. So
Speaker 12:  So, I think, yeah, There have been ebbs and flows in terms of that top
Speaker 12:  10% in terms of the revenue coming in from advertising,
Speaker 12:  but I don't think podcasting itself has changed that much
Speaker 12:  to be honest in the last 20 years.
Speaker 2:  Ooh, okay. So, that brings me to one of the things I was gonna ask you, which
Speaker 2:  is a question you asked a Spotify executive very recently that I really liked
Speaker 2:  and want to hear your answer to, which is What is a podcast in 2024.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, thanks. Because I think you could argue it is both the same and
Speaker 2:  diametrically different than What it was 20 years ago. So What, how would
Speaker 2:  you define What? It is now
Speaker 12:  So, I think a Podcast. The the easy answer is a podcast
Speaker 12:  is anything that the audience thinks it is. Whatever the
Speaker 12:  audience wants to claim is a podcast
Speaker 2:  That feels like cheating. I don't like that answer. Yeah,
Speaker 12:  I and, and it's a, and it's a cheat answer because I don't think it
Speaker 12:  necessarily understands What. The benefit of a Podcast is,
Speaker 12:  but If, you ask somebody whether they're watching a podcast on YouTube,
Speaker 12:  what's the difference between a podcast and another YouTube video
Speaker 12:  then typically you will get the answer. You can see the microphones in a
Speaker 12:  podcast, which is a really weird, weird answer. Yeah,
Speaker 12:  but I think, you know from a, you know, overarching
Speaker 12:  thing of What is a Podcast I think that a podcast is a piece of on demand
Speaker 12:  audio first content that's basically all, all that
Speaker 12:  it is now There is, There are a lot of people who will turn around and say
Speaker 12:  RSS is massively important and enclosures are important and all of
Speaker 12:  the technical detail that makes a Podcast a podcast. I'm not So sure
Speaker 12:  that that's as important as We think it is and actually
Speaker 12:  at the end of the day, it's whatever somebody thinks a podcast is.
Speaker 2:  Okay, let me just press on that slightly. You're a person
Speaker 2:  who covers Podcasts So, you have to draw a line somewhere.
Speaker 2:  Where is that line for you?
Speaker 12:  Well, So, the Podcasts that I write about are
Speaker 12:  Podcasts that are open, that are available on,
Speaker 12:  on every single platform and available, you know,
Speaker 12:  in, you know that phrase, wherever you get your Podcast
Speaker 12:  is an important thing because that to me is What. A Podcast
Speaker 12:  is So. If a podcast is only available on Audible, I typically won't, won't
Speaker 12:  write about it because it's not I. I don't think a a podcast
Speaker 12:  similarly, if it's only available on Wondery Plus or on the BBC sounds
Speaker 12:  app or whatever it might be, So, that's where I
Speaker 12:  draw the line. But I think you know, it it it
Speaker 12:  all differs If you If you ask people, you know What What,
Speaker 12:  their most favorite podcast app is, there's a lot of people that answer
Speaker 12:  YouTube even though YouTube doesn't satisfy any
Speaker 12:  of the technical elements of What. A podcast is an audio file
Speaker 12:  in an MP three without DRM available to download
Speaker 12:  via RSS with an enclosure. All of that stuff YouTube does
Speaker 12:  none of yet I think it's perfectly acceptable
Speaker 12:  to say that you can listen to a podcast on YouTube.
Speaker 2:  Speaking of things that had a moment and feel like they're fading, this
Speaker 2:  idea of the non-Open
Speaker 2:  podcast feels like it has started to go
Speaker 2:  away. There were a few years There where There was a real sense that a bunch
Speaker 2:  of companies, Spotify and Audible and Sirius and whoever else were going
Speaker 2:  to sort of build themselves a library of exclusive
Speaker 2:  audio products and would use that
Speaker 2:  to win in some large way. Wondery you
Speaker 2:  mentioned has been pushing towards that. That idea seems
Speaker 2:  to have, if not disappeared then at least gone away and There are a lot of
Speaker 2:  folks doing, you know, the advertising and distribution deals, but the idea
Speaker 2:  of like the platform exclusive podcast
Speaker 2:  seems like it is fading. Do you think that that era is
Speaker 2:  just behind us and that openness in a certain way is, is going to
Speaker 2:  win going forward here?
Speaker 12:  Yeah, I mean I, I, I would hope, put it that way. I would hope
Speaker 12:  that exclusivity is going away. I mean Daniel Ek was
Speaker 12:  very clear I I in earlier on in this year when he
Speaker 12:  was doing his earnings call. He, he, he was saying that some of those
Speaker 12:  exclusivity deals worked, but generally it wasn't aligned
Speaker 12:  with What the creator wanted. My understanding, for example, is that
Speaker 12:  There was a, There was a big author who
Speaker 12:  she put her show as an exclusive onto Spotify
Speaker 12:  and she saw that the amount of books that she was selling went down
Speaker 12:  because the amount of people who were listening to her show went
Speaker 12:  down because it was an exclusive and only available on one thing. So, you
Speaker 12:  know, So clearly, you know, If, you want both
Speaker 12:  If, you want, you know, both large audiences but also
Speaker 12:  you want to be able to get your ideas out There and have
Speaker 12:  influence. Then exclusivity doesn't necessarily work too
Speaker 12:  well. We are seeing a few hold ons in terms of exclusivity. I mean
Speaker 12:  some of the, the large broadcasters in the world
Speaker 12:  seem to be pulling, you know, some of their shows into exclusives
Speaker 12:  on their own apps and the BBC is doing a little bit more of that, which
Speaker 12:  I kind of wish that They wouldn't. and we are still seeing a few
Speaker 12:  sort of windowing type of things where you can hear a show
Speaker 12:  first on a particular, you know, exclusive platform,
Speaker 12:  Wondery Plus being a good example, but I think that those are
Speaker 12:  relatively few and far between and I think that people
Speaker 12:  now understand that reach and influence is just
Speaker 12:  as important as, you know, as as trying to build
Speaker 12:  a particular app that doesn't NN necessarily work too well.
Speaker 2:  Why do you think that is I think it's So different than the way
Speaker 2:  that streaming TV and movies has shaken out? Yeah, and I think again, the
Speaker 2:  bet five years ago was that the podcast world would Look a lot like
Speaker 2:  the TV world in that it would be a bunch of competitive platforms all competing
Speaker 2:  on their libraries, right? Why do you think Podcasts didn't go that way?
Speaker 12:  Yeah, and, and There was luminary for example, which tries to
Speaker 12:  right I think it was one of the first companies that was trying to do all
Speaker 12:  of this. And interestingly, I mean There are still quite a few large companies
Speaker 12:  in Europe which have a big exclusive, you know, amount
Speaker 12:  of of shows as well. But I think, you know, at the end of the day it
Speaker 12:  doesn't necessarily work because we are used to the status quo
Speaker 12:  of having all of our Podcasts available in one place.
Speaker 12:  And you know, I mean way back in time when I was
Speaker 12:  working in a radio station and looking at radio
Speaker 12:  apps, I used to always say to people that a radio
Speaker 12:  app was downloaded by your fans, your p
Speaker 12:  one listeners in Radio World. You know, you, you wouldn't necessarily
Speaker 12:  get people downloading an app just in case There was something worthwhile,
Speaker 12:  you know, tuning into on it. And I think that podcasting is exactly the,
Speaker 12:  the same way So, there's no doubt for example, that
Speaker 12:  Joe Rogan moving as an exclusive to Spotify helped
Speaker 12:  grow the amount of installs to Spotify, but Joe Rogan is
Speaker 12:  I think different to most shows and I, think If, you were to
Speaker 12:  say that about pretty well any other show that Spotify had,
Speaker 12:  I'm not sure that you would see a massive increase in the amount of
Speaker 12:  installs of that app just because a podcast happened to be on it.
Speaker 12:  There are, you know, 3 million shows out, There, if
Speaker 12:  one of the shows isn't available on your chosen app, then guess What.
Speaker 12:  There's another, there's another 3 million for you to go and and and
Speaker 12:  have a listen to So I think from that point of view, the exclusive should
Speaker 12:  hopefully have gone. It wasn't good for anybody really, but as you
Speaker 12:  say, it was exactly the point that TV
Speaker 12:  executives, you know, looking at Hulu, looking at Max,
Speaker 12:  looking at all of these weird and wonderful things though, well that
Speaker 12:  will work in the audio world and, and I think, you know,
Speaker 12:  again, that was one of the, the mistakes made during the big
Speaker 12:  excitement of 2019 to 2022
Speaker 2:  And What about YouTube. I think YouTube is
Speaker 2:  in a lot of ways not a platform for Podcasts and also
Speaker 2:  kind of by far the most interesting platform for Podcasts and
Speaker 2:  as a, as a person who makes Podcasts I have an awfully hard time
Speaker 2:  thinking about how I should think about YouTube. Yes, What is your sense
Speaker 2:  of of What YouTube means to the podcast industry, especially kind of over
Speaker 2:  the next few years.
Speaker 12:  I think YouTube is fascinating. I think that There is There are
Speaker 12:  a couple of things going on. Firstly, a as we have
Speaker 12:  established people don't really know What a Podcast is and So therefore
Speaker 12:  If, you ask the general public where do you listen to your podcasts?
Speaker 12:  Quite a lot of them will say YouTube, but YouTube So far as
Speaker 12:  I can see is not delivering the amount of plays,
Speaker 12:  the amount of listens to most shows than you would expect
Speaker 12:  from a very large, you know, platform for a podcast.
Speaker 12:  Listen, it seems to be delivering an
Speaker 12:  incremental amount of plays and downloads to a show,
Speaker 12:  but it isn't the number one place where people are going to have
Speaker 12:  a listen to a particular podcast that said I think What
Speaker 12:  YouTube has is it's clearly got a lot of people who use it
Speaker 12:  every day, I, I pay for it and I use it, you know, pretty well
Speaker 12:  every single day the algorithm is very good at surfacing new
Speaker 12:  content that I might want to go and have a listen to and that's a fantastic
Speaker 12:  opportunity for the podcasting world.
Speaker 12:  We are always told, aren't we that Podcast discovery, you know,
Speaker 12:  it's a real problem and blah blah blah. I'm not necessarily sure that it
Speaker 12:  is, but certainly YouTube and YouTube's algorithm can actually help
Speaker 12:  fix all of that. So I think that that's one sort of side of it. I also think
Speaker 12:  from the creator's side, They Look at some of the big
Speaker 12:  YouTubers and They go, wow, I can get some of this money.
Speaker 12:  You know, it's, it, it's a way of earning me cash and perhaps
Speaker 12:  this is the right way of earning money out of the show that I do,
Speaker 12:  but I also think that it's putting an awful lot of creators off
Speaker 12:  because all of a sudden we have to talk about cameras
Speaker 12:  and lighting and we have to talk about video editing, which is
Speaker 12:  way more complicated than audio editing, which is why
Speaker 12:  my definition of the word podcast starts with audio first. It's
Speaker 12:  something that you can enjoy with your ears
Speaker 12:  while your eyes are busy. That that's, that's the benefit of
Speaker 12:  a podcast and So YouTube on that I I find it
Speaker 12:  absolutely fascinating to watch What is going to happen with that particular
Speaker 12:  platform, but I think it's still very much, you know,
Speaker 12:  let's wait and see What YouTube actually offers I mean,
Speaker 12:  you know, it's, it's a Google thing So, therefore Google will probably
Speaker 12:  lose interest in about 18 months. I would've though
Speaker 2:  Historically speaking we're, we're I would say over time on some of the,
Speaker 2:  some of those things by now, yeah, YouTube music not exactly
Speaker 2:  innovating at all speeds right now, but no I I think you're right I think
Speaker 2:  the a again to the kind of What is a podcast question. Audio first is,
Speaker 2:  is a good one and I think yet another place where the line is really
Speaker 2:  blurry, right? I, think about I. I hear people all the time who talk about
Speaker 2:  getting YouTube premium just So. You can listen to videos in the
Speaker 2:  background and They just listen to videos. Yeah, They like What is a good
Speaker 2:  YouTube essay if not a podcast episode, right? Yeah. Like,
Speaker 2:  and There was a YouTube TV announcement the other day that you can now
Speaker 2:  listen to TV in the background with your screen off and it's like,
Speaker 2:  did They just turn every TV show on earth into a podcast like
Speaker 2:  maybe I don't know all these, all these lines are So blurry and So and So
Speaker 2:  interesting, but I I do think the video piece of it is,
Speaker 2:  is important and complicated for both of the reasons you just said. One is
Speaker 2:  that I think the thing that you YouTube has going forward is it is the
Speaker 2:  best content discovery engine on the internet
Speaker 2:  and it Podcasts are hard to find. It's, it's hard to, to find a new
Speaker 2:  podcast, it's hard to get into a new Podcast. Like the, the bar There is
Speaker 2:  very high and YouTube is very good at that, but it also me it, it also
Speaker 2:  requires video, right? Like We, we've had this experience and we've seen
Speaker 2:  at other places that If you do the thing that it's just like the the audiogram
Speaker 2:  on YouTube, it doesn't work nearly as well as If. you have video like the
Speaker 2:  algorithm likes video because YouTube is a video platform and So, we hear
Speaker 2:  this from creators all the time who are feeling somewhat forced
Speaker 2:  into becoming, if not video first, then sort of
Speaker 2:  video level shows. Yeah and it's changing
Speaker 2:  the things that people make because suddenly when you're on camera you start
Speaker 2:  thinking differently about the whole thing that you're making and you can
Speaker 2:  make different kinds of stuff. But it does feel like for
Speaker 2:  better and worse just because of like the way the business of all of this
Speaker 2:  works and how you find people video is not going,
Speaker 2:  it is more and more attached to the idea of What a podcast is than ever.
Speaker 2:  I'm curious If, you agree with that?
Speaker 12:  Yeah. I, I, I I mean you mentioned Serial earlier on, would
Speaker 12:  Serial have existed as a podcast if They had to
Speaker 12:  make video?
Speaker 2:  No.
Speaker 12:  I, I, I I would probably argue no,
Speaker 2:  You just couldn't do it. I mean They were making that show week to week as
Speaker 2:  They were doing it. You can't make a Netflix show like that. Yeah, that's
Speaker 2:  not how that works.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, exactly. So I, think I think that There are certain things that you,
Speaker 12:  you know, a chat cast or a chum cast or whatever, whatever you
Speaker 12:  want to call an interview podcast that is relatively easy
Speaker 12:  to slap a couple of cameras on and hey Presto, you've got
Speaker 12:  some video There, it becomes much harder. If, you want
Speaker 12:  to produce something a bit better and I think that's the
Speaker 12:  thing which is scaring creators away
Speaker 12:  because all of a sudden They don't want, you know, quite a lot of us went
Speaker 12:  into the audio industry because you can do amazing things with audio.
Speaker 12:  You can paint incredible pictures just using
Speaker 12:  audio, not having to worry about What. The video actually
Speaker 12:  works and in fact the pictures are better with audio in many ways because
Speaker 12:  you are tapping into people's imagination
Speaker 12:  and you know, I'm I might Look If, you don't know What, I Look like
Speaker 12:  I might Look completely different to one person in their mind's eye too.
Speaker 12:  Someone else. That's an amazing thing that audio can do. That
Speaker 12:  video can't and it worries me slightly that we are having
Speaker 12:  people who are being put off the whole podcast world because
Speaker 12:  They have to think about the video side and it's not just YouTube doing
Speaker 12:  this. Of course Spotify's big, big, big push right now is video.
Speaker 12:  Video is still exclusive on Spotify's platform.
Speaker 12:  So Spotify certainly isn't sharing that out. Even though you can do video
Speaker 12:  in a podcast RSS Feed If, you want to, that is most
Speaker 12:  definitely still an exclusive on their side. But it is interesting
Speaker 12:  seeing some of the data that's coming out of Spotify and seeing
Speaker 12:  that, for example, people are just listening to the audio
Speaker 12:  during the day but in the evening They might watch the
Speaker 12:  video
Speaker 12:  I think that There, there's some really interesting things There around
Speaker 12:  how people are consuming content and the different ways
Speaker 12:  that people consume content and video is not always right.
Speaker 2:  Well like when I talk to audio people, people who like deeply believe in
Speaker 2:  you know, public radio and audio been doing this for a long time, the thing
Speaker 2:  they're worried about is that video just eventually eats all of this because
Speaker 2:  it's easier to monetize. But then There are a lot of
Speaker 2:  cool things you can do in audio and cool things you can do with both. Like
Speaker 2:  I is, is it a better world when these two things kind of exist
Speaker 2:  separately or is is sort of smushing all of these things together on the
Speaker 2:  internet gonna lead to good stuff.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, I mean I w I was reflecting the other day that everything now that
Speaker 12:  we listen to audio on has a
Speaker 12:  full quality color screen. That never used to be the case
Speaker 12:  but it, but it is now the case that you know, literally everything that
Speaker 12:  you have, you have that beautiful color screen What are you gonna do with
Speaker 12:  it
Speaker 2:  Including like the dashboard of your car.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, exactly. Exactly. I mean I have been in, in
Speaker 12:  Ubers where the driver has been listening to
Speaker 12:  and I think watching a YouTube video. Same. Yes So,
Speaker 12:  I've been going, you know, So I think that the will intentionally be that
Speaker 12:  blurriness, I I Do think though that
Speaker 12:  There is a real opportunity for audio in this world a real
Speaker 12:  opportunity for something you know for your ears where
Speaker 12:  when your eyes are busy, I, I think that that is the thing that
Speaker 12:  podcasting has always been very good at using and
Speaker 12:  if we get rid of that unique selling point that podcasting
Speaker 12:  has and turn it into another form of video,
Speaker 12:  then I don't think that the world is a richer place for doing that.
Speaker 12:  I think that There is something to be said for something which
Speaker 12:  is specifically There for audio that you can enjoy while you
Speaker 12:  are, you know, going out for a walk while you're doing the dishes, while
Speaker 12:  you are driving a, you know, a one ton truck down a highway I. Think all
Speaker 12:  of those are very really important things and we should be
Speaker 12:  very careful about whether or not we want to lose the benefit of a Podcast
Speaker 12:  as being an audio first medium. Just because somebody at Spotify
Speaker 12:  or at YouTube has told us that we ought to have the video side because
Speaker 12:  as you So rightly say They earn more money from it,
Speaker 2:  Right? That's how They know how to sell ads. Yeah that is like you can, you
Speaker 2:  can boil So much of it down to that's how They know how to sell ads. Yeah,
Speaker 12:  Yeah, exactly. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So, What What about the user experience of of being a podcast listener.
Speaker 2:  I mean e especially If, you think about some of the open apps,
Speaker 2:  it wasn still RSS feeds with enclosures, right? We're we're dealing with
Speaker 2:  not terribly dissimilar distribution technology to What we had 20 years ago.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 12:  I, I, I. Think I think RSS has
Speaker 12:  changed and is changing. Okay, So we've seen very recently, for example,
Speaker 12:  transcripts appear in a bunch of podcast
Speaker 12:  apps. Apple is doing transcripts for everything but If.
Speaker 12:  you want to do a decent transcript and a transcript that you
Speaker 12:  can trust, you can write that transcript for yourself, you can
Speaker 12:  put that in the RSS feed and the app will pull that
Speaker 12:  creator made transcript in. Whether it's Apple Podcasts, whether
Speaker 12:  it's Pocket Casts, antenna pod, you know, So on
Speaker 12:  and So forth. So I think
Speaker 12:  one of the problems that people, that people
Speaker 12:  like Spotify have been trying to
Speaker 12:  convince us of is that you can't get some of the new
Speaker 12:  features that audiences would like into RSS
Speaker 12:  and that really isn't the case. We you, when
Speaker 12:  podcasting started, podcasting didn't have thumbnails, didn't have
Speaker 12:  categories. There were a lot of things that podcasting didn't have
Speaker 12:  and Apple came along and said, We want podcasting, but we want it to Look
Speaker 12:  better. This is What we would like to add to the spec and
Speaker 12:  one of the benefits of RSS is that it's extensible with a namespace.
Speaker 12:  So. You can put that additional stuff in. There and So, I I think this is
Speaker 12:  the exciting thing that I'm seeing with the podcasting
Speaker 12:  2.0 piece of work, which is being done by a bunch of,
Speaker 12:  a bunch of geeks, including by the way, one of the current inventors of
Speaker 12:  podcasting itself. Adam Curry, where they've actually gone.
Speaker 12:  Let's add a new namespace with some new ideas
Speaker 12:  for how podcasting can work. So not just a transcript tag,
Speaker 12:  but tags in terms of micropayments tags,
Speaker 12:  in terms of locations, tags, in terms of cast lists,
Speaker 12:  all of the stuff that We have missed from the podcast
Speaker 12:  world in the last 20 or So years and I think it's actually a very exciting
Speaker 12:  time now seeing some of these new ideas coming
Speaker 12:  in and seeing some of the more brave
Speaker 12:  apps using some of the data which is now available in them.
Speaker 2:  My last question to go all the way back to the beginning of What is a Podcast
Speaker 2:  20 years later, did We name it the right thing? Should we, should We have
Speaker 2:  just never called it a podcast in the first place? Call it a show and move
Speaker 2:  on with our lives. Was was Podcast, right? Did We get that right In
Speaker 2:  2004?
Speaker 12:  I I think the podcast is a useful word
Speaker 12:  because it says a few things. It says that it isn't a
Speaker 12:  broadcast, it's a Podcast, it's different and actually
Speaker 12:  I think, you know, to come back to some of the mistakes that perhaps were
Speaker 12:  made between 2019 and 2022, people were assuming that
Speaker 12:  podcasting was another form of broadcasting and you could reach tons and
Speaker 12:  tons and tons of people and that really isn't the case. It's more niche
Speaker 12:  casting or niche casting If you like rather than anything else.
Speaker 12:  So I think it's useful that it has a word I. Think it's
Speaker 12:  also useful that it actually, the word helps define a
Speaker 12:  little bit in terms of What. A podcast is in that
Speaker 12:  the pod bit talks about portability, talks about being able
Speaker 12:  to take that audio with you and a large amount of
Speaker 12:  Podcasts listening happens in a mobile environment. Whether
Speaker 12:  that happens to be on a car or public transport
Speaker 12:  or going out walking the dog, So I think that it is useful
Speaker 12:  to have that word, but I think that that word is becoming less and less
Speaker 12:  like by the way, the word radio is becoming less and less about the
Speaker 12:  technology and more and more about the type of programming
Speaker 12:  that it happens to be. A podcast is very clearly a different
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. All right, let's get to the hotline and before we do, I should
Speaker 2:  confess something I was supposed to ask all of you a couple of weeks ago
Speaker 2:  for hotline questions about 2004 I. Don't know
Speaker 2:  What. Those would've been, maybe you have like a 20-year-old iPod you're
Speaker 2:  trying to repurpose for something really cool or
Speaker 2:  you're I don't know. Trying to like get all the files off
Speaker 2:  your old spinning hard drive and having trouble I. Don't know. I'm sure it
Speaker 2:  would've been fun and still If. you have 2040 questions
Speaker 2:  that came up reading our package or listening to this podcast.
Speaker 2:  I. Want to hear 'em all? The number is 8 6 6 VERGE one one. The email
Speaker 2:  is vergecast at The Verge dot com. Send 'em all my way.
Speaker 2:  Gimme your 2004 questions. I'll put on my Time machine hat and
Speaker 2:  we will, we'll see What we can do for now We have something completely unrelated.
Speaker 2:  It's about iPads here. We, go.
Speaker 13:  Hey Vergecast. I was wondering that I iPod mini seven,
Speaker 13:  I've got an iPod mini six and I freaking love it. I've also got a switch
Speaker 13:  that I've been playing Tony Hawk skater on for a little bit and I just though
Speaker 13:  like, well if They put a arm shift
Speaker 13:  into the iPod mini seven, would it be an Nintendo Switch killer? Would it
Speaker 13:  be like a steam deck kind of competitor or are we not There yet with gaming
Speaker 13:  on the iPod yet? I? Don't know. Lemme know. What, you think, thanks, bye.
Speaker 2:  This is a super fun question and it's actually really timely right now
Speaker 2:  because I think we're about to get a new set of
Speaker 2:  iPads potentially as soon as like this week because there's
Speaker 2:  been a bunch of reporting that a new mini is coming. There's been a bunch
Speaker 2:  of reporting that it's gonna be early November. Like is this is the time
Speaker 2:  that would be if it's gonna start shipping in early November. I also love
Speaker 2:  the iPod Mini and desperately would love it to be
Speaker 2:  an intend to switch. It's the right size, it does all the other stuff. Like
Speaker 2:  if that could be the thing, I carried around with me all the time, I'd be
Speaker 2:  super into it. I, think There are two ways to Look at this
Speaker 2:  question and I wanna get to them both. One is just a question
Speaker 2:  of like would arm compatibility make
Speaker 2:  the iPod a more useful gaming machine And
Speaker 2:  I think to some extent the answer to that is yes, right? Like if it were
Speaker 2:  easier to take some of the games that run
Speaker 2:  on other chips and just run them on
Speaker 2:  an iPod, sure, that would be fine. I, don't think in
Speaker 2:  any way, shape or form, that is the main problem here, right? Like for one
Speaker 2:  thing, the the M series chips inside of the iPads are arm
Speaker 2:  chips. They're very good arm chips. They are vastly more powerful
Speaker 2:  arm chips than the stuff that's currently running inside
Speaker 2:  of the Switch. Like I was actually just looking at these benchmarks today
Speaker 2:  after I heard this question. If, you go back the
Speaker 2:  Nintendo switch on Geek Bench six, which is just one
Speaker 2:  sort of normal benchmark of What. It's like to use a
Speaker 2:  system under a little bit of load. The Nintendo Switch scores
Speaker 2:  702 on Geek Bench six. Again,
Speaker 2:  none of these are perfect benchmarks, but they're just useful illustrations,
Speaker 2:  right? So the Switch 7 0 2, the M four
Speaker 2:  in the iPod Pro scores a
Speaker 2:  14,621 like night and
Speaker 2:  day. The the M four is actually closer in score
Speaker 2:  to like high powered gaming PCs than it is to the
Speaker 2:  switch and yet the switch is awesome, right?
Speaker 2:  The processing power is not a problem. One, it's availability of games,
Speaker 2:  which is I. Think the iPad's main problem. There are lots of
Speaker 2:  structural reasons for that over the years. Apple until very recently
Speaker 2:  didn't want you to use gaming emulators
Speaker 2:  for instance. There was no way to have game streaming services inside of
Speaker 2:  the app store. Apple went to court with Epic
Speaker 2:  over whether Fortnite was allowed to be in the app store. That's been a whole
Speaker 2:  thing and I think will continue to be a whole thing. Apple loves
Speaker 2:  games and has had lots of games in the app store, but
Speaker 2:  particularly on the iPhone. These are just not the games by and large people
Speaker 2:  wanna play and So Apple hasn't really focused on them on the
Speaker 2:  iPod to be honest. I don't know exactly What, it is. I have
Speaker 2:  been surprised over the years to see Apple not make a bigger push into trying
Speaker 2:  to make this a really great gaming machine. And I think it's possible that
Speaker 2:  as gaming emulators become more important and as game streaming
Speaker 2:  services grow and come onto this, it will start to happen.
Speaker 2:  But it's just a lot of work to make a game available
Speaker 2:  on a new platform and you just don't see
Speaker 2:  Ubisoft being like our game is now available on
Speaker 2:  PlayStation and Xbox and PC and
Speaker 2:  iPod. Like it doesn't happen it, it doesn't work on Mac either. And Apple
Speaker 2:  has been desperately trying to change that for years to make the Mac, which
Speaker 2:  again is very powerful into a genuinely
Speaker 2:  competitive gaming platform. It's really hard to do that because
Speaker 2:  supporting any new platform is a ton of work and these companies by
Speaker 2:  and large just don't get on board with a new one until There is
Speaker 2:  vast evidence that it is going to be a good business and
Speaker 2:  no Apple product has provided that evidence. There's also the way that Apple
Speaker 2:  polices the app store and the way that it oversees things like in
Speaker 2:  game transactions and the way that it wants it was cut. There's a business
Speaker 2:  side of that that is very real I think that's starting to get stripped away
Speaker 2:  a little bit, which I think might make Apple products in general,
Speaker 2:  but especially the iPod a more interesting gaming platform. But all of that
Speaker 2:  aside, I think the thing missing from the iPod Mini in
Speaker 2:  particular is not a really
Speaker 2:  great chip or even a really compatible chip. It's
Speaker 2:  a controller, and this is kind of a weird thing to say, but I, think If,
Speaker 2:  you Look at the steam deck and you Look at the switch and you Look at even
Speaker 2:  some of these other game streaming devices. They have
Speaker 2:  dedicated controllers for a reason, right? Like if you're
Speaker 2:  building a game for the Nintendo Switch, you know exactly
Speaker 2:  What people are going to be doing, whether they're using a controller or
Speaker 2:  the joycons, whether the joycons are detached or attached,
Speaker 2:  you know the controls that are available, right? And you see a lot of
Speaker 2:  games use those things in a way that makes sense. There is an
Speaker 2:  assumption that like you're playing this game with a controller and I can
Speaker 2:  do that. You can't do that with the iPod. Most people using
Speaker 2:  an iPod I would say virtually everyone using an iPod is
Speaker 2:  not using a controller. And the iPad's technical
Speaker 2:  controller support has actually gotten very good over time. You can connect
Speaker 2:  a PlayStation controller, you can connect an Xbox controller. There are a
Speaker 2:  bunch of really good third party controllers out There, I have a a steel
Speaker 2:  series, one that I really like, but no
Speaker 2:  developer can build one of those games on the assumption that you're using
Speaker 2:  a controller and So, not only do They have to build their games differently
Speaker 2:  to work with a touchscreen, They have to build different kinds of games.
Speaker 2:  You just can't build a game as successfully
Speaker 2:  into a controller list ecosystem as you can into a
Speaker 2:  controller one. You're just by definition going to build different kinds
Speaker 2:  of games for a touchscreen. It's why you see games that are much more
Speaker 2:  swipe based and they're about tapping things and inventories become really
Speaker 2:  important and lots of turn based stuff as opposed to the kind of quick
Speaker 2:  twitch controller stuff. There's some of that out There and more of
Speaker 2:  that all the time and especially as products like the backbone get more
Speaker 2:  popular on the iPhone in particular, you'll start to
Speaker 2:  see that stuff kind of grow I. Think backbone has actually done really interesting
Speaker 2:  work growing the gaming ecosystem on the iPhone just by
Speaker 2:  being something like a targetable default controller.
Speaker 2:  But in the broad scheme of things, and again, especially on the iPod, that
Speaker 2:  doesn't exist. I think if Apple were to make
Speaker 2:  it was own controller, that would go a really long way
Speaker 2:  towards solving this because then you say, okay, this is the default thing
Speaker 2:  and accessory makers would build to something like that. Spec
Speaker 2:  There would be a way for developers to say, okay, this is probably What.
Speaker 2:  People with controllers will be using They can start to target the
Speaker 2:  one thing in the way that if you're a Nintendo developer, you can target
Speaker 2:  the switches control set. The amazing thing obviously would be if Apple
Speaker 2:  like built a gaming handheld and actually just gave me an iPod
Speaker 2:  with detachable joycons, like that's the dream. I would like that very
Speaker 2:  badly. That is a device I would use for many hours every single
Speaker 2:  day and would upgrade alarmingly quickly all the time. I kind of don't see
Speaker 2:  that happening. I think if Apple were gonna build a dedicated gaming device,
Speaker 2:  it probably would have by now. So, I. Think There
Speaker 2:  is a great gaming device inside of the iPod, but I think
Speaker 2:  because it's been So long and hasn't existed yet because of the way Apple
Speaker 2:  runs the app store and because of the pieces of What makes a great gaming
Speaker 2:  console around the chip don't exist.
Speaker 2:  I just don't see it happening. But I, hope I'm wrong. And If, you have an
Speaker 2:  awesome gaming setup for your iPod. I would love to hear about it whether
Speaker 2:  you've figured out the wire controller, the setup that works, or you've found
Speaker 2:  a thing that plugs into the iPod Mini and makes it feel like a switch. I
Speaker 2:  wanna hear all of your iPod gaming setups because There is an amazing
Speaker 2:  game console in There and I Wanna figure out how to make it work? I have
Speaker 2:  a backbone for my iPhone. I love it. But
Speaker 2:  can always email us at vergecast at The Verge dot com. Call the hotline
Speaker 2:  eight six six VERGE one one. There's an innovation for you. There are a lot
Speaker 2:  of people I talk to, by the way, who want call in Podcasts to figure out
Speaker 2:  how to really become a thing. Big fan, keep all your questions coming.
Speaker 2:  This show's produced by Liam James Will Pour and Eric Gomez The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  is The Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neela,
Speaker 2:  and I'll be back on Friday to talk about all kinds of news. We got a bunch
Speaker 2:  of Tesla stuff to catch up on. Lots of gadgety things going on this week.
Speaker 2:  Some Apple News, lots to do. We'll see you then. Rock and roll
Speaker 3:  Support for The. Vergecast comes from Batman, aum, shadow, available
Speaker 3:  only on me. Quest three and three s me quest's. Biggest
Speaker 3:  and most anticipated release of 2024 is Batman AUM Shadow,
Speaker 3:  a groundbreaking new entry in the celebrated AUM series.
Speaker 3:  Experience the world of Gotham City through Batman's eyes and his
Speaker 3:  fists become the night Batman aum. Shadow is included when
Speaker 3:  you buy Medi Quest. Three or three s available October 22nd.
Speaker 3:  Learn more@batmanarcamshadow.com. Rate a T for teen
Speaker 3:  Batman aum. Shadow is only in VR and Medi. Quest three and three s
Speaker 3:  offer valid on qualifying products purchased from
Speaker 3:  September 25th, 2024 through April 30th, 2025. Terms
Speaker 3:  apply.