# Transcript
ID: 01bcae0a-8dbd-4498-a820-8421f7488c4a
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-3553879873729643421/-7209930572037149842/s93290-US-3907s-1722332727.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of dedicated streaming hardware:
We try out a couple of show formats we’ve been planning for a while.
In Version History, we tell the story of the Roku Netflix Player, debate its legacy, and try to decide whether this thing belongs in the Version History Hall of Fame.
From Fast Company: Inside Netflix’s Project Griffin: The Forgotten History Of Roku Under Reed Hastings
From CNBC: How Roku used the Netflix playbook to rule streaming video
From CNN: Netflix Player offers PC-free movie watching
From Wired: Review: Roku Netflix Set Top Box Is Just Shy of Totally Amazing
From The New York Times: Why the Roku Netflix Player Is the First Shot of the Revolution
After that, it’s time for debates. Nilay Patel and David Pierce yell at each other about who should own the screens in your car. Are CarPlay and Android Auto the answer, the solution to universally crappy automaker software?
Car companies haven’t figured out if they’ll let Apple CarPlay take over all the screens
The rest of the auto industry still loves CarPlay and Android Auto
Everybody hates GM’s decision to kill Apple CarPlay and Android Auto for its EVs
Rivian CEO says CarPlay isn’t going to happen
Apple’s fancy new CarPlay will only work wirelessly
Later, David answers a question from The Vergecast Hotline about political spam texts.
From The Washington Post: How to stop receiving spam texts
From PCMag: Stop Robotexts: How to Block Smishing and Spam Text Messages
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (17 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of dedicated streaming
Speaker 2:  hardware. I'm your friend David Pierce, and if you're seeing this, I'm already
Speaker 2:  dead. I'm just kidding. I'm on vacation right now as you're listening to
Speaker 2:  this or seeing it on YouTube. I am probably in the woods of
Speaker 2:  Vermont, I don't know, running up and down a mountain or whatever you do
Speaker 2:  when you're in the woods. The point was just to like get away, find somewhere
Speaker 2:  with fewer screens and more trees and just spend two weeks
Speaker 2:  detoxing. And detoxing sounds like more aggressive than I actually mean it.
Speaker 2:  I kind of like life with screens. It's all, I think mostly fine, but it's
Speaker 2:  nice to have a break every once in a while and I will say when I go even
Speaker 2:  like a day or two sort of deliberately turning all of that off,
Speaker 2:  it is really rejuvenating in a way that just totally resetting usually is.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, while I'm gone, we've prepared some really fun stuff for you over
Speaker 2:  the next two twos. So we're forever experimenting with new
Speaker 2:  ideas and new formats and even new shows we might wanna launch at The Verge.
Speaker 2:  And mostly they just live like in meetings and Google Docs and their
Speaker 2:  ideas and things we wanna do. But we figured while I'm gone, let's try some
Speaker 2:  stuff out. So what you're gonna hear from us over the next two weeks is two
Speaker 2:  versions of two different ideas we've had. One
Speaker 2:  is kind of a rewatch show and one is kind of a debate show. Just new ways
Speaker 2:  to talk about tech. Still should still feel like The Vergecast, it's gonna
Speaker 2:  be people you recognize. But we wanted to just try some new ways of talking
Speaker 2:  about this stuff that we don't do on this show. Typically. Maybe there'll
Speaker 2:  be segments, maybe there'll be new shows, maybe you'll hate them and we'll
Speaker 2:  never do them again. Who knows? But we're gonna try some stuff. So the reason
Speaker 2:  I tell you all this is because I genuinely want to know what you think of
Speaker 2:  all of this as you listen or as you watch, tell us what you think. Do you
Speaker 2:  like these formats? Do you wish we asked different questions? Do you wish
Speaker 2:  we structured them slightly differently? Do you have other show ideas or
Speaker 2:  format ideas you think that we should do inside of The Vergecast? I want
Speaker 2:  to hear everything. We want all of your feedback all the time, but especially
Speaker 2:  on this, this is deliberately us just being like, these are things we've
Speaker 2:  been talking about for somewhere between months and years. We wanna know
Speaker 2:  what you think So. anyway, all of that is to say should be fun.
Speaker 2:  We're trying new things. I'm nervous about this episode in a way that I think
Speaker 2:  is very fun. So I'm gonna go back to vacation. I hope you enjoy. This is
Speaker 2:  The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Wing Weekly was a big one. There's the re watchable on the Ringer, that's
Speaker 2:  pretty popular. There are a million of these and I really enjoy them. It
Speaker 2:  seems like every Star at some point during the pandemic was like, I'll do
Speaker 2:  a rewatch podcast and I will happily listen to all of them. So our idea was
Speaker 2:  how do we do this for tech, right? There are all these stories out there
Speaker 2:  of individual gadgets or apps or kind of these
Speaker 2:  contained stories that we felt like we could go through and talk about in
Speaker 2:  similar ways. A lot of them, we at The, Verge lived through. We used them,
Speaker 2:  we wrote about them, we covered them. And there are lots of stories that
Speaker 2:  we have from those days that are just fun to talk about again. Plus it's
Speaker 2:  a good way to kind of go back in history and talk about how we got here,
Speaker 2:  right? There's a lot of good ways to talk about the history of the tech industry,
Speaker 2:  but doing it kind of one gadget and device and app at a time felt
Speaker 2:  like a really fun way to do it. So we've been kicking around this format
Speaker 2:  for a long time. I've been kind of borrowing and stealing things from other
Speaker 2:  rewatch podcasts that I really like and we've put together something, we're
Speaker 2:  calling it version history. I don't know if that's actually the name. I don't
Speaker 2:  know if this is a good idea at all, but we've recorded a couple of them
Speaker 2:  now and it's been really fun. So I hope you enjoy them as much as we did.
Speaker 2:  The first one is about the very, very, very first Roku
Speaker 2:  here goes.
Speaker 2:  All right, Alex Krantz. Hello. Hey, what's up Neela Patel,
Speaker 2:  welcome. You're dead to me. This, this is how we like to start
Speaker 2:  every, this is great. We're starting a thing. I'm on vacation.
Speaker 2:  It's the whole thing. So the thing we are going to talk about in this first
Speaker 2:  segment is the original Roku. It's called the
Speaker 2:  Roku Netflix Player. And here's how we're gonna do this. We're gonna basically,
Speaker 2:  there are three pieces of this show that we're gonna try to do here
Speaker 2:  and I think if we end up doing these longer episodes, there will be more.
Speaker 2:  But what we're gonna do is I've broken it down to three pieces. We have like
Speaker 2:  a brief history lesson. I have a whole bunch of notes. So I'm gonna like
Speaker 2:  tell you the brief story of this thing. Y'all should chime in and have feelings
Speaker 2:  and thoughts. We're gonna talk about how people felt about it. I've looked
Speaker 2:  up a bunch of reviews, I have a lot of like funny stuff I wanna show you.
Speaker 2:  And then we have some questions that we're gonna see if we can figure out
Speaker 2:  this thing's legacy and whether it matters. And then we are starting a thing
Speaker 2:  called the version History Hall of Fame. That's all I've decided about it
Speaker 2:  so far. But then at the end we're gonna decide whether this thing belongs
Speaker 2:  in the Hall of Fame. So the Roku Netflix player. So this goes all the way
Speaker 2:  back to like 2002. This guy Anthony Wood, starts
Speaker 2:  a company called Roku originally to build music
Speaker 2:  products. They built a couple of things that you've never heard of that don't
Speaker 2:  really matter, but also at the same time, Netflix, this company that shipped
Speaker 2:  DVDs to people, decided that they wanted to build hardware. They wanted to
Speaker 2:  like have a box for this new instant watch thing that they
Speaker 2:  had on Netflix where you could watch TV shows on the internet,
Speaker 2:  which was quite a thing.
Speaker 5:  Was it because they knew that Silver light sucks?
Speaker 2:  So no. Oh I mean debatable. Okay.
Speaker 2:  The only place, this is a good point. The only place at this moment that
Speaker 2:  you could watch Netflix shows on the internet was on a Windows computer through
Speaker 2:  Internet Explorer. Because of Silverlight there was a lot of
Speaker 2:  enthusiasm about Silverlight coming to other platforms, which is a very funny
Speaker 2:  thing to read about all these years later.
Speaker 6:  I think we need to stop and remind our audience that Silverlight was
Speaker 6:  Microsoft's competitor to Adobe Flash. And that Adobe Flash was
Speaker 6:  Adobe's Ill faded media platform for the web where you had
Speaker 6:  plugins in your browser and you could run entire games and
Speaker 6:  applications. But inside like Adobe's weird framework, I'm only saying this
Speaker 6:  because we have an audience that is young and this was a thing that happened
Speaker 6:  to all, like it was just made to happen to us. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  We had no choice in the matter. And
Speaker 2:  There was a time that Flash was considered like very good. Yeah. And Silver
Speaker 2:  Light was kind of a, a would be competitor to Flash
Speaker 6:  Would be is very accurate. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It was. It was a, it was a pretender to the throne of a Toby Flash
Speaker 6:  When the first iPhone came out. It was a major controversy that it didn't
Speaker 6:  run flash or silver light or is craft compressor. Oh yeah,
Speaker 6:  that's where we are. We we're we're many, many, many years away from this.
Speaker 6:  Yes, yes. I'm just pointing out that at the time Netflix was like, we're
Speaker 6:  betting on not Flash, which was in itself bananas.
Speaker 6:  But like the whole web was built on these like weird plugins. Yes.
Speaker 2:  No that that's right. That is so that is, that is good context. So at some
Speaker 2:  point in this process, Anthony Wood meets Reed Hastings, the
Speaker 2:  CEO of Netflix at a conference. And this is where there is some
Speaker 2:  disagreement on the history, but I believe the actual correct answer
Speaker 2:  is that Anthony Wood convinces Reed Hastings to partner with his company
Speaker 2:  Roku, to build a player for Netflix.
Speaker 2:  Anthony Wood was not a Netflix employee, he was kind of a Netflix employee,
Speaker 2:  but he was like a contractor who was hired to work there. Roku was always
Speaker 2:  a separate company. This is the thing a lot of people get wrong. In retrospect,
Speaker 2:  Roku did not spin out of Netflix. Roku was its own thing that worked with
Speaker 2:  Netflix But. anyway, they go through, they start building this thing called
Speaker 2:  Project Griffin that is basically going to be a box through which You can
Speaker 2:  play Netflix on your television and a team of about 20 people
Speaker 2:  work on it for a while. They get it ready, they get it done, it's gonna be
Speaker 2:  a box, it's gonna be a streaming box. Everybody's very excited. And then
Speaker 2:  right before the thing ships, Reed Hastings gets cold feet and
Speaker 2:  says basically, I am afraid that we are
Speaker 2:  going to alienate all of our partners by making hardware and
Speaker 2:  that if they mail, if they make a Netflix box, they are going to
Speaker 2:  lose all of these other companies that they wanna work with to put Netflix
Speaker 2:  on all the screens everywhere. They had made other partnerships, they were
Speaker 2:  talking to Apple and lots of others about putting Netflix on other devices
Speaker 2:  and thought if they made their own, they would piss people off. So instead
Speaker 2:  they basically give this project back to Roku and they gave
Speaker 2:  them some people, some patents, the all the work they had done so far
Speaker 2:  and in return got, I think it was 15% of Roku,
Speaker 2:  which spoiler alert they sold and should have held onto for
Speaker 2:  a very long time. Netflix
Speaker 6:  Does not have Diamond Hands.
Speaker 2:  No, not, not in that case. Certainly. So then in
Speaker 2:  March of 2008, the the Roku internet player
Speaker 2:  gets launched. And again, just to give you a sense of of timing there, at
Speaker 2:  that time Netflix had just reported that it had 8 million subscribers. Most
Speaker 2:  people were on DVDs. Again, the only way you could stream Netflix
Speaker 2:  at the time was on a Windows PC through Internet Explorer. Nothing did
Speaker 2:  unlimited streaming like this. It like wasn't a thing that you could do
Speaker 2:  the, the whole watch instantly thing on Netflix. Brand new, very
Speaker 2:  exciting. Nila, you'll, you'll appreciate this particularly, I wrote down
Speaker 2:  the list of ports that the Roku Netflix player had. It had an HTMI
Speaker 2:  port. It had component ports, it had composite ports. It had an ethernet
Speaker 2:  jack, it had S video and it had optical ports. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Everything I love
Speaker 2:  It. We call that Yeah, that's the full, the full Port
Speaker 6:  S video is a is you're like, I am not interested in quality but I
Speaker 6:  want to pretend that I am. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So it costs $99. Do either of you have memories of the
Speaker 2:  first ever Netflix box? I do as big streaming nerds. Ne
Speaker 2:  you. Yeah. You were at Eng Gadget, like chronicling this stuff. There was
Speaker 2:  a lot of Eng Gadget stuff back then. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  A OL has since deleted those posts from the internet. I went looking for
Speaker 6:  'em. They're gone. Yeah. But we wrote a lot about this device because it
Speaker 6:  was, like you said, the first mainstream streaming device, Netflix's
Speaker 6:  catalog is really small. So there's a lot of jokes about what you couldn't,
Speaker 6:  could not watch on it, but it was like obvious that gadget
Speaker 6:  nerds would love this thing. And then the fury about it
Speaker 6:  was that it was only four a DI which really explains that S video port.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Right. Like this thing could stream in in interlaced sd.
Speaker 6:  So it was, they were trying very hard to conserve bandwidth and in
Speaker 6:  an early preview of don't ever bet on someone to issue a software
Speaker 6:  update, they kept telling us that it also supported 10 a DI
Speaker 2:  And they alluded to maybe doing more than just stereo sound too.
Speaker 2:  There were lots of big ideas about like, oh this box is very powerful, it'll
Speaker 2:  do lots of other stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And then those software updates never came. Yeah. and it became the jaded
Speaker 6:  monster that I am now. But the, the idea was so sound
Speaker 6:  and then the question was do you want a single appliance for a single
Speaker 6:  app, right. That only has Netflix, it's catalog. Can Netflix make its catalog
Speaker 6:  big enough? And you kind of just like immediately got into all of the streaming
Speaker 6:  questions from this one little box that had a tiny catalog that streamed
Speaker 6:  in 40 I and was a little glitchy. You know like none of this technology worked
Speaker 6:  yet. There was, at that time there were still, it's hard to believe major
Speaker 6:  questions about whether the internet was architected to stream video
Speaker 6:  in this way.
Speaker 2:  Like infrastructural, like physically if it could
Speaker 6:  Do it, You can. Yeah. Whether like a packet switch network like the internet
Speaker 6:  could do. and it's like now you're like, what are you talking about? I can
Speaker 6:  do this on my phone, whatever I want. Like at the time
Speaker 6:  there was, there were like architecture questions and Comcast and another
Speaker 6:  big ISPs, if you will remember around the same time were
Speaker 6:  like, if you plug your Xbox into a Comcast connection,
Speaker 6:  we will give it a dedicated lane of broadband
Speaker 6:  so we can serve it. Video disclosure at Comcast is an investor, Fox
Speaker 6:  Media, you know, all this, that idea did not work and actually got in a lot
Speaker 6:  of trouble over it. 'cause that was the beginning of like a net neutrality
Speaker 6:  fight. But like in, its like primitive state. But it came outta something
Speaker 6:  very sincere, which is like, can the internet do video? And the Netflix box
Speaker 6:  was the first thing that was like, we will just stream video to you. We'll
Speaker 6:  figure this out.
Speaker 2:  Kranz, do you, did you have one of these? Do you remember this thing coming
Speaker 2:  out?
Speaker 5:  No, I didn't have one because it didn't run Plex. I, I really
Speaker 5:  wanted to be super into Netflix streaming at the time, but I only had
Speaker 5:  Max and the Windows Silver Light thing. So I was like f this noise, I'm going
Speaker 5:  full plex and it couldn't run Plex. So I was like,
Speaker 5:  I don't, why do I do that?
Speaker 2:  I honestly thought that was a bit Plex has been around that long.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I've been on Plex since like 2008.
Speaker 2:  That's nuts.
Speaker 5:  It was originally, it's a spinoff of Xbox Media Center
Speaker 5:  XPMC.
Speaker 2:  Wow. So this is, this is how old all this stuff is. Like those are the days.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I appreciate that you skipped right past let's find the
Speaker 2:  like useful way and went straight to just pirated chaos.
Speaker 2:  I love this for you.
Speaker 5:  Look, the useful way came later than, than the pirated chaos
Speaker 5:  useful way was like so far behind everybody else.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I'm, I'm glad you were also early to the let me get a movie
Speaker 2:  on Netflix, rip it to my computer and then ship it back to Netflix because
Speaker 2:  that was like the single best use of Netflix that existed. It ruled.
Speaker 2:  So Neli, you, you mentioned some of these things, but I went back through
Speaker 2:  a bunch of the reviews of this thing, which are very funny. I would say the
Speaker 2:  thing people liked most was how easy it was to set up.
Speaker 2:  You could just plug it into whatever TV you had and log into Netflix.
Speaker 2:  It did the code thing where you would like log in on Netflix's website and
Speaker 2:  enter a code and it would connect that way, which was way ahead of its time.
Speaker 2:  People were very annoyed by typing in their wifi password on a like
Speaker 2:  five arrow cursor, which still annoying. So
Speaker 2:  kudos to everybody for figuring that
Speaker 6:  Out. I just wanna point out it's been like 20 years and no one has better
Speaker 6:  ideas.
Speaker 2:  That is still the best interface we have. It's ridiculous. But the two things
Speaker 2:  that annoyed people were one, as you said Neli the selection.
Speaker 2:  And this was at the time Netflix said it had about a hundred thousand things
Speaker 2:  that you could get, which is much larger than the Netflix library today.
Speaker 2:  Most of that stuff was on DVDs and the streaming stuff was only about 10,000
Speaker 2:  titles. And that included like individual episodes of TV shows.
Speaker 2:  I have a quote from cnet, which I very much enjoyed that said March of the
Speaker 2:  Penguins is the only movie in the top 100 that's available for streaming.
Speaker 2:  And it's also only one of four streamable documentaries. There
Speaker 2:  was 30 Rock, there was the office. So like I would've been fine, but for
Speaker 2:  the most part people were unhappy about it. One thing I very much enjoyed,
Speaker 2:  people were psyched that it only took about a minute to
Speaker 2:  load a video. This was like a, this was like a win was when you press play,
Speaker 2:  it only took about a minute to start playing. And this was back in the buffering
Speaker 2:  days when you would just sit and like wait for Netflix to
Speaker 2:  chug its way through. It is impossible for me to remember when that
Speaker 2:  would've felt fast to the point where now it's like that would, I would turn
Speaker 2:  off my television and be like, something is broken.
Speaker 6:  I mean think about back then people having
Speaker 6:  megabit internet connections was still
Speaker 6:  like, it wasn't unusual but it was rare enough, right?
Speaker 6:  That you couldn't just count on it. Like I graduated from law school
Speaker 6:  in 2006 with a megabit internet connection and I was like, yeah
Speaker 6:  that was that moment. Like bandwidth was not a thing
Speaker 6:  and Netflix was trying to cram this device into an internet that
Speaker 6:  was just not ready for it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. There there were a bunch of people talking about their internet speeds
Speaker 2:  in in their reviews and a bunch of folks were like, oh yeah, I
Speaker 2:  have a one megabit per second connection and it, it does fine. And then somebody
Speaker 2:  was like, I have a 2.2 megabits per second connection and it's sick. It's
Speaker 2:  like fast as hell guys. You don't even know.
Speaker 2:  Which I, I loved,
Speaker 6:  Again, for a young audience, a megabit is a unit of bandwidth is much smaller.
Speaker 2:  Imagine if your current internet connection was 1000th the speed
Speaker 2:  that it currently is. That's what we're talking about. And also
Speaker 2:  the, the thing that Netflix did to make this thing work was it was
Speaker 2:  just a player you couldn't search at the beginning. You couldn't find stuff,
Speaker 2:  you couldn't browse. You would put things in your queue on netflix.com
Speaker 2:  and then you would go to the player and you could browse through your queue
Speaker 2:  and pick stuff to watch people had, you had two different cues. This is a
Speaker 2:  thing I had forgotten. You had a DVD queue and you had a streaming queue
Speaker 2:  and this, that was true for like years and I had completely forgotten that
Speaker 2:  that was the case and you had to like manage what you were getting when and
Speaker 2:  you could stream some stuff and you could DVD some stuff and it was insane
Speaker 2:  chaos. And I don't miss that one tiny little bit.
Speaker 6:  Well you have to remember the entire Netflix paradigm
Speaker 6:  was cues. Right? Right. So they, they had this like weird problem
Speaker 6:  where stuff that is very familiar to us now, like discovery and
Speaker 6:  algorithmic recommendations and blah blah blah, like didn't exist
Speaker 6:  because the entire Netflix model was you were gonna, we're
Speaker 6:  gonna mail you some DVDs, you're gonna mail 'em back and we'll mail you the
Speaker 6:  next ones. So even though they had recommendations, Netflix
Speaker 6:  famously had a challenge to develop a better recommendation
Speaker 6:  algorithm. The model that they were
Speaker 6:  still using was, you're gonna put physical
Speaker 6:  movies in a queue, like discs in a queue to be mailed to you.
Speaker 6:  And I think they didn't want to break that right away.
Speaker 5:  I thought it was a really good way of like, that was still at a time where
Speaker 5:  we hadn't fully like comprehended how instantaneous
Speaker 5:  media could arrive in our lives. Right. Like even music at the time was like,
Speaker 5:  wow, You can just download this off of iTunes. It was a big deal. And so
Speaker 5:  them saying, Hey You can get a whole movie. It felt like
Speaker 5:  this, this big magical moment. But also getting drunk and
Speaker 5:  then waking up the next morning and being like, what did I add to my cue
Speaker 5:  best feeling in the world. Incredible feeling when
Speaker 5:  you're in college.
Speaker 2:  Kranz, I really like imagining you like coming home from the bars at two
Speaker 2:  30 in the morning and be like, let's, let's Netflix Cube baby.
Speaker 5:  It was the frat houses because we didn't have bars. But yes. Okay.
Speaker 2:  That's that's good. Alright, well we, we are time constrained here so let's,
Speaker 2:  let's just jump, these are some of the, the questions we're gonna ask for
Speaker 2:  every single one of these as we go. The first one is, what was the best thing
Speaker 2:  in retrospect about this thing? To me it's just that it was a box
Speaker 2:  for streaming, right? Yeah. Like I feel like that's just the whole ne
Speaker 2:  Neli really wants it to be the s video port. I can like see it in your face.
Speaker 6:  No, I'm, I'm gonna give you like a really esoteric answer to this. Please.
Speaker 6:  It made a Roku like, okay, we've talked to
Speaker 6:  Anthony Wood on this show many times over the years. That
Speaker 6:  company just has rearchitected how
Speaker 6:  TVs work. Like fundamentally the modern
Speaker 6:  TV ecosystem. Every version of it looks like Roku's plan.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And they started with this silly Netflix app but they knew what they
Speaker 6:  were making was the cable box of the future. They they knew it from the beginning.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That this thing would be the cable box. They would give them away for
Speaker 6:  as cheap as they could and they would charge fees like the app store models
Speaker 6:  to all the apps that were on the thing and they would just come to dominate.
Speaker 6:  And I think that has like in some ways made the TV
Speaker 6:  world a lot weirder. It's just, it's weird out there. But
Speaker 6:  it wouldn't have happened without this device. The way that Apple and
Speaker 6:  Microsoft were going at the time was just really slow. Right. Like
Speaker 6:  the Apple TV existed, the Apple TV came out way before this. Yes. Do you
Speaker 6:  remember? It was a hobby garbage and it was basically a Mac mini with a hard
Speaker 6:  drive and you could buy movies and they would download overnight again
Speaker 6:  megabit per second internet connections. They would download overnight to
Speaker 6:  a hard drive wind. Microsoft was doing Windows Media Center. They've been
Speaker 6:  doing it for almost a decade at this point. Every CES Bill
Speaker 6:  Gates would stand on stage and be like, I'm gonna put a Windows
Speaker 6:  PC in your living room. Yep. Like just threatening America in the
Speaker 6:  world, this concept. And they were just not getting it done 'cause
Speaker 6:  they were insistent that they needed to put computers like big
Speaker 6:  computers in your living room. And so Roku showed up in this little box,
Speaker 6:  $99 didn't have much of an interface but it did the one
Speaker 6:  thing which is stream movies over the internet. And that I think
Speaker 6:  caused just a sea change in the industry.
Speaker 2:  I agree with that. I think the, like the extent to which Roku had had
Speaker 2:  this plan fleshed all the way out from the very beginning really surprised
Speaker 2:  me in going back and researching this. Like they were saying from the jump,
Speaker 2:  like we wanna have more apps on this. We have plans for an app store. We
Speaker 2:  like they saw the whole thing and like pulled it off in a
Speaker 2:  surprisingly coherent way over time And
Speaker 6:  Go, just go back. I would just tell you, just go back, look at the very first
Speaker 6:  Apple tv which was a Mac mini. Yeah. It had an Intel
Speaker 6:  processor and a hard drive.
Speaker 2:  Yep. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like they were just way off in the weeds on that thing.
Speaker 2:  One of the knocks on some of the reviews for this thing was that you couldn't
Speaker 2:  rent or buy movies. Which is a very funny knock in retrospect.
Speaker 2:  Like being mad at Netflix for not letting you rent movies would be a is not
Speaker 2:  a thing you hear so much anymore. What was the worst thing about this thing?
Speaker 6:  Oh I mean it was a piece of junk.
Speaker 5:  It wasn't very good. Yeah. Like it only ran Netflix
Speaker 2:  So good. It existed bad. Everything else about it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You know I said the thing about never not believing in in software
Speaker 6:  updates coming or like not reviewing potential. This was like
Speaker 6:  the all this is all of that is wrapped up in there. Right. We'd never review
Speaker 6:  a product based on its potential. This thing like this device,
Speaker 6:  you're like oh man the next one's gonna be great. This one on the other hand,
Speaker 6:  that's a real mess. Right? But the
Speaker 5:  Next one was great. Like the next Rokus were
Speaker 5:  exceptional.
Speaker 6:  They got there. It took a long time for Roku to, to figure out. And even
Speaker 6:  now the Roku product line is like, what are you doing
Speaker 5:  Series two They said yeah You can do Plex. And that was ah that
Speaker 5:  was,
Speaker 6:  See what else?
Speaker 5:  That was it. I was, I like, Roku is lead, nothing else matters.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  The pendulum of Roku was that it got way, way better and then it got way,
Speaker 2:  way worse. Yes. And I like, I don't think it's good now but it was good for
Speaker 2:  a long time.
Speaker 6:  I feel like we, we've talked a lot about bandwidth on this episode and it,
Speaker 6:  it is really hard to remember a time when people's ideas
Speaker 6:  were constrained by bandwidth. And so you could see like you're like,
Speaker 6:  oh this is how it should work. I should select a movie and it should start
Speaker 6:  playing. And if you'll remember, the cable companies
Speaker 6:  had those systems. They had video on demand systems running on their weird
Speaker 6:  proprietary cable networks with horrible interfaces and bad software. Like
Speaker 6:  all of it was bad. But those networks were optimized to let you just do video
Speaker 6:  on demand and no one thought the internet could do it so this device could
Speaker 6:  like let you do it. Now we live in a time when people are like six G
Speaker 6:  and everyone's like What for? And they're like, we don't know. Right?
Speaker 6:  But like it, at that moment in time, the things people wanted to do were
Speaker 6:  out racing the networks, which was what made it also exciting.
Speaker 6:  'cause you could see the networks would catch up.
Speaker 2:  All right, next question. If you could go back in time and make it before
Speaker 2:  anybody else did. So in this case you meet Reed Hastings at a conference
Speaker 2:  before Anthony Wood does. What would you do differently?
Speaker 5:  I mean I think we know NE's answer and it false CS video more
Speaker 6:  Reports, video ports. Man. It's like that first
Speaker 6:  one was was correct in its ambition. Like they,
Speaker 6:  they got there
Speaker 5:  Should have had more apps on it.
Speaker 2:  That's my answer too, actually. Go, go convince Hulu or
Speaker 2:  somebody to like also do streaming
Speaker 5:  Plex, Hulu and Boxy were all like
Speaker 5:  existing in 2008. At least two of those were brand new baby
Speaker 5:  concepts Boxy and, and Hulu. But like they could have done it. They could
Speaker 5:  have put some of that other stuff on there. And at the time most people who
Speaker 5:  were using streaming video and stuff, they were streaming it locally and
Speaker 5:  they were using XBMC, they were using Plex. That's how they were getting
Speaker 5:  everything. And so the fact that Roku was late to like
Speaker 5:  net in internal network video was was a bummer 'cause
Speaker 5:  it could have been really just hit the ground running.
Speaker 6:  I just wanna point out that Hulu launched in 2007 with only an announcement
Speaker 6:  and no content.
Speaker 5:  Yes. I love Hulu.
Speaker 6:  So it would've been, it would've been, you could've gotten Hulu on there.
Speaker 6:  That's what I'm
Speaker 2:  Saying.
Speaker 5:  Where was the ABC go?
Speaker 6:  It would've just been the logo.
Speaker 5:  I wanna look at just the logo and then I want the ABC Go app.
Speaker 6:  ABC was still on go.com for up until recently. It's wonderful. So it was
Speaker 6:  ESPN. I think the idea that it was an appliance actually served it well in
Speaker 6:  its moment. 'cause remember everyone else was trying to shove computers under
Speaker 6:  your TV and you were bringing in all of these computer metaphors
Speaker 6:  and this device was like, it's just your Netflix queue, it's
Speaker 6:  just delivered here instead of in your mailbox. and it was, there was a simplicity
Speaker 6:  to it that made people think about it differently. The
Speaker 6:  thing I would've changed is I would've gotten Netflix to spend more money
Speaker 6:  to put at least a couple hit movies on there. 'cause every review basically
Speaker 6:  ended with, there's nothing to watch. Like This is the future where there's
Speaker 6:  nothing to watch. And I, I think the big change would've been, hey
Speaker 6:  like let's find the money to get one blockbuster movie on here
Speaker 6:  so that people have something to watch and like they're excited about it.
Speaker 6:  Oh
Speaker 5:  The studios were terrified at that time though. They would've said
Speaker 5:  absolutely not. They didn't want any of their stuff streaming that way 'cause
Speaker 5:  they thought it was gonna be like the end of how they make money
Speaker 6:  And it was Yeah. To
Speaker 2:  Be clear. Yeah they were, they were, they were
Speaker 5:  They Correct.
Speaker 6:  Hundred percent correct.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But yeah, it's, it's, it's an interesting Well and I was, the next
Speaker 2:  question is actually, is there an alternate timeline in which this thing
Speaker 2:  was even more successful? Like what Parallel Universe makes the Netflix player
Speaker 2:  an even bigger hit? And I think that's the one where Netflix starts spending
Speaker 2:  on original content slightly quicker.
Speaker 6:  Right? The thing that made Netflix streaming work was years later. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Right. This is like in my in. I can't help but think about this timeline
Speaker 6:  in terms of gadget plugs. 2008 was Zy Gadget, Netflix launches House of Cards.
Speaker 6:  We were at The. Verge. Yeah. Right. And that's like years later. And that,
Speaker 6:  that was the turn like just fully the turn into, okay
Speaker 6:  now these devices have their own content and Netflix knew it. This, the movie
Speaker 6:  studios did not want to give them the content the TV studios did, which is
Speaker 6:  how you end up with the office in Suits and all this other stuff happening.
Speaker 6:  But that, that was the thing they were missing and eventually they just spent
Speaker 6:  the money to figure it out by owning it directly. Alright,
Speaker 2:  A couple more questions then we'll get outta here. Could you reboot this
Speaker 2:  in 2024? I think the answer's no. I think like a Netflix specific thing
Speaker 2:  has no place in 2024.
Speaker 5:  What if it's like an as an add-on for the Apple TV and all the other
Speaker 5:  ones where Netflix refuses to to have its continued watching
Speaker 5:  in their apps.
Speaker 2:  Oh that's interesting. I mean but like is it, is there something to I want
Speaker 2:  to turn on my TV and the very first thing that appears is just Netflix. Like
Speaker 2:  skip the home screen, do all just give me Netflix. I kind of think no,
Speaker 5:  No. Yeah, I think we're past that point. That would've been great in 2020
Speaker 5:  or 2019. But 2024, nobody wants that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's kind of where I land too. Neela, what do you think?
Speaker 6:  The constant ecosystem is just too fragmented.
Speaker 2:  That's what I think too. Would this thing have been a bigger hit if Apple
Speaker 2:  had made it Is is the next question. No,
Speaker 5:  'cause they did and it wasn't a hit. No. But
Speaker 2:  If Apple, apple had made this thing, I don't mean Apple had made its own
Speaker 2:  version of
Speaker 6:  Had like a marketed this thing. Take
Speaker 2:  The Roku player and put Apple's name in front of it. Would it have been a
Speaker 2:  bigger hit?
Speaker 5:  Yes,
Speaker 2:  I think so too. This is 2008. Apple is coming off the iPhone. Things are
Speaker 2:  starting to happen. I think this thing would've been bigger.
Speaker 6:  Wait, how do like this specific device, no way.
Speaker 6:  No P like Apple would've
Speaker 2:  The Apple Netflix player would've been a hit. I absolutely think so.
Speaker 6:  The Steve Jobs Apple does not release this device as evidenced by the
Speaker 6:  fact that they did not.
Speaker 2:  In this world that I'm creating the Steve Jobs, apple releases this device.
Speaker 6:  Walt has told this story many times. O on this show, Walt Mossberg where
Speaker 6:  he was talking to Steve and Steve desperately wanted to build a
Speaker 6:  proper cable box and he went to the cable companies and said
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna build an actual cable box that it runs our software. It looks great,
Speaker 6:  the whole thing. And the cable company said here's our garbage middleware
Speaker 6:  software to authenticate to our cable network. So you have to put a cable
Speaker 6:  card in your box. And Steve Jobs said no. Like absolutely not. Like
Speaker 6:  I'm leaving this category behind and everyone will just hear my literal dying
Speaker 6:  words. I finally cracked it haunting them for a generation
Speaker 6:  because TVs are garbage now and it was just 'cause he didn't want to use
Speaker 6:  can s video port man.
Speaker 6:  No way.
Speaker 2:  Okay, fair enough.
Speaker 6:  And to be clear, they got all the way to the future of TV's apps with the
Speaker 6:  Apple TV and they have since walked that back by launching Apple
Speaker 6:  TV plus and doing the exact thing Netflix had to do, which was making their
Speaker 6:  own content to drive their own services.
Speaker 2:  Yep. A hundred percent agree. I also think it would've been a bigger hit
Speaker 2:  if Apple made it. So almost Crans. And last question
Speaker 2:  before we go, does, does the Roku Netflix player belong in the version
Speaker 2:  History Hall of Fame?
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent.
Speaker 6:  No.
Speaker 2:  Kranz I want, I wanna hear you first. Why?
Speaker 5:  Because I think what, what we've said here, this was, this was where the
Speaker 5:  streaming box came from, right? This is where streaming kind of
Speaker 5:  like started to take off. This was that first big moment. I would argue that
Speaker 5:  the next Roku was the actual moment.
Speaker 6:  See that's the one I'd put in the Hall
Speaker 5:  Of Fame. That's the one you'd put in the Hall of Fame. I just think this
Speaker 5:  one is so important because we wouldn't have that next Roku without it. It's
Speaker 5:  tricky. It's tricky.
Speaker 2:  Neli is your argument. It's not this one. It's the next one. Yeah, it's
Speaker 6:  The first one that that people started buying, right?
Speaker 2:  I mean that's that's real. This one was not a huge hit
Speaker 6:  It. It was like the opposite. It was like a, I don't know, it was like a
Speaker 6:  sketch. It was like they sold a prototype and they realized they had a good
Speaker 6:  idea and then they finished the idea and that's the one that like actually
Speaker 6:  changed the industry 'cause it moved the way consumer demand was going.
Speaker 2:  Okay. All right, well we will, we will rehab this debate when we do that
Speaker 2:  one because that'll be a fun episode too. But for now I think it stays out
Speaker 2:  of the Hall of Fame. Okay. Also because this is the first time we've ever
Speaker 2:  done it. If we put the first thing in the hall of Fame, it just feels like
Speaker 2:  we're on a bad path. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And it just, everything's entering the Hall of Fame. Yeah, it's
Speaker 2:  No good.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's like are you gonna put Windows Media Center in the hall? No.
Speaker 6:  No.
Speaker 2:  Probably not. No. But Microsoft Silver Light. Yes.
Speaker 6:  By the way, Microsoft took the deal from the cable companies and shipped
Speaker 6:  Windows PCs with cable card slots in them. Yep. Nightmare. An
Speaker 6:  actual, I think the headline in Eng Gadget was Nightmare
Speaker 2:  Feels right. All right, thank you both for going on this
Speaker 2:  I would say one of the things we feel more aggressively
Speaker 2:  contested about right now, which is the software in your
Speaker 2:  car. This is the is CarPlay of the future or is it a
Speaker 2:  nightmare debate? Here we go.
Speaker 7:  Good day. I'm Liam James moderator for today's debate and my job is to
Speaker 7:  facilitate a debate between today's hosts on the topic of
Speaker 7:  automotive infotainment systems like CarPlay and Android Auto. Today we have
Speaker 7:  editor in Chief Neli Patel. Welcome Eli. Hello
Speaker 7:  and editor at large, David Pierce. David, welcome to the debate.
Speaker 2:  Thank you.
Speaker 7:  Alright, before we get started, I'd like to share the rules with our audience.
Speaker 7:  So each person will make their case for The Verge cast audience. A virtual
Speaker 7:  coin toss will determine my
Speaker 6:  Opponent is a communist.
Speaker 7:  A virtual coin toss will determine who goes first. We'll have opening
Speaker 7:  statements and following that, each host will be given two minutes to answer
Speaker 7:  my questions with up to an optional one minute rebuttal from the opposing
Speaker 7:  host. The questions were not shared in advance with either person. Our
Speaker 7:  hosts may use the internet to confirm factual details, but they use their
Speaker 7:  limited time while doing so. Okay, and with that, let's get to our topic
Speaker 7:  for today. All the way back in June, 2013, if You can remember that
Speaker 7:  far back, apple introduced CarPlay. Actually they called it iOS in the
Speaker 7:  car, if I remember correctly. Originally it was a standard that
Speaker 7:  enabled in dash head units in cars to display and control
Speaker 7:  a more modern smartphone like interface. Not long after Andrew introduced
Speaker 7:  their own standard with similar capabilities, but a lot has changed since
Speaker 7:  then. In mid 2024 we asked the question,
Speaker 7:  what is better for consumers? Is it CarPlay, Android Auto and similar
Speaker 7:  systems or should the automakers take back control and do this all
Speaker 7:  themselves? Alright, we are gonna start
Speaker 7:  off by doing a quick virtual coin toss. Technically you're the
Speaker 7:  visiting team, Eli, so you get to pick heads or tails.
Speaker 6:  Tails never fails.
Speaker 7:  All right.
Speaker 7:  and it is tails. So Eli would, would you like to go first or would
Speaker 7:  you like to go last with your closing
Speaker 7:  statements?
Speaker 6:  I'd like to go last.
Speaker 7:  You'd like to go last and
Speaker 2:  It's a real defer to the second half move. It's a good, it's the right call.
Speaker 2:  It's the right call. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Defense wins championships David.
Speaker 7:  Okay great. It will be no surprise to our audience that Eli will be arguing
Speaker 7:  today for the car makers and David will be arguing for
Speaker 7:  CarPlay and Android Auto. Alright, let's get started with opening
Speaker 7:  statements. David, you're up first. You have up to two minutes.
Speaker 2:  My argument is very simple, which is that it's not that you
Speaker 2:  couldn't have very good software built by car makers.
Speaker 2:  It's that you won't, it's that it doesn't exist. It has never existed and
Speaker 2:  it will never exist. By bringing your phone into the car,
Speaker 2:  what you get is an interface. You understand, you get the apps you already
Speaker 2:  have, you get the data that already exists on your device. You
Speaker 2:  don't have to rely on a bunch of car companies who have made decades worth
Speaker 2:  of awful software and now are trying to charge you more subscriptions. They're
Speaker 2:  trying to sell your data, they're trying to own more of the experience largely
Speaker 2:  based on software stacks that some company including those car companies,
Speaker 2:  is not going to keep caring about. I am in control when I use
Speaker 2:  CarPlay, I get to plug the thing in or pair it over Bluetooth, it
Speaker 2:  just works. It is my music app, it's my podcast app. I can use whatever I
Speaker 2:  want for navigation. Not whether somebody signed a deal with Waze
Speaker 2:  or here or whoever. It's my phone and the car
Speaker 2:  should do car things. The car should keep me alive and get me where I'm going
Speaker 2:  and everything else should be somebody else's problem. And there is precisely
Speaker 2:  zero evidence to show that car makers can build good software,
Speaker 2:  including the car makers. Everybody says build good software, do not build
Speaker 2:  good software, they build good car software. So my thing is, let's let software
Speaker 2:  companies be software companies and let car companies be car companies and
Speaker 2:  everybody can win and it's just that simple.
Speaker 7:  And Neli Patel, your opening statement,
Speaker 6:  My fellow Americans, I come before you with two arguments. Well three,
Speaker 6:  first David is a communist. That's important and we should not agree to his
Speaker 6:  radical communist agenda. Second, no matter what
Speaker 6:  I why if as long as I've made that point clear, I think that's important.
Speaker 6:  Two, I'm not arguing that car makers are good, I'm arguing
Speaker 6:  that CarPlay in particular is bad. CarPlay has not meaningfully
Speaker 6:  changed in a decade. You can't do something as simple as
Speaker 6:  look at a list of songs while looking at the map in CarPlay. You
Speaker 6:  just can't do it. The idea that Apple will somehow get good at
Speaker 6:  showing you two applications at once on an iOS device is a pipe dream that
Speaker 6:  we've seen fail over and over again with the iPad for a decade now
Speaker 6:  they're just not gonna do it. Your opportunity for CarPlay is limited
Speaker 6:  and that's fine if like communist David here. You think
Speaker 6:  the state should limit you to one application at a time in your car. My
Speaker 6:  second point is that cars are getting ever more complicated and the idea
Speaker 6:  is that cars are not a software experience. It is silly.
Speaker 6:  I'm not saying they're good at the software now. Even your Teslas, your rivian,
Speaker 6:  I've, I've been test driving Rivian for three days now. It's not great.
Speaker 6:  I'm not pretending it's great, but things like charging your ev,
Speaker 6:  managing your range, knowing where all the nearby chargers are
Speaker 6:  combined with autonomous driving, setting a destination on the map and letting
Speaker 6:  the car help you get there. All stuff the car is gonna do more
Speaker 6:  and more of. And if you're an Apple fan, you know that integrated
Speaker 6:  solutions are better than the weird Bluetooth fragmentation that
Speaker 6:  David and his Comey brethren would foist upon you be a
Speaker 6:  true American. Let GM put Android in your car. Vote
Speaker 6:  Patel.
Speaker 7:  That was fantastic. Okay, with those opening statements,
Speaker 7:  we'll move on to our first question, which is gonna be for David Pierce.
Speaker 2:  Hello
Speaker 7:  David. Driving compete considered one of the more dangerous
Speaker 7:  activities we complete in our daily lives. Many people
Speaker 7:  consider the CarPlay and Android auto interfaces to be
Speaker 7:  less tactile and more specifically the removal of
Speaker 7:  buttons inside of modern cars has caused a lot
Speaker 7:  of consternation on the side of older
Speaker 7:  drivers. What do you say to the people that want
Speaker 7:  all the important safety interfaces, things
Speaker 7:  like windshield wipers, climate control for
Speaker 7:  fogged up windows, things that you need to be able to
Speaker 7:  quickly turn on and off in the car being relegated to
Speaker 7:  touchscreen interfaces?
Speaker 2:  I have two points to make and and Liam, thank you for asking that. Very good
Speaker 2:  question.
Speaker 6:  Point
Speaker 2:  Number one, this is, this is a bad trend. You
Speaker 7:  Always know the person's not sure what they're gonna say yet when they compliment
Speaker 7:  the moderator's question. I'm
Speaker 2:  Sorry, I'm reclaiming my time from the moderator. This, this
Speaker 2:  trend is wrong. I, I am pro buttons, we are pro buttons here on The.
Speaker 2:  Vergecast buttons are good. We should have more dedicated controls for
Speaker 2:  doing things. That is not the trend that we are on. And neither Apple
Speaker 2:  nor Google caused that trend. This this trend towards touch
Speaker 2:  interfaces for everything in cars is I believe a bad idea. But
Speaker 2:  it is the one that we are on. And so what I'm arguing is that rather than
Speaker 2:  present you with a giant set of brand new controls, every time
Speaker 2:  you get into a vehicle or onto a scooter or
Speaker 2:  anything, that you should have a system that you understand and that I am
Speaker 2:  now bringing this thing with me instead of basically just being tossed
Speaker 2:  into the deep end of somebody's bad software design every single time
Speaker 2:  I sit down in front of the steering wheel, would I like to completely change
Speaker 2:  the car industry such that none of this was important and that there was
Speaker 2:  a button that I could just roll the windows down with and I didn't have to
Speaker 2:  guess how to open the handles to get in the freaking car? Yes, of course,
Speaker 2:  but that is not where we are. And so what matters more than ever actually
Speaker 2:  is consistency and having some cross car
Speaker 2:  understanding of where things are and how they work. And there is no better
Speaker 2:  system for that than CarPlay and Android Auto.
Speaker 7:  Wow, that was exactly two minutes Neli. Would you like to rebut that
Speaker 6:  Spoken like a true communist?
Speaker 2:  Is there a penalty for ad ho and of attacks on
Speaker 6:  This? David would have you turn away from the freedom
Speaker 6:  and innovation and liberty of the market to put
Speaker 6:  insane door handles on vehicles and instead have
Speaker 6:  Tim Cook impose a draconian system
Speaker 6:  of weird sliders and that gray scale that they do that
Speaker 6:  doesn't look good even on an OLED display. You know what I'm talking about?
Speaker 6:  It's just not good. It just doesn't look good. As Americans, we should have
Speaker 6:  the freedom to have cars that look cool and operate the windshield wipers
Speaker 6:  in evermore esoteric ways. Automatic. You say nay, I
Speaker 6:  will push whatever button I choose to push.
Speaker 2:  Am I a car socialist? I think I might be a car socialist. I never thought
Speaker 2:  about this. David
Speaker 6:  Hates liberty. He wants everyone to drive one of those weird Russian cars
Speaker 6:  with a bubble windshields and all the controls are exactly the same and you
Speaker 6:  know how to use them because you've been given a car by dictator
Speaker 6:  Pierce over here. I'm saying gentlemen, gentlemen, what's more American?
Speaker 6:  Let's, let's keep the red to the open road with a variety of buttons and
Speaker 6:  knobs.
Speaker 7:  Let's keep the rhetoric down gentlemen, moving on to our next
Speaker 7:  question. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Let's just move the gas pedal. Who even cares? Do whatever you want. It doesn't
Speaker 2:  even matter. Cars are fine. What's the worst that could happen?
Speaker 6:  That's free market baby.
Speaker 7:  Next question is for you Eli. Eli, you mentioned in your opening statement
Speaker 7:  the problem of having many more capabilities
Speaker 7:  and cars and the inability to show
Speaker 7:  those in ways that allows for multitasking or multi window
Speaker 7:  interfaces to make this both easier and safer to use.
Speaker 7:  What makes you think automakers are the right people to fix that problem?
Speaker 6:  Again, let me be clear. I'm arguing mostly that CarPlay is bad. I
Speaker 6:  don't think that car makers are the best people to solve this problem.
Speaker 6:  In fact, I think they might be some of the worst. But no one will
Speaker 6:  try to solve the problem if we just give everything to one company.
Speaker 6:  If we just hand over our interfaces to one company with no incentive to do
Speaker 6:  anything other than to get you to buy another iPhone or to sign up for one
Speaker 6:  of their their various services. You wanna buy a new car that comes with
Speaker 6:  three months of free Apple TV plus be, be my guest, let let It
Speaker 6:  Ride. I'm just saying you will never get new ideas in this market
Speaker 6:  if you give up. And David would have us give up to live in his
Speaker 6:  top down government controlled
Speaker 2:  Emphasis on live as in remain alive.
Speaker 6:  I'm just saying what we're gonna be in a, we're we're headed towards a future
Speaker 6:  where I believe people would like to both look at the
Speaker 6:  map and pick the next song without having to literally switch
Speaker 6:  apps because the car will be doing more of the work itself.
Speaker 6:  I don't see a pathway from the CarPlay we have today to that future
Speaker 6:  and I see no indication that Apple's interested in that. I also see a future
Speaker 6:  in which there are more screens in the cars, there are more screens in the
Speaker 6:  car where passengers are doing more things on the screens in the car and
Speaker 6:  having that all tied to one phone seems a little bonkers.
Speaker 6:  I think you want your car to be as integrated and as functional as
Speaker 6:  your smartphone. And I think it's on car makers to get there. I'm not
Speaker 6:  saying I'm gonna get there now, but I'm saying I I don't wanna live in David's
Speaker 6:  weird dystopian nightmare future.
Speaker 2:  The weird dystopian nightmare future you're describing is one in which you
Speaker 2:  know how to use your car. Is that, is that what we're talking about here?
Speaker 2:  I I am pro competition. I believe in the idea that
Speaker 2:  we can have lots of different options here. I don't think a world in which
Speaker 2:  CarPlay is the only interface that exists is the, the
Speaker 2:  ideal outcome. I'm just saying it's better than a
Speaker 2:  world in which I am getting into a car and just
Speaker 2:  banking on GM to have finally for the first time in its
Speaker 2:  history, built good software. I would point you to gm, a company that very
Speaker 2:  famously broke up with Android Auto and CarPlay has had
Speaker 2:  disastrous consequences, had to stop selling the first car on
Speaker 2:  which it made its own software because its software was so bad. This
Speaker 2:  is what we're up against. I'm not arguing CarPlay is the solution to all
Speaker 2:  of our problems. I'm just arguing it's better than that.
Speaker 6:  Realtime fact checks, sir
Speaker 7:  Neli is not your turn. Realtime fact. You'll have a chance to respond with
Speaker 7:  your next question.
Speaker 2:  No. Yeah, listen, NELI, the move is just talk over the moderator. We've,
Speaker 2:  we've been through this before. Come on.
Speaker 6:  I feel like all of us have learned some very bad lessons along the way here.
Speaker 2:  Please, I welcome your realtime fact checks sir. Alright.
Speaker 6:  Again, no one's saying that GM is good at software. It wasn't the move away
Speaker 6:  from Android Auto that caused the blazer to get recalled and and have the
Speaker 6:  stop sell. That was their bad battery software. It's
Speaker 2:  GM's general software in aptitude.
Speaker 6:  I'm just, it's different software. The the Escalades are moving, people are
Speaker 6:  buying Escalades, people are buying the cars that don't have the stuff, but
Speaker 6:  what they're enjoying about it is they get in the car and it already has
Speaker 6:  a Spotify app and it already has Google Maps, which are the only things people
Speaker 6:  want
Speaker 2:  And are completely duplicative of the apps that they already have on their
Speaker 2:  phone.
Speaker 7:  Gentlemen, we need to move on. The next question is for you David Pierce.
Speaker 7:  Long before options like CarPlay and Android Auto came
Speaker 7:  out, we had problems with cell phones, in cars, text messaging,
Speaker 7:  distracting people, people talking on the phone, lots of things
Speaker 7:  went in place to try to regulate that hands-free options and stuff like this.
Speaker 7:  Are you really saying that people should have apps in their cars? Should
Speaker 7:  they be playing with Spotify and Apple Music and all of these
Speaker 7:  interfaces when they're driving a car?
Speaker 2:  I would encourage you to spend one minute watching people drive
Speaker 2:  their cars. Everyone is looking at their phone all of the time.
Speaker 2:  And again, would it be great if some of the systems that these companies
Speaker 2:  had tried to implement had worked? If there, if the things like the driving
Speaker 2:  modes and the auto text response that says driving call you back later. Have
Speaker 2:  you ever gotten one of those texts? No one's ever gotten one of those texts.
Speaker 2:  Those aren't a thing. The good news is because
Speaker 2:  as my ridiculous opponent said in the first correct thing he said this
Speaker 2:  entire time people do just want a couple of apps. Maybe it's
Speaker 2:  Google Maps and Spotify, maybe it's Apple Maps and Apple Music. What
Speaker 2:  I gain by bringing my own device is I get to use the apps that I
Speaker 2:  want. I'm not forced into someone else's lockdown system
Speaker 2:  that will inevitably be an old version of Android running old apps and not
Speaker 2:  running very many apps. I get to have the stuff that I want.
Speaker 2:  So the best case that I have for safety is to push that stuff
Speaker 2:  to the large display in front of me instead of requiring me to constantly
Speaker 2:  look down at my phone. So actually every single app that I'm adding to one
Speaker 2:  of these two app stores through which I can actually get the things that
Speaker 2:  I care about is an improvement. It's not going to solve everything because
Speaker 2:  everybody is still going to look at their phone, but it's better
Speaker 6:  My friend. How popular is CarPlay?
Speaker 2:  Extremely popular.
Speaker 6:  Every everyone has it, right? It's everywhere. Yeah. Do you know why people
Speaker 6:  are still looking at their phones in their cars? 'cause CarPlay sucks.
Speaker 6:  That's why 'cause you can't do the things that the people wanna do. So they
Speaker 6:  pick up their phones anyway, making driving. According to
Speaker 6:  the latest statistics I've seen 5000% more dangerous
Speaker 2:  Based on the numbers. That's
Speaker 6:  The America David Pierce wants you to live, right? You can look at my
Speaker 6:  website, Neil Patel for CarPlay president.com and please donate.
Speaker 6:  All I'm saying is if CarPlay was good, you would not see people
Speaker 6:  constantly using their phones in their cars. And
Speaker 2:  If car makers could make good software, people wouldn't be using CarPlay.
Speaker 6:  No. 'cause you're plugging in your phone or worse, you're on wireless
Speaker 6:  CarPlay, which has brought down the rate of new car satisfaction
Speaker 6:  because it's so flaky Over the past three years, you've taken
Speaker 6:  a big real estate of the big screen and you've turned it into a single
Speaker 6:  unit tasking, limited application model. And then people use their phones
Speaker 6:  anyway. Why not allow that screen to do
Speaker 6:  multiple things at once?
Speaker 7:  Neli, what makes you think car makers can do this at all?
Speaker 6:  Two, two things. One, they're trying, which is interesting.
Speaker 6:  You don't see a lot of trying in technology these days. And second, there
Speaker 6:  are some results that show that how we build and design cars is changing.
Speaker 6:  So Tesla's way ahead here, they've reduced the number of computers in their
Speaker 6:  cars over the years to almost nothing at this point.
Speaker 6:  And that's Tesla. Great. They've also reduced the number of curved surfaces
Speaker 6:  on their trucks to zero. And then you look at Rivian, which just updated
Speaker 6:  the R one platform to something they're calling the zonal architecture. They're
Speaker 6:  combining the multiple sensor arrays and
Speaker 6:  microprocessors and controllers and sys and and integrated
Speaker 6:  systems on their cars into big computers in zones
Speaker 6:  of the car that control various functions. That's a big deal. That's literally
Speaker 6:  a rethink of how cars are designed, how they operate, all
Speaker 6:  the functions of a car, all the bits and bobs or rivian that can be controlled
Speaker 6:  not only from the touchscreen but remotely requires the car to have a
Speaker 6:  computing architecture that can do all this stuff. Then You can put an interface
Speaker 6:  on top of that. Maybe that interface is CarPlay, but you need to do that
Speaker 6:  work. The hardcore computer design integration work
Speaker 6:  across the car to even have the opportunity to do something
Speaker 6:  like introduce cool new features over
Speaker 6:  with over the air updates. You just have to design the car differently. All
Speaker 6:  the car makers wanna do this so they have the desire and then there's competition
Speaker 6:  in the market that's pushing them to deliver And. if you just give up the
Speaker 6:  screen to Apple and say, look, this car is here to get you from point A to
Speaker 6:  point B, I believe the world will turn gray. Much
Speaker 6:  like the Soviet Union. Have you ever seen the hunt for red October? It's
Speaker 6:  one of
Speaker 7:  My favorite movies.
Speaker 2:  If they had CarPlay and submarines, it would've solved a lot of problems.
Speaker 2:  I'm just saying,
Speaker 7:  David, do you wanna respond to that?
Speaker 2:  I do wanna respond. My response is that I agree that
Speaker 2:  car companies should be in charge of making their cars work. That's
Speaker 2:  not what we're debating here. That's not a complicated question and to the
Speaker 2:  extent that making a car work is increasingly a job of building and
Speaker 2:  maintaining computers, sure learn how to do that. But
Speaker 2:  it is just simply true that these companies have no track record
Speaker 2:  and very little ability to build good, usable
Speaker 2:  software for humans. Most of the time, most of what's happening in a
Speaker 2:  car is abstracted away from the person who is using it and
Speaker 2:  that's good. Most of it should not be your job to figure out
Speaker 2:  all the time. If you had to pick which brake you applied every time you applied
Speaker 2:  the brakes, bad things would happen. It's good that that's attracted away
Speaker 2:  from you. The stuff that is not is the stuff that is in front of you. It's
Speaker 2:  the navigation, it's the music, it's it's basic controls over the systems
Speaker 2:  inside of your car. That stuff should be separate and you, the
Speaker 2:  user, the driver, the passenger, whoever you are in the car, should be able
Speaker 2:  to control what that is and you should be able to bring it with you in a
Speaker 2:  way that is consistent and is personalized. And is yours. Let the car companies
Speaker 2:  be car companies.
Speaker 7:  Okay. Go into closing statements. David, you're first.
Speaker 2:  Okay, let me describe to you some things that I don't want.
Speaker 2:  I don't want a car that I get in and cannot
Speaker 2:  make any sense of. no matter what. I don't want a car that doesn't have my
Speaker 2:  apps. I don't want a car that has my apps but doesn't know anything
Speaker 2:  about me like where I live or where my office
Speaker 2:  is or any of the places that I like to go. I think of
Speaker 2:  car companies and tech companies as like sports owners. Like they're very
Speaker 2:  good at business, they make a lot of money and then they go buy a sports
Speaker 2:  team and they think because they knew how to run like a mortgage company,
Speaker 2:  they know how to run a sports team and they'll just do it the same way. Different
Speaker 2:  things let different things be different things, and letting
Speaker 2:  someone build good infotainment software that humans are supposed to use
Speaker 2:  is so radically different from what it takes to make a car work
Speaker 2:  very well. I don't think the Apple car was a good idea. I kind of
Speaker 2:  think Waymo is weird and way out over at skis and doing some
Speaker 2:  crazy stuff like let let the tech companies do the tech things, let the car
Speaker 2:  companies do the car things. I'm not interested in updating my
Speaker 2:  car's software every time a new Spotify feature appears.
Speaker 2:  I am not interested in having to upgrade my car just because Google
Speaker 2:  forgets about its Android automotive nonsense. In two years,
Speaker 2:  I want to be able to bring my technology to my car and I
Speaker 2:  want my car to keep me alive. Those are two different jobs and I'm
Speaker 2:  okay with them being different jobs. And Mr. Patel,
Speaker 6:  My friend David Pierce, makes a impassioned
Speaker 6:  case, but my friends, he's wrong because if you
Speaker 6:  listen to him, you would believe that CarPlay is any
Speaker 6:  good at all. It's not. It just isn't. Just look at it.
Speaker 6:  You don't have to believe me, you don't have to look at charts and
Speaker 6:  graphs or go to my website, vote for patel car software.com
Speaker 6:  and leave a $20 donation. 95% of Americans have donated $20 or
Speaker 6:  less. You don't have to do any of those things, but you should just look
Speaker 6:  at it. Who are you gonna believe? David Pierce his slick
Speaker 6:  tongue, his carpet bag.
Speaker 6:  It's not good. It hasn't substantively changed in a decade.
Speaker 6:  It's just the same list of things. I, like many
Speaker 6:  Americans, most Americans, all Americans believe that the greatest
Speaker 6:  joy in life is buying something expensive and then pushing all of the buttons
Speaker 6:  in Pierce's, communist America, it, there's no more, there's
Speaker 6:  none of that. You just get in the car and it's the same old dumb CarPlay
Speaker 6:  that you've had for the past 10 years with nothing new on the menu. I
Speaker 6:  don't wanna live in that America. I wanna live in America where
Speaker 6:  God forbid some software designer at Ford has decided to move
Speaker 6:  all the climate controls around and then you gotta figure it out and then
Speaker 6:  you figured it out and you've won one tiny shred of
Speaker 6:  victory in your life. Vote Patel.
Speaker 2:  I can see why you were a good lawyer. You just said nothing
Speaker 2:  and I'm like, yeah, 80% how you sound,
Speaker 6:  20% what you say.
Speaker 2:  That was good. I I feel it. You're dead wrong. And CarPlay is,
Speaker 2:  I'm not no one, no one thinks CarPlay is great. It's just that it's better.
Speaker 2:  And I'm, I I live in a world where better is enough.
Speaker 6:  Here, here I'll, I'll I've, again, I've spent several days with the Rivian.
Speaker 6:  The rivian maps are better. They're they're good, but the actual
Speaker 6:  zooming when you drive around with the maps is so
Speaker 3:  your fingertips. Expand your world with meta
Speaker 3:  ai.
Speaker 8:  these lists? Of course there's just the regular spam stuff that I get,
Speaker 8:  but it's completely taken over my messages app. I don't want to get a new
Speaker 8:  phone number. I like my phone number. A lot of stuff's tied to it. Is there
Speaker 8:  anything that I can do? I know getting on the do not call list doesn't help
Speaker 8:  with political campaigns. Help me out here. Thanks lovely,
Speaker 8:  Sean.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so at least for people in the United States, this is a huge and
Speaker 2:  widespread problem. I don't know how big a deal it is in other
Speaker 2:  countries. I've heard a lot about folks getting political spam on WhatsApp
Speaker 2:  and other places, but I just wanna talk about the US for right now because
Speaker 2:  this in a funny way, is actually maybe more complicated in the
Speaker 2:  United States than most places. And the unfortunate answer to the question
Speaker 2:  is there really isn't anything You can do, at least not
Speaker 2:  anything that is kind of guaranteed to work in a sweeping Broadway.
Speaker 2:  So there's one kind of text that is from
Speaker 2:  a legitimate business about legitimate business purposes, right? Those
Speaker 2:  are the ones sometimes that you'll sign up for when you
Speaker 2:  get a receipt from Square, right? You'll, you'll have signed up to get text
Speaker 2:  messages and usually what those things will have is they'll say Stop to unsubscribe
Speaker 2:  and typically you respond stop and it stops, right?
Speaker 2:  Like that. That is actually a thing that these companies are legally required
Speaker 2:  to do is stop. When you say stop and there are, there are
Speaker 2:  systems that some carriers have to block that stuff like that
Speaker 2:  actually works as a system when it is legitimate, when it's not
Speaker 2:  legitimate. The problem with replying stop to a mass
Speaker 2:  text message is actually what you've done is you've
Speaker 2:  confirmed to whatever spammer is sending that spam text
Speaker 2:  that your number is real and that someone is paying attention to it. And
Speaker 2:  what that essentially gives them is license to keep spamming you. There's
Speaker 2:  no technical reason that they have to stop if you say stop and
Speaker 2:  they won't. So this is the risk that you're taking, right? If you get a political
Speaker 2:  text, let's say from an actual campaign run by an actual
Speaker 2:  above board organization and you reply stop, you'll stop getting it. All
Speaker 2:  it does is stop that one thing. And frankly, the honest
Speaker 2:  truth is your phone number and my phone number have probably been sold
Speaker 2:  a million times to a million different organizations. So you're forever playing
Speaker 2:  this game of whack-a-Mole. There's no just like turn off the political text
Speaker 2:  button that You can press, but You can do it one by one And. if you reply
Speaker 2:  stop over and over and over again, the numbers will go down. That's been
Speaker 2:  my experience every time I get one that is obviously from a campaign
Speaker 2:  and usually You can Google the number by the way and it will tell you pretty
Speaker 2:  reliably if it is a real number from a real campaign, if it is and you reply
Speaker 2:  stop, it will go down again, Whack-a-Mole, but it'll work if you
Speaker 2:  get it wrong and you reply to something that looks like a political
Speaker 2:  text but is actually a spammer or a scammer of some kind,
Speaker 2:  which is a thing that they do, especially in moments like this, you've just
Speaker 2:  caused yourself extra problems. So really what you have to balance here
Speaker 2:  is, okay, do I wanna do the work verifying every one of these numbers in
Speaker 2:  order to go press the stop button, which just means
Speaker 2:  texting stop and make them go away? Or is it
Speaker 2:  less work to just frankly ignore the text messages? There are
Speaker 2:  also a couple of things You can do other than replying. One thing You can
Speaker 2:  do is delete it and report it to your carrier,
Speaker 2:  which in theory will tune their systems for detecting spam.
Speaker 2:  So that might make it better for everybody, but it also is, you know,
Speaker 2:  manual labor. Every time you get one of these from a new number, you swipe
Speaker 2:  and you hit delete and report junk and it goes to Verizon and whoever your
Speaker 2:  carrier is and that slowly makes things better, but
Speaker 2:  it will not immediately solve all their problems. There's also things like
Speaker 2:  robo Killer and other apps that try to intercept some of that stuff. I
Speaker 2:  found that they work ish, like there are a lot of things like that
Speaker 2:  that will make things slightly better, but there is no way to just go and
Speaker 2:  say, do not send me political texts. Unfortunately, by the time
Speaker 2:  you get one, that ship has probably sailed. Your number is in some
Speaker 2:  database. Everybody has access to that database. Those databases get sold
Speaker 2:  a million times over and you are forever resigned to getting a lot
Speaker 2:  of politics texts. One thing I've heard from a bunch of people is that
Speaker 2:  if you are getting a lot of these, using the
Speaker 2:  filters, especially on iOS, that will actually filter out
Speaker 2:  messages from unknown numbers can be really handy if you're getting like
Speaker 2:  an overwhelming number of these. You can go into settings, You can
Speaker 2:  filter unread messages and it'll just dump those into, it's kind of the
Speaker 2:  equivalent of like the other inbox on Facebook or one of
Speaker 2:  the other like LinkedIn kind of social apps that people you haven't
Speaker 2:  necessarily put into your contacts or declared that you care about get
Speaker 2:  foisted into that other one. I did that for a while and it turned, turned
Speaker 2:  out. I missed a lot of text messages from people who I actually cared about
Speaker 2:  but didn't have their number. Your mileage may vary, so like I said, there
Speaker 2:  are a lot of half measures here, but I think what I would recommend if you're
Speaker 2:  trying to get this down is Google the phone numbers of
Speaker 2:  ones you're getting a lot to make sure that they're legitimate and then
Speaker 2:  delete those text messages, reply, stop and report
Speaker 2:  whatever spam and junk You can to your carrier. That helps you and it helps
Speaker 2:  everybody, but be careful because all it takes is a
Speaker 2:  couple of incorrect responses and all of a sudden you've flagged
Speaker 2:  to whoever sent that message and to whoever owns the database of those numbers
Speaker 2:  and everything else, that you are legit and you are paying attention. And
Speaker 2:  when you do that to the wrong people it can be a problem. The politics
Speaker 2:  hacks are only gonna get worse. If you have a better idea about how to get
Speaker 2:  rid of them, please let me know. I am all ears because I am getting
Speaker 2:  just aggressively too many of them right now and I'm deeply tired of it too.
Speaker 2:  So good luck to all of you out there with your text messages. I hope that
Speaker 2:  helps a little. Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thanks to everybody
Speaker 2:  who came on the show. Thank you for listening. Again, we want to hear everything
Speaker 2:  you think about these pilots. We're trying new formats. It's been fun to
Speaker 2:  mess around and see like, are these things we wanna do on The Vergecast?
Speaker 2:  Every once in a while are these entirely new shows we should launch? Let
Speaker 2:  us know everything you're thinking. There's also lots more on all this stuff.
Speaker 2:  Our coverage of CarPlay and the automakers, our coverage of Roku and the
Speaker 2:  streaming wars. All this stuff is all over the verse.com. We'll put some
Speaker 2:  links in the show notes, especially to the stuff that we referenced in a
Speaker 2:  lot of these pilots. But just check out the website. It's good website. It's
Speaker 2:  a shockingly newsy summer, so keep it locked on The Verge dot com. And as
Speaker 2:  always, if you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or other streaming gadgets
Speaker 2:  that you think we should make shows about, email us at vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com or keep calling the hotline. 8 6 6 VERGE one one. we love
Speaker 2:  hearing from you. I'm on vacation. I'm gonna be back in two weeks. We're
Speaker 2:  gonna have lots more to do because again, it's a real newsy summer. This
Speaker 2:  show is produced by Andrew Marino, Liam James, and Will Poor Vergecast is
Speaker 2:  VERGE production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli and the
Speaker 2:  gang will be back on Friday to talk about, I don't even know I'm on vacation.
Speaker 2:  Whatever news there is because there just keeps being news. We'll see you
Speaker 2:  then. Rock and roll.