# Transcript
ID: a205bed8-e441-4530-9619-c7ef800f34e9
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4445795520101830791/4124168188850075081/s93290-US-6104s-1734432659.mp3
Description: The Verge's Victoria Song and Kylie Robison join the show to talk about all of Google's recent AI and XR announcements, and the company's big and Gemini-powered vision for the future of computing. Then Chris Grant, the group publisher for Polygon and The Verge, explains why GTA VI and the Nintendo Switch 2 are so important to the future of gaming — plus a few predictions about how they'll turn out. Finally, The Verge's Helen Havlak answers a hotline question about how she plans her garden in Figma. Which is a real thing she really does.
Speaker 1:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Vaporware. I'm your friend
Speaker 1:  David Pierce, and I am almost done Christmas shopping as
Speaker 1:  I'm recording this. It is December 16th Monday, which means it is
Speaker 1:  nine days until Christmas. And if I'm being honest with you, it's a record
Speaker 1:  for how far in advance I'm done holiday shopping. I don't recommend living
Speaker 1:  this way, but here we are also thank you to everyone who sent in
Speaker 1:  recommendations for like cheap stuff to buy for acquaintances
Speaker 1:  and Secret Santa gifts. A bunch of you recommended power banks, which I think
Speaker 1:  is an awesome idea. So I'm getting a lot of people like nifty little batteries
Speaker 1:  to carry around. Also, some people recommended lottery scratchers. Super
Speaker 1:  good idea. Candles was one that came up a bunch and I'm sort of
Speaker 1:  conflicted. Candles are awesome. I have them everywhere, but
Speaker 1:  is that like too intimate a gift to give to a semi
Speaker 1:  stranger or just a random person at work? I don't know, but I'm
Speaker 1:  gonna try it. We'll see how it goes. Anyway, lots coming up on the show.
Speaker 1:  Today we are gonna do two things. This is our last Tuesday episode of the
Speaker 1:  year where you take a little break around the holidays, but we have a really
Speaker 1:  fun episode coming up today. First we're gonna talk about the
Speaker 1:  Google stuff from last week. Google made some big announcements about
Speaker 1:  Gemini and AI and kind of showed off its
Speaker 1:  entire vision for the future of everything in a way that I thought was really
Speaker 1:  fascinating. So we're gonna talk about that with V Song and Kylie
Speaker 1:  Robinson. And then we're gonna talk about video games. So Ash Parrish came
Speaker 1:  on the show a few weeks ago and said the biggest story in games this year
Speaker 1:  is two things that haven't launched yet, and I think that's fascinating.
Speaker 1:  So I asked Chris Grant, who is our group publisher and was the
Speaker 1:  editor-in-chief of Polygon, to come on and talk about what that means
Speaker 1:  and where we're headed and why. The biggest story in video games is two things
Speaker 1:  that don't exist yet. All that is coming up in just a sec. But
Speaker 1:  first I have to tell you really quick before we take a break about our CES
Speaker 1:  show. So on Wednesday, January 8th, if you're gonna be in Vegas for
Speaker 1:  CES, we are doing a live Vergecast at five o'clock
Speaker 1:  at the Brooklyn Bowl, which is at the Link Hotel, which is the one with the
Speaker 1:  big Ferris wheel, like right in the middle of the strip in Vegas.
Speaker 1:  It's gonna be free to come. Super exciting. We're gonna do some fun
Speaker 1:  stuff. It's like a weird, huge concert venue that is slightly
Speaker 1:  intimidating, but I think it's gonna be very fun. You should come out, put
Speaker 1:  it on your calendar, it's free, it's gonna be super fun. We would love to
Speaker 1:  see as many of you as we can in Vegas Wednesday, January 8th. I'll put
Speaker 1:  the link to the thing in the show notes. By the way, it says you have to
Speaker 1:  be a Sky Miles member to get in. Don't worry about that. We'll figure
Speaker 1:  it out. I'm not worried. It's gonna be fine. Anyway, come to the Vegas show,
Speaker 1:  come see us at CES. Very excited to hang out with all of you. Lots to get
Speaker 1:  to today. So let's just get into it. All that is coming up, we have to take
Speaker 1:  a break. This is the first cast, we'll be right
Speaker 1:  Welcome back. Alright, it is mid-December and there is still
Speaker 1:  AI news happening, which If you wanna know anything about what 2024 has been
Speaker 1:  like, there it is. Let's just get into it. So last
Speaker 1:  week Google, over the course of a couple of days, made a couple of different
Speaker 1:  announcements. It announced Gemini 2.0, its new
Speaker 1:  flagship AI model that is gonna kind of underpin everything that
Speaker 1:  Google's doing. And then the next day it announced Android xr, which is
Speaker 1:  basically Google trying to do for headsets and smart glasses,
Speaker 1:  what it did for smartphones. Somebody is going to be the big
Speaker 1:  cross-platform operating system that all the hardware makers use to make
Speaker 1:  these headsets and smart glasses. Google would very much like that
Speaker 1:  to be Google. So Android xr, Gemini 2.0 somewhere
Speaker 1:  in the combination of those two things I think is the future
Speaker 1:  of Google, or at least is what Google thinks is the future of Google. So
Speaker 1:  I asked two of the people who covered both sides of this v song and Kylie
Speaker 1:  Robinson to come on the show and the three of us are gonna try to figure
Speaker 1:  out how to put this Venn diagram of news together into
Speaker 1:  what Google is up to and thinks might be the future. So let's just get
Speaker 1:  into it. Fi song. Hello? Hello. Kylie
Speaker 1:  Robinson. Hello.
Speaker 2:  Hello.
Speaker 1:  Okay, I have brought the two of you here together because you have
Speaker 1:  had a rarefied experience individually,
Speaker 1:  which is that you got a wacky Google demo and there are
Speaker 1:  very few things in life as a tech journalist more fun than a
Speaker 1:  wacky Google demo in which you get walked through a bunch of stuff that might
Speaker 1:  not be real, it might not ship, it might not even be the thing that you thought
Speaker 1:  it was, but someone made it and they're really excited to show it to you.
Speaker 1:  And I also think between the two of you, you got like kind of
Speaker 1:  Google's whole vision for the future of everything. And So I just wanna like
Speaker 1:  see if we can put all of these pieces together between us. But
Speaker 1:  first, for the people who don't get to do these demos, I just want you to
Speaker 1:  both like explain the days you had with Google a little bit. Let's just do
Speaker 1:  it chronologically. Kylie, you go first.
Speaker 4:  Sweet. Yeah, So I got to demo Project Astra and Project
Speaker 4:  Mariner. So they're both kind of agents.
Speaker 4:  I heard you say in the last VERGE cast that you think Project Astra is kind
Speaker 4:  of their whole vision for Gemini in the future.
Speaker 4:  So I I would agree with that. Yeah, they locked me in a library
Speaker 4:  hidden on campus and they showed me a bunch of art on
Speaker 4:  TVs and they asked Astra to talk about that and
Speaker 4:  yeah, it was really excited to talk.
Speaker 4:  It would interrupt the speaker sometimes. She had a really bebo who
Speaker 4:  she was really excited to show me and the AI was more excited to, to be shown.
Speaker 4:  But yeah, you know, I got some on Rails demos. Something I
Speaker 4:  didn't include in the story is they had this book, you know, about
Speaker 4:  France and then she flipped through the pages and asked it to remember
Speaker 4:  each page. And then she showed some wine that was
Speaker 4:  on the table and was like, okay, like for France's special
Speaker 4:  dish, you know, like their local dish, what wine should I pair with that?
Speaker 4:  The only reason I didn't include that is that I'm not a France expert and
Speaker 4:  I contacted Nathan Edwards on staff who said he was semi a
Speaker 4:  France expert and neither of us could deduce how helpful that was.
Speaker 4:  Fair enough. And then Project Mariner is just like a typical
Speaker 4:  agent, a Chrome extension that you know,
Speaker 4:  can go through your grocery list and buy stuff for you. It just takes over
Speaker 4:  your web browser. It was really slow, but both were really
Speaker 4:  interesting to see even as research prototypes, just kind of how they're
Speaker 4:  thinking about the technology. But as I mentioned in the article when you
Speaker 4:  just mentioned a second ago, like they're like, we don't know what this will
Speaker 4:  look like and if, if or when this will ever launch. And I'm like, cool. Awesome.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I, one thing I always wonder is like Google demos exist on
Speaker 1:  a spectrum between like, here's a thing a person built
Speaker 1:  that we thought was neat and figured we'd show you all the way up to like,
Speaker 1:  this is the product that will take us into the future. Sure.
Speaker 1:  Where on the spectrum do you feel like these demos were like, where
Speaker 1:  is this stuff within Google right now?
Speaker 4:  Astra is, this will take us into the future. Okay. And Mariner
Speaker 4:  is, there's, it's so new that I think it's not gonna be the future
Speaker 4:  product yet. So yeah, I I would say that's, that's we're both fall.
Speaker 1:  They just like found a thing that can open a new tab in Chrome and like got
Speaker 1:  really excited about it.
Speaker 4:  Right, exactly. That
Speaker 1:  Feels like as far as we've gotten. Yeah. Right. Okay. All right. V your turn.
Speaker 1:  Tell us, you, you got to play with hardware, which means you got Yes. The
Speaker 1:  even weirder experience of having a bunch of Google employees watch you
Speaker 1:  use a gadget, which is the literal worst thing. So tell
Speaker 1:  me a little bit about your demo Google
Speaker 5:  And Samsung employees. Hmm. So it was a, there were at times
Speaker 5:  where I had a whole crowd of people just staring at me and that was uncomfortable,
Speaker 5:  especially because, So I got to demo Android at XR
Speaker 5:  and you know, when you are in XR short for
Speaker 5:  extended reality, which encompasses augmented reality, virtual reality and
Speaker 5:  mixed reality, all these levels of reality,
Speaker 5:  you're basically in a headset. So you
Speaker 5:  can't see people necessarily depending on the demo, but
Speaker 5:  they're all just staring at you walk around a room, right? Just like,
Speaker 5:  ooh.
Speaker 1:  The worst version of this, by the way, is the Vision Pro demos where people
Speaker 1:  just sort of mysteriously appear in your vision and then slowly fade
Speaker 1:  away. And this
Speaker 5:  Was a little like that. Yeah. My god, this was a little like that. Oh no.
Speaker 5:  Because, yeah, So I got to try Android xr, which is the
Speaker 5:  broad platform, but they basically want this to be a single platform
Speaker 5:  for multiple devices, which meant I got to try Samsung's.
Speaker 5:  You're gonna love what this is called. Project Moan.
Speaker 5:  Headset. No thank you. And some Prototype
Speaker 5:  Smart glasses. So basically two different visions
Speaker 5:  for what XR is gonna look like. Project Moan,
Speaker 5:  moan being Infinity in Korean, I don't
Speaker 5:  know why they just didn't call it Project Infinity, but here you go, right.
Speaker 5:  Project Wuhan is basically a Samsung and Google
Speaker 5:  flavored version of the Vision Pro to the point where like everything I was
Speaker 5:  doing in it, I was like, ah, this eye calibration and
Speaker 5:  pinchy pinchy UI seems awfully
Speaker 5:  familiar in that it is exactly the same as as the pro.
Speaker 5:  And you know, they're showing me things like, oh you can tap this button
Speaker 5:  and go into an immersive environment to watch your movies. And
Speaker 5:  instead of saying on Apple TV, they said Google tv. And it was like
Speaker 5:  that level of like almost one-to-one for some of the things I saw,
Speaker 5:  which, you know, when we all saw the Vision Pro demos last year, we were
Speaker 5:  like, oh my God, wow, this is really impressive. So it's impressive that
Speaker 5:  they're able to do that and all of that whatnot. But yeah,
Speaker 5:  it was like Google Flavored Vision Pro that demo and then the Smart
Speaker 5:  Glasses was really cool because I, I felt like Tony
Speaker 5:  Stark, but like the whole thing behind all of that and what makes it kind
Speaker 5:  of AI related is that they're saying Gemini is the key to
Speaker 5:  unlocking XR forever, right? This is, this is the killer
Speaker 5:  app, Gemini is the killer app. And then, you know, I got
Speaker 5:  walked through a bunch of very impressive demos, frankly, but like on
Speaker 5:  guardrails. So they were all very sure that this was gonna work. And yet
Speaker 5:  at the same time, every single time I would say something and asked Gemini
Speaker 5:  something for the demo to work, they would just be like holding their breaths
Speaker 5:  and then when it did work they would just like breathe like audibly. Like
Speaker 5:  okay, okay, very cool. Very, very awesome, very cool. And like
Speaker 1:  They're like, we totally meant for that to happen. That was definitely really
Speaker 5:  Fun. We hope, thank God, thank God that, that, that worked. Because you know,
Speaker 5:  they would say something to me like, oh you know, you can switch between
Speaker 5:  different languages when you're talking to Gemini and it'll answer you in
Speaker 5:  the language that you asked it. And I was like, okay cool. Can
Speaker 5:  I try this out? And So I started speaking in Japanese and they were like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, it'll totally work. Oh my God, it works. Like that kind of,
Speaker 5:  that kind of energy that was happening in there.
Speaker 1:  So I feel like on the, on the spectrum of here's the thing somebody made,
Speaker 1:  do you wanna look at it too? This will lead us into the future. I feel like
Speaker 1:  all the Android XR stuff is like way down at the, this will lead us into
Speaker 1:  the future end, right? Like Google seems to really believe in this whole
Speaker 1:  project.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I don't know how far into the future like Project
Speaker 5:  Moan that. So they were very adamant that everything I was seeing was a
Speaker 5:  dev kit and that they were rolling everything out to devs so that
Speaker 5:  there would be a robust ecosystem of apps and experiences by
Speaker 5:  the time it hits consumers. You know, taking very vague pot shots
Speaker 5:  at how Apple just threw the Vision Pro at us without
Speaker 5:  a lot of apps to work with. Listen,
Speaker 1:  It had iPad apps and that didn't help anyone for any reason, but it
Speaker 1:  had them the, they were there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. So,
Speaker 5:  so you know, they were very like keen to be like, oh yeah, you know, you'll
Speaker 5:  be able to use all these Google Play apps out of the box when Project Wuhan
Speaker 5:  arrives in 2025. So that will be coming
Speaker 5:  next year ostensibly, whether they mean January or
Speaker 5:  December, probably closer to December is my guess. And then
Speaker 5:  the prototype glasses I saw were like super duper cool. All the
Speaker 5:  demos I saw on that. Totally. Like I'm a huge smart glasses
Speaker 5:  skeptic and I have been, If you look through the whole body of my work and
Speaker 5:  I felt myself like kind of believing, understanding that everything
Speaker 5:  was on guardrails of course. But then you know, you talk about like, okay,
Speaker 5:  so when are we gonna see these front glasses on people? And they're like,
Speaker 5:  well we're making the prototypes but we will be working with partners for
Speaker 5:  the hardware to actually come out. So like I know X reel is working with
Speaker 5:  them, but as to when we'll actually see that
Speaker 5:  ah, it's gonna be in the future
Speaker 5:  is is what it's gonna be.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. The future is a long time. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Kylie,
Speaker 1:  This thing about the killer app for AI being glasses, I think
Speaker 1:  it's really fascinating because it seems to work in both directions. Everybody
Speaker 1:  who is making glasses thinks that AI is going to be what makes the glasses
Speaker 1:  great and everybody making AI thinks that glasses are like
Speaker 1:  the natural interface for it in so many ways. Like
Speaker 1:  Google is completely bought into this idea, right? That like Gemini on your
Speaker 1:  face is going to be the best possible version of Gemini. Does everybody believe
Speaker 1:  this? Like are are smart glasses and and AI just going to smush together
Speaker 1:  across the whole industry?
Speaker 4:  No. Okay. Short answer, no.
Speaker 4:  I think it's been reported that Sam Altman's working with Johnny Ive on earbuds,
Speaker 4:  you know, so that's one way to go about it in terms of integrating AI into
Speaker 4:  the physical world and what we do with it. Glasses
Speaker 4:  is a really compelling use case. However, you have said on The Verge cast,
Speaker 4:  and I hear this all the time, that glasses are annoying and I hear people
Speaker 4:  saying, I want to like it, but I hate wearing them and I'm sympathetic,
Speaker 4:  however, I've always worn glasses, so I'm, my entire life I'm used to them
Speaker 1:  And you don't need them. They're just purely an affectation. You just Exactly.
Speaker 1:  You just wear them 'cause they look cool. Right?
Speaker 4:  Right. Do I look cool? Oh
Speaker 5:  My god,
Speaker 1:  I'm So, I didn't say you jealous
Speaker 5:  Right now because I'm wearing contacts
Speaker 5:  I have to have corrective vision so I'm jealous.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. V is well documented as, as more or less blind here on the first
Speaker 1:  cast.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no, I'm negative 2.5 negative 3.5. But that, I don't think that's blind
Speaker 4:  enough. I think my mom's negative six in both eyes, which is pretty blind
Speaker 5:  Negative nine, negative 8.75 with heavy
Speaker 4:  Damn
Speaker 5:  Heav astigmatism babies. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Love that. For the meta ray bands, you
Speaker 4:  I think negative six and above you, they can't help you like you're
Speaker 5:  Screwed. No, no. The honest to God they, when they sent me my prescription
Speaker 5:  ones, they're like, just so you know, we did this like out of house because
Speaker 5:  Ray van wouldn't do it. Yep. 'cause you're so blind. Yep.
Speaker 5:  I appreciated it. But it was also just like
Speaker 1:  You're breaking the curve V as always.
Speaker 4:  Love that. Yeah. Yeah. But so no, I think a lot of people
Speaker 4:  are not interested in it. I still think it should be built and I still think
Speaker 4:  it's really cool and I am happy to use them, but I don't think it'll be like
Speaker 4:  the killer version of this. I think they're gonna have to keep iterating
Speaker 4:  and hardware is hard. I'd be interested to see how earbuds, if that
Speaker 4:  ever drops, that's gonna be very interesting to see.
Speaker 5:  So like a really interesting conversation I had with Google and
Speaker 5:  Samsung while I was there is that they did not seem
Speaker 5:  to buy into this whole idea that it'll be one hardware device
Speaker 5:  that conquers everything, where that is the key. It was like they were
Speaker 5:  saying like, oh well, you know, VR headsets, those are gonna be episodic.
Speaker 5:  Those are things for like when you want immersive content, when you want
Speaker 5:  the 500 foot TV screen on the whatever smart
Speaker 5:  glasses are gonna be when you feel like you wanna be on the go and discrete.
Speaker 5:  But that may not be something that you do all the time. So I think the
Speaker 5:  way they're approaching it is an ecosystem of devices, which you know,
Speaker 5:  is great for spending money and trapping you into these
Speaker 5:  silos of gadget ecosystems. But I think to your point,
Speaker 4:  Consume,
Speaker 5:  Yes, to your point, I think not everyone's gonna want the glasses form factor,
Speaker 5:  but that form factor is gonna give some advantages that an
Speaker 5:  earbud can't. And that I think in the the future
Speaker 5:  they're pitching we'll all have incredible disposable
Speaker 5:  income to have 40,000 different gadgets for different use cases. Love it.
Speaker 5:  Right. So yeah.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean I think I I, I'm of two minds about the glasses thing. As
Speaker 1:  somebody who does not wear glasses. 'cause my vision is sick. Like, not to
Speaker 1:  brag, but like all right,
Speaker 5:  It's pretty okay, fine. Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 1:  I have like some of the best people are always saying I have like the best
Speaker 1:  vision. The people are saying people are, a lot of people are saying that,
Speaker 1:  but I think on the one hand the idea of like wearing
Speaker 1:  glasses I don't otherwise need for like
Speaker 1:  pure utility reasons I think is just never gonna happen. Yeah. I think there's
Speaker 1:  a world in which like they are a fashion item and people wear them
Speaker 1:  in part because they look cool even when you need them. Like correctively.
Speaker 1:  But then somebody pointed out to me recently, they were like, okay, when
Speaker 1:  you have sunglasses and you aren't wearing them, where do you put
Speaker 1:  them? And I was like, oh, well I put 'em in my like coat pocket or I put
Speaker 1:  'em on top of my head or I like fold 'em up and put 'em in my shirt. And
Speaker 1:  they were like, yeah, that's fine. That's like, that becomes a use case that
Speaker 1:  actually works. And it's, it's a thing you can both carry around and put
Speaker 1:  on in a bunch of ways. And actually that ends up being really useful. I had
Speaker 1:  this moment of being like, oh, maybe there's something to that, that actually
Speaker 1:  glasses are more able to be taken on and off than I
Speaker 1:  was giving them credit for. But then for the huge percentage of people who
Speaker 1:  need them correctively, that doesn't work at all because you're gonna have
Speaker 1:  to wear them day in and day out and Yeah. Like, I don't know. Did,
Speaker 1:  did either of you talk to Google about this idea of like, what happens
Speaker 1:  if we wear these things all day every day? Are you just going to shove ads
Speaker 1:  in my face? Is the future just giant ar billboards in
Speaker 1:  front of me all the time while I wear the glasses that I need to live my
Speaker 1:  life?
Speaker 5:  They're very adamant that that's like not what they're building towards.
Speaker 5:  And from what I saw in the prototypes that I saw, like that's gonna be very
Speaker 5:  hard to do. Okay. Because
Speaker 5:  you know, like the science fiction of it, like I, I talk like a lot in
Speaker 5:  past stuff that I've done just about how science fiction really forms
Speaker 5:  our perception of what these things will look like. Right. So
Speaker 5:  Tony Stark is the example that gets pulled out all the time. Yep. And with
Speaker 5:  Tony Stark in his smart glasses, like in that, or the ones that he
Speaker 5:  gives to Peter Parker in one of those Marvel movies, which
Speaker 5:  his name is escaping me right now. Like the, the display moves
Speaker 5:  around, right. It's like a dynamic display. The whole lens is a
Speaker 5:  display and that's just like not where we are. So they were very excited
Speaker 5:  to show me these prototypes and they're like, oh, this one prototype you're
Speaker 5:  gonna see, it's a monocular display, which means it's off to the side.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's only in one area off to the side. Okay. And then they were like,
Speaker 5:  but oh, try this prototype and it's binocular. What
Speaker 5:  do you notice about that? And so that's like a display in both of the lenses
Speaker 5:  and it's a little more centrally located, but because of how small the
Speaker 5:  display is, like you're not really seeing billboards everywhere.
Speaker 5:  You're seeing like
Speaker 5:  one area and it's changing based on your use case.
Speaker 5:  So like a notification pops up. It's not like you're seeing like
Speaker 5:  everything overlaid in a minority report type way. It's like one
Speaker 5:  notification in one area and you can see it and it's small. Or
Speaker 5:  like one of the really cool things I saw was turn by turn directions for
Speaker 5:  Google Maps and you're like, oh, you see a little bubble and it tells you
Speaker 5:  the direction and If you look down then it becomes a zoomable map. Like
Speaker 5:  you have to look down though to see it.
Speaker 5:  And I was like, interesting. And that was because they actually don't want
Speaker 5:  you to have ar directions that are so distracting when you're walking
Speaker 5:  around that you can't be aware of your surroundings. 'cause that's a safety,
Speaker 5:  right. A public safety issue. So it's a dystopian
Speaker 5:  nightmare to think about. I think about that short film, I forget the name
Speaker 5:  of it that came out a long time ago. Yeah. Where the person was on a
Speaker 5:  bus and it was just like ads everywhere and like, oh my God, just wanna
Speaker 5:  die seeing that. But I think in reality
Speaker 5:  no one would enjoy that. And then I say this about wearables all the
Speaker 5:  time, you have to want to wear them. That's the only way
Speaker 5:  that technology works. So if no one wants to wear these because the experience
Speaker 5:  is so bad full of those ads, that's just, you know, I think they're,
Speaker 5:  I asked them, they were aware of it and they tried to very much be like,
Speaker 5:  no, no, no, no, we're not gonna do that.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So it's an easy thing to say I think. Very easy.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But it is at least, it at least, at least something I'm hap I would rather
Speaker 1:  them say that than the other thing. Right. Which is like, this is such a
Speaker 1:  sick place to put ads. Like, all right, cool. Kylie, what
Speaker 1:  did you, what sense did you get? 'cause I think one of the things Google
Speaker 1:  is pretty clearly pushing towards with something like Mariners, like making
Speaker 1:  it really easy to shop for things. Yeah. Which is one heck of a way to make
Speaker 1:  money and Astra is, is super visual and is a way to
Speaker 1:  like see the world through your phone and glasses and there's all kinds of
Speaker 1:  stuff you could do there. Do you get a sense of like
Speaker 1:  Google trying to sort of sneakily find ways to turn this stuff
Speaker 1:  into money here? Of course. Or am I just being cynical?
Speaker 4:  No, of course. I once again was listening to The Vergecast that just came
Speaker 4:  out and you had mentioned that like agents are a way for them to
Speaker 4:  like, please we need money. Like we need an application for these really
Speaker 4:  expensive models. And this seems to be one of those applications. And I wrote
Speaker 4:  about that a couple months ago, that AI agents are what everyone's creating.
Speaker 4:  It's what they desperately need. 'cause they need to charge money for something
Speaker 4:  that is useful and they just haven't been able to figure out those
Speaker 4:  applications yet. And this is something I've been thinking about largely
Speaker 4:  for 2025, is that it's going to look like to me,
Speaker 4:  everyone trying to find those applications for these frontier models. Whether
Speaker 4:  that's internally or people tinkering with the models and building their
Speaker 4:  own wrappers. You know, I think agents, honestly,
Speaker 4:  like when I was doing those demos, I did get a sense of like,
Speaker 4:  oof, this is coming really fast. Like I, I felt,
Speaker 4:  you know, my brain kind of spinning a little bit because, and this is something
Speaker 4:  I was telling them too, is that OpenAI loves to say, we don't wanna shock
Speaker 4:  everybody and drop everything too soon before they're ready. And you're like,
Speaker 4:  yeah, right man, okay, whatever.
Speaker 1:  That's actually your favorite thing to do. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Exactly. So like, we don't wanna like, you know, freak people out 'cause
Speaker 4:  it's so powerful. However, when I was doing these like research prototypes,
Speaker 4:  I was like, oof, like this is actually kind of giving me vertigo. This is
Speaker 4:  like, this could be a lot to unleash into the world.
Speaker 5:  I had that too.
Speaker 1:  How so what was it, what was it that happened that made you feel like that?
Speaker 4:  I think it was just the ways that it could be used
Speaker 4:  nefariously. It's, it's obviously not that smart and
Speaker 4:  it's very slow, so like that's why it's not out yet. But
Speaker 4:  I don't know, I just haven't seen something like this yet in the wild,
Speaker 4:  something that takes control over my browser and like with natural language,
Speaker 4:  like just a few years ago when I was covering software dev culture, the big
Speaker 4:  thing was no code, low-code. So you could like use natural language to program.
Speaker 4:  And I'm like, wow, that's really cool. And now we're using natural language
Speaker 4:  to control our web browser and shop for us. Like, you know, obviously
Speaker 4:  I'm going to just say that this is vaporware, it's not out, you know, it's
Speaker 4:  research prototype, whatever. But just seeing the demo, you're like, wow,
Speaker 4:  this is, this feels like some huge leaps, you know,
Speaker 4:  we don't know when it's coming out, but
Speaker 5:  The natural language thing, it really shocks you when it does work. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  'cause I had, they, they were like really pushing that as like, why Gemini
Speaker 5:  is gonna be a killer thing. Because you can just go like, show me a video
Speaker 5:  of X, Y, Z and it'll automatically open the YouTube app and the thing without
Speaker 5:  you asking like what the app is and like that's like oh, oh, oh,
Speaker 5:  okay. But like, I had a moment like you did where I was like, oh no. Oh,
Speaker 5:  oh no, we are not ready for this. Yeah. Because they, they were basically
Speaker 5:  like, I was in the glasses and they were like, oh, why don't you ask Gemini
Speaker 5:  what the title of the yellow book behind you is? And I'm not looking at it
Speaker 5:  and I ask and because it had seen it before. Yeah. I didn't take a picture
Speaker 5:  of it. It was able to tell me the title of the, the book behind me.
Speaker 5:  Oh wow. And then I take the book and they're like, why don't, why don't you
Speaker 5:  ask open to a random page. Why don't you ask Gemini to summarize
Speaker 5:  what's on on the page for you? And I'm not taking pictures like
Speaker 5:  I would with a meta ray bands. I'm just looking. And it goes like, oh, okay,
Speaker 5:  well what this page is about is about the nexus of AI networks and blah,
Speaker 5:  blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. And it's, I was just like, oh no. College
Speaker 5:  professors and teachers everywhere are cooked because students are
Speaker 5:  just gonna take textbooks and just like, go summarize this for me and, and
Speaker 5:  whatnot. So
Speaker 1:  A thing that has started creeping onto my TikTok for you page a lot
Speaker 1:  is college students like giving tips on how
Speaker 1:  to do exactly what you just described. Like here's this cool new tool where
Speaker 1:  you can upload the, the PDF that we have to read for this week and
Speaker 1:  it'll give you this summary and these flashcards and it just, and it's just
Speaker 1:  like this is just presented as if it's like, you know, how to
Speaker 1:  access your email address and it's just like, oh my God. Like what, what
Speaker 1:  are we supposed to do with this dude? Yeah. But this is, this is one of the
Speaker 1:  things I, I've been thinking about this for forever. Like, you, you guys
Speaker 1:  I'm sure have heard the thing that Google always says about like, you know,
Speaker 1:  15% of Google searches are new every day. Like,
Speaker 1:  which is wild given how big Google is and how long it's been around. But
Speaker 1:  like this thing that everybody has been promising us with AI is that it is
Speaker 1:  going to like, completely change how we use technology.
Speaker 1:  And I think the thing that I have spent too much time thinking about
Speaker 1:  is like how I'm gonna replace all the stuff that I normally do. And so far
Speaker 1:  the answer is AI doesn't really replace any of that very successfully. But
Speaker 1:  this question of like, can it, are there going to be new things and like
Speaker 1:  new questions we can ask and new ways to do stuff that feels like
Speaker 1:  where this gets really interesting and like, what's the title of that yellow
Speaker 1:  book behind me is like, not a real use case. That's not a no. No one ever
Speaker 1:  needs to do that in real life.
Speaker 4:  It's a good magic trick or party.
Speaker 5:  The magic trick. It's a good magic trick.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But like, just the other day, so there's a, there's a bookstore like
Speaker 1:  a mile from my house that's going outta business. And so everything that
Speaker 1:  they're selling is half off. And we were in there the other night and wound
Speaker 1:  up having to like, run out before we left. But I was reading the inside of
Speaker 1:  a book, like just the, the book jacket. And I was like, oh, this sounds cool.
Speaker 1:  It's like a super spy thriller. Maybe I'll buy this, cannot remember the
Speaker 1:  title of it. And if I could just be like, what was the name of that book
Speaker 1:  I was looking at the other day in the bookstore? Like, that's the stuff,
Speaker 1:  right? Like that actually is like a sincerely useful thing to have in my
Speaker 1:  life. And ha the question for me is how far
Speaker 1:  we are from that kind of stuff. And again, it seems like the things you're
Speaker 1:  seeing in these demos are like, not,
Speaker 1:  they're not products, but they're, they're also something more than like
Speaker 1:  ideas. And So I like how I'm, I don't know, I'm
Speaker 1:  sequencing all this stuff in my brain trying to figure out like, when is
Speaker 1:  this all gonna actually work? And it gets harder and harder to figure out.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It shows that they're capable of building it. I mean, they have built
Speaker 4:  something that I am seeing with my own eyes that is working in some
Speaker 4:  capacity. So it's like the, the first like step into, you know, and
Speaker 4:  I don't know when we'll get this, I don't know when it'll be, you know, it's,
Speaker 4:  it's, it's scary. Like it genu it genuinely is scary. Yeah. And IG and you
Speaker 4:  were talking about those tiktoks earlier made me think like, is this what
Speaker 4:  people felt like, you know, when kids started using the internet for the
Speaker 4:  first time, it can't be, this just makes me feel a little sick sometimes.
Speaker 1:  Oh no, it's super Is it is. There is like the,
Speaker 1:  the thing that gives me hope is that this is the same kind of thing we've
Speaker 1:  gone through with every technical development ever. Right.
Speaker 1:  And, you know, whatever kids are growing up not learning how to read. So
Speaker 1:  like the, the internet did do that. Yay. So here we are, but, but we,
Speaker 1:  we soldier on. So v coming out of all
Speaker 1:  these demos, do you buy this big thesis from Google that like Gemini
Speaker 1:  unlocks the face, wearables for the future?
Speaker 5:  I, what I'll say is like knowing that my demos were
Speaker 5:  incredibly controlled, right? They didn't even let me take pictures of anything
Speaker 5:  knowing that, seeing everything working. Did I feel like Tony
Speaker 5:  Stark and that Gemini was my Jarvis? Yes. That was really
Speaker 5:  freaking, yeah, I did, it felt very scary. Okay.
Speaker 1:  And that's something, I mean, 'cause you, you were a person who I'm a huge
Speaker 1:  skeptic, spent a lot of time in Division Pro and kind of every time came
Speaker 1:  out of it being like, what is any of this actually doing for me? Yeah. So
Speaker 1:  the fact that you had even that much of that experience is something,
Speaker 5:  It was for the glasses though, just because there is more interaction with
Speaker 5:  the world around you and some things that I would be like, oh, this would
Speaker 5:  actually be useful in my life. Like stepping out of a subway and going
Speaker 5:  like, I have, I have no, no idea which way is north south. I have
Speaker 5:  directionally challenged, looked down, can see a map, know which way I need
Speaker 5:  to go. Like those are things that feel real. Right? But
Speaker 5:  do I think Gemini is gonna be the key to unlocking that?
Speaker 5:  Mm,
Speaker 5:  I I wanna play with it. I wanna see how I can break it. Like
Speaker 5:  I had a demo where I had a woman speaking in Spanish in front of me and I
Speaker 5:  was getting immediate translations beamed into my eyeballs
Speaker 5:  in English. And she was enunciating, she was speaking clearly.
Speaker 5:  She was not using slang, she was not talking in the ways like, would you
Speaker 5:  be able to translate a Gen Z saying like, Sigma Alpha Riz Ohio
Speaker 5:  to me, like, you know, like that sort of stuff is
Speaker 5:  the, is the st you know, like until it can do that, until it can
Speaker 5:  adopt to real life in real time. That's, that's the real
Speaker 5:  question. If we were just living in the controlled demo, sure, sure. I believe
Speaker 5:  it. But we don't, life is weird. The the
Speaker 5:  this, you know, and it's, it's very halian when you go into these demos,
Speaker 5:  they're very pollyannaish about like how people will use these things. And
Speaker 5:  I'm very curious to see how we're going to break them and how
Speaker 5:  whether Gemini's up to the task Gemini was very sassy with me though,
Speaker 5:  because I was thinking of how to phrase my, my
Speaker 5:  questions because we are so trained to be like, hey,
Speaker 5:  insert name of assistant play song from album in
Speaker 5:  app and like these very stilted ways of talking. So natural
Speaker 5:  language is mind blowing. But it, it's, it's also just like I was, I was
Speaker 5:  pausing and Gemini says to me, you don't have to say hey Google. Really?
Speaker 5:  I was like, oh geez, whoa, geez, she's so sassy.
Speaker 1:  She's like, that's actually not my name. If you could just,
Speaker 5:  If you could address me correctly, not my name. And then I said I was the,
Speaker 5:  the other really creepy thing is I said I was hungry inside of Project Moan
Speaker 5:  and I was looking at Google Maps and whatever, and it just started popping
Speaker 5:  up restaurant recommendations Whoa. All around me in the thing. And I was
Speaker 5:  like, that's creepy. That's whoa. I don't know if I like that.
Speaker 5:  Thank you. Yeah. But I don't know if I like that.
Speaker 1:  That is, that is the slow tilt toward the ad hellscape that
Speaker 1:  makes
Speaker 5:  Me worry. It is, it is. It's, wow, I can't believe you have to have boundaries
Speaker 5:  with it. Like, hey,
Speaker 1:  I'm not interested
Speaker 5:  In that. I did not ask for that. Thank you.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Here's what I will and won't talk about Gemini. Yeah. I have, oh my
Speaker 1:  gosh, I have, I have rules. Kylie, same question to you with Astro, which
Speaker 1:  I think like, like you were saying is like Google's most
Speaker 1:  ambitious version of AI things you've now used the the
Speaker 1:  latest and greatest of astral. Like do you, do you see something big inside
Speaker 1:  of that yet?
Speaker 5:  I do. I agree with V though that, I
Speaker 4:  Mean like, real life is very messy and variable and yeah,
Speaker 4:  15% of Google searches are new still this many years
Speaker 4:  after the start. I think that that's the, that's real life.
Speaker 4:  So I don't know if this comes out anytime soon. I, and
Speaker 4:  I think AI as a field is so,
Speaker 4:  it's in a really weird spot. It costs a lot of money, but Google has a
Speaker 4:  lot of money
Speaker 4:  and I think they're willing to really sink it into this. So yeah, I do, I
Speaker 4:  do see these being really useful. Astra I'm not sure how I would use that
Speaker 4:  outside of glasses if I'm being honest. That's where it seems most useful
Speaker 4:  to me in a wearable form factor. 'cause I don't think I wanna walk around
Speaker 4:  with my phone killing its battery, asking it questions. Yeah. But
Speaker 4:  it's cool. It's still cool. As for the Project
Speaker 4:  Mariner, I had said a while ago, 'cause I had gone to
Speaker 4:  New York and I, you know, was bopping between places really quickly and
Speaker 4:  I was like, I would just love something I can say like, okay, I'm boarding
Speaker 4:  this flight at this time. Can you get these groceries for me and make sure
Speaker 4:  they're at my door? You know, at this time. That would be great.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's a very silly thing. But when I saw Project Mariner, I was like,
Speaker 4:  oh, this is like almost what is trying to do except you
Speaker 4:  have to supervise it. You would be faster and you have like, you literally
Speaker 4:  just have to watch it do its work. But yeah, I think that that
Speaker 4:  could be useful if they can nail it down, make it faster, make
Speaker 4:  it safe in the long term. However, I am not a hundred percent sure
Speaker 4:  they can iron those out. I don't know what they would need to do to iron
Speaker 4:  those things out. I think as all the AI leaders like to say, like
Speaker 4:  Altman likes to say, we're gonna need some major breakthroughs. And
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Let's talk about video games and more specifically,
Speaker 1:  the most important stories yet to come in the video game
Speaker 1:  industry. There are two things looming over video games,
Speaker 1:  grand Theft Auto six, Nintendo Switch two,
Speaker 1:  both things seem to be real. Both things will ship at some point
Speaker 1:  and it's kind of all anybody has been able to talk about all year. Ash
Speaker 1:  Parish came on the show a few weeks ago and said that the biggest story of
Speaker 1:  the year in gaming was these two things that don't exist yet. Grand Theft
Speaker 1:  Auto Six just won most anticipated game at the
Speaker 1:  Game Awards. It's literally winning awards before the game. Even chips like
Speaker 1:  this is how much this stuff matters right now. And I think the
Speaker 1:  story of those two things is going to be in a very real way,
Speaker 1:  the story of the game industry, but also maybe bigger.
Speaker 1:  It might be a story about the entertainment industry or the tech industry.
Speaker 1:  If these things are as big and successful as they might be, we are going
Speaker 1:  to talk an awful lot about them. And So I figured before they launch, before
Speaker 1:  things get too crazy, Chris Grant, who is the founding editor of Polygon
Speaker 1:  and is now the group publisher for The Verge and Polygon and I think that
Speaker 1:  makes him like my boss's boss's boss or something like that.
Speaker 1:  He's just a video game nerd. So I figured I'd have him on and we'd talk about
Speaker 1:  why these things matter so much and where they're headed. Chris Grant, welcome
Speaker 1:  back.
Speaker 6:  I don't know when last time I've been on the show is so
Speaker 1:  It's been a minute I'm gonna accept
Speaker 6:  Welcome back, but it's been a couple decades.
Speaker 1:  Decades. It has been a couple of decades. Every once in a while I'm like,
Speaker 1:  Chris, you should come on the show. And you're like, I'd love to come on
Speaker 1:  the show. And then I'm like, do you wanna come on the show? And you're like,
Speaker 1:  I'm busy, this is, this happens frequently. Or
Speaker 6:  Chris, you should come on the show. I'm like, sick anytime David. And you're
Speaker 6:  like, I'll put it in your calendar and then I wait and patiently. Mm.
Speaker 1:  That doesn't sound as right to me. But anyway, I have two things I wanna
Speaker 1:  talk about before the year is over. Ash Parrish came on the show a couple
Speaker 1:  weeks ago and said that the biggest story
Speaker 1:  in gaming of 2024 was two things that have not yet shipped.
Speaker 1:  And I find that fascinating and I've been thinking about it ever since. And
Speaker 1:  I want to talk about both of them with you.
Speaker 1:  We're recording this on Friday, the day after the game awards where Grand
Speaker 1:  Theft Auto Six just won most anticipated game. So let's just start
Speaker 1:  there. Let's just talk about GTA six because I feel like I am still struggling
Speaker 1:  to wrap my mind around how important and
Speaker 1:  anticipated and big a deal this game is
Speaker 1:  in the next year, but also in kind of like the next generation of
Speaker 1:  video gaming. So like, just to wind this all the way back to the beginning,
Speaker 1:  why is Grand Theft Auto such such an important franchise? Like why has this
Speaker 1:  thing meant so much to the gaming industry for this long
Speaker 6:  Grand Theft Auto is an older franchise, so it's
Speaker 6:  been around a minute. Most notably Grand Theft Auto three, which came out
Speaker 6:  on the PlayStation two. PlayStation two is the bestselling game console of
Speaker 6:  all time. And as gaming became a more adult pursuit,
Speaker 6:  there were fewer and fewer games to play as an adult, or maybe more
Speaker 6:  specifically as a teenager, looking for things that weren't more childish.
Speaker 6:  And Grant Theft Auto three came at a time when there was a real
Speaker 6:  appetite for that. There was a real appetite for games to feel more mature
Speaker 6:  and Grant Theft Auto wanted to were, for all intents and purposes, different
Speaker 6:  games. They were top down. It wasn't the same kind of open world sandbox
Speaker 6:  that we think of today. So three was the real change. It came at the right
Speaker 6:  moment technologically, it came at the right moment. Culturally, I think
Speaker 6:  a lot of video games like it's cultural. Yeah. Video games are
Speaker 6:  entertainment products. They aren't powered by hardware, they have generational
Speaker 6:  leaps. We'll talk about some of that generational leap when we get into six.
Speaker 6:  But they are fundamentally cultural moments and how you talk about them,
Speaker 6:  how you play them, what you do, that's what powers the sort of
Speaker 6:  culture and sort of legend of some of these games.
Speaker 6:  Why are people excited about Grants Theft Auto Six? Because it's part of
Speaker 6:  the Grand Thefts auto franchise. Yeah, they haven't played it before. It'll
Speaker 6:  be different. And why are they excited about the Grand Theft Auto franchise?
Speaker 6:  Because they've played three, or they played four or they played five and
Speaker 6:  they have memories of playing with their friends or they played it in their
Speaker 6:  college dorm or they played it with their buddies after work. They played
Speaker 6:  it online increasingly is how a lot of people engage with this game. And
Speaker 6:  that volume of play across
Speaker 6:  decades is so profound and the sales
Speaker 6:  numbers are so high that the number of people who have touched this franchise
Speaker 6:  and may wanna touch it again becomes kind of staggering under its own weight.
Speaker 6:  And so when you talk about 2025, you're really looking at an audience
Speaker 6:  that, not just the audience for GTA five or GTA online, but some
Speaker 6:  of that audience for four and some of that audience for three or some of
Speaker 6:  that audience for Vice City or San Andreas or whatever. And how many of
Speaker 6:  those people will trade up for the new one. That's a lot
Speaker 6:  of folks.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Well, but what I wonder about the way you describe the
Speaker 1:  legacy is like you, you could say a lot of that same stuff about, I don't
Speaker 1:  know, the, the Halo franchise over the years or Call of Duty or
Speaker 1:  like Madden If you stretch a little bit, right? Like the, the stuff that
Speaker 1:  sort of culturally means things to people unlike your average video game.
Speaker 1:  But I don't feel like we're, we talk about Grand Theft
Speaker 1:  Auto the same way that we talk about those games. Like no, nobody is like
Speaker 1:  hanging the future of the gaming and entertainment industries on the success
Speaker 1:  of the Next Call of Duty. Mm. There's something different about GTA.
Speaker 6:  I might argue the thesis on Call of Duty a little bit. Okay. Considering
Speaker 6:  the Microsoft Activision Blizzard merger, largely powered by
Speaker 6:  Call of Duty Fair.
Speaker 1:  Alright. Maybe the next one more than most. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Call of Duty is a little different 'cause it comes out every year. Fair.
Speaker 6:  So you know, if if the last GTA came out in 2013,
Speaker 6:  which is wild, is that true? Yes. We'll talk about sort of like
Speaker 6:  what that means to have a franchise that's taking that kind of gap year
Speaker 6:  between its career and what's happened
Speaker 6:  since 2013 to now. The whole world's different
Speaker 6:  frankly. And and not to mention video gaming and technology that makes video
Speaker 6:  games possible, which is also sort of a wild testament to GTA Five's success.
Speaker 6:  That it remains one of the top 10 most played games and bestselling games
Speaker 6:  every year in that interim period. I
Speaker 1:  And I, I confess, I haven't played GTA five in a long time, but from the
Speaker 1:  little bit I understand it's a very different game now than it was in 2013.
Speaker 1:  Right?
Speaker 6:  The game is the same as in the single player game. Sure. Okay.
Speaker 6:  There's a bunch of DLC that they had committed to release that never came
Speaker 6:  out. Right? Like what is different is GTA online. And GTA
Speaker 6:  Online did not launch alongside GTA five. It came out a little later.
Speaker 6:  GTA Online is the thing that has propelled that game and propelled its sort
Speaker 6:  of popularity over the years, which we can get into. But
Speaker 6:  the, you know, games like Madden games like Call of Duty, they're
Speaker 6:  immensely popular. They sell a ton. They're some of the bestselling games
Speaker 6:  every year. Those are the games that people will trade up every year. They
Speaker 6:  have this memories of playing it and they accrue some new audience and
Speaker 6:  they shed some audience. And it's so it's like not different from a subscription
Speaker 6:  business, right? Is your churn gonna turn over the audience on the higher
Speaker 6:  end? They don't wanna play anymore. Do you pick up new audience at the younger
Speaker 6:  end?
Speaker 1:  It's an interesting way to think about it. You just pay 60 bucks a year for
Speaker 1:  Madden. That's just how it's, that's it.
Speaker 6:  That's your subscription cost. Yeah. Yeah. And so Halo a little different.
Speaker 6:  I think Microsoft wishes it had a Call of Duty or Madden and Halo is not
Speaker 6:  managed to retain that cultural relevance.
Speaker 6:  But GTA has, and it has in part because you know, previous
Speaker 6:  GTA four to five I think was 2009 to 13. So there's a four year gap there.
Speaker 6:  Reasonable, right? Same generation. That was the Xbox 360
Speaker 6:  PS three generation GTA five comes on the tail end of that generation
Speaker 6:  as in like the very tail end, like the new consoles are coming out. Hmm.
Speaker 6:  And it sets records, right? It's the fastest selling entertainment product
Speaker 6:  of all time, et cetera, et cetera, right? It continues to hold some of these
Speaker 6:  records as being one of the highest grossing entertainment products ever
Speaker 6:  made as an individual product. Wow. But that's on the
Speaker 6:  Xbox 360 hardware, that's on the PlayStation three hardware.
Speaker 6:  And just like put that in context
Speaker 6:  that those consoles, at least the 360 came out in 2005. PS three came
Speaker 6:  out the following year. That's 20 years ago. Yeah, 20
Speaker 6:  years before the 360 came out was the NES.
Speaker 1:  Wow.
Speaker 6:  Like, yeah. I don't wanna make every half the listeners just turn to
Speaker 6:  Ash. I'm sorry,
Speaker 1:  Dust. That was off. I didn't like that at all.
Speaker 6:  Shoulda trigger warning. Liam, let's add a trigger warning before I say that
Speaker 6:  just in case anyone's driving or something. So 20 years is a long time
Speaker 6:  technologically, and we're talking about, you know, a game that was
Speaker 6:  targeting hardware that came out in 2005 and now we're talking about a game
Speaker 6:  that's targeting hardware that came out in 2020. We're already on,
Speaker 6:  well you could say we're on the tail end, you know, on the back half of
Speaker 6:  this generation of hardware, the PS five and series X. So
Speaker 6:  this is a wild generational leap for a game that itself has
Speaker 6:  come to define technological leaps. What is possible with the
Speaker 6:  state-of-the-art and games technology, what is that gonna mean? I'm sure
Speaker 6:  you've seen some of the GTA five videos where they put crazy realtime mods
Speaker 6:  in there. Like it looks like real life stuff. Like it's kind of nuts.
Speaker 6:  What happens to a gate? My GTA six when this amount of budget, this amount
Speaker 6:  of time. And then to your point, the expectations that come on the other
Speaker 6:  side of it, will it meet them to some degree? I mean it has
Speaker 6:  to, it's, it's a, it's a make or break kind of moment,
Speaker 6:  but a franchise. And then on the other hand, of course it'll, right, like
Speaker 6:  the level of expectation on a game like this is so high. The number of people
Speaker 6:  that will buy it just to mess around with it. I will buy it.
Speaker 6:  I'm not a huge GTA, but I will say, I'll confess on the internet, please
Speaker 6:  don't harass me on the internet. I've never beat a GTA game.
Speaker 6:  I've played hundreds of hours of GTA games and I play the missions and they're
Speaker 6:  just, I'm not for me and I can't get through them, but I
Speaker 6:  will play it to mess around. And so you get to GTA online and the point of
Speaker 6:  GTA online is just go mess around. Right? Okay. And I think that what a game
Speaker 6:  looks like today and and how you develop a game and what kind of audience
Speaker 6:  you target, that's really hard If you haven't been providing that live service
Speaker 6:  that Rockstar has been providing this whole time. And So I assume that they're
Speaker 6:  going to GTA six with some real focus on the single player, a huge focus
Speaker 6:  on the technology and what that sandbox enables them to do. But then just
Speaker 6:  as much focus on the living game aspect of
Speaker 6:  it. Games as a service. What does it mean to have a game like GTA six
Speaker 6:  and its online component exists for another 13 years
Speaker 6:  afterwards. That's gonna put us into 2038 for everyone else that
Speaker 6:  wants to think about when their retirement target looks like. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I mean that's part of what's interesting about this moment to me, because
Speaker 1:  if, if GTA online didn't exist, I think everybody
Speaker 1:  would be making sort of the same assumption about what GTA six was going
Speaker 1:  to be. Right? They were going to expand the idea of an open world game,
Speaker 1:  give you more to do more things going on, make the world feel bigger, just
Speaker 1:  like do it at a scale nobody has done before. Right? That's kind of GTA's
Speaker 1:  thing, but that's kind of already what it's doing. That's like what
Speaker 1:  GTA online is and is becoming to a certain extent. So part of me
Speaker 1:  wonders what if there is even an obvious
Speaker 1:  thing for this game to do that feels like a, a generational leap that way.
Speaker 6:  I think that there's a couple things I could imagine them doing and
Speaker 6:  you know, GTA online is really big and ambitious, but it's not what people
Speaker 6:  think of as state-of-the-art when it comes to online social
Speaker 6:  based play. Right? Exactly. I mean, Fortnite is right there
Speaker 6:  sort of commanding a level of attention and a level of diversity across its
Speaker 6:  different products. Just this week they launched new
Speaker 6:  ballistic mode, five V five multiplayer, like they're gonna go head to head
Speaker 6:  with Call of Duty now in Fortnite. They've got a new Lego brick life mode.
Speaker 6:  So it's, you can just hang out and build Lego stuff and have a little town
Speaker 6:  and play different careers. They're gonna have, the OG mode is back.
Speaker 6:  Right. Hugely popular. And like Fortnite as a platform
Speaker 6:  is a really interesting idea and how it competes in a world of increasing
Speaker 6:  consolidation on that end of the market. Is GTA six a platform? I
Speaker 6:  don't know. I would not be surprised If
Speaker 1:  You, If you roll back to the way you described the game 20 years ago, like
Speaker 1:  the, the phrase that just popped into my mind is Roblox for adults,
Speaker 1:  which is like a thoroughly fascinating possibility that really doesn't exist
Speaker 1:  in kind of the way you're describing.
Speaker 6:  Roblox wants to tell you it exists, but it does not. It does not exist. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I think And Epic is trying to make that into Fortnite. Yeah. And I see the
Speaker 6:  Fortnite Islands and it's all the same Roblox junk,
Speaker 6:  billionaire simulator and like all this like Yeah. Clicker game
Speaker 6:  stuff. The vernacular of those games is pretty
Speaker 6:  limited. And when I see my son play Roblox
Speaker 6:  games, I know I'm a bad parent. They're trash. Yeah. The
Speaker 6:  low nutritional value, right. Trust that I make Astro
Speaker 6:  Bott available at all times for my family. It's available day or night. So
Speaker 1:  You're a good parent. That's, that's the
Speaker 6:  Job. I'm a good parent. Astro Bott notably gave me the year winner
Speaker 6:  yesterday last night. That's right. I don't wanna say
Speaker 6:  Polygon got it wrong. It was Bicho at Polygon, but in this
Speaker 6:  household we stand astronaut so
Speaker 6:  GTA six. Yeah, I, I have some real questions about what it means to support
Speaker 6:  that game over the decade plus that they intend to support it. Is it going
Speaker 6:  to be a platform? Are they gonna think of it that way? How do experiences
Speaker 6:  get built into, how do you keep an audience engaged when the competition
Speaker 6:  is more fierce? They're not going up against the competition in 2013. They're
Speaker 6:  going up against competition in 2025. You see Call of Duty. I think
Speaker 6:  doing an admirable job here with Warzone and thinking of what that free to
Speaker 6:  play environment looks like for a Call of Duty game and how that is complimentary
Speaker 6:  to a retail product and how they sort of push it forward. But
Speaker 6:  yeah, it's, it's gonna be fascinating. I think they have a
Speaker 6:  track record that really can't be denied. And I think even
Speaker 6:  just to Ash's point, one of the biggest stories this year is just like
Speaker 6:  waiting for any sign of anything having to
Speaker 6:  do with six, a news announcement, a trailer, you name it. Those things
Speaker 6:  really indicate a level of sort of like latent energy,
Speaker 6:  right? It's just gonna explode when it comes out and you'll capture all of
Speaker 6:  that. Well, you capture more and I think they do need to capture more for
Speaker 6:  a product this size to be successful. We will see. I do, I
Speaker 6:  think the, the sense though that the non-lease of some of these
Speaker 6:  things has been looming over 24 last year we
Speaker 6:  had tears of the Kingdom, which I think, you know, demanded a lot of
Speaker 6:  attention and, and sort of gathered up a lot of that energy. But in the
Speaker 6:  background, amidst gaming today, the top 10
Speaker 6:  most played games on PC in 2023, Fortnite, number one,
Speaker 6:  Roblox Minecraft, Counterstrike two counter co sort of shared
Speaker 6:  Sims four Call of Duty, you know, TKTK, mono
Speaker 6:  Warfare two three War Zone two League of Legends, Valant, GTA five, and Rocket
Speaker 6:  League. That's the top played games. Here's
Speaker 6:  the wild statistic about that. Average years on the market for those games.
Speaker 6:  9.6 years.
Speaker 1:  Wow.
Speaker 6:  So the games people are playing are not new games that just come out.
Speaker 6:  And so what's happened in gaming is that these things have to last much
Speaker 6:  longer. They have to function like platforms. They have to function. Like
Speaker 6:  I actually look at this list of games even across the other consoles, maybe
Speaker 6:  with the exception of Switch. And it doesn't look like games the way I think
Speaker 6:  a lot of times we think about it, it looks like sports, right? And I don't
Speaker 6:  mean eSports here. I mean like, it looks like the way you think of sports.
Speaker 6:  I like Minecraft. I, I like soccer. Like it's just
Speaker 6:  an abstraction. It always is there. It has rules. You
Speaker 6:  play it with friends, it's Minecraft. Will GTA six earn a spot on
Speaker 6:  this table? Like I kind of assume some of that of five volumes moves to it,
Speaker 6:  but what does it look like?
Speaker 1:  But do you think it does that by owning that mold and
Speaker 1:  sort of leaning into the, the kind of things that you're describing, you
Speaker 1:  know, Roblox for adults? Or does it do it by going, doing
Speaker 1:  the thing no one else can do and making a, a new sort of
Speaker 1:  wholly contained game that is good enough to pull this off? 'cause I feel
Speaker 1:  like you can, you can put your hopes on either one of those, but maybe not
Speaker 1:  both at the same time.
Speaker 6:  No, I'm gonna say both. I'm gonna say both. I'm gonna say that they're gonna
Speaker 6:  make a single player game that's gonna move the needle and sell a lot of
Speaker 6:  units. 'cause people wanna play it and then they're gonna make a sticky,
Speaker 6:  multiplayer online experience that is going to be competitive
Speaker 6:  across a landscape that looks like this. That
Speaker 1:  Would be a hell of an achievement
Speaker 6:  That is going to grow and shift over time because they will continue to
Speaker 6:  iterate on and develop it. Heists for GTA five came out years later.
Speaker 6:  Sure. Right. And that was 10 years ago. Yeah. And they were still
Speaker 6:  aware that that game had to shift and move. They had to continuously add
Speaker 6:  features and add functionality for it to be successful. And now again,
Speaker 6:  they're in a world where they compete against Fortnite and like they just,
Speaker 6:  it has to be different now. Right now there's an ongoing event in Minecraft
Speaker 6:  my son is very excited about. Like there's just a constant pace of iteration
Speaker 6:  innovation happening in these spaces that GTA will have to
Speaker 6:  compete with in a way that it, it kind of currently does. It is not
Speaker 6:  non-competitive. I think a lot about what happens, the pace
Speaker 6:  of development games. I think a lot about the, the new final fantasy games
Speaker 6:  that have come out and how they've really been struggling to, I think meet
Speaker 6:  some sales expectations. One of the things that was crazy is the, the last
Speaker 6:  Final Fantasy game 16, which
Speaker 6:  struggled on a PlayStation exclusive, a weird concept
Speaker 6:  these days and came to PC much later
Speaker 6:  and struggled there. They'll make it up over time, I suspect. But it started
Speaker 6:  development before Fortnite came out. Hmm. And I think that is like kind
Speaker 6:  of a wild sense, right? Of like how much changes in a certain period of time
Speaker 6:  when a game like Fortnite can come out and quite liberate change what, what
Speaker 6:  our expectations are of games and games culture, what you get for a free
Speaker 6:  to play game, how much value there is in a freemium model. Something that
Speaker 6:  a lot of gamers would turn their nose down at. Yeah. But then you look at
Speaker 6:  Fortnite and like, this is a very high quality game that's a lot of fun to
Speaker 6:  play and is very good and you don't need to pay for anything. So
Speaker 6:  if that was 2018, Fortnite really popped off
Speaker 6:  again GTA five, 2013. Like how much has changed Yeah. Since they even started
Speaker 6:  development on this game. And I think that's part of the expectation, that's
Speaker 6:  part of the anticipation, it's part of that legacy. And I think
Speaker 6:  there's, you know, there's also the technology of it. What more can they
Speaker 6:  do with another effectively 15 years of
Speaker 6:  hardware iteration, hardware development. It'll be exciting to see.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. You've, you've tracked the hype cycle of games like this many times
Speaker 1:  over the years
Speaker 1:  are like, should people keep their hopes high on this one?
Speaker 1:  Do you feel like, like is it, it does seem like if historically speaking,
Speaker 1:  if anything is going to live up to this kind of hype,
Speaker 1:  GTA has as good a shot as any. But also kind of like you said before, like
Speaker 1:  maybe nothing can be as good as we're sort of expecting this game to be.
Speaker 6:  My general point of view is you shouldn't get hyped about anything.
Speaker 6:  Try not to
Speaker 1:  Just to touch a nihilism right before the holidays.
Speaker 6:  Try not to. But If you insist on getting hyped about
Speaker 6:  GTA six, If you like those games, will this game meet
Speaker 6:  your expectations? I think so. Right. I I think that they've
Speaker 6:  had a kind of impressively consistent hit
Speaker 6:  rate Yeah. For that entire series.
Speaker 6:  Again, it's not my kinda game, but If you like those games, like they
Speaker 6:  have, I don't wanna say never missed, but they've come closer than
Speaker 6:  most franchises to upholding a certain level of expectation and value.
Speaker 6:  I think the way that they're releasing it and why to Ash's point it's been
Speaker 6:  looming over 24 is 'cause Take two has a very specific
Speaker 6:  point of view on the release strategy for this game, which is when it is
Speaker 6:  ready, there is no competition. It is an alpha predator.
Speaker 6:  There is no competition for GTA in the market. Yeah. They don't need
Speaker 6:  to release it. Nobody's nipping at their heels. There's still
Speaker 6:  banking cash on five, which is still in the top
Speaker 6:  10 most played games every year. So why rush it? They don't need to rush
Speaker 6:  it and they will wait until it is ready and done.
Speaker 6:  And I think that that is should be comforting to somebody who's looking forward
Speaker 6:  to it. And then the question becomes, do they know what done means? Hmm.
Speaker 6:  Is the target quality good? Is it what you want? Is it fun?
Speaker 6:  Again, I think they have enough of a blueprint at this point to follow that
Speaker 6:  people who like GTA games should probably be well
Speaker 6:  targeted by it and they'll appreciate it. Now again, that
Speaker 6:  isn't enough. They will need to grow new audience, they will need to bring
Speaker 6:  in new players, they will need to siphon off some of those Fortnite fans,
Speaker 6:  et cetera. Will it do that? Does it have enough
Speaker 6:  juice to continue to grow over time
Speaker 6:  instead of just keep what they have? And that's the big question for me and
Speaker 6:  I, I dunno.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. I think to some extent the the like we're just gonna make a slightly
Speaker 1:  better new game every year is like an actually easier
Speaker 1:  strategy. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  The iterative year by year strategy is like expensive and
Speaker 6:  difficult in its own way, but you know, you can have misses in there and
Speaker 6:  keep going. Call of Duty modern warfare with a notable miss a few years ago
Speaker 6:  and like a little bit of a return to form this year. Okay. It can
Speaker 6:  absorb that impact again for GTA six. If this were to be a miss,
Speaker 6:  I find it almost impossible to imagine it being a miss, but if it were to
Speaker 6:  be a miss catastrophic, right. Like you don't get another
Speaker 6:  at bat. So Yeah. It's a, it's a bit of a riskier
Speaker 6:  game. And again, to take two's point, like they'll just wait until it's ready.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There's no, there's no sense in taking that kind of risk.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So the, the other highly anticipated thing that I think we're
Speaker 1:  likely to get way before GTA six is the
Speaker 1:  switch to, I asked you when I saw you in person a couple of weeks ago to
Speaker 1:  make me feel better that, that the switch to isn't gonna suck because I have
Speaker 1:  pinned a surprising amount of my hopes and gaming future on the switch
Speaker 1:  to not sucking. Tell me how to feel about the switch to
Speaker 1:  it's, we, we assume it's coming sometime in the next three months, right?
Speaker 1:  Like it is, it is legitimately imminent in some way here.
Speaker 6:  If I were to bet, I'm gonna say it's coming in the first half of the year.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Nintendo's fiscal, I wanna say starts in Q2 in April.
Speaker 6:  So there's a reason to think maybe they try and get it out just before, just
Speaker 6:  after. We'll see. Sure. Nintendo will also wait until it's ready.
Speaker 6:  So there's that, the reporting so far has been that they
Speaker 6:  wanna wait until they have enough units that there
Speaker 6:  isn't any risk of hardware shortages or any other sort of holdups. So they
Speaker 6:  just wanna be a short when it comes out you can get one
Speaker 1:  Because there was a bunch of that at the beginning with the first switch.
Speaker 1:  Right? Wasn't it hard to get for a while?
Speaker 6:  Nintendo historically has struggled with
Speaker 6:  inventory pipeline. Right? Remember the we Oh yeah. You couldn't buy it
Speaker 6:  for years. Yeah. And it was already using old hardware
Speaker 6:  Nintendo's strategy of using older hardware. The Game Boy
Speaker 6:  was famously built using really old hardware and they reimagined what that
Speaker 6:  old hardware can do and that's sort of Nintendo's magic, but it's old
Speaker 6:  hardware. Yeah. So the, we comes out with old hardware and they can't keep
Speaker 6:  this thing in stock. That's, so there's something I always found
Speaker 6:  Nintendo's point of view and that's a little disingenuous. I think that they
Speaker 6:  like having things sell out. I think they like managing a very tight
Speaker 6:  retail environment. That feeling of you got one
Speaker 6:  fresh, I don't know if that works anymore. The space is
Speaker 6:  too competitive. If you don't get that and there's a PlayStation five right
Speaker 6:  next to it on the shelf, maybe you just pick that up instead. Yeah. That
Speaker 6:  is Fortnite on it too. Like Right. What's the point? And So I, I
Speaker 6:  do think that they recognize they're in a different environment and that
Speaker 6:  they will need to keep stock and they will need to take advantage of people's
Speaker 6:  appetite to buy. Right now every kid has a tablet. What do they need to switch
Speaker 6:  for? So we'll see that's one of the pieces that's been reported
Speaker 6:  about the timing is that they're waiting for volume
Speaker 6:  to be ready. They have released a couple little nuggets and
Speaker 6:  just for the calendar enthusiasts out there, you know who you
Speaker 6:  are. October, 2016 they announced the switch
Speaker 6:  Switch came out the following year, April, there was no October
Speaker 6:  announcement this year. Right. It has not been announced yet. They have announced
Speaker 6:  in a sort of like to shareholders way that there is a successor to the
Speaker 6:  console and their hard work on it and that they will announce more when ready.
Speaker 6:  Okay. They, they dropped one weird little nugget of news
Speaker 6:  maybe like a month or so ago, which was like random at night and it was just
Speaker 6:  like the switch successor will play switch software.
Speaker 1:  Oh yeah. That was like on election day. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Right. Yes.
Speaker 1:  Like thanks Nintendo.
Speaker 6:  What a weird drop. What a like Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Again, for the calendar enthusiast, you're looking at a calendar. What day
Speaker 6:  should we pick to put this piece in this, which is generally good news, why
Speaker 6:  would you not trumpet it? I'll say, and I'll say this about the successorship.
Speaker 6:  Nintendo has somewhat of a reputation, especially in modern times of following
Speaker 6:  up consoles that are hits with flops or duds or disappointments. Let's say
Speaker 6:  most notably you have the Super Nintendo followed up with the N 64.
Speaker 6:  There's a little bit of a back to back N 64, at least from a sales standpoint,
Speaker 6:  followed up by the game Cube X. Although game cube heads no good
Speaker 6:  console
Speaker 1:  Also N 60, this is like N 64 slander I was not prepared for and will not
Speaker 1:  acknowledge. But we can just move past that.
Speaker 6:  I have an N 64 right here. Okay.
Speaker 1:  All right then we're, we're cool. All right. With
Speaker 6:  Library games, I'm gonna not, but if you're gonna prioritize and rank
Speaker 6:  the best Nintendo consoles of all time inclusive of the virtual
Speaker 6:  boy, the Nintendo 64 is still gonna be low on that list.
Speaker 1:  That's fair. I mean, but the most recent one right, is like I've heard a
Speaker 1:  lot of people say like we, we you. Right. Huge
Speaker 1:  revolutionary hit followed by big
Speaker 6:  Flop,
Speaker 1:  Weird new idea on top of it that didn't work.
Speaker 6:  A big flop. And I actually went back before this podcast and read some of
Speaker 6:  my weu coverage from their launch event in New York. And the piece that I
Speaker 6:  was the most upset by, the most frustrated by the most
Speaker 6:  sort of like incredulous about was the absence of
Speaker 6:  an online service. Hmm. They announced the EU and they said, we'll make an
Speaker 6:  online service. You can't No it's 2013
Speaker 6:  GTA five is coming out. Like you can't, you need it now. You need it yesterday.
Speaker 6:  In fact, it's an embarrassment. Xbox Live has been out for a decade.
Speaker 6:  Like just kind of a bizarre omission and they weren't able to do it. They
Speaker 6:  partnered with a third party and we use struggled with that absence of an
Speaker 6:  online function. There was different systems, there was your Nintendo network
Speaker 6:  ID and other stuff, but it wasn't until Switch online that had something
Speaker 6:  that feels modern, right. That you could go onto. One of my examples
Speaker 6:  that I used in this piece from 2013 is that if I buy a book on a Kindle and
Speaker 6:  I lose my Kindle, I just get a new Kindle in my books there. Right. This
Speaker 6:  is something that most consumers understand. What was crazy about
Speaker 6:  Nintendo until the switch, the switch is even a little bit goofy with this,
Speaker 6:  but it's okay. Three Ds and Ds, there are
Speaker 6:  two portable consoles, three Ds also from a sales standpoint and from an
Speaker 6:  audience I think standpoint and critical standpoint, a disappointment relative
Speaker 6:  to the Ds. The Ds and threes were portable
Speaker 6:  consoles largely targeted at children or
Speaker 6:  younger people let's say. And If you lost it, can
Speaker 6:  you imagine a kid losing something? Never, never happened. Purely hypothetically.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. If you lost it and you had digital games that you
Speaker 6:  purchased, they were gone to tied
Speaker 6:  to the console. What like
Speaker 6:  what? I would never buy I, to this day, I don't buy Nintendo games digitally,
Speaker 6:  I just don't, I'm like, I'm, I don't know, I'm old, I have a lot of physical
Speaker 6:  games 'cause I'm also old. But also I just, I don't trust them still. And
Speaker 6:  so this announcement that my switch games would carry forward was like Huh,
Speaker 6:  okay. Huh. Yeah. Maybe it is okay to buy Nintendo games digitally.
Speaker 6:  Now maybe my purchases through Nintendo are
Speaker 6:  in some cases like Sacreds maybe too strong of a word but like respected
Speaker 6:  in a way that I expect them to be. And this has not happened over some generations,
Speaker 6:  right? Your, not all of your 360 games work on your Xbox
Speaker 6:  Series X, but a lot of them do and it does feel like they try and that's
Speaker 6:  been newer for them. But going forward I think to some sense
Speaker 6:  your expectation that the things that you purchase digitally will
Speaker 6:  retain their value over time and will have forward compatibility. The idea
Speaker 6:  that backwards compatibility is backwards thinking to use. I think that was
Speaker 6:  Don Matrix dumbass quote. Yeah. It's not great.
Speaker 6:  It's not just that, it's not backwards thinking. It's the way games work
Speaker 6:  today. They have to be, they have your stuff has to carry forward.
Speaker 6:  This is how and what consumer expectations are. And So I think for
Speaker 6:  Nintendo that was a huge piece of news that I don't wanna diminish. It was
Speaker 6:  a tiny weird drop on election day. But the idea
Speaker 6:  that they're thinking about that suggests to me that they are thinking in
Speaker 6:  a forward capacity about how people think about their software and their
Speaker 6:  purchases. They're thinking about it as a successor and not to Nintendo consoles
Speaker 6:  but as a successor to the Switch, which is an important differentiation.
Speaker 6:  This is not N 60 40 Game Cube or Game Cube to we.
Speaker 6:  This is more of a we to we you environment where they're keeping
Speaker 6:  the name there. They're anticipating some consumer adoption based on that
Speaker 6:  name. Your games will play the we you would play We games.
Speaker 6:  It did drop the game Cube support. I I think saying that in the three
Speaker 6:  Ds played DS games. I think that if comparing it to the three Ds and the
Speaker 6:  Weu doesn't give you a lot of comfort, it doesn't make you feel super
Speaker 6:  confident. My hope here is that they try
Speaker 6:  not to reinvent the wheel and some of the reporting suggests it will still
Speaker 6:  be a portable console that will be able to be dock
Speaker 6:  that it has a bigger screen which like maybe that's weird. It's already
Speaker 6:  kind of a big portable but so is the steam deck and I carry that around.
Speaker 6:  So maybe it's fine that it will have detachable controllers
Speaker 6:  if this sounds familiar. That should be comforting because
Speaker 6:  it's a bigger switch with maybe some better hardware and some different games.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I've really come around to that actually being my ideal outcome. I don't
Speaker 1:  know how you feel but for me, like I, I still play the Switch a lot and
Speaker 1:  the more I use it, the more I'm like okay this thing plus faster
Speaker 1:  processor, presumably more efficient chip so
Speaker 1:  it'll last a little longer. Better. Wifi is actually like the
Speaker 1:  most important one for me 'cause the wifi chip in this thing is old and bad
Speaker 1:  and just does not work very well and like maybe an
Speaker 1:  upgraded screen. But honestly even that is like relatively low on my list
Speaker 1:  is like, there's very little else I want from this like tweak everything,
Speaker 1:  upgrade all the parts to newer versions of those parts and keep it a switch
Speaker 1:  feels to me like what I'm looking for.
Speaker 6:  I would like the following things. I'd like it to be more durable. Mm.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  The Joycons are China a nightmare
Speaker 6:  if anyone has kids in their household. I don't wanna say how many times I've
Speaker 6:  taken apart a JoyCon and replaced and fixed parts of it. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  it's very tiny and those screws are very small and it's all very
Speaker 6:  tightly packed in there and I'm pretty good at that stuff. But
Speaker 6:  can I say the F word on this podcast? Is that loud? Sure. Fuck the Joycons.
Speaker 6:  I don't wanna see 'em again. Do not bring them back. I don't want get rid
Speaker 6:  of them. Stop the JoyCon shit. Gimme a better analog stick.
Speaker 6:  Please give me, get rid of the IR Port
Speaker 6:  Labo community. I see you. I don't mean any disrespect. Labo
Speaker 6:  is incredible. Everyone else got it wrong. We knew it was good. However,
Speaker 6:  get rid of the IR port. Get rid of the complexity. Lower the cost of those
Speaker 6:  things.
Speaker 6:  Make it more durable. Yeah. This is a console that you're gonna be thrown
Speaker 6:  in your bag. Why is it so fragile? Why are things so wiggly?
Speaker 6:  So I would love to see it beefed up. I would love to see multiple switches
Speaker 6:  and your profile travel better. Mm. If you have two switches in your house,
Speaker 6:  going between them is not a nice affair. It does not feel
Speaker 6:  good. And I think a lot of families now
Speaker 6:  have a lot of
Speaker 1:  Switches. I was about to make fun of you for being like the only person on
Speaker 1:  earth who's like worried about managing multiple switches. But you are probably
Speaker 1:  right that there are, there are people out there for whom that's a real thing.
Speaker 6:  I know a lot of folks who have kids that have like a switch light. Mm. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And then there's the switch at home. But why isn't, why is my game there?
Speaker 6:  Is it saved? Did it transfer? Is my saved file there? What's my thing? Do
Speaker 6:  I have to download this again? This is my home console, not my home console.
Speaker 6:  It gets like a bit goofy or it has to always be online if it's not the home
Speaker 6:  console, but then it's a switch like you're traveling with it. So there's
Speaker 6:  just like some part of managing multiple consoles that I think,
Speaker 6:  you know, especially as these things last longer and people play the games
Speaker 6:  longer, like there should be some expectation of it. This gets into Nintendo's
Speaker 6:  profile management, software management part where I have some
Speaker 6:  confidence that they have radically improved. I think their, their
Speaker 6:  yearbook title would be most improved. Maybe it would.
Speaker 6:  But I think I really wanna see that. I think for the big
Speaker 6:  open question for Switch, I, I don't know if it's or switch two, what are
Speaker 6:  they gonna call it? Polygons official vote is Super Switch. It's
Speaker 1:  Gotta be Super Switch is the, I don't think they will, but that is the correct
Speaker 1:  answer.
Speaker 6:  And the super should definitely be the super font from Super Nintendo. A
Speaker 6:  hundred percent. That's the other part I'm gonna say out loud.
Speaker 1:  We're doing a retro thing in the world right now. Like go Go for it. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  go. We're all, we all live in the nineties again. Like let's just do it.
Speaker 1:  I'm into it.
Speaker 6:  Look, I love the nineties and it turns out one of the things that younger
Speaker 6:  folks and myself still have in common is they love the nineties now too.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  The nineties are so back man.
Speaker 6:  It's great. Yeah. So let's all just live it and do the super font please.
Speaker 6:  Amen. And then if it doesn't have a lot of secrets, it doesn't have a lot
Speaker 6:  of surprises. Right. When the, we came out, do you remember the Wes code
Speaker 6:  name revolution? Oh yeah. And everyone wanted to know what the revolution
Speaker 6:  was and there was, this was like 2005, so the internet was different back
Speaker 6:  then, but there was all these rumors and mockups and somebody found
Speaker 6:  a footage but the lighting is off and you can tell because the direction
Speaker 6:  of whatever, I don't think we have that this time because
Speaker 6:  it's probably just gonna be a big switch. It's gonna be a big switch with
Speaker 6:  some different things. And then is Nintendo, will they
Speaker 6:  feel compelled to add in a gau, a whizzbang?
Speaker 6:  I don't know. Is it gonna have like a big radio antenna on the back and
Speaker 6:  it does ham radio too? I don't know. I have like no idea what the thing
Speaker 6:  is gonna be or will they just make it a better switch? Keep in mind the Weu
Speaker 6:  successor to the We all they had to do was make a faster we and they
Speaker 6:  added this goofball tablet that connected locally
Speaker 6:  Yep. To your console and it created this environment for asynchronous
Speaker 6:  gameplay, which was really cool. And then no games did that. It did give
Speaker 6:  them some of the insight into the switch, but like, okay. And then also it
Speaker 6:  was a like a cable box controller similar to the Xbox Run. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Which again, both of those two don't. It wasn't just
Speaker 6:  Microsoft being dumb. Both of them were like Yeah, cable boxes, that's what
Speaker 6:  kids love. Yeah. Right. I just actually asked the Polygon staff
Speaker 6:  yesterday who, who still had a cable subscription and the only people who
Speaker 6:  did it was only a handful of people and they have it for just sports. That's
Speaker 6:  it. Like everyone else has been a court, I've been a court coach since 2005
Speaker 6:  six. So we, you had some bonkers
Speaker 6:  ideas about what people wanted in a console and I'm hopeful that they don't
Speaker 6:  feel the urgency to like add something fancy. I will also
Speaker 6:  find one other thing. The Switch is not the best selling console ever. It
Speaker 6:  is the best selling Nintendo console ever. The best selling console is the
Speaker 6:  PlayStation two, but also the DS handheld is
Speaker 6:  still a little bit over the switch. The switch may overtake it lifetime.
Speaker 6:  We'll see. But I do wanna find another really notable part about the Switch.
Speaker 6:  It has sold more software than any other Nintendo console.
Speaker 6:  The, we sold roughly a billion units of software. The Switch has sold
Speaker 6:  1.3 billion units of software. Wow. The DS sold about a billion units of
Speaker 6:  software too. But there's a, a timeline issue,
Speaker 6:  but the DS and the, we were out at the same time. So you sold
Speaker 6:  a ton of hardware units, you sold a ton of software units and you had
Speaker 6:  two hardware lines and Nintendo consolidated those in the switch. So
Speaker 6:  again, for the Switch to be successful, it had to be, this was a consolidation
Speaker 6:  of two businesses into one the handheld in the console business.
Speaker 6:  And it did
Speaker 6:  they continue to consolidate this market and from handheld to console
Speaker 6:  is how do they again keep not only the audience it has,
Speaker 6:  but continue to grow audience. And some of that means being
Speaker 6:  increasingly competitive in a world full of these other games
Speaker 6:  we're talking about. So I think modernization
Speaker 6:  is something Nintendo
Speaker 6:  So do you
Speaker 1:  Feel like this next era for Nintendo is more
Speaker 1:  competitive because there is this huge
Speaker 1:  upswing in the Steam deck and these other kind of handheld game systems
Speaker 1:  that are starting to come out and do really well? Or is Nintendo as ever
Speaker 1:  just kind of like overhear doing Nintendo things?
Speaker 6:  Nintendo will always be over here doing Nintendo things. Okay. Like they
Speaker 6:  can't help themselves.
Speaker 1:  Right. And I do think to your point about doing all the weirdness, like one
Speaker 1:  of the things I have wondered about is if things like Alarm O
Speaker 1:  and this museum and all this stuff is like Nintendo is putting its weird
Speaker 1:  energy on that stuff so that it can keep the switch
Speaker 1:  non-insane.
Speaker 6:  I like that. That's a fun idea.
Speaker 1:  I have no evidence for that theory, but it's kind of what it feels like to
Speaker 1:  me. The
Speaker 6:  Theme parks. Yeah. Right. Like, you
Speaker 1:  Know, like all the people here we've hired to just do whatever. Yep. They
Speaker 1:  now do it over there and then the switch just gets to be the switch. You
Speaker 1:  do
Speaker 6:  Hear some reporting and, and some Nten people in me and Mud will talk about
Speaker 6:  the younger designers at Nintendo, right. The younger designers get a lot
Speaker 6:  of credit for Platoon for this platoon series, which has its own
Speaker 6:  just totally perfect vibe. And the Switch
Speaker 6:  gets some credit from the younger designers. And So I think that there is
Speaker 6:  some world in which as the old guard at Nintendo gets older and
Speaker 6:  older, even though Miyamoto doesn't appear to age true
Speaker 6:  I think. But as they get older and older, like there are younger folks
Speaker 6:  in there who are coming with a different point of view and different set
Speaker 6:  of expectations who can drive the business and the products they make towards
Speaker 6:  an audience that is going to be more compatible with that
Speaker 6:  sensibility. And so maybe there is some world in which those weird experiments
Speaker 6:  go to the side and the weird experiments are still part of what makes Nintendo,
Speaker 6:  Nintendo and I, I think that even some of the games like when the, when the
Speaker 6:  switch came out, one two switch, like I, I miss some of the goofball
Speaker 6:  again, Labo, I miss some of these goofball exercises
Speaker 6:  and I would really dread having Nintendo product come out with just
Speaker 6:  AAA metric Prime game, aaa, Mario Game, AAA
Speaker 6:  Zelda game. And that's all great. But what's exciting about Nintendo products
Speaker 6:  are the weird one two switches or Snipper clips or
Speaker 6:  Labo. Yeah. And So I, I don't
Speaker 6:  want to disabuse them of any of that whimsy,
Speaker 6:  but I worry again about integrating a pinwheel
Speaker 6:  into the console and like understandable trying to make that
Speaker 6:  a thing. So we'll see. I think it will have some
Speaker 6:  surprises in store is my guess. Whether they're going to add value
Speaker 6:  or be a distraction is a bigger question. But I'm, I'm pretty confident Switch
Speaker 6:  too will just be a a, a good or switch.
Speaker 1:  Boy, I hope so. A good or switch is, is truly all I
Speaker 1:  need in 2025. All right Chris, we gotta take a break, but thank you for doing
Speaker 1:  this. Good to have you back.
Speaker 6:  Thanks.
Speaker 1:  All right, we gotta take one more break and then we have a much requested
Speaker 1:  hotline that I'm very excited about. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the hotline.
Speaker 2:  This week's Vergecast hotline is brought to you by Amazon Queue, the new
Speaker 2:  generative AI assistant from AWS
Speaker 1:  As always. The number is 8 6 6 VERGE one one. The email is
Speaker 1:  vergecast at The Verge dot com. We love all of your questions. We've gotten
Speaker 1:  a bunch more great ones after the meta show we did last week that I think
Speaker 1:  have been really interesting and I look forward to finding a way to answer.
Speaker 1:  I will say we're taking a couple of weeks off after this week so we're not
Speaker 1:  gonna have a ton of time to do hotline stuff, but we're also gonna do a bunch
Speaker 1:  of fun catch up stuff in January and we will not lose track of your questions
Speaker 1:  so please keep them coming. All of your
Speaker 1:  weirdest tech questions, if you're ever like, huh, I want just pick up the
Speaker 1:  phone and call us or send us an email. 8 6 6 verse one one. The email is
Speaker 1:  Vergecast at verse.com. This week's hotline comes from
Speaker 1:  I would say a a semi throwaway line in last week's meta
Speaker 1:  episode that came up a whole bunch and it's time to dig
Speaker 1:  back into it. Let's hear it.
Speaker 8:  Hi, my name is Chris and I'm on vacation right now in the
Speaker 8:  United Kingdom and I was just kind of like
Speaker 8:  listening on the plane, whatever and I heard Helen have black talk about
Speaker 8:  her garden design in Figma and like what the,
Speaker 8:  like I gotta know about this. Like come I'm a designer
Speaker 8:  using Figma. It's a great tool. Like tell me about one time about your car.
Speaker 8:  Mama wants to know. Thanks so much
Speaker 1:  Helen Haack, welcome back. Thank you
Speaker 9:  So much. It's been so long. One entire week
Speaker 1:  We got so much of this like I sort of assumed there would be someone
Speaker 1:  who was like, oh I am also a gardening sicko and I want to know what
Speaker 1:  Helen is up to. But we got, we got more of this than I expected so it's,
Speaker 1:  it was just time to do this with you.
Speaker 9:  I now feel extra guilty for having drafted this how to
Speaker 9:  guide for Barbara to publish on The Verge dot com in 2023
Speaker 9:  and then never publishing it. I am sorry worlds that I did not give you
Speaker 9:  this weird and highly specific content. The
Speaker 1:  World clearly needs this in a way that I did not understand until this
Speaker 1:  past week. So let's, let's just dive in. I, I
Speaker 1:  don't even know where to start because all of this is so outrageously foreign
Speaker 1:  to me. So how did it come to pass that you are a Figma
Speaker 1:  gardener?
Speaker 9:  Yes. Well David, it's a, you might think it's a little weird that we're talking
Speaker 9:  about gardening here it late December, but
Speaker 9:  actually the timing is perfect. We are approaching the darkest day of the
Speaker 9:  year and what anyone who is a gardener knows is that you do actual
Speaker 9:  gardening from like March to November, you've got spring planning,
Speaker 9:  but from December to like February you were in pure fantasy
Speaker 9:  gardening. This is when you, all of your gardening energy is completely
Speaker 9:  thwarted. You can't do shit outside the ground is frozen. Okay? So what you
Speaker 9:  do is you fantasize, this is when you like read gardening books, which you
Speaker 9:  would never do in the summertime. This is when you draw plans for your garden
Speaker 9:  and think about what you're gonna do when it's not dark and depressing outside.
Speaker 9:  You're
Speaker 1:  Like a professional athlete in the off season basically.
Speaker 9:  So timing is perfect. Okay, so how did this come about? Well I bought a house
Speaker 9:  in 2022. It had a very kinda like formal
Speaker 9:  foundation planting that we were not super into and we were thinking about
Speaker 9:  how to expand it, plant more plants. I went full like native
Speaker 9:  plant rabbit hole, some very into like native plants
Speaker 9:  and my husband Phil and I were talking about what we wanted to plant and
Speaker 9:  we needed to come up with a plan for what we were gonna put in the ground
Speaker 9:  and therefore what did we need to buy and really what did we need to buy
Speaker 9:  when like native plant trust pre-orders went live, which is usually like
Speaker 9:  late January
Speaker 1:  February. Is that like a big moment? Like is it a, is it a Taylor Swift on
Speaker 1:  Ticketmaster kind of situation that we're talking about here?
Speaker 9:  Probably not David, but I should also set a, a set
Speaker 9:  the stage that I am not a professional gardener. I'm a very
Speaker 9:  amateur gardener and what I have is some books I have read Boundless
Speaker 9:  Enthusiasm and no practical gardening experience whatsoever.
Speaker 9:  That's
Speaker 1:  The dream.
Speaker 9:  But my husband and I were, you know, trying to figure out where did we wanna
Speaker 9:  plan for what we were going to do and he's a front end web
Speaker 9:  developer, Phil if I, I'm not mentioning his name. And so we were looking
Speaker 9:  at, okay, is there a good software that will help us do this together? And
Speaker 9:  what we were looking for is something free. We didn't, you know,
Speaker 9:  we're not landscape architects, we didn't want really expensive seats on
Speaker 9:  a software program designed for total professionals I think many of whom
Speaker 9:  use like SketchUp or other things. We wanted something that was collaborative.
Speaker 9:  We could work across both of our devices and not have to have like
Speaker 9:  access is issues. There's some guarding software out there that have
Speaker 9:  like component libraries but a lot of those have like really generic plants
Speaker 9:  and not a lot of good like local ecotype and native plants.
Speaker 9:  So we wanted to be able to put our own plants
Speaker 1:  In. So in those you're kind of like dragging clip art onto a thing
Speaker 1:  with some of those. Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 9:  So we needed to be able to put our own plants into the system
Speaker 9:  and you know a lot of times you do this fantasy gardening
Speaker 9:  and then you're outside and you have to actually place the plants and so
Speaker 9:  we wanted something that had a reasonably good mobile experience and so
Speaker 9:  that is how we landed upon the weird choice of actually Figma
Speaker 9:  was good enough for us to do all of the things we wanted to do in the free
Speaker 9:  version of Figma pretty quickly.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Was there a, was there a another set of
Speaker 1:  possibilities that you almost came to? 'cause I feel like with that number
Speaker 1:  of constraints, I can't actually think of all that many things that
Speaker 1:  would work.
Speaker 9:  You know, I looked at some Reddits for like what are, what is gardening
Speaker 9:  software? There's some that are owned by like plant
Speaker 9:  manufacturers but that's where you run into like the plant library
Speaker 9:  isn't deep enough. There's some cool startups doing interesting things in
Speaker 9:  this place, in this space. I'm gonna be real with you. I did not do an
Speaker 9:  exhaustive research of all the software before Phil and I were like,
Speaker 9:  you know what actually what about Figma? And Figma was good enough to do
Speaker 9:  all the things we wanted to do. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Were you good at Figma going in? Because I feel like Figma
Speaker 1:  Figma slightly terrifies me. I'm pretty good at like moving around in
Speaker 1:  Figma but even that took some work and the idea of like really setting this
Speaker 1:  thing up successfully is slightly terrifying.
Speaker 9:  No, I think key to this is that I am not expert in Figma. Okay. All of where
Speaker 9:  I am in Figma usually is reviewing design files that someone else has created.
Speaker 9:  The Verge has an incredibly talented design team and So
Speaker 9:  I've looked at plenty of Will Joel's Figma. Yeah. And I was like if Will
Speaker 9:  Joel thinks Figma is good enough, it's probably good enough for me. But key
Speaker 9:  to this is I am not a Figma pro and you can get pretty far in
Speaker 9:  garden design with like very little specific Figma
Speaker 9:  expertise.
Speaker 1:  That's, that's good. That's encouraging to hear. So this is tough
Speaker 1:  to do on a podcast for a visual design application that you're talking about,
Speaker 1:  but describe the Figma a little bit. What is it, how does it actually work?
Speaker 9:  Okay, so you make a free Figma count, it's very easy. You start a new project
Speaker 9:  that's very easy. It works exactly like you would think. It's the one pain
Speaker 9:  in the ass. Part of this whole process is
Speaker 9:  importing your plan and determining a scale. Unlike
Speaker 9:  a architecture design program, Figma does not work in
Speaker 9:  like inches or some of the conventions of like one eighth
Speaker 9:  inch printed equals whatever. Like that's not how Figma works. Figma
Speaker 9:  works in pixels. So you have to arbitrarily kind of set up
Speaker 9:  your place in what you are working and decide what your scale
Speaker 9:  is gonna be. What we did is we took a PDF of
Speaker 9:  our home design. It was pretty basic. A lot of people might have this from
Speaker 9:  a real estate listing of your house. If you ever did work on your house,
Speaker 9:  if you're not planning something that's like a foundation bed around your
Speaker 9:  house, you could blue sky it. But we ended up coming with the
Speaker 9:  arbitrary rule that 10 pixels would equal one inch.
Speaker 9:  Most plant stuff in the United States seems to be in inches. So
Speaker 9:  this will have a 12 inch spread, this will have a 24 inch spread. If you
Speaker 9:  live in Europe, you would pick something different based on metric.
Speaker 9:  So the most pain in the ass part is taking a
Speaker 9:  PDF, which Figma does not recognize. You have to convert it to A PNG
Speaker 9:  or jpeg and then import it into Figma. Sure we did that in Photoshop.
Speaker 9:  You put it in and then you take something where you know the length is
Speaker 9:  and you set that to the scale you want. So if there's a wall of your house,
Speaker 9:  you could go measure it and say this wall is 14 feet wide,
Speaker 9:  therefore if my scale is 10 pixels
Speaker 9:  equals 12 inches, I know how
Speaker 9:  much that needs to be. I set that scale and then
Speaker 9:  everything from now on exists in that scale. One thing
Speaker 9:  that's nice about Figma is when you specify links, for example,
Speaker 9:  you can do math in the like field where you use a little
Speaker 9:  star thing to say like 10 times 12 and it'll
Speaker 9:  just do the math for you. So as you're converting into the pixel thing, you
Speaker 9:  could actually do math directly there, but that's the hardest part of the
Speaker 9:  whole system is importing the drawing of your house or your lot.
Speaker 9:  You could use a Google Earth image of your lot as you're opening place.
Speaker 9:  People do all kinds of things but setting that scale is the hardest
Speaker 9:  part where you take one known measurement, you determine
Speaker 9:  what it should be in pixel land and then you have to do all of your planning
Speaker 9:  with that in mind.
Speaker 1:  Okay. But then at the end of it all, you have something like a rendering
Speaker 1:  of your whole space and then you can just start to populate it as you
Speaker 1:  like.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, exactly. Okay, so you get a background image then you're planning against
Speaker 9:  that and things when you, we'll talk about like when you get to planting
Speaker 9:  plants, but what you're generally thinking about is like how big is
Speaker 9:  this plant gonna spread therefore how do I space it when I'm planting?
Speaker 1:  Oh yeah. So okay, this is the thing about gardening. This is why I'm bad
Speaker 1:  at gardening because I just like, I'm looking outside, we have a a big
Speaker 1:  like raised planter out on our patio and it's like beautiful and made of
Speaker 1:  brick and we were like oh cool, we'll plant a bunch of stuff in there. We
Speaker 1:  planted it all as it turned out too close together and it all immediately
Speaker 1:  died. Super cool by us. Really happy about that.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. You know there's different philosophies of how to think about
Speaker 9:  plant spread. I generally plant things slightly tighter than
Speaker 9:  like the nursery will tell you because I don't like weeding and I don't like
Speaker 9:  looking at mulch. So there can be advantages
Speaker 9:  to packing a little bit tighter. That being said, especially if it's perennial,
Speaker 9:  it may get much, much bigger and you should think about the future.
Speaker 1:  Yes, that's a good rule of thumb. So tell me about the, the inserting of
Speaker 1:  plants I'm now obsessed with. Like you're not happy with the clip art plants,
Speaker 1:  you want your own. Yes. Are you, are you going in and like
Speaker 1:  painstakingly drawing each plant that you might wanna, how do you do this?
Speaker 9:  So this is very easy. So I use the ellipsis tool and I draw circles
Speaker 9:  and I draw the circles to the width of a
Speaker 9:  mature plant. Okay. So if the plant is going to be 12 inches, I draw a
Speaker 9:  120 pixel circle very easy.
Speaker 9:  That's what it spread is going to be. Then if you're using
Speaker 9:  what I do, which is the browser version of Figma,
Speaker 9:  that's free, you can go and say okay, I wanna plant
Speaker 9:  RIS blazing star, nice native plant. I can just go to Google photos,
Speaker 9:  copy a photo there, open Figma up, click the ellipsis
Speaker 9:  paste and it will fill that little circle with an image of that
Speaker 9:  plant. So if I care about textures and I care about colors,
Speaker 9:  I'm gonna have that image there and then I have a little
Speaker 9:  plant. Now to be practical, what I don't
Speaker 9:  wanna have to do is like go copy and paste that a bunch of times maybe I
Speaker 9:  find out I wanna plant a different variety of lely actress and it has a
Speaker 9:  different spread. So you can do something where you right click the ellipsis
Speaker 9:  and you set it up as a component. So there is like, oh okay,
Speaker 9:  a parent object and I place all of my parent
Speaker 9:  objects in like a corner of my canvas that's like my
Speaker 9:  key and I name what it is. So I have the thing,
Speaker 9:  I have a little circle that has a picture of what the foliage looks like.
Speaker 9:  It has the name of the plant and it's set to the right mature diameter in
Speaker 9:  a little like component library key. And then I can just copy paste it
Speaker 9:  in as I'm actually laying out plants.
Speaker 1:  I feel like you're describing something that is like sneakily a perfect use
Speaker 1:  for generative AI where I just wanna like you're, you're like just describe
Speaker 1:  the plant that you think it's going to be and just let it appear there and
Speaker 1:  I'm like this is what all the image systems should be doing.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. You know there's, well I'll say there's like limitations to this and
Speaker 9:  maybe this is where AI can come in is like what I'm talking about is doing
Speaker 9:  a two dimensional planting plan. Fair. Another thing you have to
Speaker 9:  worry about when you're gardening is the height of your plant. This is not
Speaker 9:  going to do height for you so you're gonna have to
Speaker 9:  pay attention or have enough knowledge of how tall things grow.
Speaker 9:  You're also not going to get seasonality out of this. So
Speaker 9:  things bloom at different times of the year. So If you were
Speaker 9:  really psychotic, what you could do is take your garden plan
Speaker 9:  once you've built it in Figma, choose all of the photos that you've
Speaker 9:  used for your plants of like springtime that make a total duplicate
Speaker 9:  of this and replace all the photos with what they look like in June
Speaker 9:  and then again in like September. But that would be
Speaker 9:  really crazy and I would say again this is not perfect,
Speaker 9:  we are just aiming for good enough for an amateur gardener. Okay.
Speaker 1:  I do feel like 2026 Helen is gonna come on and tell me about like
Speaker 1:  how you bought a vision pro to do this. So now you can see it all spatially
Speaker 1:  and actually map it in real time as you're walking through the garden and
Speaker 1:  like I feel like that's where we're headed and that is the best possible
Speaker 1:  outcome here.
Speaker 9:  No, I mean what this, yes David, that could be the beautiful future and
Speaker 9:  I'm sure there's actually a bunch of cool startup garden design apps.
Speaker 9:  Maybe. Probably are. How big is your market size of amateur gardeners
Speaker 9:  with lots of enthusiasm trapped in winter, only
Speaker 9:  using your software for two months of the year.
Speaker 9:  But no, I mean the, the end output you get here is you get an
Speaker 9:  image of your house or your garden bed, which is your background canvas.
Speaker 9:  You get a little key of all the plants in one place. That's where
Speaker 9:  you've arranged all of your components and then in your little gardening
Speaker 9:  beds that you've drawn it, you can see how you plan to space this out,
Speaker 9:  how you think layering and interspersing plants should work. And then you
Speaker 9:  can go count how many of these did it take for me to fill this bed? This
Speaker 9:  is how many I need to buy before I go put my garden
Speaker 9:  in. So it gets you, again not a
Speaker 9:  professional garden plan, but it gets you like good enough for an
Speaker 9:  average person who can use basic software.
Speaker 1:  I love this. What's the big garden upgrade for 2025? What are you working
Speaker 1:  on right now?
Speaker 9:  Ooh, we planted a bunch of native plants actually in the fall this
Speaker 9:  year, which turned out to be terrible timing because it was a big drought.
Speaker 9:  So please root for me. So this year is gonna be
Speaker 9:  more about observing how all of the stuff we've already planted now
Speaker 9:  comes up, how it looks. I'm big into like converting
Speaker 9:  grass to meadow
Speaker 9:  that I would say I'm not planning a Figma meadow is just chaos.
Speaker 9:  It is a battle, a constant battle with invasives.
Speaker 9:  Native plant meadows are more of a battleground. They're not a planned ecosystem.
Speaker 1:  AI can't solve that yet.
Speaker 9:  AI can't solve that. Phil does constantly pitch
Speaker 9:  robotics for invasives removal and also dealing
Speaker 9:  with some of the problems we now have of invasive pests. So
Speaker 9:  there's something called the jumping worm, which is exactly what you think
Speaker 9:  it is. It's a worm that jumps. Oh dear. Which is one really gross.
Speaker 9:  It's not fun to have in your land if you're gardening, but also they
Speaker 9:  really deplete the nutrients from the soil. It's pretty bad and they're
Speaker 9:  spreading and no one knows what to do about it. And this maybe is like an
Speaker 9:  ideal application for robotics
Speaker 9:  who have enough AI that they could identify and zap jumping
Speaker 9:  worms. Now how you do that without like starting a fire or
Speaker 9:  accidentally zapping other worms? Big question.
Speaker 9:  And then you can really get into like deep in the like
Speaker 9:  what invasives are bad, what invasives are good. No,
Speaker 9:  earthworm is native to the United States, for example, but they're fine.
Speaker 9:  They're good with
Speaker 1:  'em exist. Yeah. I do feel like you, you've just inadvertently started an
Speaker 1:  annual tradition, which is that you and I are gonna come on here once a year
Speaker 1:  and we're going to review the whole sweep of technology based on how capably
Speaker 1:  robots can solve your garden for you. 'cause that's, that's where we're headed.
Speaker 1:  It's like everybody wants the robot gardens to be possible. Yeah. Nature
Speaker 1:  is complicated. This, this is, this is the future. It
Speaker 9:  Seems like robot lawn mowers are getting generally better.
Speaker 9:  I've seen them at some botanical gardens. We're very curious about
Speaker 9:  lawn RBAs. I hear Jen's working on something though, so hold, hold off and
Speaker 9:  see if Jen tells you whether to buy it or not. There's a lot at C. Yes, I'm
Speaker 9:  skeptical.
Speaker 1:  There will be a lot. I will say I've only heard a little bit about what Jen's
Speaker 1:  working on when she's finished. She's gonna come on and we have a whole thing
Speaker 1:  planned, but I don't necessarily think it's going super well. So
Speaker 1:  everybody pray for Jen on that front. All right Helen,
Speaker 1:  we're gonna get some emails so I'm gonna pass 'em on. If you have tips for
Speaker 1:  Helen on her garden planning software, vergecast at VERGE dot com,
Speaker 1:  we'll pass them all along and we will do this again next winter.
Speaker 9:  I'll try and finally publish a how to in January.
Speaker 1:  Love it. Everyone needs this. It's, this is, I'm gonna get back into it for
Speaker 1:  two weeks like I do every year and it's gonna be incredible.
Speaker 9:  It's very niche. There's like three people like myself who
Speaker 9:  really need this.
Speaker 1:  Oh, I don't know. Again, the response to the off-handed thing you said last
Speaker 1:  week would, would speak differently, but, but we'll see. All right Helen,
Speaker 1:  thank you as always. Thanks
Speaker 9:  David. Have a good one.
Speaker 1:  Alright, that's it for the first cast today. Thank you to everyone who came
Speaker 1:  on the show and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on Everything
Speaker 1:  we talked about, including the information about the CES Vergecast
Speaker 1:  Wednesday, January 8th, links in the show notes. I'll put all the links to
Speaker 1:  everything in the show notes, all of our Google coverage. If Helen will let
Speaker 1:  me share her Figma, I'll put it in there too, but you never know. We'll see.
Speaker 1:  And as always, read the website, keep your feedback coming. We love hearing
Speaker 1:  from all of you. Call the hotline. Eight six six VERGE one, one. Email us
Speaker 1:  vergecast at The Verge dot com. We have one more episode to come for this
Speaker 1:  year, and then we're taking a little break before CES, but we are not done
Speaker 1:  yet with 2024. This show is produced by Liam James, Wil Poor and
Speaker 1:  Eric Gomez. Vergecast is VERGE Production and part of the Vox Media podcast
Speaker 1:  network. Neli, and I'll be back on Friday with a
Speaker 1:  bit of a surprise. But if you've been listening for a while, I suspect you
Speaker 1:  know exactly what it's, we'll see you then. I rock and roll
Speaker 5:  That. That would be a delightful punk album.
Speaker 5:  Multimodal agents.
Speaker 1:  Multimodal Agents is, that's pretty good.
Speaker 2:  Hey, it's Liam from Decoder with Neli Patel. We spent a lot of time talking
Speaker 2:  about some of the most important people in tech and business about what they're
Speaker 2:  putting resources to and why they think it's so critical for the future.
Speaker 2:  That's why we're doing this special series. Diving into some of the most
Speaker 2:  unique ways companies are spending money today, for instance, what
Speaker 2:  does it mean to start buying and using AI at work? How much is that
Speaker 2:  costing companies? What products are they buying and most importantly, what
Speaker 2:  are they doing with it? And of course, podcasts. Yes. The thing you're listening
Speaker 2:  to right now, well, it's increasingly being produced directly by
Speaker 2:  companies like venture capital firms, investment funds, and a new crop of
Speaker 2:  creators who one day want to be investors themselves. And what is actually
Speaker 2:  going on with these acquisitions this year, especially in the AI space.
Speaker 2:  Why are so many big players in tech deciding not to acquire and
Speaker 2:  instead licensed tech and hire away co-founders? The answer it turns
Speaker 2:  out is a lot more complicated than it seems. You'll hear all that and
Speaker 2:  more this month on decoder with Eli Patel presented by Stripe.
Speaker 2:  You can listen to decoder wherever you get your podcasts.