# Transcript
ID: bd0fd599-46e6-458b-9305-faf138e0a130
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5399372673158423358/-2385877240358069771/s93290-US-5777s-1725840295.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss previews for the Apple event, gadgets at IFA, the latest with Snap, and a whole lot more.
Speaker 3:  society. There are no members,
Speaker 4:  The wrongest one we've ever done. I was like, I don't
Speaker 5:  Wanna be a member of that. I don't want that
Speaker 3:  Flagship. We're still looking for our first member If. you could sign up
Speaker 3:  today. That would be much appreciated, but we are not
Speaker 3:  in it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, you have to join. We just cover the society. We are not members of
Speaker 4:  the Society.
Speaker 3:  We're the official podcast of the fine Woven Appreciation Society, but we,
Speaker 3:  we've never joined. Hi, I'm friend Eli David. Pierce is here. Hello.
Speaker 3:  Alex Kranz is here. Hey, what's up? This is a big one. This is the Apple
Speaker 3:  iPhone preview episode. Next week is the event. A
Speaker 3:  bunch of us will be there. David noted out.
Speaker 4:  That's largely correct.
Speaker 3:  David was like, screw it. I've seen these phones before. The rectangles,
Speaker 3:  he said angrily.
Speaker 3:  But there's a lot of talk about we're expecting a new iPhone, a new watch,
Speaker 3:  AirPods. We're gonna talk about all the rumors, all the things we're expecting.
Speaker 3:  It's also IFA in Germany.
Speaker 3:  They've covered this thing for 15 years. I'm like, it's Germany, right? We
Speaker 3:  got a team out there looking at just a wild collection of gadgets, including,
Speaker 3:  I just saw this, a laptop whose lid rotates by itself.
Speaker 4:  Whoa. Like, like rainbow room style. It just sort of slowly spins around
Speaker 4:  as
Speaker 3:  You use it. No, it's like a classic 2 1 1 where you like open it, You can
Speaker 3:  like flip it around and turn it into a tablet, but they're like, what if
Speaker 3:  that, but you didn't have to do it.
Speaker 4:  Oh, I like that.
Speaker 6:  And it goes,
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it, it doesn't, none of it seems reliable or good, but
Speaker 3:  that's right. That's what's happening in Germany today. So we, we had a whole
Speaker 3:  lightning round of gadgets and then we got another lightning round unsponsored.
Speaker 3:  Although I will say to the one person who sent us email saying, I
Speaker 3:  now have an entire corporate marketing budget. We're gonna spend your corporate
Speaker 3:  marketing budget. Yeah. This is what happens when you do a, a show for effectively
Speaker 3:  15 years. The people get jobs.
Speaker 3:  So there's there, there's some people who sent some emails. We're,
Speaker 3:  we're excited about this. Alright, we gotta talk about Apple. Let's start.
Speaker 3:  There's, there's a lot of rumors I would say,
Speaker 3:  but we're at the, the top line is they're iterating all of their core products.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's a, it's a weird moment. So you said that there's a lot of rumors
Speaker 4:  and my, my immediate reaction was like kind of,
Speaker 4:  because it, it's a weird year in the sense that if there is something
Speaker 4:  big coming, we don't know anything about it. Like there's not even,
Speaker 4:  there's not even light rumors that there might be something big and
Speaker 4:  every year there's like the, maybe this'll be, and there's just none of that.
Speaker 4:  So either this is gonna be a pretty straightforward Apple event
Speaker 4:  or we actually don't have that much information and I, so obviously I
Speaker 4:  hope it's the second thing.
Speaker 6:  It's kind of rude though because like action button on all models, that feels
Speaker 6:  like a big deal. No
Speaker 4:  It doesn't. That's it.
Speaker 6:  I don't have an action button on it. So it does,
Speaker 3:  It's huge for me. What I meant by a lot of rumors, I didn't mean
Speaker 3:  a lot of important rumors. I just meant the volume of rumors
Speaker 3:  is high. Yes. The number of things that people are saying will happen
Speaker 3:  is larger than normal in my opinion.
Speaker 4:  I think that's right.
Speaker 3:  But none of them add up to like earth shattering.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Except for the action button, which If you are on an iPhone
Speaker 6:  14 pro like I am is very exciting of
Speaker 3:  All of the rumored buttons. You think it's that one?
Speaker 4:  Okay. Wait, can we actually talk about this for a second? Yeah. So I, I posted
Speaker 4:  on the site the other day a really great shortcut that someone uses,
Speaker 4:  I'm sorry, I'm forgetting who it was, where they had set it up so that
Speaker 4:  like, they figured out quicker than I did. That You can use the action button
Speaker 4:  to open the camera and then again to take a picture. So You can use it like
Speaker 4:  as a basically press and hold and then press and you have immediately taken
Speaker 4:  a picture. I think that's awesome. I So I posted this on the site being like,
Speaker 4:  this is a really cool use of the action button. Do you use the action button?
Speaker 4:  And the overwhelming response I got from people is I never ever, ever, ever
Speaker 4:  use the action button because I, that it existed. I don't care about it at
Speaker 4:  all. So Neli, you I know. Set it up to do a
Speaker 4:  chat GPT thing. Do you actually like use the action button all the time?
Speaker 3:  It's, it has reached gimmick status.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So
Speaker 3:  We should just contextualize this. What I say of all of the rumor buttons,
Speaker 3:  they're rumored to be adding a camera button, a dedicated camera button
Speaker 3:  to the pro, and then bring the action button to all the models. So we'll
Speaker 3:  get to that. My use of action right now is, it's linked to the chat GBT
Speaker 3:  shortcut where you press it and it's slow. I I,
Speaker 3:  there's nothing about this. It's fast. You press it, chat GBT launches, it
Speaker 3:  flashes up some message. It's like checking connection and then a wheel spins
Speaker 3:  and you're, it's already gone. You've already been like, I don't care about
Speaker 3:  the question I was gonna ask anymore. And then You can ask it a question
Speaker 3:  and it can listen to you. That's a little dicey as well. If you're in a loud
Speaker 3:  environment or people are talking, it's not great at that. But the thing
Speaker 3:  at the end of all that, you ask it a question, natural language, and then
Speaker 3:  it just tells you an answer in natural language. And sometimes that answer
Speaker 3:  is a pure hallucination and sometimes it's not. And You can close that window
Speaker 3:  and just read it, which is much faster than listening to the voice. And all
Speaker 3:  of that feels like a little glimpse into the future. I'll give you an example.
Speaker 3:  Max and I are playing Untitled Goose game together, which is amazing. Extraordinarily
Speaker 3:  fun. If, you don't know this game. It came out years ago. You're, you're
Speaker 3:  just a a, you know, a Ms. Grant Goose just getting
Speaker 3:  into trouble, just honking at stuff. It's enormously
Speaker 3:  fun. It's like Grand Theft Auto, but you're a goose. I don't know how else
Speaker 3:  to describe it. That's perfect.
Speaker 4:  That belongs in that category of games that there is no way to say it in
Speaker 4:  words. That sounds good. Yeah. But yet it is amazing. But
Speaker 3:  If, you have a, like a 6-year-old, you're like, this is a great video game.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like one you usually like run around honking at stuff. Yeah, it's great
Speaker 3:  rules. So we're having fun and I, we couldn't figure out some puzzle and
Speaker 3:  I just asked Chad g bt like, where is this thing in this game? and it
Speaker 3:  just told me the answer with like bullets. That's cool. And there's a whole
Speaker 3:  universe of moral complaints you could lodge at opening Eye for scraping
Speaker 3:  all of the work and all of the labor of a million video game journalists
Speaker 3:  who publish the explainers and it's all in the background, but the thing
Speaker 3:  just worked. And so that is really something. There's something there and
Speaker 3:  I, I hope all the people get paid for all their work in whatever way.
Speaker 3:  But that one use of the action button to me is the most important use of
Speaker 3:  the action button. Like can you have a natural
Speaker 3:  language voice assistant? Can you actually add a new kind of
Speaker 3:  input mechanism to a computer? Yeah. If, and, and that
Speaker 3:  one's really janky and weird, but You can very, very clearly see how oh
Speaker 3:  You can make that a million times better. And I think we're, we're expecting
Speaker 3:  to see Apple add these features to Siri. I don't know if it'll be on this
Speaker 3:  phone or at this event, but You can just see how it's gonna get there.
Speaker 6:  So. I. I think the reason I'm excited about it's 'cause of the books Palmer,
Speaker 6:  it also has a button like this You can program and because I have one
Speaker 6:  I've actually used it. We, God
Speaker 3:  Did we catch the books? Palm
Speaker 6:  So I. I'm So. I'm speed running. I'm speed running today.
Speaker 3:  Seven minutes since we started the show. Alright,
Speaker 6:  We haven't gotten into the remarkable yet. Don't worry. I'm ready. But
Speaker 6:  with, with the action button, can you do like just go to home or go to
Speaker 6:  use it as a back button?
Speaker 3:  No. So, I I, I You can set it to run shortcuts and then You can shut it,
Speaker 3:  set it to run like what, five or six different system level things like turn
Speaker 3:  on the flashlight. Yeah. I don't think it has os level navigational
Speaker 3:  capabilities.
Speaker 6:  Nevermind. I'm less excited this but
Speaker 3:  Sucks. I think maybe with some of the assistive features in
Speaker 3:  iOS you might be able to do some of this stuff but it's not like top level
Speaker 3:  functionality. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  You could probably rig up a shortcut to go home's, but that's a deeply weird
Speaker 4:  use case. Yes. But I think, yeah like back as a system gesture.
Speaker 4:  I'm not sure you could do. Maybe you could but again that would be a like
Speaker 4:  weird shortcut hack that's not just sort of a thing that You can, You can
Speaker 4:  attach
Speaker 3:  To or it's buried in some, some set of assistant technology. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 3:  Specific technology configurations And a lot of times what Apple does, which
Speaker 3:  I think is really interesting and and honestly really cool, they pioneer
Speaker 3:  or they test new ways of using the products
Speaker 3:  as assistive technologies first and then they bring them to everyone. 'cause
Speaker 3:  you know the, the thing to say about assistive technology is, is making things
Speaker 3:  more accessible is actually better for everybody. So the things like
Speaker 3:  pinchy pinch on the watch started out as an assistive technology.
Speaker 3:  There's a bunch of other stuff across iOS that start off as assistive technology
Speaker 3:  and there's like a lot of them. Yeah like
Speaker 6:  The mouse on the iPad started
Speaker 3:  Great. The mouse definitely. That's a great
Speaker 4:  One. The double tap on the back to do stuff is also another one that started
Speaker 4:  as an assisted thing. There's a lot of it that starts.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, there's a lot for, so it's like there's, that system is so configural
Speaker 3:  I'm not a, I'm just saying I'm not a hundred percent sure but if it was gonna
Speaker 3:  be somewhere it would be in there. I think Yeah
Speaker 4:  That makes
Speaker 3:  Sense. But it's, they've limited what You can do with the action button into
Speaker 3:  the system level. So just a handful of things. And then You can run shortcuts
Speaker 3:  so when I push it, it runs the chat GPT shortcut. Right.
Speaker 3:  Which is fine but it's not like I push it and the computer
Speaker 3:  knows what I want as it's like I'm gonna run the shortcut that opens this
Speaker 3:  other thing.
Speaker 4:  This is where I say again that shortcuts is a failed experiment and
Speaker 4:  Apple should be ashamed of itself for not doing better with shortcuts. Yes.
Speaker 4:  'cause what you just said is either You can do one of four things or you
Speaker 4:  have to have a master's degree in computer engineering to be able to do anything
Speaker 4:  else with your phone. Well
Speaker 3:  What's supposed to happen, well to be clear, what's supposed to happen is
Speaker 3:  the, the app developer ship the shortcuts, right? So the the My chat GB shortcut
Speaker 3:  is from OpenAI, right? They're like here it is, we've added it to your system
Speaker 3:  library shortcuts. And what they want you to do is map it to the action button.
Speaker 3:  So like they're using the the pathway to get to
Speaker 3:  that button that Apple provides. But you still have to know a bunch of things
Speaker 3:  about shortcuts and it OpenAI built the shortcut and it is there and You
Speaker 3:  can, instead of being like I'm looking at the list of things it
Speaker 3:  can do and one of them is open chat GPT.
Speaker 4:  Right? Right. Exactly. Like there's a, one of the things that You can do
Speaker 4:  on the Mac that I think is the better version of this is basically just
Speaker 4:  walk it through a menu set. Like You can set up a keyboard shortcut to anything,
Speaker 4:  any menu in any app on a Mac just by saying I want it to be
Speaker 4:  this command. I'm like that's how shortcuts should work and it just doesn't.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's kind of like that. Just way more complicated. So
Speaker 3:  I'm looking at the actual list of the action button by the way it's You can
Speaker 3:  turn on silent and ring, which is the classic Mute switch. Mute
Speaker 4:  Button. Yeah. Boring
Speaker 3:  You can switch a focus mode, which is one of those features that other
Speaker 3:  people are super into or do not care about.
Speaker 3:  Classic. And by the way, focus months have been this way since like Paulo
Speaker 3:  List devices 'cause that's where they came from. So.
Speaker 4:  I have mine set up to turn Do not disturb on and off. And actually that was
Speaker 4:  great. Basically just as like a shut my phone up thing I like I
Speaker 4:  changed nothing in Do not Disturb except I turn all the notifications and
Speaker 4:  sounds off.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So you You can and the idea that you're gonna push a hard button on
Speaker 3:  your phone to switch focus modes is like very fascinating to me. But sure
Speaker 3:  You can watch the camera which is, I think this is the reason everybody sets
Speaker 3:  it to camera 'cause of the default choices, it's the thing that makes the
Speaker 3:  most sense for the most people. For sure. You can have it turn on the flashlight,
Speaker 3:  which is just like if you're If, you wanna seem like an old dad.
Speaker 3:  Set that button to flashlight. You can launch voice memo, which is cool.
Speaker 3:  You can run the translator. There's a magnifier which was fun to play with
Speaker 3:  for a day. And then it turned out You can do a shortcut and then You can
Speaker 3:  add the other accessibility features or You can set us no action. So just
Speaker 3:  of these choices, I think it makes sense why
Speaker 3:  camera is by far the most important one. Yeah. and it also why
Speaker 3:  it makes sense that am Apple is rumored to be adding a dedicated camera button
Speaker 3:  to the pro phone. But the,
Speaker 4:  So this is the reason I ask though is because I think we're at a
Speaker 4:  such a deep point of maturity with these devices that again this is
Speaker 4:  purely anecdotal just based on my own experience of talking to other people.
Speaker 4:  But I don't think the attach rate of the action button is that high.
Speaker 4:  And I think in part because it's the button that is too high on the phone.
Speaker 4:  Like I will die on that hill. They put the button in the wrong place. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But partly it's just because we all know how to do all those things on our
Speaker 4:  phones already. Right. And if I launch the camera a hundred times
Speaker 4:  a day,
Speaker 4:  Learning a new pathway to get there is actually more work than
Speaker 4:  it's cracked up to be. And I think one of the things that Apple is doing
Speaker 4:  this year with its software is making all those bits and pieces more
Speaker 4:  customizable. So You can do more stuff in the control center and You can
Speaker 4:  do more stuff on the lock screen and You can change the two things at the
Speaker 4:  bottom that were flashlight and camera. Now those are customizable and Apple
Speaker 4:  has this idea that like, okay, we're gonna give more people more tools to
Speaker 4:  do stuff however they want. And I wonder how big the group of
Speaker 4:  people who are going to make those changes and be thrilled about them is
Speaker 4:  versus the number of people who are just like, you know what, we're
Speaker 4:  17 years into the iPhone, I kind of know how to do things. None
Speaker 4:  of this actually matters. And I think the camera button is gonna be the most
Speaker 4:  interesting version of that because if the rumors are true, it's not just
Speaker 4:  gonna be a shutter button, it's actually gonna be like pressure sensitive.
Speaker 4:  So you'll be able to like press once to press half press to focus and then
Speaker 4:  press to take the photo, which is like a genuine
Speaker 4:  value add on top of anything You can do on the phone. Now it's just janky
Speaker 4:  to
Speaker 3:  Do it. They also, there's a rumor that it'll be touch sensitive for Zoom.
Speaker 3:  So You can slide your finger back. Oh
Speaker 4:  I didn't see that. That's
Speaker 6:  Cool. Wait, they're gonna put
Speaker 4:  In If. you can slide on it to Zoom. Yeah
Speaker 3:  That is the rumor. Like I said, there's a lot of rumors I
Speaker 6:  Wait but Apple's gonna put in like a fancy button
Speaker 6:  but no headphone jack. Like they, they found the room
Speaker 6:  for the button. Did that just to hurt me Alex? I did. I did.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean at this point the If, you
Speaker 3:  believe that the future of this, the technology industry is multimodal
Speaker 3:  AI then having immediate access to a camera so the phone
Speaker 3:  can look at things. If, you believe the future of the industry is ar having
Speaker 3:  immediate access to the phone, You can see why you're like, okay, I need,
Speaker 3:  I need to make this a button. Yeah. What's harder to understand is why the
Speaker 3:  action button persists if the adoption rate is so low. Yeah. and it, it's
Speaker 3:  like funny to me that one of those options isn't just open an app.
Speaker 3:  Right. If I had a button on my phone that just open threes, I'd be this button
Speaker 3:  rules.
Speaker 4:  Well and You can do that with shortcuts. Right. But this is, this is where
Speaker 4:  I go back to like shortcuts as a experiment.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You have to dive through this other system as opposed to, I don't know,
Speaker 3:  like I think a lot of people tend to use like one app a lot.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And the idea that this, you can't just like make this button open that
Speaker 3:  app from the jump from your lock screen is kinda weird. And I, I think it's
Speaker 3:  Apple is just sort of restricting that a little
Speaker 3:  too much. And so I'm hopeful that what we see is the action button gets more
Speaker 3:  useful in one way and they move all the camera usage
Speaker 3:  to the other button. Mm.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Because otherwise it's the touch bar again, isn't it?
Speaker 3:  Otherwise you're gonna have two camera buttons on your phone. Like I Yeah,
Speaker 3:  there's just gonna be a lot of people with pro phones who have effectively
Speaker 3:  two camera buttons on their phone.
Speaker 4:  Right.
Speaker 6:  They're like, this one's when I'm feeling spicy. This one when I'm feeling
Speaker 6:  not spicy.
Speaker 4:  This is the Nudies button and the non nudies button. Wow guys.
Speaker 3:  I mean I was 18 I I believe that there's gonna be like password protected.
Speaker 4:  So there we go. We did it.
Speaker 3:  We finally understand what's driving iPhone development. It's these two.
Speaker 3:  We'll be announcing some subscription offerings later in the show.
Speaker 3:  So those are the, the highlight features of the, the two buttons coming to
Speaker 3:  the fence. Like I think that's what everyone is expecting. That's the leaks.
Speaker 3:  We've seen case leaks where the case manufacturers are having to deal with
Speaker 3:  this potential capacitive touch sensitive button on the pro phones.
Speaker 3:  Then obviously we're seeing camera upgrades
Speaker 3:  potentially a new ultra wide camera on the Pro, potentially a big Zoom upgrade
Speaker 3:  on the Pro Max I would say, the thing that I'm looking for most
Speaker 3:  is processing upgrades. I don't know if Apple's gonna talk about this.
Speaker 3:  I think iPhone photos are, they're, they're just starting to look a little
Speaker 3:  wild. And I think people are noticing, I think like lots of people are
Speaker 3:  noticing, I think we talked to the Hali developers
Speaker 3:  process Zero, their like minimal processing
Speaker 3:  system in that app is like a huge hit. And I think
Speaker 3:  it's just people are like, oh, photos with shadows are pretty good.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like what if my photo looked the way I thought it was gonna look when
Speaker 4:  I took it? Like what a crazy idea that would be.
Speaker 3:  So I'm, I'm really curious to see if Apple responds to any of this anyway.
Speaker 3:  'cause the trend for all of these cameras, I think they all kind of look
Speaker 3:  the same now and they all for a minute. Do you remember like when Google
Speaker 3:  first did the Pixel, they were talking about what artists they were inspired
Speaker 3:  by.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 3:  And like they were like paintings and shadow and use of contrast and
Speaker 3:  there was this notion that cameras would have different looks and they
Speaker 3:  were like, wait a minute, what if we do Coney Island? Yeah. And now
Speaker 3:  they're all incredibly bright. Yeah. Across the board there's like no dynamics.
Speaker 3:  So I'm just interested to see if Apple starts to dial us back. 'cause I've
Speaker 3:  heard the criticism
Speaker 3:  when the criticism is in both like Kyle Chaco writing in the New Yorker
Speaker 3:  and Alex Earl sing her beach videos look gray. Like
Speaker 3:  the criticism has hit like the full spectrum of American life.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. Well and especially for Apple, which has for so long
Speaker 4:  kind of hung its hat on being the one down the middle right. Where,
Speaker 4:  where Google and Samsung both got very kind of opinionated about what their
Speaker 4:  photos were gonna look like. Apple's whole thing was like realism and, and
Speaker 4:  and beauty and everything was gonna be great. And and their idea was like,
Speaker 4:  we're just gonna, we're gonna touch it up but we're not gonna change it.
Speaker 4:  And I feel like they've, they've tipped over that line over the last couple
Speaker 4:  of years. Particularly with the fifteens. I think. Yeah. That like, I like
Speaker 4:  the photos less on the iPhone 15 than almost any
Speaker 4:  iPhone before it. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I have an upgrade. Becky has a 13 and it used to be that I made sure she
Speaker 3:  had the new one every year. 'cause we did, what do we do? We take pictures
Speaker 3:  of her kid. Yeah. So there's like, we should always just have the best one
Speaker 3:  and we just stopped at the 13. Like it is the most restrained of
Speaker 3:  the modern ones, but it's still not that restrained. So I. I'm just curious
Speaker 3:  about this like You can, You can throw hardware specs at this
Speaker 3:  camera, but it's the processing pipeline that is actually more interesting
Speaker 3:  now. And I, I don't know how they're gonna talk about it. I don't know if
Speaker 3:  they're gonna diverge on the regular and the pro, I'm, I'm just very curious
Speaker 3:  to see where this goes. Can you
Speaker 6:  Imagine the pro like good photos, the regular is
Speaker 6:  just like no day glow. We don't believe in highlights or we, we take the
Speaker 6:  highlights crank all the way to the top.
Speaker 4:  Well honestly there's a, there's a version of that that I think is completely
Speaker 4:  possible because a bunch of the rumors about the camera are about the camera
Speaker 4:  hardware that Apple is getting increasingly good at doing
Speaker 4:  teeny tiny optical zoom lenses inside of the iPhone stack
Speaker 4:  and that it's able to actually build better optics
Speaker 4:  into the phone. And in theory if You can do better optics, You can do less
Speaker 4:  processing, which gives Apple more leeway to say we're gonna do
Speaker 4:  less in your photos are gonna still look good. Whereas If, you go down to
Speaker 4:  the base level phones, it's just not gonna be as good. And so it is by
Speaker 4:  definition gonna have to do more work. So like if Apple's gonna have a process
Speaker 4:  zero type thing, I can absolutely imagine it being a pro only
Speaker 3:  So I have heard almost the exact opposite.
Speaker 4:  Really? I just made that up. It just seems logical. But have you heard actual
Speaker 4:  stuff about this? Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I I I've just been talking to some folks and
Speaker 3:  we have to see how it goes with the new phone. You are correct that Apple's
Speaker 3:  getting better at optics, they're getting better at doing the thing inside
Speaker 3:  the phone, like building the actual camera hardware. But they're
Speaker 3:  ruthlessly optimizing it to collect as much light as they can.
Speaker 4:  Oh
Speaker 3:  Interesting. Everything else, they're kind of letting go because they can
Speaker 3:  fix it in the pipeline. So Apple's view of this is much like Google's view
Speaker 3:  is they're not building a camera. They're building a whole integrated imaging
Speaker 3:  pipeline and you know, it has some goal And. if you can
Speaker 3:  compensate for everything else except light collection,
Speaker 3:  then you should just ruthlessly prioritize light collection. 'cause that's
Speaker 3:  the thing. It's the most important thing. And then You can fix fringing
Speaker 3:  or distortion or whatever else might happen at your lens level
Speaker 3:  because you have all the light. Right. So You can, You can mathematically
Speaker 3:  correct a bunch of errors that you get in the actual hardware, but You can
Speaker 3:  never really mathematically correct for I didn't get enough light.
Speaker 4:  That's fascinating. So you're basically just turning it into like a big data
Speaker 4:  problem and it's like, okay the, the more, the more light we can throw at
Speaker 4:  this problem, the better we can do. Which I would not say makes me hopeful
Speaker 4:  for the idea that we are going to get something that looks less processed
Speaker 3:  Over time. This is why I was having this conversation. So it was right after
Speaker 3:  we published Sarah's piece about not being ready for AI image
Speaker 3:  like editing everywhere and you kind of get to this place where the
Speaker 3:  iPhone is already like kind of like doing a lot of sharpening and text and
Speaker 3:  people see the text is weird. If you over zoom on an image, You
Speaker 3:  can see it, it like invents faces in weird ways. They're not quite faces
Speaker 3:  and people are like, what is happening here? And it's like, oh, that's just
Speaker 3:  a bunch of image processing just gone awry. Yeah. And So I, I'm just very
Speaker 3:  curious with this phone in particular. Apple's not shipping
Speaker 3:  a bunch of Apple intelligence, but they're right on the cusp of it.
Speaker 3:  So this is kind of the last phone that's gonna take pictures,
Speaker 3:  right? Like straightforward pictures and then every phone after this is gonna
Speaker 3:  be like pictures with Apple intelligence or like whatever the next thing
Speaker 3:  is. And I'm just curious to see if they pull it back a little bit
Speaker 3:  so they can go forward in a different direction or if they just stay it with
Speaker 3:  the like have you seen the sky look at the sky?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean it, it all does make me think of like, do you remember that
Speaker 4:  art project we talked about? I don't know God a year or so ago that it was,
Speaker 4:  it was the camera but it didn't have a lens. But every time you hit the shutter
Speaker 4:  it would like collect your location and mapping data about where you were
Speaker 4:  in all the satellite imagery and then stitch that into a photo that feels
Speaker 4:  increasingly close to where all of this is going. Like
Speaker 3:  I would like to remind you specifically David Pierce that when I
Speaker 3:  wanted to spend five hours talking about Samsung taking photos of the moon,
Speaker 3:  you were like ba and now you have just described the moon situation.
Speaker 3:  No,
Speaker 4:  No, no. When, when you said
Speaker 3:  You
Speaker 4:  Wanted to do that, we all bought tacos and then did it at Southwest. Southwest
Speaker 4:  for an hour and
Speaker 3:  A half. Well yeah, it's true. You all right? I had to pour some tequila into
Speaker 3:  David and then we talked about yeah that's Samsung generating images of the
Speaker 3:  moon instead of taking photos of the moon philosophical conundrum because
Speaker 3:  every photo of the moon is technically exactly the same 'cause the moon doesn't
Speaker 3:  change. Right. Again, we could spend five hours talking about the
Speaker 3:  moon,
Speaker 4:  But No, but it really, all that stuff increasingly feels less like
Speaker 4:  a, a weird thing and more like just where all of this inevitably is going.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And like I said, I think this camera in particular is just a, a
Speaker 3:  moment like it is for sure that the next camera will have
Speaker 3:  a bunch of AI stuff built into it. Yes. This one, they're not shipping a
Speaker 3:  bunch of it yet. So what's it, what's it gonna be? What's, what does this
Speaker 3:  destination look like and is it the final destination?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well and Apple's already starting to do some of the, the like AI post-processing
Speaker 4:  stuff where You can move things around and remove them from photos. It's,
Speaker 4:  it has a lot of the stuff we've been talking about Google doing and I think
Speaker 4:  it's, it's gonna be really interesting to see and A how good that stuff is
Speaker 4:  on this camera and B, how close it is in the pipeline
Speaker 4:  because like Google and others have been putting it in other apps
Speaker 4:  and and making it like a slight sideline feature
Speaker 4:  Apple. We will see how quickly this becomes like just a normal part of the
Speaker 4:  image taking process. Its gonna be fascinating.
Speaker 3:  Other stuff we we're seeing rumors, again,
Speaker 3:  lots of rumors that there's gonna be colors, like saturated colors instead
Speaker 3:  of all the pale stuff. Particularly in the regular 16. I think the pro
Speaker 3:  will probably still come in some muted colors. Mark Erman thinks there's
Speaker 3:  gonna be a gold. Yeah. Have been wanting angle gold iPhone back,
Speaker 3:  some minor improvements to screens, displays of the rumor. But the big rumor
Speaker 3:  is that everything's gonna get a little bit bigger. So 6.3 on the
Speaker 3:  little iPhone and 6.9 on
Speaker 3:  on the, on the maxes, which is fascinating. You know they already do the
Speaker 3:  plus size phones at 6.7 so we will, we'll just see where they land
Speaker 3:  on a bunch of screen sizes, but I think they're trying to differentiate the
Speaker 3:  plus from the max. 'cause I, big phones are just a
Speaker 3:  thing people like as much as we complain about them, people love a big phone,
Speaker 4:  But that has to have a maximum, right? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like people's hands, right. Have maximums. Like we're not, we
Speaker 6:  can't all palm a basketball
Speaker 3:  But some of us can and
Speaker 6:  And they will have a phone finally.
Speaker 3:  Many people aspire to apparently. Well obviously
Speaker 3:  the next turn is folding,
Speaker 4:  Right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, well that's what 25, 26 I think was what they were saying.
Speaker 4:  That's what we keep hearing. Yeah. And that it might be a flip before it's
Speaker 4:  a fold because that is the correct and good thing. And flip phones are better
Speaker 4:  than full
Speaker 6:  Phones. They're both good, they're different.
Speaker 3:  I, we, there's pixel line fold in the office. Chris Walch has one and I was
Speaker 3:  looking at it the other day and I was like, this phone rules, like it is
Speaker 3:  a beautiful piece of hardware. Yeah. And I was like, they got the aspect
Speaker 3:  ratio on the front, right? And he was just like, yeah, I never unfold it.
Speaker 3:  I was like, well this is the problem.
Speaker 6:  So
Speaker 4:  Like what's funny is I was, I was at the doctor the other day
Speaker 4:  and my, when the guy checking me in found out what I did, we started
Speaker 4:  talking about tech and he had Motorola's new razor with the big
Speaker 4:  screen on the front and he said exactly the same thing. He was like, this
Speaker 4:  phone's so awesome. I never even opened it up. And I was like,
Speaker 6:  What do you have it?
Speaker 4:  You just have like an original iPhone basically.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You just want the binky of having a giant phone If you need it. Right?
Speaker 3:  Just like everyone needs has the, the binky of wanting an Android tablet.
Speaker 3:  There's one thing that's deeply reassuring in all technology. It's the state
Speaker 3:  of Android tablets that that will always work the
Speaker 3:  absolutely great that's, I mean that's the phone, those are the phone rumors,
Speaker 3:  right? We're we're expecting slightly bigger screens action button on the
Speaker 3:  regular 16 camera button on the pro, you
Speaker 3:  know, some upgrades to wifi and blah blah blah. But really it's,
Speaker 3:  we're at, we're adding buttons to everything.
Speaker 6:  They might change the camera, right? Like they might change the positions
Speaker 6:  of the cameras.
Speaker 3:  I yeah, the rumor is that they'll do that to make spatial video support better.
Speaker 3:  But like, I
Speaker 4:  Think
Speaker 6:  You don't think that's a reason?
Speaker 3:  I think they just rotate the cameras every couple years. Yeah, I think there's
Speaker 3:  just a wheel with three camera lenses on it and they spin it and they're
Speaker 3:  like, all right, that's it this year. Like it looks different now. I mean
Speaker 3:  there's, there's reasons to orient these cameras in all kinds of ways, but
Speaker 3:  I think they strive to make obvious visual changes more often than
Speaker 3:  we think because the dumb consumer
Speaker 3:  psychology is, if it looks different, you think it's different, then you
Speaker 3:  open it up and it's iOS and you're like, well nothing here has really changed.
Speaker 3:  So we'll see.
Speaker 4:  I do think there are, there are two interesting AI upgrades
Speaker 4:  that have been rumored. One is obviously the new chip.
Speaker 4:  We, we saw the M four in the iPad and that was
Speaker 4:  like a whole big AI story. The rumor for this one is that it's, it's still
Speaker 4:  gonna be Acer chips but presumably there will be a whole big like, oh my
Speaker 4:  God, look how fast it is. AI story about this one.
Speaker 4:  Yet again we're in a place where it's like when was the last time you
Speaker 4:  needed all of the horsepower of your iPhone? No one does ever for
Speaker 4:  anything. Who knows? And then the other one, the
Speaker 6:  For chatt PT.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Right. Shortcuts does take all of your processing power. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  that's real. And then the other one is a rumor I was just reading earlier
Speaker 4:  about apparently there there's some indication that there's going to be a
Speaker 4:  much improved microphone, which for me is a person who
Speaker 4:  uses Siri all the time for like reminders and random
Speaker 4:  nonsense. And if indeed Siri is going to be like the
Speaker 4:  core of Apple intelligence as a lot of people are expecting and big redesign
Speaker 4:  coming this year, like better microphone goes a really long
Speaker 4:  way towards making a lot of that stuff really work. Yeah. Which I think
Speaker 4:  would be very cool. But like the question then is like, is it have, have
Speaker 4:  you made like a very slightly better microphone or did did Apple like solve
Speaker 4:  something here that I I'm, I'm gonna be very clear,
Speaker 3:  They're gonna claim they solve something no matter what. For sure. I'll be
Speaker 3:  clear about that. But again, If, you think the future of input
Speaker 3:  is multimodal AI where the computer You can just talk to a computer
Speaker 3:  where it can see stuff. These are little upgrades that actually add up to
Speaker 3:  an idea a hundred percent the whole idea, which is there are more ways
Speaker 3:  to communicate with this computer about what you want and it will have more
Speaker 3:  ways to communicate back at you. But Apple intelligence isn't shipping it.
Speaker 3:  I mean that's actually the question we're these products right? Is you're
Speaker 3:  gonna announce new iPhones, you're gonna announce basically a bunch of iterative
Speaker 3:  upgrades that seem really nice and then the big software turn
Speaker 3:  that makes them worth buying that Apple I think is banking on driving a huge
Speaker 3:  upgrade cycle isn't gonna be here. Right? We're not
Speaker 3:  expecting that into potentially all the way into next September. Like
Speaker 3:  the rollout of iOS 18 Apple intelligence features
Speaker 3:  is just gonna take a long time. Particularly like the big ticket ones. What
Speaker 3:  now? Like what, what are we gonna get today? Like we're not getting the
Speaker 3:  apps can plug into Siri so You can talk to Siri and have it executed.
Speaker 3:  Bunch of actions across Wrap. Like that's not, that's probably a year right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So what are we gonna get today? Is it summarizing notifications? Like
Speaker 3:  I don't think that's good enough.
Speaker 4:  Those are already seeing people on the beta get the summarized
Speaker 4:  notifications is so funny 'cause it's so not
Speaker 4:  helpful. Yeah. Like so many of these things are like I send somebody
Speaker 4:  a 70 word long text message and it summarizes it in 58 words.
Speaker 4:  Like what if we accomplished here? Like this is nothing we're not
Speaker 4:  doing, we're not doing anything anyone. So
Speaker 6:  Copy editor is very pleased with that though. Yeah. I guess like 20 words.
Speaker 6:  That's nice. Cut.
Speaker 4:  Yeah and I think with all of this again, like we're still very much in this
Speaker 4:  place of what is any of this for right? And I think
Speaker 4:  the, the thing that has been true about Apple forever is it has done a better
Speaker 4:  job of telling the what this is for story than anybody else. And
Speaker 4:  even with the iPhone it does a very good job of explaining to you why you
Speaker 4:  need all of the incredible processing power
Speaker 4:  on your phone that you're never gonna use. It's why they have the games on
Speaker 4:  stage, it's why they did the AR stuff on there for years. Like they, they
Speaker 4:  do a very good job of being like, here is a thing we built and here's why
Speaker 4:  it's going to matter in your life. And I don't think that quite landed
Speaker 4:  at WDC
Speaker 4:  whatever did land is not shipping yet. And so like this is just
Speaker 4:  another crack at that same story for Apple and both how it has
Speaker 4:  refined that story over the last few months And whether it has figured anything
Speaker 4:  out to me is like the big question of this event. And
Speaker 3:  I'll add one more thing to it and the amount of times Apple
Speaker 3:  and other companies have shot themselves in the foot trying to tell
Speaker 3:  that story.
Speaker 4:  Totally.
Speaker 3:  Because you know, Google got in trouble with, for the Gemini ad at the Olympics
Speaker 3:  where the dad asked the AI to write a letter on behalf of a little girl to
Speaker 3:  Olympian and everyone's like, this is garbage. Like don't do this. Apple
Speaker 3:  has had a number of ad related controversies lately and then
Speaker 3:  one of their demos for summaries is Apple Intelligence
Speaker 3:  summarizing the Steve Jobs think difference speech. Oh
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's right
Speaker 3:  From the ad. You know, it's like here's the crazy ones. What like
Speaker 3:  don't, don't summarize that. Like no that's the art,
Speaker 3:  you know like even though it's a commercial, like people regard that in a
Speaker 3:  very emotional way and being like, here's what we can do now. We can make
Speaker 3:  that dumber. It's not actually the message we're trying to send. Right. And
Speaker 3:  So I think Apple's looking at all of this and saying, okay,
Speaker 3:  this is the real shot to communicate to customers. WWC is for
Speaker 3:  developers and hardcore nerds and you're listening to the show and that's
Speaker 3:  you. That's just you. But
Speaker 4:  We love you to be clear. We love you. That's
Speaker 3:  That's us.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Right. And that's the first cut where they can be technical and they can
Speaker 3:  talk about token sizes and APIs and all this stuff. They talk about wc,
Speaker 3:  the iPhone event is we're gonna put this thing on local
Speaker 3:  news broadcasts around the country to be like, look what it can do.
Speaker 3:  And they, I don't think they know besides like,
Speaker 3:  read my boss's email and give me the bullet points of it. Erase people or
Speaker 3:  Right. If I had a shortcut, if I set the shortcut button to just be like,
Speaker 3:  no, but nice I could, I could just motor through my inbox.
Speaker 3:  You know, it's actually really good. Right? Like that would be great. But
Speaker 3:  can they tell that story? Like, I don't know So I
Speaker 3:  think that's gonna be a real question 'cause the features aren't shipping
Speaker 3:  yet. Right. And so you're still kind of concocting these demos
Speaker 3:  about stuff that doesn't exist yet for a phone that might not be able to
Speaker 3:  do it. And that is I think a real puzzle. But
Speaker 6:  It also seems like they may potentially plow through a little
Speaker 6:  bit of this because we're seeing like a lot of other devices rumored like
Speaker 6:  more than I usually think of for an Apple event.
Speaker 3:  Right. So that's the phone. So I just wanted to wrap up on the phone. Like
Speaker 3:  the phone has a question mark in it, which is like how are they gonna talk
Speaker 3:  about AI features aren't there? The rest of them are,
Speaker 3:  except for the AirPods, which I think we're expecting some amount of redesign.
Speaker 3:  The Apple watch seems like a another bump. Right?
Speaker 3:  But
Speaker 6:  There may be three getting bumped.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's the one spot where it seems like if there is going to be
Speaker 4:  something new and exciting, it's gonna be in
Speaker 4:  the watch. Like there's been some, is there a, you know, apple Watch
Speaker 4:  series 10 series X
Speaker 4:  wild thing to happen? I think that there's probably not, but there's been
Speaker 4:  like a little bit of smoke around. Maybe there are some surprises in the
Speaker 4:  Apple Watch line coming this year because it's the anniversary. Well
Speaker 6:  The big rumor was that they were gonna get blood pressure monitoring or
Speaker 6:  sleep apnea detection and both of those are sound pretty
Speaker 6:  dead in the water for this year
Speaker 3:  Because they're in a giant lawsuit with the company. Yeah. Stealing because
Speaker 3:  they're
Speaker 6:  In a giant lawsuit and like blood pressure monitoring. They haven't gotten
Speaker 6:  FDA clearance or anything. Right. And and they have to, you
Speaker 6:  can't just be like, yeah we can test your blood pressure no FDA approval.
Speaker 6:  That's not gonna happen. So yeah, it sounds like they, they were trying
Speaker 6:  to line a bunch of stuff up for the, the 10, the Apple Watch 10 and it just
Speaker 6:  sort
Speaker 3:  Park. Yeah. So I guess it feels like what we're gonna get is a very minor
Speaker 3:  bump to the Ultra because basic, I mean look the, the Apple
Speaker 3:  watch has like the best lock-in story of all time. Yes. Yep. If, you have
Speaker 3:  an iPhone, You can only buy this product. That's it.
Speaker 3:  There it is. Unless you're, you know, unless you're one of the people who
Speaker 3:  wants to buy a Garmin, in which case you buy a Garmin and use it sometimes,
Speaker 3:  but then you might still have an Apple watch like good luck. Weird. Right?
Speaker 3:  So like their need to competitively upgrade these products is very
Speaker 3:  low and then the products are really good, which is just a pretty
Speaker 3:  disastrous one-two punch of wanting to see like huge upgrades.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It does seem like the, we're gonna get a bigger
Speaker 4:  regular watch to be the size of the ultra,
Speaker 4:  which is both cool and sort of alarming. Like I hate
Speaker 4:  truly hate that we are going to normalize these gigantic screens on
Speaker 4:  our wrist. Like Neli, I can read your watch through Riverside right now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I can see what's on your watch that can't pos this is not good.
Speaker 4:  How are we doing this? It's just, this is just what we
Speaker 3:  Decided. I stare down Tim Cook's watch at every event. I'm like, what,
Speaker 4:  What's
Speaker 3:  On there buddy?
Speaker 3:  Look, if they I'm at like, make the Apple watch ultra black and I'll buy
Speaker 3:  a new one, great. That's what I want. This
Speaker 4:  Might happen, this product might happen. There's been some rumors about colors.
Speaker 3:  But yeah, there there's this rumor that we'll see the Apple Watch series
Speaker 3:  10 or the Series X, which is the 10th anniversary and it have like magnetic
Speaker 3:  bands and be thinner and be the design jump. And I,
Speaker 3:  I strongly think that in a time of sort of like declining
Speaker 3:  sales and up and like upward going services revenue
Speaker 3:  that Apple's desire to do that is quite low.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Because again, the product has like perfect lock in. Like what are you gonna
Speaker 3:  do? Right? Like Tim Cook's staring you at me like, all right, you're leaving
Speaker 3:  with an iPhone, would you like to buy AppleCare a set of AirPods and an Apple
Speaker 3:  watch? 'cause you can't buy anything else.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I doubt it's very popular to first buy a watch and then
Speaker 4:  buy an iPhone. Right? So it's not like they're trying to sell some, who is
Speaker 4:  that
Speaker 6:  Person?
Speaker 4:  This is what I mean. They're not like the, the, the impetus to get people
Speaker 4:  in if you're trying to make the Apple Watch great, is you're like, okay,
Speaker 4:  there are a bunch of people who will switch for an Apple watch. And I don't
Speaker 4:  think that exists. I think like the, the Apple watch is not the first thing,
Speaker 4:  right? So, I feel like there's one, it's either the iPad or the iPhone. It
Speaker 3:  Is the first thing's one tiny category. And I'm only saying this 'cause it's
Speaker 3:  like the third day of elementary school here. Parents are buying Apple watches
Speaker 3:  for their kids who don't have phones. Fair. That's
Speaker 4:  Real
Speaker 3:  As tracking devices, it's texting devices and then you just, you're in the
Speaker 3:  ecosystem
Speaker 3:  then they got you.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's something. And that is that, that I think is like the beginning
Speaker 4:  of something potentially big and interesting,
Speaker 4:  but that feels very new and yeah.
Speaker 3:  We'll, we'll see, like I said, I, I think we're gonna see upgrades to the
Speaker 3:  Apple watch. I just think they're, it's all gonna be pretty iterative. That
Speaker 3:  is my bet. There is this rumor that you'll see the big upgrade. We'll see
Speaker 3:  how it goes. Yeah. The AirPods seem like the bigger change. Yes. Right. We're
Speaker 3:  expecting new AirPods,
Speaker 3:  AirPods four maybe AirPod, maybe new AirPods Pro.
Speaker 3:  and it seems like that's where you're gonna get the design change. And I
Speaker 3:  think that is partially because that there's still open competition there.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like You can get other Bluetooth EarPods
Speaker 4:  And there are in fact lots of really good ones out there.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So You can see a little competition is, and obviously AirPods haven't
Speaker 3:  changed in a long time, but
Speaker 6:  If they change the design, what are all of those like horrible
Speaker 6:  knockoffs at seven 11 gonna do
Speaker 4:  Immediately change. The good news about that industry is, boy it does it
Speaker 4:  adapt? Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Exactly. The, the factory in Shenzhen across from Apple's factory in
Speaker 3:  Shenzhen is on Red alert.
Speaker 3:  So AirPods four might have noise canceling.
Speaker 3:  They, they'll be more of an open ear design. They'll sit on your ear instead
Speaker 3:  of like all the way in the way that the pros do like
Speaker 4:  That, which would be a big deal, right? If the the, the A NC plus
Speaker 4:  the like hang on your ear instead of stick in it. Super hard
Speaker 4:  to do. Chris Welch was pointing out in our slack the other day that lots
Speaker 4:  of companies have tried this and basically no one has ever done it very well.
Speaker 4:  As somebody who hates the ear blocking of the AirPods Pro. Like
Speaker 4:  I just don't, I just don't like 'em. Yeah. It feels bad. My ear, they make
Speaker 4:  my ears like hot and pressure. I don't like it. So I use the hangy ones,
Speaker 4:  but then I don't get any of the noise cancellation. So if You can get, if
Speaker 4:  You can get the best of both worlds there, that's pretty awesome. Yeah. But
Speaker 4:  super hard to do. Technically
Speaker 3:  I'm looking And then the AirPods three maybe we'll see, they'll add some
Speaker 3:  more sensors to complete the health story that
Speaker 3:  Apple's trying to tell all of this stuff. Potentially a new case.
Speaker 3:  We'll see what I don't know is whether they're gonna upgrade the
Speaker 3:  AirPods Max, which they have not touched in a million years. Yeah, right.
Speaker 3:  What do they I'll use lightning.
Speaker 6:  Oh there we go. So they'll just get like A-U-S-B-C upgrade
Speaker 3:  Or they can make him not weigh 5,000 pounds. That's a choice. They
Speaker 6:  Can, they'll take out some of those weights, those Beats weights,
Speaker 3:  Those p Man, I forgot the Beats used to put weights in the headphones. They
Speaker 3:  could make the case good. There are lots of things You can do with your AirPods
Speaker 3:  mask. I
Speaker 6:  Love the little purse.
Speaker 3:  That's adorable. Hey, here, would you like your headphones to be dirty?
Speaker 6:  They sure will.
Speaker 3:  We, we've, we've forgotten to put them in a case in this case. We'll see.
Speaker 3:  I mean, you know, there's a spatial audio story to be told here, but it seems
Speaker 3:  like of all the things that we expect to change that AirPods
Speaker 3:  lineup is the most ripe for actual change. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Because it's a thing that You can, well one people lose them and then when
Speaker 3:  you lose them you might buy new headphones and when you buy new headphones
Speaker 3:  you actually have choices in the market.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well and again, if Apple is trying to tell this like big multimodal
Speaker 4:  AI story, headphones actually end up being really important. And
Speaker 4:  my big hope for AirPods Max has been that like,
Speaker 4:  that could be a place where Apple can start to do more like local AI
Speaker 4:  processing inside of your headphones. Like give me the, the AirPods
Speaker 4:  max that can do some of that stuff just inside of the headphones. Like I
Speaker 4:  want an AirPods max that has all the
Speaker 4:  software of an Apple watch in my headphones. That's, is that a bad idea?
Speaker 4:  Probably, but that's what I want. I wanna just be able to run with headphones
Speaker 4:  and nothing else. And they could do that in the max. Would
Speaker 6:  You tap on the little ear cup and send a heartbeat to your wife?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I just send my heartbeat to Neli like three or four times a day. It's
Speaker 3:  True. It's really weird. Yeah. Have you ever gotten a weird blacked out video
Speaker 3:  of just thumps and you're like, oh, David loves me.
Speaker 3:  The other rumor is, I, I sincerely doubt this will happen,
Speaker 3:  but an M four Mac mini is on the list of things I
Speaker 6:  Like. That's October. I
Speaker 3:  That's October I think. I think we'll see you Max in October. That's, that's
Speaker 3:  been the schedule, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I'll be shocked. But you know, if they don't do anything with the phone,
Speaker 6:  it would make sense to do the M four. There's
Speaker 4:  Just been a lot of smoke about the Mac Mini, which is weird. So I I
Speaker 4:  think like we're obviously due for a refresh of
Speaker 4:  MacBooks, right? The the M four is out there. It's time for
Speaker 4:  all of this from like the studio on down.
Speaker 4:  But the mini is the only one that anyone is talking about right now. Which
Speaker 4:  is maybe just like a function of the rumor mill and the way that these things
Speaker 4:  work and an October event is not that far away. So it, it could very well
Speaker 4:  be, but the, this one is particularly just sort of out in the
Speaker 4:  ether right now.
Speaker 6:  Mini's also the one that's getting a major case redesign, right? Like the
Speaker 6:  other ones aren't getting big case redesigns.
Speaker 3:  And that is that if If you believe it's gonna get a big case redesign. It
Speaker 3:  is definitely happening in October. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  That's
Speaker 3:  Good. Apple is very good at being like, look at this thing. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. One
Speaker 3:  Thing at a time.
Speaker 6:  I think it's really likely that we're just seeing a lot of smoke right now
Speaker 6:  because there's a lot of leaks because it's a whole new case, but it's gonna
Speaker 6:  happen in October. Not
Speaker 3:  That's my bet. Yeah. Is that Apple wants all of your attention to be on the
Speaker 3:  iPhone, which makes all the money and the services component of the iPhone,
Speaker 3:  which makes all the money and that is what you're gonna pay attention to.
Speaker 3:  And then in October we can talk about whether or not they're gonna make a
Speaker 3:  a M four Mac mini or a 27 inch chime mac or whatever. I'm just saying that
Speaker 3:  'cause I desperately want a new 27 in Chime mac just trying to speak it into
Speaker 3:  the world. That's
Speaker 4:  How I feel about the M four Mac mini. Like give it to me now please.
Speaker 4:  The rumor is that it's gonna be like closer to the sides of an Apple TV and
Speaker 4:  it's just gonna have a bunch of USBC ports. Like Yes, that's, yes,
Speaker 4:  that's
Speaker 6:  It. That's all you
Speaker 4:  Have to do. Inject that into my veins right now.
Speaker 6:  Make it under a thousand dollars please.
Speaker 3:  I feel like I use all the ports in this Mac mini.
Speaker 4:  Oh, I use all the ports and I have a dongle in my Mac Mini like it's, it's
Speaker 4:  a, yeah, I have
Speaker 3:  Thunderbolt four dock plugged into a Mac Mini because I use all the ports
Speaker 3:  in the Mac Mini. Yeah. All right, we'll get, I'm telling you that's October.
Speaker 3:  We'll talk about this again another time. I think you're right. That is it.
Speaker 3:  I mean that's the list of things. David, you have some prompts here to which
Speaker 3:  I will answer both with the same answer.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, this is, well, so we, we play a version of this game every year, which
Speaker 4:  is basically just before we get off the Apple stuff, we're, we're gonna
Speaker 4:  give ourselves something to be held to. So we, we each had to come up with
Speaker 4:  a prediction that you think genuinely will happen neli,
Speaker 4:  you have to think it's going to happen. Oh. That we haven't yet talked about.
Speaker 4:  And then one thing that you're desperately hoping for but have no evidence
Speaker 4:  is real. I'll go first and then, and then
Speaker 4:  just to give you guys time to, to think about this, my prediction
Speaker 4:  that I think will happen that we haven't talked about is I think we're gonna
Speaker 4:  get a Ted Lasso season four trailer. God
Speaker 6:  Dammit. That was mine.
Speaker 4:  I don't know what it's gonna be. It might just be Jason Sudeikis just like
Speaker 4:  saying four words because they haven't shot anything. This is how
Speaker 3:  We do trailers now, right? Yeah. It's like it'll be the back of his head.
Speaker 4:  I mean, do you remember the Apple event where like they all just stood on
Speaker 4:  stage and said, we're making a TV show. I made fun of that for a year and
Speaker 4:  then they made all of those shows. So the See
Speaker 6:  Apple, he's not gonna be in it very much. He's he, he
Speaker 6:  apparently like
Speaker 4:  What's he doing now? Do
Speaker 3:  You think it's gonna be called like Dead lasso?
Speaker 6:  Well the rumor is it's probably, it's gonna be about a
Speaker 6:  woman's football team.
Speaker 3:  It's really Come
Speaker 4:  On. It's just Ted Lasso in the Severance Universe. It's called Dead Lasso.
Speaker 6:  He's just dead.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, I've just, I'm just very excited about Ted
Speaker 6:  Lasso.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, but he's not gonna be there and and like any good company, they're
Speaker 3:  like, let's just go back to the, well they just
Speaker 6:  Signed all those people in the last few weeks. It feels like this is where
Speaker 6:  they're gonna answer it. Apple
Speaker 4:  Is just speed running the TV industry, right? Yeah. Like they've pissed off
Speaker 4:  George Clooney and Brad Pitt. Congratulations. Now they're bringing back
Speaker 4:  the hits. Like this is just what you do. Great job them. And then the thing
Speaker 4:  I'm desperately hoping for but have no evidence is real is I
Speaker 4:  want a cellular connected set of AirPods.
Speaker 4:  I want, I want a thing. I will switch to Apple Music you
Speaker 4:  like as God is my witness. I will switch to Apple Music. If, you just let
Speaker 4:  me stream directly to my headphones. That's all I want.
Speaker 4:  Is that a bad idea? Yes. But I want it anyway. I don't care.
Speaker 3:  Would
Speaker 6:  You, would you
Speaker 3:  Like text from it? You directly to the brain? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Just, alright, ela you go, what do you got
Speaker 3:  My prediction. One thing that I'm hoping that will happen and we haven't
Speaker 3:  talked about,
Speaker 4:  No one thing you think will happen that we haven't talked about.
Speaker 3:  Oh wait, it
Speaker 6:  Has to be real,
Speaker 3:  Right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You have to think it's gonna happen.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Apple TV home screen upgrade.
Speaker 6:  Oh,
Speaker 4:  Ooh, okay.
Speaker 6:  That's a good
Speaker 3:  They're they're due. It won't happen. They're due. It won't do, they would've
Speaker 3:  announced it at wwc, but they're way overdue
Speaker 3:  on just scooting that stuff around. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Can I just say, by the way, I bought an Apple TV because it was on sale from
Speaker 4:  Verizon for $90 for some reason plugged it into my
Speaker 4:  crappy TCL Roku tv. Set it so that it just goes straight
Speaker 4:  to that input when I turn on the TV and now suddenly my TV viewing experience
Speaker 4:  is like 75% better. Yeah, you got rid of Ro boy. Is Roku bad now?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And boy did the Apple TV make it better?
Speaker 3:  I don't think we've talked about this very much in the show, but our own
Speaker 3:  will Joel, our senior creative director, will, Joel has a Roku tv
Speaker 3:  and the thing happened to him where it just started motion smoothing this
Speaker 3:  also happened to be at my sister's house over the 4th of July where her Roku
Speaker 3:  TVs just turned on motion smoothing. So he wrote about it and he wrote, the
Speaker 3:  people in the forum are all mad about this motion smoothing just being turned
Speaker 3:  on on Roku TVs. We have not yet written the follow-up, but they got back
Speaker 3:  to him somewhat irritatedly, and they're like, we have not turned
Speaker 3:  on motion smoothing. We've turned on
Speaker 3:  like per frame interpolation, which is motion smoothing. Yep.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 6:  The
Speaker 4:  Same thing. Same thing. It's
Speaker 3:  The same. They're like, we're not motion smoothing. We're going into the
Speaker 3:  spaces between frames and making up additional frames. And it's like, that's
Speaker 3:  motion smoothing. That's one. So he's gotta write it up. But Roku has secretly
Speaker 3:  turned on motion, smoothing on, on millions of TVs with no ways turn off.
Speaker 3:  And now they're denying they even did it. Throw 'em out, get all lets, yep.
Speaker 6:  They're too busy counting that ad money they get. They don't, they don't
Speaker 6:  care.
Speaker 3:  All right. That's my prediction. We haven't talked about that. I, on the
Speaker 3:  closest that I think is real. Can I say the one thing that will definitely
Speaker 3:  not happen? Yeah. Apple will definitely not announce a single
Speaker 3:  other car maker, maker has taken them up on Next generation.
Speaker 4:  Okay. I like this. Fair. Is this the one that you're hoping for but have
Speaker 4:  no evidence is real? Someone please. One other car maker do CarPlay.
Speaker 3:  I mean, I will say the decoder inbox right now is full of car makers who
Speaker 3:  are like, let us justify what we won't, we're not doing this anymore, which
Speaker 3:  is
Speaker 4:  Weird. Wait, who would you like it to be? If. you could If, you could be
Speaker 4:  CEO for a day and make somebody adopt the new car play for either good or
Speaker 4:  chaos reasons. Which car maker would you want it to
Speaker 3:  Be? It would be Honda or Toyota, in my opinion. Okay. Who have some of
Speaker 3:  the ugliest in-car interface designs? O of all the
Speaker 3:  mainstream cars. It's like, just tell your designers that
Speaker 3:  lowercase letters exist.
Speaker 6:  They refuse.
Speaker 3:  Like why are, we're we're just doing all cap software. Everybody, all
Speaker 3:  the time. Like just lowercase. That's the
Speaker 3:  level we're working at with Honda and Toyota.
Speaker 4:  I like it. All right. Cranz, what do you got?
Speaker 6:  All right. So my prediction that I think will happen was also Ted Lasso,
Speaker 6:  so we covered
Speaker 4:  It. Oh, okay. Well now you have to come up with the new one. Yeah. Ready
Speaker 4:  to go. I
Speaker 6:  Wrote it. I wrote it down. I wanna be very clear. I didn't make it up.
Speaker 4:  Do you think Jason Sudeikis will be there? That's the
Speaker 6:  Real question. No, I don't think he will be. I think if they have anyone
Speaker 6:  it'll be Hannah Watting because like she has never turned down a,
Speaker 6:  a press tour. That's right. She, if somebody's like, Hey, you wanna show
Speaker 6:  up? She's like, I'm here for you.
Speaker 4:  Maybe she'll be the musical act at the end.
Speaker 3:  We should get Hannah Wat can we get her to come on The. Vergecast
Speaker 6:  She, yeah, she I bet she would.
Speaker 4:  She seems like good people. Yeah, lets do it. Yeah, she seems fun. We'll
Speaker 4:  make it happen. Leah. Let's get that done.
Speaker 3:  Chop chop.
Speaker 4:  All right. And one thing you're hoping for would have no evidence is real
Speaker 6:  RayBan meta glasses, but Apple.
Speaker 4:  Mm.
Speaker 6:  Just because I really like the RayBan meta glasses, but the meta
Speaker 6:  AI sucks. I wanna talk to Siri. She's also suck. Or excuse
Speaker 6:  me, Siri also sucks and is not gendered,
Speaker 6:  but it sucks in a more familiar way.
Speaker 4:  Well, it sucks in a way that actually accesses other apps on my phone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like, like I, whereas
Speaker 4:  Meta sucks, like in its on it all by itself. Yeah. It just sucks over here.
Speaker 6:  Meta's like, I can play your Spotify. That's it. Like,
Speaker 6:  well
Speaker 3:  Stop. I didn't do my no evidence for, which is the only thing I
Speaker 3:  every, I predict this at every Apple event I have for a decade. Just make
Speaker 3:  a tv.
Speaker 3:  Just make a tv. It's you're, what are you doing guys? You
Speaker 3:  you love services businesses. Do you know what every TV maker is doing right
Speaker 3:  now? They're just doing services. They're giving 'em away for free. You could
Speaker 3:  charge real money. Tim You can be like, I don't know, this TV costs
Speaker 3:  $3,000 and people would buy it and still pay for your weird new cable bundle
Speaker 3:  that you're making. But not saying that you're making
Speaker 6:  Yeah, but they gotta spend all their money on the weird cable bundle. They
Speaker 6:  can't afford the TVs. Apple
Speaker 4:  Releases an iPad at studio display size.
Speaker 4:  Is that a television?
Speaker 3:  What is a tv?
Speaker 3:  I mean, every TV is just an Android tablet.
Speaker 6:  Okay. But like
Speaker 4:  Feeling good one.
Speaker 6:  I feel like the tablet is larger than the child holding it. It's, it goes
Speaker 6:  into TV territory
Speaker 3:  That's pretty dependent on the size of the child.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, but like
Speaker 3:  Who else? So wait, you're saying as my child gets older Yeah. It
Speaker 3:  it some point it stops seeing a tv. It's the
Speaker 4:  Tablet diagonal
Speaker 3:  Like size of child versus size of tablet. Exactly. And then age is like the
Speaker 3:  Z axis.
Speaker 4:  Okay.
Speaker 3:  In in four dimensional space. This is a TV is what you're trying to say.
Speaker 6:  Exactly.
Speaker 3:  I'm just saying make a tv. It is, it is almost comical
Speaker 3:  that the one category that they could thoroughly dominate,
Speaker 3:  they are just like, eh, healthcare.
Speaker 4:  Well, and what's funny is, for all the reasons it actually never
Speaker 3:  I beg If you.
Speaker 4:  Gene Munster needs this.
Speaker 3:  Okay, we're back. We're already over.
Speaker 3:  We've had a lot of people asking lately how long the show's supposed to be
Speaker 3:  and the answer is we're never gonna tell you.
Speaker 3:  That's the it's the joke. Yeah. You will notice the show is almost
Speaker 3:  very consistently the same length, but we're always over our minds.
Speaker 4:  We are always over.
Speaker 3:  It's never as long as it's supposed to be. The other thing that is true,
Speaker 3:  as I make the show longer with this fan thing about how long the show is
Speaker 3:  gonna be when we make it shorter, everyone yells at us. But then
Speaker 3:  when we ask people for feedback on the show, they tell us to make it shorter.
Speaker 3:  So we're just trapped in like a paradox loop of feedback
Speaker 3:  where the show can only ever be this long, but it's never long enough and
Speaker 3:  it's also too long. Yep.
Speaker 4:  The other thing people need to understand is you're, you're just doing this
Speaker 4:  all the time. Like ELA is just sitting in front of a microphone talking about
Speaker 4:  things all the time. We just occasionally record it and then and then ship
Speaker 4:  it. So it can be as long as we want. Yeah. But it's also just always
Speaker 3:  Imagine what our meetings are like. Let's drop in on Neil. I've birch
Speaker 3:  casting the no one.
Speaker 3:  Alright. It's IFA, which is a German word for gadget show.
Speaker 3:  Sure. We got a team there. There's a million gadgets being
Speaker 3:  announced. I think we should do this as a lightning round. We should just
Speaker 3:  go through 'em all except the first one. There's no chance we're gonna get
Speaker 3:  through this enlightening round fashion. No, because it is the remarkable
Speaker 3:  Paper pro, which Alex's headline is, is as outrageous
Speaker 3:  as it is luxurious. Alex, what is going on here?
Speaker 6:  Okay, so they took the gallery e ink
Speaker 6:  display and then they, which
Speaker 3:  Everyone, everyone remembers the gallery. Everybody
Speaker 6:  Knows this classic, everybody knows gallery. Duh. It's a well
Speaker 3:  The street. Oh day talked about the gallery when Mom's
Speaker 4:  Fault earlier and it was like, oh the gallery. What's up with gallery?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like when I go to the grocery store people are like, do you think gallery's
Speaker 6:  coming this year? And I can say yes. It finally came.
Speaker 6:  So, so there's two types, there's two ways to do color, E color on E
Speaker 6:  ink. One is you push the black and white ink pixels in the
Speaker 6:  e ink against a color filter. That's how Kaleido works. That's how
Speaker 6:  like anything from books or Cobo and probably
Speaker 6:  if Amazon ever does it, that's what they'll use as Kaleido. 'cause it works
Speaker 6:  really, really fast. Then there's gallery which looks way, way better.
Speaker 6:  The color is way, way cooler because they get rid of the filter and all the,
Speaker 6:  the pixels being moved are actual color pixels of cyan, yellow
Speaker 6:  and magenta. And that's what they did here. And
Speaker 6:  usually you don't wanna do that 'cause it's slow and sucks but
Speaker 6:  it's fast. How do you make it fast? They made it fast when I asked. They
Speaker 6:  were like, we can't tell you trade secrets.
Speaker 4:  Coco. That's like the magic sauce here is they figured out how to refresh
Speaker 4:  it quickly. Cocaine.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. That, that's totally Your display
Speaker 3:  Has cocaine in
Speaker 6:  It. They call it the canvas tech stack.
Speaker 6:  And, and I don't know, I'm not entirely like, I have some theories of what
Speaker 6:  they've done. I've been playing with it a lot. I'm gonna keep playing with
Speaker 6:  it, but it just, it works. But there's like a really
Speaker 6:  obnoxious flashing problem with anything that you write in color.
Speaker 6:  Anytime you write in color, it like has to refresh the entire display. Ooh.
Speaker 6:  As soon as you stop writing, that sucks.
Speaker 4:  Don't love that. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But then for just regular writing it works perfectly.
Speaker 4:  But it looks great. I mean like you, you've just been like holding it up
Speaker 4:  in, into the camera as we've been talking and like the screen looks awesome.
Speaker 4:  Let
Speaker 6:  Me, I'm gonna pull up another photo 'cause I just keep doing that.
Speaker 6:  Poor Liam was at the office the other day and I was like, Liam look. And
Speaker 6:  he's like, please just stop showing me color pictures from like,
Speaker 6:  like that just looks like real nice art. Yeah, it's
Speaker 4:  Nice.
Speaker 6:  It's just real pretty.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's one of those Don't buy it. Please. Please don't buy this. This
Speaker 6:  is, this is not for normal people. But this is such like, the fact that they
Speaker 6:  pulled it off is really cool.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So to your don't buy it point like Dave,
Speaker 3:  It's like I'm gonna buy it. I
Speaker 4:  Do, I I want it more than I am proud of. So the thing
Speaker 4:  remarkable has done really well is like relentlessly focus on
Speaker 4:  of doing a very small thing really, really well. Yep. Right. Like or the
Speaker 4:  remarkable tablet all the way back to the first one is like a thoroughly
Speaker 4:  mediocre reading experience and just like deeply lovely to write on. Yep.
Speaker 4:  The the keyboard case. I have only used a little. You've used it a lot more
Speaker 4:  is wonderful by all accounts. So it's like as a,
Speaker 4:  as a note taking machine, this thing is really expensive. It's what,
Speaker 4:  $579? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It starts at 5 79 without the case. Like the typing case is
Speaker 6:  like 2 29.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So you're looking at like a $900.
Speaker 6:  Don't don't do that. But also thing all way here. Also do it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But that's the thing. And I'm like it, I just, I even If you don't
Speaker 4:  buy it. I appreciate that. Remarkable is just like we are going to make digital
Speaker 4:  handwriting note taking. Awesome. And have like done it. Like kudos to you.
Speaker 4:  Remarkable. Yeah. You did the damn thing. Great job. I have a re
Speaker 4:  the remarkable two here and I love it. I never write by hand because my handwriting
Speaker 4:  is awful and I find myself using this thing just 'cause it's really nice
Speaker 4:  to write on. Well and
Speaker 6:  It's actually pretty, I also have awful handwriting 'cause it's a child.
Speaker 6:  I wanted to be a doctor and I thought you had to have bad handwriting. But
Speaker 6:  it actually does a really good job of of, of taking that and putting it into
Speaker 6:  text If you do to do it. Like it It does, it sucks. It sucks a little bit,
Speaker 6:  but not like awful. And it's just like, it does the one thing
Speaker 6:  really, really, really well. and it does it, it executes it so wonderfully
Speaker 6:  and it takes this technology that I never thought I would see being used
Speaker 6:  this way and doing it remarkably
Speaker 6:  very well and it very good.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna
Speaker 6:  Move on now. It's Yeah, it's great. I I did, I did the dad jokes, so
Speaker 3:  That's good. Well, you're gonna review it, I assume. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I did like kind of a mini review of it. I, I, I've only spent about
Speaker 6:  six, six or seven days with it at this point. I wanna spend more time with
Speaker 6:  it, but it's, it's a remarkable tablet. If you've used another one,
Speaker 6:  it'll be the exact same thing. Only now it's color.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Honor announced a super thin foldable IFA. It's
Speaker 3:  very cool. and it, what we're seeing, and I'll I'll put it right next to
Speaker 3:  Huawei, announced a trifold phone. And also
Speaker 4:  I forgot that the thing IFA does, like when IFA is at its best IFA is the
Speaker 4:  time where they're like, oh you silly Americans. You don't get to have the
Speaker 4:  good gadgets. Yeah. Yeah. and it always makes me sad, right?
Speaker 3:  It's like you have lockdown cell networks that prevent you from having the
Speaker 3:  cool phones. You know, I, I think I said earlier, the pixel line fold
Speaker 3:  is great. It's like the end of that road. I, I think the same with
Speaker 3:  the newest Samsung folds. Like they, they're done. They, we figured out
Speaker 3:  how to do that thing. They look as good as they're gonna look. The hardware
Speaker 3:  is great. The form factors are getting there. And now they're like, what
Speaker 3:  If you folded it twice.
Speaker 3:  Like what If, you made them thinner. Like we're just adding these refinements
Speaker 3:  now to the, the form factor. I'm not sure that the form factors
Speaker 3:  were the revolution in the phone industry that everyone was hoping they would
Speaker 3:  be. But I think the trifold is really interesting, right? Like
Speaker 3:  what if You can get to a landscape tablet in this form factor is like kind
Speaker 3:  of wild. Yeah. Especially If. you can make it thinner. You can fold it yet
Speaker 3:  one more time.
Speaker 6:  They didn't actually show it. Right? Like they, like they showed cl
Speaker 6:  glimpses of it while Andy Lau is just thinking about how much he loves movies.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I think the, the official reveal of it is I think the day after
Speaker 4:  the iPhone event. Yeah. So we'll, we'll have that to talk about next week
Speaker 4:  also. But yeah, there's, there's a video that, we'll, we'll put it in the
Speaker 4:  show notes you should look at. It is just, you get a brief look at it closed
Speaker 4:  and then a brief look at it open and it's like very thin and very cool and
Speaker 4:  very futuristic. I have lots of questions. Yep. What about
Speaker 4:  creases? What if instead of one crease, you had two creases, wouldn't that
Speaker 4:  be so fun? Probably not
Speaker 3:  The big disagree. The definitely sells a crease TCL. We love an
Speaker 3:  ePaper phone. Apparently it's
Speaker 6:  Not ink
Speaker 3:  Here in the B Palma fan club.
Speaker 4:  Welcome. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  All Kranz. This is just your segment. What I know, I'm so
Speaker 6:  Happy.
Speaker 3:  What kind wacky, inefficient display technology do we have here?
Speaker 3:  They're
Speaker 6:  They're not the only ones doing this. Like a whole bunch of people at EFA
Speaker 6:  this year are like, we're doing Color E ink. And you're like, are you?
Speaker 6:  And they're like, we're doing electronic paper. And you're like, okay, is
Speaker 6:  that just an LCD and you took the light out? And they're like, yes. That's,
Speaker 6:  that's that's what it is. Yeah. With next paper.
Speaker 6:  Next paper always loves to call it that All they're doing is putting a mat
Speaker 6:  finish on the display. That's about it. In this case
Speaker 6:  there's a button and the button will turn everything monochrome and make
Speaker 6:  it look more like a book's Palmer.
Speaker 4:  Wait, but Alex, you, you forgot the best part. What is, what is the button?
Speaker 4:  What is the mode? The button engages.
Speaker 6:  It's like maximum E Ink. Right? Maximum
Speaker 4:  Ink. It's Max ink mode.
Speaker 3:  Max ink mode.
Speaker 4:  Max ink mode.
Speaker 4:  Don't gimme regular amounts of ink. Give me max ink.
Speaker 6:  But then there's no ink at all. It's fine. I'm fine with it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But, but yeah, TCL L's been doing
Speaker 6:  this next paper thing for five years now and it's,
Speaker 6:  it's, it's not fancy. This
Speaker 3:  Is their moment. We the, the B Palma finally kicked the door down
Speaker 3:  and it, now the next cycle is everyone's gonna have a Max Ink mode phone.
Speaker 3:  But you are,
Speaker 6:  You are seeing like, like I heard it when I spoke with the folks at Remarkable.
Speaker 6:  We're seeing it in a lot of the announcements out of IFA. This idea of of
Speaker 6:  drawing our attention away from the screen and and doing, doing a dumber
Speaker 6:  screen. A a a simpler screen is is really
Speaker 6:  starting to take off.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's ever and it iss funny 'cause the iPhone is like what If you screen
Speaker 3:  was alive. Yeah. It's trying to bang you and then everyone
Speaker 3:  else is like, what if it looked more like paper? And I'm not sure how that,
Speaker 3:  those are two very different directions to Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I don't think they're ever gonna meet up. I don't, I think what's gonna happen
Speaker 6:  is a bunch of old people are gonna get e ink stuff and a bunch of young people
Speaker 6:  are gonna get the phones that bang you. I got real ageist there.
Speaker 6:  I don't know where I am on that spectrum yet.
Speaker 3:  I would say, my instinct is that recent history is that it's actually old
Speaker 3:  half weird relationships with technology. But we'll see how that goes. This
Speaker 3:  this is true. Alright, one last gadget in this section and we should talk
Speaker 3:  about the wave of lunar lake laptops that just hit, this is my
Speaker 3:  favorite one of all of efa. It is DGI has a new selfie drone.
Speaker 3:  It's $190. It's called the neo You can launch it from the pond of your hand.
Speaker 3:  4K 30 You can do pre-programmed stuff. Thomas Kar has a video of it hitting
Speaker 3:  a tree and staying alive and completing its little pre-programmed. Do a circle
Speaker 3:  around me, flight path, all that's whatever. Great. I mean I'm, I'm a
Speaker 3:  sucker for these. I will probably buy one but it has
Speaker 3:  voice controls and the voice. The act,
Speaker 3:  the, the wake word for the voice controls is, hey fly.
Speaker 6:  That's what my brother said to a hamster one time before he threw it.
Speaker 3:  I just love the idea that, and it's really small so like to, there's a photo
Speaker 3:  of Thomas putting it in his pocket and the idea that you're gonna pull out
Speaker 3:  a drone for your pocket, hold it out and be like, hey fly and it's gonna
Speaker 3:  take off and like do a a 360 around you. This is all I've ever wanted from
Speaker 3:  technology. I dunno if it's gonna work, you know, we gotta see it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But I love that. That's the wake word they chose.
Speaker 4:  It's very good. And I, I appreciate like Thomas wrote it as if
Speaker 4:  it is, it's two separate sentences. It's like you're, you're, you point at
Speaker 4:  it and you go, hey fly.
Speaker 4:  Like you're just, you are demanding that it fly and I love that.
Speaker 3:  Very confusing. Of course it's DGI, so it's a drone itself is is
Speaker 3:  1 99, but then you gotta buy the battery thing and the the
Speaker 3:  handhold controller and you're gonna end up spending a lot of money. And
Speaker 3:  this happens to me every two years on the dot. And then I use the
Speaker 3:  thing twice and put it away. But that's life.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's so funny to me that this thing and the new GoPro launched in the
Speaker 4:  same week because I have the exact same opinion about both of them, which
Speaker 4:  is that no one cares. Yeah. There's this like small group of people they
Speaker 4:  have already hit whatever product market fit they're ever going to find.
Speaker 4:  and we had this idea that action cameras were gonna be a mainstream thing
Speaker 4:  and then we had this idea that drones are gonna be a mainstream thing and
Speaker 4:  they just aren't. And that's okay. And I think this one will be fun because
Speaker 4:  it's $200 and it seems to be very easy and very resilient. So like if,
Speaker 4:  if there's ever going to be a new group of people who buys these,
Speaker 3:  The one Wait, I just want to, I just want to, I want to push back just ever
Speaker 3:  so gently on this. 'cause I, I broadly agree with you. I watch a lot of car
Speaker 3:  videos on YouTube and the presence of action cameras and drones that
Speaker 3:  You can destroy has made car videos on YouTube infinitely better.
Speaker 3:  So I would just like to say, I think they should keep going.
Speaker 4:  Oh, I think they should keep going also. But I think this idea that like,
Speaker 4:  I mean this, this thing that DJI just shipped is, is the snap
Speaker 4:  pixie? Yeah. Like it just is that, but it works with not Snapchat and
Speaker 4:  thus we'll be more successful. But like there's this idea that, oh
Speaker 4:  if we just make a a little flying selfie camera, easy
Speaker 4:  to use, everybody will want it. Just not true.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Especially there's just like, imagine, I don't know,
Speaker 3:  Lollapalooza with 15,000 people at the Chapel run show being like, hey
Speaker 3:  fly
Speaker 6:  At once.
Speaker 6:  You just hear the v as all those little engines take off.
Speaker 4:  No,
Speaker 3:  I hope it does. And I hope So I hope they pay some artist to write a song
Speaker 3:  called hey fly with for the drone. It's my dream. All right.
Speaker 3:  Lunar lake. So there just to color in Lunar lake a little bit, this is Intel's
Speaker 3:  newest laptop chip. They need to compete with windows going on arm and the
Speaker 3:  new Qualcomm chips, the A IPC that Qualcomm is doing. There's a lot of
Speaker 3:  color about Intel, which is having its struggles lately. That most important
Speaker 3:  thing to know is that I think Lunar Lake is being made by TSMC. Like
Speaker 3:  Intel isn't making their own chip, which is a big deal.
Speaker 3:  Like just a huge monumental deal. But like, here's the next wave of these
Speaker 3:  laptops. They have big promises about battery life and performance obviously
Speaker 3:  and performance per what? But the reason is 'cause someone else is making
Speaker 3:  the chips on the pro on the, on the most advanced process node. So it just
Speaker 3:  a weird, these are like historical computers.
Speaker 3:  'cause they're the ones that might signal like the end of Intel as we know
Speaker 3:  it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Weird. And then I just need to point out the Lenovo auto Twist
Speaker 3:  AI PC is a motorized two in one.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Wait, I still, I'm looking at a picture of this thing and I still don't
Speaker 4:  understand how it works.
Speaker 3:  I think Lenovo was like, well we've already put one gimmick in here with
Speaker 3:  ai. What about a second gimmick?
Speaker 6:  Lenovo just likes to see what they can do. Lenovo loves a gimmick sometimes,
Speaker 6:  especially for a big show. Oh
Speaker 4:  Wait, so this is basically like apple's center stage
Speaker 4:  thing where the camera will follow you but it's for the whole screen. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  the whole
Speaker 3:  Screen just like spins around on the base looking at you with
Speaker 3:  a, with the power of ai.
Speaker 4:  Oh man. Okay. Now what needs to happen is Razor needs to make
Speaker 4:  a circular treadmill desk that you just walk around all day
Speaker 4:  while your screen slowly follows you in circles.
Speaker 4:  And then everyone will, if
Speaker 6:  The treadmill also charges the screen Now we're
Speaker 4:  Talking. Yeah. Not Yeah. Hell yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So our, our folks spent time with it. And I just wanna read this sentence.
Speaker 3:  The concept unit responded to voice commands within a second or two,
Speaker 3:  but the motors are slow. Taking about 10 seconds to transform
Speaker 6:  If. you watch the vi the video is just like, it's so slow. You're like
Speaker 6:  Sure. Yeah. Thanks Lenovo.
Speaker 3:  All right. And then Acer had a couple as well, right? Alex, what's going
Speaker 3:  on? These
Speaker 6:  They have one that's called project Dual play Of course. And Acer I love
Speaker 6:  because I always forget that they're like, they make okay laptops, they make
Speaker 6:  really wild gaming laptops. And this one has just got like a controller
Speaker 6:  in it.
Speaker 3:  No, sure. Like you do.
Speaker 4:  It's not even Alex, you're not even doing it justice. Imagine if
Speaker 4:  the track pad underneath your keyboard on your laptop just
Speaker 4:  popped out and became a game controller. Yes. That rules
Speaker 4:  dude. Like no notes on that idea. I love it. So I feel
Speaker 4:  like so much. Where do the joysticks go? What do you do with the buttons
Speaker 4:  when it's docked? I have a lot of
Speaker 3:  Questions. There are no pictures of this thing with the controller docked
Speaker 3:  is the mouse. Yeah. I don't
Speaker 4:  Understand it.
Speaker 3:  How thick is it? How it happens? If, you need to use a mouse
Speaker 3:  while gaming.
Speaker 6:  You don't, you just keep going.
Speaker 3:  I guess the middle of the controller is still a track pad.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I But again amazing. I love it. No, no, it's,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's, it's my favorite thing that's happened. I kept thinking how to
Speaker 6:  display.
Speaker 3:  Display The top of the keyboard releases a controller and causes two five
Speaker 3:  watt speakers to pop out from the sides of the laptop. Oh, I thought there
Speaker 3:  PC card slots.
Speaker 4:  They're little, they they look like little handles that you would grab.
Speaker 3:  This is great. I would buy this tomorrow but this thing has to be
Speaker 6:  Be so thick.
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah. I don't, that's not the point.
Speaker 6:  I know.
Speaker 3:  The point is that when you take out the game controller built into the keyboard
Speaker 3:  deck, two little speakers pop out and RGB lights light up. I
Speaker 6:  Hope they go p when they do it. I wanna see the person playing this at
Speaker 6:  Starbucks.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  This great. Leaving their whole tower behind. They're ringing this thing,
Speaker 6:  they're playing Fortnite with their friend.
Speaker 3:  Okay. And then here I just wanna end with talking about Intel and Qualcomm
Speaker 3:  one one more time. Yeah. Acer announced a bunch of 14 inch laptops. Some
Speaker 3:  have Lunar Lake, some have the new Snap track and X some have the A MD rise
Speaker 3:  in AI 300, which is quite a name it claims all of them
Speaker 3:  have 24 hours of battery life.
Speaker 6:  That's not surprising, right? Do
Speaker 3:  You believe this?
Speaker 4:  No big battery life has been like one of the ongoing claims at
Speaker 4:  efa. Like Dell has said it's battery life is getting better with all these
Speaker 4:  things. Like if this is true, it's awesome, right?
Speaker 4:  Like if, if we're gonna get to the point where all of these things do these
Speaker 4:  like table stakes things very well, but then in Intel, Qualcomm and a MD
Speaker 4:  get to compete and sort of do the different things that each of them does.
Speaker 4:  Well that's amazing. I have
Speaker 4:  absolutely zero reason to believe that that is actually the case. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I also wanna point out that these claims are fundamentally unmeasurable.
Speaker 3:  So for the Intel Swift AI laptop, it's the quote
Speaker 3:  is 29 hours of video playback, 23 hours of web browsing. The
Speaker 3:  A MD is 19 hours of web browsing, 27 hours of video playback. And the Qualcomm
Speaker 3:  one is 19 and a half hours of web browsing and 28 hours of video playback.
Speaker 3:  I'm just pointing out this requires someone to watch videos for over
Speaker 3:  a full day on three different computers and or browse the web for
Speaker 3:  nearly a full day. And I don't, I am very
Speaker 3:  motivated to test these claims.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Well also I think probably, I
Speaker 3:  Dunno if I can do it without breaking the labor law of the United States.
Speaker 6:  I, I suspect in
Speaker 3:  Some kind of clockwork or situation.
Speaker 6:  No, you use a GoPro. I used to have to do these tests and we would just point
Speaker 6:  a GoPro at it and then the next morning come in and like be like, okay, let's
Speaker 6:  see if it recorded it and sometimes it didn't and you're like, okay, I guess
Speaker 6:  I test again. This will be fun. Let's chart fast. This
Speaker 3:  Is the market for GoPros David. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  That's the market.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You scream, hey fly and then it,
Speaker 6:  You just stares at a computer
Speaker 4:  Covers and watches
Speaker 3:  Top doing a video playback, I don't even know, 24 hours of video playback
Speaker 3:  as a useful stat for anyone in the world.
Speaker 6:  I think it was once and I think there was a lot of reviewing reviewers who
Speaker 6:  were using video playback as like the primary way to do battery testing
Speaker 6:  for a very long time. And so like but also 24 hours
Speaker 6:  isn't a lot nowadays. Like given the size of these batteries. Yeah. These
Speaker 6:  things should be able to like do this. It
Speaker 6:  should be relatively easy for them to do this if they put a big enough battery
Speaker 6:  in the laptop.
Speaker 3:  No, IIII and I, I certainly understand why in the beginning when video
Speaker 3:  playbook was like particularly chip
Speaker 6:  Bound hard. Yeah, it makes sense.
Speaker 3:  It was hard to do. So it was like a very heavy task. All video playback now
Speaker 3:  on these, on these computers is being routed to an ultra efficient,
Speaker 3:  specialized part of a chip that is doing it for almost no power. Yep.
Speaker 4:  Well the only reason they're useful is because they're apples to
Speaker 4:  apples. Right. Like thi this is a thing we've dealt with for forever for
Speaker 4:  like as long as The Verge has existed. How do we benchmark battery
Speaker 4:  life in a way that is both real and actually
Speaker 4:  like objective apples to apples. It's impossible. You can't do it. There's
Speaker 4:  just no way. So you have to do the thing where you're like, I ran this test
Speaker 4:  that doesn't mean anything but is at least one-to-one and then I
Speaker 4:  just use it like a person and try to report battery life. Yes. This is
Speaker 4:  a thing that does that If you
Speaker 3:  Have ever angrily commented in one of our laptop reviews about why we continue
Speaker 3:  to play shadow of the Tomb Raider. It is exactly for this reason.
Speaker 3:  Totally. It's just, we, we just picked a game and that's the game. That's
Speaker 3:  it works on everything Monica picked quite honestly, Monica shouldn't pick
Speaker 3:  that game. And now we're gonna play shadow of the Tomb Raider a couple times
Speaker 3:  a year for the rest of our lives.
Speaker 6:  It had some challenging like graphic
Speaker 6:  stuff. There was like the tres locks, the res the
Speaker 6:  hair, yeah.
Speaker 6:  it is,
Speaker 3:  It's actually worse than Intel on
Speaker 3:  I don't know what happens next.
Speaker 6:  Well they're trying to
Speaker 3:  Fios was not its future. Sold off a bunch of Fios assets and customers embed
Speaker 3:  everything on little technology we like to call 5G,
Speaker 3:  which you will recall was supposed to enable everything from robot surgery,
Speaker 3:  which never happened to self-driving cars, which only happened in two cities
Speaker 3:  with no 5G involved to you just name it, you just name it. Remember remember
Speaker 3:  5G by the way, the, the camera button on the iPhone 16 pro,
Speaker 3:  it's supposed to be where the millimeter wave in 10 is right now.
Speaker 4:  Perfect.
Speaker 3:  I don't know where the millimeter wave is gonna go or if it's even gonna
Speaker 3:  still be there, but do you remember all this? Sure do. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Turns out 5G accomplish nothing. And now Verizon is gonna
Speaker 3:  spend $20 billion to buy Frontier,
Speaker 3:  which it sold a bunch of F assets to Hans Vesper. The CEO of
Speaker 3:  Verizon says the acquisition of Frontier is a strategic fit. It'll build
Speaker 3:  on Verizon's two decades of leadership at the forefront of fiber. And it's
Speaker 3:  an opportunity to become competitive in more markets in the United States.
Speaker 3:  The two decades of leadership were building the network. It sold the frontier
Speaker 3:  and is now buying again. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  So, so Verizon was like what if
Speaker 4:  really fast wired internet was not important and then
Speaker 4:  realized a decade later that very fast wired internet is actually like pretty
Speaker 4:  important.
Speaker 3:  But India, they're an investor at our parent company Box media. I am often
Speaker 3:  accused of being hopelessly biased in favor of wired
Speaker 3:  connections. It comes up on the show a lot that I think wired
Speaker 3:  connections are good and reliable. Headphones for example, as
Speaker 3:  Alex painfully brought up earlier,
Speaker 4:  I think two of the official stances of The Vergecast are, are more buttons
Speaker 4:  are better and plug it in. Yeah, it'll be fine. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Wire connections are better than wireless ones. Yeah. Yeah. When I covered
Speaker 3:  starlink, I was accused of being in the pocket of Bing, Comcast. 'cause I
Speaker 3:  pointed out that wired ethernet is more liable than sending
Speaker 3:  internet to space, which seems obvious on space.
Speaker 3:  Big
Speaker 4:  Comcast. Gotcha.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Right. So I basically Verizon was like all in on its
Speaker 3:  own 5G bet high in its own supply. They thought this was gonna do whatever
Speaker 3:  it was gonna do and they started selling off these assets because they thought
Speaker 3:  they weren't durable. And the reality is over and over and over again
Speaker 3:  that in particular wired internet connections are what people want.
Speaker 3:  Like pe If, you give people the choice between some
Speaker 3:  weirdo
Speaker 3:  wireless line of sight, ir tin can
Speaker 3:  internet connection or like fiber to their house. They will always pick the
Speaker 3:  fiber. And so it's just been more durable over time and it doesn't, I don't
Speaker 3:  think that actually is a knock on 5G. Like I know
Speaker 3:  we're gonna get emails 'cause we always get emails people, a lot of people
Speaker 3:  have like 5G home internet connections now. Yeah. Because they have no access
Speaker 3:  to the other thing and the 5G Home internet connection is an upgrade. It's
Speaker 3:  the same
Speaker 4:  Thing with Starlink If you had, if your options are nothing and Starlink
Speaker 4:  starlink is great,
Speaker 3:  But if your options are starlink or 5G Home, internet or fiber,
Speaker 3:  a lot of people pick the fiber and the fiber is really useful. So it's just
Speaker 3:  like Verizon just got high and it's UNP supply and it, it's spending $20
Speaker 3:  billion to go a circle.
Speaker 4:  You know what's nuts? This is, this is a total tangent that we shouldn't
Speaker 4:  go down, but just a thing I realized as you were explaining that is like
Speaker 4:  you just described what's happening to the whole tech industry and AI right
Speaker 4:  now. Yeah. Everybody's like, what if we threw away everything we were good
Speaker 4:  at because AI is going to change everything about everything forever. And
Speaker 4:  it's like, you wanna know, you wanna know what happens when it doesn't Is
Speaker 4:  this, you spend $20 billion to undo
Speaker 4:  your own weird ideas about
Speaker 3:  Future. They, they sold these customers to Frontier in 2015 for 10
Speaker 3:  and a half billion dollars and it's rebuying them for $20 billion. Frontier
Speaker 3:  made outta abandoned. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I mean did did they go bankrupt in the interim there and then have to go
Speaker 6:  do a whole restructuring?
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Who, who among us hasn't gone bankrupt at one point or another? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Especially If you, especially if you're a cable company, CEO, this is just
Speaker 3:  like what you do. Yeah, this is true. I you're sending the bankruptcy forms
Speaker 3:  from your yacht, you know, you're, you're fine. Alright Dave, what's yours?
Speaker 4:  I just wanna talk briefly about Snapchat. So
Speaker 4:  Alex Heath was on the show with me two weeks ago I
Speaker 4:  think. And one of the things he said was basically like Snapchat is
Speaker 4:  both more popular than ever and also maybe in more trouble as a business
Speaker 4:  than ever. And I think there is no better way to look at that
Speaker 4:  than a note Evan Spiegel posted on the company website that we reported
Speaker 4:  on that one of the things it's going to do is start putting ads in your
Speaker 4:  chat lists. Which to me is one of the things that has been
Speaker 4:  like untouchable in a messaging app forever. Like ads in
Speaker 4:  the messages and ads between the threads in my
Speaker 4:  inbox have been two things that companies are very afraid of doing. Like
Speaker 4:  Google does it in your Gmail a little and everybody hates it and it sucks.
Speaker 4:  But like Snap is about to start putting ads in your chats like
Speaker 4:  with your friends. And basically Evan Spiegel's reason for
Speaker 4:  doing it was like, our business is bad
Speaker 4:  and investors are mad at us about it. And it's just the whole thing, just
Speaker 4:  like reeks of desperation from Snapchat. And I just, I think that
Speaker 4:  is fascinating. Like this company is absolutely ubiquitous
Speaker 4:  among like a certain generation of internet users. It is everywhere
Speaker 4:  among like my, my high school age nephews. Like Snapchat is how
Speaker 4:  you live your life at that age right now. And yet this company just cannot
Speaker 4:  figure out how to make any money. Yeah. And it's, it's just a really, really
Speaker 4:  strange
Speaker 3:  And they can't do the one thing that they should do, which is charge a
Speaker 3:  fee. Right.
Speaker 4:  Because my nephews are 17 that they're not gonna do that.
Speaker 4:  And Evan Spiegel's quote is, the growth of our digital advertising business
Speaker 4:  is one of the most important inputs to our long-term revenue potential. And
Speaker 4:  investors are concerned that we aren't growing faster. Like if, if
Speaker 4:  you're a, if you're a CEO of a big tech company writing like a, here's why
Speaker 4:  we're doing a product thing, that's not what you say. And when you've gotten
Speaker 4:  to the point where that's what you have to say that like you, you are deep
Speaker 4:  down the road of like,
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  What choice do I have like this? That is where Snap is.
Speaker 3:  Yikes. Put Snap on the Go 90 Scale. The Go 90 scale of Doom
Speaker 3:  streaming services I understand is not about Snapchat but
Speaker 4:  We're very close. 75.
Speaker 3:  75.
Speaker 4:  Wow. I think, I think Snap Snapchat as its
Speaker 4:  own public company as is at, is at a
Speaker 4:  75. And I think if we were in a different world of
Speaker 4:  antitrust regulation and big tech questions, snap
Speaker 4:  probably would've been bought by somebody at this point.
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah. Google would've bought and killed Snapchat by now. Within a heartbeat.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So I. I think I'm 75 might be a little high, but
Speaker 4:  only because of like bigger macro reasons.
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna say 65 I think. I think it's so sticky.
Speaker 4:  It is so sticky. It's you like you cannot overstate how much people
Speaker 4:  love Snapchat. Yeah. But
Speaker 6:  It's only sticky for the people who actually use it and not enough people
Speaker 6:  use it. It's not growing.
Speaker 4:  No, but like tons of people use it. It's again, it is more popular than ever.
Speaker 4:  It's huge. It just can't make any money. Like this is, this to me is the
Speaker 4:  fun. Like, but it's not
Speaker 6:  That huge. Is it? Like how many people
Speaker 4:  Are using it? I think it's like 800 million. Like it's huge. Oh that is,
Speaker 4:  it is sufficiently large. It's just that teens sending
Speaker 4:  each other silly selfies is not a monetizable business
Speaker 4:  is that they're sending each other learning it. And so what they're gonna
Speaker 4:  do is they're gonna ruin
Speaker 3:  It. It all comes back to this idea, doesn't it Alex?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The question now is basically for Snap is going to be how bad
Speaker 4:  can we make this before you leave? And that's like, that's a sad place for
Speaker 4:  a company to have to get to. and it really feels like that's where Snap has
Speaker 4:  gotten. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I will say if they don't light up some kind of actual
Speaker 3:  subscription, it, they will be past
Speaker 3:  65 or 75 very quickly. I think they have to
Speaker 4:  Like charge 20. I mean there's, there's, you know, Snapchat plus is like,
Speaker 4:  it's a thing. Sure. But there there's never really
Speaker 4:  been any energy behind that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Ugh. That's sad.
Speaker 3:  All right. Kranz, what you got
Speaker 6:  Bringing on the sadness was Concord. Concord, you may have heard about it
Speaker 6:  in the last eight years because it was this, it was gonna be a new live
Speaker 6:  service game from Sony and they spent over eight years making
Speaker 6:  it and then it came out and they've already pulled it within a month. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  and it coming out because just nobody was playing it. It hit at the wrong
Speaker 6:  time. It didn't have any of the cool features.
Speaker 6:  Like when it started, I don't think Fortnite and Pub Underground
Speaker 6:  were even really a thing for most people. And that's all happened
Speaker 6:  since then. So it came out at the wrong time. It's been, it had a
Speaker 6:  disastrous launch and now it's been so
Speaker 4:  Bad. Is it bad? Like
Speaker 6:  Just
Speaker 4:  Boring. What was the problem? Okay.
Speaker 6:  It was just boring. Yeah. and it was just like, there's been such a glut
Speaker 6:  of these free to play live services video games. Everybody thought
Speaker 6:  that this was gonna be how they were gonna make all of their money. And over
Speaker 6:  time it's been like, oh wait, no. A few of 'em will do it and some will carve
Speaker 6:  out their little fiefdoms, some will be Fortnite, which, you know,
Speaker 6:  everyone under the age of 14 plays and otherwise it's like
Speaker 6:  there's not a lot of room for this because there's a finite number of people
Speaker 6:  who wanna play video games and then that group gets smaller and smaller the
Speaker 6:  more specific the games are and then you need a lot of people to play it
Speaker 6:  in order to make it interesting. And then this happens. Well,
Speaker 4:  But I also feel like it it, if I rewind a few years ago, the big
Speaker 4:  idea in the industry was like, okay, live service games are the thing
Speaker 4:  and what's gonna happen is, is the same thing that happens in the gaming
Speaker 4:  industry, right. There's gonna be a big one and then there's gonna be a next
Speaker 4:  big one and then there's gonna be a next big one and there's gonna be a next
Speaker 4:  big one. and it turns out like no there's, it's just gonna be Fortnite and
Speaker 4:  League of Legends the whole time. Yeah. And Minecraft is gonna keep being
Speaker 4:  huge and Roblox is gonna keep being like, it's, it's just been the same
Speaker 4:  handful of giants for so long now.
Speaker 4:  And I like it is, it is astounding to me how big those games still are
Speaker 4:  and how much saying power they've had and it just feels like all these companies
Speaker 4:  made the right, they like bet on the right industry and were just
Speaker 4:  completely wrong about how it was gonna go. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. In this case they were just way too late. Like Concord eight years
Speaker 6:  in development for a live service
Speaker 6:  video game is just, that's way too long.
Speaker 4:  And also isn't the lesson from PUG just like ship your shitty game and it'll
Speaker 4:  be fine. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Ship it and go sort of
Speaker 3:  Ship your game with an innovative new business model and a dynamic
Speaker 3:  new gameplay mechanic before anyone else and then you'll be fine.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, sure.
Speaker 6:  And then con
Speaker 3:  It's spend eight years doing this to not Yeah. That
Speaker 4:  That sounds as
Speaker 3:  Good as Fortnite is a different lesson, but
Speaker 6:  It sounds like this may be like teaching, this may be that one of those learning
Speaker 6:  moments for the video game industry. They may be going, oh wait, we don't
Speaker 6:  need to do this. But I mean, EA still exists so presumably we'll get
Speaker 6:  a ton more of these
Speaker 3:  As someone who just bought the new Madden, which is so hard. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I will say that no one's learning anything. I will say Sony, by the time
Speaker 3:  you're listen to this Astro bot will be out for the PS five. And that game
Speaker 3:  by all accounts looks to be the game of the year.
Speaker 4:  People are obsessed with
Speaker 6:  With this game. They love
Speaker 3:  It. Yeah. I, I bought the control. I've been playing Astros playroom with
Speaker 3:  Max. Oh nice. And So I, we bought the controller because she's obsessed and
Speaker 3:  I'm very excited by this game. And it's like a totally different lesson.
Speaker 3:  Like what If, you made a jewel like platformer with a lovable
Speaker 3:  character that had innovative gameplay mechanics, the
Speaker 6:  Nintendo
Speaker 3:  Playbook. Yeah. and it's a what if we made Mario again? And I understand
Speaker 3:  saying Make Mario again is like
Speaker 4:  Fine. Nobody ever thought of that. That's weird.
Speaker 3:  You thought of making Jurassic Park again exactly the way it was when I was
Speaker 3:  eight. That's gonna save the movie industry.
Speaker 3:  But it's funny that Sony is doing both things at the same time. Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  one of them is gonna be a way bigger hit than the other. Yeah. Yep. All right,
Speaker 3:  here's my last one. I just wanna call this out. We are deeply committed to
Speaker 3:  covering the Fedi verse and all things open social web. And this one is
Speaker 3:  very small, but I think it has glimmers of a big idea.
Speaker 3:  It's called Sub Club, it's from the company, it makes Mammoth, the Masson
Speaker 3:  client. It's paid social feeds. So
Speaker 3:  one of the things I think about all the time is people subscribe to on
Speaker 3:  a platform or four four media or all of our friends who have substack or
Speaker 3:  ghosts or whatever. And the way that that dynamic
Speaker 3:  usually works is the social media is the marketing to get you to subscribe
Speaker 3:  to a newsletter. But the social media is often the content, right? Like it's
Speaker 3:  the thing and no one has figured out how to like monetize a feed
Speaker 3:  at all. And you know, you like paid Twitter
Speaker 3:  posts like never took off like that. There was that button there and there's
Speaker 3:  some of this on some of the platforms, there's some kind of premium subscription
Speaker 3:  stuff, but none of it happens at scale. And certainly none of it supports
Speaker 3:  anybody at scale. I think the idea of the open social
Speaker 3:  internet interconnected, federated networks, having this built into them
Speaker 3:  from the beginning is super powerful.
Speaker 3:  And the idea that you subscribe to some creator and as part of it you get
Speaker 3:  authenticated into one of their feeds that You can subscribe to anywhere
Speaker 3:  as opposed to just on Twitter or just on YouTube or just on Instagram. That's
Speaker 3:  a big deal. Yeah. I don't know. I don't know if this one's gonna go anywhere.
Speaker 3:  I'm exci. I'm just excited to see the ecosystem is starting to generate
Speaker 3:  these new ideas about what could you do if all of
Speaker 3:  these networks actually work together. And one of those ideas is like what
Speaker 3:  If you could pay creators directly and what you've got is also their social
Speaker 3:  media and not just like links to this stuff that you pay for
Speaker 3:  somewhere else. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. This ecosystem is like finally starting to productize in really exciting
Speaker 4:  ways. And like the other thing that launched this week was
Speaker 4:  reader, the RSS reader app. R-E-E-D-E-R. The guy who
Speaker 4:  made it, it's like the best RSS app that exists made
Speaker 4:  a new one that is all just following feeds. So You can, like, instead of
Speaker 4:  it being an RSS feed from a website, You can now follow, like You can get
Speaker 4:  a YouTube subscription in there and You can get MAs on feeds in there. And
Speaker 4:  it's, it's another one where like you, you put a bunch of feeds in that are
Speaker 4:  all these different things and it just renders in this one multimedia timeline.
Speaker 4:  And it's one of those things that like turns your brain onto like, oh, I
Speaker 4:  get it now. Yeah. And like what you're talking about is the idea of like,
Speaker 4:  what if, what if I could pay for just your stuff,
Speaker 4:  that's that's the stuff man. Yeah. That's the thing that
Speaker 3:  just see them across the ecosystem. Like, oh, this is where investment is,
Speaker 3:  that isn't, we're gonna spend a trillion dollars stealing everything on the
Speaker 3:  internet to train. Oh yeah. Like this is much more like, what
Speaker 3:  if it was sustainable to make things for other people on the internet, which
Speaker 3:  is just not, there hasn't been this kind of very
Speaker 3:  sincere engagement in that for a while yet. Okay. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's it. We're miles over six hour Vergecast.
Speaker 3:  It was real. We gotta, we gotta go, we gotta get on planes. I, we are at
Speaker 3:  the Apple event next week. We got stuff to write about. IFA is gonna keep
Speaker 3:  happening. There's, there's You can read coverage of the matter spec. It
Speaker 3:  feels like every time Jen goes to a trade conference and a different matter
Speaker 3:  executive shows up and promises her, it's gonna be better. That's on the
Speaker 3:  website. There's more gadgets on the website 'cause IFA is ongoing. Check
Speaker 3:  it all out, but we gotta go. That's it. That's The Vergecast Rock.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one. The. Vergecast
Speaker 1:  is