# Transcript
ID: a6651abf-57ef-44a0-8af4-e5b6273a046a
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8269891288870014738/7905355328181313614/s93290-US-4411s-1715069466.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of enterprise certificate hacks:
03:22 - The Verge’s David Pierce chats with Riley Testut, founder of AltStore and developer of the game emulator app Delta, about how his app finally made it into Apple’s App Store.
The free Delta game emulator for iPhones is live on Apple’s App Store
Third-party iPhone app store AltStore PAL is now live in Europe
Delta is the game emulator your iPhone has been missing
46:17 - David walks us through his experimentation with the many software and hardware solutions for “AI voice notes.”
Cleft Notes is an AI voice notes app that really works
1:02:02 - David answers a question from the Vergecast Hotline about the Rabbit R1.
Rabbit R1 review: nothing to see here
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (15 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Enterprise Certificate
Speaker 2:  Hacks. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am having a project day.
Speaker 2:  I feel like being an adult is just like a long unending list
Speaker 2:  of maintenance tasks. There's always things to hang up and things to take
Speaker 2:  down and filters to change and sinks to clean. And did you know you're supposed
Speaker 2:  to clean your garbage disposal and your dishwasher? Apparently.
Speaker 2:  There's all kinds of stuff like that and rather than let it hang over my
Speaker 2:  head, I've discovered that what works for me is to just keep a long running
Speaker 2:  list and then once a month or so, whenever I'm feeling
Speaker 2:  particularly energetic and have some time, I try to just knock
Speaker 2:  out as many of those things as I can, right? It just feels better. And most
Speaker 2:  of those tasks take like one to five minutes anyway so I can get up,
Speaker 2:  do a whole bunch when I'm feeling energetic or have a show I wanna watch
Speaker 2:  or whatever and then it's done. And then I don't have to think about it for
Speaker 2:  a month. I'm sure there are a million things that are supposed to be on that
Speaker 2:  list that I don't even know about, but I've made it this far. I don't wanna
Speaker 2:  know. I'm sure it'll cause me pain and I'll deal with it as it comes. That's
Speaker 2:  what being an adult is, right? Anyway, we have an awesome show coming up
Speaker 2:  for you today. We're gonna do two things. We're gonna talk a bunch about
Speaker 2:  the Delta emulator because that little retro game emulator
Speaker 2:  has kind of taken over the app store the last couple of weeks and it turns
Speaker 2:  out its story is both longer and weirder
Speaker 2:  and more interesting and maybe more reflective of kind of the whole
Speaker 2:  evolution of the tech industry than you think. So we're gonna talk to the
Speaker 2:  person who made Delta about the whole journey to get here and what it says
Speaker 2:  about where we might be going next. After that, we're gonna talk about AI
Speaker 2:  because I've been testing AI gadgets, AI apps, AI
Speaker 2:  platforms, AI everything for like a year and a half now. And
Speaker 2:  I've found one use case for me that is perfect and it's awesome
Speaker 2:  and I want to tell you about it. And this probably won't surprise you, but
Speaker 2:  it does involve talking into a microphone. We're also gonna answer The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  hotline. Question about the Rabbit R one. We got lots to do. Super
Speaker 2:  fun show. All that is coming up in just a second. But first I just noticed
Speaker 2:  this like pile of laundry and socks behind me and it's starting to
Speaker 2:  stress me out. So I'm gonna go deal with that Project number one off the
Speaker 2:  list. This is the first cast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  for 10% off your first booking
Speaker 5:  at SVB dot com slash vox.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. For all of the last two weeks, the most
Speaker 2:  popular app in the Apple app store has been a game emulator called Delta.
Speaker 2:  We've been talking a lot about Delta on this show over the last few weeks,
Speaker 2:  both because it's a huge hit and because it seems like
Speaker 2:  maybe the start of a new era for the app store, like in the
Speaker 2:  history books of smartphone apps, there might be a before
Speaker 2:  Delta and an after Delta for lots of reasons. But there's actually
Speaker 2:  nothing even remotely new about Delta. The story of this
Speaker 2:  app is actually a full decade long and it starts with this guy,
Speaker 6:  I'm Ri Testa and I'm the founder of alt store developer of Delta.
Speaker 6:  Riley
Speaker 2:  Has had, as you might expect, a pretty wild few weeks in
Speaker 2:  the middle of it all. I asked him to come on the show and just tell me the
Speaker 2:  whole Delta story, why he wanted to build an emulator in the first place,
Speaker 2:  how the regulatory and technological world changed around him and
Speaker 2:  in general, how Delta went from a big hack to a big hit.
Speaker 2:  It starts with RI in high school, just kind of looking for something to do.
Speaker 6:  I was just back in high school, I think it was my junior year and I just
Speaker 6:  one day came across just like the open source repo for
Speaker 6:  a jailbreak game boy Van Simulator, GPS phone. And
Speaker 6:  I was like, oh this is cool. This is all the code. I can probably just download
Speaker 6:  this and tweak it and then put it on my own phone without having to jailbreak
Speaker 6:  because yeah, I've never been a fan of jailbreaking, it's just never really
Speaker 6:  appealed to me. So I found this code base, I hacked out
Speaker 6:  away for a couple months, put it on my phone, I put
Speaker 6:  it on a few of my friends' phones, they liked it and then I uploaded it to
Speaker 6:  GitHub and called it GB Afri West and then
Speaker 6:  kind of left it there for a bit and then people
Speaker 6:  found it on GitHub and started talking about it. And so I was like, oh,
Speaker 6:  there's interest in this kind of thing.
Speaker 2:  So you just made it as, as sort of a, it sounds like a mix of like a thing
Speaker 2:  that you thought would be useful and just kind of a thing to do.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I just wanted Pokemon on my phone. That was literally just, I found
Speaker 6:  this, I was like, oh cool, I can Pokemon on my phone now and that's awesome.
Speaker 6:  And that's really all I was thinking at the time. And then I put on my friend's
Speaker 6:  phones and then we were playing just Pokemon ourselves. And then just completely
Speaker 6:  coincidentally, there was this service that came out around the same time
Speaker 6:  that let you connect, like get open source GitHub projects and
Speaker 6:  sign it with Apple's enterprise certificate. Basically there's a company
Speaker 6:  that had enterprise certificate and you could just connect your GitHub account
Speaker 6:  and then resign your apps like that. And so I was like, oh cool,
Speaker 6:  I'll connect this to GBA for iOS and then people can install it outside the
Speaker 6:  app store. Maybe a few people will download it. And that's basically when
Speaker 6:  I learned, oh wait, there's a huge demand for this thing. Oh
Speaker 6:  interesting. I did that and then within like a week people were like
Speaker 6:  posting videos about how to install it. There were lots of Reddit posts and
Speaker 6:  I was like honestly caught off guard. 'cause at this point it was still just
Speaker 6:  a project I made for me and my friends like in high school. And so right
Speaker 6:  then I was like, okay, there's demand for this thing. Let's take this seriously.
Speaker 6:  Let's like build like a real version of this app that's not like throwing
Speaker 6:  together not hacky. And so that's when I got my friend Paul Thorson
Speaker 6:  on board, my also still in high school. And we were like, we're gonna do
Speaker 6:  a brand new version of GBA, fry Wests, GBA, fry Wests 2.0. We're gonna
Speaker 6:  redesign it from the ground up, just build it and make a really polished
Speaker 6:  experience. And so we basically spent all of senior year working
Speaker 6:  on that and in like halfway through senior year we released GBA
Speaker 6:  for iOS 2.0 and that's the version that most people know. That was the version
Speaker 6:  that you installed from my website. You set your date back like 24 hours
Speaker 6:  and you can install it because of the weird bug that allowed enterprise certificates
Speaker 6:  to work that way, even if they're expired.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Wait, so real quick, just pause for a second and explain the enterprise
Speaker 2:  certificate thing to be, because I feel like part of the story here is like
Speaker 2:  Riley's adventures in figuring out how to install apps on phones.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Yeah. Slowly getting more and more complicated. Yeah. Yeah. So this
Speaker 6:  was the easiest hack is just, yeah, as long as I found an enterprise certificate,
Speaker 6:  I could just sign GBA for I os with it. And literally anyone could just
Speaker 6:  download it from a website on the phone. Super simple.
Speaker 2:  And the idea is basically it's like that's the certificate you would use
Speaker 2:  if I'm like a company wanting my employees and no one else to have that app,
Speaker 2:  right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The exact same flow. And so it's just, you're not supposed to do it
Speaker 6:  for this reason. And so what Apple normally would do is they would just
Speaker 6:  like revoke the certificate, they'd make it, this is no longer valid and
Speaker 6:  all apps that are signed with it can no longer be installed. And so the bug
Speaker 6:  that I took advantage of was apparently at this time, like in Iowa seven
Speaker 6:  If, you just set your date back on your phone by more than an hour. The
Speaker 6:  checks for whether a certificate is valid or not just don't work. They
Speaker 6:  just don't do it. Sure, you did try to install GBA and Apple
Speaker 6:  would've revoked the certificate, but because you set your date back, iOS
Speaker 6:  was fine installing it. And so it was just like a really weird bug that I
Speaker 6:  could take advantage of because there Apple couldn't do anything easily about
Speaker 6:  it. They had to actually fix iOS to address it. They couldn't just be like,
Speaker 6:  okay, nope. Turn off certificate. It was about nine months later that they
Speaker 6:  finally addressed it. And then that was when I moved on basically from
Speaker 6:  GBA for iOS is when they, it was like iOS 8.1, they
Speaker 6:  killed the date trick. It was literally on my birthday when it actually happened
Speaker 6:  and I was like, oh that's funny. But honestly at that point I just gone to
Speaker 6:  college and so I was like, you know what, I'm gonna move on from this whole
Speaker 6:  thing. GBA fires is really cool. I wanted to go on to the next thing.
Speaker 2:  Do you know how many people were using GBA for iOS? Like at that sort of
Speaker 2:  peak moment before it got shut down?
Speaker 6:  A lot of people like more than 10 million for sure.
Speaker 2:  Wow. Whoa. Yeah. That's like a zero or two bigger than I thought
Speaker 2:  you were gonna say.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There was a stupid amount of people using GBA Fire Wests, which
Speaker 6:  is why I was so motivated to do this for this whole time was I just knew
Speaker 6:  that there was a market for this kind of thing that everyone just kind of
Speaker 6:  assumed there wasn't. But I'm like, no GVA got 10 million downloads outside
Speaker 6:  the app store. Like it's just people just really wanna do this, like play
Speaker 6:  old games. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So you kind of, you, you're sort of forced to shut down that project
Speaker 2:  a little bit. Yeah. Was there a moment where you're like, okay, I'm ready
Speaker 2:  to go to war with Apple, let's fight this to the death and figure out
Speaker 2:  how to get GBA for iOS back Or when it, when the sort of exploit gets shut
Speaker 2:  down, do you just kind of say, you know what, like you said, I'm going to
Speaker 2:  college anyway, this is just a moment, let me focus on other things.
Speaker 6:  It is basically that. Yeah. I was like, you know what, this is just a sign
Speaker 6:  that I should move on to something else. This was really cool. I'm glad I
Speaker 6:  got to do this, got a lot of experience but maybe I'll try to make an app
Speaker 6:  in the app store next time. That was what I was thinking. I'm like, this
Speaker 6:  is a lot of work. Should have an app outside the app store. Yeah. So then
Speaker 6:  that whole thought process lasted like a few months and then I got bored
Speaker 6:  and I needed a new app to work on. And so yeah, swift had also just been
Speaker 6:  announced like the previous year and so I was like, oh you know what? Let
Speaker 6:  just make another toy app for myself to learn Swift just for
Speaker 6:  me. And you know what? I'll make another emulator, it'll have more systems,
Speaker 6:  but it's just for me like I'm again like it's just like a fun thing I wanted
Speaker 6:  to work on to learn Swift. That was like my entire motivation. So
Speaker 2:  You're just run the exact same playbook again. Yeah. Without even realizing
Speaker 2:  Exactly.
Speaker 6:  I was like, you know, I'm just gonna make for fun. Yeah, I know you'd think
Speaker 6:  I'd learn at some point.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so and that's where Delta starts.
Speaker 6:  Yes. And so that's the beginning of Delta was like, okay, I'll call it Delta
Speaker 6:  and just build it for fun and that is what I thought I was gonna be working
Speaker 6:  on. And then I went to WDC that year. It was my first
Speaker 6:  time ever at WDC. What year
Speaker 2:  Is this at this point?
Speaker 6:  2015. Okay. So I go to WC and I talk to the
Speaker 6:  app review team like 'cause they have like a lab there and I basically just
Speaker 6:  say, Hey I'm working on this EM other app, is there any
Speaker 6:  world that it could be approved in the app store? And then they were like,
Speaker 6:  actually yeah, we'll allow that. You just gotta like comply with some weird
Speaker 6:  things. Basically they said I had to like submit a list of approved games
Speaker 6:  to them whenever I submitted a version of Delta so that could, they could
Speaker 6:  just make sure all the games that Delta supports were safe. Like they just
Speaker 6:  didn't wanna have like an open pipeline of like games and everything. And
Speaker 6:  so I was like okay fine that works for me. I'll submit a version of Delta
Speaker 6:  to you and I'll have like a eight list of games that you can play and then
Speaker 6:  every app update I'll expand it to include more games. And
Speaker 6:  it seemed like that would be something I could do. And so I was really motivated.
Speaker 6:  I'm like cool, I'm gonna get Delta in the app store. And so then I spent
Speaker 6:  the next year like actually building it for real. I was like okay, this is
Speaker 6:  now a real app no longer just for me. I like really want it to be
Speaker 6:  polished, I want to be good. I took a lot of my time. I got on my college
Speaker 6:  schedule to be working on it and then I went to the WWE C
Speaker 6:  next year and I talked to the same person and I said, Hey, I'm
Speaker 6:  ready to submit, can I submit it now? And he was just like,
Speaker 6:  so I talked to some people we can't allow
Speaker 6:  Ambulator and that was just all I got. I didn't get a
Speaker 6:  why. It was just like a, we can't allow that.
Speaker 6:  And I was just pissed off.
Speaker 2:  Do you think this person was wrong the first time they told you it
Speaker 2:  would happen or do you think something happened in that year and they changed
Speaker 2:  their mind?
Speaker 6:  Honestly, I don't know. It's either one's possible. My guess is though that
Speaker 6:  they thought it was okay and then they talked to someone in the year and
Speaker 6:  then maybe they just had discussions about it and then they came away basically
Speaker 6:  like it's not worth the risk because I think that's what it's been this whole
Speaker 6:  time. Apple is just like, it's not worth the risk to allow these emit, there's
Speaker 6:  just so much stuff that could open up. So I think they're just like, eh,
Speaker 6:  it's one kid, whatever, we don't need to allow his app in the app store and
Speaker 6:  it'll be fine. And
Speaker 2:  At that point, I mean I I, I confess I was late to the
Speaker 2:  iOS emulation universe, but it seems it's a weird thing
Speaker 2:  like GBA for iOS was huge and then it kind of went away. And so I
Speaker 2:  would assume we're back to like lots of pent up demand. People are very excited
Speaker 2:  about it. So it's not like you're the first person in history to ask Apple
Speaker 2:  this question, I'm sure. But at that point emulation was just kind of, it
Speaker 2:  was sort of nowhere on the iPhone. So I guess for them to say no, we're going
Speaker 2:  to continue to not allow it is not totally out of character.
Speaker 6:  Exactly. Like yeah, I wasn't surprised. I was just pissed off. Like I
Speaker 6:  was just like, I wasted a year of my life working on this and
Speaker 6:  'cause you told me I could release it. That was really just all I was feeling.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's fair. That's fair. So what do you, at that moment you're faced again
Speaker 2:  with this same decision of like, okay, do I just call this a
Speaker 2:  successful project, I learned how to use Swift, let me just move on with
Speaker 2:  my life or do I go the other way? I know the answer. Yeah, historically
Speaker 2:  speaking but what, what is that? What do you, what is that moment like? Yeah
Speaker 6:  And this time I was just so pissed off. I was just like, you know,
Speaker 6:  this is not okay. I am gonna get this out there somehow. It's just
Speaker 6:  like really what I came to and I did at that point I really didn't know what
Speaker 6:  it would be but I was just like, I just wanted to show Apple that they can't
Speaker 6:  treat developers kinda like this. It was really just like, I was like, you
Speaker 6:  can't treat us like this. You can't tell us one thing and then change your
Speaker 6:  mind the next year 'cause real people are spending real time doing this kind
Speaker 6:  of thing. So I, yeah, I just motivated to just, I dunno, prove them
Speaker 6:  wrong. This is the best I could say. And so yeah, I was like I'll figure
Speaker 6:  out a way.
Speaker 2:  So then next project is figure out a way like how do you,
Speaker 2:  how do you even start?
Speaker 6:  I just got lucky honestly, apple had also just around that time made it so
Speaker 6:  that you can install apps from Xcode for free with
Speaker 6:  a free Apple id. Like they just changed that rule of right around now so
Speaker 6:  that students could start developing. And so I saw that and I was like, wait,
Speaker 6:  you can install apps for free If, you just have an Apple id. There's
Speaker 6:  something there. Like I was like that's all the technical thing I needed
Speaker 6:  to, I could make something from that. And so that was just like the beginning
Speaker 6:  of Alt Store was like, okay, I gotta do something with this free Apple
Speaker 6:  ID side loading from Xcode thing that Apple has just announced.
Speaker 6:  And then I was basically just like took a few years to
Speaker 6:  research that, build it up, find out what would be the most convenient flow
Speaker 6:  'cause yeah, there are a lot of obstacles with that. It was apps installed
Speaker 6:  this way only could last seven days. You could only have three apps installed
Speaker 6:  at a time this method. So it was just like kind of trying to come up with
Speaker 6:  creative ways to make a lot of these restrictions not as annoying. Like the
Speaker 6:  fact that Alt Server's a thing was the number one that alt server could just
Speaker 6:  refresh your apps every week in the background. And when I thought of that,
Speaker 6:  that's when I was like, okay, I think there's something here we can
Speaker 6:  at least work with that's good enough.
Speaker 2:  So when did the first version of alt store like work,
Speaker 2:  what was sort of the first version of it that you had that you were like,
Speaker 2:  okay this, this does the thing that I need it to do?
Speaker 6:  I think that was 2019 is when I finally like had put
Speaker 6:  together all the pieces into One Flow, whereas in like I had a program
Speaker 6:  on a computer that could install Alt store onto my phone and then Alt Store
Speaker 6:  could send apps to that device or to my computer and then reinstall it. And
Speaker 6:  then it was early 2019 I was like, okay, this can
Speaker 6:  work. Okay. Like just seeing it actually work in practice, it was totally
Speaker 6:  janky. Like the UI was horrible, but just like the fact I could press a button
Speaker 6:  on my phone and it would do everything, send it to Alt Server and install
Speaker 6:  it was just honestly kind of magical.
Speaker 2:  So explain to me why that worked okay in in the sort of infrastructure of
Speaker 2:  Apple's universe. Like why did that system work?
Speaker 6:  Because, so the way Apple allows students to test out their apps
Speaker 6:  is they have to have a Mac and they have to be using Xcode and they have
Speaker 6:  to plug their phone into Xcode and then they have to install an app from
Speaker 6:  Xcode onto the phone. Like you can't just download a file and do it. It's
Speaker 6:  all through Xcode and all through a computer. And so Alt Server
Speaker 6:  is basically replicating everything Xcode does. You can have an
Speaker 6:  app file, but iOS can't install an app file on itself. You have to send it
Speaker 6:  to a computer. And then Alt Server does the same stuff Xcode
Speaker 6:  does behind the scenes to install it back onto the phone as if you're a developer
Speaker 6:  testing out yourself.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. And you were able to basically build a thing that lets
Speaker 2:  anyone kind of mimic that system for themselves? Yes. When I
Speaker 2:  set it up it was, I wouldn't say it was a lot of work, but it wasn't no work.
Speaker 2:  It's,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's a lot. It's a bit, yeah. Especially on the Mac, there's the
Speaker 6:  mail plugin for a long time that was just, oh yeah, really it
Speaker 6:  was, yeah, it was confusing to everyone and I was like, oh this is too nerdy
Speaker 6:  to try to explain even to people why it matters but just, yeah. Yeah, people
Speaker 6:  got through it.
Speaker 2:  Well so, and this is, this is, I feel like the, the sort of ongoing story
Speaker 2:  here is you're, you're finding these increasingly complicated ways to do
Speaker 2:  this and continuing discover that there is so much demand for something
Speaker 2:  like Delta that people will jump through basically any hoops that you ask
Speaker 2:  them to jump through in order to do this.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, the biggest thing I was surprised about with all stores, we need to
Speaker 6:  get your Apple ID and password to like log in with your account.
Speaker 6:  And I was like, wow, we really are just asking people to trust us and give
Speaker 6:  us your Apple ID of password. And I mean we're, we do everything we can with
Speaker 6:  it. We literally don't touch ourselves, we send it straight to Apple. But
Speaker 6:  I was like, ooh, that's a big scary thing that you really just
Speaker 6:  aren't supposed to give your password to random people. And then nope, people
Speaker 6:  are still giving us their password as if they don't care. I'm like, this
Speaker 6:  is cool. But also it makes you nervous for security as a whole that people
Speaker 6:  are just doing, just not thinking about it.
Speaker 2:  Oh, for sure. And it puts you in a really interesting position I would think
Speaker 2:  as the, as the developer of this to say okay, what is
Speaker 2:  this thing? Like am I just building this as sort of a fun side
Speaker 2:  project for people who wanna play Pokemon on their phones? Which comes with
Speaker 2:  I think one set of like security and privacy. Yes. Implications.
Speaker 2:  Like to some extent honestly If, you send your Apple ID and password
Speaker 2:  to just a dude, I don't think you have any reasonable expectation of privacy.
Speaker 2:  Exactly. Like I think it's good thing that you were taking care of people's
Speaker 2:  privacy as best you could. But I think for me as the user, I
Speaker 2:  deserve what I'm getting at that point, right? Yeah. Yeah. But then if you're,
Speaker 2:  if you're like a company that is, that has a terms of service and is set
Speaker 2:  up to make money and you're like, we're in this for the long haul and we're
Speaker 2:  serious about it, I think that changes both the way you have to
Speaker 2:  treat stuff and the way that I can expect you to treat stuff. Yes. And it
Speaker 2:  seems like as you were going through this, you were also trying to decide
Speaker 2:  like how professionalized do I want this thing to be?
Speaker 2:  Is that, is that fair?
Speaker 6:  That's pretty fair because when the first version of Al Store that launched
Speaker 6:  was literally just like a Delta installer. The only app in it was
Speaker 6:  Delta. It could install Delta. And I just knew that was
Speaker 6:  important. But even at that point I knew I wanted alt store to be a bigger
Speaker 6:  platform. That was like kind of what motivated it was like I didn't wanna
Speaker 6:  build a whole nother workaround just to install Delta. The fact that I could
Speaker 6:  do it for alt store and for other apps too made it more appealing to me.
Speaker 6:  I was like fine, I can do the work and then lots of other apps can take advantage
Speaker 6:  of it. And so it was always the plan to expand beyond Delta,
Speaker 6:  but I just didn't know really what that would look like until probably like
Speaker 6:  a year or so after we launched and I started, we started actually having
Speaker 6:  some third party apps wanting to be on the store. And then I got a sense
Speaker 6:  of, okay, this is the type of apps people wanted to install, this is what
Speaker 6:  I gotta be dealing with. And yeah, that's helped a lot.
Speaker 2:  See so what, what was that like? We're gonna get into the kind of history
Speaker 2:  moved towards you a little bit aspect of this in just a sec, but I
Speaker 2:  am curious in that moment the idea of like, I'm gonna get my third party
Speaker 2:  app store to be sort of, you know, legitimate in Apple size.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Was completely off the table like 20 19, 20 20. There was just no world
Speaker 2:  in which that was gonna happen. But you're like, you're talking about, you
Speaker 2:  know, other apps that want to do this kind of stuff. What were you starting
Speaker 2:  to see? What was kind of the, the like unifying thesis behind apps that
Speaker 2:  wanted to be part of this thing you were doing?
Speaker 6:  I, I mean at first it was just any app that wasn't allowed in the app store.
Speaker 6:  Okay. And honestly is still a big appeal date. It's like for whatever
Speaker 6:  reason that was rejected for whatever type of rule, they just could be the
Speaker 6:  app store and so then they'd see alt store and then they'd be like, oh an
Speaker 6:  alternative. There are a lot of emulators like obviously. Sure. So there's
Speaker 6:  plenty of those. There's stuff you can expect. Like I Torrent had like an
Speaker 6:  app and so you can be like, yeah I can see why Apple wouldn't approve it.
Speaker 6:  But stuff like that. UTM, the virtual machine app, just
Speaker 6:  running Windows on your iPad, really cool. Not loud in the app store. So
Speaker 6:  it was just like a bunch of different random project or another
Speaker 6:  one I liked that I think is really cool old os, if you've heard of that one.
Speaker 6:  No it's so, it's like a high schooler just recreated iOS four
Speaker 6:  in Swift ui and so it's just like the whole exp If, you open the app and
Speaker 6:  it's the home screen from iOS four, you can open all the apps and it looks
Speaker 6:  exactly like it did back in the day. Oh that's awesome. And it's really cool.
Speaker 6:  And so it's just like, oh a fun little idea that not Latin app store.
Speaker 6:  So it's, yeah, a bunch of stuff like that. So I launched alt store and the
Speaker 6:  first year was really great but the first year was also a lot and it was
Speaker 6:  just me working on at the time. And then I honestly was like, what am
Speaker 6:  I doing here? Am I gonna keep with alt store? Is this ever gonna be a real
Speaker 6:  thing? Should I just like move on to something else now I was really going,
Speaker 6:  trying to figure out what I wanna do and then it was really that point I
Speaker 6:  realized what I wanted was I saw basically that the US was investigating
Speaker 6:  Apple and that the EU was investigating Apple around this time. And I was
Speaker 6:  like, you know what? I feel like there is gonna be something that happens
Speaker 6:  in the next few years. I wanna be ready for that but I need help. And
Speaker 6:  that's when I basically brought on my partner Shane Gill, who is my best
Speaker 6:  friend and I've lived with for like 10 years. And I was like, Hey, I need
Speaker 6:  you with this with me. I need just do it together. I need you to do all the
Speaker 6:  business stuff. And so I can just focus on the programming and then we can
Speaker 6:  make that happen. And at that point we started like making the
Speaker 6:  plans for what alt store is today or at least an alt store in the EU alt
Speaker 6:  store pal.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So you, you actually really were betting on the theory that eventually
Speaker 2:  this was gonna be a real thing that you could do and not just sort
Speaker 2:  of a series of ever more elaborate attacks.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Yeah. By that time I was convinced it would happen. Just I didn't
Speaker 6:  know when but just at some point in the future.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. Okay. So, and this was like peak covid.
Speaker 2:  If I'm, if I'm doing my timing math here correctly, everything's weird at
Speaker 2:  this time and you're like, well let's, let's just go for it.
Speaker 6:  Everything's weird. I'm, yeah, everyone's reevaluating their lives. My original
Speaker 6:  plan was, I was like, Hey Shane, let's move to New Zealand together. Let's
Speaker 6:  just escape everything. Let's build this in New Zealand. 'cause I'm a New Zealand
Speaker 6:  citizen so it'd be cool to go home for me. But that didn't work out. It was
Speaker 6:  too hard to get New Zealand during Covid. Yeah, understandably So. We're
Speaker 6:  in Dallas now,
Speaker 2:  Which
Speaker 6:  Is the same thing. It's
Speaker 2:  Like this close, yeah.
Speaker 6:  Space close.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So you start building this thing and was the idea
Speaker 2:  we wanna build sort of a full app store? Like was that
Speaker 2:  is is it as simple as that? That was the pitch.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. When Shane Karen board, that was the full pitch. Like we're gonna build
Speaker 6:  a real app store and show people what life could be like if there
Speaker 6:  were other apps. Just like just be the example and then whenever it was official
Speaker 6:  be the official like be an official store.
Speaker 2:  And what was, what were developers saying? Were you like reaching out to
Speaker 2:  folks being like, do you wanna be part of this and what were they telling
Speaker 2:  you?
Speaker 6:  Honestly, we didn't need to be reaching out to anyone. People were just reaching
Speaker 6:  out to us. Like there are a lot of people who just have app ideas that just
Speaker 6:  aren't getting in the app store and just, and even I'm like, wow, there are
Speaker 6:  just so many apps that like were getting like reaching out to us. I'm like
Speaker 6:  Oh wow, that was rejected. That was rejected. So we've just, yeah, people
Speaker 6:  just reaching out for us.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And were you having any contact with Apple at this point? Obvi,
Speaker 2:  other than you know, those two conversations at WBDC, was there any inclination
Speaker 2:  that Apple was even sort of aware of your existence throughout this process?
Speaker 6:  We did. At one point when the EU started investigating stuff,
Speaker 6:  me and Shane sent an email to the executives at Apple basically saying,
Speaker 6:  Hey y'all, I think the EU may be going too much and do you
Speaker 6:  like we just reach out, Hey like we're here and we don't want like a crazy
Speaker 6:  world of side loading. Do you wanna like be on the same page here? And they
Speaker 6:  didn't respond at all. But we were at the time just thinking we don't want
Speaker 6:  a crazy free for all. And that's what it seemed like maybe the EU was gonna
Speaker 6:  be, we wanted a more restricted siloing world where the app store
Speaker 6:  was still the main app store. Why? I really think that's what makes
Speaker 6:  iOS so good for like the vast majority people. Like it is just so simple
Speaker 6:  that you can get any app that you trust through one store. I think
Speaker 6:  that's really valuable. It's why like so many people I know personally use
Speaker 6:  an iPhone that aren't techies. And so I just always knew that there
Speaker 6:  needed to be a way for siloing to exist without taking over the app store
Speaker 6:  or taking like so many apps away from it.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So you then are watching the regulation stuff happening. Are you like
Speaker 2:  barreling through all the, you know, DMA white papers and trying to
Speaker 2:  get the deep sense of what's going? Like how into this were you as that
Speaker 2:  regulation was happening
Speaker 6:  Once the DMA was like an actual thing and they were talking about Oh yeah,
Speaker 6:  we were very much deep in it and then we were just like, we gotta be ready
Speaker 6:  for anything li because literally until Apple announced what they were doing,
Speaker 6:  we just were like, are we gonna be a siloing tool? Are we gonna be a a full
Speaker 6:  app store? Are we gonna exist at all? Like we just had no idea what was gonna
Speaker 6:  come next. We just knew that there would be some way of installing apps.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And so I guess with that idea you can kind of keep
Speaker 2:  building Delta and alt store the way you had been without making too
Speaker 2:  many kind of unchangeable decisions at
Speaker 2:  that point?
Speaker 6:  Yes. We basically were working on like stuff that we knew would be true
Speaker 6:  no matter what. Like we were building up like the UI for browsing apps and
Speaker 6:  like we were expanding like, or building the Patreon flow so that people
Speaker 6:  could connect their Patreons and and install that. 'cause we just knew no
Speaker 6:  matter what, that would be good for this world. We just
Speaker 6:  didn't go into like the really technical stuff about like the actual installing
Speaker 6:  process. Right. It was just basically making the app look as much like a
Speaker 6:  store as it could be. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That makes sense. And at that point, how are you thinking about like the
Speaker 2:  business of Delta? You've been working on this thing for an awfully long
Speaker 2:  time without making any money on it. I'm assuming there were conversations
Speaker 2:  about like how do we, how do we all get rich from this thing that clearly
Speaker 2:  lots of people want?
Speaker 6:  I, people do keep asking me but the thing that I've
Speaker 6:  believed in and what Shane, like Shane, before he even joined Al Store, he
Speaker 6:  was the one that convinced me to make a Patreon for all this in the first
Speaker 6:  place. He was like, Hey, when you're working on Delta and Al Store just have
Speaker 6:  a Patreon the side to support yourself. 'cause honestly I thought my original
Speaker 6:  plan was to release Alt store and Delta and then move on to something else
Speaker 6:  and like, like just let it exist and let people install it. But Shane was
Speaker 6:  the one telling me, no people wanna support creators right now. You
Speaker 6:  should just have a Patreon that people wanna subscribe to and just support
Speaker 6:  future development. And so I start, I launched alt store at that and
Speaker 6:  it did really well. Like it has paid for everything ever since I launched,
Speaker 6:  started Alt store. We really believe that's a really important thing that
Speaker 6:  should exist. 'cause developers right now you can't sell apps
Speaker 6:  through Paton in the app store. And it's just such a really good way I think
Speaker 6:  for creators to build like a relationship with their audience and just
Speaker 6:  people also don't mind spending a few bucks to a person
Speaker 6:  but they do mind spending a few bucks on an app. Yep. So it's just like very
Speaker 6:  different relationship. And so we are basically just trying to really
Speaker 6:  promote the Patreon idea. Our own income basically is just through the
Speaker 6:  Patreon. We're still selling or having access to our betas for our
Speaker 6:  patrons and that's worked out pretty well as a way of monetizing Delta
Speaker 6:  honestly.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Yeah, I mean even just the idea of thinking of an app developer as
Speaker 2:  a creator in the same way that you think about like a content creator as
Speaker 2:  a creator is really interesting and is totally not
Speaker 2:  how most people perceive it. Right. Exactly. And and I think, I think it's
Speaker 2:  coming around a little bit like personally at least I've seen a lot more
Speaker 2:  of the sort of bootstrapped one person app become a
Speaker 2:  thing that people like in a way that I didn't and they like associate the
Speaker 2:  app with the person who makes it. Yes. Yeah. But I think for most people
Speaker 2:  it's all so faceless, right? Yes. Like you just, it's just an app that exists.
Speaker 2:  I don't know if it's made by one person or 10,000 and I don't care. I'm just
Speaker 2:  mad that they're charging me money. Yep. And it's interesting to think that
Speaker 2:  like maybe the business model is part of the problem there that because it
Speaker 2:  all just sits in the app store and it is so divorced from
Speaker 2:  personality and people that maybe that's the problem. So actually connecting
Speaker 2:  Patreon to that is, is a really interesting way of just changing the way
Speaker 2:  people think about what like an app is and how it gets made.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, exactly. And I'm so, yeah, I'm really excited for that. And I'll, another
Speaker 6:  nice benefit is we can just have our apps be free
Speaker 6:  and then people just get the betas and, but so it means there's no features
Speaker 6:  that are locked behind paywalls like forever. It's just a, you can wait forever
Speaker 6:  and get it for free or If you just want early access, you can donate. And
Speaker 6:  I think that's more appealing to people to like when they're trying to support
Speaker 6:  an app versus, oh you've locked away a feature and now I can never use it
Speaker 6:  unless I pay. It's like, yeah that difference I think makes a huge
Speaker 6:  deal.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no, I, I totally agree. So, okay, so right before the
Speaker 2:  DMA drops and I guess, what was it like March of this year
Speaker 2:  when Apple put out its third party app store plans?
Speaker 6:  It was end of January. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So this year, yeah, this year. Apple right before that,
Speaker 2:  what was kind of the status of Delta and alt store? It sounds
Speaker 2:  like it's, it's growing. People are using it. Like how, how were things?
Speaker 6:  Things were good. We had like at that point, like 4 million users on
Speaker 6:  alt store, like just existing. I was like, oh wow, this is going great.
Speaker 6:  Things are going great. At Delta we had been prioritizing basically a new
Speaker 6:  version of Delta 1.5 to release alongside
Speaker 6:  whatever Apple announced. And so we just like, we're working on that. But
Speaker 6:  then basically by January we're just like, okay, everything's in a good
Speaker 6:  spot. We're ready to go. We just need to know what the hell is
Speaker 6:  happening. And so we were just basically just waiting around to see like,
Speaker 6:  okay, we can do this. We have like the store had
Speaker 6:  been finished by then, like all the UI was done, Delta was ready, clip was
Speaker 6:  ready. So,
Speaker 2:  So you, you have this thing and you're like, this exists, we made it, it's
Speaker 2:  good. We have absolutely no idea what we're about to do with it.
Speaker 6:  Exactly. That is exactly where we were.
Speaker 2:  What a strange place to
Speaker 6:  Be. It was very strange. It was, yeah. 'cause we're just, every day we're
Speaker 6:  like, what do we do? Like we can't move forward in a lot of things
Speaker 6:  but, so it was just a lot of planning and strategizing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that makes sense. So then end of January, apple drops
Speaker 2:  like a million press releases and technical documents about how all this
Speaker 2:  is gonna work. What, what happens to you on that day? What do you do?
Speaker 6:  Wow. What? That was a overwhelming day like for sure.
Speaker 6:  And the first thing that we try to do is figure out, okay,
Speaker 6:  can we exist at all in this new world? Because yeah, there's all these like
Speaker 6:  restrictions and we're trying to figure out what the hell like an alternative
Speaker 6:  marketplace is and we're like, and so yes we're, we spend that whole day
Speaker 6:  basically trying just to parse what Apple's announced. And then we basically
Speaker 6:  are like, okay, we think we can do this. We think we can
Speaker 6:  meet the criteria if we get very creative. 'cause yeah, the criteria was
Speaker 6:  like a lot of things like you needed to have like the standby
Speaker 6:  letter, we need to have a subsidiary in the eu. Right.
Speaker 6:  And just like a bunch of things that we just sat down like, okay,
Speaker 6:  we gotta make all this happen in a month basically. 'cause we're like, okay,
Speaker 6:  we have it until March 7th was like the DMA compliance day. I'm like, okay,
Speaker 6:  let's set up a subsidiary. Let's get the standby figured out. Let's build
Speaker 6:  everything. 'cause also they announced all the stuff we had to build and
Speaker 6:  it's like, okay, let's build everything we need to do. And then for the next
Speaker 6:  month was like extreme crunch time, just like getting
Speaker 6:  everything done. Shane honestly was incredible. He was calling
Speaker 6:  so many countries to figure out where we could incorporate. Oh wow. We finally
Speaker 6:  incorporated in Ireland. So we have a nice subsidiary in Ireland, which is
Speaker 6:  great. He was the one talking to banks to get someone to
Speaker 6:  believe in two people who are trying to do something crazy and they need
Speaker 6:  this. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  How hard was that process? You're like, so we build a game emulator and also
Speaker 2:  other app stores. I'm imagining a bunch of banks are just like, this is a
Speaker 2:  prank call and hang up on you
Speaker 6:  A lot did. Yeah. It so many people just like wouldn't listen to us. It was
Speaker 6:  true pure luck that we found one person lo, his name's Logan,
Speaker 6:  he just like Morgan Stanley and he was just understood what
Speaker 6:  we were doing and really wanted to go out of his way to help us.
Speaker 6:  And I honestly, if we had not met Logan, I don't know if we would've got
Speaker 6:  this all figured out, but he was like, okay, let's do this. I believe in
Speaker 6:  y'all. I can work with my bosses. We can make it happen. That that was
Speaker 6:  a big win getting that one for sure.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean I remember when the news came out thinking that there were
Speaker 2:  like, you described a bunch of technical challenges, but there were always
Speaker 2:  gonna be a bunch of technical challenges, right? Yeah. I feel like that you,
Speaker 2:  you sort of know going in, there's gonna be a bunch of weird work you have
Speaker 2:  to do to get this thing to comply with what Apple wants. But the business
Speaker 2:  challenges of just like the, the hoops you had to jump through as an
Speaker 2:  organization seemed like they were designed to keep almost everybody out
Speaker 2:  except for the, the truest of true believers
Speaker 2:  and maybe just the most stubborn people building this thing.
Speaker 6:  Yes, exactly.
Speaker 2:  And, and part of me wonders if if going back a few months, apple just deeply
Speaker 2:  underestimated your willing to your willingness to pick this fight after
Speaker 2:  so many years of picking this fight. You're like, I've been through your
Speaker 2:  nonsense before Apple. Oh,
Speaker 6:  I I, yeah, I know they were caught off guard. They, they told us that they,
Speaker 6:  like when we, when we ended up going to the lab and everything, they just
Speaker 6:  said straight up, oh we did not expect anyone to be
Speaker 6:  this prepared, especially as a two person team. They just did not expect
Speaker 6:  us to be as prepared as we were. which I think
Speaker 2:  It had to feel good.
Speaker 6:  Oh it did feel good. I was like cool. But at the same time I was like, well
Speaker 6:  then let us launch. It was like, cool. Okay, that's amazing. Let us launch,
Speaker 6:  we're ready.
Speaker 2:  Was there any question for a team of two whether to invest all
Speaker 2:  this time on something that at least for now and potentially forever
Speaker 2:  is only going to exist in the eu? Like there's a lot of people in the eu
Speaker 2:  but there's a lot of people not in the EU also.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean, so two parts of like one, I do think this is gonna come outside
Speaker 6:  the EU at some point. I think it's a just question of time. So
Speaker 6:  I, I expected to see within a few years it'll expand out to like, I don't
Speaker 6:  know, Japan, United States eventually. So, so we viewed this as like the
Speaker 6:  beginning of a much longer process us to expand.
Speaker 6:  But then the other thing was like we had nothing to lose. This is literally
Speaker 6:  all we're doing. All our income is working on Al Store of Delta. We're like,
Speaker 6:  well we might as well just go all the way with it. Like what else? Like why
Speaker 6:  not?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean I think the long bet I think is probably a safe one. Again,
Speaker 2:  it's a question of how long it takes. Yeah. But it, I do think you're probably
Speaker 2:  right. It also seems like you were in a position where even
Speaker 2:  if it didn't sort of immediately reach a ton of people, you were gonna get
Speaker 2:  so much notice just because this is such a big thing and such a big change
Speaker 2:  that like I all of a sudden alt sort just appeared in so many headlines
Speaker 2:  in like February and March of this year, which is like, yes.
Speaker 6:  That was very, very surreal seeing that all of a sudden. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean it's so funny 'cause like explaining alt story to people, it's
Speaker 2:  like, okay, it is this bizarre sort of convoluted
Speaker 2:  experience where you have to set up a server and I'm seeing this in like
Speaker 2:  mainstream news articles.
Speaker 6:  I know. I'm like, oh my God. It's
Speaker 2:  Like, oh my God, if my mom asked me what alt story is, I'm not gonna know
Speaker 2:  how to answer that question for her.
Speaker 6:  I same, I, yeah, I explained to my friends, I'm like, eh, don't worry.
Speaker 6:  It's just a tool to install apps. That's it.
Speaker 2:  So, okay, so then we're almost to the present time, but I feel like we still
Speaker 2:  have not gotten to the single wildest part of this whole timeline. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  That's been accurate.
Speaker 2:  So you're, you're building the store, things are going well, you launch,
Speaker 2:  I think on launch day, right? March 7th, was it ready to go?
Speaker 6:  No, we, we were ready. We were all ready
Speaker 6:  to go and that was the beginning of like this frustration. So
Speaker 6:  we were, yeah, we were invited to a lab in Cork for the Apple
Speaker 6:  to like help us implement our backend and everything. So like a week long
Speaker 6:  lab for us just to work with Apple Engineers to get everything working. So
Speaker 6:  then we flew out to Cork, it was like the week before March 5th. So the end
Speaker 6:  of it, the end of February, we flew out day one, I showed up, I said,
Speaker 6:  okay, here's everything. We're ready to go. Can we launch? And then
Speaker 6:  they were like, oh hold on.
Speaker 2:  They expected you to show up and be like, I'd like to build an app store.
Speaker 2:  And instead you show up and you're like, I have built an app store.
Speaker 6:  They literally, I really think they expected everyone to show up with like
Speaker 6:  no code base, like to just start from scratch and how to do this. And yeah,
Speaker 6:  so we show up and we're like, here's the entire product. It has store pages,
Speaker 6:  everything you could possibly need downloading works. And then they were
Speaker 6:  just like, oh wow. Yeah, just very clearly. Yeah, they were not expecting
Speaker 6:  that. And so it basically was then, okay, so Monday I was like trying to
Speaker 6:  pressure them, can we launch tomorrow? Can we launch tomorrow? I watch 71 4
Speaker 6:  is coming out tomorrow, can we be there? And then it just
Speaker 6:  became clear that this whole process was gonna be much longer than
Speaker 6:  we expected for a lot of boring reasons. Like basically just
Speaker 6:  legal, like giving them documents, having them review documents,
Speaker 6:  stuff like that. So I 74 came out and me and
Speaker 6:  Shane were very bummed because we were like, we were ready to launch
Speaker 6:  on launch day. We were all ready to go and then, ugh. So that was
Speaker 6:  frustrating.
Speaker 2:  So how long did it take before you actually got the thing up and running
Speaker 6:  Then? I think it was two months later. Like it was, yeah, it was April 17th.
Speaker 6:  Like yeah, so yeah, from May, from March 5th to
Speaker 6:  April 17th was just waiting. It's a month and a half. And
Speaker 6:  so we did that and then, yeah, the reception was immediately just
Speaker 6:  phenomenal. People just so excited and, but then we also immediately saw,
Speaker 6:  which we expected that Delta was the main story. Sure that Delta in the
Speaker 6:  app store was the big deal. But we had to figure out what to do and we knew
Speaker 6:  that would be the outcome if we released Delta in the app store, that Delta
Speaker 6:  would get like its big moments to be everywhere. And we just were like, you
Speaker 6:  know what, that's fine. It's free marketing for alt store if everyone just
Speaker 6:  knows about Delta and then they talk about it and then they get it through
Speaker 6:  alt store in the eu. So you just,
Speaker 2:  You just glossed past part of it though. Like the, the whole Apple suddenly
Speaker 2:  allows emulators in the app store. Yeah. You say that as
Speaker 2:  If, you expected that to happen. I don't think anybody expected that to happen.
Speaker 6:  Not at all It the most, yeah. Unexpected thing that could have happened.
Speaker 6:  And me and Shane had different reactions at first. Shane was
Speaker 6:  more like, what this changes everything now we gotta think through.
Speaker 6:  And my just reaction was, wow, what validation
Speaker 6:  that Apple had to change the rules to allow emulators because
Speaker 6:  they were threatened by us about to launch with an emulator. Like that to
Speaker 6:  me was like invigorating. I was like, this is, yes, it means we're doing
Speaker 6:  something right. That Apple is literally like doing something I never thought
Speaker 6:  they'd do because it was the only way they could try to make the
Speaker 6:  story. Not the EU now has the best apps outside the EU has, doesn't
Speaker 6:  have the coolest apps and I just knew Apple like yeah they just couldn't
Speaker 6:  have that story. Which is also why em are allowed worldwide is my guess is
Speaker 6:  the story just could not have been the EU has better apps than the rest of
Speaker 6:  the world.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no I, I think that's exactly right. And it is very hard to argue that
Speaker 2:  this wasn't specifically about Delta. Like I just can't, the timing,
Speaker 2:  it's too, it
Speaker 6:  Is all about Delta it because we haven't had a direct
Speaker 6:  confirmation from Apple, but our app Delta was being notarized for like five
Speaker 6:  weeks. They changed this rule, it's approved the next day. Oh wow.
Speaker 2:  Like,
Speaker 6:  Oh wow. It's almost like they were holding it to figure out what they could
Speaker 6:  do about it.
Speaker 2:  Did you get any heads up that they were gonna make this change? Nope.
Speaker 6:  Nothing at all.
Speaker 2:  Well, and it, I would guess after that happened you would've
Speaker 2:  expected it to be big. It sounds like you did expect it to be big, but I
Speaker 2:  feel like it's been, it's certainly been bigger than I expected. Like
Speaker 6:  It is bigger than I expected. I can,
Speaker 2:  It's been nuts man.
Speaker 6:  It's so validating. Like I really can't like, because yeah, we're doing this
Speaker 6:  because we just really believe that people just want to play old
Speaker 6:  Nintendo games or old old games. We just, I think it's just a thing people
Speaker 6:  wanna do and for so long everyone just says no, that's only for the
Speaker 6:  nerds. It's only for like people who know what they're doing. And I've just
Speaker 6:  been like, you just have to make it accessible. That's all it means. Like
Speaker 6:  all you gotta do, if it's accessible, people will know how to do it and they
Speaker 6:  will love it. We we're seeing that that is exactly the case and yes. So even
Speaker 6:  more people than I thought are enjoying it. It is the most surreal thing
Speaker 6:  seeing it not only in the app store but being the top app
Speaker 6:  in the app store
Speaker 2:  For like a long time. Are you still the number one app in the app store?
Speaker 6:  I mean, I think last time I checked, but yeah, since we've launched we've
Speaker 6:  been number one and yeah, so surreal. Like
Speaker 6:  the most, like anytime in my life I've never felt more like
Speaker 6:  I actually am dreaming right now. Like I need like pinching myself like,
Speaker 6:  'cause it was just too perfect. Like work on this app for 10 years and then
Speaker 6:  day one in the app store, it's the top. I was just incredible.
Speaker 2:  Has it changed what you think about how to do all of this? I mean, If, you
Speaker 2:  had charged 2 99 for Delta. You would've made a crap ton of money by
Speaker 2:  now. Like have you, are, are you thinking about the business of all of this
Speaker 2:  differently after it's blown up the way that it has?
Speaker 6:  I think we want this to be bigger than just like Delta.
Speaker 6:  And we want this to cause like actual change in
Speaker 6:  like the emulation scene or in the gaming sphere. Just like we want to
Speaker 6:  make this more accessible for everyone. We want people to start talking about
Speaker 6:  it and to have real conversations about it without just being like, piracy.
Speaker 6:  Piracy. And so a lot of what we're doing is we thought Delta
Speaker 6:  to make that change happen, we had to like, it had to be free, had to be,
Speaker 6:  everyone had to have it. And that's, I think just what we're focused on really
Speaker 6:  is like, as long as we're, we're making, like we're making enough to support
Speaker 6:  ourselves and so we're not in need of more money, but I just think for Delta
Speaker 6:  have the biggest impact. It's just make it as fully free and
Speaker 6:  accessible to as many people as possible and let them just start reliving
Speaker 6:  games.
Speaker 2:  Are you worried at all about legal ramifications? I mean there was
Speaker 2:  obviously the, the yuzu thing that happened kind of right before this. It's
Speaker 2:  been a, it's been a weird moment in the emulation community. Have has, have
Speaker 2:  you heard from any Nintendo lawyers?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That came out as we're also like in Europe trying to launch this. I'm
Speaker 6:  like, oh, interesting. Very, very relevant to us. But
Speaker 6:  I'm not gonna say I'm not nervous about things, but
Speaker 6:  I am confident in what we're doing. I've learned a lot of what
Speaker 6:  not to do over the past 10 years. And I think that we are really
Speaker 6:  trying to show how you can do something like this legal. Like we're not yuzu,
Speaker 6:  we're not emulating a current generation console. We're not doing
Speaker 6:  a lot of things that other emulators get in trouble. Like we're, there's
Speaker 6:  no DRM we have to deal with to like for the the game. So just the game files
Speaker 6:  ripped from cartridges. So we don't have to do anything like that.
Speaker 6:  We're doing everything we can to do it right. And there was no world that
Speaker 6:  I wouldn't have done this. I guess that is a better way. Like I wouldn't
Speaker 6:  have got this far and not released Delta. I just had to Yeah,
Speaker 2:  No, I, I think that Well and I think that's part of why this moment of your
Speaker 2:  story is so interesting because we're at the beginning of
Speaker 2:  this weird new era of apps in the app store and
Speaker 2:  I think a lot of stuff is changing and a lot is gonna continue to change.
Speaker 2:  But we're also, in a funny way kind of at the end of your 10 year
Speaker 2:  journey, like the this you, you finally finished the thing
Speaker 6:  That, that is what it feels like. It's really weird, but I'm like, wow,
Speaker 6:  it actually happened like it got in the app store and yes,
Speaker 6:  it does feel like the culmination of that whole journey, which is very
Speaker 6:  weird. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Does that make it feel like I finally got to do it and it worked
Speaker 2:  and it was huge and it was awesome and now I can go do something else?
Speaker 6:  I honestly, the, the fact that Delta's doing so well has just motivated me
Speaker 6:  to just wanna work on it so much for right now because I've just been working
Speaker 6:  on it in isolation. Assuming one day it could like be a big deal
Speaker 6:  That I don't know, actually seeing everyone play it right now has made me
Speaker 6:  really motivated to like really focus on it again. And also because so much
Speaker 6:  of the past two years has been like a lot priority working on alt store and
Speaker 6:  now that we launched alt store, we can just like have some fun with Delta
Speaker 6:  again. Like there's just so many fun features I want to add that I haven't
Speaker 6:  had time to, 'cause we had to get alt store up and running for this deadline,
Speaker 6:  but, so I'm looking forward to a lot of that. But I don't know if this is
Speaker 6:  a 10 year thing. I don't know if this is the beginning of like another 10
Speaker 6:  year adventure To me, I think it's, I'll work on Delta for a bit and
Speaker 6:  I think I gotta finish up what Alt store is like. We still have some to do
Speaker 6:  to prove it out, like we gotta get the third party apps on there. We gotta
Speaker 6:  build up the platform and I think that's, to me, the next step
Speaker 6:  is just making sure that Alt Store is a real app store that people are using
Speaker 6:  and happy with and then maybe I'll be done
Speaker 2:  And then then you will have resoundingly defeated Apple, which very few
Speaker 2:  people can say,
Speaker 6:  That's what I want. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  All right. We gotta take a break and then I have to tell you about this weird
Speaker 2:  obsession I've
Speaker 8:  a Prop G Pod special sponsored by Canva. You can find it on the Prop G
Speaker 8:  pod wherever you get your podcasts.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. I've spent most of the last month and really most of
Speaker 2:  the last year talking about and testing AI gadgets. It's been
Speaker 2:  a long time, maybe since the early VR days, but maybe even as far
Speaker 2:  back as the early smartphone era since we've seen this many new things with
Speaker 2:  this many new ideas, most of those ideas right now
Speaker 2:  are very bad. Well, not bad necessarily, it's just that they don't
Speaker 2:  work so they're bad. You know what I mean? The Humane AI pin has
Speaker 2:  some interesting theories about how you might use a device without a screen
Speaker 2:  and without getting sucked in and distracted. It's just that none of those
Speaker 2:  things work very well. The Rabbit R one just kind of puts an AI
Speaker 2:  chatbot on a device that looks like a rearranged phone, and again,
Speaker 2:  none of it works very well so far. For me at least, there is only
Speaker 2:  one thing about AI that really feels like it works and
Speaker 2:  actually makes my life better, and that is voice notes, a good microphone
Speaker 2:  plus good transcription software plus some useful models for
Speaker 2:  summarizing and grabbing the most important bits of what I say. It works
Speaker 2:  and it's awesome. I kind of feel like a doctor now running around talking
Speaker 2:  nonsense into my tape recorder like JD from season four of Scrubs,
Speaker 9:  Mrs. Mcal forties, moderately attractive, conditioned, improving.
Speaker 10:  Did you just say I was moderately attractive?
Speaker 9:  Excuse me, Mrs. Mcal
Speaker 11:  Patient's complaint of hearing loss was clearly just to get attention
Speaker 2:  Though I also, to be fair, have this experience a lot doing that.
Speaker 2:  I
Speaker 12:  Thought, I like toast. They aren't all
Speaker 2:  Winners In actual reality, by the way, doctors have used voice recorders
Speaker 2:  forever. Talking is a lot faster than typing, and a transcript
Speaker 2:  of a conversation can often give you a lot more information quickly
Speaker 2:  and with context than you'd get from just a written thing, and a lot of
Speaker 2:  doctors are now using AI to help summarize those transcripts and help them
Speaker 2:  find key information later because the problem with recording everything
Speaker 2:  on a voice recorder is that it's a lot of information and it takes a lot
Speaker 2:  of time to parse through it all, listening to your own voice for hours at
Speaker 2:  a time just to find that one thing you said, not fun. The big thing that
Speaker 2:  happened to make all of this stuff work recently is that OpenAI built
Speaker 2:  a speech to text tool called Whisper. When OpenAI launched it in
Speaker 2:  2022, it said that the model approaches human level
Speaker 2:  robustness and accuracy on English speech recognition in its blog
Speaker 2:  post announcing it. It used this audio as an example. This is
Speaker 13:  The micro machine man presenting the most midget miniature motorcade of
Speaker 13:  micro machine speech. One has dramatic details.
Speaker 2:  That's a guy named John Mota, Jr doing a commercial, by the way. He's actually
Speaker 2:  in the Guinness Book of World Records as the world's fastest talker. I've
Speaker 2:  now listened to that ad approximately a million times, and I do think Whisper
Speaker 2:  gets one word wrong. It says R near the end, and I
Speaker 2:  think Mota says and but I can't even tell for sure
Speaker 2:  and that's all Whisper missed. That's how good this is. OpenAI
Speaker 2:  reportedly developed Whisper as a way to transcribe millions of hours of
Speaker 2:  YouTube videos in order to get training data for its GPT models, which
Speaker 2:  is a strange and somewhat nefarious way to have gotten to this point, but
Speaker 2:  let's just leave that aside now. We have this open source whisper model that
Speaker 2:  works incredibly well and is being used all over the voice notes world.
Speaker 2:  The first gadget I got to try all this out is called the pla note.
Speaker 2:  P-L-A-U-D. It's a $160 recorder about the size of a credit
Speaker 2:  card, just a little thicker and a little heavier. It's just a microphone
Speaker 2:  basically that connects to an app on your phone to store and process all
Speaker 2:  of your recordings. You just press the one button on the plot to start recording
Speaker 2:  and a little red light turns on to let you know it's working. It has one
Speaker 2:  mode for just recording your voice and another that's supposedly optimized
Speaker 2:  for recording phone calls. It actually comes with a case you can attach to
Speaker 2:  the back of your phone for recording those calls and it's surprisingly good
Speaker 2:  at it.
Speaker 14:  Authority note that this call may be recorded for quality assurance
Speaker 14:  If, you have an emergency, please press one now. If, you would like to fill
Speaker 14:  a prescription. Press two.
Speaker 2:  As a reporter who has spent most of my career constantly trying to find
Speaker 2:  ways to record phone calls, this is awesome. For years, I've used this
Speaker 2:  weird rig where I have a headphone splitter that goes into a pair of ear
Speaker 2:  pods and also into a voice recorder. This is just way better, but you
Speaker 2:  can also use it to record sales calls and meetings and that sort of thing.
Speaker 2:  Claude definitely imagines the note as a business tool. First and foremost,
Speaker 2:  I have been using it mostly for things like to-do lists or when I wake up
Speaker 2:  in the middle of the night with a fun idea and want to get it down before
Speaker 2:  I forget and I love, love using it while I wander
Speaker 2:  around my kitchen to see what needs to go on the grocery list.
Speaker 15:  Okay, this is my grocery list for the week of May. First
Speaker 15:  I need bagels, potatoes,
Speaker 2:  Almost outta bread flour, so I should get bread flour. I need more
Speaker 15:  Paprika, but the smoked paprika, not the other stuff.
Speaker 2:  So I record that and then a few seconds later I open up the plot app, which
Speaker 2:  is very bare bones, but works basically fine, and that recording shows up.
Speaker 2:  I open it up and I get three options, transcription summary and mind map.
Speaker 2:  Mind map is useless. Let's not worry about mind map. I tap on transcription
Speaker 2:  and it asks what language the recording is in and what kind of note it is,
Speaker 2:  call meeting, interview, task assignment, that kind of thing. I pick task
Speaker 2:  assignment in English and a few minutes later I get a full and very accurate
Speaker 2:  transcription of my grocery list. That's kind of useful, but
Speaker 2:  really what I want is for this to just make me a grocery list, so I tap
Speaker 2:  on summary. It tells me at the top, the meeting outlined the necessary grocery
Speaker 2:  items to be purchased for the upcoming week, ensuring a sufficient supply
Speaker 2:  of food and essentials, which is true, I suppose, but totally
Speaker 2:  unnecessary, and then it gives me the list. All is a single
Speaker 2:  action item. This is not what I was hoping for, but all the stuff is
Speaker 2:  here and the coolest part is when I said I was good on peanut butter and
Speaker 2:  good on coffee, it actually kept those things off of the list,
Speaker 2:  which means it actually in some way understood the difference between me
Speaker 2:  saying something and me deliberately adding it to the list.
Speaker 2:  That's the stuff, right? The plot note is very cool, but
Speaker 2:  it's expensive for just a voice recorder, and you do also have to pay 80
Speaker 2:  bucks a year for the AI features. That is a lot for a grocery
Speaker 2:  list tool, so instead I turned to the Rabbit R one, a more
Speaker 2:  full featured AI device. That in general is pretty bad. It can't
Speaker 2:  do a lot of what it promises, but it can record, transcribe and summarize
Speaker 2:  audio, so I started carrying this thing around just to see how it would do
Speaker 2:  with to-do lists and journal entries and all that stuff as well.
Speaker 15:  This is me testing out the voice recorder. Let's see what
Speaker 15:  I have to do today. I need to finish
Speaker 15:  my Apple story. I sent edit back to Jake. He's gonna get it spec to
Speaker 15:  me. I'd like to get that at least into top edit. Today we have The
Speaker 15:  Vergecast it to
Speaker 2:  Once you record something, rabbit stores it all in an app called The Rabbit
Speaker 2:  Hole, which is not a good app in general, but for these purposes it's fine.
Speaker 2:  It pulled out a very basic plain text list of stuff from my note
Speaker 2:  in addition to just giving me access to the recording itself and it got most
Speaker 2:  of the stuff on that to-do list that I said, but it did just completely ignore
Speaker 2:  a couple of things and since Rabbit doesn't just make a transcript and let
Speaker 2:  you see it, I don't actually like this one quite as much. At least it is
Speaker 2:  easy to download the audio and upload it somewhere else, which is something,
Speaker 2:  and the mic is pretty good. I need to write the container post for tomorrow,
Speaker 2:  but I can do that tonight while Anna is at class. That's my day, but in general,
Speaker 2:  buying a whole device just to record audio is probably
Speaker 2:  only for the most dedicated users of this stuff. The main advantage
Speaker 2:  of a dedicated voice recorder is that the battery tends to last a lot longer.
Speaker 2:  They tend to have better mics and also because they're not an app, you don't
Speaker 2:  run the risk of weirdness with background apps shutting down or getting
Speaker 2:  a phone call in the middle that screws everything up or just loud pinging
Speaker 2:  notifications constantly popping up in your recording. Not everyone needs
Speaker 2:  a voice recorder all the time, but If you do. You'll probably appreciate
Speaker 2:  it being a dedicated device, but If, you want to get most of the
Speaker 2:  functionality of those devices, but you'd rather just use your phone. Oh
Speaker 2:  boy, do I have good news for you? There are suddenly a million apps out there
Speaker 2:  that are making use of Whisper and other models, especially from OpenAI
Speaker 2:  to transcribe, summarize and make use of all of your audio.
Speaker 2:  You can basically Google and find a thousand options, but let me just tell
Speaker 2:  you about two. The first is called Cleft Notes and it works on Mac and
Speaker 2:  iOS. This one I think is the best Voice Notes app I've tried period.
Speaker 2:  You open it up and hit record and it shows this a morphous meshy
Speaker 2:  blob that moves as you record, which is kind of delightful to look at. Like
Speaker 2:  most other apps. It gives you both a full transcription of your audio and
Speaker 2:  tries to make some sense of it after you finished, but cleft goes further
Speaker 2:  actually, it tries to format and structure everything you said so that If,
Speaker 2:  you come out of a call and you wanna write down some takeaways. Okay, I just
Speaker 2:  got off the call where we were planning Steve's bachelor party. It sounds
Speaker 2:  like the plan is to go to Myrtle Beach for
Speaker 2:  three days. It then turns that into a document with bullet points and numbers
Speaker 2:  and headings. It's not always right, but it's usually actually a pretty good
Speaker 2:  start. Like that voice note I just played turned into a cleft note with
Speaker 2:  an itinerary, golf plans, a transportation section, a food and drinks
Speaker 2:  section, and a note about renting golf clubs. It's written strangely,
Speaker 2:  formally, but it is really helpful. There are, like I said, tons of
Speaker 2:  apps that do this and since they basically all use open AI's models,
Speaker 2:  they're all roughly equivalent in terms of the actual quality of the
Speaker 2:  transcript and information. But I just wanna quickly mention one other app
Speaker 2:  I really like. It's called Audio Pen and it's a web app, which means it works
Speaker 2:  everywhere and it's super easy and fast. You just record some audio.
Speaker 2:  My grocery list for today, I need eggs, I need nut butter.
Speaker 2:  I'm good on coffee and good on tea. I need red wine for this
Speaker 2:  weekend. I need coffee filters. I need three balls of
Speaker 2:  mozzarella for pizza. Once you do it gives you the same summaries and information
Speaker 2:  as the rest, but what I really like about Audio Pen in particular is that
Speaker 2:  If, you pay the $99 a year for audio pen prime, which gets you more
Speaker 2:  transcriptions and storage and whatnot. You can also tell it how to format
Speaker 2:  what it creates. So If, you want everything in bullets or paragraphs or
Speaker 2:  like iambic pentameter. You can do that. Here for instance
Speaker 2:  is my grocery list in iambic pentameter, which I had a different AI from
Speaker 2:  11 labs. Read out loud
Speaker 16:  Eggs and nut butter I require on coffee, tea, I'm
Speaker 16:  satisfied. Red wine for weekend filters, two, three
Speaker 16:  mozzarella balls will do pepperoni for pizza's taste more bread,
Speaker 16:  flour not to waste broccoli mandarin's combine
Speaker 16:  and peaches sweet, these fruits divine.
Speaker 2:  You probably don't want your groceries in iambic pentameter. More likely
Speaker 2:  you'll want to tell it to be formal for business stuff or write like an author
Speaker 2:  you like or something, but it works pretty well, whatever you pick,
Speaker 2:  and it even goes another step toward turning my rambling thoughts
Speaker 2:  into something that feels finished and useful and not just like
Speaker 2:  rambling thoughts. Another thing you can do in audio pen is upload existing
Speaker 2:  audio, so like If, you have a meeting you already recorded and now need to
Speaker 2:  get something from, or you want notes on a YouTube video you liked, you can
Speaker 2:  just dump the audio in and get info out. I've heard a lot of people
Speaker 2:  say recently that summarizing YouTube videos is one of their core uses
Speaker 2:  for chat GPT and other AI models, and this is another way to get the
Speaker 2:  same kind of thing you could put this podcast in and it would probably give
Speaker 2:  you some information. Basically, all of these tools do cost money, If, you
Speaker 2:  wanna do stuff like that, at least If, you wanna use them heavily. Whisper
Speaker 2:  is an open source model that anyone can use. You can actually download it
Speaker 2:  to your computer and run it locally. If you want to, but it is really
Speaker 2:  computationally intensive and for all the summarization stuff, these apps
Speaker 2:  still are mostly using open AI APIs anyway, oh,
Speaker 2:  one exception I should mention actually, If, you have a Google Pixel phone.
Speaker 2:  The built-in pixel recorder is a terrific voice recorder and
Speaker 2:  there's a new summarize button in there that also works really well. Apple's
Speaker 2:  voice memos app doesn't do any of the transcription or summarization stuff,
Speaker 2:  but I wouldn't be shocked if that's coming soon. In the last few months I've
Speaker 2:  been using AI audio for lots of things, meeting notes to-do
Speaker 2:  lists, searchable transcripts of YouTube videos that I wanna refer back to,
Speaker 2:  but I actually like it best as a journal. I've never been good at keeping
Speaker 2:  a journal over the years because it always involves taking the time and sitting
Speaker 2:  down to do it and it's an activity and it's a whole thing, but now I can
Speaker 2:  just sit down in the morning and quickly brain dump everything
Speaker 2:  I'm thinking about while I brush my teeth. Today is Wednesday May 1st.
Speaker 2:  The first thing I have to do is finish up the
Speaker 2:  Apple story and my rabbit review. I also have to
Speaker 2:  book train tickets to get to New York for tomorrow, should
Speaker 2:  be a relatively chill day, and then at the end of the day, while I'm doing
Speaker 2:  dishes or getting ready for bed or just walking around, I can just ramble
Speaker 2:  about what happened that day for a few minutes. I was in Chicago today for
Speaker 2:  the Chicago Humanities Festival. It was a really fun day. We did
Speaker 2:  a good job of I think not having the whole thing be a bummer, but
Speaker 2:  also having it not be too sort of Pollyanna-ish
Speaker 2:  optimistic. When I do that, I now get instead of just an audio
Speaker 2:  file, a really good transcript that I can find again later and a
Speaker 2:  nice summary of the key points of everything I talk about. It's both incredibly
Speaker 2:  low effort and surprisingly useful. Honestly, I hope
Speaker 2:  Day one, which is the journaling app I've been trying to force myself to
Speaker 2:  use for like a decade now adopts some of this stuff. This feels like a
Speaker 2:  good way to get things into a journal. Honestly, I think these
Speaker 2:  apps and devices are kind of perfectly indicative of how AI works
Speaker 2:  right now in general for all the hype over image generation and
Speaker 2:  AI's abilities to write emails for you or you know, replace your job entirely.
Speaker 2:  The thing these models do best is take a bunch of information and try to
Speaker 2:  simplify and summarize it. That's handy If. You're trying to get the gist
Speaker 2:  of a long legal document or you wanna know what a podcast was about before
Speaker 2:  you devote 90 minutes of your life to it. That's why I'm so intrigued by
Speaker 2:  Notion AI and all the other tools that aren't trying to understand all of
Speaker 2:  the universe's information. They're just focused on the stuff that you care
Speaker 2:  about and making sense of that. That is a really good use case of AI
Speaker 2:  If. you ask me and it's working pretty well for me because as you guessed,
Speaker 2:  I do love rambling into microphones. Actually, you know what? I should stop
Speaker 2:  doing that for a minute. We're gonna take a quick break and then we're gonna
Speaker 2:  come back and take a question for the Birch Cast hotline. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 19:  peanut butter and chocolate. However,
Speaker 2:  back. Let's get to the hotline as always. The number is 8 6 6 VERGE one one
Speaker 2:  and
Speaker 2:  non-cynical answer. The non-cynical answer is that I think there
Speaker 2:  is room for something that isn't a smartphone. In a funny
Speaker 2:  way, we're actually going through the beginnings of an
Speaker 2:  unbundling process in a lot of ways. I think there is a set
Speaker 2:  of people who are realizing that they want multiple devices
Speaker 2:  for multiple things. The idea that I should just have a smartphone that does
Speaker 2:  everything was never really true. I mean, think about that brief
Speaker 2:  moment where we tried to use our smartphones as TV remotes.
Speaker 2:  It turns out that having buttons you can press without having to look down
Speaker 2:  at is a good idea. Something like the RayBan
Speaker 2:  Metas Smartt glasses I think is really interesting or the snap spectacles
Speaker 2:  that they've been working on for years. The idea that actually a camera
Speaker 2:  that's not in my pocket but is on my face is
Speaker 2:  actually a good idea. So I think there are some things that should have been
Speaker 2:  shoved into the phone, right? Like my phone as a music player and not
Speaker 2:  necessarily needing a dedicated music player makes a lot of sense, but
Speaker 2:  I think there is room for some kind of AI device that
Speaker 2:  isn't your phone. The idea that it could be a little more accessible, it
Speaker 2:  could be closer to your face and mouth and eyes and the sort of
Speaker 2:  biometric stuff that actually can make AI really useful. My guess is
Speaker 2:  that's probably something that looks more like a smartwatch or a pair of
Speaker 2:  glasses than it is a sort of dedicated handheld device. But the reason
Speaker 2:  I was so intrigued by Humane is I think the idea of a wearable that's like
Speaker 2:  on your lapel kind of always within arm's reach is
Speaker 2:  really interesting. That's also how I felt years ago about things like
Speaker 2:  Alexa and Google Assistant and the idea that, you know, I can talk to
Speaker 2:  technology without having to pull my phone out, look at a screen, unlock
Speaker 2:  a thing. This idea of ambient computing that's been floating around actually
Speaker 2:  requires lots of different kinds of devices. I think the smartphone is going
Speaker 2:  to keep being the main one for a long time, and I think any product
Speaker 2:  that tries to subvert that and say ditch your phone and use this other
Speaker 2:  device is just gonna fail because A, people don't wanna ditch their phone
Speaker 2:  and B, you shouldn't. Phones are great and they're useful and they do lots
Speaker 2:  of things, but we can attach stuff to phones that does more things in
Speaker 2:  more ways and I think that's gonna be very cool. The AI
Speaker 2:  gadget remains to be seen, but there are ways it could work and there are
Speaker 2:  ways it could happen and there are ways that it might be exciting. That's
Speaker 2:  the non-cynical answer is I think there is something here. The cynical answer
Speaker 2:  is that they're just desperately trying to find a
Speaker 2:  way to sell you something. We have gotten into a place in the
Speaker 2:  smartphone market where there are two companies, apple and Google, that are
Speaker 2:  total gatekeepers for the entire industry, right? If, you want to do something
Speaker 2:  in the iPhone, you have to play nice in the App Store, you have to play by
Speaker 2:  Apple's rules, you have to give Apple a cut. That is just how it works.
Speaker 2:  Same in the Play Store. There's like a little more openness in Android, but
Speaker 2:  for all intents and purposes, If, you wanna be on Android, you have to play
Speaker 2:  by Google's rules. That means there are certain kinds of things you just
Speaker 2:  can't do. That means there are certain kinds of apps that
Speaker 2:  you can't make a real business out of because of the way that Apple's rules
Speaker 2:  work. And so what you're left with is saying, okay, there are two companies
Speaker 2:  that are just going to tax us every time we want to do anything,
Speaker 2:  and I think we've kind of spent a decade watching
Speaker 2:  companies that didn't win in mobile, try to win in the next
Speaker 2:  thing, and I think in a huge way that was why
Speaker 2:  then Facebook now Meta bought Oculus all those years ago because
Speaker 2:  it was saying, okay, we think that there is going to be a huge
Speaker 2:  new VR platform and we cannot lose it again to
Speaker 2:  Apple or Google because there's so much money in being Apple and Google.
Speaker 2:  You get to do all kinds of things, you get to insert yourself in the middle,
Speaker 2:  you get to take the tax, you get to become a huge ad business, you set the
Speaker 2:  defaults. It's just a massively powerful thing to be, and so when there
Speaker 2:  was the idea that, okay, VR is the next thing, you saw a bunch of companies
Speaker 2:  chase VR when everybody thought AR was gonna become the thing that was where
Speaker 2:  Snap showed up and was like, we're a camera company and we're gonna build
Speaker 2:  spectacles and we're gonna take over and you know the HoloLens did it and
Speaker 2:  Magic Leap did it and there was this crazy rush to not just be the
Speaker 2:  first great device but be the first great platform. The same thing is happening
Speaker 2:  right now in ai. As I talked to both Humane and Rabbit and
Speaker 2:  frankly a lot of other companies in this space, the idea is to start with
Speaker 2:  hardware, right? You build a product, you make people buy the product, you
Speaker 2:  make people like the product and then you build a platform out of it. Humane's
Speaker 2:  big idea is this thing called Cosmos. That's their operating system. They're
Speaker 2:  hoping basically to have an app store for Cosmos. You'll be able to use
Speaker 2:  the APIs to plug in, it'll work on lots of different devices like they are
Speaker 2:  very much trying to build a software platform with
Speaker 2:  the size and power of iOS or Android Rabbit has been a little
Speaker 2:  less ambitious about how it talks about that, but when it talks about
Speaker 2:  the large action model, this thing that can actually go and use the apps
Speaker 2:  you use for you, that's the same thing, right? Like there's
Speaker 2:  a version of this that is kind of hacky, that is you teach the system how
Speaker 2:  to do it, but there's a much easier version that is just partnering with
Speaker 2:  companies that exist and have existing products. And for Rabbit,
Speaker 2:  if it can be that center point, the sort of place that you go to
Speaker 2:  use the apps, that's very powerful. OpenAI is trying to do the same thing
Speaker 2:  with the GPT store and Custom GPTs. Google I suspect
Speaker 2:  is going to start to push into that pretty hard. I think you're gonna start
Speaker 2:  to see Apple have AI APIs that you can plug into. The
Speaker 2:  idea is just If. you can be the sort of hub
Speaker 2:  for all the different features of AI that is going to be
Speaker 2:  hugely powerful. We've seen in this first phase, a bunch of companies kind
Speaker 2:  of try to do everything right. You build the one huge perfect model that
Speaker 2:  solves all your problems. Everybody uses it for everything. The end. I don't
Speaker 2:  think that's the future. I think the future is actually sort of an
Speaker 2:  interconnected galaxy of models and systems and tools
Speaker 2:  that you use. And so the question then is who sits in the middle? What is
Speaker 2:  the platform that you use that translates all of that stuff for you and
Speaker 2:  picks the right agent depending on what you need? And I suspect
Speaker 2:  all of these companies think that if they can be that platform, they can
Speaker 2:  make an awful lot of money off of being that platform. Hardware is
Speaker 2:  part of the business. I think actually a lot of these companies genuinely
Speaker 2:  would like to make money from their hardware. Rabbit is
Speaker 2:  hard to tell and frankly so is Humane if there's actually any money in it
Speaker 2:  right now, but they do seem to both wanna be hardware companies, but more
Speaker 2:  than that, they want to be platforms and you cannot build a
Speaker 2:  platform on top of iOS or Android. They just won. And as they push into
Speaker 2:  ai, they're going to entrench that even further, right? I think we're gonna
Speaker 2:  see a lot of AI stuff at WW DC, we're gonna see a lot of AI stuff at
Speaker 2:  Google io. Gemini is already all over Android. Those companies
Speaker 2:  are not interested in letting other AI platforms in and I think
Speaker 2:  there's really interesting regulatory questions about whether they're going
Speaker 2:  to be forced to like what If, you picked your AI model the
Speaker 2:  same way you picked your default browser. Really interesting idea. These
Speaker 2:  companies will not do that unless they're forced to do that, so we'll see.
Speaker 2:  But the way that these companies are thinking is that the only way
Speaker 2:  in is to build a new thing that doesn't require a smartphone
Speaker 2:  and start to slowly siphon you away from these two
Speaker 2:  companies, Google and Apple that have essentially owned our internet experience
Speaker 2:  and have been between any company that wants to build something
Speaker 2:  and you for 15 years. That's a hard, hard, hard
Speaker 2:  thing to upset. It's why a lot of the antitrust stuff going
Speaker 2:  on right now, especially in the US is happening. And if
Speaker 2:  I'm a new company, that's the only reason I would build hardware because
Speaker 2:  building an app is too hard, there's too much stuff in the way and you're
Speaker 2:  probably just going to get eaten alive by Apple or Google. So that's the
Speaker 2:  cynical answer I hope for the non cynical answer and reality. In
Speaker 2:  reality, I think it's a little bit of both. Like we are in a phase where
Speaker 2:  there are interesting new ideas about hardware because there are interesting
Speaker 2:  new ideas about how we interact with technology. We're going to spend, I
Speaker 2:  think, less time tapping on our phones over time and less time
Speaker 2:  looking at screens just to do basic things. So
Speaker 2:  if that's the case, we are going to need new devices, but also
Speaker 2:  anyone trying to compete in those spaces knows that the
Speaker 2:  only real way to build a company the size of Google or Apple is to
Speaker 2:  do it outside of Google or Apple, and that's what everybody is desperately
Speaker 2:  trying to figure out. That said, all the AI stuff we've seen so far should
Speaker 2:  pretty much just be an app. I have yet to see the one that I am like, this
Speaker 2:  is a new category of device, but I'm holding out hope. I haven't tried all
Speaker 2:  the glasses yet. I'm excited to see. Alright, that is it
Speaker 2:  for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everybody who came on the show, and
Speaker 2:  thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on everything. We talked
Speaker 2:  about My rabbit review, lots of our Delta coverage, all kinds of stuff on
Speaker 2:  AI, voice notes, lots more on The Verge dot com. I'll put some links in the
Speaker 2:  show notes, but as always, read the website. It's a good website. We try
Speaker 2:  hard to make it great. If, you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or other
Speaker 2:  AI gadgets you want me to try out. You can always email us at Vergecast at
Speaker 2:  The Verge dot com or just call the hotline eight six six VERGE one one. We
Speaker 2:  love hearing from you. Send us all your thoughts and questions and ideas
Speaker 2:  for what we should do on the show. Feelings about everything. It's my favorite
Speaker 2:  thing. We have a slack room, by the way, where every single one of the hotline
Speaker 2:  questions comes in as they are received and I get to listen to them and it's
Speaker 2:  just so fun. I listen to every single one, I promise. Whether or not it makes
Speaker 2:  it on the show, please know our whole team hears all of your calls, we
Speaker 2:  read all of your emails. we love hearing from you. This show is produced
Speaker 2:  by Andrew Moreno, Liam James, and Wil Poor The. Vergecast is VERGE production
Speaker 2:  and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli Alex Nile will be back on
Speaker 2:  Friday to talk about earnings, iPads, and a whole bunch more. We'll see you
Speaker 2:  then. Rock and roll.