# Transcript
ID: 2c088d83-6eff-43bb-bef7-2cb2bee78cae
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6452785020366677793/-6819001026341769913/s93290-US-3620s-1723573464.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of the correct height-to-width ratio of a foldable phone:
The Verge’s David Pierce, Allison Johnson, Victoria Song, and Chris Welch discuss all the new gadget announcements from Google’s Pixel event — including the Pixel 9, the Pixel Watch 3, the Pixel buds, and more.
Speaker 1:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the correct
Speaker 1:  height to width ratio of a foldable phone. I'm your friend David Pierce
Speaker 1:  and I'm back. I was on vacation for the last two weeks up in New
Speaker 1:  England, looking at leaves and froing in fields and
Speaker 1:  drinking fancy coffee and doing all the things that you normally do on vacation.
Speaker 1:  I missed a shocking amount of news for like late July and
Speaker 1:  early August. Truly bonkers how much stuff is going on, but now
Speaker 1:  I'm back. The team did an awesome job while I was out. Thank you to everybody
Speaker 1:  who sent us feedback on the pilots we've been doing. We have lots more fun
Speaker 1:  stuff coming up on that front, but it's gadgets and friends. So we have a
Speaker 1:  lot to do today on the show. We are going to talk all pixel all the time.
Speaker 1:  The reason this episode is coming out a little bit late is because Google
Speaker 1:  is having an event today, potentially right now as you're listening to this,
Speaker 1:  announcing all of its hardware for the year. We've gotten some of the hardware
Speaker 1:  already, the New Nest thermostat, the new TV streamer, but all
Speaker 1:  the phones, all the, everything that's been leaked and talked about for months,
Speaker 1:  it's all coming out right now. A couple of folks on our team have seen this
Speaker 1:  stuff. They've been briefed on the news. They know what's coming. So we are
Speaker 1:  gonna talk about all the new stuff coming from Google and what it means.
Speaker 1:  I really can't figure out Google as a hardware company. I've spent a long
Speaker 1:  time trying to figure it out and we're gonna try and do it all at once on
Speaker 1:  this episode. So that's what this episode is. It's all Google all the time.
Speaker 1:  It's The Pixel special. We're gonna get into it, but first I just have
Speaker 1:  one quick PSA for you. And I learned this again. I've learned this a hundred
Speaker 1:  times and I keep forgetting every time I go on vacation. The buffer day
Speaker 1:  is everything. When you get home from a trip, make sure there is one whole
Speaker 1:  day between the end of that trip and whatever thing you have to do next,
Speaker 1:  back to school, back to work, whatever it is you're doing. Come home on Saturday
Speaker 1:  instead of going on Sunday and night and then going back to work Monday morning.
Speaker 1:  That's awful. Didn't do the buffer day. Regret the buffer day. All
Speaker 1:  hail the buffer day. Let's talk Pixel. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right
Speaker 1:  back.
Speaker 1:  very, very few of you
Speaker 1:  and I have a list of gadgets that I wanna talk
Speaker 1:  about. And first what's gonna happen is I'm gonna give you the list and then
Speaker 1:  you're gonna tell me if there's anything that I'm missing that are surprises
Speaker 1:  because I'm coming back from two weeks of vacation and I missed a lot of
Speaker 1:  things and then I have ranked the things in the order in which I am
Speaker 1:  interested in them and then we're gonna talk about them. That'll sound good.
Speaker 1:  Great.
Speaker 6:  So
Speaker 1:  Here's my whole list. I have The, Pixel nine, The, Pixel nine
Speaker 1:  Pro, the other Pixel nine Pro and The Pixel nine fold. Are those all the
Speaker 1:  phones? Did I miss any phones? Those
Speaker 6:  Are the phones.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I have a Pixel Watch two and Pixel Buds.
Speaker 5:  Pixel Watch three. Oh
Speaker 1:  God. David is it the Pixel Watch three already? It
Speaker 5:  Is the Pixel Watch three already.
Speaker 1:  Okay, alright. Oh and there's two of them. So we have the Pixel Watch three
Speaker 1:  and the other Pixel Watch three. Yes. And the Pixel buds with a number attached
Speaker 1:  that I can't be bothered to worry about right now. We also have the Google
Speaker 1:  TV streamer, nay Chromecast, RIP, which I wanna
Speaker 1:  talk about. Those are all the gadgets, but I also have, I haven't Nest thermostat
Speaker 1:  I guess. We'll, we'll touch on that, but we're gonna get to that with Jen
Speaker 1:  later this summer I think. And I have The Pixel screenshots thing, a bunch
Speaker 1:  of AI and just some other random nonsense to get to. Am I missing anything
Speaker 1:  before we dive in? I don't think so.
Speaker 6:  I think you got it
Speaker 5:  Probably, but we'll get to it. We'll get get to it
Speaker 1:  Probably. Yeah, this is Google, like there's probably several gadgets that
Speaker 1:  the leak between now and the event on Tuesday when folks are hearing this.
Speaker 1:  So for anything we missed, I apologize. Blame Sue Hai. Let's start with the
Speaker 1:  funds, because I feel like this is, this is just where we have to start
Speaker 1:  again, this, this is all new. I don't know any of the specs of these things.
Speaker 1:  So the first thing you, you're all gonna have to do is kind of give me the
Speaker 1:  rundown of what's going on and then we're gonna, we're gonna talk about our
Speaker 1:  feelings about all of it. So let's, let's start with The. Pixel nine.
Speaker 1:  Allison, tell me about The. Pixel nine.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, pixel nine. So we used to have two phones. Wow.
Speaker 6:  Two phones that didn't fold. Now there's three phones that don't fold in
Speaker 6:  half. So Pixel nine is still the, the entry level is
Speaker 6:  a hundred dollars more expensive this year, which seems to keep happening
Speaker 6:  to this phone.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, remember when The Pixel was like the cheap flagship that was like its
Speaker 1:  whole thing that is long
Speaker 6:  Gone. I looked at it The Pixel six was 5 99 and we are
Speaker 6:  $200 farther away from that. So this year
Speaker 6:  it's got 6.3 inch screen, which is like, they keep
Speaker 6:  making it a tiny bit bigger without making the phone like
Speaker 6:  meaningfully bigger. So it's still like this small phone
Speaker 6:  of the pixels like due without what you want, but
Speaker 6:  there's more ram this year upgraded ultra wide
Speaker 6:  camera, little bit bigger battery, that kind of thing,
Speaker 6:  like incremental stuff. And then there's all the ai,
Speaker 6:  you know,
Speaker 1:  There's a new chip, right? That's, that's like, yeah, I would assume for
Speaker 1:  all the AI stuff they're trying to do that ends up being like the big spec
Speaker 1:  bump here would be the new chip
Speaker 6:  Tensor G four and that's a across the board in all of them.
Speaker 1:  That is one thing Google does that I really like is have the same chip in
Speaker 1:  everything and they claim it's an AI thing and that sort of makes sense.
Speaker 1:  But at least your phone should perform very well no matter which one
Speaker 1:  you buy is a is a nice and not always common thing to have
Speaker 1:  going on.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Good job Google.
Speaker 1:  Not a lot of enthusiasm coming from you on The. Pixel nine. I gotta say like,
Speaker 1:  I'm just, it's just, it's those not brimming with excitement.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's, it's the boring one this year. Okay. I think mostly because there's
Speaker 6:  now a pro version like pro phone
Speaker 6:  that's basically the same size. And I get excited about this size phone.
Speaker 6:  So I wanna see The Pixel nine Pro. Unfortunately it is
Speaker 6:  shipping much later than the other ones. So it's gonna
Speaker 6:  be TVD on like opinions about that one. The
Speaker 5:  Colors are nice this year on the, on the small phone. The,
Speaker 5:  the boring phone.
Speaker 1:  Are they, what are the colors?
Speaker 5:  You know, there's always the two boring colors and then there's this winter
Speaker 5:  green, yeah. Peony. So it's very like pink and
Speaker 5:  green. It's, it's a vibe. It's a very happy pink.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's pink. It's not like here's a drop of pink.
Speaker 5:  It's basically white. They
Speaker 6:  Went for it.
Speaker 5:  They went for it. They, they were just like colors. We love them.
Speaker 1:  I actually appreciate that from Google. I feel like everyone else is out
Speaker 1:  here trying to like come up with fancy names for beige on their phones
Speaker 1:  every year. And Google at least is, is committed to the bit of, do
Speaker 1:  you want this green phone? Yeah. And I do want the screen phone.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like I I do Google. Yes. Thank you. Alright, so le let's talk about
Speaker 1:  the, the pro because the, my guess would be that
Speaker 1:  the pro is going to be vastly more interesting to most people than the
Speaker 1:  regular Pixel nine. Especially because The Pixel nine is not so
Speaker 1:  cheap anymore as to be kind of a tiebreaker for money reasons
Speaker 1:  for most people. So what, and and like you said, You can now get a Pixel
Speaker 1:  nine Pro at the same size as The Pixel nine, which I think is also a big
Speaker 1:  deal. So what's, what's the story of the pro here?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, the Pro. So all three other phones are
Speaker 6:  pro something. There's the Nine Pro, that's the smaller one
Speaker 6:  nine Pro xl, which is a 6.8 inch grain, which
Speaker 6:  is up in, you know, Samsung Galaxy S 24 Ultra
Speaker 6:  Territory. It's like a big one. And then the, the Fold The Pixel
Speaker 6:  nine Pro Fold is a pro phone this year. And
Speaker 6:  as best I can tell, I made a spreadsheet of the Specs Pro
Speaker 6:  means it has 16 gigs of Ram. That's the only like
Speaker 6:  through line on the pro phones. Okay. So like you said, they all
Speaker 6:  have 10 zero G four, you have two choices of pro
Speaker 6:  phones that don't fold in half super big screen or
Speaker 6:  reasonably sized screen. The nine Pro is
Speaker 6:  9 99. So that's, no it's not a price increase
Speaker 6:  even though the phone is small. It's weird comparing the eight Pro to the
Speaker 6:  Nine Pro. 'cause it's, you really wanna compare the eight Pro to the Nine
Speaker 6:  Pro xl. It's real wonky. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Chris, Chris, can you make sense of this lineup for me? Because you're, you're
Speaker 1:  the person I trust to want the most phone at all times possible and I
Speaker 1:  I, I appreciate that about you. What do you make of this lineup?
Speaker 7:  It feels pretty conventional. Like once you like, just look at the nine and
Speaker 7:  nine Pro xl which are gonna come out first. So that's kinda like just the
Speaker 7:  usual playbook for Google. And then Nine Pro will be out sometime next month
Speaker 7:  they say. But yeah, I mean I want the fold obviously for no reason other
Speaker 7:  than it's very
Speaker 1:  Previous
Speaker 7:  And they got the screen size right and yeah, there's a lot to like about
Speaker 7:  it this year.
Speaker 1:  Let's just get into that because I feel like I wanted to start with The Pixel
Speaker 1:  phones because I feel like a, they are the ones that most people who want
Speaker 1:  these phones will buy, but also they are what they are, right? Like we're,
Speaker 1:  we're in a phase with all of these phones, no matter what company you buy
Speaker 1:  from, where You can pretty much write down a list of what's going to happen
Speaker 1:  next year. And you're almost always right. So let's move on from that because
Speaker 1:  I, I agree it seems like the fold is probably the most different
Speaker 1:  and maybe most compelling thing in this phone lineup. And
Speaker 1:  Chris, I particularly, I want you to explain this phone to me because you
Speaker 1:  just wrote a, a thing that I would call like a, a deep backhanded
Speaker 1:  compliment to The Pixel fold where you're kind of like, I love
Speaker 1:  this thing, it sucks. I can't wait for them to do it better. So
Speaker 1:  so tell me, tell me about the, the new pixel fold and, and what it seems
Speaker 1:  like Google maybe did right this time.
Speaker 7:  So they changed the whole form factor. So the first fold was like a passport
Speaker 7:  style, like short and squat. And that was fun. Like the outer screen was
Speaker 7:  like not quite as tall as most phones you could use with one hand very easily.
Speaker 7:  And then when you opened it, it was like a very wide like inner screen. Now
Speaker 7:  they're going towards like the one plus open direction where it's like a
Speaker 7:  very tall outer screen. It's like a normal phone. It's like a 6.3 inch display,
Speaker 7:  like just like The Pixel nine display essentially it's like the same size.
Speaker 7:  So you've got like a whole phone on the outside now, so you're not really
Speaker 7:  like making any compromises there. And then you open it up, it's just like
Speaker 7:  a giant, like whole tablet now. So the first to, I like
Speaker 7:  had a ton of like black bars with many apps on the sides 'cause like it's
Speaker 7:  Android and no one actually like, you know, cares about like one device.
Speaker 7:  So hopefully now Google's gonna say that like all these apps are gonna like
Speaker 7:  open full screen by default now. So it's gonna have like better app compatibility
Speaker 7:  and it's way brighter too. Like the first fold wasn't that bright outside
Speaker 7:  this one, it was like very, very, very bright. So they have like fixed many
Speaker 7:  problems. The cameras are still nowhere near as good as the pros obviously
Speaker 7:  that's the main issue. And there's just, just like not much room to fit,
Speaker 7:  super nice cameras in there. So that's the main compromise you're gonna make
Speaker 7:  if there is one. But it just seems like a super refined, nice version of
Speaker 7:  the first fold. It's like what the first fold should have been essentially.
Speaker 7:  And, but it's but it's now $1,800, which is
Speaker 7:  extremely expensive.
Speaker 6:  Hmm. Improve flatness. It
Speaker 7:  Is very flat
Speaker 1:  18. Yeah. I just, the price kills me and it's like Google, if I, if they
Speaker 1:  made me the CEO of Google, I would be willing to lose so much money on pixel
Speaker 1:  folds just to like, this is, this is your chance
Speaker 1:  if you're Google. And I want, we're gonna get back to some of the like big
Speaker 1:  picture, where does Google fit into this universe stuff in, in
Speaker 1:  a minute. Because I wrote a bunch of years ago when the first pixel
Speaker 1:  came out that this was the best phone on the planet and I believed it then.
Speaker 1:  And I think Google has the potential to do it now and like just keeps getting
Speaker 1:  in its own way in a thousand ways. But we're gonna come back to all of that.
Speaker 1:  But this is like, if, if I'm Google, this sounds like a
Speaker 1:  real chance for this company to be like, we have done, we have done the thing
Speaker 1:  like we got it Connor, right? Samsung is getting a little closer to getting
Speaker 1:  it right but is doing sort of a series of boring iterative
Speaker 1:  upgrades. And Alison, I remember at IO last year we were talking and it was
Speaker 1:  like, okay this pixel fold feels like it's not, it's almost there but it's
Speaker 1:  not quite there. And the, the clear vibe from the first pixel fold was like,
Speaker 1:  I cannot wait for the next one when they have another year to push at the
Speaker 1:  hardware. Another year of trying to convince people to make these apps. and
Speaker 1:  it feels like this has a real shot of like, this might be the one
Speaker 1:  like in terms of the closest foldable phone to getting it fully right,
Speaker 1:  we might be almost there from Google. Am I, am I too excited about this?
Speaker 6:  I I think I'm just like slightly less optimistic. Okay. It does
Speaker 6:  feel like the move they should have made and like the phone that we wanted
Speaker 6:  last year is here. I love the OnePlus open
Speaker 6:  form factor. So like moving towards that I think is a great
Speaker 6:  move that my biggest complaint about the original
Speaker 6:  pixel folder is so heavy, it was just uncomfortable to
Speaker 6:  hold it for a while and then it, it can be the best foot in the world but
Speaker 6:  if you don't wanna hold it, there's a problem. So this one's
Speaker 6:  significantly lighter. I think those are all really good things.
Speaker 6:  I think I'm still confused by the, like I get that they have to make trade
Speaker 6:  offs for the camera, but if you're putting pro on the name of this
Speaker 6:  phone and you're still having to compromise on
Speaker 6:  the camera,
Speaker 1:  You're also charging $1,800. Exactly. Which I feel as the person who says
Speaker 1:  prices very loudly occasionally on this podcast, it's $1,800.
Speaker 1:  That's so much money.
Speaker 6:  I know that's like the going rate for a folding phone I guess,
Speaker 1:  Which is like fine, I get that. That's, they're expensive and that's what
Speaker 1:  they seem to cost. But like I just don't, and I feel this way with everybody.
Speaker 1:  I don't think you get to make any kind of significant
Speaker 1:  compromise and get away with it at that price. And Google is gonna
Speaker 1:  say it can do a lot of stuff in software for the camera and that what a lot
Speaker 1:  of people are doing with the camera is not taking photos. They're doing all
Speaker 1:  this AI stuff and that's all well and good but I do think the, we
Speaker 1:  are going to end up pretty rigorously stress testing this thing. And I think
Speaker 1:  there is absolutely no room for error in the camera in these folds because
Speaker 1:  they're just too expensive. Agreed. V are you a folding phone person? I
Speaker 1:  don't feel like you and I have ever talked about folding phones.
Speaker 5:  It's too expensive for me. I am a cheap ass with my phones.
Speaker 5:  Well not really because I have the iPhone provac.
Speaker 5:  You know what I really don't like is I don't like how they keep adding adjectives
Speaker 5:  to the ends of these phones along with numbers. Correct. So that it's like
Speaker 5:  an alphabet soup. But like I'm always intrigued by them. I just,
Speaker 5:  so I take my phone running and I have this feeling of
Speaker 5:  if I drop this while I'm running 'cause I have eaten
Speaker 5:  it while running before, I'm just gonna sit there and be like,
Speaker 5:  no I'm bleeding. But also the repair
Speaker 5:  bill, I'm bleeding both my blood and money.
Speaker 5:  So that's why I haven't gotten any kind of
Speaker 5:  folding phone yet because then I would feel the need to have like a safe
Speaker 5:  phone for running and then that's, we're getting into two phone, three
Speaker 5:  phone territory. I'm already have, I'm all, I'm already dual wielding phones
Speaker 5:  because they've decided to make it so that wear West
Speaker 5:  watches don't work with an iPhone. I used to be able to get away with one
Speaker 5:  phone and test all of these watches. Nope. I have to have two fricking phones
Speaker 5:  at all times now. So welcome to my, I don't need a third, I
Speaker 5:  don't need a third folding phone. even though I would like one, I would just
Speaker 5:  wanna play around with it. But you know, I'm still mad at you David
Speaker 5:  for talking about the book's Palma so much. So stop asking me to buy more
Speaker 5:  things. I
Speaker 1:  Talked about it once. Everybody needs to leave me alone about this. I
Speaker 1:  got very excited about it one time and I was right
Speaker 1:  and now this is, this is somehow my legacy as I have convinced too many people
Speaker 1:  to buy this deeply overpraised adorable little gadget and to all
Speaker 1:  those people, I'm not sorry at all remotely. Sorry. Just be glad
Speaker 1:  v that they didn't release a pixel ring because I, I literally had the thought
Speaker 1:  in going through this that like v it's gonna run outta fingers. Like it's
Speaker 1:  just, we're just, we're toast here.
Speaker 5:  So like I, I'm basically testing all of these and I've narrowed it down to
Speaker 5:  the three that I think are the best. If they came out with a pixel ring,
Speaker 5:  that's probably next year. But if they came out with a pixel ring this year,
Speaker 5:  I would be in so much trouble. I already have
Speaker 5:  six ring tans. It's bad.
Speaker 1:  So let's actually move on to the wearables 'cause while we're just running
Speaker 1:  through the news, let's run through the news. So the, the Pixel Watch three,
Speaker 1:  which I am reliably told is the new one.
Speaker 1:  What's the deal with the Pixel Watch three?
Speaker 5:  Well there's a new size now there after everyone complained that the
Speaker 5:  41 millimeter is too small, they have now come out with a 45
Speaker 5:  millimeter and then they were like, okay so the hardware, it's basically
Speaker 5:  gonna look the same as last year. Except we're gonna add an ultra wide man
Speaker 5:  chip and actual displays. They're Viggo writer bold
Speaker 5:  now. Yeah sure they look the same. Most people
Speaker 5:  looking at the watches are just gonna be like that. That sure is a watch
Speaker 5:  that bezels are 16% slimmer. Love that. And then they were just
Speaker 5:  like, and here is a laundry list of software updates that there's,
Speaker 5:  it is physically impossible that I will remember every single bit of
Speaker 5:  software that they've crammed into this thing. And it's like actually quite
Speaker 5:  impressive the amount of software updates. There's like You
Speaker 5:  can stream your nest doorbell or cam feed straight to your wrist.
Speaker 5:  You can unlock your BMW if you have a BMW You can also
Speaker 5:  unlock your pixel phone. You can do custom
Speaker 5:  runs now, which you know, other watches have been able to do for a long time.
Speaker 5:  But now You can program your actual thing. It's very Garmin like
Speaker 5:  you have a morning summary of all of your stuff. There's an auto sleep
Speaker 5:  mode, there's cardio load, it's, it's a lot.
Speaker 1:  So Google is is deep in the like health and fitness
Speaker 1:  race now they are like Google, there was a minute at the beginning of the
Speaker 1:  Pixel Watch where Google was doing that but also had some big ideas about
Speaker 1:  like the assistant and this is an AI thing and it feels like they're getting
Speaker 1:  away from that and just pushing towards this is a health and fitness device.
Speaker 5:  I actually think they're, they're, they're pushing equally okay towards the
Speaker 5:  productivity stuff and the health stuff. It was very heavy on the
Speaker 5:  productivity stuff first I think because they were mostly coasting on Fitbit
Speaker 5:  exists. This is a Fitbit platform. Sure. Now this time around they've basically
Speaker 5:  gone, what is Garmin doing and let's just add it to the watch.
Speaker 5:  So there's like a morning summary. Now, you know Garmin,
Speaker 5:  a couple of generations ago they introduced this thing called morning Morning
Speaker 5:  report and it'll tell you like your overnight stats and the
Speaker 5:  weather so that You can wake up and go like, oh it's 90 degrees time
Speaker 5:  to die on this five mile run. So now the Google
Speaker 5:  Pixel Watch three is gonna do that and then, you know, they're adding
Speaker 5:  something called cardio load. Now I think if you've ever used a Garmin
Speaker 5:  or a Polar or just like a multi-sport watch, you know what cardio load is.
Speaker 5:  But that's not really something we've seen on these major flagship watches
Speaker 5:  to be like, what's your cardio load And cardio load is basically how
Speaker 5:  intensely your heart has been working in your workouts over
Speaker 5:  a period of time. And it's kind of a gauge of like, oh, you know, maybe
Speaker 5:  my cardio load is really high, I should ease off or just do more
Speaker 5:  like, I hate this but like zone two training,
Speaker 5:  it's, it's, it's very triggering to hear zone two training for me. So, you
Speaker 5:  know, that's what that cardio load thing is. And then, you know, custom running
Speaker 5:  workouts and running metrics like vertical oscillation,
Speaker 5:  stride cadence, vertical oscillation is the most useless metric by the way.
Speaker 5:  I don't know what you're supposed to do with that. It just tells you how
Speaker 5:  far up and down you move while you run and like the less the better, but
Speaker 5:  you're just gonna, what do you whatcha gonna do? I'm a bouncy runner.
Speaker 5:  How are you gonna change the fact that you're a bouncy runner anyway? But
Speaker 5:  it's gonna tell you all those things. There's a new running dashboard within
Speaker 5:  the, the Fitbit app. It's, it's a lot of stuff
Speaker 5:  and just like, oh the the biggest one that I haven't mentioned that yet is
Speaker 5:  that it can now detect a loss of a pulse and
Speaker 5:  call emergency services for you.
Speaker 1:  That seems good.
Speaker 5:  Loss of pulse. Like it's basically like are you dying? Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I, love it. Loss of pulse is such an amazing euphemism. Yeah this is
Speaker 1:  a serious one, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah it's very serious. So it's like, you know, if you overdose, if
Speaker 5:  you have a heart attack and you're alone, it's gonna call
Speaker 5:  emergency services for you in the eu, not in the US yet.
Speaker 5:  'cause obviously this needs regulatory. Go ahead
Speaker 5:  for that because the potentials for a false alarm are
Speaker 5:  very scary. I talked to Google and they were like sensor fusion.
Speaker 5:  Don't worry if you just take your watch off, which is a loss of pulse
Speaker 5:  event, it's not gonna call emergency services. But you know, that's like
Speaker 5:  kind of an interesting thing from Google because thus far they have
Speaker 5:  pretty much been playing catch up in the smartwatch space. They are very
Speaker 5:  late. We're only on iteration three of the Pixel Watch Apple Watch.
Speaker 5:  We're coming out with number 10 and Samsung's fucked
Speaker 5:  up their numbering such a long time ago, but we are already on seven.
Speaker 5:  So you know, there they're pr there are several generations behind, but they
Speaker 5:  are coming out with a health feature that nobody else has
Speaker 5:  by gen three. And you know, they say it's because the Pixel Watch samples
Speaker 5:  your heart rate at a, at a much, much, much higher frequency than other
Speaker 5:  flagship smart watches. Which is true because they're doing it every other
Speaker 5:  second, most other smart watches, unless you are in the middle of a
Speaker 5:  workout, will do it once every five minutes or so. So, you know,
Speaker 5:  it's, it is something that they can differentiate themselves with. So many
Speaker 5:  updates. I liter, I'm sure I forgot like five or six software
Speaker 5:  updates in there. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But there's an interesting theme there, which is like down this deep
Speaker 1:  tracking yourself rabbit hole, which is kind of what everyone has, has leaned
Speaker 1:  into in this space, which makes a lot of sense. Two more questions on this
Speaker 1:  and then we're gonna take a break and then we're gonna do the rest of these
Speaker 1:  gadgets. Question number one, Fitbit. Where
Speaker 5:  Fitbit is increasingly going the way of nest in that like
Speaker 5:  it is a word that we use. There's a lot of history there. Technically you
Speaker 5:  still are using the Fitbit app but is all Google now baby.
Speaker 5:  That's what it simplification of Fitbit is I think
Speaker 5:  almost complete. I think next year is the deadline for migrating
Speaker 5:  all of your Fitbit accounts over to Pixel or Google
Speaker 5:  accounts rather And. if you wanna buy the new watches, you gotta migrate.
Speaker 5:  So e
Speaker 1:  My absolute hottest take on all of this is that Google branded these exactly
Speaker 1:  wrong. That it should have gone all the way into the Fitbit
Speaker 1:  brand and all of these products should be called Fitbits, which were like,
Speaker 1:  Fitbit was like Kindle and Kleenex for the longest time and Google was just
Speaker 1:  like, nah, nevermind. Nobody, nobody knows what Fitbits are. They're like
Speaker 1:  Pixel watches.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's weird because they still have some Fitbits. It's just this
Speaker 5:  main flagship Fitbit watch that's actually a Pixel watch.
Speaker 5:  And I think that's just probably part of their ecosystem play because
Speaker 5:  you do see it working more with other Google services
Speaker 5:  offline maps, you have Google maps, offline maps now. So there that, that's
Speaker 5:  why. But at the same time it's just very confused
Speaker 5:  and it was more so confused with the original and the Pixel Watch too. So.
Speaker 1:  Okay, last question on the Pixel Watch if memory serves, we have
Speaker 1:  broken our review unit both years of the Pixel Watch.
Speaker 1:  I believe
Speaker 5:  Chris cracked the first one. I cracked the second one. Oh
Speaker 5:  Chris,
Speaker 1:  That was you the first time. Yeah. Yeah. And I, if, if memory serves, it
Speaker 1:  was one of those like you didn't do anything and then it was cracked. That's
Speaker 7:  How it went. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that Google doesn't believe me, put it on a
Speaker 5:  charger, looked at it and I was like, why is it scratched to hell and back
Speaker 5:  and everyone's like, you, there's no way you got those scratches without
Speaker 5:  knowing what you did. I don't know what I did. They it, I woke up and it
Speaker 5:  was scratched. So yeah.
Speaker 1:  And that to me is like the bar for me, right? It's like if I fall on the
Speaker 1:  ground and scrape it against concrete and it scratches, like I understand
Speaker 1:  how that happens, but if I don't even know how it got scratched and it
Speaker 1:  scratched, that's that's, that's a you problem. It's just a very fragile
Speaker 7:  Design, you know, it's like a glass dome that's gonna happen. Totally.
Speaker 5:  And it's not sapphire. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I will say I wear a pixel watch with most of the Android phones are
Speaker 6:  reviewed and I'm just a dingus. I'm like always ram it into
Speaker 6:  like a doorway.
Speaker 1:  Allison is seven feet tall is an important thing to tell everybody.
Speaker 6:  It's like flailing all the time. It's been okay. I don't have any, I don't
Speaker 6:  have any scratches. I dunno.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I I was totally fine with the first one. I, I legitimately am telling
Speaker 5:  you I went to bed and I either put it on the charger where I was wearing
Speaker 5:  it, I don't remember. It was zero ago. I woke up, it looked like my cat
Speaker 5:  went to town on it, but my cat did not go to town on it. So I,
Speaker 5:  I don't know what happened. Google actually took the watch from me and they
Speaker 5:  sent it to a lab and they were like, abrasions happened. Whoa. I was like,
Speaker 5:  well no shit, but I, we don't know what they were.
Speaker 1:  Abrasions happened Is the title of your memoir by the way? Just to Yeah,
Speaker 1:  just to put that out there right now. A any word on if this one is going
Speaker 1:  to be better at that stuff? Do we have any like we've been saying since the
Speaker 1:  jump that one of the worries of this design was that it would be more fragile
Speaker 1:  and that has clearly I would say proven out over time. No changes this time,
Speaker 1:  no
Speaker 7:  Changes. Yeah, I'm very excited for the big watch, but like that's even more
Speaker 7:  like surface area for it to be damaged, so we'll see. Right.
Speaker 1:  All right, all right, fair enough. All right, well we gotta take a break,
Speaker 1:  but we have a couple more GA to get to. We'll be right back.
Speaker 7:  case. The case now has a speaker on the outside, so if you lose it, you'll
Speaker 7:  make a noise. So some small quality of life improvements, but yeah, the main
Speaker 7:  things are the much better A NC and the sound quality, which we'll see.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I'm very curious to see how the sound quality turns out because like,
Speaker 1:  at least for my purposes, it's always been good enough. Yeah, definitely
Speaker 1:  not best in class, but good enough. and it was the, the pairing was super
Speaker 1:  easy. I always found them more comfortable than most of the other ones. I
Speaker 1:  think they super comfortable, they just fit my ears better for whatever reason.
Speaker 1:  And I always thought their noise cancellation was pretty good. Anyway, they
Speaker 1:  do a really good job with noise cancellation on mic performance. We've tested
Speaker 1:  them on the show and they, they did some, they did really well canceling
Speaker 1:  out noise as you're talking into them. So if they can like vastly improve
Speaker 1:  that again yeah, that's pretty exciting. Yeah, absolutely. But yeah, they're
Speaker 1:  like, they're just AirPods for Android territory and I think that is a useful
Speaker 1:  and good thing and frankly every company is gonna end up having those and
Speaker 1:  that works fine. Now we get to the big news, big news, which is, which is
Speaker 1:  the, the death of Chromecast. This is the real story here.
Speaker 1:  This is, I, I went on vacation Google lost an
Speaker 1:  antitrust trial and killed Chromecast and it was just, I was like, I don't
Speaker 1:  know how I'm supposed to deal with this when I don't have a podcast on which
Speaker 1:  to talk about this. So Chris, gimme the quick rundown both on the new
Speaker 1:  thing that is coming out and the old thing that is dying. What,
Speaker 1:  what's going on here? Yeah,
Speaker 7:  So the new thing is the Google TV streamer. Quite a name,
Speaker 1:  Terrible name by the way. Just before, just before we get in, awful awful
Speaker 1:  name,
Speaker 7:  Chromecast had brand recognition, but now let's do Google TV streamer.
Speaker 7:  This flows right off the tongue,
Speaker 1:  It really does. What if we had more pixel streamer, pick that, pick
Speaker 7:  Anything. So it costs a hundred bucks. It's a box now, it's not a dongle
Speaker 7:  anymore. So it's a set top box. It's, it's nice, it's pretty, it's got like
Speaker 7:  a built-in ethernet jack, which is nice to have on streamers all the time.
Speaker 7:  But it runs the same like software as the most recent Chromecast. So you're
Speaker 7:  gonna have all that, it'll have like Gemini AI features. Sure
Speaker 7:  it's gonna be 20% faster than the Chromecast. People have always been like
Speaker 7:  waiting for like a fast Chrome cast. And so they claim that like the Nvidia
Speaker 7:  Shield was their like main like goalpost here to reach. I don't, I don't
Speaker 7:  think it's gonna reach that because like 20% faster than the 4-year-old Chromecast
Speaker 7:  with Google TV is like still not gonna be a barn burner of a, of a
Speaker 7:  device. And it's like most of our comments were like, that's not gonna get
Speaker 7:  it done for me. I'm gonna, you know, just go buy an Apple tv, yada yada.
Speaker 7:  But the Chromecast is dead, but the casting feature is still alive and well
Speaker 7:  obviously, so You can still cast to the box, do all the same stuff, but the
Speaker 7:  name is now gone. Quick
Speaker 1:  Poll before, before I, I get it. How do all of you do your
Speaker 1:  smart TV stuff? Like v what's your, what's your smart TV situation like when
Speaker 1:  you wanna watch Netflix on your tv, what do you have?
Speaker 5:  I got two Apple TVs.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Allison, what about you? We
Speaker 6:  Have a Samsung tv. We do all the built-in apps.
Speaker 5:  Oh my god, that's so brave.
Speaker 1:  No, well, so okay, we're gonna come back to that because I think, I think
Speaker 1:  this is the whole point of this device. Chris, what's yours?
Speaker 7:  I mean I have everything. So I've got the Apple tv, fire TV, cube,
Speaker 7:  Roku, ultra.
Speaker 1:  What is your like main when you're like not thinking about work and you're
Speaker 1:  just like, I just wanna sit down and watch something. Which remote you grab?
Speaker 7:  It's the Apple TV 4K.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So if I, if I were to like big picture, try
Speaker 1:  and explain what Google is doing here. It seems like the thesis is if you
Speaker 1:  want just a simple kind of cheap,
Speaker 1:  don't really worry about it. Way to stream shows
Speaker 1:  performance isn't amazing, but you just like need a thing that plays your
Speaker 1:  shows. You, you kind of have agent in it choice, right? Like your, your
Speaker 1:  TV probably does it. You probably have a dongle that does it. You probably
Speaker 1:  have a box that does it. Your cable company will happily give you one. Like
Speaker 1:  there's a million ways to do it. And so if you want to
Speaker 1:  differentiate and win, you have to do
Speaker 1:  better, right? And, and we've been in this weird space for the last few years
Speaker 1:  where the only ones doing better have been the Apple TV
Speaker 1:  and the Nvidia Shield, both of which are like old outdated devices at this
Speaker 1:  point. But both of which were so far beyond everybody else that they continue
Speaker 1:  to be the only options if you're like, I want my TV to be fast.
Speaker 1:  And on the, on the one hand I think that the idea of let's compete at the
Speaker 1:  top end and make them better and make people want to buy them instead of
Speaker 1:  just the default thing that they have is very exciting. But I do, I kind
Speaker 1:  of agree with our commenters in the sense that I'm not sure, at least from
Speaker 1:  what we've seen so far, we'll have to test the thing and see that this
Speaker 1:  is that thing. Like if Google had come out and been like, we have five Xed
Speaker 1:  the performance of the Chromecast, it's gonna blow your freaking mind
Speaker 1:  through the back of your head and it's $500
Speaker 7:  People would've freaked out.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, but I am, I am I, am I thinking about this the right way Chris? Like
Speaker 1:  is that your read on the situation too? Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah, for sure. I think like they're saying prices like their ceiling for
Speaker 7:  like what they can do as far as like a device, which is fine, but even then
Speaker 7:  I think you could have squeezed some out, just toss like a 2-year-old tensor
Speaker 7:  in there, you know, like what's the issue here? Like you've got your own
Speaker 7:  silicon, like toss a tensor G one in there, you know, or whatever they are
Speaker 7:  and just, yeah, so like 20%, I mean it's not nothing. It's got like twice
Speaker 7:  the ram, which should also help out quite a bit. But as far as like a speed
Speaker 7:  demon, you know, this is probably not gonna be quite that. We could see a
Speaker 7:  new Apple TV this fall. So that would just be like Apple just kind of like
Speaker 7:  lapping them again very quickly. So we'll see how that shakes out.
Speaker 1:  Alison, is is there anything here for you? Are you excited about this at
Speaker 1:  all? I just, they're they're going for you, right? Like you're now the person
Speaker 1:  who is not gonna buy a Chromecast and because your TV does it fine,
Speaker 1:  they're trying to give you something else.
Speaker 6:  Okay. You know what they don't have is there's a all the like
Speaker 6:  10,000 free, you know, ad supported channels on the Samsung tv.
Speaker 6:  We have one called Ocean Vibes and that's just plays
Speaker 6:  when we o when we turn the TV on is the best
Speaker 6:  thing in the world. There's just like fish swimming around and coral reefs
Speaker 6:  and you just sit there and you're like, yeah, this is all right.
Speaker 6:  So talk to me. No, talk to me when you have
Speaker 6:  ocean vibes Google
Speaker 1:  That is so diametrically opposed from the answer I was expecting from you
Speaker 1:  I. love it.
Speaker 7:  That's great. That's
Speaker 1:  A fantastic, fantastic outcome. But yeah, I mean, and I think
Speaker 1:  to some extent Chris, like the, this, this is the thing here, right? Is if
Speaker 1:  I'm Google and I am curious what they've been telling all of you about the,
Speaker 1:  the AI stuff coming in general here, because I'm very excited about The Pixel
Speaker 1:  screenshots feature, which is like a sort of managed
Speaker 1:  AI organized library of all the screenshots you take. I think that's very
Speaker 1:  smart. But in general, the idea here is like we're going to put lots of new
Speaker 1:  power into these new devices, dot, dot
Speaker 1:  ai, and I don't know, at least from what I've seen so far, again, it's Monday
Speaker 1:  as we're recording this, the event is on Tuesday. I'm very curious to see
Speaker 1:  if they can find a way to make a really compelling AI case for this stuff.
Speaker 1:  But with a TV streamer in particular, I'm like, okay, you're giving me theoretically
Speaker 1:  more power other than my apps launch faster, which is meaningful to me, but
Speaker 1:  not to most people.
Speaker 7:  You can use Gemini to make screen saves, which is interesting
Speaker 7:  because they see like how all the frame TV's doing. So they're like, you
Speaker 7:  know, you've got this whole ambient mode
Speaker 1:  So Gemini can make you open ocean vibes.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Oh no, no, that'll be your ocean vibes. I don't, I don't want real ocean.
Speaker 6:  I don't want your AI ocean vibes.
Speaker 7:  So there's that. And also I guess they're gonna do summaries now, so
Speaker 7:  they already show you like the Rotten Tomato scores for movies, but now it's
Speaker 7:  gonna like us bring in content from across the web. So it might be like,
Speaker 7:  here's what someone on Reddit said about this show. Hopefully not that, but
Speaker 7:  you know, we'll see. Oh
Speaker 6:  God.
Speaker 7:  So that's the other thing is like summaries for everything that you are like
Speaker 7:  seeing and browsing. But beyond that, you know,
Speaker 7:  not, not too much compelling. Which
Speaker 1:  Kind of brings me back to like, I'm, I'm very sad that Chromecast has gone
Speaker 1:  because I, I continue to think the Chromecast was a really good idea
Speaker 1:  because I think this might be an unpopular opinion. I have no idea how people
Speaker 1:  feel. I think Google TV is like by a mile the best
Speaker 1:  interface. Yeah, I like it a lot. It, it does a really good job of like,
Speaker 1:  it's, it's very content first, but it also makes getting to the apps easy.
Speaker 1:  Apple is super App first. I think the Fire TV is mostly
Speaker 1:  just trash. Roku is super app first and I think Google TV
Speaker 1:  like does a pretty good job of showing you everything you would wanna see
Speaker 1:  relatively in one place. And so for me, like I have a Roku TV
Speaker 1:  and I bought an Apple TV that I just use instead on my Roku tv.
Speaker 1:  So my Roku TV's one job is just to take me to my Apple TV because it is
Speaker 1:  like an unusable interface on this trash TCL TV I bought at Costco a
Speaker 1:  million years ago.
Speaker 7:  That is probably true for many people these days. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Right. So I think if, if I'm Google I'm like, okay, keep pushing at
Speaker 1:  this idea of like a 30, $50 way to give you Google tv, which is
Speaker 1:  better. And, and I feel like what Google is instead doing is saying, okay,
Speaker 1:  we wanna, they're, they're like splitting a weird difference between make
Speaker 1:  it easy to get Google TV and make a really powerful box. It seems like they're
Speaker 1:  kind of in a middle ground that I'm not super positive is gonna work for
Speaker 7:  Them. Yeah. They're not gonna make anybody happy. It's like not quite the
Speaker 7:  full speed right box and not the cheap thing that the Chromecast was either.
Speaker 7:  So we'll see. I mean I'm looking forward to checking it out, you know, if
Speaker 7:  it's faster, that'll be, that'll make a big difference. But yeah, I love
Speaker 7:  Google tv. Like you David, the ads aren't as in your face as Roku or
Speaker 7:  you know, so there's that. But yeah, we'll see. I'm excited to check it out.
Speaker 7:  It's shipping like last among all these devices in like late September, so
Speaker 7:  it's gonna be a while before we get it in our hands, but it's coming.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it's, it's gonna be an interesting fall for a lot of that stuff, so,
Speaker 1:  okay. Any other announcements coming? You, y'all have gotten all the news,
Speaker 1:  seen all the things. Any, any other like newsy cleanup we should do here
Speaker 1:  before we talk Big picture? What is the future of Google and everything?
Speaker 6:  No.
Speaker 1:  Have you, have any of you tried Pixel screenshots?
Speaker 7:  They showed me a very, very briefly, it seemed cool that they did a search
Speaker 7:  for like someone's wifi password that, that someone had like sent like a
Speaker 7:  screenshot of Oh that seems to be like the example every company shows. But
Speaker 6:  It's a separate app, right?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's a separate app.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Oh, it's its own app. It's not like, I assumed it was like in the,
Speaker 1:  in the photos app in Interesting. That's what
Speaker 6:  I'm so curious about is like, that sounds great. We've got
Speaker 6:  that feature over there. Like how do you bring it all together? Is it gonna
Speaker 6:  be Gemini, is it gonna, am I gonna have to pay for
Speaker 6:  a version of Gemini that's gonna do all these things? I don't know. That's,
Speaker 6:  that's where I am with AI on pixel phones right now. Yeah. Is like,
Speaker 6:  show it to me.
Speaker 1:  My thing is like, I was thinking about this recently, my go-to use case
Speaker 1:  is, so we live maybe like a mile down the street from the library
Speaker 1:  and I'm frequently walking past the library and every once in a while they
Speaker 1:  put up a banner with the dates of the book sales that they're doing.
Speaker 1:  And every single time I take a picture of the banner 'cause I'm like, oh,
Speaker 1:  I have to remember when the book sale is and every single time it just goes
Speaker 1:  into my camera roll and disappears. Like all of those photos and screenshots
Speaker 1:  and that kind of stuff does where I'm like, oh, this is a thing I should
Speaker 1:  buy and then it goes into my camera roll and disappears. And so the idea
Speaker 1:  of like I can just sort of constantly tell my phone, this is
Speaker 1:  the thing I think is interesting and then it can make sense of all that for
Speaker 1:  me is so compelling to me and I think makes way more sense than all the
Speaker 1:  recall stuff is. Like I, all I have to do is tell it remember this for me
Speaker 1:  and it will do it. Like that is perfect. But I think you,
Speaker 1:  to your point Alison, like how you integrate that with everything else makes
Speaker 1:  a lot of sense. 'cause if I have to take a photo and then put it in the screenshots
Speaker 1:  app, I'm gonna forget to do that. And I have now solved none of my problem.
Speaker 1:  So I think it's, it's gonna be a really interesting like push and pull there
Speaker 1:  trying to figure out how do you make this not creepy, but really seamless
Speaker 1:  but not too in your face as you're trying to do other stuff. Which I feel
Speaker 1:  like it's kind of the story of all things AI and Google right now.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that is the thing I want, I want to be able to
Speaker 6:  look up the door code for the Airbnb without like digging through
Speaker 6:  emails or logging into Airbnb or whatever. I,
Speaker 6:  I don't need to put a hat on a picture of a
Speaker 6:  bunny that I took. What do you
Speaker 5:  Mean?
Speaker 1:  To be fair, you have been doing that nonstop for
Speaker 6:  Weeks, which I have been, it's a blast. But honestly it's
Speaker 6:  where we're at I think with Apple Intelligence, which is still, you know,
Speaker 6:  in developer preview blah blah blah. It's like,
Speaker 6:  it's still missing that thing of like, what is gonna tie it all
Speaker 6:  together and am I just gonna be able to be like, Gemini, put the book
Speaker 6:  sale on my calendar, tell me if I have a conflict or something.
Speaker 6:  Or or is it gonna just be like, I don't know.
Speaker 5:  I think the latter. Yeah. Based on the history of AI
Speaker 5:  features. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I'm so nervous about it because I got, I'm doing the labs
Speaker 6:  for the labs like preview for Gemini in your
Speaker 6:  Gmail. They fi which they like finally integrated and I was like, great,
Speaker 6:  I'll search for this order number for my shoes and it does its thing
Speaker 6:  and it's like thinking, it's like there's no order number for your shoes.
Speaker 6:  I'm like, this is no, you had one job like it, it was
Speaker 6:  right there. And like I tried it again later and it it
Speaker 6:  able to do it. I don't know why you got caught up that time. It's like, it
Speaker 6:  feels that one time for you and you're like, why am I gonna try and use this
Speaker 6:  again? I'm not.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it it is really funny. We're, we're in this phase with so many of these
Speaker 1:  features where like, because I have this specific problem that these
Speaker 1:  things can solve for me, I'm willing to try any of them, but the tech
Speaker 1:  broadly speaking just isn't there. And so like you try it twice
Speaker 1:  and it doesn't work and it's like, well that's pretty much that.
Speaker 5:  Yep. Or you could get nagged by it.
Speaker 1:  Oh yeah. Oh my god.
Speaker 5:  Google is is just basically also kind of following
Speaker 5:  Samsung's lead and I forgot, but they're adding AI suggested workouts to
Speaker 5:  the Pixel Watch three based on like your metrics.
Speaker 1:  My suggestions are gonna be like, just do anything. Just stand up. Just just
Speaker 1:  what if you just walked around for once in your life? But,
Speaker 5:  But you know, they were showing it to me and they were like, oh you know,
Speaker 5:  you haven't really been pushing it in terms of cardio load and you
Speaker 5:  took a rest, so why don't you do like a bunch of sprints and
Speaker 5:  it's just like,
Speaker 6:  Oh, get
Speaker 5:  Outta here. Oh fine. I mean it's hard, it's hard. Building a training plan
Speaker 5:  is hard but that I was just like, okay, if my
Speaker 6:  Pixel watch tells me I'm gonna throw it into the sea.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Wait v can we talk about the notification you got from your galaxy
Speaker 1:  ring? This is just a little, little, little diversion into v's experience.
Speaker 5:  I was about to say. So like I, you know, I'm sinking my ring this morning
Speaker 5:  looking at the energy score and it's like, hey, you need to move around or
Speaker 5:  you might start gaining weight. No. And I was like, excuse me, what,
Speaker 5:  what I ran three miles this morning, go to jail.
Speaker 5:  Wait,
Speaker 1:  Is that, that's literally the words that it said you or you might start gaining
Speaker 1:  weight.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Hold on, let me, lemme look at this.
Speaker 1:  Absolutely not.
Speaker 5:  Your active time has decreased compared to your usual insufficient
Speaker 5:  activity may result in weight gain and other health issues. Try
Speaker 5:  standing up, moving around and reducing your sedentary time.
Speaker 5:  And it's because I let this dumb ring die yesterday so it didn't, it
Speaker 5:  didn't basically like capture my three mile run yesterday too.
Speaker 5:  'cause you know, I'd be out here doing 10 hours of workouts a week,
Speaker 5:  but you know, just like it thinks I missed one day and it's like, get
Speaker 5:  up hoe move around. Oh my gosh the ai, you might gain
Speaker 5:  weight. And I was just like, yeah, but what if I want it? I'm trying to get
Speaker 5:  jacked, I wanna gain weight 'cause muscles are heavier. It's so,
Speaker 5:  there's a lot of nuance and context
Speaker 1:  I'm
Speaker 15:  policy is, what a
Speaker 1:  it for a long time. Never say never with Google, but it feels like this
Speaker 1:  matters to Google in a very real way. What I still wonder
Speaker 1:  and what seems to be true is that Google has not made
Speaker 1:  any kind of like mainstream dent as a hardware
Speaker 1:  company yet. I think ironically like the Chromecast was probably the most
Speaker 1:  successful piece of hardware Google ever made. It was a huge hit, especially
Speaker 1:  at the beginning 'cause it was cheap and it worked really well and there's
Speaker 1:  really nothing since then that feels like a sort
Speaker 1:  of gigantic mainstream winner. Like there is still very much Apple and Samsung,
Speaker 1:  especially in the United States. And then like gigantic gap down to
Speaker 1:  Google. I
Speaker 5:  Would argue that the Pixel Watch is actually kind of the opposite
Speaker 5:  really. I think Samsung is hurting a little bit and they're having to
Speaker 5:  actually bring up their game a little. And because the Pixel Watch
Speaker 5:  was wildly popular when it first came out to the point where Samsung was
Speaker 5:  like, uhoh, I gotta do things. Here's a copycat Apple Watch Ultra and a
Speaker 5:  ring. So you know, I think that's surprisingly one area
Speaker 5:  that it's doing pretty well in. But you know, smart watches are kind of
Speaker 5:  bifurcated into iOS and Android at the moment anyway, so it didn't
Speaker 5:  have to really compete with Apple at all because people on Android can't
Speaker 5:  get an Apple watch. It only really had to compete with Samsung, which is
Speaker 5:  weirdly its partner in where OS land.
Speaker 5:  But it's kind of been eating Samsung's lunch for a
Speaker 5:  little bit 'cause it's, I don't know, it's it's, it's interesting. They're
Speaker 5:  doing weird interesting stuff there and it's kind of ecosystemy in a weird
Speaker 5:  way.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I mean I think the The Pixel watches actually is is a good example
Speaker 1:  and it does seem like, at least on that front, with the first one I remember
Speaker 1:  people being so excited just about the way it looked that it was like this
Speaker 1:  is the first smartwatch that doesn't sort of scream technology at
Speaker 1:  you. And that was, that was a big win for Google. So maybe that's
Speaker 1:  one of the answers to my question, which is gonna be, do we see anything
Speaker 1:  here that feels like it has kind of breakout potential? I think
Speaker 1:  I'm maybe the most bullish of the four of us on the possibility that the
Speaker 1:  fold could be a winner. I think at $1,800 there's a pretty big
Speaker 1:  within low cap on how big a winner it can possibly be.
Speaker 1:  But from the stuff that you've seen and you know, y'all have been testing
Speaker 1:  and talking to folks about these things for years now, do we see anything
Speaker 1:  that's sort of a, a possible kind of game changer in the Google hardware
Speaker 1:  business
Speaker 7:  Screenshots app? I dunno, it really comes down to like past
Speaker 7:  years have always been, oh the camera is great. Which it still is. Like people
Speaker 7:  know that The Pixel camera is great. Like that's its like main thing. But
Speaker 7:  this year it feels like all this AI stuff, like if it works it's gonna be
Speaker 7:  great. You know, like if it doesn't then it's gonna be meh. Like I see pixels
Speaker 7:  out in the world, like I think they're selling some, they are selling a few.
Speaker 7:  So I think like, you know, they've got a base of customers but it's like
Speaker 7:  how do you get them to upgrade? 'cause like hardware is like all the same
Speaker 7:  year over like all these like Pixel nine Pro and Pixel nine. It's like there
Speaker 7:  was some like tensor G four benchmarks. It's like barely faster than last
Speaker 7:  year's chip. So like it's not gonna be like that. That's not why you're gonna
Speaker 7:  upgrade. You're gonna upgrade four Gemini potentially for like some of these
Speaker 7:  new camera software features. It's like software, software, software this
Speaker 7:  year. And so like if the screenshot app works, like that's gonna be great
Speaker 7:  and if it doesn't then it's then I'm going to buy the fold and
Speaker 7:  for the next five years that'll be my phone because I can't afford an $1,800
Speaker 7:  phone.
Speaker 1:  I was gonna say, and and you are historically representative of people who
Speaker 1:  buy smartphones. Yeah. So that, that makes perfect sense. Exactly. No, I
Speaker 1:  mean the, the AI thing I think is, is a really interesting point because
Speaker 1:  the bet from all of these companies really is that they can take
Speaker 1:  a bunch of kind of little AI things, whether it's in the camera
Speaker 1:  or in the productivity stuff or in some of the wearables and that all of
Speaker 1:  that adds up to something that is kind of a tie breaker to
Speaker 1:  other devices. And I feel like, Alison, this has been a theme of a lot of
Speaker 1:  the coverage you've been doing recently is like, does all this AI stuff really
Speaker 1:  add up to anything? And I'm curious how you feel. Obviously we, we have to
Speaker 1:  review all these things, there's still lots to be seen and this is all changing
Speaker 1:  really fast. But do you have an early read of like, is there a kind
Speaker 1:  of whole greater than the sum of its parts in the AI story here?
Speaker 6:  This, I wish I did. This is just one of those like I feel like you
Speaker 6:  gotta live with the phone a little bit to see if it, I, I
Speaker 6:  think, you know, we, we all bought a Chromecast 'cause it solved a problem
Speaker 6:  where like, this is incredible, it's 20 bucks and you just plug it in the
Speaker 6:  back of your tv. I don't see anything like
Speaker 6:  that. You know, like in The
Speaker 5:  I think it's just the whole ambient computing thing. Like I think
Speaker 5:  completely to your point, it's gonna be the whole ecosystem play
Speaker 5:  because you know, The Pixel, I'm just, you know, wearable ladies, so of course
Speaker 5:  I think in wearables, but like the Pixel Watch when it came out they were
Speaker 5:  like, this works for anyone with any phone. And just increasingly year
Speaker 5:  by year, more and more features are just gonna work better if you have a
Speaker 5:  pixel phone with your pixel watch. So like this year it's gonna be
Speaker 5:  pixel recorder app on the watch, it's gonna be seeing your doorbell
Speaker 5:  feed and it's just gonna be one of those things where
Speaker 5:  I think it's just what do my gadgets play
Speaker 5:  well with? And that's how we win dominance. So if the Pixel Watch is
Speaker 5:  great and it works with other pixel hardware, that's Google saying
Speaker 5:  suck it Samsung because who uses smart things? Honest, honest
Speaker 5:  to God. I think that's like kind of what they're doing and why they just
Speaker 5:  go ambient computing when you're now watching every once in a while.
Speaker 5:  Wink, wink, nudge, nudge.
Speaker 1:  Well, and I think that's, that's what's been so sort of backhanded about
Speaker 1:  Google's entire hardware strategy over the years is that like
Speaker 1:  the reason people end up in the Samsung ecosystem is because they buy
Speaker 1:  Samsung phones and so then, then they're forced to use smart things. Google
Speaker 1:  is trying to convince you that there is some like essential googs
Speaker 1:  that is worth buying into the ecosystem. and it has just always felt like
Speaker 1:  they needed the one hardware victory to get there.
Speaker 1:  And, and it's like people, people want the gadget and then they buy into
Speaker 1:  the software and Google is trying to do that backwards, which I think is
Speaker 1:  really interesting but doesn't really seem like it has worked in a huge way.
Speaker 1:  Obviously time will tell and, and the reviews will be really interesting
Speaker 1:  and I'm, I'm like, I I think it's
Speaker 1:  are more important than I'm realizing You can always email us at Vergecast
Speaker 1:  at The Verge dot com or call the hotline eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 1:  We love hearing from you. We love hearing all of your thoughts and questions
Speaker 1:  about all things tech. I'm still looking for some