# Transcript
ID: 46dd2ce3-0ad0-4f9d-9587-c694e27768d1
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6478704668024196838/-2587906941310819761/s93290-US-3363s-1723975256.mp3
Description: Laura Mae Martin is a big believer in the settings menu. Martin is Google’s Executive Productivity Advisor, and spends much of her time working with other Googlers on improving their productivity and communication systems — and one of the things she often recommends is taking a few minutes to poke through the options. “With your phone, with your email, your Slack, all these things, the features are there but we don’t take the time to dive into them,” she says. She even thinks you should maybe have to look at settings before you can use the app. “Like, you can’t get into the app unless you spend 10 minutes figuring out what it can do.”
On this episode of The Vergecast, the first in our three-part miniseries about all things productivity and work, we talk to Martin about how she sees things changing. Four years after the pandemic forced us all to work from home, are we finally figuring out remote and hybrid work? Are managers realizing that butts-in-seats isn’t, and maybe was never, a good metric for productivity? And is the era of the hard-charging hustle bro finally giving way to a healthier, more holistic way of thinking about being productive? Martin sees all these things from so many perspectives, and has lots of thoughts on everything from communication styles to energy flows.
We also talk about the rise in digital productivity tools like Notion and Slack, and why email is still so important — and still so terrible. One of Martin’s jobs at Google is to consult with the teams building Workspace apps like Docs and Gmail, and she has lots of thoughts on how those product works and how they could be better. We also talk about whether AI stands to change the way we get things done, and whether it’ll help us do more or just give us more to do.
Along the way, Martin offers us lots of practical tips on how to manage our digital lives a little better. Charging your phone outside the bedroom, no-tech Tuesdays, and a couple of prettier email labels might actually go a long way. And if you have too many notes in too many places, it’s time to get a Main List going.
If you want to know more on everything we talk about in this episode, here are a few links to get you started:
Laura Mae Martin’s website
Her book, Uptime: A Practical Guide to Personal Productivity and Wellbeing’
The Google Workspace guide to productivity and wellbeing
The Verge’s favorite tools to stay organized
The best note-taking apps for collecting your thoughts and data
All I want is one productivity app that can handle everything
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (21 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the Zettel Cast and System.
Speaker 2:  If you don't know what that is, don't worry about it and honestly you're
Speaker 2:  probably better off for it. But if you know, you know, I'm your friend
Speaker 2:  David Pierce and this is the first in art new three part series
Speaker 2:  that we're calling Works Smarter. And the idea is basically to talk about
Speaker 2:  productivity. But I mean that in the biggest, broadest
Speaker 2:  loosest way possible. Like I will talk to you four
Speaker 2:  hours about calendar apps and task management systems and
Speaker 2:  whether notion is better than one note. Like truly, I will talk to you about
Speaker 2:  this four hours, but no one needs to hear that.
Speaker 2:  I, I just think that these questions about how we should deal
Speaker 2:  with all of the stuff that happens in our digital lives
Speaker 2:  is really interesting. How should we think about screen time and managing
Speaker 2:  our relationships with our devices? Where should we put all of our
Speaker 2:  stuff? We have all this stuff online, from photos to sensitive
Speaker 2:  documents to emails to like just the random things that you
Speaker 2:  accumulate as you go about your life day to day. How should we manage all
Speaker 2:  of that? Does it matter? Do you need to manage all of that? These are the
Speaker 2:  questions I think are really interesting and we're in a minute right now
Speaker 2:  where a, there are a lot of new tools being built to make sense of
Speaker 2:  all of your digital stuff and we're starting to rethink
Speaker 2:  what it means to be productive. What it means to be a person
Speaker 2:  online is changing and I think that's really interesting. And so we're gonna
Speaker 2:  spend the next three Sundays talking about all of that. We're gonna talk
Speaker 2:  to people who make products, people who use products, people who talk to
Speaker 2:  people about using those products and try to make sense of all of it
Speaker 2:  and maybe come up with some like cool practical tips. Along the way
Speaker 2:  for the first one we're gonna talk to Laura Mae Martin who works at Google,
Speaker 2:  helping other people at Google be more productive. She coaches,
Speaker 2:  executives, she teaches courses. She has a newsletter that You can subscribe
Speaker 2:  to. She just wrote a book called Uptime that's really good and the
Speaker 2:  thrust of her work is to help people get more done but to also
Speaker 2:  redefine what that looks like. She thinks a lot about how you should use
Speaker 2:  downtime and how you should structure your days and how you should think
Speaker 2:  about your own energy flows and communication styles and really what it means
Speaker 2:  to just kind of be more deliberate about everything that you
Speaker 2:  do and not just professionally. One of her big ideas that I really like and
Speaker 2:  we talk about a bit is this collapse of the idea of there's a professional
Speaker 2:  you and a personal you. I think that's wrong. There's just you. You have
Speaker 2:  to do all this stuff and increasingly all this stuff is meshed together and
Speaker 2:  happening on screens. So we talked about all that and
Speaker 2:  much more. It was a really interesting conversation and I learned a ton so
Speaker 2:  let's just get into it. All of that is coming in just a second but I have
Speaker 2:  to check my notes to make sure I got to everything. So hold on, we'll be
Speaker 2:  right back.
Speaker 2:  And all of that she says is just wrong. It's
Speaker 2:  unhealthy, it leads to burnout, it doesn't actually help you accomplish more
Speaker 2:  over time, it's just unproductive. So we started just
Speaker 2:  by talking about that and I asked her basically yes, okay you
Speaker 2:  want this more holistic, more sane, less hustle
Speaker 2:  culturey way of thinking about productivity but is that
Speaker 2:  realistic? Are we actually going to get that in a time where
Speaker 2:  still maybe the best way we have to measure productivity is how many hours
Speaker 2:  are you in the office and how many things do you produce?
Speaker 2:  Even if everybody intellectually agrees those are bad measures. Those are
Speaker 2:  kind of still the measures we have. So I asked her what she's seeing. Is
Speaker 2:  there a real cultural shift happening in the way that we
Speaker 2:  talk about productivity or is this just kind of a woo woo
Speaker 2:  thing that we like to tell ourselves before we get back to yelling at people
Speaker 2:  about not working enough?
Speaker 4:  What I would ask of you too is all these people you've talked to that kind
Speaker 4:  of had that mentality for maybe 10 or 15 years, what happened is then is
Speaker 4:  that sustainable or are those people now totally stepped back from
Speaker 4:  the workforce and started a farm because that was their only way of kind
Speaker 4:  of pulling out of it. And so I think that one thing the pandemic did is
Speaker 4:  kind of shift our mindset to, okay, we have to think of ourselves as whole
Speaker 4:  people and everything we have going on, it's work,
Speaker 4:  it's home, and how do we look at how to keep employees happy and
Speaker 4:  productive long term? And so the, even the word productivity, I didn't really
Speaker 4:  want it in the title of the book 'cause I just feel like it brings up this
Speaker 4:  sense of like, ugh, I gotta churn more out. Kind of that sense of dread.
Speaker 4:  But I think when we think about wellbeing and people ask about the
Speaker 4:  balance of the two, it makes it seem like they're the
Speaker 4:  opposite and they're two ends of the stick that you're trying to go back
Speaker 4:  and forth on. But when you think about the fact that when you
Speaker 4:  prioritize your wellbeing, you end up more productive, which
Speaker 4:  gives you more time for your wellbeing, which makes you more productive.
Speaker 4:  And so it ends up being actually this holistic view and
Speaker 4:  sustainable view of getting things done. I think the hustle culture
Speaker 4:  is still having its moment in the sense of, you know, you hear a
Speaker 4:  lot of, ugh, I'm back to back, I'm crazy, you know how
Speaker 4:  it is, fire drills this, this language around it. And so I
Speaker 4:  try to be aggressively the opposite and say awkward things like, oh I'm actually
Speaker 4:  the perfect level of balance or I have the right exactly the right amount
Speaker 4:  of commitments or you know, I, I have breaks in my day and it, it makes people
Speaker 4:  feel weird because you know, that's what we're supposed to do but nobody
Speaker 4:  talks like that. So I think we're the, the language is dragging a bit but
Speaker 4:  I think the mindset is there, which is great.
Speaker 2:  It's so funny you bring up the word productivity 'cause this is the thing
Speaker 2:  I've been thinking a lot about too. And like we talk about productivity,
Speaker 2:  going back to like the industrial revolution is like literally how many things
Speaker 2:  are you making intellectually if you ask anyone,
Speaker 2:  it's a terrible measure, right? Like all of our measures of productivity
Speaker 2:  in life now are bad. The like how long were you sitting in your
Speaker 2:  chair is not a good measure of productivity? How many things did you make
Speaker 2:  as like a knowledge worker is not even a thing and yet it, it
Speaker 2:  feels like in aggregate nothing has changed. And I, I think
Speaker 2:  in a certain way, like I talk to folks at companies like Microsoft and Google
Speaker 2:  who are like looking for new ways to track people with the idea that maybe
Speaker 2:  if we attach more numbers to this we'll suddenly figure it out and everything
Speaker 2:  will be great. What I wonder is whether
Speaker 2:  like we're gonna look back 50 years from now and realize that like the pandemic
Speaker 2:  was a real sort of cultural inflection point or
Speaker 2:  if we're gonna be stuck in these problems forever even though everybody knows
Speaker 2:  the solutions we've been talking about for decades are not the right ones.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think even the like how long are you sitting at your desk that you
Speaker 4:  mentioned? You know that nine to five, I feel like even with the pandemic
Speaker 4:  we saw a little bit of a shift to and and some companies like Google are
Speaker 4:  already thinking this way, but oh if somebody feels like they work
Speaker 4:  better from 10 to six, is that something we can honor? And and we
Speaker 4:  only would've figured that out about ourselves when we were given that little
Speaker 4:  bit of breathing room and flexibility to decide our schedules and without
Speaker 4:  commutes and working from home. And so I think the goal when I talk
Speaker 4:  to managers and and people who are thinking how do I judge if
Speaker 4:  it's not number of calls per day, if it's not, you know, how much did I get
Speaker 4:  done that day? What should I be really judging? And I think it goes back
Speaker 4:  to that longevity piece. Do you have happy, successful,
Speaker 4:  inspired creative employees that want to stay and that are performing
Speaker 4:  well? And when we look at the macro level, so instead of hey, what did you
Speaker 4:  get done this week? How long were you sitting in your chair today? Knowing
Speaker 4:  that there will be ebbs and flows and giving people that flexibility instead
Speaker 4:  saying, what did you accomplish this quarter? Or Hey we're gonna look at
Speaker 4:  this you know, half year project and you do it in the way that feels best
Speaker 4:  to you and it gives more of that chance for you to figure out what
Speaker 4:  is the best way to do this, that breathing room instead of the micromanage
Speaker 4:  mentality.
Speaker 2:  I'm curious how you think about this even in like the coaching you're doing
Speaker 2:  with folks at Google. 'cause I, I would assume most of the people you're
Speaker 2:  working with are managers and other sort of high ranking people, people
Speaker 2:  who oversee people generally speaking, right? Yes. And like those are the
Speaker 2:  people who set the rules for the other people, many of whom are, are gonna
Speaker 2:  read a book like yours in order to figure out how to escape the meeting hell
Speaker 2:  that their managers have put them in. And so like I think I,
Speaker 2:  this idea of starting at the top to make some of this change makes
Speaker 2:  a lot of sense to me. But it also seems like the last few years have been
Speaker 2:  a lot of people raising their hands being like, I get way more work done
Speaker 2:  at home. Can I stay at home? And a lot of managers being like absolutely
Speaker 2:  not come into the office because that's how I tell if you're working. What
Speaker 2:  are you seeing from the manager side of thing? Like are they just slowly
Speaker 2:  like learning how to let go a little bit on some of that stuff?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think, you know, there's a lot of flexibility in the sense that okay,
Speaker 4:  if you're gonna spend three days at home, then I'm gonna be okay with whatever
Speaker 4:  you're choosing to do on those two days. If you wanna switch the days that
Speaker 4:  you're here or let's think about our team meeting schedule. And so you're
Speaker 4:  right, I always encourage even from the wellbeing perspective, we were just
Speaker 4:  talking about, you know, I tell managers if you're gonna say, oh don't
Speaker 4:  worry about working on the weekends, but I'm sending emails on the weekends
Speaker 4:  or take your vacation off. But you know, you'll see me emailing on vacation
Speaker 4:  that doesn't set the example. So it really does have to start at the top
Speaker 4:  where you might create, you know, one thing I do with a lot of executives
Speaker 4:  is create a user manual meaning a a description of how they
Speaker 4:  work. And I think it's important to showcase there, hey, I've really thought
Speaker 4:  about where I work best and I've thought about the fact that I have my power
Speaker 4:  hours or my best work time when I'm at home in the morning. And so I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  do my best to keep those free and communicate that and encourage people on
Speaker 4:  your team to do the same and have that empowerment to say, I'm really
Speaker 4:  thinking about when I get my best work done. And then as a manager both
Speaker 4:  living that and communicating it. Because the more that you talk about those
Speaker 4:  things, the more it says, oh you know, our VP does this so I
Speaker 4:  feel like I can do that. And they're showing how they get more done and I
Speaker 4:  can do the same.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Do you have a strong thesis on hybrid work? It feels like
Speaker 2:  we're in a moment right now where I suspect everyone you talk to is asking
Speaker 2:  you like, how do I set up my team to succeed in a hybrid
Speaker 2:  universe? And at some point maybe the answer is lots of answers, but that's
Speaker 2:  no fun. So do you have a sort of strong idea about how to kind of do this
Speaker 2:  correctly?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think that some level of flexibility is ideal.
Speaker 4:  So saying, you know, everyone has to be in the office every day at this time.
Speaker 4:  I don't think you're gonna get your best results at that point. You
Speaker 4:  might not even get the best people with that schedule. And so I think figuring
Speaker 4:  out what is that right mix of saying, hey, we as a team need to connect
Speaker 4:  and that needs to be on this day. And setting those things from the beginning
Speaker 4:  so that people can then work around it. But at the same time, you know, I
Speaker 4:  know a lot of successful companies that have only remote employees, but they're
Speaker 4:  really thinking about, okay then we need to have these connection points
Speaker 4:  throughout the year. Maybe more in-person offsites or you know, if you're
Speaker 4:  working globally, you need to have more of a structure of saying, okay, when
Speaker 4:  we have APEC US meetings, they're always on Tuesday night, Wednesday morning.
Speaker 4:  'cause that's respecting, you know, culturally and everybody's not just working
Speaker 4:  at all different times. And so I think it's looking at the makeup of your
Speaker 4:  team. 'cause hybrid can mean lots of different things. It can mean, you know,
Speaker 4:  in the office and in work it can mean some of your team is in the office
Speaker 4:  and some of your team is remote, which says you know a lot about how you're
Speaker 4:  conducting meetings and making sure that people feel included and things
Speaker 4:  like that. So I think it's really about intention. I mean so many things
Speaker 4:  are about intention, but sitting down and saying, what does this actually
Speaker 4:  look like and how can I make it work? And then the other thing I always encourage
Speaker 4:  is, you know, don't just set it and forget it. If you have a team who's hybrid
Speaker 4:  and you're saying, Hey, let's test out this three, two model, let's test
Speaker 4:  out all of us being here Wednesday, and then you choose these other days
Speaker 4:  and our meetings fall these days, go back in a quarter half year
Speaker 4:  and take a survey and ask how it's working. Because a lot of times you won't
Speaker 4:  flush that out unless you ask. And so that's the best way to make sure it's,
Speaker 4:  it's working for everyone.
Speaker 2:  Totally. Yeah. One of the things I really liked about your book is you, you
Speaker 2:  keep coming back to the idea that you just kind of have to do this stuff
Speaker 2:  on purpose. And I never, I never, I hadn't really thought about it
Speaker 2:  until I was reading it, but I think it's really true how much of work, and
Speaker 2:  frankly like digital life in general just happens to us,
Speaker 2:  right? Like things appear in your inbox, stuff happens in your calendar,
Speaker 2:  like Slack is always going, there's just, there's just things always happening.
Speaker 2:  And I think like the, all the examples you gave of executives you talked
Speaker 2:  to where you're like, where are you spending time and they just don't know
Speaker 2:  was both very, made me feel a lot better about my own habits,
Speaker 2:  but was also really interesting and, and I think we're in a moment right
Speaker 2:  now where so much has changed about how we work and
Speaker 2:  like the tools that we use and the kinds of work that gets done. and it feels
Speaker 2:  like we just haven't developed the muscles in so many
Speaker 2:  ways to actually both like measure this stuff with
Speaker 2:  numbers and tools and stuff, but also to just say like, okay, how is any
Speaker 2:  of this supposed to work? What am I actually doing? What am I getting out
Speaker 2:  of this? And I feel like it was, it was such a simple piece of advice to
Speaker 2:  take out of like a, in in a lot of ways a very sort of practical technical
Speaker 2:  book. But it was just like, just pay attention. Like yeah,
Speaker 4:  Just, just, yeah,
Speaker 2:  Just look at this as you're doing it.
Speaker 4:  Well I think it was one of Cal Newport's books, maybe Digital Minimalism
Speaker 4:  that talks about Amish culture and how they don't reject all
Speaker 4:  technology. They actually look at each individual technology and really
Speaker 4:  analyze is this technology, what is it gonna do for us? What is it gonna
Speaker 4:  take from us? Is it worth adopting? They like really think through it. And
Speaker 4:  I feel like it's the opposite where like you said, it's like, all right,
Speaker 4:  slack's on the scene, now we're all in Slack. Okay now we have our phone,
Speaker 4:  now we sign up for this newsletter. It's just like we default into these
Speaker 4:  things and then we spend a lot of time kind of backtracking
Speaker 4:  and say like, okay, do we really need this email in our inbox? Do I actually
Speaker 4:  want to be on my phone for this many hours every night? You know, so it's
Speaker 4:  that reverse mentality. But you know, I joke with people, my phone
Speaker 4:  has a bedtime, like the alarm goes off, I put it to bed, I put it to bed
Speaker 4:  in its own bedroom. But that requires a lot of intention 'cause it's much
Speaker 4:  easier for me to just sit with it all night on my couch doing things that
Speaker 4:  I actually don't wanna do. So it does kind of require that thoughtfulness
Speaker 4:  of what time do I wanna be done with my phone at night? And then how do I
Speaker 4:  make that happen with a routine?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. And I think there's an interesting tension
Speaker 2:  in that that I, I find really fascinating about this whole space. Like I
Speaker 2:  really like the productivity subreddit because half the posts on there are
Speaker 2:  just somebody being like, I I, why can't I get anything done? I'm super burned
Speaker 2:  out. And half the comments are always like trying to be helpful and give
Speaker 2:  them tips and sort of build them up and say, take a break, you know, here
Speaker 2:  are some things that work for me. And then the other half are just people
Speaker 2:  being like, just be disciplined. Shut up. Like just if you've stuff to do,
Speaker 2:  just do the stuff. Why I don't understand what the problem is. And I think
Speaker 2:  it's, it's such an interesting dichotomy because on the one hand,
Speaker 2:  like if you want use your phone less, just use your phone less,
Speaker 2:  right? Is, is not, I think is, is not a particularly helpful piece of advice,
Speaker 2:  but is not a wrong piece of advice and like charge your phone in the other
Speaker 2:  room is a thing You can just do, right? But I also
Speaker 2:  think we're in a moment right now where all of the questions are being asked
Speaker 2:  about like, okay, how can I sort of use technology to help me
Speaker 2:  manage my technology? And we're talking about, you know, focus modes and
Speaker 2:  all these different apps that build trees when you're not using them and
Speaker 2:  all this different stuff. So I, I'm curious like how you feel
Speaker 2:  about just kind of being a thoughtful person and being
Speaker 2:  proactive and thinking this stuff through versus like, can you build systems
Speaker 2:  to protect you from your own worst instincts? Because I feel like a lot of
Speaker 2:  technology is trying to take advantage of your worst instincts
Speaker 2:  and you're very much trying to keep people out of those holes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think I equate it always to just, if you were saying, hey I want
Speaker 4:  to eat healthier, you know, that's like a lofty, it's just kind of a
Speaker 4:  big goal. And so I, if you have years of having those
Speaker 4:  practices and recipes and it may, it's easier, but if you're getting started
Speaker 4:  you really wanna drill down to what does that actually look like? So all
Speaker 4:  the way down to like a grocery list, like this week I wanna eat healthy,
Speaker 4:  what am I actually gonna buy at the store and what am I gonna clear out of
Speaker 4:  my cabinet? And so that's why in the book I didn't just want these like
Speaker 4:  delegate more, you know, I feel like those are just like too big I think.
Speaker 4:  And those, those are the people on Reddit you're talking about that are like,
Speaker 4:  just put your phone away. It's like, well we almost need to trick our brain
Speaker 4:  into these like little small, you know, routines. Even with
Speaker 4:  myself, I see, you know, when I can't get something done, I talk about in
Speaker 4:  the book, that's been a really popular idea of like splitting up the task
Speaker 4:  into the preparation of the task and the doing of it because for some reason
Speaker 4:  I like that. Yeah. You know, setting out anything I need to do and then walking
Speaker 4:  away and then stumbling upon it the next day and saying, oh this is
Speaker 4:  already set out. It's like, that's such a simple thing. And so you could
Speaker 4:  just say, just do it, just bake the muffins. But you know, instead of that
Speaker 4:  I can say, okay, no I have actually a recipe something to do, I'm just gonna
Speaker 4:  set that ingredients out. And so I think it's a mix of, you know,
Speaker 4:  having the understanding why these things are important,
Speaker 4:  but then also giving yourself a break and saying yes it's very hard
Speaker 4:  to just say, put your phone away. So maybe I will take advantage of
Speaker 4:  something on my phone that turns off certain apps at a certain time just
Speaker 4:  to remind myself and maybe in three months that could be turned off and I
Speaker 4:  would have the good habits to just put my phone away. But if you never start
Speaker 4:  with some of those things and, and I do think the technology itself
Speaker 4:  has a lot of those features that we just don't go into, which I talk about
Speaker 4:  in the tools chapters, you know, like You can choose, here are the 10 people
Speaker 4:  I wanna get email notifications from after hours and that
Speaker 4:  can be a setting and no one takes the time to set that up again. We default
Speaker 4:  into, oh you know, there was a office wide email about the
Speaker 4:  carnival going on and I open my phone at nine to see it. You know, so it's,
Speaker 4:  we really just have to either take the time to set up rules
Speaker 4:  for ourself, set up the rules and the technology itself, but then knowing
Speaker 4:  that with time we'll see the benefits of those things and say, wow, I
Speaker 4:  really see when I do this, it makes a big difference. And now I have that
Speaker 4:  as a habit in, in general.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. One of the reasons I knew I wanted to have you on the show was because
Speaker 2:  you have a whole chapter in your book in which you just yell at people to
Speaker 2:  use the settings of their apps. And it's like, that's, that's a vergecast
Speaker 2:  thing if I've ever heard it in my entire life.
Speaker 4:  It's simple, but it's underlooked. I think, you know, I even talk about the
Speaker 4:  dishwasher thing in the book about how my father-in-law, just
Speaker 4:  it's his dishwasher is a piece of art. It's so perfectly
Speaker 4:  stacked and everything comes out clean. He gets so much in there. And when
Speaker 4:  I asked how did you learn how to do this? Like, he's like, no, the curved
Speaker 4:  bowls go over here. Just like, how did you know that? He's like, well I read
Speaker 4:  the manual for 10 minutes when I got the dishwasher. And it's like, how many
Speaker 4:  of us do that? No one. And, and if we run the dishwasher every single day,
Speaker 4:  imagine how much that 10 minutes of just really understanding the settings
Speaker 4:  would benefit us every single time we run the dishwasher. So, you know, With
Speaker 4:  your phone with your email, your Slack, like all these things,
Speaker 4:  the features are there, but we don't take the time to
Speaker 4:  dive into, you know, there should be like a limit. Like you can't get into
Speaker 4:  the app unless you spend 10 minutes figuring out what it
Speaker 4:  can do basically.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I've spent a lot of time in recent years trying to figure out
Speaker 2:  whose responsibility it is to do that stuff. 'cause on the one hand,
Speaker 2:  like there are a lot of tools out there that are vastly more powerful than
Speaker 2:  almost anybody knows, right? And sometimes, like Excel is the perfect example,
Speaker 2:  right? Like if you really know how to use Excel, You can run the damn world
Speaker 2:  out of Excel. But if you don't and you just need to type a bunch of numbers
Speaker 2:  in and get the sum of those numbers, like that's fine. You don't actually
Speaker 2:  need to know how to use the tool. And so I think to force you to learn how
Speaker 2:  to do everything before you do anything is actually the wrong outcome.
Speaker 2:  But then is it excel's job to teach me as I go or
Speaker 2:  is that gonna be annoying? Because you get all those little pop-up tool tips
Speaker 2:  that everybody just ignores and closes anyway. So I I I don't know, part
Speaker 2:  of me wonders if this is just sort of an impossible problem to solve that
Speaker 2:  it's like how do you help me along without getting in the way
Speaker 2:  as I do the stuff that I actually need to do? 'cause I think to your point,
Speaker 2:  the, the other thing that's happening is like you get Slack for the first
Speaker 2:  time and you open Slack and there's already stuff happening. Like the,
Speaker 2:  the minute you get Slack, you are already behind and and that's
Speaker 2:  stressful, right? And so, and I think it's true with a lot of work. It's
Speaker 2:  like you don't download PowerPoint to learn how to use PowerPoint. You download
Speaker 2:  PowerPoint because you owe somebody a deck, right? And so I think the, this
Speaker 2:  thing of like building the work about work into
Speaker 2:  the work is just really hard. And I agree with you that it's really valuable
Speaker 2:  and, and sort of whose responsibility it is to make that easier has always
Speaker 2:  been a challenge. And I think I talk to a lot of product people who can't
Speaker 2:  figure out how to do it. 'cause like we don't wanna get in your way. Oh,
Speaker 2:  I
Speaker 4:  Was gonna say, yeah, I work a lot with our product people and I think it's
Speaker 4:  a finding that right balance of like Google Calendar for example,
Speaker 4:  can tell you how much time you're spending in each type of event and give
Speaker 4:  you all this data and it's like, but if you're my mom
Speaker 4:  who's just kind of scheduling a couple one-off things on her Google calendar,
Speaker 4:  you know, she doesn't care about that. So I think it's, and she, it would
Speaker 4:  actually probably waste her time to see a whole tutorial of how I'm
Speaker 4:  using Google Calendar. But I think the right point to hit is maybe
Speaker 4:  if I'm changing the color of an event, you know, then they say,
Speaker 4:  okay, this person is now customizing, you know, all of their
Speaker 4:  events and maybe they care about did you know, you can see how much time
Speaker 4:  you spend in each calendar color. You know, so that, and then, oh, and by
Speaker 4:  the way, You can click this little tutorial. So it's kind of like, where
Speaker 4:  is the right hook? You know? Or if you see somebody add one
Speaker 4:  multiple time zones, now you know, okay you're working across time zones,
Speaker 4:  did you know You can add world clock? And so you know, just finding that
Speaker 4:  right, what is the profile of the user? Where are they looking
Speaker 4:  for more information? And then how can you make it easy from there? Because
Speaker 4:  I totally agree, people are using the tools in so many different ways. You
Speaker 4:  don't wanna overwhelm the getting the sum in the sales person
Speaker 4:  with right, every single formula available. So I think it's, it's trying
Speaker 4:  to find that profile person and and give them the right things they need.
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta take a break, but then we're gonna come back and we're
Speaker 2:  gonna talk about digital tools because I have too many of them on my computer
Speaker 2:  and it's time to figure out which ones to use. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  stuff that you're talking about?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's a great question. I think the first thing I like to
Speaker 4:  for tools just to solve their problems, but it's really the intention
Speaker 4:  behind the tools, it's how you're using the tools that makes the biggest
Speaker 4:  difference. And so it's thinking through that first before, again, before
Speaker 4:  you just dive into the tool.
Speaker 2:  Okay, well as someone who uses every tool and expects them all to solve my
Speaker 2:  problems, I feel personally attacked by that. But, but I think
Speaker 2:  that makes sense to me. And I think the idea of
Speaker 2:  having one thing that you treat as sort of your main
Speaker 2:  communication system is, is really smart, right?
Speaker 4:  It telling people is the next step. So if people chat me or
Speaker 4:  say, Hey, can I grab time on your calendar? I usually say, Hey, do you mind
Speaker 4:  starting with email and then we'll go from there. And so it's just a gentle
Speaker 4:  nudge putting it, you know, and of course I still meet and chat with people,
Speaker 4:  but it's just, hey, this is where I prefer communication and it just makes
Speaker 4:  it a lot easier on you. 'cause I always say if you have like 12 places
Speaker 4:  to check for things you need to do, think about if you went out to your street
Speaker 4:  and you had like 12 mailboxes, it's like you'd have to go to every single
Speaker 4:  one and be like, is there a bill in here? Is this all advertisement? So by
Speaker 4:  having less places to check, it gives our brain a little bit
Speaker 4:  less stress. So if yours is Slack, then you've funneled people there and
Speaker 4:  your brain thinks, okay, if I check here, I'm pretty much good, you know,
Speaker 4:  I gotta look other places, but people know, look for me here. And that can
Speaker 4:  help a lot.
Speaker 2:  What do you tell people who are like, I wanna do chat
Speaker 2:  or I want to do email, or I really believe in meetings but my
Speaker 2:  boss is different and that's not up to
Speaker 2:  me. Like Yeah, I, I do think the, the one thing I hear a lot from people
Speaker 2:  who are sort of mad at productivity culture is they're like this, this all
Speaker 2:  sounds great for people who are completely in charge of their own life and
Speaker 2:  schedule. Yeah. And that's just not most people, right? Yeah. Like most people
Speaker 2:  have a job where someone else tells them more or
Speaker 2:  less where to be and what to do and how to communicate all the time. And
Speaker 2:  I, I think it's, it's easy in that moment to just kind of throw your hands
Speaker 2:  up and be like, well I'm not in charge, there's nothing I can do about it.
Speaker 2:  But I'm curious, I mean most of the people you talk to I think are are fairly
Speaker 2:  senior, but like they have bosses. What do you tell those people? Is the
Speaker 2:  job just to kind of adapt?
Speaker 4:  Well I think now I coach executives, but I mean in my 14 years
Speaker 4:  at Google I've coached, you know, all levels and I've also been all
Speaker 4:  levels, I've been what I call the sandwich level, which is I have people
Speaker 4:  reporting to me, I'm reporting to people, you know, I'm not the executive
Speaker 4:  who's making all the decisions. And so I, I try to include in the
Speaker 4:  book those things that I still teach in my scalable learnings that are
Speaker 4:  more directed at what you're talking about. And I think when I had that,
Speaker 4:  I prefer email since I also had a manager who
Speaker 4:  exclusively chatted. You know, that was the only way he was gonna communicate
Speaker 4:  with me. And so I think that what I talk about the whole book is
Speaker 4:  even 80 20 is gonna make a huge difference. Like if everybody who's coming
Speaker 4:  to me and says, Hey, can you do a coffee chat? And I say, Hey, can you
Speaker 4:  actually send an email first? But then I say, you know, I always pick three
Speaker 4:  people that can chat me no matter what. And it's usually like my boss, my
Speaker 4:  boss's boss, and maybe like a cross-functional partner that I'm working with.
Speaker 4:  Sure. If they chat me, I'm not going to say, well I prefer email. But
Speaker 4:  if I've done that with everybody on my team,
Speaker 4:  then now I've still shifted, you know, most of my energy into the
Speaker 4:  right place. So same thing, you know, if you make this perfect schedule that
Speaker 4:  you wanted to fall this way, you know, you can't tell your manager, Hey,
Speaker 4:  I can't meet during this time, that's my power hours. But you know,
Speaker 4:  if you've set aside, that's
Speaker 2:  My designated walk time.
Speaker 4:  Exactly right. But if you've done that with everyone else, you
Speaker 4:  know, if you have no plan then it'll never fall a plan. But if you have some
Speaker 4:  plan, it'll at least fall some and you feel a difference with
Speaker 4:  some, you know, you feel a big difference with saying, so I think sometimes
Speaker 4:  people just throw up their arms and say, well I don't have control over my
Speaker 4:  meetings and I don't have control over this. But no matter what your level,
Speaker 4:  there still is something you have control over. You know, and,
Speaker 4:  and that's the only lever You can really pull.
Speaker 2:  Where is the science right now on kind of energy
Speaker 2:  flows and how we're starting to understand when people are and are not
Speaker 2:  productive? Because again, I think it's, it's pretty obviously a
Speaker 2:  personal thing, but also it seems like there's an increasing body of research
Speaker 2:  that says everyone has that kind of cycle
Speaker 2:  that you're describing and we can attack those cycles with different
Speaker 2:  systems in different places. Like how well do we kind of understand
Speaker 2:  what peak productivity looks like for people?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, weirdly, I feel like a lot of the studies that have been happening,
Speaker 4:  like almost started with sleep. So like those natural
Speaker 4:  circadian rhythms of like how are we sleeping, when are we resting? And
Speaker 4:  then one of my favorite books is by Daniel Pink called When. And I feel like
Speaker 4:  he really started talking about, okay, but how does that
Speaker 4:  apply to productivity? You know? And so how do we take those rhythms that
Speaker 4:  we know about ourselves and say I'm just somebody who sits down at
Speaker 4:  eight in the morning and does not feel like jumping into the day or
Speaker 4:  you know, I'm a person who naturally gets an afternoon lull. And of course
Speaker 4:  it's very personal and I would say that if you talk to the a hundred last
Speaker 4:  people that I coached, I would say this would be the top answer of the
Speaker 4:  one thing they took away and, and immediately applied and made the
Speaker 4:  biggest difference. Because not all time slots are created equally. And
Speaker 4:  I think that we look at our schedule and we say, okay, I need 30 minutes
Speaker 4:  tomorrow. I need an hour to work on something. So for me,
Speaker 4:  blocking nine to 10 is so different than blocking four to five.
Speaker 4:  It's totally different. I'm gonna feel different in that moment. I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  produce different work, you know, and so I, I'm gonna be in different
Speaker 4:  energies. And so just knowing that small thing about myself can help me shift
Speaker 4:  just a couple things so that I can do it where it feels right, but it
Speaker 4:  doesn't just mean, hey, I'm focused two or three hours of the day. That's,
Speaker 4:  that's my day.
Speaker 2:  Is your experience that most people, when you ask them about that,
Speaker 2:  can self-assess pretty quickly?
Speaker 4:  No. Okay. I think they can say things like, I'm not
Speaker 4:  really a morning person or I'm a bit of a night owl, or
Speaker 4:  I like to do, I find myself not wanting to do this work
Speaker 4:  at this time. You know, it's kind of these like little snippets. But if I
Speaker 4:  say, Hey, what are two or three hours a day that you do your best heads down,
Speaker 4:  focus strategic work. Not a lot of people have like that exact
Speaker 4:  answer. So, but it's so fun to uncover it with people because
Speaker 4:  you know, it can be as simple as, okay, just keep a little post-it and when
Speaker 4:  you're feeling your best, write down what time it is. Some of the conditions,
Speaker 4:  you know, this goes back to working from home, working in the office kind
Speaker 4:  of thing. Just what are some of those patterns you're noticing? Well, oh,
Speaker 4:  every time I'm working from home and it's, you know, one woman I loved, she
Speaker 4:  noticed it was like 10 to one every day she would write down, I'm feeling
Speaker 4:  really focused. Well then when she was in the office, she was taking a break
Speaker 4:  every day at noon to eat lunch and she was like, you know what, I actually,
Speaker 4:  that's like one of my best hours of the day and I'm just eating lunch, so
Speaker 4:  what if I shift some of my lunches to 1:00 PM and squeeze that extra hour
Speaker 4:  out of my best time? And that's just such a small change and such a small
Speaker 4:  thing she noticed. But now she's getting back like three hours of the week
Speaker 4:  of focus time just from shifting lunch and knowing that about herself. So
Speaker 4:  I think that people have those general
Speaker 4:  nuggets, but they haven't actually thought through what is my
Speaker 4:  ideal two to three hours. And you know, it can be from sometimes getting
Speaker 4:  yourself thinking about it can say, Hey, if you had these things to do tomorrow,
Speaker 4:  some focus things that just require you like build a new presentation or
Speaker 4:  write something and you had no meetings, no commitment, no
Speaker 4:  structure to your day at all, how would you set it up for tomorrow?
Speaker 4:  So that's when You can get the sense if they're like, well I'd wake up kind
Speaker 4:  of late and you know, then I'd do this for a while and
Speaker 4:  then I might take a break and work out. And then now, okay, now I can
Speaker 4:  tell you're kind of more of an afternoon person. 'cause you haven't ever
Speaker 4:  said, you know, then you have people who are like, well I wake up at five
Speaker 4:  and I'd start right away. And you know, so it's like those little nuggets
Speaker 4:  can help you figure out, okay, they're airing on this side or this side and,
Speaker 4:  and figure it out for,
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna come back and
Speaker 2:  we have a few more things to talk about. Some apps, some ai, we'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 2:  will make everything easy forever. And not actually just doing the thing
Speaker 2:  that would've taken me less time to go get done. And there's tons of tools
Speaker 2:  out there being built for this stuff, right? You can build an incredibly
Speaker 2:  complex web of notes and personal knowledge management is a thing. And
Speaker 2:  we can talk about Zeel Caston for hours, but I wonder if at the end of the
Speaker 2:  day you're spending a lot of time with these people being like, just write
Speaker 2:  a list. Like is that where we need to land? So much of what you're talking
Speaker 2:  about
Speaker 4:  thinking about your dryer, like your inbox and you know, you have all these
Speaker 4:  laundry baskets of things you need to do. So that's my system
Speaker 4:  that can actually be then applied to any email program. I
Speaker 4:  happen to think Gmail does it best because I worked on that. But I think
Speaker 4:  it's then saying, okay, I have this system for email
Speaker 4:  or I have this system for capturing things I'm thinking about and getting
Speaker 4:  them to a, to-do list. Now that I open the tool instead of looking at the
Speaker 4:  tool to solve all of those things of the system, how can
Speaker 4:  the tool support the system that I've created in my head and then
Speaker 4:  sometimes enhance it like, like things like my ability to add things to my,
Speaker 4:  to-do list using my voice on Google Keep. It's like
Speaker 4:  that is a tool-based feature that's amazing and helps me keep up
Speaker 4:  with the system that I started on paper, you know, and I used to have to
Speaker 4:  run to my paper and write something down, which is inefficient. But instead
Speaker 4:  of kind of logging into the tool and saying, what are you gonna do for me?
Speaker 4:  Having that behind the scenes, like this is how I wanna think about email,
Speaker 4:  this is how I wanna capture. So that's why I try to make those
Speaker 4:  systems
Speaker 4:  for people so that they can say like, Hey, this is how an idea, when you
Speaker 4:  get an idea, this is how it should travel until it's actually executed. You
Speaker 4:  know, you're on a run, you think of something, you know what tool can get
Speaker 4:  it outta your head, what tool are you looking at to put it in a group of
Speaker 4:  things to do when you're at your computer, when are you actually scheduling
Speaker 4:  the time to do that in a calendar and then executing. And so
Speaker 4:  I think everyone's different, but the way that you're talking does make
Speaker 4:  me feel like you have a lot of focus on tools. Whereas some people,
Speaker 4:  I feel the opposite where it's like, hey, you know, some of the stuff you're
Speaker 4:  doing with paper and pencil can really be enhanced with some of these tools.
Speaker 4:  So let's see if we can just shift, you know, I work with a lot of teams that
Speaker 4:  are global and you know, they're trying to do asynchronous
Speaker 4:  communication about priorities and there is a lot of benefit and things like
Speaker 4:  Google Docs and you know, we're all working on the same time in the middle
Speaker 4:  of the night you're here, I'm adding priorities. So, you know, that would
Speaker 4:  be impossible if you're not using a tool like that. So I think
Speaker 4:  in some ways you can go too far one direction,
Speaker 4:  but it does feel really nice to always have that sense of,
Speaker 4:  hey, if this tool was ripped from me right now, I'd be able
Speaker 4:  to replicate this system because it's mine, it's not the tools, you know?
Speaker 4:  So I think that's a good place to start.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that makes a lot of sense. I I am curious about the voice thing because
Speaker 2:  I was all prepared to have a fight with you about pen and paper versus digital
Speaker 2:  tools. Where
Speaker 4:  Do you stand? Let's go.
Speaker 2:  I'm, I'm fully digital tools. Okay. But only
Speaker 2:  I, I was, I, I'm less mad at your approach because I
Speaker 2:  love the idea of making a list and then taking a picture of it on your phone.
Speaker 2:  I think that is like a, an extremely clever middle ground of
Speaker 2:  like the, the science on when you write by hand you remember it better seems
Speaker 2:  just unshakeable. Like that just is true. My handwriting is trash and
Speaker 2:  I mostly can't read it, which is a bit of a problem. But, but I think that
Speaker 2:  there is something too that, but for me it's always been just like the, the
Speaker 2:  availability of my phone in particular is just untouchable
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Compared to everything else. But I'm, I'm really curious particularly
Speaker 2:  because you're, you're an advocate for pen and paper, but you're also an
Speaker 2:  advocate for voice dictation and I'm curious about both of those things and
Speaker 2:  how you can push them together. Yes.
Speaker 4:  That's a great question. I think it's just an advocate for whatever gets
Speaker 4:  you excited because you're only gonna stick with a system that you like and
Speaker 4:  use, which kind of goes back to your customizable question. So I like pen
Speaker 4:  and paper because I like writing in pretty colored
Speaker 4:  pens and I have good handwriting, you know, that I like to, to decorate
Speaker 4:  August and make it, you know, all fun. So it's like,
Speaker 4:  that's more fun to me.
Speaker 2:  So you're the one I see like all over Instagram showing the beautiful bullet
Speaker 2:  journals and that kind of stuff?
Speaker 4:  No, no. Like that's, no, I don't have time for that. Just, that's, that's
Speaker 4:  why I kind of pick a lane where it's like I'm gonna have one thing that I,
Speaker 4:  that I keep going back to. That's my list, my what I call my main list. and
Speaker 4:  it's just, you know, if you came to me and you're like, what's everything
Speaker 4:  that you not personal you and work you, you Laura have to do?
Speaker 4:  I would have a list, okay, these are all the returns I need to do, these
Speaker 4:  are all the things for my kids' summer camp, this is everything I have to
Speaker 4:  do at work. These are all things I need to buy. Like, those are all in one
Speaker 4:  place. And, and I like having that kind of one touch point where I write
Speaker 4:  everything like that out. Could this just as easily be a, a digital list?
Speaker 4:  Yes. But it's not as fun for my brain. So, you know, I think it's just a
Speaker 4:  personal thing, but it's more important to have something that you're
Speaker 4:  consistently using. And the capture thing, I talked to one productivity
Speaker 4:  expert on his podcast and he said he has a little, he has like 20
Speaker 4:  little journals that he brings everywhere and instead of
Speaker 4:  using voice dictation, he just always has a little journal in any pocket
Speaker 4:  of any pants. And he writes down all these things that come to him. So it's
Speaker 4:  just so funny because
Speaker 2:  He, that's my nightmare. I would never get anything, I would never remember
Speaker 2:  one thing. Me too.
Speaker 4:  Then every day at the end of the day he takes 20 little journals and deposits
Speaker 4:  them into like a bank box and then he goes through each little journal.
Speaker 4:  So, but the point is the little journals give him joy, they work for him.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You know, that's, so for me, the dictation, I think a lot of times
Speaker 4:  I get those ideas in the shower on a drive, on a walk, you
Speaker 4:  know, when I don't wanna pick up my device. So the dictation helps with that.
Speaker 4:  But him and I essentially have the same system if you
Speaker 4:  think about it. It's just, we're doing it in different ways, so.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well, and it feels like spiritually the process there is is not that
Speaker 2:  different from the way you were talking about communication, right? Where
Speaker 2:  it's, it's less about having
Speaker 2:  this sort of one specific thing work one specific way and more about
Speaker 2:  having things that work for you. But like most importantly, not having very
Speaker 2:  many of them. Right. Which is a, a thing I had not really thought about
Speaker 2:  that. Like the, the problem with living the way that I live, which is
Speaker 2:  between a thousand different productivity apps, is that universe running
Speaker 2:  is. And so I spent an enormous amount of time collating all the stuff in
Speaker 2:  all the places to try and make sense out of everything. And there's something
Speaker 2:  e even in your case where you're like, you, you have, you, you get stuff
Speaker 2:  on the one list that then goes onto the other list that's still only two
Speaker 2:  places. And that's that I feel like, and I would expect for a lot of the
Speaker 2:  folks that you're meeting with, like they have so many things in so many
Speaker 2:  places and just the act of having all of your things in fewer places seems
Speaker 2:  like it goes a really long way.
Speaker 4:  Yes. If you're like, I'm so overwhelmed, I can only do one thing, what should
Speaker 4:  it be? I always recommend just making this main list from all your
Speaker 4:  lists, from all the 12. It sounds like you have 12 mailboxes. So just saying,
Speaker 4:  okay, I got all the mail out, I've, I've taken my brain and said, no, these
Speaker 4:  are in these categories things I need to buy, things I need to do, things
Speaker 4:  I need to put on my website. You know, whatever those are. Even if you haven't
Speaker 4:  actually done any of them, it feels like, ah, okay, I've
Speaker 4:  got a dashboard because then I can make decisions based on
Speaker 4:  that. I know, wow. I, my main list is blowing up right now. I,
Speaker 4:  I've gotta make more time for these personal things. 'cause it's the beginning
Speaker 4:  of the school, you know, like, I need more than Sunday night to do some of
Speaker 4:  these personal computer things or I have a lot going on at work, I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  need to start saying no to things personally because I really need to make
Speaker 4:  more time for this. So it just gives you that constant gauge of what's
Speaker 4:  going on, you know, instead of trying to do the math on each of your
Speaker 4:  tools and say, you know, the tools, but sometimes the tools work for
Speaker 4:  people. So I think it's just, you know, how are you feeling using them
Speaker 4:  is the biggest question.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that makes sense. So real quick, I'm gonna let you go here in a minute,
Speaker 2:  but I, I wanna talk about downtime and we've talked a little bit about this,
Speaker 2:  the, the sort of needing downtime in order for Uptime to be a thing
Speaker 2:  and to be successful. And I think right now
Speaker 2:  we think of downtime so much as like, you know, the joke is I go from
Speaker 2:  the big screen to the small screen while I watch the biggest screen and that's,
Speaker 2:  that's how I relax now. And and I think part of what you
Speaker 2:  advocate for is like finding more
Speaker 2:  pockets of like space, right? And you talk a lot about focus and,
Speaker 2:  and kind of disconnecting and pulling back. And I, I would assume
Speaker 2:  again for a lot of the people that you coach at Google and a lot of the people
Speaker 2:  who've read your book and things like that, the idea of like when my
Speaker 2:  downtime is I sit and scroll TikTok for an hour, which is a certain kind
Speaker 2:  of downtime, but it's not solving the problem that you're talking about.
Speaker 2:  It's like how do you coach people through how to not scroll
Speaker 2:  TikTok for an hour? And again, it goes back a little bit to that discipline
Speaker 2:  of just like, don't just, just don't scroll TikTok for an hour. But yeah,
Speaker 2:  I think one of the theories I have is that one of the reasons walks have
Speaker 2:  become so popular is that it is, it is a thing to do, right? and it's like,
Speaker 2:  it's not just don't look at a screen, it's go do something else.
Speaker 2:  Right. And so like is that, is that the kind of advice you give folks is
Speaker 2:  sort of redirect that focus to something better? Or like how do you talk
Speaker 2:  people through that?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, like what you're talking about is kind of the crowding out method.
Speaker 4:  Like You can't scroll TikTok if you're doing something else. So I even do
Speaker 4:  that, you know, with my kids. It's like if you want screen time first you
Speaker 4:  need to play outside for an hour. And it's like by the time they're outside
Speaker 4:  for an hour, they're having so much fun and playing and then, you know, so
Speaker 4:  redirecting the focus. But I think it's starting small
Speaker 4:  realistic ways before you're diving
Speaker 4:  into some big, every night I'm doing this or I'm never scrolling.
Speaker 4:  TikTok. And like you said, I think there are some benefits
Speaker 4:  of scrolling TikTok. Maybe you enjoy the content, maybe you're getting something
Speaker 4:  out of that. But you know, I made a rule for myself that
Speaker 4:  I am not going to scroll on my phone and watch
Speaker 4:  TV at the same time. And so if there's a show I wanna watch or something
Speaker 4:  or you know, something, I wanna go watch or look at it, it kind of makes
Speaker 4:  me have to decide again the attention piece. Well, do I wanna sit here and
Speaker 4:  scroll or do I wanna watch this show? You know, I have to now
Speaker 4:  decide, sometimes I'm like, no, I wanted to look for new recipes today, so
Speaker 4:  I'm actually am gonna look on here. But then I'm kind of done. And I think
Speaker 4:  that having some structure, so one challenge I started,
Speaker 4:  which I talked about the, in the book, which has been so popular, is the
Speaker 4:  No Tech Tuesday Night Challenge. So again, it was a small thing.
Speaker 4:  Not everyone wants to give up technology every night, but let's just say
Speaker 4:  one night a week from dinner to bedtime, could you give
Speaker 4:  up technology? You know, one night for five weeks, six weeks.
Speaker 4:  And so thousands of people started signing up for it. I really did it to
Speaker 4:  keep myself accountable. 'cause I was like, if I tell all these people I'm
Speaker 4:  doing this and I don't, I'll be so embarrassed. So let's make it kind
Speaker 4:  of a big challenge. So, but what now has gone on
Speaker 4:  for five years and, and it's been this huge success. But what's so interesting
Speaker 4:  is looking at the feedback, you kind of think it's gonna be, oh, I,
Speaker 4:  I felt so good during that downtime. You know, so like
Speaker 4:  I was, you know, really relaxed off my phone. But it ends up being these
Speaker 4:  longer term things like I slept so much better. Like
Speaker 4:  I, I have a, you know, watch that keeps track of my sleep cycles and it was
Speaker 4:  the best night of sleep I get all week is Tuesday night. So then the biggest
Speaker 4:  piece of feedback that I thought was so interesting, which just kind of proves
Speaker 4:  my point of the whole book is I am so much
Speaker 4:  more focused and productive on Wednesday
Speaker 4:  because I took Tuesday night off. And so I think that that's
Speaker 4:  where people have that aha moment and then they stick with it every Tuesday
Speaker 4:  all year, or they start doing two or three nights a week, or they start
Speaker 4:  doing little more adjustments saying Now I'm gonna start doing this at eight
Speaker 4:  o'clock every night because it made such a difference in my sleep. But if
Speaker 4:  I had said Do it at eight o'clock every night from the start, no one would've
Speaker 4:  started. So it's about, you know, even with people I'm coaching, I just say,
Speaker 4:  Hey, if even if it's just like on my commute, I'm just gonna have silence
Speaker 4:  for 15 minutes, you know, or I see people walk to the bathroom in the
Speaker 4:  office and still have their phone. I'm just like, that is the shortest walk.
Speaker 4:  Like could we just use that time to decompress? And as someone
Speaker 4:  who
Speaker 2:  Is very guilty of both watching TikTok while I make
Speaker 2:  coffee in the morning and taking my phone to the bathroom, I feel like I'm
Speaker 2:  learning a lot right now.
Speaker 4:  Well see, for someone like you, it's just about like, I was really bad about
Speaker 4:  waking up and looking at my phone right away and then I just realized unless
Speaker 4:  I'm sending emails at six 30 in the morning, like why am I going to do this?
Speaker 4:  Nothing's gonna happen between six 30 and seven. And so I
Speaker 4:  had to start putting my phone outside my room and then it was like,
Speaker 4:  now if my phone's in my room, I still don't look at it 'cause it's such a
Speaker 4:  habit. But it's, you know, it's hard to trust yourself that you're gonna
Speaker 4:  wanna do that or do that. And so having little tiny habits
Speaker 4:  like No Tech Tuesday or like just setting your phone and then you start
Speaker 4:  sitting there and making your coffee and realize, wow, this is actually relaxing.
Speaker 4:  Makes you want to scroll less. You know? So I think it's just gradual and
Speaker 4:  any amount of change is helpful, but an overhaul is unrealistic. I think
Speaker 4:  that's where people go wrong sometimes.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I agree. All right, I've kept you too long. I have one more thing I
Speaker 2:  wanna talk about. Do you have, do you have five more minutes? Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I wanna talk about AI before we go. Yes. Which we can do very quickly
Speaker 2:  'cause it's a super small topic. Yeah, it's fine. I, I do think
Speaker 2:  the, the like bull case for AI says
Speaker 2:  that it can do a lot for a lot of the stuff you're talking about, right?
Speaker 2:  Not just like write emails and help you do some of that stuff more quickly.
Speaker 2:  But like you talk a lot about sort of bridging different ideas and pulling
Speaker 2:  stuff together and part of the work is like
Speaker 2:  collating all the information going on inside of your head and part of the
Speaker 2:  promise of AI is that it can start to do some of that stuff for you, right?
Speaker 2:  That it, it can teach you how to use these tools so you don't have to muck
Speaker 2:  around in settings so much. It can make sense of all of your ideas for you.
Speaker 2:  Like do you think of AI as kind of a key part of what you're
Speaker 2:  gonna be working on and coaching people on in the next few years?
Speaker 4:  Yes, it already is. Definitely is really, I think I, I'm glad you brought
Speaker 4:  it up 'cause I meant to mention it when you were talking about some of that
Speaker 4:  automation of tools and I think that the first
Speaker 4:  tool that's really come around that I think can replicate some of these or
Speaker 4:  create some of these backend systems that I'm talking about is
Speaker 4:  ai. I think that AI right now is at that level of,
Speaker 4:  okay, these are the tasks that I know I need for my system and then I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  get AI to help with those tasks. I think where
Speaker 4:  we're going is AI knows what tasks I need for my
Speaker 4:  system and AI helps with those tasks. Or for example,
Speaker 4:  I have an idea and I put it on my capture list
Speaker 4:  and by the time I get back to my desk it's already on my part of
Speaker 4:  my main list that I want it to be. You know, so kind of that next level of
Speaker 4:  taking the systems and making it totally easier for me
Speaker 4:  and just questions about, you know, maybe AI will be able to tell us
Speaker 4:  what are my power hours? You know, can you tell how many times I'm switching
Speaker 4:  tabs or when my output is best or when I'm, you know, going to TikTok
Speaker 4:  too many times, you know, how it, it might be able to give us some of that
Speaker 4:  information about our own productivity, whether it's hours and meetings,
Speaker 4:  who we're meeting with, which platform do I prefer? Am I responding to emails
Speaker 4:  faster than I'm accepting meeting invites, you know, whatever that is. So
Speaker 4:  I think that it's just getting more and more exciting right now. It's kind
Speaker 4:  of that helpful tool, but I think it's gonna be one step ahead of us
Speaker 4:  in figuring out our own productivity and kind of bringing it all together.
Speaker 4:  And it's a fun time to be in productivity I would say, because it's just,
Speaker 4:  it's cool to see what a difference it's already made and I feel like we're
Speaker 4:  just at the tip of where it's going and I work super closely with
Speaker 4:  our Gemini product managers on just like what is the
Speaker 4:  ultimate productivity things that this tool could do and how can we get
Speaker 4:  there? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So talk me through kind of the the North Star you're thinking about because
Speaker 2:  I think, yeah, you just brought up a couple of different versions of it that
Speaker 2:  I think are interesting. The one is like I say something to
Speaker 2:  my device, it recognizes it as a to-do and it puts it on my list, right?
Speaker 2:  That's very useful and very accomplishable, right? Like I think it
Speaker 2:  most tools will do that pretty soon and we're already like every meeting
Speaker 2:  now is like, there's some app that will take your action items and
Speaker 2:  shove it into your to-do list. I actually, I think that's great. But then
Speaker 2:  there are all these tools out there that are like the, the sort of AI
Speaker 2:  calendars where you, you put a bunch of stuff in and it'll try to organize
Speaker 2:  your days for you based on all of the stuff that you need to get done and
Speaker 2:  kind of the optimal flow like you're talking about. I'm skeptical of that
Speaker 2:  stuff now because my experience has just been that it doesn't seem to actually
Speaker 2:  work all that well. But that is the sort of thing that might get better
Speaker 2:  as technology gets better. But I'm, I'm curious like as you think about fast
Speaker 2:  forward a few years and this tech keeps getting better and like, do you think
Speaker 2:  of AI as kind of, I just sort of yell at my
Speaker 2:  system all day and then it kind of goes and accomplishes everything on my
Speaker 2:  behalf? Or is it like you're talking about kind of the, the great engine
Speaker 2:  of like insights and summarization and then I'm still on the hook to actually
Speaker 2:  like make the most out of that stuff? Like where does this sort of land in
Speaker 2:  the process?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's a good question. I think it's always gonna be
Speaker 4:  how am I powering some of these things that
Speaker 4:  AI is doing for me? And so to your point about the calendar piece, it's like
Speaker 4:  unless I tell the calendar I'm very
Speaker 4:  productive between nine and 11 and that's when I like to do focus time,
Speaker 4:  how is it really gonna optimize for that? So I feel like that personal
Speaker 4:  knowledge of your own patterns and things like that still starts with you
Speaker 4:  now I think of it kind of like an intern, like what things
Speaker 4:  can I assign? But I think ultimately it will become more of that like
Speaker 4:  assistant business partner, you know, with me
Speaker 4:  where it's like we're both thinking on the same level and bouncing off of
Speaker 4:  each other to make these great results. Whereas I think currently
Speaker 4:  we're in more of the what can, what am I doing that I can assign, which that's
Speaker 4:  what I always tell people if you're kind of like, where do I start with ai,
Speaker 4:  take a look at your to-do list and just circle three things that
Speaker 4:  you might be able to delegate to AI and just try it. Because I think a lot
Speaker 4:  of people get that like blank screen nervousness for sure. Just like
Speaker 4:  what do I put in here? But you know, I talk about summarizing,
Speaker 4:  brainstorming, planning, you know, those are kind of like the key buckets.
Speaker 4:  Researching And, if you can just start with those and then
Speaker 4:  I think it will become that next level
Speaker 4:  partnership with us. You know, not, not solving
Speaker 4:  everything we have to do and not us yelling at it, but just like
Speaker 4:  this understands what I'm thinking, how I'm doing it
Speaker 4:  and give, gives me, most importantly the time, the downtime
Speaker 4:  to come up with the next level things because I'm not spending
Speaker 4:  hours sorting through comments. And so I think that's, that's the coolest
Speaker 4:  part about it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I have to say from intern to assistant to business partner
Speaker 2:  is one of the best summations of the path of AI that I think I've ever
Speaker 2:  heard. That's very good. That's very
Speaker 4:  Good. Yes, that's where I'm hoping I, I think we're kind of between intern
Speaker 4:  and assistant right now, but every time it does something cool, I'm like,
Speaker 4:  oh this is, this is assistant level, you know, so yeah,
Speaker 4:  it's exciting.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today, thanks to Laura Mae Martin again
Speaker 2:  for coming on the show. And thank you as always for listening. If you wanna
Speaker 2:  buy Laura's book, it's called Uptime. It's very good. I actually listened
Speaker 2:  to the audio book on Spotify work, create Big Fan. There's lots
Speaker 2:  more on all this stuff that we talked about. Productivity tools, how to be
Speaker 2:  a Person on the internet, screen Time, focus modes, all that at The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com. I'll put some links in the show notes. But you know, as always,
Speaker 2:  read the website and as always, if you have thoughts, questions, feelings,
Speaker 2:  or apps you think I should try because I'm a true masochist, You can always
Speaker 2:  email us at vergecast at The Verge dot com or call the hotline. It's six
Speaker 2:  six VERGE one one. we love hearing from you. Send us all of your thoughts
Speaker 2:  and questions on this episode or anything. This show is produced by Andrew
Speaker 2:  Marino, Liam James, and Will Poor. And this episode was edited by Zander
Speaker 2:  Adams. The Vergecast is VERGE production and part of the Vox Media podcast
Speaker 2:  network. Neli, Alex, and I'll be back on Tuesday and Friday.
Speaker 2:  Lots of news, lots of fun stuff. And this Tuesday we actually have a really
Speaker 2:  fun different kind of episode for you that I'm very excited about. We'll
Speaker 2:  see you then. Rock and roll