# Transcript
ID: 1e77c8af-9684-4317-94f1-c148539c5216
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-6577428409837480608/2752846446590469345/s93290-US-4948s-1721123667.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of nose bridge microphones:
03:10 - The Verge’s David Pierce enlists help from Alex Cranz and Sean Hollister to figure out the best gadget setup for his handheld gaming needs.
The Steam Deck wasn’t born ready, but it’s ready now
Nintendo Switch OLED review: screentime
Sony PlayStation Portal review: flawed but fun
Asus ROG Ally updated review: it’s a bit better now
This amazing knockoff GBA SP comes stuffed with software piracy
42:10 - Victoria Song joins the show to test out the microphones on a bunch of smart glasses and headsets.
Razer’s new Anzu smart glasses break from the pack with truly wireless audio
The Ray-Ban Meta smart glasses actually make the future look cool
Amazon’s latest Echo Frames are more style than substance
Meta Quest 3 review: almost the one we've been waiting for
Apple Vision Pro review: magic, until it’s not
01:10:26 - Later, David answers a question from the Vergecast Hotline.
North Focals glasses review: a $600 smartwatch for your face
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (46 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Nose Bridge
Speaker 2:  Microphones. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am sitting in
Speaker 2:  my new bathroom. It's been almost a month since we've been
Speaker 2:  doing this construction, and I'm sure you've heard me complain about
Speaker 2:  all of the construction noise and chaos on the show over the last month.
Speaker 2:  I, you've probably even heard some of the noise and chaos on the show over
Speaker 2:  the last month. So I'm sorry for all of my noise and chaos,
Speaker 2:  but it's done. It's not all the way done because as I've learned with a project
Speaker 2:  like this, it's never all the way done. I can like see the paint touchups
Speaker 2:  and everything that I have to do. You do one of these things and you're suddenly
Speaker 2:  just very like aware of your surroundings in a way that is
Speaker 2:  honestly not helpful. I don't recommend it. It's better to just sort of live
Speaker 2:  your life and not notice all the imperfections. But now I have a sink that
Speaker 2:  works. We have a shower that works. We have a toilet that works. I have places
Speaker 2:  to put things. It's all very exciting. And now honestly, given
Speaker 2:  the amount of money and time and energy we've spent in this bathroom, it
Speaker 2:  only feels right for me to just live in this bathroom. So this is my home
Speaker 2:  now. I'm VERGE casting from the bathroom from now on. Anyway,
Speaker 2:  we have a lot of stuff to do today, so let's dive into it. We're gonna do
Speaker 2:  two things. First, we're gonna talk about a bit of a gaming
Speaker 2:  hardware conundrum that I'm having, and we're gonna see if two of
Speaker 2:  my colleagues can help me figure out how to upgrade my PS four and
Speaker 2:  what I actually need to buy. Then we're gonna do a test of some
Speaker 2:  new wearable microphones. We love doing mic tests on this show and we haven't
Speaker 2:  done them with the glasses and headsets and all that
Speaker 2:  kind of stuff that is out there in the world in a big way. So we're gonna
Speaker 2:  test some microphones and see how everybody sounds. We also have a really
Speaker 2:  fun glasses question from The Vergecast hotline. Lots to do, so
Speaker 2:  let's get to it. All that is coming in just one second. But first
Speaker 2:  I just, there's a grout line that I have to go fix and it's gonna drive me
Speaker 2:  crazy if I don't do it. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  so as I
Speaker 2:  that I can play for like 15 minutes at a go. And the challenge I've always
Speaker 2:  had with a game like Elden Ring is I just wanna play it for hours.
Speaker 2:  And I feel like it never rewards you for just a couple of minutes of playing
Speaker 2:  at a time in a way that some of these more finite battle
Speaker 2:  royale or like football game sized games really are.
Speaker 2:  So all of this is to say I'm pretty happy with my gaming setup.
Speaker 2:  I haven't really felt the need to get a PS five or anything like that.
Speaker 2:  I'm still on a PS four pro. It works fine, everything's great. But more recently
Speaker 2:  I want something new. We've been talking a lot about
Speaker 2:  handheld consoles on this show over the last eight months or so,
Speaker 2:  I would say. And there's just a lot of cool stuff happening. I also
Speaker 2:  travel more than I used to and I'm back to wanting something
Speaker 2:  I can play on the train or on a plane or in a hotel room when I'm not
Speaker 2:  at home. I also just spend too much time sitting at my desk. Like right now
Speaker 2:  I'm sitting at my desk, my monitor's in front of me, my computer is
Speaker 2:  underneath it. I have a Mac mini that I use for most things. And then right
Speaker 2:  off to the right is my PlayStation. And so having this one space
Speaker 2:  be the place that I sit for work all day and then to play games at night,
Speaker 2:  I just don't like it. And I want something that I can take and sit on the
Speaker 2:  couch while I hang out with the dog or play out in the backyard when the
Speaker 2:  weather's nice. So I'm really into the idea of a handheld console, but
Speaker 2:  I have no idea which one to get. So I enlisted two people to help
Speaker 2:  me figure it out. Sean Hollister and Alex Kranz, they both know this stuff
Speaker 2:  way better than I do. And to together we are going to make a decision
Speaker 2:  about which handheld console I'm gonna buy. Let's get into it.
Speaker 2:  Alex Krantz. Hello in Texas. Howdy y'all.
Speaker 2:  Well this is, this is what we're gonna do here. Sean Hollister. Hello.
Speaker 8:  Hi. From the land of Gambling handhelds,
Speaker 2:  I have brought you here to do personal tech support for me because that is
Speaker 2:  what the first cast is about, is helping David figure out which
Speaker 2:  gadgets he should buy. Good. I'm going to lay out for you my current situation
Speaker 2:  and then you are going to help me solve my current situation. So
Speaker 2:  my current situation is I have a PlayStation four, I've had it for a million
Speaker 2:  years. It's fine. It plays video games. I would like to
Speaker 2:  upgrade, but I don't think what I want is a PS five. I think what I want
Speaker 2:  is something handheld and portable because my PS four
Speaker 2:  like lives next to my computer in my basement and I'm spending too much time
Speaker 2:  sitting in this chair looking at this screen. And I would like to have something
Speaker 2:  that can like go out in the world with me and I travel a lot and all these
Speaker 2:  things. So I want something that is like primarily but not entirely
Speaker 2:  a portable handheld gadget. I would like to play
Speaker 2:  lots of games. We can talk about which games I do and don't care about, but
Speaker 2:  I have exactly one non-negotiable game, which is, which is fifa,
Speaker 2:  EA Sports FC is the new name of it. I will call it FIFA until the day I die.
Speaker 2:  I play that game more than I play every other game combined and I need that
Speaker 2:  game. That's it. That's literally like, that is the entirety of where I am
Speaker 2:  and I wanna buy something and I want you to tell me what to buy.
Speaker 8:  Why? Why is that your game? Why is that your game? Because I have an
Speaker 8:  answer for you, but the answer has just been foiled by the fact that you
Speaker 8:  have picked a game which, and I quote runs a,
Speaker 8:  this program encountered E 1 1 1 0 0 B during initialization.
Speaker 8:  Okay. Error message when you try to run it on a steam deck.
Speaker 8:  So I guess I'm not gonna tell you to buy a steam deck.
Speaker 2:  My worry was this is going to be the shortest VERGE cast in history because
Speaker 2:  I was gonna say all that and you were both gonna say Steam Deck and then
Speaker 2:  we were gonna hang up and move on with our lives if it were not for this
Speaker 2:  one game that I require. Is the world sort of that simple
Speaker 2:  at this particular moment?
Speaker 9:  Yeah,
Speaker 8:  It kind of is. and it maybe it won't be in like, okay,
Speaker 8:  two weeks in, in, in two weeks or so through, is it three weeks? There
Speaker 8:  will be a Windows handheld with a battery that is bigger than any other
Speaker 8:  handheld on the market. And maybe that will solve the issue of Windows handhelds
Speaker 8:  don't have great battery life.
Speaker 9:  That won't solve all the other problems with the Windows handheld.
Speaker 9:  I'm gonna say David, you're, you're, you know, you're on The Vergecast, so
Speaker 9:  I feel very comfortable saying you like to tinker, you enjoy
Speaker 9:  a little tinkering. So
Speaker 2:  I, I do, when I don't, I will say what I'm, I am willing to tinker.
Speaker 2:  Like if it, if it's a matter of I need to like buy this thing and spend a
Speaker 2:  couple of hours like downloading and tweaking and doing whatever I need to
Speaker 2:  get it set up fine. I am not buying a
Speaker 2:  thing with the intention of screwing with it forever. I would like this thing
Speaker 2:  to play video games and I want to be able to sit down on my couch and be
Speaker 2:  playing video games as quickly as possible. That's actually very important
Speaker 2:  to me.
Speaker 8:  Would you spend those two hours, hear me out? Would you spend
Speaker 8:  those two hours setting up your steam deck to dual
Speaker 8:  boots windows off of an SD card?
Speaker 8:  Occasionally with the one non-negotiable game that apparently you
Speaker 8:  must have
Speaker 9:  You can get FIFA on the steam deck without doing dual boot? I was,
Speaker 9:  I was looking this up.
Speaker 2:  Tell me more.
Speaker 9:  You will need to be comfortable diving
Speaker 9:  into the Linux side of Steam deck.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 9:  And do some tweaking. And also does it have to be
Speaker 9:  FIFA 24?
Speaker 2:  Yes.
Speaker 9:  Oh, it can't can't be FIFA 23. Well
Speaker 2:  No, it actually, it, what's important is that it's going to be 25 in like
Speaker 2:  six weeks and it's actually what I need is that one.
Speaker 8:  Do you have to play it online? Because it's the anti sheet That's, that's
Speaker 8:  the problem here. Ea insisting on its own version of Anti Sheet instead of
Speaker 8:  the ones that actually work on the steam deck.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I need to be online. Shit.
Speaker 8:  Well
Speaker 9:  I feel like the other FIFA games have appeared in Xbox Cloud
Speaker 9:  and I feel like this one would also appear in Xbox Cloud.
Speaker 8:  That was my next thought. You
Speaker 2:  Make a very good point here, which is a thing that I should have said. I
Speaker 2:  don't need to be able to play this game on the first day that it is available.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I just need to play it at some point. Yeah. And what I have discovered
Speaker 2:  about the video game world is that those things are, are very different.
Speaker 2:  Like when things come to Game Pass and there's stuff that comes to PlayStations
Speaker 2:  Cloud stuff later on that isn't there, like day and date when
Speaker 2:  they release, like the reason I picked this game that matters is because
Speaker 2:  I, I can just like get lost down this impossible universe with any game that
Speaker 2:  I want. And it's all very complicated. But just, just to tie off the one
Speaker 2:  piece of this, if, if all I was saying is I want a handheld thing to
Speaker 2:  play games on and I did not give you any specific games Yeah. Is the answer
Speaker 2:  like the steam deck and it's not even close?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, it really is. It really is. The steam deck.
Speaker 8:  We, we we're in this moment where all of these other
Speaker 8:  companies are like, we want a piece of that steam deck action, but we're
Speaker 8:  gonna build it on Windows because gamers tell us that Windows is
Speaker 8:  where all of the games are and they want to just be able to play the games
Speaker 8:  they already own. Which
Speaker 9:  Is true.
Speaker 8:  Which is true. But the reality is that the Steam deck
Speaker 8:  plays Windows games and it plays more of them
Speaker 8:  better than a native Windows system plays Windows games.
Speaker 2:  What is the problem with the native Windows system? Because
Speaker 9:  Windows is built for computers for laptops and, and
Speaker 9:  desktops and things that you use with a mouse and a at least 13 inch
Speaker 9:  display. And then you put that on a seven inch display
Speaker 9:  and instead of a mouse you have a joystick.
Speaker 2:  Okay, that sounds awful. Now that I'm thinking this through, that sounds
Speaker 2:  like a nightmare.
Speaker 8:  That part's kind of a You can, if you wanna spend your two hours of setup,
Speaker 8:  You can certainly spend 10 minutes of them setting up steam
Speaker 8:  to launch every time you launch your Windows computer, enter launch right
Speaker 8:  into big picture mode. And then you have an interface that's similar to the
Speaker 8:  steam deck, but it doesn't have the ability to like
Speaker 8:  tweak the handheld very easily so that you get great battery life. The
Speaker 8:  chips won't give you great battery life to begin with. 'cause there's all
Speaker 8:  that other overhead for all the other shit you don't need in Windows. Sometimes
Speaker 8:  you'll turn off your Windows system, you'll, you'll put it to sleep and you'll
Speaker 8:  turn it back on again and wake it up again and all of a sudden your app will
Speaker 8:  be gone. And where did it go? I wonder why it isn't full screen anymore.
Speaker 8:  It's this tiny icon on the Windows taskbar that's not great. Sometimes it
Speaker 8:  won't wake up from sleep, it'll have restarted itself.
Speaker 2:  I'm having like netbook flashbacks to 10 years ago as you're describing
Speaker 2:  this,
Speaker 9:  Sometimes for some reason I can't get it to stop asking for the password
Speaker 9:  when I open one of my Windows game consoles. And so then I have to like figure
Speaker 9:  out how to get the, the accessibility keyboard up, which always
Speaker 9:  takes at least five minutes and then very carefully type
Speaker 9:  in the password, which is super long because I like to be safe.
Speaker 9:  It's, it's my favorite thing to do, David, you don't wanna do that.
Speaker 2:  This is not the most compelling case you've ever made, Alex. But wait, Sean,
Speaker 2:  you, you alluded to maybe there is something coming that solves this problem
Speaker 2:  for me. Okay.
Speaker 8:  Not most of these problems. Okay. But, but the but the battery life. Okay,
Speaker 8:  the battery life problem, as with the rug ally, the
Speaker 8:  ROG ally, they're, they're gonna, they're gonna hop on me. So the ROG ally
Speaker 8:  came out a year ago as like a steam dick, but
Speaker 8:  worse in almost every way except that it had a better screen,
Speaker 8:  a variable refresh rate screen. It has since been surpassed by the Steam
Speaker 8:  deck oled, which has an OLED screen that goes 90 hertz. I'm gonna stop getting
Speaker 8:  into the weeds, but they're coming out with a new version of that
Speaker 8:  later this month that will have a doubled battery in it
Speaker 8:  and all kinds of other creature comforts. It'll be more comfortable to hold
Speaker 8:  in the year since they shipped the original ROG ally, the
Speaker 8:  UI hass gotten a little bit better. It's smoother. Like Tom
Speaker 8:  Warren likes his, I think he might prefer that over the steam deck. He
Speaker 8:  is a notorious Windows fan boy.
Speaker 9:  That's why he doesn't count.
Speaker 8:  I I think it's going to be very possibly the first Windows
Speaker 8:  handheld that I can recommend because they've gotten so many
Speaker 8:  things right. but it fundamentally still runs Windows and
Speaker 8:  Microsoft has not improved Windows in any meaningful way in the year
Speaker 8:  and a half, two years since Steam Deck came out.
Speaker 9:  They could though, right? Like, like we've been hearing a lot of rumors that
Speaker 9:  they're gonna introduce some sort of Xbox handheld in the next couple of
Speaker 9:  years that'll very likely run on Windows because technically the Xbox
Speaker 9:  runs on that. There's like the opportunity, I feel like a lot like
Speaker 9:  remember when a MD was having its big resurgence. Nvidia was the game
Speaker 9:  GPU and then a MD was like, we're gonna start doing this again. And the
Speaker 9:  difference was Nvidia actually did software and made the games
Speaker 9:  work really, really well. Whereas a MD didn't for at least a year or two.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. That's where the Windows handhelds are. No one's done those really
Speaker 9:  important software tweaks. So the Steam Deck wasn better, but
Speaker 8:  Microsoft would have to be like, we're gonna ship a different OS on it. We're
Speaker 8:  gonna ship conversion to Windows that's so stripped down. You don't recognize
Speaker 8:  it as Windows anymore. Look,
Speaker 9:  If it opens ea origins then the like I'm fine.
Speaker 8:  EA is one of the achilles of the steam deck you brought up fifa. fifa
Speaker 8:  EA games will notoriously, particularly if you need online, they will just
Speaker 8:  break on Steam deck because EA does not give a shit about
Speaker 8:  valves handheld, and they'll just like change their stupid mandatory like
Speaker 8:  DRM app all the time. Used to be called Origin. Now it's like EA app and
Speaker 8:  games will just break there on Steam deck. But everything else works pretty
Speaker 8:  good.
Speaker 9:  But they do participate in cloud gaming. They're, they, they, most of their
Speaker 9:  stuff is available on the various cloud gaming platforms and all of those
Speaker 9:  work on the steam deck and You can get 'em up and running pretty quickly
Speaker 9:  and then not have to like constantly go into the Linux backend to tweak 'em.
Speaker 9:  Just the one time meaning
Speaker 2:  Like I could do like steam deck plus
Speaker 2:  game pass and solve my problem.
Speaker 8:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  Is is this a good idea?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, you could do that. Okay. You can even, you could stream your, your
Speaker 9:  Sony PS four from there so you don't have to like sit in front of it to play
Speaker 9:  the last of us. Oh
Speaker 8:  Yeah. You can stream your Xbox and your PlayStation and cloud
Speaker 8:  to the steam deck. It does all these things.
Speaker 2:  I'm glad you brought this up because this is, this is a, a thing I have deeply
Speaker 2:  investigated and have come up with is a, is just a terrible nightmare that
Speaker 2:  I will not subject myself to. There are, there are things about
Speaker 2:  remote streaming your own console that are really great and they
Speaker 2:  immediately fall apart as soon as you get anywhere outside of your
Speaker 2:  house. Like it just doesn't. Yeah. Oh yeah.
Speaker 8:  Do you, do you need to play FIFA outside your house?
Speaker 2:  I do. Like, for me, honestly. Okay. The, the two biggest things
Speaker 2:  I'm trying to solve in switching from this console on my desk to
Speaker 2:  the handheld is I wanna play other places in my house than at this desk,
Speaker 2:  which is a victory for console streaming. And I wanna play when
Speaker 2:  I travel in part because I'm addicted to this game. And it's set up in such
Speaker 2:  a way that the mechanics are, if you don't play every day, it's actually
Speaker 2:  kind of like, it's a real problem as I'm describing this. But this is where
Speaker 2:  I'm at in life and the console streaming thing is great for the first
Speaker 2:  thing. Like I can, I can sit upstairs on my couch and play my
Speaker 2:  PS four on like an iPad and it actually works passively well, total
Speaker 2:  non-starter trying to stream any stuff over the internet. I just,
Speaker 2:  it's just not even worth it.
Speaker 8:  This goes for all streaming. Yeah, I agree with that. All streaming breaks
Speaker 8:  down once you leave your house because you no longer have control over making
Speaker 8:  sure you have a good internet connection. If you're out there like on 5G,
Speaker 8:  if you have a great 5G signal and nobody else in the node is using it right
Speaker 8:  then, yeah, You can have a great streaming experience. But I, I would sit,
Speaker 8:  I would sit in, you know, a hospital waiting room or out in a cafe and
Speaker 8:  I'd be using that, that Razer device, which could only really do cloud streaming.
Speaker 8:  And I would have a beautiful streaming experience that would drop
Speaker 8:  out five minutes later and be completely unplayable over and over and over
Speaker 8:  again. I had that experience with cloud gaming with a good cloud gaming
Speaker 8:  service like GForce. Now great service. This connection would not maintain
Speaker 8:  that. Now if you're talking about going over to a friend's house who, which
Speaker 8:  your friend also has amazing internet at home and you wanna stream from
Speaker 8:  Xbox Cloud there. Great. That, that could, that could, that could work great.
Speaker 9:  I was just assuming that David has like a hotspot with him at all time. That
Speaker 9:  gives him brilliant internet like 90% of the time,
Speaker 2:  To be honest, I do a lot. Yes. It's called, it's called an iPad Pro with
Speaker 2:  Cell Connection and it's actually like an unbelievably great hotspot. The
Speaker 2:  problem is, I'll give you the worst case scenario for my own
Speaker 2:  gaming usage is on an Amtrak train from DC
Speaker 2:  to New York. No. And at that point, realistically what I need is games I
Speaker 2:  can play offline. Right. Which I, I think just rules out full reliance
Speaker 2:  on game streaming services. Like I actually, this is why I'm, I'm compelled
Speaker 2:  by the combination of Steam Deck and Game Pass. Like I,
Speaker 2:  I can do mostly online stuff and like I have, I, I don't need to be able
Speaker 2:  to play FIFA online while I'm on Amtrak wifi. That's like not possible in
Speaker 2:  the world that we live in. So I'm fine with that, but I need to be able to
Speaker 2:  do something on that thing when I have crappy connection and the idea of
Speaker 2:  just having like a brick in my hands when the wifi is bad feels
Speaker 2:  bad.
Speaker 9:  I do have one other suggestion and it is actually even more
Speaker 9:  basic than the steam deck and it's a switch.
Speaker 2:  I I'm glad you brought this up.
Speaker 9:  It's, yes, it's like the steam deck gives you all of the
Speaker 9:  customization and gives you, it's like a Swiss Army knife. The switch is
Speaker 9:  like just a really good K bar. Like it's good for one thing and
Speaker 9:  that's playing the games that Nintendo is okay with you playing on it. And
Speaker 2:  One of those games is, is EA Sports FC 24,
Speaker 2:  the dumbest name game in soccer. But you're
Speaker 8:  Still not gonna play it online on Amtrak, right? No,
Speaker 2:  But so I I have almost landed there except, and, and Kranz I'm glad you
Speaker 2:  brought this up because I wanna know what you guys think right now feels
Speaker 2:  like a stupid time to buy a switch. It feels like the end of a switch cycle.
Speaker 2:  They have already talked about the next one, like the switch by all
Speaker 2:  accounts is still very good, but this feels like a ridiculous time to buy
Speaker 2:  a switch.
Speaker 8:  It is absolutely the end of the switch cycle. They're they're, they're delaying
Speaker 8:  it a little bit. They're not like, they don't want to come out right away
Speaker 8:  and do switch tube. They're biting their time probably 'cause they want to
Speaker 8:  get some great software lined up for it. And I imagine that
Speaker 8:  that software, if you wanna play a metro prime for or whatever the
Speaker 8:  next game is, the Nintendo does, it probably won't work as well
Speaker 8:  on the current switch. 'cause the current switch is not only seven years
Speaker 8:  old in terms of its processing power, but also was
Speaker 8:  already weak to begin with. Like when you played Zelda
Speaker 8:  breath of the wild on day one on the switch and you go to the, the forest
Speaker 8:  where the master sword is like, it's choppy. It was choppy then
Speaker 8:  it was choppy seven years ago. You know,
Speaker 9:  I was like, FIFA will look like a bunch of potatoes are on a big green field.
Speaker 9:  But, but you'll be, but you'll know what those potatoes are and you'll be
Speaker 9:  able to control all the little potatoes. So like if the control of the
Speaker 9:  potatoes is important and not how they look, the switch could be an
Speaker 9:  option. 'cause there's a lot of good deals right now because there's a ton
Speaker 9:  of different ones. Like I, I just recently picked up the, the new Zelda one
Speaker 9:  because somebody left it on a plane and I bought it at a thrift store.
Speaker 8:  Have you played the news Ilda yet?
Speaker 2:  I have. So I actually have an OG switch and it
Speaker 2:  worked great and I loved it very much. And then it got to the point where
Speaker 2:  literally the battery lasts like six minutes. Mm. Like it's, it's
Speaker 2:  fine. The thing is seven years old, I got a lot of love out of it. I used
Speaker 2:  it for a long time and it just basically doesn't work anymore. And so now
Speaker 2:  it's just like a pretty yellow thing that sits over there.
Speaker 8:  Do not trade that in because if it's an original switch that the battery
Speaker 8:  is six minutes, it also means that it is hackable and You can do fun things
Speaker 8:  with it and it is worth money. Okay. So
Speaker 2:  I deal, okay, well that's David's side business in selling
Speaker 2:  old gadgets is is a whole nother thing you and I should do on this show,
Speaker 2:  Sean. So yeah, so I think one of the outcomes I'm afraid
Speaker 2:  of is that the answer is just wait a year because there's gonna be
Speaker 2:  a new switch and they might fix windows and maybe we'll get the Xbox thing.
Speaker 2:  and it feels like in a weird way, we're in like a bad middle zone between
Speaker 2:  good things.
Speaker 9:  No, you need to get the steam deck with Ola and just be done and happy.
Speaker 9:  I
Speaker 8:  Think what you need to do is you need to unlock, you need to unlock
Speaker 8:  a mountain of amazing PC games you've been missing that are
Speaker 8:  incredibly cheap and brilliant and beautiful and
Speaker 8:  rut on this handheld with an amazing screen. That's what you need to do.
Speaker 9:  And it's also hackable,
Speaker 2:  Sean, I gave you one game, one game that I need to play
Speaker 2:  and you're telling me that I can have everything I want except the one game
Speaker 2:  that I need to play.
Speaker 8:  If you wanna play Fortnite on there, it doesn't do that either. So unless
Speaker 8:  you're gonna stream that, I
Speaker 2:  Literally, I almost wrote down that the two games were Fortnite and fifa
Speaker 2:  and I decided I could live without Fortnite because there are other good,
Speaker 2:  David has an hour to kill Battle Royal games out there. I could, I could
Speaker 2:  take or leave Fortnite at this point in my life. I
Speaker 9:  Was like, You can just use your iPad.
Speaker 2:  That is, that is true. So let me float another idea by you,
Speaker 2:  which is that I, instead of buying one thing, I buy several
Speaker 2:  things and, and I just yes, acknowledge that
Speaker 2:  at least for this next phase of my life, the right thing to do is get
Speaker 2:  a PS five and a PS portal for my house
Speaker 2:  projects and then I get a steam deck for travel.
Speaker 2:  I have just quadrupled the amount of money that this is costing. Is this
Speaker 2:  the outcome?
Speaker 9:  Don't do that. Save your money. Just get like,
Speaker 9:  never ever, ever, ever, ever buy a portal unless you
Speaker 9:  just have zero computer skills. If you
Speaker 9:  have none whatsoever. If all you do, if you like, struggle to turn
Speaker 9:  your phone on, get the PSP portal. People
Speaker 8:  Love the portal there, there are people who love the portal. It is selling
Speaker 8:  really well. I would never touch one except to like
Speaker 8:  to have the knowledge of having touched one because the steam deck
Speaker 8:  has an app on it. And the app is the PS portal. Yeah. That's in an app for
Speaker 8:  your steam deck. Yeah, basically it's, it's called chiaki
Speaker 8:  chiaki for deck and it, and it works great. Just make sure your PS five,
Speaker 8:  your PS four has an ethernet cable plugged into it or it will not work very
Speaker 8:  well.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Don't
Speaker 9:  Get the PS portal because that is, that's for like, that's for people who
Speaker 9:  love to game and don't have a lot of computer skills and so they're like,
Speaker 9:  okay, I just need to go play right now. And that's great,
Speaker 9:  but like you spend a little bit more money, you get the steam deck, you spend
Speaker 9:  a little extra time and you have just way more capability. Okay.
Speaker 2:  So, alright, so let me, let me play out this scenario. So what's
Speaker 2:  happening here is I, I'm going to make
Speaker 2:  sure that my PlayStation streaming setup is as good as
Speaker 2:  possible. I'm going to make sure that I have an ethernet port. I'm gonna,
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna plug my PlayStation into the Euro gateway and not the
Speaker 2:  euro in the basement. I'm gonna, I'm gonna make sure that my internet
Speaker 2:  connection for my PlayStation is as good as possible. TBD on whether
Speaker 2:  that's gonna be a PS four or PS five, we're gonna see how poor I feel at
Speaker 2:  the end of this episode, but that, that essentially becomes my like,
Speaker 2:  dedicated FIFA machine, which is an absurd place to have landed. But
Speaker 2:  again, here we are.
Speaker 8:  If you've already got the PS four, I mean, why not?
Speaker 2:  So that I'm, I'm relegating this thing to being my FIFA machine and then
Speaker 2:  I'm going to download the app you just said for the steam deck for when I
Speaker 2:  wanna play FIFA and I'm gonna play FIFA on the steam deck through my PlayStation,
Speaker 2:  which seems ludicrous, but you're telling me will kind of sort of work. As
Speaker 2:  long as I have very good internet,
Speaker 9:  It'll work great
Speaker 8:  Inside your house. Remote is theoretically possible, but you'll play it in
Speaker 8:  your house realistically.
Speaker 2:  So I've, I've, that's my solution to the, how do I play on my couch instead
Speaker 2:  of in the basement problem. Great. For everything else,
Speaker 2:  I'm just going to broaden my horizons and play less FIFA and play more other
Speaker 2:  games. Is this what you're telling me? This is, this is where I need to land.
Speaker 9:  I, I feel like You can find a really good FIFA clone, but like they all
Speaker 9:  have swords or something. I like, I feel like this exists.
Speaker 9:  Someone's made this game an alpha. So
Speaker 2:  What is ironically possible is that because
Speaker 2:  EA Sports FC is no longer called fifa, somebody else is making a FIFA game
Speaker 2:  and maybe that FIFA game will be on the steam deck, which will solve all
Speaker 2:  of my problems all at once. This is, this is what I'm hoping for done
Speaker 8:  And also you'll write about this experience hopefully for The Verge and then
Speaker 8:  EA will start taking care of its shit. Okay,
Speaker 2:  So ea very large company makes a lot of very popular games. Is there any
Speaker 2:  hope for EA on the steam deck ever? Like should I have any optimism for that
Speaker 2:  to be a thing? The steam deck's very popular. What are we doing here?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I mean they just, they just break things willy-nilly and they don't
Speaker 8:  think about it. It's not like they don't want money. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  E ea is like kind of notorious for being one of the
Speaker 9:  worst companies in the United States. Like I think when Consumerist existed
Speaker 9:  it was regularly beating cable companies Oh boy. For being the worst
Speaker 9:  because they just, they, they put money ahead of
Speaker 9:  usability frequently and so they could fix it, but I don't think they have
Speaker 9:  a whole lot of interest because most of their players, the bulk of their
Speaker 9:  audience is not, is, you know, it's on the switch. It's on the, the PlayStation.
Speaker 2:  Okay. One other steam deck question. The, the one other thing I forgot to
Speaker 2:  mention is I do wanna be able to plug this thing into a large
Speaker 2:  screen and play it. I don't think that's like the most common use case for
Speaker 2:  me, but I do want to be able to sit in front of a television and
Speaker 2:  play it like a console as I normally would. And for me with the switch,
Speaker 2:  I have done that way less than I expected because you have to have such specific
Speaker 2:  hardware to pull that off and like carrying around the dock is annoying.
Speaker 2:  And I bought the little plug thing and that helped, but then I lost that.
Speaker 2:  And so I want, I want something that is a little easier to turn into like
Speaker 2:  a full fledged console when I want to, is the steam deck good at that?
Speaker 9:  You're still gonna need a little dongle. Okay. To, to mirror
Speaker 9:  things. Dongle
Speaker 8:  Or dock.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, you're gonna need a dongle or doc. I think the official one's like
Speaker 9:  what, a hundred dollars Sean?
Speaker 8:  It's less, it's, I wanna say 70, 80, something like that. But You can buy
Speaker 8:  much cheaper than that. I'd used like an off the shelf like $35
Speaker 8:  USBC hub that A-H-D-M-I that worked. I used docs from
Speaker 8:  like J-S-O-J-S-A-U-X great company with an alphabet
Speaker 8:  soup name surprisingly 40, 50 bucks. And those docs are, do all
Speaker 8:  the things you'd want from a doc. It's really easy once you get one of those
Speaker 8:  things to get it up there. The question is, is your TV like 4K and
Speaker 8:  you're expecting 4K visuals from a console that normally plays at 800 because
Speaker 8:  it's not gonna look as good up on a big 4K tv
Speaker 2:  I will say, and Liam or producer can vouch for this. The least VERGE
Speaker 2:  casty thing about me is I don't care all that much about pixel density. So
Speaker 2:  the idea of playing like at, you know, medium settings and having it work
Speaker 2:  okay is completely fine by me.
Speaker 9:  I just heard Neli screaming, this
Speaker 2:  Is the last time you'll ever hear from me on The Vergecast. But that is,
Speaker 2:  that is where I'm at and especially with something like this, like battery
Speaker 2:  life is much more important to me than like getting 10
Speaker 2:  extra frames per second. And so I think again, the customizability of the
Speaker 2:  steam deck to be able to like dial that up and down as I want it seems
Speaker 2:  useful.
Speaker 9:  You wanna steam deck ola, like get the steam deck ole every
Speaker 9:  once in a while you'll plug it into the tv, you'll be like, oh, I did it.
Speaker 9:  This looks kind of shitty. And then you'll unplug it and go back to the really
Speaker 9:  pretty ole display and be very happy.
Speaker 2:  I do suspect my switch experience has been that I set it up in
Speaker 2:  such a way that it was gonna be really easy to dock. It was gonna be great.
Speaker 2:  And then most of the time I would sit on my couch in front of the TV and
Speaker 2:  just play on my lap. And I, I would assume the steamed deck will end up being
Speaker 2:  kind of the same way. Yep.
Speaker 8:  It's so good. My, we will watch, watch some shows together with my wife and
Speaker 8:  I'll, I'll have my hand held out and get to do some, some gaming at the same
Speaker 8:  time. It's great.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Are there any other like crazy wild card
Speaker 2:  possibilities coming that we know of that might win? Like
Speaker 2:  you, you mentioned the, the RIX seems like a possible
Speaker 2:  improvement if not sort of equal to the Steam, Deck wasn there
Speaker 2:  anything else on the horizon that in three months I'm gonna be like, oh,
Speaker 2:  this is the one I needed. I don't
Speaker 8:  Think so, but there are two very different directions
Speaker 8:  you could go and I don't have one of them here in front of me, but one of
Speaker 8:  them is a 10.1 inch laptop with like
Speaker 8:  keys that actually feel good full-size SD card reader You can
Speaker 8:  actually shove the SD card all the way inside. We've got full-size
Speaker 8:  USBA ports,
Speaker 9:  It has more ports than a MacBook
Speaker 8:  USBC ports. There's an OCU link port HDMI,
Speaker 8:  it is your doc built into it. And then you take these little things off and
Speaker 8:  you got joysticks a deep head. And even even this,
Speaker 8:  this menu button in the center acts like an Xbox button, which for some reason
Speaker 8:  none of the other Windows handhelds have. And this thing is
Speaker 8:  way expensive. I mean it's twice the price of your steam deck. It costs more
Speaker 8:  than any of the handhelds, but it doubles as a laptop that has the power
Speaker 8:  of one of those other gaming handhelds in a decent sized battery, all this
Speaker 8:  stuff.
Speaker 9:  But Sean, how's it, how is it to play?
Speaker 8:  It is a laptop first and a game
Speaker 8:  handheld second.
Speaker 2:  Such a perfect gadget because that is both the stupidest thing I've ever
Speaker 2:  seen and I want it so bad. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  Right.
Speaker 9:  It's beautiful.
Speaker 2:  It's like what if instead of the touch bar, we just put a PlayStation controller
Speaker 2:  in pieces like I love it.
Speaker 8:  I I can't get, I can't get over at the boss mode. Like, like you got this
Speaker 8:  thing and you're like, no, I can't show my game pad at work. Let's take this
Speaker 8:  little metal, let's take this little slip of metal out of the back of the
Speaker 8:  fig and and drop it on top boss mode. It's a physical
Speaker 8:  boss mode. Yeah. Okay, moving on from that. Okay, so your, your
Speaker 8:  other possibility is you could embrace, you could embrace software
Speaker 8:  piracy and you could buy one of these things, which is, looks
Speaker 8:  like a game boy advances p it is the enver next fig,
Speaker 8:  but actually just comes with thousands of pirated games. And, and so
Speaker 8:  you could play all your gay boy VAs and PlayStation games on this and you
Speaker 8:  delete the pirated games first and dump your own ROMs or something like that,
Speaker 2:  As I always do.
Speaker 8:  As you do. Yes.
Speaker 9:  I feel like Berg's already gonna get wrecked for you just saying. Yeah, it
Speaker 9:  comes with all of the pirated games on it. Every
Speaker 2:  Time Sean talks about one of these, there was, I think you did a, you did
Speaker 2:  a TikTok Sean talking about the, the new Amber Brunick thing and every single
Speaker 2:  comment was like, Sean, be cool man. Stop telling people about Amber.
Speaker 2:  Gimme my
Speaker 8:  Freak was
Speaker 9:  TikTok shop is all over this thing. Like it's been
Speaker 9:  snitched on enough.
Speaker 8:  Just to illustrate though that the ea the ea FIFA game
Speaker 8:  is not a steam deck problem. The top comment on EA sports
Speaker 8:  FC 24 is ea FFC 24 not launching on
Speaker 8:  PC after anti cheat back to EA f Oh. So it's not a steam deck thing
Speaker 8:  so much as it is an EA doesn't care thing.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. Okay. So it it truly is ea is like, there are ways
Speaker 2:  you could get around the rules that we have. So we're just taking our ball
Speaker 2:  and going home. Yep. That doesn't feel like it's getting better anytime soon.
Speaker 2:  That, that does not give me hope for the, for improvements coming here, which
Speaker 2:  also means, listen, there's, there's a lot of sports games. This means I
Speaker 2:  can't play anymore, but now I'm gonna have to get into like cool nerd games.
Speaker 2:  It's gonna be great.
Speaker 9:  You You can play 'em streaming. That's
Speaker 2:  True. Steam deck plus game pass I think is starting to feel like the realest
Speaker 2:  answer I have here.
Speaker 9:  You'll have Halo and fifa, like you'll be the, the
Speaker 9:  hit of every frat party you go to. Okay,
Speaker 2:  Last question and then, and then we have to go, am
Speaker 2:  I stupid for buying a steam deck right now in the same way that I might be
Speaker 2:  stupid for buying a switch right now? Where are we in the steam deck cycle?
Speaker 9:  We're fine, right?
Speaker 8:  We're mid, yeah, we're, we're mid cycle. We're not late
Speaker 8:  yet. The thing that, the thing that valve needs, they've, they've told us,
Speaker 8:  like told me to my face, what they need to see is they
Speaker 8:  need to see a major improvement in performance without
Speaker 8:  sacrificing battery life from a chip manufacturer before
Speaker 8:  they start building the next true steam deck. And I've heard this from
Speaker 8:  other companies too. Like as with the, with the R-O-G-L-I-X, they were like,
Speaker 8:  we don't think we can get it right now, so we're gonna ship the wrong LIX
Speaker 8:  with the same chip.
Speaker 9:  And I don't think Qualcomm has changed that calculus at all. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  With the Snapdragon
Speaker 2:  And even if it has, we're a ways away from that actually appearing inside
Speaker 2:  of a product.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I think, I think we're probably a good, we're at least a year out.
Speaker 9:  I think you'll have one beautiful blissful year before you get FOMO at
Speaker 9:  least.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And that's, I mean honestly in gadget world, that's is, that's all
Speaker 2:  You can ask for.
Speaker 9:  It's like a year is an, is is an eternity in gadget world.
Speaker 2:  I mean, listen, I've made it this far into the PS five cycle without upgrading.
Speaker 2:  Like it turns out I can, I can manage my FOMO on on this one. I
Speaker 9:  Am so impressed.
Speaker 2:  Thank you. That's actually the other question I should ask is like, am I
Speaker 2:  being ridiculous? Should I just buy a PS five and move on with my life? Oh,
Speaker 9:  I mean, have infinite, if you have infinite money, yes.
Speaker 2:  If I buy a PS five, I almost certainly will end up buying a portal
Speaker 2:  and I, I hate myself for it, but it will probably happen
Speaker 9:  Then I say don't, because I wanna save you from the portal.
Speaker 8:  You could buy a used steam deck LCD for the price of a portal and also have
Speaker 8:  a portal built into it with an app. Oh,
Speaker 2:  Well that's very compelling.
Speaker 8:  But PS five, like if you do love that I'm sitting
Speaker 8:  on my couch with my 4K ole TV experience,
Speaker 8:  it's hard to beat the PS five for that. I'm playing Spider-Man two on it
Speaker 8:  right now on a just a gorgeous new ole panel that was deep discounted
Speaker 8:  recently and wow the pop of that city, the lights
Speaker 8:  at night. It's, it's, it's, it's, it's really something.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I, and I do love that, but I think I, I am increasingly coming
Speaker 2:  around to like, having a thing with me is
Speaker 2:  more important than the sort of very best possible experience.
Speaker 2:  I I would love to have both, but I don't think You can really have both right
Speaker 2:  now in the world we live in
Speaker 8:  And. if you, if you really want to have that thing with you, I don't think
Speaker 8:  there's anything that beats the steam deck. There's just so much You can
Speaker 8:  now take with you that you can't the same way through the window as handhelds.
Speaker 8:  You can't really with Android. Alright,
Speaker 2:  Well we have ended where we began, which I find very frustrating, but also
Speaker 2:  sort of telling I'm gonna buy a steam deck. Yeah. I probably should have
Speaker 2:  bought a steam deck a really long time ago. I'm gonna buy a steam deck and
Speaker 2:  I I will start yelling loudly at ea I'll report back.
Speaker 9:  I'm so excited for you. Everybody's excited about the EA though.
Speaker 2:  Do you have any immediate setup tips before we talk again? I will have purchased
Speaker 2:  a steam deck. What, what should I do Immediately outta the box with my brand
Speaker 2:  new steam deco lead?
Speaker 8:  I have so many nerdy suggestions. I
Speaker 2:  Don't want nerdy suggestions. Sean. I say this with love. I want to, I want
Speaker 2:  to get
Speaker 8:  To, I know I was like
Speaker 2:  Playing games well as quickly and seamlessly as possible.
Speaker 2:  Like I am worried about the steam deck because I'm worried it's so fidgety
Speaker 2:  and finicky that I'm gonna spend my whole life goofing with the joysticks
Speaker 2:  and not playing games.
Speaker 9:  So, so Steam Deck has this, like on the steam deck they have compatibility
Speaker 9:  for games and You can also see it on the Steam software. So like You can
Speaker 9:  just go download steam ahead of time, find some games you like, make sure
Speaker 9:  they're compatible and then it'll be just outta the box ready to go. Anything
Speaker 9:  that's like yellow or red, you'll have to mess with a little bit. That's
Speaker 9:  where you have to start tweaking things. Like I try to play Crusader Kings
Speaker 9:  on it. Don't, that's it's not for the Steam deck. It's terrible.
Speaker 8:  There's even a tab in the store where You can just like, only show me games
Speaker 8:  that work well with the Steam deck. And for the most part they do.
Speaker 9:  They Yeah, and it's, it's a lot of stuff, right? Like, it, it's, it's a ton
Speaker 9:  of stuff. The ones that don't is stuff that's like mass effect, which is
Speaker 9:  an EA game. So you know why it doesn't work.
Speaker 2:  Well, I will say the other game in my life that I have loved with my whole
Speaker 2:  heart, the way that I have loved FIFA with my whole heart is portal. And
Speaker 2:  the idea of having a steam thing that will let me play the portal games forever
Speaker 2:  is very exciting.
Speaker 9:  And it will just straight out of the box, you'll be, you'll be off to the
Speaker 9:  races having a great time. Yeah. It, it really is so easy to just get
Speaker 9:  going on the steam deck, provided you already own games.
Speaker 8:  Elden Ring plays well there, Ori and the Will of the
Speaker 8:  Wisps, if you haven't played that yet, play that on Deco lid. Okay. Oh my
Speaker 8:  God, it looks brilliant. On the deco lid. That game is made for HDR
Speaker 8:  Persona five. Have you played any persona games?
Speaker 2:  Bits and pieces, but never, never super deeply. Okay.
Speaker 8:  Get Persona five or Persona five, Royal, whichever one is better for your
Speaker 8:  budget. Play that on Steam Deck. It's, it's, it's epic.
Speaker 8:  We could, we could spend the rest, you spend, spend another hour talking
Speaker 8:  about games to play on.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I was about to say have, have you played Final Fantasy remake yet?
Speaker 9:  Like beautiful on the Steam
Speaker 2:  Deck. Okay. All right. My list is long and none of them are the only game
Speaker 2:  that I need it, but you know, we're doing the best we can here. You
Speaker 9:  Can get FIFA 23 fairly easily on, on the Steam deck.
Speaker 2:  Okay. That might help. Maybe that's like my gateway drug out of being obsessed
Speaker 2:  with fifa. I'll just play old games enough to satiate me
Speaker 2:  and then go play Better Games. You
Speaker 9:  Get Ted Lasso in that one, you'll be fine.
Speaker 2:  All right, thank you both. This was very helpful.
Speaker 2:  anything yet. If you have ideas, please let me know. Vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com. Call the hotline. Eight six six VERGE one one. What do you think
Speaker 2:  I should buy? Tell me everything. I'm still so torn. I think Sean and Alex
Speaker 2:  gave really good advice, but I don't know if I've actually solved my problem
Speaker 2:  yet. Anyway, let's get into the next thing. Every once in a while in the
Speaker 2:  show we like to test some microphones. I think this stuff really
Speaker 2:  matters and it doesn't get talked about a lot. When we talk about headphones
Speaker 2:  and when we talk about wearable devices, we talk to our gadgets
Speaker 2:  a lot. And, if you believe that AI is the future of how we talk to
Speaker 2:  gadgets, it's gonna get more vocal over time. Microphones really
Speaker 2:  matter whether you're just talking to Siri to set reminders, which is a thing
Speaker 2:  I do constantly all day every day. Or it's gonna be how you talk
Speaker 2:  to chat GPT or your robot AI best
Speaker 2:  friend for forever. Microphones really matter and we've tested
Speaker 2:  a lot of earbuds. We actually probably overdo for an earbuds test.
Speaker 2:  But the thing that we haven't really done is maybe one of the
Speaker 2:  wearable categories I'm most excited about, which I'll say broadly
Speaker 2:  speaking, is face gadgets. You have things like the Meta
Speaker 2:  Quest three and the Vision Pro. You also have things like the Meta Smart
Speaker 2:  glasses and Amazon's echo frames and the idea of
Speaker 2:  just a thing you wear on front of your eyes on your face.
Speaker 2:  That is a super powerful computer. I think we're at the very beginning
Speaker 2:  of that genre of gadget, but I already think there's a lot of
Speaker 2:  interesting stuff out there. So as we do, it's time to do a microphone test.
Speaker 2:  I asked V Song who has almost all of these gadgets, somewhat
Speaker 2:  remarkably just lying around her house to come on and do some tests with
Speaker 2:  us. So we're gonna hear how it all sounds. Let's go V Song. Welcome
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 11:  Thanks for having me again.
Speaker 2:  You and I have done so much stuff together recently. This is very exciting.
Speaker 2:  This is terrible for you and great for me. I'm, I'm happy about it. So I
Speaker 2:  have brought you here for the thing I have been like very excited to do for
Speaker 2:  months because what I have discovered in my own life is that now
Speaker 2:  when I take a phone call and I'm at home, instead of holding
Speaker 2:  my phone to my ear, I actually put on the Meta Smart glasses and that is
Speaker 2:  now my like hands free phone experience and I love it very much.
Speaker 2:  And I have found myself wondering a lot how I sound to other people when
Speaker 2:  I do that. So you and I are going to do, I think, maybe the most ambitious
Speaker 2:  microphone test we've ever done on this show because it involves a deeply
Speaker 2:  weird set of gadgets and I'm very excited about it.
Speaker 11:  I spent so much time yesterday and this morning prepping
Speaker 11:  the, just for the technical logistics
Speaker 11:  of all of it. And I looked ridiculous at every step of the
Speaker 11:  way. So
Speaker 2:  As it should be. So yeah. Okay, run me through the list of all the stuff
Speaker 2:  we're about to test, which is basically like every weird face
Speaker 2:  gadget in v's house.
Speaker 11:  You know, it's a very thoughtful selection of the weird face gadgets in
Speaker 11:  my house. Okay, so we have the Razer Zu, which are a
Speaker 11:  productivity pair of smart glasses. You know, they marketed as
Speaker 11:  basically like smart glasses for hands-free calls.
Speaker 11:  And when you're on your computer that has blue light, what, what do you
Speaker 11:  call these lenses? So we have those, then we have the
Speaker 11:  RayBan Metas Smartt glasses, we have the Apple Vision Pro
Speaker 11:  and we have the Meta Quest three. Amazing.
Speaker 2:  I will say the only one in this category I feel like we don't have in here
Speaker 2:  is probably the echo frames. I think anecdotally no one
Speaker 2:  seems to care about the echo frames, so I don't feel that bad leaving it
Speaker 2:  out. But I do think it's like, it's like the one in this category that I'm
Speaker 2:  curious about that we're not testing. So we'll have to come back and do that
Speaker 2:  another time.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, well I do have a pair. I just moved not that
Speaker 11:  long ago and then did spring cleaning. So the charger, where is the charger?
Speaker 11:  I have been tearing my house apart for the charger because it's a, it's
Speaker 11:  a weird charger. Okay,
Speaker 2:  This is a good point. It's not just A-U-S-B-C port, which
Speaker 2:  is what all chargers should be. It's a stupid like stand that you have
Speaker 2:  to stick them on top of And. if you don't push them down at the
Speaker 2:  right angle in the right way, it doesn't work. It's one of the worst chargers
Speaker 2:  I've ever used. I hate
Speaker 11:  It. It's also the glasses that stay on my face the least because I have
Speaker 11:  a low nose bridge and it just slips down.
Speaker 2:  That's my problem with the metas smartt glasses. So I'm sort of hoping
Speaker 2:  that the meta ones don't win so that I can convince myself to
Speaker 2:  buy something else. But we're gonna see how this goes. So before we dive
Speaker 2:  in, I think the one caveat we should provide here is that so
Speaker 2:  far you're talking into your podcast, Mike. So I would say this is, this
Speaker 2:  is kind of the gold standard of the audio that you should hear. Anything
Speaker 2:  that we test is going to be compared to this. There are a couple that we're
Speaker 2:  about to test that are Bluetooth devices. So you're gonna be pairing Bluetooth
Speaker 2:  devices to your computer. So you're gonna get whatever Bluetooth weirdness
Speaker 2:  exists. But I would say that's fine. 'cause that's pretty indicative of normal
Speaker 2:  Bluetooth weirdness. Like most of peop, most of the time people are talking
Speaker 2:  through Bluetooth gadgets. So we're gonna do that. But then there's a couple,
Speaker 2:  I think the headsets are going to be basically treated like
Speaker 2:  microphones on computers because we're actually gonna be able to do it natively
Speaker 2:  inside of the device. So we'll talk about those when we get to those. But
Speaker 2:  let's just dive in. Which one do you wanna do first?
Speaker 11:  I've got the Anzo on right now, so let's just do that because I
Speaker 11:  swear to God this is gonna be a logistical nightmare when we're switching.
Speaker 2:  I cannot wait. This is, this is one of those times where podcast editing
Speaker 2:  becomes very, very, very helpful because you don't have to listen to us fiddle
Speaker 2:  with Bluetooth settings, but all right, let's, let's dive in. Let's go.
Speaker 12:  All right. I am talking, I am saying a sentence. Oh no, and your face
Speaker 12:  is like saying that it does not sound good. This
Speaker 2:  Is terrible. This is like, okay, how would I describe it?
Speaker 2:  You sound like you're on a phone call on speaker phone,
Speaker 2:  but you've done the thing where you put your phone down on the kitchen counter
Speaker 2:  while we're talking and then you've like walked into the other room.
Speaker 12:  Cool. Love it. I can imagine what that sounds like. And you
Speaker 12:  know, I don't, I, I not really sure where the mics are on
Speaker 12:  this particular thing, but I don't think they're like the Met Ray bands
Speaker 12:  where the mic is in the nose bridge. So it's like kind of close
Speaker 12:  to your mouth. It says that they have omnidirectional mics
Speaker 12:  probably in the temples. So if they're in the temples, that's, you know,
Speaker 12:  pretty far away from the actual sound source.
Speaker 2:  And actually in a certain way sort of defeats the purpose of why I'm excited
Speaker 2:  about these devices. 'cause as you're talking about, one of the nice things
Speaker 2:  about glasses is just that they're closer to your mouth, right? We have,
Speaker 2:  yeah, all these Bluetooth headphones and stuff, they, they are constrained
Speaker 2:  by the fact that they're on your ears. So they have the stems that point
Speaker 2:  towards your mouth and that kind of helps. And they're getting smarter with
Speaker 2:  the software. But fundamentally, like the way to get a good microphone is
Speaker 2:  to put it closer to your mouth, where the sound is coming from and
Speaker 2:  it feels like Razer just sort of beefed this one. So
Speaker 2:  to razor's credit, I guess defense slightly, these
Speaker 2:  aren't necessarily meant for this kind of like
Speaker 2:  communication sorts of calls, right? These are things you're supposed to
Speaker 2:  wear like at your desk to make it a little less painful to look at a screen
Speaker 2:  all day.
Speaker 12:  So they, you know, there's like a while where Razer was just like, we're
Speaker 12:  not just gaming, we do productivity stuff too. Yay for the office.
Speaker 12:  And I think this was part of that push, like yeah, they do have blue light
Speaker 12:  lenses so that if you're looking at the screen a lot, it's easier for you.
Speaker 12:  They are your typical pair of glasses that are also headphones.
Speaker 12:  So You can just listen to stuff. But you know, like when I took the briefing
Speaker 12:  a couple years ago and was testing this, it was just basically like,
Speaker 12:  yeah, it is meant for like productivity in the office. So You
Speaker 12:  can take phone calls and you'll sound really great. So obviously that
Speaker 12:  was some marketing spiel because clearly
Speaker 12:  judging by your reaction, I do not sound that great.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, you will not sound really great. I can tell you that now with, with
Speaker 2:  great confidence. Andrew Marino. I don't usually get to
Speaker 2:  do this when we're here, but Andrew is, is our sound expert and podcast
Speaker 2:  editor. Andrew, I, I want you to weigh in on all of these with me. What do
Speaker 2:  you think of this one?
Speaker 13:  Okay, so these aren't as bad as I thought. It is a
Speaker 13:  obviously a clear difference between a podcast microphone and, and this,
Speaker 13:  but I don't hear a lot of background noise. That is true. That is
Speaker 13:  good. I would actually like to hear how this sounds compared to like
Speaker 13:  someone wearing AirPods though too, because would you
Speaker 13:  prefer hearing AirPods microphones or would you prefer hearing
Speaker 13:  the glasses microphones?
Speaker 2:  I was just thinking about that actually. And I think the thing that the AirPods
Speaker 2:  do that these aren't doing is at least the AirPods push the
Speaker 2:  voice more to the center of the mix, right? Like it's trying really
Speaker 2:  hard to like raise the volume of your voice as opposed to everything else.
Speaker 2:  This feels flatter in a way that is like probably more
Speaker 2:  pleasant in a certain way, but also just means I can like hear you less.
Speaker 2:  Well
Speaker 11:  I also wonder what it would be like if, you know, the other proposition
Speaker 11:  for glasses is that like you're on a walk, You can go outside and take the
Speaker 11:  phone call as well and you know, outside there's a lot more ambient noise.
Speaker 11:  There's cars, there's wind. I wonder what this would sound like if you were
Speaker 11:  on a walk. 'cause I've taken calls on the Met of Raybans while I'm on a
Speaker 11:  walk and people think they're pretty decent, pretty good just 'cause of
Speaker 11:  where the microphone is situated. So I, you know, they always claim that
Speaker 11:  they're great for wind and I'm always like, but are they, are they?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, we should say you're, you're in your house in what I would call like
Speaker 2:  a relatively quiet space. This is kind of as good as
Speaker 2:  it's gonna be. We'll we'll have to come back and do this another time with
Speaker 2:  worse environments. But I think particularly 'cause we had some of the headsets
Speaker 2:  and these are like things you're mostly gonna be doing inside. We wanted
Speaker 2:  to give it its best shot. Yeah. But okay, I'm done with these. These are
Speaker 2:  not great. Let, let's, let's move on. Let's do, let's do The Ray band
Speaker 2:  ones next. That feels like a good one-to-one comparison here. Let's switch
Speaker 2:  to those.
Speaker 11:  All right. Okay. This is me and the meta and I
Speaker 11:  just want you to know that I'm blind because I have my contacts on and these
Speaker 11:  are prescription lenses, so you are just a big blob on my phone.
Speaker 2:  This sounds way better like night and day to the
Speaker 2:  last one. This is actually like the sound I was hoping that this was
Speaker 2:  going to give me. It's not like amazing. It's, it's definitely, I'm hearing
Speaker 2:  a lot of compression on your voice. It's, it's like clearly trying very
Speaker 2:  hard to get your voice and cancel even not a lot of background noise, but
Speaker 2:  this sounds great. I should say also you're on your phone
Speaker 2:  to do this, normally record these things on your computer, but because of
Speaker 2:  the weirdness of these glasses, you had an easier time connecting
Speaker 2:  them to your phone than to your computer because Bluetooth is dumb and
Speaker 2:  bad and complicated and nobody is good at it. But you sound really good to
Speaker 2:  me.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, so this was like one of the limitations that Becca pointed out when
Speaker 11:  we were both doing The Ray Vanta meta testing and she
Speaker 11:  like went all in on the, the microphone testing for these and
Speaker 11:  it's just not really all that easy to, you know, connect with
Speaker 11:  your computer while having these on. This is just a very phone
Speaker 11:  first kind of pairing situation, which is a little annoying,
Speaker 11:  but great. If you wanna take these outside I think and
Speaker 11:  just like walk around and take calls while you're, I do that all the time.
Speaker 11:  Like I'll be on a walk and a friend will call and I'll just gab and
Speaker 11:  people will look at me crazy 'cause I don't have the social cue of having
Speaker 11:  AirPods in my ear and these just look like a normal pair of glasses,
Speaker 11:  so I just look like a psycho.
Speaker 2:  Well, and right now you have sunglasses on indoors, which I would say is
Speaker 2:  like an extremely cool move.
Speaker 11:  Is it, is it, is it, is it cool who can say
Speaker 11:  also like, yeah, so I got these sent with prescription lenses as
Speaker 11:  sunglasses and I was like, I would've loved it if these were
Speaker 11:  the transition lenses, but alas,
Speaker 2:  I have the transitions and they're awesome. My dad who does not have
Speaker 2:  smart glasses, just has transition lenses in his regular glasses
Speaker 2:  and we made fun of him about it for so long because it's like you go
Speaker 2:  inside and for four minutes you just have sunglasses on and we always used
Speaker 2:  to make fun of it and like boy has history proven him, right? Like, congrats
Speaker 2:  dad, you made transition lenses a thing. They are great. I'm, I'm a fan.
Speaker 2:  So the thing that I like about these, this is the one where they put the
Speaker 2:  microphone like right next to your nose, right? So it's, it's yes sort of
Speaker 2:  perfectly where it should be to sound good here.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, there's, I believe there's five microphones in the glasses at various
Speaker 11:  points, but the one that captures your voice is just right in the nose bridge,
Speaker 11:  so it's like right above your mouth. So like I think that was
Speaker 11:  the kind of low key genius move that they
Speaker 11:  did with these compared to the other smart glasses that I've tested. So
Speaker 11:  I, I gotta say I really enjoy these as my outdoor walk,
Speaker 11:  outdoor, I wear these while running too and it's pretty great as like a
Speaker 11:  pair of open hair, headphones, I can take calls. The
Speaker 11:  sunglasses are great, the sound quality is great. So I just wish
Speaker 11:  I had transition lenses 'cause then I could just use these all the time.
Speaker 11:  That'd be great. Totally.
Speaker 2:  Andrew, what do you think?
Speaker 13:  Yeah, these sound better than the Razer ones. I wouldn't be
Speaker 13:  mad at all about this as far as like Bluetooth goes. It's pretty, pretty
Speaker 13:  good.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I, I agree. This is definitely one that is like notably better
Speaker 2:  than AirPods and it just, you feel much closer, which
Speaker 2:  is really nice. Like a lot of the things, and this is the challenge with
Speaker 2:  the, the Razer one is a lot of Bluetooth headphones just make you feel sort
Speaker 2:  of far away because you are far away. This one you, you feel
Speaker 2:  much closer to the mic, which makes you feel much closer like to me as we're
Speaker 2:  talking. Which is, which is very cool. This one I'm calling a victory. Let's,
Speaker 2:  let's move on to some of the other ones. What do we have next?
Speaker 11:  We have your pick of which headset? The Vision Pro or
Speaker 11:  the Meta? Quest.
Speaker 2:  Let's start with the Quest because I would assume that the Vision Pro is
Speaker 2:  gonna sound better, but also I think more people have quests. So let's,
Speaker 2:  let's start with Quest.
Speaker 11:  This is going to be logistically fraught, so
Speaker 2:  We're gonna play some hold music. We'll be back in like 45 minutes once we
Speaker 2:  get this set up. Okay,
Speaker 11:  Let's do it. Alright.
Speaker 2:  Meta. Quest. Is this the Quest two or the Quest three that we're on here?
Speaker 2:  V
Speaker 11:  Quest three I believe. Yeah, quest three.
Speaker 2:  All right, let's hear it. How do we sound?
Speaker 11:  I am talking, supposedly You can hear me even though
Speaker 11:  this gave me a lot of grief about there being no microphone while logging
Speaker 11:  into this. So it's very confusing.
Speaker 2:  Okay, this sounds really good. I, this is kind of right in line with the
Speaker 2:  smart glasses actually, which I'm realizing now it's two meta products
Speaker 2:  that sit on your face. Maybe there's some shared technology there, but I
Speaker 2:  don't know how that didn't occur to me until just now. But yeah, you sound
Speaker 2:  pretty good. This is just another like big
Speaker 2:  microphone on your face. And this is another one that I think they, they
Speaker 2:  put the microphone pretty centrally on the thing, so it
Speaker 2:  might even be closer to your mouth than the smart glasses.
Speaker 11:  Oh well it certainly is weighing on my head so it feels like it's
Speaker 11:  falling down my face more than the smart glasses.
Speaker 2:  It's gonna be on top of your mouth here in a couple of minutes as you're
Speaker 2:  trying to talk. It'll be good.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, it's, it's actually, it's 'cause I don't have it super tight on the
Speaker 11:  the back because I get headaches when these are too tight. Mm. Oh there
Speaker 11:  we go. There we go.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so what I, what I also want to know is tell me about the experience
Speaker 2:  of getting into this call from the Quest
Speaker 2:  because there's like the, one of the things that Meta would really like to
Speaker 2:  convince you of is that eventually a VR headset is going to be a work tool
Speaker 2:  and You can you just like open up a browser and use it for Google Meet or
Speaker 2:  whatever. I have never done that one time and I'm very curious how it's going
Speaker 2:  for you.
Speaker 11:  So I basically had to log into
Speaker 11:  Slack, right? Because I need a link to this meeting and so how
Speaker 11:  am I gonna get a link to this particular meeting? So you know, like
Speaker 11:  either you have to have your calendar in here, some in some capacity, or
Speaker 11:  you have to basically go into the browser, go into your Google calendar
Speaker 11:  and and whatnot. But I then I was just like, oh God, okay.
Speaker 11:  So I went into Slack, which in our
Speaker 11:  workplace, because things are secure was real effing
Speaker 11:  annoying because
Speaker 2:  Two factor authentication in a headset, not a solved problem, two
Speaker 11:  Factor authentication in a headset, lemme tell you it's not fun. And
Speaker 11:  I was a good Foxed employee. I have a very complicated
Speaker 11:  password for my work thing. So I'm just going in and this
Speaker 11:  13, 14, 15 character, long pa, I don't know how long it is, it's long, but
Speaker 11:  I'm just like punching it in with this stupid little keyboard just going,
Speaker 11:  eh, eh, capital, oh that's not a capital, I have to reenter all of this.
Speaker 11:  Then we have two factor authentication and I have to go, thankfully I get
Speaker 11:  it sent to my watch. So I get it, boom into the watch. I'm like, yeah, cool,
Speaker 11:  awesome. Then I'm in Slack and then I have to go like in the wa in the browser
Speaker 11:  and Slack and I have to go, okay, now I gotta go to the link that I know
Speaker 11:  is in this dm and then, oh, okay, I gotta scroll on the dm, click on the
Speaker 11:  link that opens up Riverside and the browser. And then I'm like,
Speaker 11:  cool, I'm gonna just log in even though it's saying that there is no
Speaker 11:  micro camera detected. So yeah,
Speaker 11:  Andrew helped me test this before.
Speaker 2:  It is, it is quite a project, so, okay. Andrew, I, I'm really curious
Speaker 2:  for your thoughts on this one because I, I want to know how you feel about
Speaker 2:  this versus the smart glasses because what I am hearing is very similar,
Speaker 2:  but this sounds like it's compressing harder to me, but
Speaker 2:  what are you hearing?
Speaker 13:  There's a bit of compression here. I'm also wondering if it's
Speaker 13:  Riverside's echo cancellation here, but it is not
Speaker 13:  significantly better than the meta ray bands.
Speaker 13:  This is a great sound for taking a meeting
Speaker 13:  call, but if he was like, Hey, can I join the podcast
Speaker 13:  with the Quest three? I'd be like, well can you use your
Speaker 13:  phone?
Speaker 2:  Right. I think that's right. Like none of this has gotten even up to like
Speaker 2:  wired ear pods quality, but at least so far this is
Speaker 2:  definitely better than Razer, but I would say not quite as good as the Meadow
Speaker 2:  ones. My theory, I wonder about the echo cancellation too, but I also wonder
Speaker 2:  if, because meta assumes you're gonna be playing games all
Speaker 2:  the time on this thing that it's going to have audio all the time. And so
Speaker 2:  they've just turned up the echo cancellation on the device itself
Speaker 2:  just so it's trying to noise cancel against what's coming out of the speakers
Speaker 2:  all the time. 'cause it's just, it is compressing this pretty
Speaker 2:  aggressively.
Speaker 13:  It does sound like there is some processing happening. Yeah. Before it gets
Speaker 13:  into here.
Speaker 2:  V how are the speakers on this? Like the actual listening experience is
Speaker 2:  pretty solid, right? I feel like. Yeah, yeah. So this, this, I agree it would
Speaker 2:  work in a pinch in a meeting, but Andrew would not allow you on The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  in, in the headset under normal circumstances.
Speaker 11:  Also, like if you're reaching for a headset in a pinch
Speaker 11:  for a meeting, something has gone terribly wrong,
Speaker 2:  Consider
Speaker 11:  Your choices. Something has gone terribly wrong, terribly, terribly wrong
Speaker 11:  because where's your phone? There's just easier things to do than to
Speaker 11:  swap on a headset. And then, you know, like I had gotten logged
Speaker 11:  out of my account because the spouse logged into this at some point and
Speaker 11:  it was playing games. Then it was just like, where's my account? Oh,
Speaker 11:  I forgot. I don't remember what my Facebook password is. Oh, you're telling
Speaker 11:  me I have to log into this with that, that this was an ordeal yesterday
Speaker 11:  getting this prepped for today.
Speaker 2:  Well, in the name of making everything simpler and better, let's make it
Speaker 2:  more complicated. Let's switch and do the Vision Pro. Let's try that next.
Speaker 2:  Oh
Speaker 11:  Good lord. Here we, you know, actually that might be slightly easier than
Speaker 11:  this one because Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Okay. All right, we'll, we'll we'll go back to the hold music. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 11:  All right, hold on.
Speaker 2:  All right, well it took, it took some digging in settings and some app
Speaker 2:  rebooting, but we got it working and now your persona is here and I, I
Speaker 2:  hate this already, but I'm, I'm gonna not look, I'm just gonna listen.
Speaker 2:  How do we sound? How are we doing?
Speaker 11:  This was a nightmare. This is a nightmare. Everything's a
Speaker 11:  nightmare air. I can't stop looking at my horrible
Speaker 11:  persona. Why is my hair so lumpy?
Speaker 11:  My eyebrows are also misaligned, so I just look
Speaker 11:  dubious.
Speaker 2:  The good news is you sound great. I'm actually like amazed
Speaker 2:  by how good this sounds. I suppose it's a $3,500 headset.
Speaker 2:  Again, it's a thing on your face. There are a lot of microphones, apple's
Speaker 2:  pretty good at noise cancellation. I sort of figured this would be just in
Speaker 2:  terms of raw audio, the best one. but it is,
Speaker 2:  I I would say like a full leap be above anything else we've
Speaker 2:  tested so far
Speaker 11:  Is surprising just because of how annoying it was to get into this
Speaker 11:  app.
Speaker 2:  There's definitely some compression I will say that, that I'm hearing more
Speaker 2:  and more as you talk. It's doing a lot of the same like processing
Speaker 2:  and and cancellation stuff, but it still sounds very good and it's,
Speaker 2:  it's very central. Like you, you are right in the middle of the mix and it,
Speaker 2:  it sounds like you're talking to me instead of shouting
Speaker 2:  at a phone from several rooms away, which is very nice.
Speaker 11:  I will say that whenever I've done my cursed vision Pro
Speaker 11:  FaceTimes with Wes, everything sounds great. Like, 'cause he's
Speaker 11:  obviously in the Vision Pro and it using that mic and it's
Speaker 11:  always sounded like he's in the room with me, which
Speaker 11:  is uncanny and freaky on top of
Speaker 11:  his mustache that won't move.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The real takeaway from this is FaceTime Audio is your friend on
Speaker 2:  the Vision Pro not FaceTime video and that is, that is the way to
Speaker 2:  live your life on the Vision Pro.
Speaker 11:  Now half the time our FaceTimes are like, oh, why do I have
Speaker 11:  this over my mouth, this cloud because my hand is there.
Speaker 11:  Alright,
Speaker 2:  Well it sounds good. Let's, let's get you out of your misery here.
Speaker 2:  I do, we should, we weren't planning to do this, but we should test AirPods
Speaker 2:  last just as kind of a control on the rest of it. Do you have a pair of AirPods
Speaker 2:  lying around?
Speaker 11:  I do.
Speaker 2:  Alright, let's go get those, take off this Godforsaken headset
Speaker 2:  and let's, let's try those.
Speaker 11:  Thank you. Thank you for letting me leave virtual jail.
Speaker 13:  I don't know what is happening right now, but your voice is sped up like
Speaker 2:  Like a hundred x. Yeah,
Speaker 13:  I'm gonna have to kick you out V and then you're gonna have to come back
Speaker 13:  in. I can't even understand what you're saying. Yeah, I got
Speaker 2:  Nothing. Yeah, just kick her out. Yeah. V you're back with AirPods on
Speaker 12:  My AirPods Pro USBC version. So I guess the
Speaker 12:  latest versions of the AirPods Pro You can have.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so I have to say this is, this sounds comparatively
Speaker 2:  worse than I actually expected. I would say I would put this
Speaker 2:  like pretty close to the very first,
Speaker 2:  the Razer ones that we listen to in the sense that it is, it kind of sounds
Speaker 2:  like a far away omnidirectional microphone and like You sound fine, I can
Speaker 2:  hear you, I can hear everything you're saying, but like, I expected
Speaker 2:  this to come on and me to be like, oh yeah, this sounds kind of like the
Speaker 2:  The Ray band Smart glasses. This is like demonstrably worse than those, at
Speaker 2:  least to my ears. Andrew, is that, am I way off here?
Speaker 13:  No, absolutely. I actually would like to hear how the Razer won't sound
Speaker 13:  again because those were a lot more fuller sounding in a
Speaker 13:  frequency range than these, these kind of sound pretty tinny actually
Speaker 13:  in comparison.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, I mean I, I do have an assortment of just gadgets in my
Speaker 12:  strewn across my room, which is like my office rather, which
Speaker 12:  is a fricking, it's a disaster zone, it's like late in
Speaker 12:  the week, so I haven't put my gadgets away like a naughty, naughty gadget
Speaker 12:  reviewer. So it's, it's literally right here. I could put them back on if
Speaker 12:  you
Speaker 13:  Want. Let's, let's do it really quickly. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Let's just do it. Yeah, just really, really quick and then we'll let you
Speaker 2:  go.
Speaker 12:  Okay. All right. I'm back in these
Speaker 12:  glasses, which you guys say look fine on me, but I think I look a little
Speaker 12:  like, I look a little bit like the grandpa from Up,
Speaker 2:  First of all. That's a compliment. You should be psyched to look like the
Speaker 2:  grandpa from Up, but yeah, Andrew, I'm, I'm kind of hearing what it sounds
Speaker 2:  like you were saying that like this is a little fuller, but to
Speaker 2:  me a little sort of further back where like, it, it sounds further away
Speaker 2:  but in a certain sense better.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, so it's probably like their worst microphones, but they
Speaker 13:  are closer to the face so you get a little more detail
Speaker 13:  of what's saying. I mean,
Speaker 12:  Yeah,
Speaker 13:  There's a trade off there, but like if I'm on a call, like I would almost
Speaker 13:  prefer these not on a podcast but in a meeting. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. You do sound clearer in this. Like I, I feel like I
Speaker 2:  hear your voice more clearly. It just sounds to me like you're further
Speaker 2:  away from it. That's really interesting. Big win for headsets today.
Speaker 2:  I expected AirPods to come somewhere in the middle, but I think you could
Speaker 2:  make a pretty compelling case that all four of the things you just tried
Speaker 2:  are better microphones for talking to people than
Speaker 2:  a pair of AirPods.
Speaker 12:  Wow. That's a, that's a big boon to the smart glasses category.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, right. This is also a big win for you and me wearing glasses,
Speaker 2:  walking around talking to ourselves like maniacs kind of situation.
Speaker 12:  You know, my neighbors have seen me do walk and talk like just
Speaker 12:  filming social videos and just, I did a social video while doing a
Speaker 12:  walk and talk and someone was just like, this, this hoe
Speaker 12:  really just be walking out here talking to, to thin
Speaker 12:  air. And I was just like, yeah, you know what, This is the future baby.
Speaker 12:  Everything is a microphone.
Speaker 2:  I really hope you say that to people. You just say This is the future baby
Speaker 2:  and then you just high five them and move on. I. love it. Alright, well we
Speaker 2:  need to get outta here, but big giant win for smart glasses today. I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  say in terms of like the combination of
Speaker 2:  you don't look like a lunatic and you sound
Speaker 2:  pretty good. I think the metas smartt glasses here are probably the winner
Speaker 2:  for me in terms of like, what would I tell you to go get for a good microphone?
Speaker 2:  Andrew, what's your read?
Speaker 13:  Yes, I would like to note that. V how much are the Razer
Speaker 13:  and zoo, how much do they cost
Speaker 12:  On Amazon? You can get them for $40. Jesus Christ,
Speaker 12:  right? That's pretty cheap.
Speaker 13:  That's really cheap for that.
Speaker 2:  That is really cheap.
Speaker 13:  If someone was like, should I get the $250
Speaker 13:  meta glasses or should I get these $40 glasses and I can take calls with,
Speaker 13:  I might just say get those.
Speaker 2:  That is fair. That's a big price difference. The meta ones definitely sound
Speaker 2:  better, but yeah, for, for 50 bucks as a, as a thing to just
Speaker 2:  throw on when you have a phone call, the, the Razer one's not a terrible
Speaker 2:  choice,
Speaker 12:  So that's shocking to me. That's like, obviously I've tested these a long
Speaker 12:  time ago so I didn't remember, but that's just a wow.
Speaker 12:  Talk about bank for your book.
Speaker 2:  The thing that I use the the Meta smart glasses for a lot is it's like
Speaker 2:  I, I've had, I had, I was in a car accident a couple weeks ago, so I spent
Speaker 2:  a lot of time on hold with the claims department and rather than wear
Speaker 2:  headphones I can just like throw them on and sit on hold and then I can like
Speaker 2:  listen to music in the room or whatever. And actually for sitting on
Speaker 2:  hold a pair of smart glasses is like weirdly great. So I think in, in that
Speaker 2:  case again, like the, the $50 anus are are also a pretty solid
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. All right, let's get to the hotline as always. The number is
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 VERGE one one. The email is vergecast to The Verge dot com. We
Speaker 2:  love all of your questions. Please keep sending us all of your
Speaker 2:  wildest, weirdest questions about technology. Also in
Speaker 2:  particular, I'm really eager to start doing more like teeny
Speaker 2:  tiny tech mysteries. So if you have a weird tech problem that you can't solve
Speaker 2:  and we might be able to help with, let us know. This week we have a question
Speaker 2:  which seemed fitting about glasses.
Speaker 19:  Hey David, it's Ruby from the uk. I
Speaker 19:  have bad eyesight and I wear glasses all the time and it's getting to
Speaker 19:  the point where I really need new glasses, but I told myself I
Speaker 19:  wouldn't buy new frames unless they wear smart glasses.
Speaker 19:  I don't like meta. So those are outta the question, but I don't know if
Speaker 19:  it was you, but The Verge reviewed a pair of smart glasses called focals
Speaker 19:  by a company called North. It got bought by Google and they had a little
Speaker 19:  laser projector that just gave you a hu and from those reviews
Speaker 19:  it looked pretty cool. Do you think that's maybe something we might see
Speaker 19:  in the near future and maybe even an AI version of it? That's
Speaker 19:  not stupid. Thanks and take care.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so real quick, if you don't remember the North focals and you'd be
Speaker 2:  forgiven for not remembering the North Focals. Basically the way that they
Speaker 2:  worked was instead of being two screens in front of your eyes, there was
Speaker 2:  a little laser projector off to the right, I think
Speaker 2:  of the glasses. So it would project the laser onto this
Speaker 2:  little polymer in the middle of the right lens,
Speaker 2:  which would then reflect that light back into your eyes. So instead of looking
Speaker 2:  at a screen, you were getting what mounted to, I think it was a 300 pixel
Speaker 2:  by 300 pixel display kind of right in the middle of
Speaker 2:  your right eye. And you could see through it when it wasn't projecting, it
Speaker 2:  looked just like a little smudge on the lens itself. It was a very
Speaker 2:  clever system. North had a real problem making
Speaker 2:  these things work though for one, it's expensive technology, it's a startup.
Speaker 2:  They ended up trying to sell these things I think for a thousand dollars,
Speaker 2:  which most people are just not gonna spend a thousand dollars on a pair of
Speaker 2:  glasses. Google ended up buying North, I think mostly for the technology,
Speaker 2:  but obviously Google has a complicated relationship with smart
Speaker 2:  glasses all the way back to Google Glass. I do think the company is
Speaker 2:  committed to doing some kind of ar XR thing. The company keeps
Speaker 2:  teasing it and talking about it. There was that thing in the Project
Speaker 2:  ASRA video where You can see the glasses like it's, it's out there. Google
Speaker 2:  is still thinking about this stuff. But what North did was really
Speaker 2:  clever, honestly, and I'm sort of sad to have seen the company go, but it
Speaker 2:  was tough, right? Not only was it really expensive, but North famously had
Speaker 2:  trouble with people with longer eyelashes and evidently
Speaker 2:  the display struggled when people were wearing
Speaker 2:  mascara. So this stuff is hard is my point. It's hard
Speaker 2:  and it's expensive and there is just not a lot of progress
Speaker 2:  being made towards putting this kind of technology in something that looks
Speaker 2:  and feels and costs like a normal pair of glasses. All that
Speaker 2:  said, I do think something like the focals is
Speaker 2:  probably where we're headed in the immediate future. Like look, sure,
Speaker 2:  someday the whole vision pro Meta Quest thing might be the
Speaker 2:  future, but it's only gonna be the future when those things look like a pair
Speaker 2:  of glasses. And I think we're just a bunch of huge technical
Speaker 2:  innovations away from that being the case. So what we're gonna see
Speaker 2:  instead I think is something that feels more
Speaker 2:  like a heads up display, right? Something that projects little bits of information
Speaker 2:  at a time onto your face. And as we've been talking about this whole episode,
Speaker 2:  if you believe that chat and particular
Speaker 2:  voice in voice out chat with AI systems is going to be a key part
Speaker 2:  of how we talk to computers, something like that becomes really powerful,
Speaker 2:  right? It can display your text message and You can respond to it. It can
Speaker 2:  show you the answer to a question that you asked. It can show you the information
Speaker 2:  that you asked for. It becomes this really useful thing in a
Speaker 2:  way that even north five years ago was trying to
Speaker 2:  like awkwardly rewrite apps to make them make
Speaker 2:  sense on this tiny display in a way that was just really hard. Now we have
Speaker 2:  a confluence of things, whether it's voice or we've had
Speaker 2:  a lot of work with widgets on you know, lock screens and home screens of
Speaker 2:  phones. That stuff has also been transferred to smart watches
Speaker 2:  which have made a lot of progress in the last five years. Put all of that
Speaker 2:  together and You can sort of see how the interface for a pair of glasses
Speaker 2:  that is just listening to you talk maybe doing some gesture control.
Speaker 2:  Again, we have these new smart rings like the galaxy ring that are starting
Speaker 2:  to experiment with maybe You can use your fingers to control devices just
Speaker 2:  with your hands. Meta is also working on this kind of stuff. Mark Zuckerberg
Speaker 2:  even said that there is a new wearable that the company has been working
Speaker 2:  on that it's getting ready to release that is going to be a new way to control
Speaker 2:  gadgets. So again, all of this is just coming together. The
Speaker 2:  question is going to be can anyone make a product out of it? Can you
Speaker 2:  do North's thing where North also had a a little ring
Speaker 2:  joystick thing that was kind of neat but also kind of got in the way. Can
Speaker 2:  you do that well with a smart ring? Can you figure out the interface
Speaker 2:  in a way that is useful and will make people wanna spend the extra money
Speaker 2:  on it without being too much extra money to the point where people just don't
Speaker 2:  want it in addition to their regular pair of glasses? Can you make the battery
Speaker 2:  last long enough that it doesn't feel like I have to charge my glasses twice
Speaker 2:  a day because that's a terrible experience? And then I think there's the
Speaker 2:  biggest question, which is just that we haven't solved how any of this is
Speaker 2:  supposed to work. A Google executive a few years ago said to me that one
Speaker 2:  of the most challenging things about AR is figuring out kind
Speaker 2:  of the relative noise level of an AR system. And I mean noise
Speaker 2:  in the sense of like how in your face it is and involved
Speaker 2:  it is in your life, right? Sometimes you want lots of information, you want
Speaker 2:  it to be telling you what's going on around you, you want it to point you
Speaker 2:  to the coffee shop down the street or the cool place
Speaker 2:  that you totally should go or the fact that your friend is over there and
Speaker 2:  then other times you want it to just shut up and go away. And you want
Speaker 2:  all of that to happen automatically and seamlessly and without you having
Speaker 2:  to decide
Speaker 2:  we are as people and how we use technology and what we care about
Speaker 2:  and what we don't care about. And putting all those pieces together I think
Speaker 2:  is actually the hardest part of all of this. Because again, you have rings
Speaker 2:  which I think are doing interesting gesture and sensing stuff, you have other
Speaker 2:  devices doing that. There's we who knows, we might get like brain computer
Speaker 2:  interfaces soon enough. I think the glasses technology is getting
Speaker 2:  better pretty quickly. North's projector was not amazing
Speaker 2:  but it was pretty good and that was a while ago and frankly it's a bummer
Speaker 2:  that we haven't gotten to see five years of progress there. We also are seeing
Speaker 2:  companies like Meta really start to bet on the smart glasses space.
Speaker 2:  I think the idea that we were gonna get headsets and we were all gonna learn
Speaker 2:  how to live inside of headsets was just the wrong one. And I think even
Speaker 2:  the success that Meta has said it's seeing from the smart glasses is
Speaker 2:  proof that what we're doing is saying how do we
Speaker 2:  make glasses that look like glasses and work like glasses and feel like glasses?
Speaker 2:  And then how do we make them more useful over time? And I think that is a
Speaker 2:  really interesting road that is going to lead to interesting things fairly
Speaker 2:  quickly. So I would say to your question specifically, I think if you need
Speaker 2:  a pair of glasses today, you should just buy a pair of glasses. There's not
Speaker 2:  anything that is so smart and so good even at doing
Speaker 2:  one thing beyond being a pair of glasses that it feels worth making a
Speaker 2:  huge bet on. But it's kind of like the one after this one, right? Like
Speaker 2:  someday in, you know, a couple of years when you lose these glasses or
Speaker 2:  need to increase your prescription or they break or whatever, I think at
Speaker 2:  that point we might be somewhere where there is a heads up display
Speaker 2:  in your glasses that is pretty useful. It won't do everything. It won't
Speaker 2:  be a full on Metaverse AR experience
Speaker 2:  where You can like play games in the world around you. But it'll be something,
Speaker 2:  maybe it'll just show you your text messages, but that'll be something and
Speaker 2:  I think that'll be pretty cool. There are companies out there working on
Speaker 2:  this. I think Google has intimated that there's stuff going on. There's some
Speaker 2:  indication from reporting that we've seen from Mark Kerman at Bloomberg and
Speaker 2:  others that Apple is starting to really work