# Transcript
ID: 3f70480b-3a22-4e58-b8f4-07f5146cf0df
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/41114267863200268/3746629004976169122/s93290-US-4877s-1721383071.mp3
Description: Nilay, Alex, and David talk about what's happening on social media — and around the web — in the wake of the attempted assassination of Donald Trump. Then they talk about their early impression of Apple's public betas, from the redesigned homescreens to the iPad's fancy new math abilities. After that, it's time for a bunch of gadgets all asking the same idea: is this anything? Then it's off to the lightning round, filled with 4K streams and leaky infinity pools.
Speaker 5:  lightning round what I want and I put my name next to it in bold with great
Speaker 5:  enthusiasm. and it is one of those things, I love a thing that's a metaphor
Speaker 5:  for something. Yeah. But you don't know what, but it is for sure a metaphor.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like a vibe's a four. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's really good. Yeah, that's, that's right.
Speaker 3:  It's just like, oh, this story is the correct vibe for the, this moment of
Speaker 3:  America. Yeah. Alex Kranz is here.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I I, I don't own a house, but if I did, it wouldn't be that one for
Speaker 4:  a variety of reasons.
Speaker 3:  All right. There's a lot of talk about the Apple betas came out this week.
Speaker 3:  We've got a, what David is calling an, is this anything gadget bonanza,
Speaker 3:  and then we got the lightning round unsponsored. Mm. At this point,
Speaker 3:  someone should start a company called Unsponsored. Just putting that out.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's pretty good.
Speaker 3:  But we should start with what is arguably the biggest story in the world,
Speaker 3:  which is the attempted assassination of Donald Trump and then
Speaker 3:  the RNC in which Trump was nominated and announced JD Vance as
Speaker 3:  his running mate. The is the vice presidential nominee, and I wanna spend
Speaker 3:  a lot of time on this. It feels important to talk about. It is the biggest
Speaker 3:  story in the world, and there are lots of VERGE stories in this story. For
Speaker 3:  example, I think as we learn more about the would be assassin who
Speaker 3:  was 20 years old. It feels likely it is digital footprint will reveal a bunch,
Speaker 3:  and that means things like hacking his phone were immediately important.
Speaker 3:  We've talked a lot about cops trying to hack phones on the show and on The
Speaker 3:  Verge over the years, and they got into it almost immediately. And
Speaker 3:  that's because they've just gotten good at it. The FBI isn't running to Apple
Speaker 3:  to ask them to break the phone open. So there's that sort of stuff happening
Speaker 3:  as that investigation goes forward, more
Speaker 3:  immediately important in the context of The Verge and The Verge has,
Speaker 3:  is what happened to the social networks afterwards. We've talked a lot about
Speaker 3:  content moderation on the show and whether or not social networks have have
Speaker 3:  a duty to the truth. Mark Zuckerberg has famously said he doesn't want to
Speaker 3:  be the arbiter of truth and set up a weird fake Supreme court for content
Speaker 3:  moderation on Facebook platforms. We are at a place now
Speaker 3:  where they appear to have given up. Right. Like
Speaker 3:  you would put COVID. It's sort of the high point of content
Speaker 3:  moderation, controversies and discussion and interest
Speaker 3:  from the platforms.
Speaker 5:  Maybe not in terms of success, but certainly in terms of volume. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like it was, it was the moment everyone was most aggressively like on it
Speaker 5:  one way or another. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And whether, you know, like are you gonna amplify conspiracy theories? And
Speaker 3:  there was just a lot there that has resulted in major
Speaker 3:  lawsuits. And one of them just hit the Supreme Court and the Supreme Court
Speaker 3:  said no, the government's allowed to talk to the social networks. Like
Speaker 3:  all of that had happened, and it feels like it's in the past and
Speaker 3:  we've been sort of talking about it, but then the
Speaker 3:  shooting happened and you just saw in real time
Speaker 3:  the social networks, Twitter X, whatever it's called
Speaker 3:  threads. They were good at it for one second.
Speaker 3:  They were like, this thing happened and here's video of it,
Speaker 3:  and here's some photos of it, and here's everyone just reacting to it for
Speaker 3:  like one second. You could verify that a thing had happened and they
Speaker 3:  were ahead of the major news networks, which are very, very cautious in
Speaker 3:  breaking news events like that. So if you just wanted a shot of pure
Speaker 3:  adrenaline, they would give it to you.
Speaker 5:  Well, and this was actually an, an unusually perfect case in
Speaker 5:  that sense because you had a, a televised event, right? Like
Speaker 5:  the, he's, he's on stage talking as all of this is happening. Like
Speaker 5:  the person this is happening to is right there in front of a camera. You
Speaker 5:  have what turned out to be some like truly historic photographers out there
Speaker 5:  working, taking shots that ended up being really important really quickly.
Speaker 5:  And that stuff gets uploaded faster than ever. So we had this like primary
Speaker 5:  source material faster and more sort
Speaker 5:  of remarkably than almost anything I can ever remember. Like
Speaker 5:  the speed with which, what you would call, like the photo of the things
Speaker 5:  started. Yeah. Floating around the internet was just unbelievable to me.
Speaker 5:  It was like seconds. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And it just wa was there, and then you saw this sort of like weird,
Speaker 3:  everyone quoting the like CNN or New York Times headline that was more cautious
Speaker 3:  than the rush to judgment on the social networks and be like, why? This is
Speaker 3:  like, it's like the big networks are cautious. The the rigor
Speaker 3:  is the point. And like there's a gap here. And that gap
Speaker 3:  has only gotten wider, which is utterly fascinating to me.
Speaker 3:  There's no attempt to moderate
Speaker 3:  pictures of a shooting like a guy got shot and there's pictures
Speaker 3:  of it everywhere and there's no attempt to moderate it. On top of that,
Speaker 3:  there is just, I mean, an, an explosion of
Speaker 3:  conspiracy theories from everyone. E everyone
Speaker 3:  is a conspiracy theorist right now, and they're all just like flooding onto
Speaker 3:  these platforms, particularly X and there's no
Speaker 3:  attempt to slow it down or fact check it or anything like that. And You can
Speaker 3:  just see like, oh, the, the knob got turned. We're just not doing content
Speaker 3:  moderation anymore. Like we, we don't care about this. We're gonna do the
Speaker 3:  really bad stuff. You, you talk to people who are still working in the industry,
Speaker 3:  right? They're gonna continue to not, they're gonna continue working
Speaker 3:  against child sexual abuse material or just like
Speaker 3:  abject pornography and platforms that aren't supposed to have it. They will
Speaker 3:  all for, for forever and ever. Copyright infringement will
Speaker 3:  be a thing that the platforms care about, but this, they're just
Speaker 3:  like over it, right? The idea that harmful information can spread on social
Speaker 3:  networks and that the platforms of any responsibility,
Speaker 3:  it's gone. It, and it, it, i I think this one's a marker. Like, it feels
Speaker 3:  like a real marker to me that that's where the information environment is
Speaker 3:  now. And for all the other stuff we talk about, like AI or sludge or
Speaker 3:  fake photos. Yeah. It all happened immediately.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. After this event and nothing happened.
Speaker 5:  You know what I think a lot about in these events now is the, the sort of
Speaker 5:  public turn Mark Zuckerberg made over the last several years where
Speaker 5:  he went from being the guy who was talking really earnestly about
Speaker 5:  how hard meta and Facebook in particular was trying with content
Speaker 5:  moderation and saying things true things. Like, the
Speaker 5:  reason we get so much crap for this is because we're the ones trying the
Speaker 5:  hardest and the most transparently. Like, I think that's basically true.
Speaker 5:  And he even, he eventually was just like, you know what? This is actually
Speaker 5:  not worth it. Like, all I'm doing is signing myself up to get yelled at.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna go back to posting about new WhatsApp features and
Speaker 5:  cool stuff in the Metaverse, and I'm gonna go back to being the product guy
Speaker 5:  and Nick Clegg, who nobody cares about, gets to be the one who talks about
Speaker 5:  content moderation. And I think that is, to me, is so indicative of
Speaker 5:  how we've gotten to this place of like, it's somewhere
Speaker 5:  between like resignation and nihilism where there is a sense that
Speaker 5:  this isn't going to get better, so why even try
Speaker 5:  and what does better even look like? Because no one agrees on what it's supposed
Speaker 5:  to be anymore. So it just feels like at some point the only like rational
Speaker 5:  thing to do is just throw up your hands and be like, you know, whatever you
Speaker 5:  guys do whatever you want, I'm out. Yeah. and it really, really feels like
Speaker 5:  that's where everyone has landed.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's a value proposition, right? Like there, there is no value in,
Speaker 4:  in content moderation for at this point. And in maintaining that
Speaker 4:  theater of content moderation, the value has, has just vastly
Speaker 4:  diminished over the last few years. So it's like, okay, I don't need to do
Speaker 4:  it anymore. I can move on to other stuff. And we've seen that in a lot of
Speaker 4:  things, a lot of these kind of theatrical moments, particularly in Big Tech
Speaker 4:  where they're like, oh yeah, we, we, you know, we care about being good.
Speaker 4:  We care about doing all these things. They no longer have to, they realized
Speaker 4:  that actually doesn't net them as much as they need it. They thought it would.
Speaker 4:  And so they've just kind of said, nah, nevermind.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's just fascinating to me because, you know, the immediate reaction
Speaker 3:  from everyone is like, tone down the rhetoric, be good to each other. We're
Speaker 3:  all Americans. And then a day later, all of the social
Speaker 3:  platforms are flooded with conspiracy theories.
Speaker 3:  My favorite one is the shooter was in a video that
Speaker 3:  was an ad for BlackRock, which is a private equity company that is an, an
Speaker 3:  investor in like gun companies. And they did something at a school
Speaker 3:  and he was like in the background of the video that they did about the teacher
Speaker 3:  at the school. And so now there's a BlackRock conspiracy theory. Okay. And
Speaker 3:  it's like, even that is like fine,
Speaker 3:  fine, fine. You should be able to post that to social media. Like whatever.
Speaker 3:  You wanna have some wackadoo like idea. But you look at
Speaker 3:  Twitter and it's like, because of the volume and because Twitter
Speaker 3:  has driven away so many otherwise sane people or X has driven away so many
Speaker 3:  other, it's not just like sort of conventional wisdom, right? And it's like,
Speaker 3:  oh, this is the stuff that actually poisons the discourse. Right? This is
Speaker 3:  a thing that actually makes it harder to bring people together and actually
Speaker 3:  creates the social division. And the platforms have basically given up. You
Speaker 3:  can see it on TikTok too in a very different way, right? It's just people
Speaker 3:  yelling at each other all day about this and like insisting that one
Speaker 3:  side or the other has it for each other. And the platforms have basically
Speaker 3:  given up trying to stop it. And I, there's it's election
Speaker 3:  year, it's bound to be polarized. But that's, to me, that's the big VERGE
Speaker 3:  story here is there was a moment several years ago when the
Speaker 3:  platforms really wanted to, to like create healthy
Speaker 3:  conversations that was Twitter's metric and now they're over it,
Speaker 3:  you know? And like meta is like threads is a place for conversations. And
Speaker 3:  what that amounts to is people just asking questions
Speaker 3:  where they appear to be idiots so people will yell at them for engagement
Speaker 3:  all day long. Yep. Like everyone's like people on like you open threads and
Speaker 3:  like every third post is someone's like, I just took a bite of an orange
Speaker 3:  without taking the peel off. Did you know that that's bad? And it's like,
Speaker 3:  what the fuck?
Speaker 3:  Like truly, what are you talking about?
Speaker 5:  I, I posted on threads the other day that Amazon is a terrible website because
Speaker 5:  Amazon is a terrible website and I had a bunch of people accuse me of engagement
Speaker 5:  bait for it, which I really enjoyed. Yeah. It's the first time in a while
Speaker 5:  I've been accused of engagement bait and it, it made me very happy.
Speaker 3:  Threads is the first platform that has completely incentivized people from
Speaker 3:  asking questions because you, no matter what, you seem like
Speaker 3:  you're Jason clout. It's very good.
Speaker 5:  It's good stuff. But no, I think to your, to your point about the like
Speaker 5:  matching all of that sort of giving up on content
Speaker 5:  moderation with the fact that what, like the FBI
Speaker 5:  does immediately is try to get into the shooter's phone is like,
Speaker 5:  it, it's, it's both getting worse and higher stakes all the
Speaker 5:  time, right? Yeah. And so much of what we've been seeing over the last few
Speaker 5:  days is like Discord released a statement that
Speaker 5:  the shooter had a Discord account like that that is news
Speaker 5:  that he was on Discord. And there there's been this weird back and forth
Speaker 5:  on whether there was some kind of like,
Speaker 5:  not manifesto, but like hint as to what was coming on a Steam account that
Speaker 5:  seems like it was and it wasn't some, and so we're in this place where it's
Speaker 5:  like this stuff matters more than ever as they try to figure out what
Speaker 5:  happened. And yet the ability to figure out what is actually going
Speaker 5:  on feels like it's getting further and further away from us.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And especially if you're just a normal person who's just opening
Speaker 3:  an app on their phone, right? Yeah. So that's that We're gonna cover a lot
Speaker 3:  of that. It, it seems important. I'll give, I'll give you one
Speaker 3:  other example, which is just a very new example. These photos that we're
Speaker 3:  all talking about, those photos were taken by professional photographers
Speaker 3:  who were in the pit to get paid to do a job with very expensive cameras.
Speaker 3:  People have argue, started arguing with the settings of the cameras, by the
Speaker 3:  way, which is very nerdy I thing to do online. Those
Speaker 3:  photos are owned. They have, you know, they're copyrighted image images.
Speaker 3:  One of them is owned by the New York Times. I think the other one's owned
Speaker 3:  by the, the ap. They're everywhere. They're just straight
Speaker 3:  copyright infringement. All the merch. You're seeing the hats with the photos
Speaker 3:  on them. It's a straightforward copyright infringement. The photo
Speaker 3:  agencies and the Times and all those other companies, they're gonna have
Speaker 3:  to issue a bunch of take downs. It, we, we went out and asked them
Speaker 3:  and basically all of them were like, we are evaluating our options. Weird,
Speaker 3:  weird. Like that photo feels like it immediately belongs to the world, right?
Speaker 3:  but it super doesn't Well, and
Speaker 5:  In part it feels that way because all of these other machines moves so much
Speaker 5:  faster than the lawyers for those news organizations, right? Like
Speaker 5:  the, the Etsy's popular page was filled with
Speaker 5:  that kind of merch that you're talking about. Yeah. Like Amazon has a thing
Speaker 5:  that You can print on demand. Like literally all you have to do is upload
Speaker 5:  a photo to Amazon and boom, you're selling merch. Like, it,
Speaker 5:  it is crazy how quick, how quickly that stuff is able to happen now.
Speaker 5:  And it's happening faster in every other part of the system
Speaker 5:  than like within these organizations that are actually trying to figure out
Speaker 5:  what to do about it. And so they all figure, you know, I'm gonna go, I'm
Speaker 5:  gonna make my money. I'm gonna sell my T-shirts and I'm gonna get out before
Speaker 5:  anybody else has even like figured out what their first move is.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And I would just wrap this up. We spent a lot of time talking to AI
Speaker 3:  and boy do I get the emails when we talk about AI and hint even a little
Speaker 3:  bit that AI might be useful or interesting, right? That it's stealing work.
Speaker 3:  That it's stealing creativity. If you have those feelings about the AI companies
Speaker 3:  and You can and should, I don't, I won't stop you.
Speaker 3:  How do you feel about someone whose job it is to stand in a place where you
Speaker 3:  might get shot at, take some of the most historic photos in the world and
Speaker 3:  immediately watch that stuff get stolen by very opportunistic
Speaker 3:  merch vendors on Amazon. Is that bad? Like May,
Speaker 3:  maybe, but I don't think anybody has the same immediate reaction to
Speaker 3:  it the way that I know they do. We talk about opening ai totally. Like
Speaker 3:  there's something there that's weird. We, we spend a lot of time talking
Speaker 3:  about how copy law is the only functional regulation in the internet. 'cause
Speaker 3:  it's effectively a speech regulation and you're about to see it
Speaker 3:  used as in a way that feels very much like a speech regulation.
Speaker 3:  You wanna sell a hat with this photo on it. Some photo agency is gonna come
Speaker 3:  and tell you that you can't. And like we reckoning
Speaker 3:  with that is it's right next to the content moderation question.
Speaker 3:  'cause a lot of people are gonna lose their minds 'cause they feel like that
Speaker 3:  photo belongs to the world or those photos belong to the world. Anyway, lots
Speaker 3:  of urge stories there. I'm confident we co you remember the Shepherd
Speaker 3:  fairy picture of Obama? We covered the copyright case around that
Speaker 3:  photo of Obama for like 10 years and we we did a story and it like six
Speaker 3:  months ago, it's gonna be that again. Yeah, right. Just like what does it
Speaker 3:  mean for these images to exist on the internet in the way they do? And
Speaker 3:  who gets to, who gets to make money on them? It's like kind of one question.
Speaker 3:  And the second question is like, that is content moderation and the content
Speaker 3:  moderation apparatus of our information environment is, it's in a,
Speaker 3:  I think as Alex was saying, like in a pretty nihilistic space. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like, like you have to make sure there's not the worst thing. You
Speaker 3:  clear that bar. It's like a free for all. Yep. All right. So
Speaker 3:  that is that event. Immediately thereafter, there was a
Speaker 3:  Republican national convention this week. It was not a quiet week for politic
Speaker 3:  politics in America. President Biden has covid. It's like chill times all
Speaker 3:  around. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Not a quiet week by any means. My instruction, the only news on the RC that's
Speaker 3:  worth talking about is Trump picked JD Vance, who's center from Ohio is his
Speaker 3:  running mate, his vice presidential nominee. And then a million people
Speaker 3:  in tech came out in support of Trump. Elon Musk,
Speaker 3:  the Andreessen Horowitz partners, mark Andreessen, Ben Horowitz, just like
Speaker 3:  down every crypto bro You can think of is pro-Trump. They love JD
Speaker 3:  Vance, who was a venture capitalist, took a lot of money from Peter
Speaker 3:  Thiel over the years. There's just a reactionary right wing
Speaker 3:  crypto bro
Speaker 3:  situation there. There it is. We will cover it
Speaker 3:  more. I don't, we don't wanna talk about, about it in the Vergecast. Now
Speaker 3:  I wanna make sure we do some like reporting on it. Yeah. But JD Vance is
Speaker 3:  a really interesting character. And I, I don't mean that in the, like
Speaker 3:  you should read his book, which is bad. I mean that in the, it's
Speaker 3:  it's, it's not good. And the movie's worse. I mean that in the,
Speaker 3:  the malleability of his positions is really interesting. His relationship
Speaker 3:  to the power of Big Tech is
Speaker 3:  interesting. He was just at a conference that r and Lauren Finer was at
Speaker 3:  called Remedy Fest, where he said, I think Lena Kahn's doing a good job.
Speaker 3:  Why does he think Lena Kahn's doing a good job? Because he thinks they should
Speaker 3:  break up Google. Why does he wanna break up Google so he can push weird right
Speaker 3:  wing conspiracies on the internet. Like you, it, you start at, oh, we agree,
Speaker 3:  and then you like drill down and it's like, oh, the,
Speaker 3:  the flow of information is not going the way that some of these people
Speaker 3:  want. So we will use the power of the state to like
Speaker 3:  break these companies up. And then you just like end up in this is like total
Speaker 3:  horseshoe theory, strange bedfellows moment. So we're gonna cover a lot of
Speaker 3:  that. I just warning the listener like it's
Speaker 3:  coming because it's so, it's so much, there's so much weird
Speaker 3:  Mark Andreessen Peter Thiel crypto tech money
Speaker 3:  now involved in this presidential election that it's impossible
Speaker 3:  for us not to cover
Speaker 4:  It. Yeah. Because Peter Thiel famously stayed out of the last one, right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Well I mean he said he was
Speaker 4:  He said he would. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It's outta control. All right. I just, you know,
Speaker 3:  I'm like a cranky gen Xer You can imagine how I feel about this entire situation,
Speaker 3:  but here it is. Anyway, iOS 18 betas,
Speaker 4:  They're out. They're here. They're out.
Speaker 3:  No,
Speaker 4:  David's been checking a bunch of them out. Like David, you, you risked your
Speaker 4:  phone. You, you took the hit for the rest of us. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I started with the iPad because I was like, that's safe. It's just
Speaker 5:  an iPad. I have thousands of them what could possibly go wrong?
Speaker 5:  And now somehow I'm running iPad OS 18 iOS 18
Speaker 5:  macOS Sequoia and the new TV o s
Speaker 5:  like how is what, how is this my life? Everything is broken. My batteries
Speaker 5:  have just absolutely gone to hell. But I get to use the cool new stuff.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's fine. It's a trade. Yeah. I'll say the single
Speaker 5:  most important thing that has happened to me in my technology life this year,
Speaker 5:  I'm not exaggerating, is having RCS on the iPhone.
Speaker 4:  Well, it's like saving your marriage, right?
Speaker 5:  Like, like literally my, my wife uses an Android
Speaker 5:  phone. She's a pixel row for life.
Speaker 5:  And steadfastly refuses to understand that
Speaker 5:  when she sends me a video, it, it looks like a potato every
Speaker 5:  single time. So like what will happen is the, the woman who runs our daycare
Speaker 5:  will send Anna a adorable video of my child and Anna will forward it to me.
Speaker 5:  And I literally can't see it because it just, it's just eight
Speaker 5:  pixels stacked that sort of looks like blonde hair. Like that's just all,
Speaker 5:  it's Yeah. But now I have RCS, the photos are
Speaker 5:  big, the videos are big, like it works correctly. I, I don't have to like
Speaker 5:  make every make her send me Google photos links anymore. It's the best.
Speaker 5:  And it's like a little wonky and it falls back to SMS too often. It's
Speaker 5:  getting better as time goes on. I think like the networks and the carriers
Speaker 5:  are all kind of figuring it out. But RCS on, on
Speaker 5:  iPhone like huge win. Yeah. And to all the people who have been
Speaker 5:  in my mentions telling me like, oh, you silly Americans, we all use
Speaker 5:  WhatsApp. First of all, congratulations. Like, I don't know what to tell
Speaker 5:  you. Great job. Second of all, making people switch messaging apps is
Speaker 5:  impossible. Yeah. It's just, I don't care what messaging app you use, try
Speaker 5:  your best to get all your friends and family to use a different one. Just,
Speaker 5:  just try best of luck. It's not gonna work no matter what it is that you
Speaker 5:  use. And so for us here in the good old
Speaker 5:  US of A, we're stuck with text messaging. So anything that makes text
Speaker 5:  messaging slightly better, humongous victory.
Speaker 3:  I'm excited for this to roll out wide and for people to,
Speaker 3:  how do I put this? I'm excited to see if when RCS rolls out wide with iOS
Speaker 3:  18, if the green bubble stigma reduces. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I actually think it's going to, I really do. You I do because the, the, the
Speaker 5:  main things that it improves are, what I
Speaker 5:  haven't done is, is like really stress test group chats with this. So I,
Speaker 5:  that is like the main problem, right? So I'll have to see how that does.
Speaker 5:  But the ability to get read receipts
Speaker 5:  and the ability to send high res images and videos and
Speaker 5:  the typing indicators, those are like the three things that immediately
Speaker 5:  my messaging system with my wife got better. Also, the tap
Speaker 5:  backs work a little better, but now that You can use any emoji, it's still
Speaker 5:  kind of wonky on the Android side because if you'd use one that it
Speaker 5:  doesn't recognize it just punts it through as a text message. But I,
Speaker 5:  it's like, it's not all the way better. And there's all the new iMessage
Speaker 5:  stuff, the like animations and the text decorations and all that that You
Speaker 5:  can do that you still can't do in Android. But it's much closer. And
Speaker 5:  I think it's like, it's not gonna get all the way better, but I think it's
Speaker 5:  gonna get a little better.
Speaker 3:  Is this gonna work in messages on a Mac?
Speaker 5:  Yes. I have been RC sing from my Mac, but only because it
Speaker 5:  linked to your phone's just forwarding to your phone. Does it,
Speaker 4:  It break as often as like, I feel like when you're just text
Speaker 4:  messaging, it breaks all the time.
Speaker 5:  It, it was actually worse at first. Like
Speaker 5:  when I first downloaded all the betas, it was really slow and was occasionally
Speaker 5:  just failing to send messages at all. But in the last I would say
Speaker 5:  week it's been super stable. So I, I have, I have high hopes
Speaker 5:  for where this is gonna land, but it was definitely wonky at first.
Speaker 3:  Alright. I, there's, we won't have to do endless follow up once this hits
Speaker 3:  wide if people like it. Yeah. Even try the
Speaker 3:  Phone mirroring on the Mac too. That seems amazing.
Speaker 5:  It is. Oh boy. It is. and it isn't, but it is because it works, right? It's
Speaker 5:  like, it's like continuity camera in the sense that like, it just, it just
Speaker 5:  mostly does the thing and every once in a while it doesn't, for some indiscernible
Speaker 5:  reason, like Liam, our producer, we were on a call the other day and he just
Speaker 5:  for the whole call couldn't get continuity camera to work. And then like
Speaker 5:  the next time you tried it works. And phone mirroring is a little like that.
Speaker 5:  But the biggest problem is you can't change the size of the
Speaker 5:  window. So if you're on a laptop screen, it shows up like relatively close
Speaker 5:  to kind of real size of your iPhone, which I think is what they were going
Speaker 5:  for. But if you're on a big densely pixel display, it shows up
Speaker 5:  teeny tiny. It's like I'm on, I'm on a pretty, I'm on a 27 inch screen
Speaker 5:  here and the iPhone on my screen is like half the size of my actual
Speaker 5:  iPhone and there's nothing I can do about it. and it drives me nuts.
Speaker 3:  That is great. I'm sorry. That's that's great.
Speaker 3:  The, and it is like, I know that's like a beta bug. Like they have to know
Speaker 3:  and they'll do something, but it's
Speaker 5:  Actually just resize the window. It's just hilarious. We solved, it's such
Speaker 5:  a stage manager problem where they're like, what if we give you a new way
Speaker 5:  to do wind? Like, no, let me drag the corner of my window to make it bigger.
Speaker 5:  This is not complicated.
Speaker 3:  It's very good. Does it? It's you don't have a touchscreen on a max. So it
Speaker 3:  does it like do the,
Speaker 5:  If you have the magic mouse or the magic track pad, it's great.
Speaker 5:  It just like maps all the gestures the same way you swipe and you scroll
Speaker 5:  and everything else on a, I use a Logitech mouse
Speaker 5:  and it's basically unusable. You, you like click on the bar at the bottom
Speaker 5:  to go to the home screen. Some things will scroll, some things don't scroll,
Speaker 5:  you can't scroll left and right. Like so on Instagram, if there's a gallery,
Speaker 5:  I just can't do it.
Speaker 5:  I think some of these things will probably get better over time. I also think
Speaker 5:  Apple, it's, it's really, it's like on a laptop it's solid, right? Because
Speaker 5:  you, you have the track pad, you have the gestures. That all works fine,
Speaker 5:  but Apple is just not interested in you if you don't use
Speaker 5:  exclusively Apple gear. And so I think this is like
Speaker 5:  for, for all of us Logitech fans out there, this is gonna be problematic.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I was gonna say this is, this is kind of common for all Apple integrations
Speaker 4:  on the computer. You're just like, okay, cool. I can't do any of this unless
Speaker 4:  I buy a magic track pad and then I have to use that instead of a really good
Speaker 4:  mouse. I don't want to Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Pretty much. I hate the magic track pad. Like I know there are a lot of people
Speaker 5:  out there who really like it. I hate it. Yeah. Like I get the
Speaker 5:  idea of it, but because it's so far away from the screen, it's so divorced
Speaker 5:  from what's actually going on that it feels like it's trying way too hard
Speaker 5:  and it just, it feels bad at the angle. My hands are at all the time. I
Speaker 4:  Hate it. No, IIII can't stand it. I, that's why I use a track ball. I, because
Speaker 4:  the track ball You can sometimes set like a key. So You can still get a lot
Speaker 4:  of the gestures in by like hitting a key and using the ball. That's cool.
Speaker 4:  But with the regular mouse, you're just like, well, I guess I don't, I don't
Speaker 4:  horizontal scroll ever again. Cool.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Can't do it. I'm out.
Speaker 3:  I can't wait to try this. A tiny little phone monkeying with a mouse. Oh,
Speaker 3:  it's
Speaker 5:  Gonna be great. Just truly for me, I suspect there are gonna be lots of little
Speaker 5:  things people do with it. Like for me, like the one I wrote about in the
Speaker 5:  story is my thermostat only works as a mobile app. So just being a, to
Speaker 5:  like fire that up from my laptop is really handy without getting my phone
Speaker 5:  outta my bag or whatever. But truly for me, it's just
Speaker 5:  gonna be a way to drag and drop things from my computer to my phone and vice
Speaker 5:  versa. Like it just solves the airplay problem of, I have a photo
Speaker 5:  here and I need it to be over here. And it's, it's easier and faster
Speaker 5:  and that feature's not out yet, but it's apparently coming and just as a
Speaker 5:  drag and drop machine, I'm very excited about it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, you gotta get Home Bridge, dude. No, I'm Tony, you need a little
Speaker 3:  raspberry pie that just bridges your thermostat into home Kit. You'd
Speaker 4:  Be great. Then you get home assistance to also be a bridge into
Speaker 4:  home kit.
Speaker 3:  We could do this for you. The Alex and I are waiting.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, we're here, we're coming down.
Speaker 3:  We can put a little Tamagotchi home bridge server in your house. So
Speaker 5:  You have to care for I'm, I'm stuck at trying to get a lock for my front
Speaker 5:  door that I can open with my fingerprint. And even that Anna's like, no,
Speaker 5:  that's why Keys are great. She's not wrong. Keys are great. Like
Speaker 5:  somebody
Speaker 4:  Like Hlu on it and you're just like, against it. Don't get in my house ever
Speaker 4:  again. Exactly.
Speaker 3:  Once you get to You can unlock this door by beeping your phone at it.
Speaker 3:  Then the flip is my wife is like, I don't
Speaker 3:  ever wanna see again a key. I don't ever wanna see a key again in my life.
Speaker 3:  Don't you dare.
Speaker 3:  That's not, that's not a choice.
Speaker 5:  I need that. We need Becky and Anna to hang out. Can we, can we make this
Speaker 5:  happen?
Speaker 3:  We, we were test driving a rivian. So next week on decoder there, it's a
Speaker 3:  co rivian rj sc cr and so we had Rivian to test drive and
Speaker 3:  they didn't give us the keys. Rivian do come with a regular key fob, but
Speaker 3:  they just gave us the cards and I showed them to, I was like, these are the
Speaker 3:  keys. And she was like, no, they're not.
Speaker 4:  Just
Speaker 3:  Reject it. She was just like, I'm never gonna drive that card. Like, no
Speaker 3:  thanks. She's like, I don't wanna know anything about that at all. Like
Speaker 3:  0% interest in your dumb key cards.
Speaker 3:  All right. We gotta talk about the biggest, the biggest thing in the beta,
Speaker 3:  which is a calculator in the iPad.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That that is it. That's
Speaker 3:  It. It's, I mean when I think about wwdc, like what did they announce? Some
Speaker 3:  bullshit and then a calculator for the,
Speaker 5:  That's basically right.
Speaker 4:  Change your life. Is it like a whole new world?
Speaker 5:  No, I, I confess I'm slightly disappointed by the whole, you,
Speaker 3:  You haven't been doing like, like high school algebra this whole time. Wow.
Speaker 3:  So
Speaker 5:  I think Apple really
Speaker 5:  thinks that if you're like a graduate
Speaker 5:  student studying mathematics, that you're gonna love this. And I think
Speaker 5:  Apple also thinks there's like tens of millions of those people in the world
Speaker 5:  and they're wrong on both counts. But the, the weird thing is, so like
Speaker 5:  the calculator app is fine, right? It's a calculator app. And I think it's
Speaker 5:  so funny that Apple is like, we wanted to really take the time to get this
Speaker 5:  right. It's like, no dude, you shipped the calculator app and then you also
Speaker 5:  made another feature. Like you could have just shipped the calculator app.
Speaker 5:  It's just the calculator app with bigger buttons. I don't know, I don't know
Speaker 5:  how to be clearer about that. That's what it is. But the cool thing is,
Speaker 5:  is math notes, right? And it's like, that is both, it's the thing
Speaker 5:  inside of notes where You can, You can hand write stuff and it'll do the
Speaker 5:  equations for you. And that thing is incredible when
Speaker 5:  it works, which is a lot. But also missing some sort of obvious
Speaker 5:  stuff. Like you write a list of numbers and then you draw a line underneath
Speaker 5:  and it'll automatically sum those numbers up for you, right? And then You
Speaker 5:  can actually tap on one of the numbers and, and drag a slider to make the
Speaker 5:  number go up and down. Super cool. and it attempts to do it in your
Speaker 5:  handwriting, which failed spectacularly for me. But I think that's just because
Speaker 5:  my handwriting is so bad, it's like borderline unreadable. I've talked to
Speaker 5:  some other people with pretty good handwriting and they've said it works
Speaker 5:  much better. So your mileage I think will vary depending on your handwriting.
Speaker 5:  But there's just little things. So, right, so like, one of the use cases
Speaker 5:  I've heard a bunch is like, you're, you're totaling up expenses for
Speaker 5:  a weekend, right? I'm in the middle of planning vacation and we're trying
Speaker 5:  to like total how much everything is gonna cost. So you write a bunch of
Speaker 5:  numbers down, it'll total 'em all up for you. But then if you go
Speaker 5:  next to it and you write like food colon next to the, you know,
Speaker 5:  $225, the whole thing falls apart. It just like
Speaker 5:  doesn't understand what your equation is anymore. and it won't total anything
Speaker 5:  up for you. So it's like you have to, you have to operate under these very
Speaker 5:  like, specific confines of what it understands as an equation.
Speaker 5:  and it's awesome. And as long as you do that. So this is what I mean by like
Speaker 5:  graduate math, right? Like if you're sitting there doing math problems as
Speaker 5:  math problems, it's awesome, awesome. and it works really well. But if you're
Speaker 5:  like a person taking notes and you want to do math inside of them,
Speaker 5:  it doesn't work quite as well. Mm. Does that make sense?
Speaker 4:  So it's for like just kids who have homework,
Speaker 5:  It's for doing math. Like I, it's like that really is what it is. It's like
Speaker 5:  what I want it to be is like do the math inside of my notes
Speaker 5:  as I take notes. and it is not for that, it's for doing math problems.
Speaker 4:  Do you think that the iPad Pro is now gonna become
Speaker 4:  two like mathematicians and scientists, what the iPad Mini was to
Speaker 4:  pilots?
Speaker 5:  I need to, I need to write this story. I'm so convinced that this
Speaker 5:  pilot thing is a lie
Speaker 3:  And
Speaker 5:  I have no evidence for this, but
Speaker 3:  I'm,
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm so sure that like three Delta Pilots got iPad
Speaker 5:  Minis and then Apple was like, yes, this is it.
Speaker 3:  And
Speaker 5:  It is only time I fly. They're still bringing on briefcase full of paperwork.
Speaker 5:  Like if this got replaced by iPads, I don't know where it is.
Speaker 5:  But. anyway, all that aside, I do think Apple really, really, really, really
Speaker 5:  wants the iPad to be an education device. Like I think the way that a, a
Speaker 5:  whole generation grew up with Max in the classroom
Speaker 5:  and basically the generations recently have grown up with Chromebooks. Apple
Speaker 5:  is like desperate for that thing to be iPads. And I think it sees the pencil
Speaker 5:  in particular as a way to get there. I don't
Speaker 5:  necessarily know if it's gonna work. I'm also not the Target demo, so I don't
Speaker 5:  know. Yeah. But like it's very clear that that is like, even, even
Speaker 5:  going back and looking at the demos, they're, they're doing really sophisticated
Speaker 5:  math, like not the kind of thing that a normal person does in their day-to-Day
Speaker 5:  life. And I think for the sophisticated stuff, it, it works better than for
Speaker 5:  just like trying to make sense of my notes.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna miss Texas Instruments when the TI 83 gets killed by the iPad Pro,
Speaker 3:  There's a store in my little town. I'm not sure if they
Speaker 3:  make any money selling anything other than T 80 threes to the high schoolers.
Speaker 3:  Like they just have a wall of T 80 threes and then all the high schoolers
Speaker 3:  in town go to that store to buy their TA 83. And I, it's just
Speaker 3:  so confusing. The whole thing is confusing to me. Especially because
Speaker 3:  when I was in high school 20 years ago, we were using
Speaker 3:  T 80 threes. Yeah. 25 years ago we were using
Speaker 5:  Is that the most enduring technology like it might be of the last two
Speaker 5:  decades? Might
Speaker 4:  Be. I feel like it is.
Speaker 3:  Here's what I learned about the TI 82. The 83 is different. The
Speaker 3:  case of a T 82, the Shell was exactly
Speaker 3:  the right size to fit a game boy pocket. So You
Speaker 3:  can just slide a game boy pocket up into that shell.
Speaker 3:  And the thing that we had to figure out was how to hide the sound. The game
Speaker 3:  boy, you know, ding your
Speaker 5:  Teacher's like, gosh, Neil is really doing some calculations over
Speaker 3:  There. We were
Speaker 4:  Furiously calculating,
Speaker 3:  Dude, you were just fully playing Game boy in the back of that.
Speaker 5:  He's, he's math and so hard. His parents are gonna be so proud.
Speaker 3:  But the problem, you had to turn it on before, before he walked in.
Speaker 3:  'cause you can't shut off the startup hep of a game Boy Pocket.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Ding.
Speaker 3:  Definitely not caught at least once.
Speaker 3:  All right. Two other Apple things I wanna talk about. One very, very funny.
Speaker 3:  Apple has partnered with Taboola to put ads in Apple News. You don't know
Speaker 3:  what Taboola is, except you obviously do. It's the Trump box provider on
Speaker 3:  every website in the world, including our own. We don't, we don't like it.
Speaker 3:  But you know, we don't work for free. So there's some Taboola ads at the
Speaker 3:  bottom of our pages that make our company some money and then they pay the
Speaker 3:  bills. It's famously the belly fat ads, right? Like for years. Yeah. That
Speaker 3:  was who was serving the belly fats. And we've written stories about the belly
Speaker 3:  fat ads. I I think it was Caitlin Tiffany wrote a story for us that like
Speaker 3:  chased all the way down what the one weird vegetable is. Oh no way.
Speaker 3:  It's corn.
Speaker 3:  It's nonsensical. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  All bad. But Apple doesn't wanna do ads.
Speaker 3:  They had a partnership with NBC to sell ads in Apple News. It didn't work.
Speaker 3:  I don't think they got the scale. And now they have this partnership with
Speaker 3:  Tabula and it's like, what, what kind of ads are we gonna see in Apple News
Speaker 3:  now? And then you look in Tabula is actually a huge company.
Speaker 3:  Like massive company. 'cause they just put the garbage across
Speaker 3:  the entire web. And wait, did Tabula buy Outbrain the other chum box
Speaker 3:  provider? Or was it vice versa? No, it didn't happen. It got, it got broken.
Speaker 3:  Oh, it was, it was so big it wasn't allowed. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  The FTC said no, only we must have competition in the
Speaker 4:  chum box industry.
Speaker 3:  I can't believe we didn't do features on chum box warfare. Oh my God.
Speaker 3:  Anyhow. Very bad. One of the least, one
Speaker 3:  of the least on-brand deals in Apple history. Yeah. And I
Speaker 3:  think they're gonna, I think they're gonna keep it. 'cause what are you gonna
Speaker 3:  do? I think Apple's at the, what you gonna do phase of this where
Speaker 3:  they were just like, yeah, whatever. It's money. What, what are you, what
Speaker 3:  are you gonna do? You're gonna go somewhere else. You're gonna not read Apple
Speaker 3:  News publishers are gonna, you're gonna respond to
Speaker 3:  chum boxes and Apple. Well look at your sites. And I I think they're
Speaker 3:  just gonna take the money. I I there's no way that unless it's like
Speaker 3:  egregiously bad, which with Tabula it could be egregiously bad. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I dunno. Just a weird deal for them all the way around. Like people reacted
Speaker 3:  to it so negatively and I don't think they give a shit. Yeah, well I
Speaker 4:  Think that's right. It's just Apple being a content creator, right?
Speaker 4:  Like, like they're, they're in the, the, the industry of content now in a
Speaker 4:  way they haven't been in for A long time. And this is just like
Speaker 4:  finalizing the form for that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's just, if you think about Apple's pitch to everyone,
Speaker 4:  This is not it. This is like
Speaker 3:  Right. It's like premium experience. It's,
Speaker 3:  this is trusted publishers. It's not just garbage and then, or
Speaker 3:  Tabula ads. Yeah. I mean this is what, this is what endlessly chasing
Speaker 3:  services revenue eventually leads you to,
Speaker 5:  Right? Yeah. Like, it, it just, it just gets uglier and uglier as time
Speaker 5:  goes on because you have to keep finding ways to turn pennies
Speaker 5:  into dollars and turn free things into pennies. And
Speaker 5:  it's, it sucks And like it's, this is gonna go in the news app, it's gonna
Speaker 5:  go in the stocks app. Like Apple has gotten
Speaker 5:  slowly sort of frog boilingly aggressive
Speaker 5:  about advertising all over iOS. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  this just feels like, it feels like it's about, this will not be the last
Speaker 5:  thing we see from Apple with ugly ads, I don't think. But
Speaker 4:  But don't worry David, because in just seven days you two can
Speaker 4:  lose seven inches off your waistline.
Speaker 3:  But not if you eat corn,
Speaker 4:  Stay away from corn, the
Speaker 3:  Get this great vegetable you, you have to avoid. Avoid. Why don't we hawk
Speaker 3:  supplements? We could all, we could be doing the show in a boat. The other
Speaker 3:  piece of Apple News much more. I I don't think we're ever gonna hawk
Speaker 3:  supplements. Look, I I, you all know that I want a boat, but there's, there's
Speaker 3:  a line and that's it.
Speaker 3:  The lightning round remains unsponsored. I'll just put one after.
Speaker 5:  If you go buy Eli a boat called supplements though, that's pretty funny.
Speaker 5:  And I'll allow that
Speaker 4:  Still on the table. That's still on the table.
Speaker 3:  And there's one last piece. Apple I think is really interesting and sort
Speaker 3:  of like in a tangential way related, which
Speaker 3:  is the sort of competitive pressure put on the app store
Speaker 3:  by the DMA and the eu. And by emulators means that Apple
Speaker 3:  has now approved the first like nineties
Speaker 3:  PC emulator for iOS. So it can, it's it's
Speaker 3:  U-T-M-S-C. It can run Windows XP that looks
Speaker 3:  like Windows xp, Mac Stein and, and Linux. If you
Speaker 3:  wanna run Linux on your phone, which I think you do,
Speaker 3:  this was, they rejected it, it was gonna go into alt store
Speaker 3:  and then Apple approved it. And You can see just
Speaker 3:  that competitive dynamic occurring where they do not
Speaker 3:  want the other store to be good. Yep. So they're loosening
Speaker 3:  the rules of their own store over and over again. And that
Speaker 3:  competition is working. It
Speaker 4:  Rules,
Speaker 5:  I think it was ri test it who, who runs alt store and
Speaker 5:  does Delta and has been on this show a couple of times. I think it was him
Speaker 5:  that posted, basically it turns out the best way to get your app onto the
Speaker 5:  app store is to is to threaten to be on alt store.
Speaker 4:  That's exactly, yeah. He did it.
Speaker 5:  It it's true. Like it is, it is real that like any,
Speaker 5:  it is increasingly clear that if you want to get something onto an iPhone,
Speaker 5:  there are going to be other ways to do it. And Apple is so desperate to keep
Speaker 5:  you in the app store that it will bend its rules in any direction. It has
Speaker 5:  to to keep you there. I believe I owe somebody some money because
Speaker 5:  I said on this show not that long ago, I would be shocked if we got a
Speaker 5:  full PC emulator because Apple's rules
Speaker 5:  have been very clear that it is a, it is like, it's it's for retro games,
Speaker 5:  right? Like that was clearly what Apple wanted these things to be for. So
Speaker 5:  this strikes me as yet another goalpost move that
Speaker 5:  I didn't even expect. No. For what Apple will allow.
Speaker 4:  Is it, is it a, is it a PC emulator? It's, it's xp.
Speaker 5:  Well, so UTM will let you emulate all the way up through Windows 11. Okay.
Speaker 5:  So I, I don't, I don't, I have not tried it in the app so I don't
Speaker 5:  actually know what's possible. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But like we Davis was trying out XP and it took him like two hours
Speaker 4:  to install it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  These things are not easy, but like it, it'll You can emulate it an X 86
Speaker 5:  pc. Like I think with some work there's
Speaker 5:  probably a lot more You can do here than gets credit for. Also you could
Speaker 5:  emulate XP and then emulate a Windows 11
Speaker 5:  computer with an emulator on Windows XP and just, just turtles all the way
Speaker 5:  down this bitch. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yes. Hell yes.
Speaker 3:  So I think it's so there's a reason they've not wanted like general purpose
Speaker 3:  computer emulators 'cause they don't want people to run apps on them,
Speaker 3:  right. Like that. It's a big complicated loophole. But
Speaker 3:  it's a loophole, right? Yeah. You, you put a general purpose PC emulator
Speaker 3:  on the phone and then anyone can just run whatever software they want without
Speaker 3:  paying Apple 30%. Yep. Not a loophole that Apple will allow. But
Speaker 3:  now they've allowed it. And what's fascinating to me about this is like maybe
Speaker 3:  on the phone this isn't such a big deal 'cause whatever, it's a phone,
Speaker 3:  an iPad running Macs nine or even
Speaker 3:  Windows XP is like, wait, does this rule?
Speaker 3:  Like is that I did a lot of work in Macs nine. I like
Speaker 3:  many things happened in my life in the context of Macs nine.
Speaker 3:  Like yeah, I'll, I'll just run Mac West nine in my head all day. It has
Speaker 3:  better multitasking the iPad does today.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's real.
Speaker 4:  And more customization too.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The apps me the just quit in the background on you all the time in
Speaker 3:  Mac West nine Windows XP actually has
Speaker 3:  technically more advanced multitasking than macOS nine.
Speaker 3:  So it's just like you just like find yourself running in this circle where
Speaker 3:  you're like, wait, does the window management and multitasking of an emulated
Speaker 3:  operating system from 20 years ago, is that a better iPad experience?
Speaker 5:  I mean it honestly might be. Yeah. Do you think we're gonna get to the point
Speaker 5:  where You can emulate a Mac on your iPhone and then
Speaker 5:  mirror your phone to that Mac that's being emulated on your iPhone and then
Speaker 5:  use that phone?
Speaker 4:  God, I hope so.
Speaker 5:  That's the dream right there. That's
Speaker 4:  The dream. Yes.
Speaker 5:  I wanna use my phone three level steam on my phone.
Speaker 5:  That's what I'm going for. I
Speaker 4:  Think you just invented Atrix, the Motorola Atrix.
Speaker 3:  Oh man. The thing ruled. It did not. No it did not. Anyway.
Speaker 3:  I'm very excited for this emulation scene in particular to hit the iPad
Speaker 3:  because this is the thing that Apple has feared And. if you get to a place
Speaker 3:  where it's just like easy where it's like push a button and turn
Speaker 3:  your iPad into a Windows PC and people start doing it.
Speaker 3:  That's the thing that makes Apple Jake iPad multitasking. Seriously. I don't.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna get there. It just, there's a glimmer of it now, which is fascinating
Speaker 3:  competition. It works. Yeah. All right. We gotta take a break. We are just,
Speaker 3:  I don't even know we're way over. It's, it's next week already. We'll be
Speaker 3:  right back.
Speaker 1:  best part is You can find meta AI right in the apps you already have
Speaker 1:  Instagram, WhatsApp, Facebook, and Messenger.
Speaker 5:  things that have made you feel a lot of feelings.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Okay. So there's a new Canon EOS R one and R five mark two.
Speaker 3:  And they are some of the first cameras, especially pro cameras like this
Speaker 3:  from brands like this that just have AI features in them.
Speaker 3:  And the AI features are fine. Like I, they're fine. They have
Speaker 3:  noise reduction that gets you two more stops. So You can
Speaker 3:  run the ISO a little bit hotter and the noise direction is good.
Speaker 3:  That's AI powered. And then they have 400% image
Speaker 3:  upscaling, which is bananas. So if you just think about it, they've got a
Speaker 3:  sensor in them. Light hits the sensor that makes the image. The sensor is
Speaker 3:  usually, it determines the size of the image. Now the cameras can just
Speaker 3:  make you an image that's four times bigger.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The image is however big you want it to be.
Speaker 3:  And it's just in the camera. and it is based on the fact that the camera
Speaker 3:  knows everything about the light hitting the sensor. It knows the lens you're
Speaker 3:  using. It knows the settings you're at. And so, you know, the argument is
Speaker 3:  their AI upscaling will be better in camera 'cause it's all
Speaker 3:  one closed ecosystem than if you take it out to one of the many, many, many
Speaker 3:  software up upscales that exist out in the world. Weird.
Speaker 3:  Right. Weird to have the camera itself generate
Speaker 3:  pixels that weren't there.
Speaker 5:  I mean this is the stuff we've been talking about with smartphones for like
Speaker 5:  two years now. Right? And we're now at a point where
Speaker 5:  this feels like it's about to become unavoidable. And there
Speaker 5:  there was a thing where it was like, okay, the the like last
Speaker 5:  bastion of photo or photographic
Speaker 5:  honesty is going to be these like fancy high-end
Speaker 5:  cameras. And even that is going away like really, really fast.
Speaker 4:  I'm just so surprised it's Canon doing it and not like
Speaker 4:  Sony or or Panasonic or anybody else who's been in the
Speaker 4:  muralist game.
Speaker 5:  This doesn't seem like a Panasonic move. They're like, do you want our cameras
Speaker 5:  now? How about this? Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Right. Like, like Olympus, like these companies have all been here
Speaker 4:  doing muralist cameras for a lot longer than Canon and, and messing
Speaker 4:  with like computational photography a lot longer than Canon. And Canon was
Speaker 4:  like, Nope, we're doing it now.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I mean that's exactly how Canon talks by the way.
Speaker 3:  They I agree.
Speaker 5:  Thomas Canon, the Thomas Cannon just out there yelling.
Speaker 3:  So it's wonky. You gotta use some Canon menus.
Speaker 3:  The cameras can only do it with pictures they taken themselves. Oddly
Speaker 3:  the upscaling only works with JPEGs and Acfs
Speaker 3:  in case you're a sort of monster shooting Heaths on your
Speaker 3:  DORI
Speaker 5:  What you're doing. I wonder if that's an intentional choice that they're
Speaker 5:  like, we, we have to preserve the sanctity of the raw file, I feel like,
Speaker 5:  but we start to do weirder stuff with some of these other things. Well
Speaker 4:  Yeah, Canon's also always done kind of weird stuff with the, the the regular
Speaker 4:  ones, right? Like the JPEGs, they they would make 'em warmer too. Like it
Speaker 4:  was noticeably warmer on a Canon jpeg.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I mean look, going from a raw to a JPEG is a processing step.
Speaker 3:  There's stylistic choices You can make It is if you have
Speaker 3:  a modern DSLR and you shoot raw at high ISOs,
Speaker 3:  the pictures are gonna be noisier than the JPEGs. 'cause the JPEGs have noise
Speaker 3:  reduction built into them. But like that is usually taking
Speaker 3:  detail out, Not adding it in. And so like you're like, yeah, I
Speaker 3:  like, I personally love the AI noise removal in Lightroom. I use it all the
Speaker 3:  time. I think I've said on the show, like it has re it has changed my
Speaker 3:  relationship to some of my older cameras 'cause it's so good. But now the
Speaker 3:  camera's doing it itself and there's none as far as I can tell, none of the
Speaker 3:  AI metadata that everyone has been talking about putting into these things
Speaker 3:  to indicate that some of these pixels are fake. Like the computer just made
Speaker 3:  up some of these pixels, some of these details might not have been there.
Speaker 3:  Like we don't know in, in the examples I've seen
Speaker 3:  it's kind of accurate, but then you're like, ah, is that right? Like, we
Speaker 3:  just don't know how it's gonna work in every case. And then the,
Speaker 3:  the chain of like metadata that you would need to
Speaker 3:  verify this is a real image. No, it just isn't. It just doesn't
Speaker 3:  exist. And actually, you know, we were talking about the Trump, the images
Speaker 3:  of the Trump shooting, immediate AI generated
Speaker 3:  images from that AI modifications, lots and lots of
Speaker 3:  weird images. They changed the secret service agents to smiling in some,
Speaker 3:  like all this like crazy stuff and all of this stuff that
Speaker 3:  we have talked about for years about content authenticity, about
Speaker 3:  labels, about blah blah. It's just out the window. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Nowhere to
Speaker 3:  Be found. Yeah. I was like, none of that worked. Like, nope, you're like,
Speaker 3:  we're gonna build in all these safeguards like are you using any safeguards?
Speaker 3:  It's like, no. Like we were overwhelmed by sheer volume of crap.
Speaker 3:  And so like it's just fascinating. The canons putting it in the camera now,
Speaker 3:  it is buried in the menu system of a professional Canon diosa. It is
Speaker 3:  not, the apocalypse is not totally here yet, but it's, it's like staring
Speaker 3:  us in the face.
Speaker 5:  That's kind of the thing I've been thinking about with this this week is
Speaker 5:  the thing you said, and I think it was around the Pixel last year
Speaker 5:  about like the question is where in the pipeline do you encounter this ability?
Speaker 5:  And that ends up being really important. Like in, in Lightroom that's an
Speaker 5:  app you downloaded onto your computer that you brought your phone in or your
Speaker 5:  photo into and you pressed a button on purpose to do it. And that, that feels
Speaker 5:  like one thing as opposed to having it happen, you know in
Speaker 5:  Google photos where your photos live or in the app on your phone
Speaker 5:  where the photos go, like the camera roll and this goes even further to,
Speaker 5:  okay now it's a setting on your camera. What if you move it to being
Speaker 5:  a button on your camera to what if you move it to just being there on your
Speaker 5:  camera by default. Like where this goes from a thing I'm doing
Speaker 5:  to, you've just completely changed what is happening without me even
Speaker 5:  being aware of it all. Just feels very weird Yeah. And as soon as you
Speaker 5:  move it to the device, it feels like you've, you've shifted that threshold
Speaker 5:  in a pretty meaningful way because now I think like what, what a lot of people
Speaker 5:  want reasonably is to be able to just take photos off of their camera and
Speaker 5:  have them be good. Right? Like that, that's a good outcome. I don't think
Speaker 5:  most people want to muck around with their photos in Lightroom. So in a certain
Speaker 5:  way it makes sense to say, okay, this thing that you're doing, that we can
Speaker 5:  actually do very well with ai, we're just gonna do it for you because it's
Speaker 5:  a good thing. but it, it, it changes that to, this is now something you've
Speaker 5:  done to my photos rather than something I am able to
Speaker 5:  do. and it does, it does change things.
Speaker 4:  I can't wait for the first like, wedding photographer who uses this and gets
Speaker 4:  a whole new like, set of lace detailing on a wedding dress
Speaker 5:  Or just like a new bridesmaid. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's like there's an extra one there now. Yeah. What's up girl?
Speaker 3:  I mean, look, the R one is 62 99. The R five mark two
Speaker 3:  is 42 99. If they could be like add bridesmaid. Yeah. That's
Speaker 3:  the money. I would pay that money. Yeah, absolutely. I just add a bridesmaid
Speaker 3:  to all of my photos.
Speaker 4:  Just a picture of your kid and a bridesmaid
Speaker 3:  There. She's good. Different one every time Who thought,
Speaker 3:  yeah, let's go for it. Yeah. The, you know, there are professional
Speaker 3:  photographers right now who have basically pushed meta into changing the
Speaker 3:  made with AI label that they're putting on Instagram. So you
Speaker 3:  would export a photo from Lightroom or Photoshop, it would take some metadata
Speaker 3:  that's like used AI to edit this image. They would put it on Instagram, and
Speaker 3:  Instagram would ha like add a label that was like made with AI
Speaker 3:  when maybe all they had done was the deno or maybe all they had done is like
Speaker 3:  a little generative fill or something. Like some thing that is
Speaker 3:  becoming very commonplace where the photographers were like, no, this image
Speaker 3:  is not generated with ai. I edited it with
Speaker 3:  AI and that is meaningfully different when I communicate with the audience.
Speaker 3:  And meta was like, yeah, we agree with you. That's weird. And we're just
Speaker 3:  at a place where actually we might need 50 labels
Speaker 3:  to explain to people what all the different things You can do.
Speaker 3:  Upscaled in camera with ai.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Is that bride's,
Speaker 4:  Brides
Speaker 3:  Made added bridesmaid added, right. Versus I typed a prompt
Speaker 3:  and now here's a picture. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Which is a's a perfect
Speaker 3:  Segue of possibilities.
Speaker 5:  It's a perfect segue into the Samsung thing that Allison Johnson wrote about
Speaker 5:  this week.
Speaker 4:  It rules I. love it so much. It's so stupid.
Speaker 3:  This is the most Samsung caution to the goddamn
Speaker 3:  wind. Yes. I can't tell if I am mad about this
Speaker 3:  or impressed or whatever. I
Speaker 4:  Was, I was mad about it reading it until you get to where like,
Speaker 4:  she tried to make the Lochness monster come out of a lake and instead it
Speaker 4:  was just a giant green bear with like super shredded
Speaker 4:  green bear. And she tried to pick, make like the pope as
Speaker 4:  a rabbit. Like she took a photo of a rabbit and tried to be like, make this
Speaker 4:  the pope in a popemobile. and it was just like, we're gonna put a giant rabbit
Speaker 4:  head inside a car.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So just to, just to quickly explain what's going on here.
Speaker 3:  Sorry. Samsung's image generation software having stroke is bizarrely woke.
Speaker 3:  We, yeah. The wokeness has
Speaker 3:  infected Samsung galaxy folds and it will not
Speaker 3:  let you generate the poke.
Speaker 5:  That's probably it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The Alison Johnson is testing Samsung's new phones, the flip six
Speaker 5:  and the fold six. Nobody listened to what Neli is saying. It's very important
Speaker 5:  that you never listen to what Neli says. And I think the
Speaker 5:  fold six has a feature called sketch to image, which is You can You
Speaker 5:  can take a photo draw
Speaker 3:  Pretty
Speaker 5:  Crudely, a thing you want on that photo and it will generate that thing
Speaker 5:  onto your photo. So I think the first one I saw her do was, it's a,
Speaker 5:  it's a picture of like a, a harbor with a port and some
Speaker 5:  flowers in the foreground. And she draws this like adorable little
Speaker 5:  cartoon bee and I, I guess prompts it
Speaker 5:  to be out of focus and
Speaker 4:  No, she didn't prompt it.
Speaker 5:  Oh, she didn't prompt it. Oh wow. She didn't prompt it. She give a B. She
Speaker 5:  just drew a B. Yeah. Oh, and she put it on a part of the photo that's out
Speaker 5:  of focus. Yeah. And so it generated an out of focus B in that spot
Speaker 5:  in the photo And. if you just look at the photo, there is not a single chance
Speaker 5:  in hell. You would think that that B was not part
Speaker 3:  Of the photo. There is an, there's a tiny little watermark in gray and
Speaker 3:  the bottom left that says AI generated content
Speaker 4:  If you squint.
Speaker 5:  I literally, I had, I have looked at this photo a hundred times. I hadn't
Speaker 5:  seen that until just now.
Speaker 3:  It's pointed out. Yeah. It's, it is Samsung being like,
Speaker 3:  this is what I mean. I can't tell if I'm upset or I'm just impressed at the
Speaker 3:  fuck it like Yeah, like let's just do different disinformation.
Speaker 3:  Would you like to draw some, some disinformation? Not the pope, sir, but
Speaker 3:  any other thing is fine.
Speaker 3:  and it, it is crazy. Like she go look at the pictures in the, in the article
Speaker 3:  that she put a ship in a harbor. It is true that she's, the bear
Speaker 3:  is very good. I mean, fair. She's got a hat on a bunny.
Speaker 3:  And then the water, if you look at the, at the picture of the, the, the hat
Speaker 3:  on the bunny, the watermark is invisible. Yeah. It's there. It just totally
Speaker 3:  bl blended in the grass. And Samsung is like, why wouldn't you just
Speaker 3:  make that bigger for people? You also, you just crop it out. It's not in
Speaker 3:  the photo. Right. This is what I mean by the, what is a photo
Speaker 3:  apo? Like this is full. What is a photo apocalypse? So you are giving
Speaker 3:  people the tool to just generate fake imagery based on real imagery
Speaker 3:  and then send it out into the world with nothing with
Speaker 3:  They can just lie. And like, we're gonna get to a place, I think
Speaker 3:  more quickly than people want to, where
Speaker 3:  no one trusts any image and then we're gonna have to work backwards from
Speaker 3:  there. Or the alternative, which is
Speaker 3:  very scary, where everyone trusts every image. There's not
Speaker 3:  gonna be like some middle ground, right? Like
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I don't think the middle ground exists. You either just say, oh sure,
Speaker 5:  it's probably all real, and let the chips fall where they may. Or you trust
Speaker 5:  nothing. Yeah. And trusting nothing requires a lot more work. And, and
Speaker 5:  so I think it's, it's actually easier to just say, oh sure, it's probably
Speaker 5:  real and I'll be wrong sometimes. And that's fine. And I, I think like nihilism
Speaker 5:  kind of leads you there in a way that's pretty scary. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I just, I'm, I'm, I'm gonna reserve my judgment on how, how
Speaker 4:  panicked to be about this until we find out like if You can just draw abs
Speaker 4:  on someone and it gives them abs,
Speaker 5:  In which case you'd be pro,
Speaker 4:  I'd probably be con. 'cause I don't wanna see a bunch of like, I want the
Speaker 4:  abs to be real. Mm. Like don't, don't fake no fake abs here. Only real
Speaker 4:  abs. So, so I'm, I'm very curious to see. I ask Alex, it's
Speaker 5:  To have moral boundaries. Crans. Yeah. I appreciate that about you. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Small six, six pack of a moral boundaries. Everybody's gotta
Speaker 3:  Have line. So it,
Speaker 3:  And that moral boundary is shredded abs. That's it. Don't,
Speaker 3:  don't fake me out wash water. Nothing. So
Speaker 3:  interestingly, Samsung is not doing this locally. The picture
Speaker 3:  gets sent out to the cloud, which is where some of the content moderation
Speaker 3:  seems to come in, right? Like once you go away from your phone and into a
Speaker 3:  cloud server, everyone wants to take responsibility for it, which is good.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Tech companies taking responsibility, unclear how long it will
Speaker 3:  take over time. You know, these, these systems aren't being stressed yet.
Speaker 3:  Well, data usage, power usage, all this stuff. But
Speaker 3:  boy did Samsung just be like, fine, just draw on the photo and like we'll
Speaker 3:  just make a fake photo for you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You want the Lochness monster. Have the Lochness Monster or a Green
Speaker 5:  Bear. Or a green bear.
Speaker 3:  All right. Is this, if you're calling it the, is this anything gadget Bonanza?
Speaker 3:  is this anything?
Speaker 5:  This is something, yeah, I don't know what, but it is something, but I would
Speaker 5:  like to, I would like to segue to one that is the most, is this
Speaker 5:  anything of anything, which is that years after essential,
Speaker 5:  the, the once promising Andy Rubin led phone
Speaker 5:  company went away. We finally are starting
Speaker 5:  to get information about the second thing they were building. There was a
Speaker 5:  lot of like, I think at the time we saw like
Speaker 5:  renders of this very tall sort of remote controlee lookin phone,
Speaker 5:  but somebody found one on eBay and got a hands-on.
Speaker 5:  I think this is the most interesting phone I've seen in years. and it also
Speaker 5:  might be so stupid. It
Speaker 3:  Looks so
Speaker 5:  Dumb.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I I love stupid tech, so I'm just, I adore this thing.
Speaker 4:  I don't understand how you would use it long term.
Speaker 5:  It's basically the best way I can describe it is like, imagine two iPod nanos
Speaker 5:  stacked on top of each other. Yeah. But it's all screen. It's just a,
Speaker 5:  it's just a remote control and it looks like it's basically just a bunch
Speaker 5:  of widgets, which perhaps unsurprisingly makes me very
Speaker 5:  excited. I love a good widget. I
Speaker 4:  I think that my, my big call out for this one is that it was obviously
Speaker 4:  made before TikTok was a thing.
Speaker 5:  No, but on this you could open TikTok on the bottom and then TikTok again
Speaker 5:  on the top
Speaker 4:  Little tiny TikTok.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it would be dope. I could make a TikTok and
Speaker 5:  watch a TikTok all at exactly the same time. I
Speaker 4:  Bet it would be really good for fidgeting. Like, just kind of flipping it
Speaker 4:  around in your hand, the, the whole phone. 'cause it's so long.
Speaker 3:  That's true. Like a pencil, if you'll recall, essentials plan
Speaker 3:  was to do ambient computing. They were gonna put stuff in your house. The
Speaker 3:  phone was just the first thing. So maybe this really was just a remote control.
Speaker 3:  Mm.
Speaker 5:  That's very possible. Yeah. That it was like they, they were making a, a
Speaker 5:  home device. I wrote a whole thing about this when, back when I was at Wired
Speaker 5:  that they were, their big plan was like you said, to have,
Speaker 5:  they were doing sort of an Alexa thing, but we're promising to do it in a
Speaker 5:  much more elegant way. And even just looking at some of the stuff here, it
Speaker 5:  is very much like get quick information and
Speaker 5:  see what's going on rather than like endlessly scroll on Instagram.
Speaker 5:  Which like, I'd take that, that that works. But I just, I miss
Speaker 5:  this thing where there were people asking questions about what size a phone
Speaker 5:  was supposed to be and now no. We're, we've just decided that phones should
Speaker 5:  be huge and leave weird divots in your pinky from trying to hold them. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna say this isn't anything.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Yeah, you're right. Sorry. Well, objectively co
Speaker 3:  Conclusively not
Speaker 5:  Anything. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Can I, can I interest you in the tiny, the tiny pot? is this
Speaker 5:  anything?
Speaker 4:  Okay. Which one? Which one? Let
Speaker 5:  Me, let me back this up instead. Can I interest
Speaker 5:  you in a little silicon case for your Apple watch that gives
Speaker 5:  it a scroll wheel that appears to just mechanically move the digital crown?
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Very
Speaker 3:  Good. I mean, perfect.
Speaker 4:  I wish it wasn't $80.
Speaker 3:  No, that's the right price. You wish it was more That's the price of hubris.
Speaker 4:  They have a version without the wheel for like $30.
Speaker 3:  Oh, come on. And I'm
Speaker 4:  Just like, what's the point of that? Who's, who wants that?
Speaker 3:  Okay. So I will just remind everyone that when the Apple Watch was launched,
Speaker 3:  You can go back and watch this video. Bono was there. They,
Speaker 3:  they built a tent at a community college in California. This is a real thing
Speaker 3:  that happened and they sat us all down
Speaker 3:  and they were like, with every new Apple product comes a revolutionary
Speaker 3:  input device. You'll recall the mouse, here's Steve Jobs and a mouse.
Speaker 3:  You'll recall the, the click wheel on the iPod, the Multitouch
Speaker 3:  on the iPhone. And now with the Apple watch, the digital Crown.
Speaker 3:  And I just think a device that's like no actually click wheel. What if
Speaker 3:  we just use a click wheel to turn the digital account is perfect. I will
Speaker 3:  pay $80 just for that.
Speaker 4:  Are you gonna put your watch in it?
Speaker 3:  I mean, I, I have so many old Apple watchOS, I'd be like, can shovel in here?
Speaker 3:  It does look delightful. I don't know why they've exposed the heart rate
Speaker 3:  sensors on the back. You can like, like are you supposed to hold it, press
Speaker 3:  it
Speaker 5:  To your neck?
Speaker 3:  Like
Speaker 5:  No. Okay. Wait. I I have one.
Speaker 3:  Oh, it's for charging. It's for charging. Oh,
Speaker 5:  Sure. That
Speaker 4:  Makes sense. That makes more sense.
Speaker 5:  My, my stupid usability question about this is the
Speaker 5:  watch, every time you take it off it locks. Like the way it
Speaker 5:  authenticates is by staying on your body and then you turn it on. Are you
Speaker 5:  gonna have to enter your passcode every single time you want to touch this
Speaker 5:  thing? Because that sounds awful. I think
Speaker 4:  You, you used to be able to dis disable.
Speaker 5:  Can you turn that off? Okay. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You should be able to turn the watch stuff off. I never do
Speaker 5:  This. Okay. If that's the case, I'm gonna buy the hell outta this thing.
Speaker 5:  Also, it will decimate the battery life because you are absolutely not supposed
Speaker 5:  to actively use the watch very much. But I don't care. I'm gonna use it.
Speaker 4:  Do, yeah.
Speaker 3:  Okay. This is something. Love it. Go. I'll say that the between the weird
Speaker 3:  b Palmer news cycle that you and Craig might have kicked off
Speaker 3:  and the, the, the interest in the, these things.
Speaker 3:  Some something's happening out there. I dunno what it is. I dunno if it's
Speaker 3:  measurable. I dunno if anyone's actually giving up their phone, but people
Speaker 3:  are very much like, I'm sick of these rectangles. What do I think?
Speaker 3:  Dumber worse. Rectangles.
Speaker 5:  There is a, there is a moment of phone
Speaker 5:  disintermediation that is happening that I think is very exciting.
Speaker 5:  Let's see. Oh gosh, there's so many. Let's do the Dyson on track
Speaker 5:  headphones.
Speaker 3:  This is
Speaker 5:  Nothing. That's the first time I've said that name out loud. I don't like
Speaker 5:  it. It's not on track. The on track on track. Bad,
Speaker 3:  Bad. They're very, they're Dyson made very customizable headphones. That's
Speaker 3:  cool. I'm, I'm super down. And
Speaker 5:  They don't look like a band mask, which I would argue is a tremendous
Speaker 4:  Improvement and, and they cost $500
Speaker 5:  Less improvement. Yeah. Not as
Speaker 4:  Good. Yeah, I, well really curious to see how they, they
Speaker 4:  work out. I know Chris Welch is gonna probably review 'em, call 'em in, but
Speaker 4:  yeah,
Speaker 3:  They do look cool. They're just expensive. Did the
Speaker 5:  Band one sound good? I don't remember.
Speaker 4:  They sounded okay. Okay. But this is giving real skull candy and
Speaker 4:  I don't know if that's a derogatory skull candy or a pos, it's just skull
Speaker 4:  candy.
Speaker 5:  It's a little derogatory for $500. It's derogatory. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I think my issue with these and I, you know, I know people lo love Dyson
Speaker 3:  products. I just wanna sit on an airplane with headphones and say Dyson on
Speaker 3:  them in this way.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Also there's no fan. Where is the fan? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  You've got spin spinning. You've got one core technology Dyson.
Speaker 4:  Gosh.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Okay. I wanna, maybe there's something, but I don't think there are
Speaker 3:  anything. So the
Speaker 5:  Way you just said Neli Dyson in this way, it makes me think you
Speaker 5:  like bring your vacuum on the plane and you're like, happy to show that off.
Speaker 5:  But you don't wanna rep Dyson in this way.
Speaker 3:  That's what I'm saying. It's a, it's a very confus,
Speaker 5:  You're like with this air wrap style and they're just like killing it on
Speaker 5:  the
Speaker 3:  Plane. If you sat down on an airplane, I dunno. And you like opened a
Speaker 3:  box of food and had a Chevy logo, I'd like, what is happening here?
Speaker 3:  This makes no sense.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I can give you that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that makes sense. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I think Dyson just had a bunch of headphone parts left and just
Speaker 5:  shipped them. That's my theory. The let's do last one
Speaker 5:  and then there I have, I have more. I have, we could do this forever, but
Speaker 5:  let's just do one last one and then we should go. And I think it is the most,
Speaker 5:  is this anything of all the major phone companies right now? and it's that
Speaker 5:  Google just leaked its own Pixel nine. Yeah. Yeah. Google was just like,
Speaker 5:  here's the Pixel nine pro. is this anything
Speaker 4:  I like They asked, I
Speaker 5:  Don't know. That should be the title of the YouTube video. They're like,
Speaker 5:  do do you like this? Well
Speaker 4:  They did this, was it last year?
Speaker 4:  Was it last year that they leaked the pixel? Like where
Speaker 3:  Is this just a leak? Can we stop calling this a leak? They just posted it.
Speaker 5:  They just posted the phone. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  That's true. I mean like a high res photo. They're like, here it is.
Speaker 5:  They did a video that just says introducing the Google Pixel nine Pro. You're
Speaker 5:  right. They just launched the damn phone
Speaker 3:  Stop. That's not a
Speaker 5:  Leak. You're absolutely right. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They just were like, here it is for now.
Speaker 3:  It the camera bump is outrageous. It's huge. What are
Speaker 3:  we doing guys?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I
Speaker 3:  The the camera bump is like starting to be the size of a phone
Speaker 3:  like that. The little i i Apple What's the Apple Watch phone called?
Speaker 5:  Wait, tiny pod. The,
Speaker 3:  Yeah, the tiny pod. I am I'm curious if the tiny pod with the Apple watch
Speaker 3:  in it is as big as the bump on the,
Speaker 5:  Okay, so pixel 10, you make the bump removable.
Speaker 4:  That's what
Speaker 5:  I was gonna say. And it's its own thing. Yeah. Now we're talking crazy. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  See what I'm saying? We did. Now we're talking. That's the good stuff.
Speaker 5:  We just did it. It's really like the whole story of this thing is going to
Speaker 5:  be, it runs Gemini fast. It's like, it's very clear.
Speaker 5:  That is the whole sales pitch here.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Which, what else does Google has? I,
Speaker 5:  I do not find that.
Speaker 3:  Do people want this? But I am not convinced Gemini's doing
Speaker 3:  all the things Google wants to do. We'll, we'll get to that later. But if
Speaker 3:  that's the whole pitch here, it has to be good. And what have we learned
Speaker 3:  about AI hardware? It's probably broken and I don't
Speaker 3:  believe you.
Speaker 5:  So yeah, we're gonna say that launch is August 13th,
Speaker 5:  right?
Speaker 5:  So TBD But I'm gonna, I'm gonna say tentatively it is not
Speaker 5:  anything. We should take a break. But the last
Speaker 5:  one is the The OnePlus Pad two has a vibrating stylus
Speaker 5:  for reasons.
Speaker 3:  This is another thing.
Speaker 4:  Okay. You know what the, you're writing utensil to vibrate
Speaker 3:  A
Speaker 5:  Linear motor inside that makes the tip vibrate to give you that
Speaker 3:  break dancing. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Which is to be fair, kind of jumping and and and yeah.
Speaker 3:  Every Olympic sport is one of those three. Jumping, flipping and swimming.
Speaker 3:  As you know, sports in America are basically in seven 20 p and have been
Speaker 3:  forever because there's no competition for broadcast. Comcast
Speaker 3:  is going to do the Olympics in 4K,
Speaker 3:  but they're only gonna do it. Comcast is gonna do the Olympics in 4K, probably
Speaker 3:  in Peacock, but probably like the horrible upscaled 4K that they do.
Speaker 3:  If you have a Comcast cable box, you will get
Speaker 3:  a high bit rate, low latency 4K feet of the Olympics.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So if you have an A XI six A
Speaker 3:  she six, I don't know what kind of cable box that is because I live
Speaker 3:  here in the future. But if you have one of their cable boxes,
Speaker 3:  You can get Hi-Fi audio and a 30 megabits per second
Speaker 3:  low latency 4K stream of the Olympics. Which sounds awesome,
Speaker 3:  frankly. That sounds awesome. Yeah. It is just ridiculous that they're eliminated
Speaker 3:  to their K walks, which they say they have to do because of their custom
Speaker 3:  network, blah, blah blah, blah. There's absolutely no reason they have to
Speaker 3:  do this. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  What, why didn't they put those resources into Peacock and letting Peacock
Speaker 4:  do it?
Speaker 5:  I will say this is going to work for Comcast. Like the obvious move
Speaker 5:  here is to get people who don't have this box but have a
Speaker 5:  Comcast account to upgrade to this box. And it's gonna work
Speaker 5:  like the, the sporting events that make people go out and buy new
Speaker 5:  higher res televisions. Like it, it's the same
Speaker 5:  push it's gonna work.
Speaker 4:  Are the Olympics that Yeah, dude,
Speaker 5:  It's the Olympics. The Olympics are huge
Speaker 4:  Sometimes.
Speaker 3:  So you get W Vision, HDR and Atmos immersive sound
Speaker 3:  and then Yep. Channel 1350, which is USA 4K
Speaker 3:  will get the
Speaker 5:  Wait. It's just the one channel. It's not all of the Olympics. It's just
Speaker 5:  USA
Speaker 3:  And Yep. And then four. So you, you get
Speaker 5:  The Olympics and Mon reruns. Yes. Congrats.
Speaker 3:  Yes. It's, it's 24 7 access to the national screen.
Speaker 3:  The national stream.
Speaker 5:  Oh, that's worse. I take it back.
Speaker 4:  Nevermind. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Peacock
Speaker 4:  Just peacock's gonna like peacock. They seem to have been doing a really
Speaker 4:  smart design for it.
Speaker 5:  I got an email this morning telling me that my peacock price is about to
Speaker 5:  go up and guess when my price changes. Oh, it's in the middle of the
Speaker 5:  Olympics.
Speaker 5:  Surprise. You can test and see Peacock,
Speaker 4:  See if it like, which is better with or without paid
Speaker 4:  Peacock.
Speaker 5:  I, I am required to keep paid Peacock because it somehow has all my shows.
Speaker 5:  We've talked about this,
Speaker 4:  This is true. This, I don't know why I, I suggested
Speaker 5:  That too. Yeah, peacock, I'm sorry, is weirdly like central to my day-to-Day
Speaker 5:  existence. But I try not to, I try not to think too much about that
Speaker 5:  'cause it just makes me sad.
Speaker 4:  You get all the girls five ever though. So
Speaker 5:  I do like that
Speaker 3:  If you have a compatible streaming device, you will get W Vision HDR and
Speaker 3:  Atmos. But you don't, you don't get the, the enhanced 4K.
Speaker 3:  This is very complicated. Yeah. All I'm saying is Sony Petra core, that
Speaker 3:  rebranded Sony a Bravia core that I have on, on my Sony tv still
Speaker 3:  showing me Madame Webb at 80 megabits per second. The finest dream experience
Speaker 3:  You can have in America today. All Kranz, what's yours?
Speaker 4:  Also 4K related because Sling TV is adding four K streaming
Speaker 4:  for free, unlike everybody else who has
Speaker 3:  Charging for it. Where's where? Sling on the go. Nineties sale would you
Speaker 3:  say
Speaker 4:  With this?
Speaker 5:  At least in the seventies. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  This is like Hail Mary.
Speaker 4:  This is help. They've already done it once. They they did it, they did
Speaker 4:  a couple of days ago with the Fox Sports All Star game and we all
Speaker 4:  immediately went to social media to talk about watching
Speaker 4:  4K.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that was huge news. Everybody, everybody knew that on
Speaker 4:  Sling TV and on their Roku or Amazon Fire advice,
Speaker 4:  but they didn't. Partially because it's, it's pretty much limited to sling
Speaker 4:  blue subscribers. 'cause there's two versions of Sling only in a couple
Speaker 4:  of major, a few major cities.
Speaker 3:  Okay. They're fully at an 80. They're fully at an 80. This is so common.
Speaker 3:  I care about this so much and it's so hard to understand what you're saying,
Speaker 3:  but if
Speaker 4:  You're in Gainesville, Florida, yeah. You You can get it
Speaker 4:  and you don't have to pay extra. Okay, sure. So it's yeah.
Speaker 5:  Big up to Gainesville. Yeah. I'll say if you run a streaming service and
Speaker 5:  you're out there 4K streaming as a, as a
Speaker 5:  like free up service to keep people engaged is going
Speaker 5:  to work. Someone needs to go out and just be the one that's like, yes,
Speaker 5:  You can have 4K for no more money because we love you. Besides Sling it will
Speaker 5:  work. Sling did it for what sounds like 11 people. So
Speaker 5:  great. I'm thrilled for those 11 people. Gainesville I'm
Speaker 5:  sure is, is, you know, happy rioting in the streets, like that's great, but
Speaker 5:  this, this is a feature that could work. Like this is the kind of thing
Speaker 5:  that people want and someone who wants their customers to be happy
Speaker 5:  should give this to them.
Speaker 3:  Again, I have said many times YouTube should just pay to produce all the
Speaker 3:  games in 4K and then just have 4K games on YouTube tv.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. and
Speaker 3:  It, it's too con like they have the money and I, I'm pretty sure they would.
Speaker 3:  It's Google. They're like, whatever. I think it's too complicated.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. All right, David, bring us home. Oh my God. Okay. $27 million mansion.
Speaker 3:  That sucks. This is the, this
Speaker 5:  Is the best news. So Sam Altman bought a house
Speaker 5:  in 2020 for $27 million. That was,
Speaker 5:  I don't know if it was when he bought it, but it was at least at one time
Speaker 5:  the most expensive San Francisco real estate listing ever. and it
Speaker 5:  sucked.
Speaker 3:  And
Speaker 5:  He sued or he his his people through a
Speaker 5:  series of weird corporate things that is fighting another
Speaker 5:  series of weird corporate things on the side of the developers sued
Speaker 5:  because basically they built him, what,
Speaker 5:  what his lawyers are alleging was a lemon of a $27 million house.
Speaker 5:  This whole story is bananas. So the Architectural Digest made
Speaker 5:  an 11 minute long video. I'll link it in the show notes going through
Speaker 5:  the house before it was sold. And the house is, it's not
Speaker 5:  beautiful, but it's like incredible if that makes sense. It has,
Speaker 5:  it has a gym, it has a massage room, it has a closet that is larger
Speaker 5:  than most houses. It has a
Speaker 4:  Wellness cottage, right?
Speaker 5:  It has a wellness cottage. Thank you. That's the phrase I was looking for.
Speaker 5:  It has three ovens in the kitchen, which seems like one more than even like
Speaker 5:  the very extravagant amount of ovens to have it,
Speaker 5:  but it's real like show showstopping piece was this
Speaker 5:  cantilevered infinity pool that kind of looked out over San Francisco. It's
Speaker 5:  gorgeous.
Speaker 5:  According to the lawsuit, the people who were building
Speaker 5:  the house were involved in a bunch of like
Speaker 5:  corporate and financial shenanigans that led to
Speaker 5:  them doing a crappy job and not paying contractors.
Speaker 5:  Who then as a sabotage move did things like
Speaker 5:  shove bags and debris into drains, which then
Speaker 5:  clogged those drains, which did things like cause a ceiling to collapse
Speaker 5:  in the gym in the house it caused,
Speaker 5:  there were, there were like inches of standing water under some of the walkways.
Speaker 5:  There was apparently mold everywhere. Let's see, what else do I have?
Speaker 5:  Numerous leaking irrigation lines that were incorrectly installed on the
Speaker 5:  rooftop garden. Failure of the tread lights and the exterior
Speaker 5:  staircase, which were repaired but then failed again, defects in the design
Speaker 5:  and waterproofing of exterior planters just over and over and over again.
Speaker 5:  Big giant pool basically leaking into and rapidly destroying the rest of
Speaker 5:  the house. And the, the estimates were that the price
Speaker 5:  to fix all of this is going to be more than $4 million, which is
Speaker 5:  a number for repairs that I cannot fathom. And so
Speaker 5:  basically the, the lawsuit now is saying that Sam Altman was
Speaker 5:  essentially duped into buying a $27 million piece of crap.
Speaker 4:  Who made it? Was it It is so funny. It was like DR Horton behind it because
Speaker 4:  it,
Speaker 4:  one of the other big builders.
Speaker 3:  Well, I'm just saying sometimes you get duped into spending a lot of money
Speaker 3:  on an engineering marvel that can't actually do all the things people say
Speaker 6:  It could do.
Speaker 6:  Just, yeah,
Speaker 3:  Just one of those things. What if the capabilities of this cantilevered pool
Speaker 3:  do not match with the staggering amount of hype that
Speaker 3:  has come with said pool?
Speaker 5:  Hmm. Do you think the pool helps you send like slightly better business emails?
Speaker 3:  The pool has already tried to have sex with Kevin Ru,
Speaker 5:  But yeah, I should say
Speaker 3:  On the one hand, I love you Kevin. On the one
Speaker 5:  Hand, like this sucks. I don't mean to like particularly make fun of Sam
Speaker 5:  Walt, but like, as somebody who just went through a much less expensive and
Speaker 5:  problematic house renovation, this sucks. And like the
Speaker 5:  idea of spending all of this money on a house and then basically
Speaker 5:  discovering it is literally collapsing inside of itself.
Speaker 5:  That sucks. I don't wish that on anybody in another way. It's very funny.
Speaker 3:  It's the, the metaphor here is very good. Yeah. Also, he was just driving
Speaker 3:  around like a $5 million clinic segment, right? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's fine.
Speaker 4:  And the house is so ugly. Like it's just
Speaker 4:  like incredibly, incredibly unattractive house.
Speaker 4:  So good for him. He can go get it redone. Like take his his earnings from,
Speaker 4:  from the lawsuit, make it look like a real house. It'll be great.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's just, I, it, I would encourage everyone to go read the lawsuit.
Speaker 5:  I'll link it. It's, it's 38 pages and the first like 10 pages
Speaker 5:  are just explaining the structure of the company that
Speaker 5:  built this house and how insane it was. And there was like, they lost
Speaker 5:  a $50 million
Speaker 5:  judgment against them for other shoddy work that they did. And they were
Speaker 5:  like, the company was like running outta money. So they stopped funding their
Speaker 5:  projects while also at the same time doing marketing about
Speaker 5:  how like their whole thing was detailed and 25% of their work went into things
Speaker 5:  that the owner would never see because they just care that much. And that's
Speaker 5:  how it's 27 million I. love it. It's so, so funny. The
Speaker 5:  whole thing is just like, there, there will be a documentary about this and
Speaker 5:  I will watch every single second of it.
Speaker 3:  And the documentary will be made by SOA and most of it'll be lies.
Speaker 3:  It's gonna be great. Yeah. I'm excited. Alright. We are way over. Like I
Speaker 3:  said, it's already next week. It's next week at the end of the first segment.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's fine Now it's September. Yeah. The iPhones are here now. Let's
Speaker 5:  talk about that. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Oh no. All right. You gotta go. But before we do, I just wanna call it one
Speaker 3:  story and it said this incredible, if you're an old head gadget blogger like
Speaker 3:  me, Sean Hollister and John Porter wrote about the
Speaker 3:  stream deck, the Elga stream deck and where it came from, which is this
Speaker 3:  legendary gadget blogger obsession, the Art
Speaker 3:  Leive optimist keyboard. It turns out, by the way, art Leiv
Speaker 3:  turned into like a very weird, hard right Russian
Speaker 3:  nationalist, which we had to add to the story. Oh boy. Which was not what
Speaker 3:  I wanted out of this very innocent story about the stream deck, but that
Speaker 3:  is such as 2024. But if you were like me, you're like reading
Speaker 3:  and writing gadget blogs it like 20 years ago, this keyboard
Speaker 3:  just kept coming up as the thing everybody wanted. and it turns out the company
Speaker 3:  that made the actual display has kept going and that turned into the stream
Speaker 3:  deck. And it's just like a winding tale of some people really
Speaker 3:  believe in that key should light up and I love it. And the design is incredible.
Speaker 3:  Cool. So go read that and then we've, we have just tons and tons of stories
Speaker 3:  on this. It was a great week on the site actually. And then I, I promise
Speaker 3:  you we will moderate the politics, but they're here. So just get ready. It's
Speaker 3:  it's election
Speaker 5:  Year and I will say we're gonna, and everybody should hold us to this. We,
Speaker 5:  I wanna spend a lot of time talking about like policy and less
Speaker 5:  talking about like horse race shenanigans of the next, what do
Speaker 3:  The poll say
Speaker 8:  Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you. Give us a call at eight six six
Speaker 8:  VERGE one. One The Vergecast is the production of The Verge and Vox Media
Speaker 8:  Podcast Network. Our show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James.
Speaker 8:  That's it. We'll see you next week.
Speaker 1:  Have a question
Speaker 1:  Facebook, and Messenger.