# Transcript
ID: f402bb43-3f45-495e-988d-cd4b75ec641b
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7946957092093692839/-4103204848988393182/s93290-US-5894s-1728383325.mp3
Description: For this full-on “what is a photo” episode, we start by chatting with Halide developers Ben Sandofsky and Sebastiaan De With about what it means to build a camera app in 2024 — and what it means to try and accurately capture a photo. Then The Verge’s Allison Johnson joins the show to talk about her experiment going all-in on AI-ifying her photos. Finally, we answer a hotline about which gadgets to attach to your head when you go for a run.
Speaker 1:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of knowing that the key
Speaker 1:  to the camera control on the iPhone 16 is that it does whatever it's gonna
Speaker 1:  do when you let go of the button, not when you press the button. Total game
Speaker 1:  changer. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am doing what I guess you would
Speaker 1:  call a camera audit. So I've decided for a bunch of reasons
Speaker 1:  that I want to take fewer photos and videos on my phone, especially
Speaker 1:  of like life memories. I think if you're doing it for a purpose, it's fine,
Speaker 1:  but I just wanna have these photos and not take them in a way
Speaker 1:  that sort of ruins the memory of the moment, if that makes sense. And I have
Speaker 1:  definitely been guilty of taking out my phone, taking a picture,
Speaker 1:  and then being like, oh, while I'm here, let me check my fantasy team for
Speaker 1:  45 minutes. And that's bad So. I'm trying to get outta that. And I've discovered
Speaker 1:  I actually have a lot of options around here. I have old phones and really
Speaker 1:  any phone from the last couple of years, I have old pixels, old iPhones,
Speaker 1:  I have a nothing phone. Like there's a bunch of decent camera options here.
Speaker 1:  Maybe I should use one of those. I have a dj, I Osmo pocket.
Speaker 1:  This thing takes great videos. I do a lot of Vergecast stuff with it actually.
Speaker 1:  And I like it quite a bit. I have an old Sony
Speaker 1:  Alpha 6,000 lying around here somewhere. I have a lot of options
Speaker 1:  and I was thinking, I need to buy a new camera, some fancy
Speaker 1:  new, you know, the Fuji X 100 or whatever. And
Speaker 1:  I probably will. Let's be honest, this is just the life I've chosen.
Speaker 1:  I spend all of the money on gadgets that I don't have.
Speaker 1:  But I think there's something interesting about repurposing one of these
Speaker 1:  gadgets. I mean, hell, I have the humane AI pin and the rabbit R one
Speaker 1:  here. Both of those are cameras. Maybe there's something to thinking about
Speaker 1:  the camera I have with me in a slightly different way. Maybe it's another
Speaker 1:  phone, maybe it's an old camera. Maybe I should go just like buy a bunch
Speaker 1:  of disposables. I have a friend who does that and it seems sort of delightful.
Speaker 1:  Anyway, all we are here to talk about on the show today, almost
Speaker 1:  all we're here to talk about is photos. We've been talking about this idea
Speaker 1:  of what is a photo for years now as
Speaker 1:  smartphone cameras have gotten more and more AI based. And the whole idea
Speaker 1:  of what happens when you hit the shutter button on your camera or on your
Speaker 1:  phone or wherever has shifted the question of
Speaker 1:  what you get out of it.
Speaker 1:  It feels harder to know than ever. And it's a thing we've talked about a
Speaker 1:  lot on this show. And so for today's episode, we're just gonna dig way
Speaker 1:  into that for the whole show. We're gonna talk to the folks behind the super
Speaker 1:  popular super cool camera app, Halide, maybe it's Hali, I don't know. We're
Speaker 1:  actually gonna sort that out when we get them on here to talk through how
Speaker 1:  they think about photos and why their new feature called Process Zero,
Speaker 1:  which just removes all of Apple's processing from the iPhone
Speaker 1:  has been such a hit. The photos are worse. People really like it, it's really
Speaker 1:  fascinating. So we're gonna talk to them about all that stuff. And then Allison
Speaker 1:  Johnson on our team has been doing kind of an AI photo
Speaker 1:  experiment on herself to see how it changes the photos
Speaker 1:  you take, the way that you take them, the way that you edit them, the way
Speaker 1:  that you remember them, when you know that you can change just about anything
Speaker 1:  about them after the fact. Then we have a hotline question that has nothing
Speaker 1:  to do with the photos but is still very fun. All that is coming up in just
Speaker 1:  a second. But first, I just realized that if I'm gonna charge this Sony camera,
Speaker 1:  I have to get a micro USB cable, and that means I have to go into
Speaker 1:  the dreaded bucket of cables to see if I still have a micro
Speaker 1:  USB cable. The good news is I'm who I am, so I'm sure that I do. The
Speaker 1:  bad news is that bucket of cables is a deeply terrifying
Speaker 1:  place. Wish me luck. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  let's get into it. So this app, Halli or Halide, again, we're gonna
Speaker 1:  figure that out in a minute, has been around for a bunch of years and it
Speaker 1:  has gone through a lot of changes as the iPhone has gone through a lot of
Speaker 1:  changes. Not only, you know, the tech getting better and the things
Speaker 1:  about the design changing and the lenses moving around and all that stuff.
Speaker 1:  But the whole idea of what the iPhone camera is supposed to do and
Speaker 1:  b feels like it has changed. And the two guys, Ben
Speaker 1:  and Sebastian, Hey,
Speaker 5:  I'm Ben Sand Osky and I'm co-founder of Lux Optics and I'm the
Speaker 5:  developer half that works on Halide and Keynote and our other fun side projects.
Speaker 1:  I'm Sebastian Dewith, I'm the design half
Speaker 6:  Of that that, so the co co-founder and designer slash
Speaker 6:  photographer part of it
Speaker 1:  Have been going through all of this and trying to figure out not only
Speaker 1:  how to make a really great camera app, but what kind of camera app people
Speaker 1:  need now given what the iPhone and other smartphones are becoming.
Speaker 1:  We had a really fun conversation, NELI and I grabbed Ben and Sebastian
Speaker 1:  hashed all this out for a long time. Let's hear it. Excellent. All right.
Speaker 1:  And Neli Patel is also here. Hi Neli.
Speaker 7:  I think we should just get them to pronounce Halide over and over
Speaker 1:  Again. You, you just did the thing that I wanted to do first, which is how
Speaker 1:  in the, how is it how light or is it Halide? Can we, can we solve this for
Speaker 1:  people in the world right now? You just said Halide Ben, is this the official
Speaker 1:  correct answer?
Speaker 5:  I alternate because it's based on halogen, right? Oh God. and it so
Speaker 5:  Silver Halide halogen. As long as it's not Haliday, which is a Middle Eastern
Speaker 5:  name. No,
Speaker 7:  That's what it is now. Well,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, sorry. There was, there was actually someone who worked at The Verge,
Speaker 6:  John Porter, I think he has moved on now, but he, he once pr pronounce it
Speaker 6:  on a podcast Halide and we sent him a Happy Holidays Christmas card and
Speaker 6:  we'll never let him live that down. We continue to do this every year because
Speaker 6:  that's very good. It's so good.
Speaker 7:  That's very good.
Speaker 6:  Haylight or highlight, depending on how, how fancy you feel. No,
Speaker 1:  No. You guys, this is the worst. We have to pick one. Let's do this right
Speaker 1:  now here on the verse cast, can we name your app please?
Speaker 7:  What is your name
Speaker 5:  On 3 1 2? Allied. Allied. Okay, there we go.
Speaker 5:  All right, good. And I, I just wanna point out that like when we release,
Speaker 5:  I want point
Speaker 7:  Out that you super cheated in one Seb. Say it first.
Speaker 5:  I I I think he went on, he went on two. You never go on
Speaker 5:  two.
Speaker 6:  We're a very good team actually when it comes down to it.
Speaker 5:  I just wanna close this discourse on names that we were like when we're building
Speaker 5:  keynote No one can mess up that name. And then it was featured in the
Speaker 5:  keynote from Apple and they told us we're having trouble
Speaker 5:  because it sounds a lot like Keynote Ooh and So I think
Speaker 5:  every time we build a new app it just needs to challenge someone.
Speaker 6:  Well the best part was that I was like, it's actually pronounced kno. And
Speaker 6:  then they were like, really? And I was like, no.
Speaker 1:  Happy Kino everybody. That's what we're doing now.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So I. Think we, we have a bunch of stuff to talk about and we, we should
Speaker 1:  just, we've been getting into our feelings on this podcast about what a photo
Speaker 1:  is for years now, and we have invited you two to essentially do the same
Speaker 1:  thing with us. But my first question as we get into this, I wanna talk a
Speaker 1:  lot about Process zero and a lot about what has changed with iPhone photography
Speaker 1:  in particular and all this stuff. But I am desperately curious like when,
Speaker 1:  when you guys started building a camera app many years ago at this point,
Speaker 1:  did you know at the time how big a like, philosophical
Speaker 1:  exercise it was to build a camera app? I think we, we think about it as like
Speaker 1:  you, you add a bunch of filters and buttons, but it's really like
Speaker 1:  you, you are making decisions about the universe when you build a camera
Speaker 1:  app in a way that I think people are only coming around to. Did you know
Speaker 1:  this all those years ago when you started working on, on Allied
Speaker 5:  So I guess like the origin story? I think like the
Speaker 5:  first, the first code commit for a Halide was 2014.
Speaker 5:  For about like one day it's pronounced
Speaker 1:  How, actually
Speaker 5:  I don't, I'm gonna switch three times over. Oh my god.
Speaker 1:  All over the place.
Speaker 5:  So for Halladay in 2014 it was like
Speaker 5:  three lines of code and then put away until like 2016.
Speaker 5:  And so I'd say that in 2016 none of this computational
Speaker 5:  photography was happening. It was to,
Speaker 5:  to put it simply, a lot of these apps were just wrappers around the, the,
Speaker 5:  the APIs that Apple gave you and it was just a more pretty veneer. And so
Speaker 5:  we, we were doing at the time was, and then I connected with Sebastian in
Speaker 5:  2016, like we were adding a value like focus
Speaker 5:  peaking so that you could actually tell what was in focus. You could dial
Speaker 5:  in manual values, but for the most part until Apple released
Speaker 5:  raw that up there about it, it it was that you had no
Speaker 5:  real say on how the final image would look.
Speaker 6:  And what's interesting is, I think when it came out, so highlight is, is
Speaker 6:  now seven years old. It's, it, it came out in 2017,
Speaker 6:  that's exactly when the iPhone 10 launched that year. And with the iPhone
Speaker 6:  10, I think Apple started using the word smart HDR for the first time and
Speaker 6:  that kind of, they started using that very famous slide where it take one
Speaker 6:  photo and it kind of onion slice it into like 12 of them and it to try to
Speaker 6:  show you like, oh look, we look, we do a lot of stuff and there's a lot of
Speaker 6:  smart things happening here. And I think that was, you know, around the same
Speaker 6:  band that Pixel started, you know, talking, the Pixel team started talking
Speaker 6:  about like the Italian renaissance and how we can use science to influence
Speaker 6:  things. It was, it was a very early time where people were trying to figure
Speaker 6:  out like how do we get better images out of these tiny sensors? And that's
Speaker 6:  when everything exploded with like night mode and all those kind of things.
Speaker 6:  When it basically turned photography from just taking
Speaker 6:  a snap to like a data science and it was like, okay, no, if we actually
Speaker 6:  just use these processors and like do a crazy amount of computation on it,
Speaker 6:  we can fundamentally alter the output and we can just,
Speaker 6:  we can beat physics, we can just cheat it. Like we can do depths of field,
Speaker 6:  we can all these things that big cameras can because they have giant lenses
Speaker 6:  and giant sensors we can shoot at night and we can totally take photos with
Speaker 6:  like bouquet. It's not real, but nobody cares because you're still taking
Speaker 6:  a photo at night, you're still taking a photo with what looks like a shell
Speaker 6:  depth of field. And so we were kind of emerging at
Speaker 6:  the same time as that all emerging. So,
Speaker 1:  And and how much control over that stuff do you get? Like do you look
Speaker 1:  at that in those early days as like, oh my God, look at this incredible toolkit,
Speaker 1:  we suddenly have to play with all of the, the light that this thing is
Speaker 1:  capturing instead of just doing like a thing at the end of the pipeline?
Speaker 1:  Or is it like, oh, this is barely photography
Speaker 1:  anymore. What, what, how do we deal with this? Like what, how do you look
Speaker 1:  at that when those tools start to come available?
Speaker 5:  I, I'd say like around 2020 is when things started to converge of where
Speaker 5:  things were getting a lot smarter. Also, we had like this existential question
Speaker 5:  of why should our app exist when the first party cameras getting so much
Speaker 5:  better? And fortunately both Sebastian and I were already shooting raw
Speaker 5:  photography, which in a nutshell means that you're capturing
Speaker 5:  the sensor data as a file and then you can bring it into a third party app
Speaker 5:  like Lightroom and you can make different decisions on how you wanna process
Speaker 5:  the final image. And so around 2020 was like we were starting to see like,
Speaker 5:  wait a minute, like what Apple's doing is great, you tap a button and anyone
Speaker 5:  can get a good photo. Like my parents who don't know anything about photography
Speaker 5:  tap a button and they got a photo of their grandchild, right? But If, you
Speaker 5:  looked at the underlying sensor, apple is kind of underselling like
Speaker 5:  how much better the hardware was getting. And then over time the sensors
Speaker 5:  were getting bigger and better, the optics were getting better. And so that's
Speaker 5:  when we started being like, wait a minute, like how can we build a feature
Speaker 5:  around this where it stands on its own?
Speaker 7:  One of the questions I have about RAW is what it has
Speaker 7:  come to signify what is a raw photo? Yeah, yeah, exactly.
Speaker 7:  Not, not quite that, but people are like,
Speaker 7:  I don't like my iPhone 15 camera or I don't like my iPhone 14 camera.
Speaker 7:  And then you see in the comments on social media, people say, oh
Speaker 7:  you should shoot raw. And my reaction to that is like, that
Speaker 7:  is, that's a horrible suggestion, but all it really, because
Speaker 7:  you're gonna get this giant file and you actually have to process it to a
Speaker 7:  look. But what it really means is, oh, there's a way to turn
Speaker 7:  off this processing, right? Even inside of Apple's like pro raw system,
Speaker 7:  you're gonna generate a file that lets you
Speaker 7:  turn off this ultra HDR look. And that just means
Speaker 7:  something to people. And the fact that the word is raw I think is deeply
Speaker 7:  fascinating. Like the word and what it means and what you get are all kind
Speaker 7:  of wrapped up in a mess. But you guys are describing
Speaker 7:  like, we're gonna take the sensor data and start making different kinds of
Speaker 7:  images with it.
Speaker 5:  I, I think we make an effort to say native raw versus pro raw because what
Speaker 5:  Apple calls raw in pro raw is not technically raw.
Speaker 5:  And If, you read the comments on a photography website like a pet aix,
Speaker 5:  I'm sorry, but it'll be just constantly that guy being
Speaker 5:  like, you know, it's not really raw and like, yeah, yeah. Cool. Awesome.
Speaker 5:  Well
Speaker 7:  Explain the difference for people who don't, who aren't as deep in the weeds
Speaker 7:  as we are. What is, what is Apple's version of pro raw? What is your definition
Speaker 7:  of native
Speaker 5:  Raw? So technically raw is you have these sensors
Speaker 5:  that have voltage values from light converted to, you know,
Speaker 5:  these numbers, right? And then that's it. And then you need to run an
Speaker 5:  algorithm to take on the sensor. There's this Bayer filter which
Speaker 5:  are discreet red, green and blue values. So it needs to kind of mush 'em
Speaker 5:  up in a blender and it's all like, it's like basically like If you were to
Speaker 5:  buy the ingredients of making a cake and then the JPEG
Speaker 5:  is the final cake. Well I guess pro raw
Speaker 5:  is kinda like a half-baked cake. Like, like you get to pick the
Speaker 5:  frosting If you, If you like sprinkles, whatever,
Speaker 5:  raisins, I hate you. But pro raw is Apple solution to what you're
Speaker 5:  just talking about where it felt like you needed a PhD in image
Speaker 5:  processing to take one of these native raws and make them approximate
Speaker 5:  anything that Apple has. And that's partly because Apple, when they take
Speaker 5:  a photo, they're actually taking a burst of nine photos and then merging
Speaker 5:  them together. So the concept of having any of these Bayer underlying
Speaker 5:  values just doesn't exist anymore because it's all gonna be squashed
Speaker 5:  together to create smart HDR to reduce noise and do all these effects.
Speaker 5:  I really wish Apple hadn't said pro raw because it's, it's gonna haunt me
Speaker 5:  for the rest of my life explaining this to people. But it's like kind of
Speaker 5:  halfway between the native raw and the final jpeg.
Speaker 6:  And I think what is a really important thing to say there? 'cause I see a
Speaker 6:  lot of people saying something like, oh, like
Speaker 6:  this is just the same, like If, you just take a raw photo. That that in itself
Speaker 6:  is a really fascinating sort of phrase because If you say a raw photo,
Speaker 6:  a raw file technically is not a photo yet. So what, what Ben said, you know
Speaker 6:  it's like you got this sensor data, red green two, green two
Speaker 6:  to one blue, one red subpixels to make up the pixels. All that data needs
Speaker 6:  to be combined. You can think of it as kind of a giant spreadsheet that just
Speaker 6:  like has all these values of what the sensor caught in that moment in time
Speaker 6:  from one photo, one important, one photo.
Speaker 6:  And that's not a picture like you have to process
Speaker 6:  a native raw file to get the photo out of it. So per
Speaker 6:  definition, a raw file has to be processed for it to be displayed on a screen.
Speaker 6:  It actually has too much information to even be displayed on a screen. And
Speaker 6:  so a pro pro raw file is, is essentially already done that step. It has
Speaker 6:  created an image because a lot of the processing that happens on iPhone images
Speaker 6:  requires it to become an RGB image, a bitmap essentially. And so it's a
Speaker 6:  very deep image with separate information for stuff like what Neil mentioned,
Speaker 6:  like the tone mapping, which you now have the tone control for, for iPhone
Speaker 6:  16 that's separately stored in the profile game table. So you can now
Speaker 6:  adjust just how much that HDR effect is. You can adjust a white balance completely,
Speaker 6:  you can adjust the amount of sharpening. Noise reduction is something that
Speaker 6:  is baked in per se, and not just because Apple thinks
Speaker 6:  noise shouldn't exist, like notably native raw files have a lot of noise
Speaker 6:  because you have a tiny sensor, you can have a lot of noise but If, you combine
Speaker 6:  images, you can think of it If, you perfectly combine the same image. Noise
Speaker 6:  is different for every frame. So you're gonna average out the noise no matter
Speaker 6:  what you do. If you're combining images
Speaker 5:  Behind the scenes, like when we're talking about raws, we've been trying
Speaker 5:  to call them digital negatives, which I
Speaker 5:  don't know if that's any better for casual users, but it's the same concept
Speaker 5:  of when you had film photography you would have a negative, but then a
Speaker 5:  lot of the work of great photographers would be during the development
Speaker 5:  where you would take the negative and print it on paper, you would dodge
Speaker 5:  and burn it to recover the dynamic range, which is now an algorithm that
Speaker 5:  Apple does for you. But like there's really cool videos of like Ansel Adams
Speaker 5:  with some of his majestic landscapes, he's kind of doing like analog
Speaker 5:  photoshopping where he is like, okay, I gotta bring back some of the sky
Speaker 5:  values and bump this part up. So this isn't particularly
Speaker 5:  new, but Apple gives you like, okay, you want it on or off or
Speaker 5:  somewhere in between. That's all right. You can have any colors as long as
Speaker 5:  it's black, like Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Well I was just gonna say it's, it's just fascinating to me that a lot of
Speaker 6:  people say, I see all the processing that's happening and and maybe sometimes
Speaker 6:  don't even have a word for it. Like that's kinda like what you're alluding
Speaker 6:  to. Neli is like people are just like taking photos and, and then they take
Speaker 6:  a photo with Disney that's like prefer it even though it, it lacks this absolute
Speaker 6:  like, I mean literally the best teams in the world right now in in photography
Speaker 6:  are working at Google, are working at Samsung, are working at Huawei, at
Speaker 6:  Apple, like to make this pro processing to do all this processing engineering
Speaker 6:  and they work from the silicon up to do like insane innovations and then
Speaker 6:  people, because they're like, haha, that was an app and skip all that and
Speaker 6:  get what of sometimes is an objectively worse image. If you were to objectively
Speaker 6:  judge image quality. But
Speaker 6:  we find that people, yeah, people just seem to have
Speaker 6:  a current preference for authenticity through imperfection I think. And that
Speaker 6:  is really interesting.
Speaker 1:  I just keep coming back to this idea that like, and we've talked a bunch
Speaker 1:  about this on the show, that there is this increasingly pervasive feeling
Speaker 1:  among people that their iPhone camera in particular is bad. And,
Speaker 1:  and I think like to your point, the the on any objective
Speaker 1:  measure of quality, it, it gets better and better and better. And yet people
Speaker 1:  seem to like it less and less at the end. And
Speaker 1:  I like that disconnect is so fascinating to me because, and and it goes back
Speaker 1:  to what you were saying about like the, the iPhone has decided that noise
Speaker 1:  is bad period, right? Like it noise sucks, shadows
Speaker 1:  suck, they should not be allowed and we will get rid of them at all costs.
Speaker 1:  And I think like to your point about imperfections, like I think that's right
Speaker 1:  and I think everybody has sort of ideas about what older photos
Speaker 1:  look like and there is a thing where like photos can be too good, but I also
Speaker 1:  think as the hardware has gotten better, the software has
Speaker 1:  gotten vastly more opinionated about how a photo is supposed to look
Speaker 1:  in a way that just feels sort of incongruous, right? And, and like maybe
Speaker 1:  what's happening now is we're getting some of that choice back where it's
Speaker 1:  like, oh the hardware's really good, you can do a bunch of stuff with it.
Speaker 1:  Here are some options. and it seems like maybe that's what you, you
Speaker 1:  guys have even seen as developers is some of those tools are becoming available
Speaker 1:  to you to make available to other people and that actually that's what people
Speaker 1:  want now is some, some choice back with all this great hardware
Speaker 1:  instead of just wild new ideas about shadows.
Speaker 5:  So actually can I just dial back, I just said that process
Speaker 5:  zero is rebranded raw and I can already see a thousand comments on Pet
Speaker 5:  Aix and I thank you for pointing out haunted
Speaker 1:  By the comment section
Speaker 6:  On Pix. That's what I'm
Speaker 5:  Getting from you. Yeah, yeah. No, it's, I I think that it, you know, but
Speaker 5:  that's between me and my therapist. Now the, the, the, the thing is
Speaker 5:  what the value add here is that we do have opinions about, you know, there's
Speaker 5:  a million different ways that we could develop the raw. And what I think
Speaker 5:  with Process zero is we decided we like noise. I have
Speaker 5:  a friend who works in visual effects and he calls noise analog
Speaker 5:  dithering. And you can't remove noise without removing these
Speaker 5:  details because that's what the was captured at the time. We have opinions
Speaker 5:  on sharpening, our images are a little softer by design
Speaker 5:  and If, you look at, you know, you look at analog photography
Speaker 5:  actually last summer before we really went all in on this, I was shooting
Speaker 5:  with a, a Cannon AE one on 35 millimeter film
Speaker 5:  and I was like, oh, it just feels so warm. Like it's, it's so flawed but
Speaker 5:  I love it the fact that you can't get this crazy HDR in there.
Speaker 5:  And I think the challenge is gonna be as we're building out more features
Speaker 5:  and we start, you know, adding the ability, like in the future If you wanna
Speaker 5:  recover dynamic range, okay, at what point do we allow users to make fake
Speaker 5:  looking images, right? It's something we'll have to face in
Speaker 5:  the future.
Speaker 1:  That's a big question. And at what point does something become fake looking
Speaker 1:  is like back to big philosophical existential questions about photos. Like
Speaker 1:  where to draw that line is super messy.
Speaker 6:  I think one of the things that you're touching on that route too is like
Speaker 6:  at some point these cameras all started looking very similar, right? So you
Speaker 6:  get your photo out of Samsung phone of the pixel of the iPhone and they all
Speaker 6:  look like they boost the shadows way up and there there could
Speaker 6:  not be any reduction or clipping of dynamic range that is just considered
Speaker 6:  data loss. We cannot have any noise. We've all agreed on that. And I think
Speaker 6:  what the, that's simply the result of making a camera for the greatest common
Speaker 6:  denominator. Like this is a camera used to work for everyone. I think at
Speaker 6:  some point someone was mentioning like, oh I use my camera for like reading
Speaker 6:  like a serial number on the bottom of like a car or something, right? Like
Speaker 6:  at that point like If, you don't If you get an artistic photo that just has
Speaker 6:  like really nice kora rendering that's really cool for you but like this
Speaker 6:  camera literally doesn't work for me anymore. And so that's a really, really
Speaker 6:  difficult position to be in. I often tell people like, wow, I, I
Speaker 6:  would on the one side it's a fascinating job to design the camera at Apple,
Speaker 6:  but at the same time I have to make a camera that works for my one and a
Speaker 6:  half year old daughter and like my 80-year-old father and myself
Speaker 6:  like who is like an incredibly pedantic annoying photographer that frequents
Speaker 6:  the pet of pixel comment section. Maybe it's simply the time that like cameras
Speaker 6:  do allow, and this is what app skater too do allow people to like find their
Speaker 6:  own style and shoot in a different way. And you see that now with like the
Speaker 6:  very on apple like thing of like adding so much control to like what kind
Speaker 6:  of like final output you get in your image. And maybe that goes down to processing
Speaker 6:  too because processing I think people are becoming aware of how many creative
Speaker 6:  decisions are being made for you. And that's fascinating to me because there
Speaker 6:  was one time like in 2020 a year of unprecedented times, if I wanna like
Speaker 6:  pull an anecdote where people ran into this 'cause they were all taking photos
Speaker 6:  with their Samsung or Pixel or iPhone and they woke up in San
Speaker 6:  Francisco one day and the entire city was orange. Like completely orange
Speaker 6:  because there was a huge wildfire near the place where I live now. Yep. And
Speaker 6:  the sun was being filtered through it and it was all orange and people took
Speaker 6:  a photo with it and the craziest thing happened, the camera recognized it
Speaker 6:  as being like, oh the white balance is way off, we're gonna correct for that.
Speaker 6:  This doesn't really happen because it's trained on everything that's happened
Speaker 6:  before it. and it has, it's literally old, its smart stuff is
Speaker 6:  based on precedent and we were in 2020 living in
Speaker 6:  unprecedented times and so people started downloading like a camera
Speaker 6:  app like ours to you know, like try to correct that set manual wide
Speaker 6:  balance. And that I think was like beginning to be the turning point
Speaker 6:  around when people started like exploring options like that and being aware
Speaker 6:  of something like that existing. Like they were aware that as they took a
Speaker 6:  photo like, oh wait, it's doing something for me and I don't like
Speaker 6:  that it's doing that. And that has become a greater
Speaker 6:  awareness even in like Gen Z even in people who don't know what a file is,
Speaker 6:  they know that processing is a thing and that that increasingly is making
Speaker 6:  decisions for them to go on a long rant. But yeah,
Speaker 7:  One question I have, and I I've talked to you about this ever so slightly.
Speaker 7:  So
Speaker 7:  Apple designs the camera is a system, Samsung is a system, Google
Speaker 7:  is a system, you've got the hardware, the lens, and then you've got a processing
Speaker 7:  pipeline to lean on and they obviously know exactly what's gonna happen in
Speaker 7:  their processing pipeline. In the case of Apple, they're designing their
Speaker 7:  own chip as part of that processing pipeline and it feels like they can
Speaker 7:  make decisions about what they can handle in
Speaker 7:  processing at the expense of what the hardware can do.
Speaker 7:  And If, you all are making an app that just pulls the raw data off the
Speaker 7:  sensor. Apple gets to say, well we know there's gonna be some
Speaker 7:  fringing, we know there's gonna be some distortion in this lens, but we're
Speaker 7:  gonna optimize it to collect all the light we can because our pipeline
Speaker 7:  can fix almost anything except not having the light. Has that come up for
Speaker 7:  you now in these, in the newer versions of the phone where you can see that
Speaker 7:  optimization starting to shift against like quality
Speaker 7:  outta the lens for lack of a better term, in favor of just light collection?
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  the, that was actually one of the craziest things I saw when we started shooting
Speaker 6:  a lot of native raw and 'cause for a while I was just like pro rah maxing,
Speaker 6:  like just shooting on pro rah all the time. And then I was like, okay, let's
Speaker 6:  go back to native raw for a second. I noticed that the output was just getting
Speaker 6:  a little, was just getting a little worse. Like if I were to objectively
Speaker 6:  look at it, you know, and just take a this again to clarify the difference
Speaker 6:  between pro rah and and native raws. You get raw sensor data, which you just,
Speaker 6:  I just quickly throw in Lightroom to develop it. Lightroom processes that
Speaker 6:  sensor data and spits it out. There's actually some corrections already baked
Speaker 6:  into that. So some of the pipeline does raw data at on the Apple
Speaker 6:  iPhone and some of it gen it starts converting it to images so it can start
Speaker 6:  merging geometric geometry, corrections, those kind of things.
Speaker 6:  For instance, your ultra wide camera will have a lot of corrections because
Speaker 6:  otherwise it looks like a crazy fish island basically. Right? And then, yeah,
Speaker 6:  we noticed a few years ago, like the main camera especially, which is the
Speaker 6:  one that needs to gather the most light, you know, the camera people use
Speaker 6:  for 99% of the time it has more color fringing than it has in the past. and
Speaker 6:  we, we, we, I think we talked about it as in person briefly neli. I was like,
Speaker 6:  no, like the crazy thing that's happening here is they just,
Speaker 6:  there's a realization there. They're like, oh wait, it might be color
Speaker 6:  fringing, but we can just fix that in the pipeline if we get more light in.
Speaker 6:  We can just correct that out and the, the smart fuckable make
Speaker 6:  up for what would traditionally be considered a bad, the worst photographic
Speaker 6:  lens, right? If it just, it just becomes a data problem essentially.
Speaker 6:  And that is coming up a little bit and I wrote a little bit, I just published
Speaker 6:  a review of the iPhone 16 yesterday and I wrote like,
Speaker 6:  look, you gotta get used to processing because gadgets in our phones,
Speaker 6:  I can, I can see going in one direction David, I I'm, I feel like you're
Speaker 6:  like the pixel fold kind of guy, but like you're gonna get devices that are
Speaker 6:  thinner and folding and sometimes they fold three ways. Now in China here,
Speaker 6:  the devices are folding three ways. It's, it, it's, it's going, it it's going
Speaker 6:  that way. We're not going to opt for thicker phones and bigger cameras
Speaker 6:  and to make cameras work that are smaller and thinner and tinier and fit
Speaker 6:  into like very small headsets and ray band glasses. We're gonna need more
Speaker 6:  processing because the sensors, the images aren't gonna get any better. That's
Speaker 6:  just physics So I fully believe that, you know, as
Speaker 6:  we go towards slimmer and foldable iPhones or whatever
Speaker 6:  the, our output on something like a process zero image is probably gonna
Speaker 6:  get objectively worse. That's just the way it is. But old fashioned photography
Speaker 6:  in that way, that's just, I don't know how long that's gonna be around
Speaker 6:  on these kind of devices as they get smarter and smarter. 'cause they'll
Speaker 6:  just start relying more on the fact that they're magic, hyper powerful computers
Speaker 6:  and they're not gonna rely on the fact that they're good at collecting light
Speaker 6:  'cause they're just not.
Speaker 7:  Wait. So let me ask you about that. Let me send you all the way down the
Speaker 7:  existential rabbit hole. This is where I live down. Welcome to the basement
Speaker 7:  with me
Speaker 7:  at the end of this, right? You're, you, you, the hardware is just there
Speaker 7:  to collect light and everything else happens in
Speaker 7:  the processing stack. Everything else is an average of values from the past,
Speaker 7:  right? Is that, do you see that all the way at the end that it,
Speaker 7:  you just spin the dial all the way on the path that we're on and we don't
Speaker 7:  really care if the sensor is any good or the lens is any good as long as
Speaker 7:  we can collect as much massive light as possible.
Speaker 6:  See I think that's a great philosophical question because If, you come down
Speaker 6:  to it every, you can solve it the way the Samsung moon photo situation happens.
Speaker 6:  Most of the world is completely been captured before and done before If.
Speaker 6:  you train a good enough model with a bad enough sensor, you can probably
Speaker 6:  take photos of 99.95% of the things out there and they'll be really good.
Speaker 6:  So like, I don't know, that seems kind of like the
Speaker 6:  reality that we're heading towards where the processing is just simply good
Speaker 6:  enough and the reality does, the reality of capturing images just needs to
Speaker 6:  correspond to like what the internal logic can cor can, can
Speaker 6:  cohere together. And I personally philosophically find that a really big
Speaker 6:  problem. I want to make a camera that like If you go
Speaker 6:  to on the, what is a photo thing? I was talking to Ben about this, I was
Speaker 6:  like, we should probably think about what we consider to be a photo. And
Speaker 6:  to me it is an image that's generated largely majority, at least by photons
Speaker 6:  that you have captured at a moment in space and time. But I'm not sure if
Speaker 6:  that is going to be the case. I think in the future, some cameras, maybe
Speaker 6:  not all of them, but some cameras are going to increasingly rely on data
Speaker 6:  sets of what the world should look like and what images should look like
Speaker 6:  and just use data, use light as data, not as like
Speaker 6:  visual aid as much.
Speaker 1:  What is allied for all the way at the end of that road? Like what's, what's
Speaker 1:  your job when we get all the way to the end of that?
Speaker 5:  Well I mean like the invention of the automobile didn't
Speaker 5:  put an end to horses. It's just horses were allowed to be this fun
Speaker 5:  thing, you gotta look at 'em and ride 'em and stuff, right? But as far as
Speaker 5:  utility for every day, you know, people stopped keeping barns I guess.
Speaker 5:  Okay. And I mean like look, you know, photography didn't end
Speaker 5:  painting, painting. The reason people look at paintings is because the amount
Speaker 5:  of skill and craftsmanship that goes into it and being able to work within
Speaker 5:  these constraints. And again, it was really eye-opening last summer shooting
Speaker 5:  analog because there's just something about an analog
Speaker 5:  photo and actually the removal of details, right? And So
Speaker 5:  I don't know if anyone tried to watch one of these high frame rate movies
Speaker 5:  like The Hobbit at 48 frames per second or, or that HDR
Speaker 5:  Will Smith movie, the one with his clone, what was it called? Gemini Man,
Speaker 5:  there we go. Yeah. and it goes ultra high frame rate HDR. And what
Speaker 5:  ends up happening with movies is when you shoot high frame rate ultra realism,
Speaker 5:  it breaks the magic because your mind isn't able to fill in the
Speaker 5:  details and it turns out 24 frames per second with a slow shutter, like it
Speaker 5:  feels more dreamlike and you're able to suspend disbelief, right? And so
Speaker 5:  with photography, there's just something about a photo that is less perfect
Speaker 5:  that, that feels magical about it. So I think there's always gonna be that
Speaker 5:  as an art form and but as far as something that you're gonna
Speaker 5:  just tap a button and get a nice photo, you know, I think that we are smart
Speaker 5:  enough that we're never gonna enter that kind of battle with a world's most
Speaker 5:  valuable company.
Speaker 7:  Well lemme say this, just to put your definition in the test photons you
Speaker 7:  collected in a moment in space and time, right? I buy that, that's a pretty
Speaker 7:  good definition app. Does that count if you're taking nine photos and merging
Speaker 7:  them that that moment has extended to nine captures, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So I think so. The the thing is like, let's say,
Speaker 6:  you know, and the same thing goes for cleaning up, like let's say use AI
Speaker 6:  cleanup to, to, to erase a part of the photo. I feel, I still think it's
Speaker 6:  a photo, but once you fill that in with the majority of a cleanup feature,
Speaker 6:  so like 50% or more of the pixels become filled in by a model, I feel
Speaker 6:  like it see, it ceases to be a photo meaning in a meaningful way because
Speaker 6:  it has now been filled in by a data set.
Speaker 7:  You guys are are making a tool. It sounds very much like you're focused on
Speaker 7:  the creative and artistic aspects of photography. There's a whole other conversation
Speaker 7:  about can we trust these images that exists in the world. Have you looked
Speaker 7:  at the various watermarking features from C two PA
Speaker 7:  that say, actually this happened, right? This photo of Donald Trump, it
Speaker 7:  occurred. We're gonna mark it, we're gonna send it to Getty. Getty's gonna
Speaker 7:  know this was real. This, this photos were marked at, at the camera level
Speaker 7:  when they went to to Getty. Have you looked at doing that? Is that something
Speaker 7:  you're allowed to do on iOS?
Speaker 5:  That's all bullshit. Am I allowed to swear? Like if not, like write down.
Speaker 5:  Okay, good. Yeah, you're allowed to swear. So alright. Everything that Adobe's
Speaker 5:  pushing as far as like content authenticity is, it's just, it's like
Speaker 5:  DKS and anti DVD kind of stuff in the two thousands. It's
Speaker 5:  like I If you look at it, the ability to just strip the metadata, the fact
Speaker 5:  that you can just point your camera at a screen and take a photo. Like
Speaker 5:  it's not gonna do anything other than convince people to sign up for Creative
Speaker 5:  Cloud and use Adobe products. I I, I don't know,
Speaker 5:  I I don't know how much deeper you want get in that, but I don't Right.
Speaker 5:  Think it's a, a useful use of time. Although they do have a verification
Speaker 5:  feature where I think it does like a signature of like you can, I
Speaker 5:  think kinda like c sam detection. Like it'll get a signature of a photo you
Speaker 5:  could drag and drop it to UI and it, whoever first posted it, like it'll
Speaker 5:  tell you who did that. That's pretty cool. But the rest of the stuff is just
Speaker 5:  a waste of time. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I'm just curious. It, this is right next to the creative part of how much
Speaker 7:  can I change this or how much data processing can I do is the, how much can
Speaker 7:  I trust this? and it feels like both of those are
Speaker 7:  unsolved.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. When we launched process zero, like I thought I was talking to Ben,
Speaker 6:  I was like, can we use the fact that we shoot a jpeg that is the process
Speaker 6:  zero component and like the raw the the sensor again the sensor single shot
Speaker 6:  raw Bayer data as sort of a pro proof of provenance, like a proof
Speaker 6:  like that. There are not a lot of data sets of generative ai,
Speaker 6:  if any. I haven't found any at least that work on raw files. Right? But consider
Speaker 6:  conceivably you could totally do it. That's the thing. So it's, it's, it's
Speaker 6:  not a good, you know, it'd be a fig leaf of authenticity. It would be like,
Speaker 6:  look, there is a raw file. You can see that it was actually taken. But
Speaker 6:  you know, like it's still, it's just a such a losing battle.
Speaker 6:  We the we at some point, you philosophically as a, as a photographer or a
Speaker 6:  camera app maker or both or esteem member of photography,
Speaker 6:  common sections, you, you just go through the same existential crisis and
Speaker 6:  you just realize, okay, there's nothing stopping this.
Speaker 5:  And can I just back up to what you were saying about like editing photos
Speaker 5:  and where's the line that you're gonna draw? So in 2016 there was
Speaker 5:  a famous National Geographic photographer, Steve McCurry, and
Speaker 5:  so he got into hot water because people noticed one of his award-winning
Speaker 5:  photos was actually different on his website because there's like a dude
Speaker 5:  in the background who wasn't in the final award-winning photo. And people
Speaker 5:  started digging into it and like basically he would use what is
Speaker 5:  iOS eighteen's object removal feature before it existed. He did
Speaker 5:  that equivalent kind of editing. And this was a huge, like, you, you don't
Speaker 5:  do that if you're actually taking photos. So
Speaker 5:  I, I, and I guess this is also a question for you as journalists, like when
Speaker 5:  you, at what point when you're doing like an interview
Speaker 5:  or you're transcribing, you're pulling quotes, at what point is it okay to
Speaker 5:  remove the likes and the buts? You'll be doing a lot of that with me
Speaker 5:  and thank you,
Speaker 7:  But,
Speaker 5:  But at what point are you then editorializing what you're trying
Speaker 5:  to capture and telling a story that actually didn't occur and
Speaker 5:  effectively, you know, everyone has to have that level of journalistic integrity
Speaker 5:  if they wanna call it a photo.
Speaker 7:  So David and I are both gonna answer on three and we're gonna see if we have
Speaker 7:  the same answer. Okay.
Speaker 7:  I actually, I'll let David answer my, my quick version of that is,
Speaker 7:  that's norms, that's professional norms, that's what you're describing. Yep.
Speaker 7:  Right. This guy was a professional photographer, he entered a professional
Speaker 7:  photography contest, he broke the rules, he got kicked out and they got in
Speaker 7:  trouble. You're a journalist, you get a bunch of quotes, you go
Speaker 7:  too sideways, you're over the line, right? Like the journalist
Speaker 7:  club will, if it still exists, will will get mad
Speaker 7:  at you and your, your reputation will suffer If you're a Getty photographer,
Speaker 7:  there's a, there's a list of rules of things you're allowed to edit and most
Speaker 7:  of them are like, you can change exposure and that's about it, right? You
Speaker 7:  can do some vignetting If, you look at, at New York Times photos, all they're
Speaker 7:  allowed to do is vignette. So they're all just vignette to hell and back.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Because that's the only button they get. So like that's professional
Speaker 7:  norms. I don't know what consumer norms are gonna be and what we're seeing
Speaker 7:  is an explosion of consumer photography and that I think is really challenging.
Speaker 7:  I dunno, David, what, what's your answer?
Speaker 1:  I, I I think about the same. I mean there's been a, a big discussion this
Speaker 1:  year about how people transcribe
Speaker 1:  Donald Trump. There, there's been all this stuff about sane washing Donald Trump
Speaker 1:  where he'll, he'll go on like a nine minute ramble of nonsense
Speaker 1:  and then a, a reporter will, will essentially try to make it make sense,
Speaker 1:  which on the one hand is like good, useful journalism. Like here
Speaker 1:  are the words that he was trying to say. On the other hand, it makes somebody
Speaker 1:  who doesn't make any sense makes some sense. And I think
Speaker 1:  it's, it's a complicated thing. Like at what point is my job to make
Speaker 1:  something, make as much sense as possible. So I can help my reader understand
Speaker 1:  and at what point is my job to represent something as it was
Speaker 1:  in all its messiness. Yeah. And it's like, it, I think it is kind of a perfect
Speaker 1:  analogy for what we're trying to do with photography and I, I don't have
Speaker 1:  great answers, right? Because it's, especially when it's messy how
Speaker 1:  uny you're supposed to make it, it's really complicated.
Speaker 7:  And, and really the question is, can you make everybody believed
Speaker 7:  in the professional norm? And the answer is just like, obviously no
Speaker 5:  So I guess the closest that we have around ethics right now is
Speaker 5:  Apple's decision that they're not gonna allow fully generated AI
Speaker 5:  in iOS 18. And there was the interview with Gruber where they're talking
Speaker 5:  like, okay, we're gonna generate cartoons, but we're not gonna generate
Speaker 5:  photorealistic stuff. And so that's nice when you have someone who is,
Speaker 5:  you know, not enabling outright bad actions,
Speaker 5:  although then you have someone like Google who's also letting you like yeah,
Speaker 5:  just change the background type in what you want.
Speaker 6:  That does like, remind me of like that amazing quote that Neli got from
Speaker 6:  Apple's John McCormack that basically was like, okay, we believe a photo
Speaker 6:  is a thing that really happened, which is still not going as far as saying
Speaker 6:  like a photo is a thing you capture with a camera or is light that is captured.
Speaker 6:  It is a thing that happened, which totally fits in the model of having a
Speaker 6:  generated future where there is a super great Apple model that will just
Speaker 6:  basically fill in the blanks if the image data isn't good enough. It just
Speaker 6:  needs to confirm that a thing has actually happened. So it's like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  like surely we will continue to have journalistic standards and there will
Speaker 6:  be a few of these things like C two PA to work in
Speaker 6:  their niches, but I mean, there's no stopping
Speaker 6:  the train that's heading down the tracks of like the absolute apocalypse
Speaker 6:  of like what the meaning the meaningfulness of photos on the internet. I
Speaker 6:  I truly think if I look at my daughter, she's one and a half years old now
Speaker 6:  when she's a teenager, I don't think she will believe any single image she
Speaker 6:  sees on the internet.
Speaker 1:  I think the, the piece of this could think is lost in a lot of this conversation
Speaker 1:  I think is like we, we talk a lot about the sort of really
Speaker 1:  high stakes photos and we talk a lot about
Speaker 1:  like the photos of a serial number, right? But I think like Sebastian,
Speaker 1:  to your point, you, you have a young kid. I, I think I have a young
Speaker 1:  kid, ELA has young kids, Ben, I don't, I don't know.
Speaker 5:  I got one. He is got hand foot and mouth disease right now, so yeah. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Good times all around. But I think like Sebastian, to your point, your kid
Speaker 1:  will probably grow up in a world where they don't believe photos they see
Speaker 1:  on the internet. I think that's probably right. But the question of like,
Speaker 1:  will they believe photos about themselves from when they were kids? Mm. Is
Speaker 1:  is the other part of this that I think is like complicated and is is such
Speaker 1:  a like normal everyday use case. We don't talk about in this context,
Speaker 1:  but the, the question of like, when I, when I take pictures of my
Speaker 1:  kid, what is, what is what responsibility
Speaker 1:  in in air quotes, do I have to like truth and honesty versus like taking
Speaker 1:  a fun picture of my child having fun
Speaker 1:  I feel like is is such a like mainstream every single person
Speaker 1:  use case that we just don't talk about enough because it, I it feels
Speaker 1:  mely, but I don't know. And as you guys think about tallied, like people
Speaker 1:  download this stuff in part because they wanna make beautiful art that hangs
Speaker 1:  in museums and in part because they wanna take better pictures that are kids
Speaker 1:  and like, what, what is the job there in, in this world?
Speaker 5:  All of my son's photos are in native raw So, I can show him the
Speaker 5:  receipts afterwards.
Speaker 1:  He can develop the negatives themselves. Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  No, but that's, that's a really good point too
Speaker 1:  Birthday here, son, I've made you some negatives.
Speaker 5:  You know, it's important that every dad has a talk with a son about
Speaker 5:  noise reduction. It's dangerous world out there and you know how to be
Speaker 5:  prepared. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  But So I mean to that point. Like some part of me feels like, you know,
Speaker 6:  we're gonna go back and look at, we're gonna recognize this era of
Speaker 6:  mobile photography for looking a certain way. That's just a fact. And
Speaker 6:  we're, look, we're recognizing the first generation of Instagram photos by
Speaker 6:  the heavy filters, which also means people are going look at the first generation
Speaker 6:  of Instagramed photos and be like, oh, these are real, there's no generative
Speaker 6:  AI in them because you can see by how bad these filters are. This was before
Speaker 6:  the end times of photographic integrity, which is fascinating to me by the
Speaker 6:  way that those fake c pia filters are gonna go down in time as like a symbol
Speaker 6:  of authenticity, which at the time were derided as being universally deeply
Speaker 1:  Real Photos. Yeah. Deeply
Speaker 6:  Unreal. Yeah, deeply real Photos must be real. And
Speaker 6:  I think we, we would love to kind of in a same, in, in a way
Speaker 6:  provide that niche too, because we want to offer that extra tool that
Speaker 6:  just gives you a, a more authentic shot because it's a bit more true to like
Speaker 6:  what an old fashioned camera might have captured. It has a bit of less of
Speaker 6:  that process look going on.
Speaker 6:  But two, like I I I also believe those photos are more representative
Speaker 6:  of your memories because they, they are more like the way you remember a
Speaker 6:  moment. Like when I edit my photos, actually, I tend to make the sunsets
Speaker 6:  warmer and the cozy times nicer. And the time when I walked in
Speaker 6:  Tokyo all alone 3:00 AM bluer and more cyber punky because that's just
Speaker 6:  the way it felt. And I think those aren't perfect representations of reality
Speaker 6:  and that greatest common denominator photography thing is kind of what's
Speaker 6:  making people pull towards that a bit more. And maybe also ironically,
Speaker 6:  making the pull more towards generative things or, or more creative ways
Speaker 6:  altering photos because they're deeply unsatisfied with how,
Speaker 6:  how perfectly photos represent reality when they're sensing reality around
Speaker 6:  them, but not the world that they perceive per se,
Speaker 6:  emotionally.
Speaker 1:  Right. We gotta take a break and when we come back we're gonna talk to Allison
Speaker 1:  Johnson about how to take pictures of your kids
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. So the verges, Allison Johnson has been
Speaker 1:  reviewing all of these AI phone cameras for us all summer
Speaker 1:  and she decided to run an experiment on herself that I find very fun. She
Speaker 1:  basically wanted to go all the way in and figure
Speaker 1:  out what life is like when you just lean into the AI ness
Speaker 1:  of your phone, all the things it can do for you, all the ways it can change
Speaker 1:  your photos, all the upgrades and cool processing things
Speaker 1:  it can do. Just what If, you didn't have any existential crises
Speaker 1:  about AI photos and cameras and just bought in what would happen?
Speaker 1:  I have been excited for weeks to hear about the results of this
Speaker 1:  experiment and Allison is here now to tell me all about it. Allison, hello.
Speaker 9:  Hello.
Speaker 1:  We're back to talk about phone cameras because that's what you and I do on
Speaker 1:  this show is just talk about our feelings about phone cameras.
Speaker 9:  I love it. I'm here for it.
Speaker 1:  I think that might be the official mission statement of Vergecast at this
Speaker 1:  point, which is weird. We make an audio product about cameras
Speaker 1:  is a thing that I never really thought about.
Speaker 9:  Let's talk about photos for a while. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  So we, we've been looking for different ways to talk about this
Speaker 1:  stuff. Sometimes it's just like me, I having an existential crisis on The
Speaker 1:  Vergecast, but you went out and actually like tried to live
Speaker 1:  out this experiment a little bit in, in what the future of
Speaker 1:  photography looks like. Tell me a little bit about this experiment you've
Speaker 1:  been running.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, so the idea was what if I put myself in this head space
Speaker 9:  of I am using this phone camera to take
Speaker 9:  not photos, but memories
Speaker 9:  and just sort of like, ran with that for a little while.
Speaker 9:  I carried around the Pixel nine pro, the memory
Speaker 9:  making machine that it is and just kind of
Speaker 9:  set out to like, you know, I, I take a thousand
Speaker 9:  pictures of my kid anyway, but I was like, especially on a mission
Speaker 9:  for a, you know, about a week. So we went to
Speaker 9:  this science fair, it was kind of outdoors, indoors,
Speaker 9:  very kind of steam punky, cool, awesome
Speaker 9:  situation. We went to the park, rode in one of those little
Speaker 9:  fake stationary jeeps. He loves that.
Speaker 9:  I went to Starbucks. He is a good sport and, and goes
Speaker 9:  with me to get my coffee. So all of the usual things,
Speaker 9:  I just took photos for a week and
Speaker 9:  brought them into Google photos afterwards and pushed myself to
Speaker 9:  use the tools that I probably wouldn't have done
Speaker 9:  anyway. Like the reimagine, you know, take things outta the frame.
Speaker 9:  Just kind of put myself in an uncomfortable position to like
Speaker 9:  try and use as much of the AI as I could.
Speaker 1:  Well, so it makes me think of a conversation you and I had, this is
Speaker 1:  probably almost a year ago at this point, where we were talking about the
Speaker 1:  thing that happens when you go in and edit a photo
Speaker 1:  and you remember you've edited the photo and that something is sort of
Speaker 1:  inexorably changed when you edit the photo
Speaker 1:  that maybe it's good, maybe it's bad, maybe it doesn't really matter, but
Speaker 1:  like somewhere in your brain, the fact that you moved stuff around
Speaker 1:  inside of the photo becomes attached to that photo.
Speaker 1:  And I feel like a year later we're, we're even deeper into that theory
Speaker 1:  being the way that this works. So I'm, I'm very curious to hear how all of
Speaker 1:  this went, but like give me the, give me the setup how you were thinking
Speaker 1:  about approaching this experiment. 'cause I feel like I wanna make memories,
Speaker 1:  not photos is a very like, beautiful high-minded
Speaker 1:  thing to say that we can interrogate forever. But I'm, I'm curious if you're
Speaker 1:  like, I wanna actually live out this definition and, and I think it's Google
Speaker 1:  in particular, right? That has said a camera is for memories, not for photos.
Speaker 1:  So you're like, I wanna live in the universe. Google imagines, like how do
Speaker 1:  you set yourself up to do that?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it, it was mostly in the, in the back half, like editing
Speaker 9:  the photos. So kind of just went into Google photos on the phone
Speaker 9:  and that's where you get the like reimagine tool and
Speaker 9:  all the AI stuff. So it was like a very
Speaker 9:  uncomfortable territory for me. 'cause I really don't like
Speaker 9:  edit phone photos at all. I just kind of like put
Speaker 9:  all my faith in the computational photography process.
Speaker 9:  So this was an exercise and like sitting down and kind of, I had to kind
Speaker 9:  of clear my mind and be like, okay, what, like what did this moment feel
Speaker 9:  like versus what's here? And sometimes it was obvious. It was
Speaker 9:  like, well this person was in the frame and you
Speaker 9:  know, I, my memory is of my child in this
Speaker 9:  situation not, and this person's distracting, So I would take them out.
Speaker 9:  But then I like pushed myself beyond that to kind of
Speaker 9:  be like, is there something I would add to the scene
Speaker 9:  that would make it feel more kind of like express how, like
Speaker 9:  magical or whatever it felt at the time. Because I think that
Speaker 9:  happens a lot too when you're taking pictures of your kid where like this
Speaker 9:  is such a special moment. And then you go back and there's just like
Speaker 9:  snot all over their nose and they look kind of annoyed. You're like,
Speaker 9:  oh, okay. We missed the mark on that one.
Speaker 1:  But I can imagine to all of that stuff that
Speaker 1:  it, it makes sense that that all comes up in, in the editing process, right?
Speaker 1:  You sit there and you're like, how did I feel and how does this photo feel?
Speaker 1:  And I wanna, I want to interrogate that 'cause I think it's really interesting.
Speaker 1:  But I can also imagine that you would start thinking differently about
Speaker 1:  the kinds of photos you're taking and even like the way you're setting
Speaker 1:  up to take those pictures, right? Like I'm thinking about, I was out
Speaker 1:  with my son yesterday. He loves trains and all he wants to do is
Speaker 1:  there's a, there's a walking path near a train track and he just wants to
Speaker 1:  stand there and wait for trains and a train goes by and he yells and
Speaker 1:  dances and then it leaves and then he just goes more choocho. And then we
Speaker 1:  wait until there's another train and we do that for hours. And
Speaker 1:  I was standing there like when he would get really excited about a train
Speaker 1:  and sort of stop paying attention to me, I would like back up and take a
Speaker 1:  picture of him or, and I was like running around trying to get the angle
Speaker 1:  just right and try to get the, the train in the exact right spot. And I had
Speaker 1:  this thought of like, oh, maybe it, I don't need to do any of this.
Speaker 1:  Like, I'm just gonna stand here and just sort of point my camera in, like
Speaker 1:  his vague direction and then worry about it later. But also maybe
Speaker 1:  like, do I even need this picture in an a, like, I don't know, it just, it
Speaker 1:  sort of messed with your head in terms of just like when you decide to hit
Speaker 1:  the shutter button in the first place, did you have any of that experience?
Speaker 9:  I did and it was like more forcing myself to take
Speaker 9:  a photo when I normally would've been like, this isn't really gonna work.
Speaker 9:  Oh,
Speaker 1:  Interesting.
Speaker 9:  Someone's in the way or you know, I was like, no,
Speaker 9:  I'll take the picture anyway and see what we can do and with ai.
Speaker 9:  So that was kind of more my experience. And so
Speaker 1:  You're kinda like, maybe there's a good picture in here somewhere. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And all I have to do is take the bad one and see what we can do later.
Speaker 1:  Right.
Speaker 9:  It it forced me to take more shots, I guess.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. I am, I'm like a classic parent photographer where
Speaker 9:  my kid was like, we, he was on a bridge in this little park
Speaker 9:  and I'm like waiting for the perfect moment when he's gonna like come running
Speaker 9:  back. Yep. And he's in, you know, framed perfectly in the middle of the
Speaker 9:  bridge and like just didn't cooperate, you know, like
Speaker 9:  he didn't wanna do that. But I'm like, well I'll take pictures anyway and
Speaker 9:  see what I can get away with.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So, and then take me through the editing process a little bit. You,
Speaker 1:  you know, you mentioned you're not really a, a phone editor. I think most
Speaker 1:  people aren't. I'll do occasional, like one
Speaker 1:  edit, a little bit of cropping, a little bit of straightening, maybe like
Speaker 1:  mess with the saturation every now and then. But I think most people
Speaker 1:  just like you take 10, you pick the best one and you put it on Instagram.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like that is, that is the pipeline we've all been taught at this point.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But tell me about the process of going into these photos and, and you
Speaker 1:  open one up in this headspace of, what is the memory here? This feels
Speaker 1:  like a very like, philosophical thing to go through every time.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, yeah. It was odd and it was uncomfortable honestly.
Speaker 9:  But yeah, just kind of taking, taking myself back in in
Speaker 9:  the moment and like opening up those photos and I, I really
Speaker 9:  had to like sit with it for a minute. 'cause I was like, well this is what
Speaker 9:  I remember. Like, it was just like this, you know, he was stand, my husband
Speaker 9:  was standing here holding our child and we were looking at
Speaker 9:  something and then to kind of like, push myself a little bit
Speaker 9:  more. Like the, the one I came up with is like,
Speaker 9:  one of us is always carrying this massive diaper bag like a hundred percent
Speaker 9:  of the time at like a pack mule. And my husband had it,
Speaker 9:  you know, the strap around his shoulder in this
Speaker 9:  photo. And I was like, well, you know, I don't re like remember
Speaker 9:  the diaper bag? Like it's just there like furniture all the time.
Speaker 9:  So I took that out.
Speaker 1:  You sent me a bunch of the photos that you took and I'm looking at them now
Speaker 1:  trying to like, guess which ones you're talking about? Yeah. And there's
Speaker 1:  one, it's, it's your husband. He's holding your, your kid in his right arm
Speaker 1:  and they're looking at like machinery of some kind it looks like. Yeah. Like
Speaker 1:  this looks like a very old printing press is kind of what they're like poking
Speaker 1:  at. Yeah. And all I see on
Speaker 1:  your husband is is T-shirt. Yeah. But you're saying there was a diaper bag?
Speaker 1:  Yeah, a strap of a diaper bag is, am I thinking about the right picture?
Speaker 1:  Do I, am I guessing correctly? That's the one.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Like there's a big black strap and it's, I don't know, it's not like
Speaker 9:  that distracting or anything. You look at it, you're like, yeah, that's the
Speaker 9:  kind of bag you carry around. Sure. If you If, you're hauling a kid everywhere.
Speaker 9:  But yeah, it's, it kind of amazed me just how
Speaker 9:  easily you can take something like that out. And it's not
Speaker 9:  a challenge for generative ai, it's just like, we got
Speaker 9:  it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I'm looking at this now and there's like, there's a little bit of
Speaker 1:  a wrinkle in a black line kind of going across
Speaker 1:  his chest that probably wouldn't be there. But If, you had never said that.
Speaker 1:  I looked at a bunch of these photos being like, okay, where, where did choose
Speaker 1:  ai? What did she did? And this was one where I, I had nothing, no idea. Wouldn't
Speaker 1:  have ever in a million years have noticed that this wasn't in here. Especially
Speaker 1:  at Instagram size. Right. Like even blowing this thing up as big as it goes.
Speaker 9:  Exactly.
Speaker 1:  I never would've noticed. So what, what tools do you end up using
Speaker 1:  in all of this? Are you're just like in Google Photos playing with the AI
Speaker 1:  stuff? Like what did you find yourself gravitating to messing with these
Speaker 1:  photos?
Speaker 9:  I stuck with Google photos and I,
Speaker 9:  some of these photos were taken on an iPhone
Speaker 9:  on in a different session. Sacrilege, you know, I I know
Speaker 9:  still messed with them in Google photos
Speaker 9:  and I uploaded a bunch of them to Instagram, which I
Speaker 9:  also felt weird about, felt like I was tricking my friends. But
Speaker 1:  Wait, why? Tell me more. Why did that feel weird?
Speaker 9:  It feels strange because, you know, like I've changed
Speaker 9:  enough of a lot of these that they're materially
Speaker 9:  like different, you know, I'm like, that is not
Speaker 9:  how that scene looked. One of them is cheesy as hell. There's like
Speaker 9:  birds in the sky that were there. That was the one I was, oh yeah, I really
Speaker 9:  gotta try this. Like,
Speaker 1:  Okay, wait, so let me, can I just explain two that I saw that really jumped
Speaker 1:  out to me? Yeah. There's one that's like the, the, the 10 out of 10 on this
Speaker 1:  scale I would say. Okay. Yeah. Is a, a photo that you took
Speaker 1:  of your son in a park. He's driving like a little, it looks like a little
Speaker 1:  one of those little like stationary cars that you can just sit in. You pretty
Speaker 1:  obviously just put a dinosaur in the background. Yeah, right. There's just
Speaker 1:  a dinosaur there. Now.
Speaker 9:  I had to throw that one into to be a little like, okay, something's up here.
Speaker 9:  Like, please don't believe all of this.
Speaker 1:  I will also say it's not a very good dinosaur. The head is
Speaker 1:  very good.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. The teeth,
Speaker 1:  It just sort of wisps as it turns into its dinosaur body. It
Speaker 9:  Has like, just kind of too many limbs I think. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  But the teeth are pretty scary. But
Speaker 1:  It's still, and it's, this is like the sixth photo in a gallery and I just
Speaker 1:  flip through and it's like, it works. It kind of, it's, it's fun. Like I
Speaker 1:  don't think it's real. Yeah. But it, it does give it a fun like Jurassic
Speaker 1:  parky kind of vibe. I'm into it. Yeah. And then the other one, which is I
Speaker 1:  think the one you were just describing, he's running through,
Speaker 1:  I I wanna say a field, but it's like a field next to some kind of
Speaker 1:  industrial machinery. I don't know what where you were for all of this, but
Speaker 1:  everybody looks like they're having fun. There's an
Speaker 9:  Interesting backstory. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And so this is one that I actually lingered on for a minute because
Speaker 1:  he's, he's running and he is got his right arm up in the air and the sky
Speaker 1:  is beautiful and blue and there is just this big flock of birds basically
Speaker 1:  right above his head.
Speaker 1:  And if it's, if it's not ai,
Speaker 1:  this is like a perfectly reasonable thing to have photographed, right? Like
Speaker 1:  it's, it's, it would, it would be a lovely shot. Like I would be very proud
Speaker 1:  of you for getting this photo with this dimensions in these
Speaker 1:  particular ways. But then I found myself wondering like, okay, are the, are
Speaker 1:  the birds just not there at all? Were the birds like off to the side and
Speaker 1:  she just sort of like grabbed them and moved them over so that they were
Speaker 1:  directly on top of his head? Or is this just a perfectly timed photo? And
Speaker 1:  I think my hunch is you put the birds there, but
Speaker 1:  I couldn't say that with great confidence.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Yeah. I did add the birds. Okay. Wholesale there,
Speaker 9:  there were no birds there. No birds. The funny thing is, we were
Speaker 9:  at this, they called it a science fair. And
Speaker 9:  outside just to the left of where you see Lennox, there's like a
Speaker 9:  giant iron kind of bird sculpture that flaps
Speaker 9:  its wings when you like pull, there's a little pulley. It was
Speaker 9:  so cool. and it was just kind of like,
Speaker 9:  you know, like the sun was hitting just right and it was like so beautiful.
Speaker 9:  And Lennox is kind of running around after we played with this thing and
Speaker 9:  he just looked super happy. I was like, what could I add that would
Speaker 9:  like, make it feel like that moment felt? And
Speaker 9:  I landed on putting these birds in and it just so cheesy and
Speaker 9:  like, I don't enjoy it. Like I look at it, I am like,
Speaker 9:  you know what? The birds are convincing and this is like a
Speaker 9:  pretty photo, but am I gonna like print it
Speaker 9:  and put it on the wall? Like no, I can't.
Speaker 1:  Well, and, and that, I mean, this is where you get back to the, like what
Speaker 1:  is the, what is the memory piece of this? Because I, I think
Speaker 1:  there is some part of this as a viewer that I'm immediately like, oh,
Speaker 1:  what a fun beautiful day outdoors. Right. And that's
Speaker 1:  like you are communicating to me, I think the correct thing.
Speaker 1:  I don't know how much the birds really add to that. Like it's, it's, it's
Speaker 1:  him smiling and running with his arms up that does most of the
Speaker 1:  work in this photo Yeah. Of like communicating the feeling.
Speaker 1:  But putting birds there certainly helps and it makes the photo cooler to
Speaker 1:  look at, but it doesn't sound like it accomplishes anything for you.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I find that really fascinating. Like as the person who is likely
Speaker 1:  to look at this photo the most over time, it doesn't sound
Speaker 1:  like this improve. Like you're not gonna look at this with fonder memories
Speaker 1:  because of the AI birds you put there.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. and it really, it really made me think about the whole exercise
Speaker 9:  is like, who's this for? Is this, would I make these edits for
Speaker 9:  me? So it felt more like what it was in my mind, or
Speaker 9:  am I trying to portray something on social media
Speaker 9:  that's like, looks more idyllic?
Speaker 9:  And I kept coming back to like, we have kind of a set of
Speaker 9:  expectations from like professional photography. Like if we had
Speaker 9:  hired a professional portrait photographer to kind of follow
Speaker 9:  us around for an afternoon, you would sort of expect you
Speaker 9:  like suspend your disbelief a little bit. Like,
Speaker 9:  you know, they, they know how to get the right moment and the right light
Speaker 9:  and like your kids smiling and not screaming and all that stuff.
Speaker 9:  And I think this like, one way that these AI
Speaker 9:  tools is, are maybe intended to be used is to kind of
Speaker 9:  achieve more of that, like without it being a
Speaker 9:  professional photographer. And that's where I was like iffy on it.
Speaker 9:  I was like, I don't think this quite works because there's just
Speaker 9:  too much that you can't like recreate afterward. It has to be
Speaker 9:  there. And like the photos I like are Yeah.
Speaker 9:  The things were just there. Like, Lennox is having a great time Right. And
Speaker 9:  the light was right. And that's what makes it a good photo, I think. Or like
Speaker 9:  a photo I wanna keep looking at not AI birds
Speaker 1:  To keep on that photo. I think the, the thing about
Speaker 1:  what you just said that I I I find very compelling is the idea that like
Speaker 1:  a professional photographer would know how to get the moment when they're
Speaker 1:  not screaming. And like your memory of this day
Speaker 1:  is, it was a very fun day. We all had a really good time. Right. Like I,
Speaker 1:  I bet Lennox at one point made a sad face or like,
Speaker 1:  or like had a bunch of snot everywhere, right? Like these things happen.
Speaker 1:  Yes. And So I look at this photo and I wonder, okay, what if instead of adding
Speaker 1:  birds, you had just opened his eyes or
Speaker 1:  Mm. You had just wiped away the snot on his face. Or like,
Speaker 1:  I'm thinking about my, my own kid right now who has a, he just, he's, he's
Speaker 1:  a 18 month old boy, so he's a, his face is a disaster all the time. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And right now he just has this like little scratch right on the side of his
Speaker 1:  face and I'm like, what if all I did was just get rid of that? Just, just
Speaker 1:  sort of yank that away. And my memory of it is not the scratch
Speaker 1:  on his face. Right. Right. My memory of it is we all had a really nice day.
Speaker 1:  Not that he was very snotty for two thirds of it. And I wonder
Speaker 1:  like, to me there's a very stark line between like, I added a dinosaur and
Speaker 1:  I wiped away the snot. But I guess somewhere between those things it's very
Speaker 1:  blurry. But did you, did you do any of the like
Speaker 1:  tiny AI cleanup rather than kind of using the tools to their full extent?
Speaker 1:  Did that feel any different?
Speaker 9:  Well, so the generative AI in Google photos
Speaker 9:  right now will not let you do anything to a person. Oh, that's right. Right.
Speaker 9:  So, and that's, that occurred to me a lot. I was like, well,
Speaker 9:  you know, he looks kind of bummed in this picture.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Like, would I wanna change that? And the
Speaker 9:  closest you can get is with Best Take So I did like, take
Speaker 9:  bursts of photos and then you can kind of pick, you know,
Speaker 9:  the expression you want afterward. It didn't, it, it's
Speaker 9:  not super effective with just one subject. 'cause you could just
Speaker 9:  pick that photo rather than the other. It makes a lot more sense. If you
Speaker 9:  have multiple people in the scene. But yeah,
Speaker 9:  that was, that was the weird area. I was like, I don't know, I think I would
Speaker 9:  like clean up some boogers and not feel too
Speaker 9:  weird about it in any of that. You get to like a, well, where
Speaker 9:  do I stop doing this? Right. You know, once you've like cleaned up boogers,
Speaker 9:  you're like, well what else can I do now?
Speaker 1:  Right. It's a slippery slope to adding dinosaurs. Like it literally is,
Speaker 9:  That's exactly where you end up, you end up in dinosaurs. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  No, it was just a strange thing of like, I would start taking something outta
Speaker 9:  the back, like there's a stroller in the background and I erased that and
Speaker 9:  I'm like, well, what else can I take out here? And then the,
Speaker 9:  the thing that is so wild to me, you just end up with this like
Speaker 9:  bland picture. I'm like, I took out
Speaker 9:  all of the clutter and all of the stuff in the background and it just looks,
Speaker 9:  I'm like, well, where were we? You know, some of that stuff
Speaker 9:  adds the context and the kind of like, we were really here
Speaker 9:  doing this thing kind of feeling. And that's what really
Speaker 9:  struck me in this experiment is like, oh, you can just ai your way into
Speaker 9:  a picture that just could be anywhere just looks
Speaker 9:  lovely.
Speaker 1:  Totally. Yeah. And, and there is a weird thing that
Speaker 1:  you see in a lot of sort of overly doctored photos like this where
Speaker 1:  everything kind of happens in a vacuum, right? Like, there's so many photos
Speaker 1:  that If you remove people from the photo. It's like the,
Speaker 1:  a beach is a perfect example, right? Like If, you're at the beach and you're
Speaker 1:  the only person there. It's actually weird, right. Like on a nice
Speaker 1:  beachy day. So then you go, but you go in and you, you do the magic eraser
Speaker 1:  and you get rid of all this stuff and now it looks like the rapture has happened
Speaker 1:  and you're the only person left on earth at the beach. Yeah. And there, there's
Speaker 1:  just, it's a strange thing to try to dial in. And there was a, there was
Speaker 1:  a photo in the, the ones that you shared where Lennox is like,
Speaker 1:  he's playing with a truck on a table and there's like a glass of milk in
Speaker 1:  front of him and there's a blurry person in the background. And this
Speaker 1:  was another one that I, I struggled to figure out what, if anything you had
Speaker 1:  done with ai and I'm curious what the answer is, but I was looking at this
Speaker 1:  and I was like, okay, my immediate instinct would be to remove the glass
Speaker 1:  of milk because it's only like two thirds in frame and it's not really part
Speaker 1:  of it. So it's just a little bit distracting. And then like, okay, maybe
Speaker 1:  I'll get rid of the person in the background. And now I've turned this kind
Speaker 1:  of nice photo of a person living in the world into like
Speaker 1:  a kid at a table in an empty warehouse with nothing. And like, I think I've
Speaker 1:  made the photo worse. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. That's a conclusion I came to a lot. And actually,
Speaker 9:  so the glass of milk is not real. Oh really? Yeah,
Speaker 9:  it is ai.
Speaker 1:  Whoa. That is a convincing glass of milk,
Speaker 9:  Isn't it? We were at the, we were at a Starbucks, but a fancy Starbucks,
Speaker 9:  you know, the like ones where they would like roast the coffee
Speaker 9:  in front of you.
Speaker 1:  Oh
Speaker 9:  Yeah. He had a, a little orange juice bottle, which is, I
Speaker 9:  don't know how you feel about being a parent on Instagram
Speaker 9:  is like loaded with sugar. I am like, well what if I put something in
Speaker 9:  front of him that wasn't so overtly unhealthy, quote
Speaker 9:  unquote. I don't know. Sure. I don't care if my kid drinks orange juice.
Speaker 9:  I think orange juice is
Speaker 1:  Basically fine.
Speaker 9:  It's so good. Anyway.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Don't, don't cancel us internet.
Speaker 9:  No bad opinions about orange juice.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. I was like, well I'll just put a glass of milk in front of him. Like
Speaker 9:  he ordered it at Starbucks. Yeah. And it's super convincing. I was
Speaker 9:  like, well if Matt smiled and Wow. Yeah. Yeah. You can go like
Speaker 9:  one of the pictures where he is in that little jeep in the
Speaker 9:  park, the one that doesn't have any dinosaurs just has a park
Speaker 9:  behind him. I actually took out like, there's like this
Speaker 9:  building that has the bathrooms. It's like brick and
Speaker 9:  it doesn't, it doesn't look like offensive. It was just kind of
Speaker 9:  in the background. I was like, well maybe I can just put some trees there
Speaker 9:  and it's a thousand percent convincing completely. But then it's also like,
Speaker 9:  it's, it just looks like some trees. Like it doesn't tell me about anything
Speaker 9:  about like where we were.
Speaker 9:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It does this, the picture becomes very kind of generic in that way. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  One thing I find myself wondering about this process is how you'll
Speaker 1:  think about these photos differently over time.
Speaker 1:  A whether you'll go back to the photo of Lennox with the
Speaker 1:  birds in six months, a year or five years or 50 years.
Speaker 1:  And remember that those birds weren't there. Or if you'll forget
Speaker 1:  and think they're part of the photos and maybe that's success in a certain
Speaker 1:  way, but also it, whether
Speaker 1:  changing the photos changes how you'll remember them in a way
Speaker 1:  that feels weird. It's like so much of what we talk about with photography
Speaker 1:  is it's, it's a documentation of a thing and If, you change the thing, you're
Speaker 1:  gonna change your memory of the thing and that all gets very hairy
Speaker 1:  and philosophical. But even just like removing people from
Speaker 1:  something is gonna change how you remember that experience when you go back
Speaker 1:  to the photo. I don't know, did, are you thinking about that at all
Speaker 1:  as you're going through being like, how do I, how do I make this photo what
Speaker 1:  I remembered versus what I want to remember it as many, many years from now?
Speaker 1:  Or how I will remember it?
Speaker 9:  Yeah. I like personally my Google photos
Speaker 9:  is my journal at this point. Same. Yeah. Like I haven't written in a
Speaker 9:  journal in a long time. If I'm trying to remember like
Speaker 9:  where did we go when we were in Portland 10 years ago? I
Speaker 9:  go to Google Photos and that's where the answer is
Speaker 9:  So I did come across, you know, some examples of like,
Speaker 9:  I was taking a, a friend, like a friend of ours was kind
Speaker 9:  of half in the frame and I had a picture of
Speaker 9:  Lennox and my husband and I was like, well I'll take him, our friend
Speaker 9:  out of the picture. and it just fills it in, you know,
Speaker 9:  perfectly. I would never think there was another human there. I was like,
Speaker 9:  well, am I gonna remember that we were there with our friends on that day?
Speaker 9:  Or am I going, is that like lost to time if
Speaker 9:  I take him outta this photo? I started feeling really strange about it and
Speaker 9:  I undid it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. There's a little bit of like, are you lying to your journal in, in
Speaker 1:  all of that? Which is, which is very strange.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Oh, which I never lied to my journal.
Speaker 9:  I would never do that.
Speaker 1:  No. Who would, yeah. And then figuring out where that
Speaker 1:  scale begins and ends, it's kind of the same thing. It's that same slippery
Speaker 1:  slope, right. Where you're, you're saying, okay, I is
Speaker 1:  is remembering that my friends were there an important part of this memory.
Speaker 1:  Sometimes, sometimes probably not, but sometimes yes. Is
Speaker 1:  remembering that, you know, whatever, he had a runny nose. Definitely not.
Speaker 1:  But like those are, it's just strange to think you're making those decisions
Speaker 1:  now. Also about the future. Like maybe,
Speaker 1:  maybe you will wanna remember that you were there with your friends. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Maybe it doesn't seem so significant now, but it will later. And those are
Speaker 1:  just making that decision now is,
Speaker 1:  is an interesting way to like, you're changing the way that future,
Speaker 1:  you remembers this without any real knowledge of how it might do it.
Speaker 9:  Right. It's uncomfortable.
Speaker 1:  It is, yeah. Uncomfortable is exactly the right word for it. Like even when
Speaker 1:  it's useful it still feels kind of uncomfortable.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1:  Did you have any of these that you, you came out of it and felt better about?
Speaker 1:  Like I, I keep thinking about that thing you said at the beginning where
Speaker 1:  you're like, I took photos I wouldn't have taken otherwise because I'm like,
Speaker 1:  I bet there is a good photo in here somewhere. I find that very compelling.
Speaker 1:  Did you have any of those experiences? Anything where you came out of it
Speaker 1:  and you were like, I have made this into something out of nothing.
Speaker 9:  Say yes and no. I have only reinforced
Speaker 9:  my belief that you cannot edit a bad photo into a good
Speaker 9:  photo.
Speaker 1:  Mm. Even with ai.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Okay. That's true of Photoshop. That's true of putting
Speaker 9:  birds in, you know, AI birds in your photo. Like
Speaker 9:  nothing's going to, I tried, I tried to make some just
Speaker 9:  bad photos look better and there's still stinkers. But the thing
Speaker 9:  I am convinced now is I will
Speaker 9:  take more photos where there's someone in the frame
Speaker 9:  and I kind of wish they would move out of the way, but you know, you
Speaker 9:  can't ask them to move. Right. Or
Speaker 9:  I, I'll take more of those photos now and just
Speaker 9:  remove them from the background. 'cause I, I don't feel bad about that
Speaker 9:  and especially if it's like someone else's kid is in the
Speaker 9:  background and it's a picture, you know, I can't get my
Speaker 9:  my kid to stay still forever So I take the picture anyway
Speaker 9:  and then I can remove the other kids so I'm not putting them
Speaker 9:  on my Instagram. I'm like, I actually feel fine about that.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. So that's where I landed. That
Speaker 1:  Feels like a good use case. And especially like, the thing
Speaker 1:  that immediately comes to mind there is like whenever If, you go to the zoo
Speaker 1:  or whatever, you're inevitably going to take pictures of something
Speaker 1:  with a thousand strangers right on, right on all sides of it.
Speaker 1:  And you can make a case that actually not only are you making your photos
Speaker 1:  better, you're kind of doing like a public service to the world by removing
Speaker 1:  those people from the photos. Right. Like in a, you're you're, you're fighting
Speaker 1:  the surveillance state with ai. Right? I love that.
Speaker 9:  Not today surveillance
Speaker 1:  State. Exactly. So how do you feel at the end of this
Speaker 1:  experiment? Has it, you're, like you said, a person who takes a lot of photos
Speaker 1:  anyway. Do you take anything away from this that makes you think you might
Speaker 1:  act or operate differently with a camera from now on?
Speaker 9:  I think the big one is I might rely on it more
Speaker 9:  for those photos when I'm like, well I couldn't reframe this and
Speaker 9:  there's someone here and I I just don't want them in my
Speaker 9:  photo. It is very good at that. Sometimes it takes a couple
Speaker 9:  of tries to get like the best version. But
Speaker 9:  yeah, I was super surprised even with like kind of a complicated
Speaker 9:  background or things in the foreground. I think that's where
Speaker 9:  Magic Eraser hasn't been good in the past and where generative
Speaker 9:  AI actually is like, makes it better. It isn't just
Speaker 9:  like a gimmick, but there are also gimmicks and like
Speaker 9:  Sure. I yeah. Remain unconvinced that
Speaker 9:  anybody was asking for the ability to like put dinosaurs
Speaker 9:  in their photos and like, it's kind of funny for a minute,
Speaker 9:  but yeah, I'm, I'm gonna, I'm gonna stay away from the dinosaurs, I
Speaker 9:  think.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean, and, and I think it, it goes back to that question of who is
Speaker 1:  it for, right? Because I think there's a, there's a world in which you
Speaker 1:  can make the case that this stuff is, it's fun to share with people, right?
Speaker 1:  Like people who weren't there, people who care about you and
Speaker 1:  and your kid. And like, it's silly and fun in the way that, like
Speaker 1:  I think about the, the pictures you get at Disney World on a rollercoaster,
Speaker 1:  right? Where they pick this one very specific moment and it always has a
Speaker 1:  silly background and like No one believes that that
Speaker 1:  is like a representative photo of your life. Right. But it is, it is.
Speaker 1:  That to me is actually a perfect example of like, that is a photograph of
Speaker 1:  a memory and not of a, it's not a photo. Right. Even though in a way it is
Speaker 1:  a photo, it's so exactly staged and put together
Speaker 1:  and directed and, and yeah. Surrounded with a frame that like they make
Speaker 1:  a memory out of that in a way that I think is, is mostly cool and fine.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But there is still something
Speaker 1:  different about it when you're doing it on your phone
Speaker 1:  and your camera roll in these like very mundane things.
Speaker 9:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Like the taking out the background of a shot of a park
Speaker 1:  to remove a building is like not the same thing as the rollercoaster shot
Speaker 1:  at Disney World in a way that I'm still having trouble putting my finger
Speaker 1:  on. It's not the same.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, no, I agree. I think that's a good analogy.
Speaker 1:  So what, what has this given you in terms of new perspective on the,
Speaker 1:  what is a photo debate? Like do you, do you buy Google's memories, not
Speaker 1:  photos, thesis a little more, even if it doesn't quite pan out in reality.
Speaker 9:  I, you know, I dunno, I don't wanna give them too much credit.
Speaker 9:  I do in a way, you know, I, the thing that struck
Speaker 9:  me is really, it's such a different approach than,
Speaker 9:  than the iPhone 16 camera, which is more about, you know,
Speaker 9:  the new photographic styles and kind of
Speaker 9:  their response to what is a photo is like,
Speaker 9:  we will give you the tools to dial in the color and the skin
Speaker 9:  tones the way you see it, which is, is kind
Speaker 9:  of, they're answering the same question and it's not like we're going to
Speaker 9:  reproduce this thing the way it absolutely was. It's sort
Speaker 9:  of putting it, giving you more input
Speaker 9:  over like, no, I it felt more like this. Or it looked more, it looked
Speaker 9:  warmer or cooler. Adding dinosaurs to your photos is not
Speaker 9:  a thing, you know, you can do with the iPhone camera right. Presently.
Speaker 9:  But it kind of struck me how they're both kind of turning from
Speaker 9:  this like, you know, push to like
Speaker 9:  represent reality as faithfully as they can and like
Speaker 9:  do it with as many, you know, as much data as
Speaker 9:  they can gram into a single image. And it's sort of turning to
Speaker 9:  like, no, you make the call on this. Actually.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, there's a real like theory of relativity thing happening in
Speaker 1:  photography that is maybe true. Like it has, I think it has never
Speaker 1:  been true that cameras perfectly captured exactly
Speaker 1:  everything right in the real world. Like it's just never been true.
Speaker 1:  It's just that now the tools with which you can make it more
Speaker 1:  real are the same tools with which you can make it less real and Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I think you can't have one without the other. Right. Like If, you If you
Speaker 1:  give me the tools I can, I can inevitably use them in both directions and
Speaker 1:  we have to decide if we're okay with that. I think. Yeah. and it, like the
Speaker 1:  magic eraser thing is really interesting 'cause this tech is getting better,
Speaker 1:  like shockingly fast and I think is probably going to keep getting better
Speaker 1:  shockingly fast for a pretty long time. So like the, the capabilities are
Speaker 1:  not getting worse anytime soon.
Speaker 9:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  All right. Before we go, give me, give me the single worst example that you
Speaker 1:  had. What, was there a photo that you made disastrously,
Speaker 1:  unusable would never share with another soul
Speaker 9:  In this project?
Speaker 9:  Let's see, I tried to do a bunch of my vaca.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the hotline as always. The number 8 6 6
Speaker 1:  VERGE one one, the email vergecast at The Verge dot com. We love all
Speaker 1:  your questions. We try to answer at least one on this show every single week.
Speaker 1:  Thank you again to everybody who reaches out. They all get funneled into
Speaker 1:  a slack room that more and more people keep requesting access to because
Speaker 1:  it's so fun to hear all of your awesome questions. So thank you to everybody
Speaker 1:  who reaches out this week. We have a question, God help me
Speaker 1:  about running.
Speaker 10:  Hello Bridge cast. This is Zach from Las Vegas. I have a few hundred dollars
Speaker 10:  that I wanted to spend on a new gadget and I've been looking at the Pixel
Speaker 10:  Buds Pro two, I have the original pros and I'm mostly happy with them,
Speaker 10:  but when I take them running, they often aren't very secure and I thought
Speaker 10:  the Pro Twos would fix that. However, I've recently been intrigued with
Speaker 10:  Amid of Ray Band glasses. I think they'd work well on my runs,
Speaker 10:  incorporating sunglasses and speakers for music and it the new fun
Speaker 10:  class of tech that I don't have. However, I'm all in on the Google
Speaker 10:  ecosystem and Pixel products and I didn't want to add a new assistant or
Speaker 10:  AI to my life. If, you are in my position, which would you purchase? Thank
Speaker 10:  you.
Speaker 1:  All right. Vs. Song is here to help me. Hy-Vee.
Speaker 11:  Hi I I empathize so much. Right?
Speaker 1:  You know why you're here for this, right?
Speaker 11:  I know, I know. Yeah, I, yeah.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So I. I wanna, I wanna reframe this question very slightly because
Speaker 1:  I think I, I don't wanna spend a ton of time litigating the Pixel Buds Pro
Speaker 1:  specifically in part just because everybody's ears are different, right?
Speaker 1:  And the only actually good advice we can give is try them,
Speaker 1:  buy 'em both, try 'em, see what happens. But I do think the question of
Speaker 1:  can the RayBan Meta Smart glasses be a kind of
Speaker 1:  multipurpose useful exercise thing is a question we've actually gotten a
Speaker 1:  bunch of times. So I want to talk about that. And I also wanna throw in,
Speaker 1:  you and I have both tried and are fans of the, the Shocks open
Speaker 1:  runs So, I. Think in, in those three categories, you have the headphones
Speaker 1:  that go in your ears, you have the bone production headphones and you have
Speaker 1:  smart glasses. You're literally in running gear right now about to go running.
Speaker 1:  My first question is, what are you going to put in or on or near your ears
Speaker 1:  when you run today?
Speaker 11:  Today when I run, I'm going to be wearing the shocks Open Run Pro
Speaker 11:  two. I genuinely love them. They're, I
Speaker 11:  used to be a big Beats fit pro girly and then I
Speaker 11:  moved to the suburbs and the Range Rovers here are unhinged.
Speaker 11:  It's a safety thing. I really need situational awareness. So I've been wearing
Speaker 11:  these and I just love them compared to the
Speaker 11:  previous versions of Aftershocks because the base is decent.
Speaker 11:  Like If, you really love base, this ain't going to do it for you.
Speaker 11:  But compared to other bone conduction headphones, the base is quite
Speaker 11:  good. The sound quality for bone conduction is quite good.
Speaker 11:  And it's because it's using some like regular
Speaker 11:  air conduction speakers on top of the bone conduction. So the base is the
Speaker 11:  air conduction and the, the mids and treble are
Speaker 11:  bone conduction. Works great, really love it. Pretty
Speaker 11:  secure. It's not falling off. But to
Speaker 11:  to, to the, to the point of the question, it's not great
Speaker 11:  If, you wanna wear glasses on top of it, like
Speaker 11:  everyone's faces are different. Everyone's ear capacity is different. I
Speaker 11:  have pretty narrow ear two head space.
Speaker 11:  I, I guess what you, what you would say. So when I don't feel like we're
Speaker 11:  in contacts when I'm running and I put the open,
Speaker 11:  the, the shocks in and I have my glasses on or my sunglasses on
Speaker 11:  is very crowded in the ear space. And that is like the, I think
Speaker 11:  my biggest complaint of those so far. So met Ray bands are fucking great
Speaker 11:  If, you just wanna consolidate two things and like I'm, I did
Speaker 11:  several miles this summer wearing the met
Speaker 11:  ray bands as as like a two in one. It's both my sunglasses
Speaker 11:  and it's my form of audio. Like it's
Speaker 11:  actually pretty great for that if you're running in a relatively quiet area
Speaker 11:  or you're not like by like a highway. Because if you're by a highway,
Speaker 11:  it's, it's just not gonna, it's not gonna do that for you.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. In terms of like running in loud environments, it's in your headphones
Speaker 1:  of the move. And then honestly I would say bone conduction is second
Speaker 1:  and then like big gap, meta RayBan, smart glasses,
Speaker 1:  like those things, if there's, if there's a truck idling that you
Speaker 1:  run by like you're toast, you're not gonna be able to
Speaker 11:  Hear anything your toast. And also If, you are someone who runs races. So
Speaker 11:  I ran New York half marathon a couple years ago with the Bose tempo love
Speaker 11:  to the Bose tempo. It was great during all throughout my training, I was
Speaker 11:  like, this is great. I'm gonna do this race day. 'cause the general rule
Speaker 11:  for runners is nothing new on race day. You wanna have practiced
Speaker 11:  everything beforehand, went they are blasting
Speaker 11:  music at these races. A critical failure on my part.
Speaker 11:  'cause I have my very specific running playlist. It is
Speaker 11:  highly curated
Speaker 11:  and I was just like, I do not jam with these jams
Speaker 11:  and it really kind of ruined my, my vibe. So like in that sense
Speaker 11:  they're not great. So it really depends on where you're running. The other
Speaker 11:  issue I have with the meadow ray vans is that they are heavier.
Speaker 1:  That was my question. I I, my only real worry
Speaker 1:  in recommending these to a lot of people is just that they are large,
Speaker 1:  like physically heavy sunglasses. And I,
Speaker 1:  I am not a consistent enough runner to weigh in on this, which is the thing
Speaker 1:  I was most curious about from you. But like you've complained about how heavy
Speaker 1:  they are when you're not trying to run fast and long. How do
Speaker 1:  they feel in a, in a real like run scenario?
Speaker 11:  I would say if you're doing like 5K or less, you're really not gonna nervous
Speaker 11:  too much. But like the more you run the sweatier you are, especially if
Speaker 11:  it's in the summer, especially if you're wearing a hat. So like, like I
Speaker 11:  said, I wear them a lot from my mileage during the summer and
Speaker 11:  you know, I'd have a little hat to protect me because the sun is deadly
Speaker 11:  and I have the ray bands and like I'm running in 80 plus degree
Speaker 11:  weather, high humidity in Jersey. My face gets
Speaker 11:  sweaty. Sunscreen is just like melting down my face. These things. And so
Speaker 11:  like, you know, these glasses are pretty good
Speaker 11:  If. you have a low nose bridge like I do,
Speaker 11:  but when you have sweat and sunscreen, they, they kinda slip a little bit.
Speaker 11:  They're gonna slip a little bit. That's just like inevitable. 'cause you
Speaker 11:  are in a up and down running motion
Speaker 11:  if you're doing like really long mileage. I wanna say like if you're training
Speaker 11:  for a half or you're training for a marathon, you
Speaker 11:  kind of gotta deal with the fact that they are heavier battery
Speaker 11:  life. Like it's hard to say because you could be a fricking
Speaker 11:  cheetah and a half marathon is like an hour and a half for you. So like
Speaker 11:  whatever, it'll be fine for your long runs or you could be slow like
Speaker 11:  me where you're just like, you know, like Turtle steady does it
Speaker 11:  and you're running like two and a half hour to three hour
Speaker 11:  half marathons and you're just like, this is this battery
Speaker 11:  life. It should, it should work if you're fully charged. But who
Speaker 11:  whom among us always has a fully charged headphone when we run out the
Speaker 11:  door. So like it could you plan a little bit with fire there.
Speaker 11:  So yeah, like unfortunately you're gonna have to try a couple
Speaker 11:  of things.
Speaker 1:  So, but what it sounds like you're saying is that if you're just a person
Speaker 1:  who just sort of casually runs for exercise, you just wanna like get out
Speaker 1:  in the morning and run a couple miles to get the blood flowing. All those
Speaker 1:  concerns you just described probably don't really apply. So you should mostly
Speaker 1:  be fine with the, with the Raybans, right?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, you should mostly be fine. So long as you don't like, like like you
Speaker 11:  said, you're not running by highways and like a lot of construction 'cause
Speaker 11:  you ain't gonna hear nothing like I, I have done that and you're not gonna
Speaker 11:  hear anything. You know, obviously fit is very personal. So
Speaker 11:  before you buy, I would go to the store and see how they fit on your face.
Speaker 11:  But I actually really enjoyed running with them this summer, particularly
Speaker 11:  when it was really sunny and the, I don't wanna have multiple
Speaker 11:  things sitting in my ear. It's actually very smart. It's a very smart option.
Speaker 11:  But again, loud environments, races, you're probably not
Speaker 11:  gonna have a good time going, especially if it's a big race. It might not
Speaker 11:  be a problem if it's a smaller race and they're not blasting like somebody
Speaker 11:  else's playlist. But for me, like at a big
Speaker 11:  race when I wore the Bose tempo, I was like, I've made a huge
Speaker 11:  mistake because I had to listen to like
Speaker 11:  pit bull and pit bull doesn't get me going for a run.
Speaker 11:  So
Speaker 1:  No one needs that for a half marathon. The thing I keep thinking about
Speaker 1:  with all of this is just that we can't be that far away from like
Speaker 1:  the wraparound oakley's smart glasses. Like that is so clearly
Speaker 1:  the next one of these you would do if you're a meta, everybody's into
Speaker 1:  health and fitness as a wearable thing. It's exactly for the people you're
Speaker 1:  describing. Like somebody is gonna make those like rainbow tinted
Speaker 1:  wraparound oakley's with the the croakies on the back that you can just secure
Speaker 1:  to your head and it's gonna be RayBan meta glasses and they're going to sell
Speaker 1:  so many of those. And that becomes the answer to this question because then
Speaker 1:  it's like, you're gonna look like a doofus, but it's gonna rule and you're
Speaker 1:  gonna win all your races. So congratulations. And
Speaker 11:  That was supposed fit tempo. They already did it. Like both. That's true.
Speaker 11:  Both just didn't manage that side of the business well. But like you can
Speaker 11:  see some of my pictures from the, my first New York City half marathon.
Speaker 11:  I am wearing the Bose Fit Tempo. I look like a fricking jabi. And
Speaker 11:  you know, if if, if they could have beaten the, the pit bull and
Speaker 11:  the pop music that I am not a fan of just blasting, it
Speaker 11:  would've been perfect as it was. I was just like, I can't hear my K-pop.
Speaker 11:  I have no motivation. This is terrible. So those are
Speaker 11:  all things to consider. If, you really wanna go with the metal ray band
Speaker 11:  for running.
Speaker 1:  All right. What's on the running playlist right now?
Speaker 11:  A lot of re hits because as far as K-pop
Speaker 11:  goes, they're not very bubblegum. They're kind of like pots and pans,
Speaker 11:  crazy electronica music and it's just like,
Speaker 11:  I'm like, yeah, there's a beat I can go to that I hate everything right
Speaker 11:  now, but I can, that can go. I can go. I also, I run, a lot of times I run
Speaker 11:  to K-pop because I'm not super fluent in Korean So. I can just be like ignoring
Speaker 11:  what they're saying and it's just like, yeah, they're just saying you can
Speaker 11:  do it. That's great. I love this. For me,
Speaker 11:  yeah, I'm a very, I need a lot of bass and a
Speaker 11:  lot of when I run otherwise like I don't know
Speaker 11:  how people listen to podcasts or audio books 'cause I'll just stop. There's
Speaker 11:  nothing like, it's
Speaker 1:  So boring. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  It's so, it's like I could just listen to this audiobook on a couch.
Speaker 11:  I don't need to be suffering while I run. So
Speaker 11:  yeah, a lot of straight kids,
Speaker 11:  Buzi and Duckworth, they have this song called Start a Riot and I'm
Speaker 11:  like, they're like, who the hell gonna start a riot and I'll run, I'll be
Speaker 11:  like me. I'm starting the riot up this
Speaker 11:  hill. So yeah,
Speaker 1:  I love that. All right, well I think my recommendation for this question
Speaker 1:  is start with the Ray Bands a because they're a really fun gadget and If,
Speaker 1:  you just have a few hundred dollars you wanna blow on a gadget. It's a really
Speaker 1:  good one to mess with. They're super fun. You'll enjoy them, take
Speaker 1:  them on a run and a half and you will immediately know whether they work
Speaker 1:  for you or not. And then you can try the other things. But I think if, if
Speaker 1:  the, if the Raybans work for you, that feels like the most fun outcome here.
Speaker 1:  So I would say start there.
Speaker 11:  That is the most fun. And if those don't work, highly recommend the shocks.
Speaker 11:  Just because like If, you look at any running influencer on TikTok right
Speaker 11:  now, they all got shocks on their ear. They all got that exact thing. They
Speaker 11:  all love it. And I'm like, yeah, I do too. I was, I was pleasantly
Speaker 11:  surprised by the latest version of the Open Run Pro.
Speaker 1:  I started using them for runs, for dog walks for like pushing
Speaker 1:  the stroller to go pick up my kid. And now it's like, you know the thing
Speaker 1:  when you get a car and all of a sudden you start seeing the car that you
Speaker 1:  have everywhere.
Speaker 1:  That has been my experience with these. They are everywhere. And everyone
Speaker 1:  I see who is like way too good at running those people who
Speaker 1:  like, you know, If, you like met them, they would talk to you about how much
Speaker 1:  they like running. They all wear them and I feel like it makes me hate
Speaker 1:  myself and them, but it's also like clearly there's there's something here.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, they're like
Speaker 1:  Fair enough. All right, well I hope that helps
Speaker 1:  gadgety stuff going on. We might get some Apple stuff soon. Lots to talk
Speaker 1:  about. We'll see you then. Rock and roll