# Transcript
ID: d7dbd2f4-c59f-4e76-965c-184b5e757945
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/3261879416375082955/-2913574467239920670/s93290-US-3705s-1704881764.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz are discuss all the things with screens announced at CES 2024.
Speaker 2:  Hello and welcome to Our Chest, the flagship podcast of Mobility
Speaker 2:  Solutions here at CSS 2024.
Speaker 2:  That's if you spend enough time at CES, you just start to
Speaker 2:  talk like that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You just can't help it.
Speaker 4:  You start saying the word innovative. Yeah. Like as all parts of speech.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And just lose all track of what's actually words.
Speaker 2:  You just, you just look around. There's companies here, no one's ever heard
Speaker 2:  of selling.
Speaker 4:  Enable Selling
Speaker 2:  By ai. Enabled by ai. Remember to solutionize the future of innovation.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  With hk, with eight K and
Speaker 2:  5G, with eight K and 5G. It's all, it's all happening all at once. Hi, I'm
Speaker 2:  your friend Eli. I'm here at css. We're here in the Kia connected home, which
Speaker 2:  means we're above a number of Kias downstairs, which I'm told are powering
Speaker 2:  the home,
Speaker 4:  Which is kind of cool. Yeah. Yes. We also have a view that I would call like
Speaker 4:  Regal above CES. Oh yeah. We're sort of gazing upon our
Speaker 4:  kingdom. I
Speaker 2:  Feel very powerful. I'm just saying we're slightly above the Google booth
Speaker 2:  right next door. It's, that's
Speaker 4:  Right. It feels right. What's
Speaker 2:  Up Android? David Pierce is here. Hi. Alex Francis is here.
Speaker 2:  Hi. There's a whole Verge team here at cs. A huge number of people.
Speaker 2:  We've been out on the show floor. It's the day after all the press
Speaker 2:  conferences. There's an awful lot of news here at css. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  David, you have some sort of gambit to organize our two CSS shows.
Speaker 4:  I do. So we have to do two shows this week at CES. And the thing
Speaker 4:  about CES is it's just a grab bag of things. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And so we, we broke it into two things Today we're going to talk about things
Speaker 4:  that are mostly screens. I believe you called them Screen gadgets. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And then on Thursday we're gonna talk about all the things that aren't screens.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Do these things blur together? Yes. All the time.
Speaker 4:  Is the Venn diagram of them mostly nonsensical and made up In my head? Yes.
Speaker 4:  But this is, this is what we're gonna do. So today is the screens day. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  There's like a version of this where we were like, okay, it's kind of a car
Speaker 4:  show, it's kind of a TV show. Let's talk about those things. But it's just
Speaker 4:  like, we're gonna do screens and no screens.
Speaker 2:  It's a better organizing principle than CSS has for itself,
Speaker 2:  which this year is just a mishmash of ideas. They're like
Speaker 2:  ai, do you want AI to do it? At one point VW announced
Speaker 2:  that you could just talk to chat GPT in the car. Sure. Which
Speaker 2:  seems like don don't know if you guys are aware of this chat. GT often makes
Speaker 2:  things up. So just being confidently lied to while you drive
Speaker 2:  is now a feature of the new vw.
Speaker 4:  There's so much of that this year where yeah, somebody is just like, well
Speaker 4:  we made a product last year and now that product,
Speaker 4:  but also Chad, GPT and nothing else. Is that new? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Is that what you want?
Speaker 4:  Like telly, the the free TV we talked a bunch about on the show. Their new
Speaker 4:  thing is you can talk to chat GPT to get like recommendations for stuff
Speaker 4:  to watch. Which I think is hilarious because to your point, Ja, GBT loves
Speaker 4:  to like make up movies that don't exist. So you can just like
Speaker 4:  invent movies out of whole cloth and then not watch them on your free television.
Speaker 4:  Well, show
Speaker 2:  Show is advertising to you. Right. We should actually start with with TVs.
Speaker 2:  So if you don't know CSS is a consumer electronic show. We're here in Las
Speaker 2:  Vegas is the biggest industry trade show there is.
Speaker 2:  That does not mean the entire industry is here in an odd way.
Speaker 2:  Apple for example, is not here. But Apple loves to
Speaker 2:  upstage CES. So they announced the Vision Pro early this week. We'll, we'll
Speaker 2:  get to that later in the show. Microsoft isn't here. They all have employees
Speaker 2:  here and people here wandering around. But in terms of announcements, css,
Speaker 2:  it waxes and wanes. Yeah, that's right. Yeah. Google is here, but Google
Speaker 2:  didn't make a lot of announcements, but everything runs Android. So
Speaker 2:  technically millions of Android products were announced here. It's Cs. So
Speaker 2:  it just, it it's a real grab bag of things. The in, the good thing about
Speaker 2:  it is that everyone is here. Right? Everyone's talking. If you're a tech
Speaker 2:  reporter, this is fish in a barrel. Yeah. You're just in Las Vegas
Speaker 2:  and everyone is holding a drink and ready to tell you a story about something.
Speaker 2:  And in fact ready to tell you how much they think the Vision Pro costs to
Speaker 2:  build. Which has been the best gossip of the week for me. Just people yelling
Speaker 2:  numbers. So making up numbers outta blue. But the history of CSS
Speaker 2:  is that this is a show where TVs are announced. Yeah. Like in the long history
Speaker 2:  of css, the, the one constant that has held the show together
Speaker 2:  and really given it its sort of center of gravity, is the TV industry shows
Speaker 2:  up here. They show you new TVs. The buyers from retailers
Speaker 2:  like Best Buy and Amazon and don don't know who Circuit City. Circuit City
Speaker 2:  still exists. They show up,
Speaker 4:  They do. RCA has a big booth here. Everybody's
Speaker 2:  Coming back. Liam is telling me Circuit City no longer exists, rip Circuit
Speaker 2:  City. But anyway, the buyers from those big retailers show up. They, they
Speaker 2:  debate about what will be the hot trends in TVs to sell this year. They place
Speaker 2:  their orders and then later in the year, The TVs show up on, on on the retailer
Speaker 2:  shelves. That's been the pattern, still the pattern here at css. Although
Speaker 2:  interestingly, Sony has broken this pattern now two years in a row. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  no. TVs at CSS and the, the big Sony booth at the end of the hall
Speaker 2:  has no TVs in it. Wow. Like there are TVs to show you other
Speaker 2:  Sony stuff, but there's not even like a whisper of like Sony's TV
Speaker 2:  models. Right. It's like PlayStation stuff, some camera stuff, half
Speaker 2:  a car. Then the rest of the car that Sony's building with Honda, which we'll
Speaker 2:  talk about on Thursday, they're just outta the game. Like Sony wants the
Speaker 2:  high, high end of the TV market and then the rest of it is kinda up
Speaker 2:  for grabs. Yeah. So we should start with the other announcements. But that
Speaker 2:  to me is just the fascinating turn of the show. As I think about the tech
Speaker 2:  industry, this has been the place where TVs get announced and Sony's opting
Speaker 2:  out Samsung and LG, which obviously dominate the TV market.
Speaker 2:  They are doing stuff but they're don don't know. They're kinda
Speaker 2:  like, what if the TV was clear? You know? It's like they're, yeah. They're
Speaker 2:  in that zone with it. And then the the cheaper brands, the TCLs, the high
Speaker 2:  senses. I wanna talk a lot about mini LED. They're coming up fast.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It feels like for the big companies, they've gotten kind of less and
Speaker 4:  less practical over time with what they show off. These are just sort of
Speaker 4:  like tech demos. Yeah. And some of 'em are very cool tech demos. Well I think
Speaker 5:  They, they plateaued, right? Like the technology is plateaued so well
Speaker 4:  So I don't think that's true, but I think Oh really people don't care anymore.
Speaker 4:  That's very true. Right? Like true. The technology keeps getting better.
Speaker 4:  But my ability to experience said technology as like long
Speaker 4:  sin plateaued. So the only thing to do is like get real weird with it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Because, and I think part of what we were gonna talk about in a little while
Speaker 4:  is like monitors which are now on this run of like getting better
Speaker 4:  to the point where you're not gonna start to notice the difference anymore.
Speaker 4:  But there was just like more to do with computer monitors. Whereas like if
Speaker 4:  you wanna kick ass TV, that is too high res for you to know the
Speaker 4:  difference. Anyway, you've had that for a while.
Speaker 2:  Oh my friend, I'm ready to talk about this. Alright, so we should talk about
Speaker 2:  some news because I think there's, this year it's css. I think that has been
Speaker 2:  true for a minute. It's about to stop being true again in a really exciting
Speaker 2:  way. So the news Samsung LG LG has a new transparent
Speaker 2:  OLED tv. It's the T
Speaker 4:  Dealed T
Speaker 2:  OLED t That's
Speaker 5:  T-V-T-T-V-T.
Speaker 2:  That's, that's what they're calling it.
Speaker 4:  It's T for C through.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's clear it has like a black thing that you can motorize
Speaker 2:  pull down to make it not clear. But then you can make it clear again.
Speaker 2:  Chris Welch looked through it, he was blown away. You can read that piece.
Speaker 2:  I went and looked at it on the show floor. It's just out.
Speaker 5:  Did you notice a crucial thing about it? No. So one of the, one of
Speaker 5:  them they had, they were playing like wheel of time on it. Yeah. And they
Speaker 5:  had motion smoothing on Ooh on their like invisible
Speaker 5:  well transparent TV that everybody should care about. Motion
Speaker 5:  smoothing. That was just like
Speaker 4:  Somewhere Tom Cruise is furious. I
Speaker 2:  Didn't, I was furious. I didn't actually see content. I just saw like CES
Speaker 2:  demo reels. Yeah. And it was like, like water falling, you know,
Speaker 2:  Flowers opening. They
Speaker 5:  Were beautiful. Yeah. This such smooth
Speaker 4:  Motion. And
Speaker 2:  Then you saw real content,
Speaker 5:  You're like, yeah there was like, there was one TV like in a corner and it
Speaker 5:  was playing just some of wheel of time being like, isn't Amazon Prime great?
Speaker 5:  And I was like hmm. Is it? And also motion smoothing.
Speaker 5:  Yikes. I turned into Tom Cruise for a moment. I can you, I almost kicked
Speaker 5:  the TV in.
Speaker 2:  Does the transparent TV have film remote? Because I'd like to enable it.
Speaker 2:  Please. I was
Speaker 5:  Like, can I have a remote real quick? I just need to fix something for you.
Speaker 2:  Show up at CSS with an LG remote. Just like, so that's, that's
Speaker 2:  lgs big announcement. Samsung has its own riff on a transparent display.
Speaker 2:  They're very excited about all that. Samsung has, Samsung famously
Speaker 2:  is now now doing QD OLEDs. Quantum OLEDs. That's the panel Sony's using and
Speaker 2:  it's, it's high-end OLEDs. They're doing anti-glare on that.
Speaker 2:  Here's my argument to you about all these TVs. OLED is hitting a weird
Speaker 2:  interesting peak. So the sort of base technology reed is like where it's
Speaker 2:  at Samsung displays between Quantum Dots in front of
Speaker 2:  OLED pixels to make 'em brighter. LG is doing the micro lens array,
Speaker 2:  which is, I mean all this is really cool. Yeah. They're just like trying
Speaker 2:  to make the OLEDs brighter. Right. But the fundamental technology is like
Speaker 2:  hit its point and it's gotten to about 77 inches and that's kind of how big
Speaker 2:  they can get 'em. LG LG can get to like 83.
Speaker 2:  But do you need bigger? So here's, here's what Yeah we're gonna, here's what's
Speaker 2:  happening. And those are expensive. Like a big OLED TV is like pretty
Speaker 2:  expensive. Yeah. Like a Sony A 80 is like a pretty expensive TV
Speaker 2:  that's four four grand. Right. And that's about as big as ole like 83 is.
Speaker 2:  Right? That's basically it. If you walk on the show floor, you see
Speaker 2:  mini L led D TVs are everywhere. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  TCL is all in on them. High sense is all in on them. High sense is
Speaker 2:  picking up from Samsung. They know that people think like, oh
Speaker 2:  lead is good. So high sense is like ours are U LEDs.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The longest time. So, or Samsung is like Q eds.
Speaker 2:  It's like you think people are so stupid.
Speaker 2:  Like truly you think people are so dumb they'll do it. So if you, if you're
Speaker 2:  not caught up on this, the thing that is happening with back lights on LCD
Speaker 2:  TVs and LCD TV can't make light by itself. You can make the color so you
Speaker 2:  need to put a back light behind it. Those back lights have basically gotten
Speaker 2:  more and more advanced over the years. They started out with literally fluorescent
Speaker 2:  lights on the side of the tv. They didn't look great.
Speaker 2:  Like old, like old, old LCDs. Literally fluorescent lights on the side of
Speaker 2:  the, on the side of the, of the panels. Then you got into like LEDs
Speaker 2:  behind the panels. That's where you get LED D TVs. That's where people are
Speaker 2:  always talking about. Then you started adding local dimming. You started
Speaker 2:  turning those LEDs on and off in zones. Then there was a hilarious spec race
Speaker 2:  over how many zones of local dimming you could have. Oh that's the best.
Speaker 2:  That was good. Which is thousands of zones. Right. And then you, what
Speaker 2:  do you, what's next? You make the LEDs themselves smaller, you pack 'em more
Speaker 2:  on, you get more zones. You're now up to like 6,000 zones. 60,000 zones is
Speaker 2:  like one of the claims that's out there. I don dunno if that's true or not.
Speaker 2:  It's too many zones. It's too many zones looking at this thing, I was like
Speaker 2:  I don dunno. The same company put a U in front of the LED to confuse people.
Speaker 2:  Like whatever you want man. And so this thing, if you look at these TVs that
Speaker 2:  back lits are really bright. They have really, really, really well controlled
Speaker 2:  local dimming and they look amazing. They do. And they're
Speaker 2:  cheap as hell to make. 'cause they're just still LCD TVs and the core
Speaker 2:  LCD technology is all the way at the bottom of the cost curve. Like all the
Speaker 2:  way bought because we've been doing this for a long time. We're doing it
Speaker 2:  forever. Yeah. And what, what we've been iterating on is the backlight. So
Speaker 2:  now the backlight is starting to come down the cost curve. This mini LED
Speaker 2:  and this is like year three or four that we've been typed many other day.
Speaker 2:  This is the year that it's down the cost curve. And the thing that these
Speaker 2:  manufacturers are doing is they're not saying we've made a better cheaper
Speaker 2:  65 inch tv. They're saying, what if you bought a 98
Speaker 2:  inch tv? Oh
Speaker 5:  That's too much.
Speaker 2:  And TCL has a giant display that's like, we are the number one provider of
Speaker 2:  98 inch TVs in the country. And this is our fastest
Speaker 2:  growing like model.
Speaker 4:  There's this amazing graph in the TCL booth that they have printed up next
Speaker 4:  to one of their TVs that is like percentage growth of various
Speaker 4:  sizes. And all the other ones are, you know, like steady growth from 60 to
Speaker 4:  70. Steady growth. Steady growth. And then the highest one
Speaker 4:  is like 398% growth. And it's like first of all that means you
Speaker 4:  sold 16 TVs and you sold 40 TVs. So like
Speaker 4:  cool, great job.
Speaker 2:  Get outta here. You math magician.
Speaker 4:  But I do think like we, we've talked about this before and and like you in
Speaker 4:  particular are kind of an OLED purist. Yeah. Like you,
Speaker 2:  You, I came very close to buying a mini lady Sony and I was like couldn't
Speaker 2:  do it.
Speaker 4:  But I think all these companies are correctly betting that most
Speaker 4:  people are less obnoxious than you about TVs.
Speaker 4:  And thus we'll buy something that is
Speaker 4:  95% as good as OLED for a
Speaker 4:  literal fraction of the price. Yes. And
Speaker 2:  Brighter. Right. And this is, and this is the thing that, and basically what
Speaker 2:  you lose is off axis viewing. So an OLED looks
Speaker 2:  perfect from basically any angle LCD screen. You're familiar with LCD
Speaker 2:  screens, you get wide enough, things get weird. Right. But it's still
Speaker 2:  pretty good on these TVs. Especially when The TVs are huge. Yeah. It's actually
Speaker 2:  very hard to get off axis on a 98 inch tv. You need a
Speaker 4:  Big couch. I'm
Speaker 2:  Four miles away to the left. So you have this huge tv, it's really bright.
Speaker 2:  'cause you can make an L CD really bright and like you have to go look
Speaker 2:  for the blooming. Yeah. Yeah. On some of these video, not all of them, they're
Speaker 2:  gonna be all prices and shapes. But I'm just telling you this is the year
Speaker 2:  that that technology just like enters the mainstream. And
Speaker 2:  I think it will probably take the default big TV size from
Speaker 2:  65, maybe not to 98, but it'll go from 65 to
Speaker 2:  75 pretty fast. 'cause it's gonna be cheaper, bigger and brighter.
Speaker 2:  And it's gonna look in a store almost as good as ead. Yeah. Like
Speaker 2:  almost as good as ead. Like I really had to look on the show floor. And the
Speaker 2:  show floor is like a bad environment and it's like bright and crazy and all
Speaker 2:  The TVs are cranked up to, to 9,000 knits or whatever like,
Speaker 5:  And they're playing like the best content to make the TV look good. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  There are no blacks. You, you cannot see
Speaker 2:  No there. So this is the demo that in particular Tcell is doing. There's
Speaker 2:  big TV and it's like, you know it's a flower over black.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Or like an Edison light bulb just kinda lighting up in the middle of it.
Speaker 4:  So they're trying
Speaker 2:  Stress the TV
Speaker 4:  And they have a few that are settings. Were you playing with the button?
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. You can push the button, you can basically put it in a mode that simul.
Speaker 2:  It's an old backlight and you turn it on and it does the mini lady backlight
Speaker 2:  and it looks amazing. It looks really good. Now this is a totally controlled
Speaker 2:  demo.
Speaker 5:  I'm just remembering, do you remember,
Speaker 2:  I'm not gonna promise you that this is perfect. Huh? Do you remember
Speaker 5:  Like 10 years ago when Vizio did their a hundred and I think it was like
Speaker 5:  120 inch tv? Yeah, yeah, yeah. And it was the ugliest thing and
Speaker 4:  Everybody was like, this is preposterous.
Speaker 5:  Like you could only check it out like in a giant warehouse. 'cause that's
Speaker 5:  the only place the TV would fit. And it was garbage tv. Yeah. It was just
Speaker 5:  the ugliest tv possible.
Speaker 2:  That's when they, that's when we people started doing really intense local
Speaker 2:  dimming demos. Yeah. And TV companies will still like the drop of a
Speaker 2:  hat. A TV company will go this the summer. Like here's a TV without the tv.
Speaker 2:  It's just the backlight. And then I'll show you like half the screen has
Speaker 2:  a TV on it and the other half is just the backlight. Yeah. Look at the backlight
Speaker 2:  move with the, the image and you
Speaker 5:  Just watch Sandra Bullock like spiral out and turn into lights.
Speaker 2:  Pretty good. Pretty good. Demo all around. I'm just saying this is the year
Speaker 2:  you see it on the show floor this year it's everywhere. And
Speaker 2:  you know, my prediction is always rooted in my firm belief that people
Speaker 2:  will pick big sheep screens. And so if you can give people a
Speaker 2:  screen at at 65 say that is almost as good as an A lid
Speaker 2:  but cheaper, they're gonna pick that one. Right. Especially they can't tell.
Speaker 2:  And then if you can get and it's brighter, which is always the thing. Well
Speaker 2:  like
Speaker 4:  I, to that point actually, like it makes me think of the, the test Marquez
Speaker 4:  Brownley does every year with the smartphone cameras. Yeah. And every year
Speaker 4:  what wins is just the brightest camera. Yeah. It's like people don't want
Speaker 4:  anything else, but it's just, if it's bright and there's lots of colors that's
Speaker 4:  people are into it. They're, and it's the same thing. You, you see it in
Speaker 4:  a store, it's the same thing. It's why they crank the brightness to
Speaker 4:  50000%. But
Speaker 2:  I, the, the thing that that I think is just like really interesting. It's
Speaker 2:  like, oh man, like what if the baseline size of a TV gets
Speaker 2:  even bigger next year and it's, you're no longer picking 55 and
Speaker 2:  65. You're picking between like 65, 75 and 85 and
Speaker 2:  98. It could be kinda wild.
Speaker 4:  My wife steadfastly refuses to buy a TV above 50 inches for our
Speaker 4:  house Ooh. She just thinks anything over 50 inches is like outrageous and
Speaker 4:  unnecessary and no one should have it. And the number of choices
Speaker 4:  that we have under 50 inches is getting so small.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So like it's crazy. And
Speaker 5:  The TVs aren't very good at that
Speaker 4:  Size. No, they're trash. You can't buy a good TVs. Which is
Speaker 4:  why we have like, you
Speaker 2:  Gotta get to 55 crappy
Speaker 4:  TCL L Roku. What could you tell Anna this
Speaker 2:  Please. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Can you like black out the 65 inch on the box and just,
Speaker 4:  I promise
Speaker 5:  It's 50. Yeah. Don't worry about
Speaker 4:  It. She's like, I thought the other one was 50. Like no, that one's 30 You
Speaker 4:  don't
Speaker 5:  Like say they measure 'em differently now
Speaker 4:  Don't measure it. It's
Speaker 2:  Fine. It's fine. Don't measure the tv. So that actually brings us to like
Speaker 2:  the next thing that's happening here, which is for all of this
Speaker 2:  talk about fancy backlight technologies and good looking pictures.
Speaker 2:  The bestselling TV in the country is the Frame TV
Speaker 5:  Just you're nemesis,
Speaker 2:  It just, it's the proud owner of Frame tv. Well
Speaker 4:  Those, those two things totally square for me. Yeah. Right. Yeah. Like if
Speaker 4:  you're gonna put this increasingly humongous thing
Speaker 4:  in your home, like an 85 inch black
Speaker 4:  panel just looks ridiculous.
Speaker 2:  I see. In my mind it's beautiful. That looks like a symbol of success,
Speaker 2:  stability. But you are correct, most people do not just want a wall
Speaker 2:  of black in their ass. Right. They would prefer to have a middling, single
Speaker 2:  backlight, extremely bad LCD panel. It's extreme.
Speaker 2:  It's all want throwing some art. The frame is
Speaker 2:  wildly successful. Yeah, it is. It dominates Samsung's TV sales.
Speaker 2:  They they love it. It is, I'm just gonna tell you it is not
Speaker 2:  a great tv. Like it's a find It will do the job. They've
Speaker 2:  updated it nothing this year because it is basically fine and
Speaker 2:  they're just, they're flying off the shelves. The update for the frame this
Speaker 2:  year is that now in art mode, the refresh rate lowers to 60 hertz
Speaker 2:  instead of just staying at one 20.
Speaker 4:  Sick.
Speaker 2:  If you have been following like cell phones for any period of time, you're
Speaker 2:  like, oh this is four generations behind variable refresh tech
Speaker 2:  in cell phones. And Samsung's like, no, no, this is plugged into the wall
Speaker 2:  all the time. We're going down to 60 to show us static image of a painting.
Speaker 2:  The frame is a monopoly. I'm just telling you right now, the frame is a monopoly.
Speaker 2:  They feel no competitive pressure and they're like whatever. You want some
Speaker 2:  art.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Everybody's out here now making things that they want to be frame
Speaker 4:  competitors. Yeah. And what they are is just television.
Speaker 2:  Right. So TCL has an art store. I, it's unclear what that
Speaker 2:  is. They have a a, there's just a sign on the show for it says TCL Art. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And art is written in like marker font and
Speaker 4:  All it is on the booth is a TV with a bunch of paintings around it. And it's
Speaker 4:  like, I think you fundamentally misunderstand what the frame is doing.
Speaker 2:  High Sense has a like it looks like a Jetson's tv. That's the, the art tv.
Speaker 2:  See? Yeah. Okay. So everyone's trying to come at this idea, which is the
Speaker 2:  TV should look good one's off. And I think Samsung just has such a dominant
Speaker 2:  position here that they just do not care. It would be cool if the TV
Speaker 2:  was better.
Speaker 4:  Well, but that's also one of the reasons I think that transparent displays
Speaker 4:  are interesting. It's 'cause like, and this is the stuff we were talking
Speaker 4:  about last week too, that these things are sort of increasingly
Speaker 4:  furniture and there's a feeling like this should blend into the rest of my
Speaker 4:  house instead of just being a gigantic black
Speaker 4:  thing. To the
Speaker 5:  Point that LG one is, is furniture like Right. And
Speaker 4:  They actually got like shelves like going it with Right. With all this other
Speaker 4:  stuff on the stand and yeah. I think that's really cool.
Speaker 5:  I I think it's like very, very cool. I would almost wanna get one,
Speaker 5:  but like Chris Welch pointed out the, the picture's kind of garbage when
Speaker 5:  you just wanna watch tv. It's like, it's worse but it it's better than the
Speaker 5:  frame at least.
Speaker 4:  So is everything. Yeah. It's like
Speaker 5:  No bar but better than the frame. No,
Speaker 4:  I think that's right. But I think that trend I think is super interesting.
Speaker 4:  even that we're not getting what we should have. 'cause the transparent thing
Speaker 4:  is also gonna cost a billion dollars and it kind of
Speaker 4:  sits in a really awkward way in that it's actually gonna call more
Speaker 4:  attention to itself Yes. Than a normal TV would. 'cause we're all kind of
Speaker 4:  conditioned to not notice TVs. It's just a fireplace
Speaker 5:  On for it the whole time. You're like, I have a wire frame fireplace. Don't
Speaker 4:  Worry about it. Yeah. Like the fish tank mode just 24 7. Yeah. I
Speaker 2:  Love it. I The fish tank thing is so cool.
Speaker 4:  I swear that was the moment it clicked for me. 'cause I was like, oh this
Speaker 4:  is going to fancy doctor's offices. Yeah. Like that's, that's who's gonna
Speaker 4:  use fish.
Speaker 2:  That's what you want. The bleeding edge of Ola technology. You're like, we'll
Speaker 2:  at some fish in your doctor's office. Alright. Samsung did announce some
Speaker 2:  other stuff in the TV zone. I'm just gonna read you one
Speaker 2:  and here's what I'm gonna do. First I'm just gonna say this word to you and
Speaker 2:  I want you to guess what you think this feature is. Oh boy.
Speaker 2:  Samsung announced that it's new 24 24 TVs
Speaker 2:  will feature in addition to Workout Tracker and techno gym,
Speaker 2:  which I think are self
Speaker 4:  Perfectly understandable.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. I get those.
Speaker 2:  Samsung tail.
Speaker 4:  Samsung tail tail. TAIL. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Is it an acronym? Nope.
Speaker 5:  Is it like Paw Patrol? Is it like for children?
Speaker 4:  Oh, that's good. It's not
Speaker 2:  For children. Okay.
Speaker 5:  It's not for children.
Speaker 4:  It's like, it's like, okay. This is, this is my,
Speaker 2:  It's a series of cops that are dogs.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 5:  With tails.
Speaker 4:  It's it's pet mode for your television. Oh yes. Instead of turning
Speaker 4:  it all the way off and showing art, you show like puppies running
Speaker 4:  around. That's
Speaker 2:  Good. Or squirrel something. It's wrong
Speaker 4:  Dog. It's good.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's just dead wrong, but it's
Speaker 4:  Good. Okay. Alex, what's
Speaker 5:  Your guess? Well, it was Paw Patrol, but it,
Speaker 2:  It's just the Paw
Speaker 4:  Patrol. Just
Speaker 2:  Paw Patrol. You push the button, dogs come running out and solve crimes.
Speaker 4:  It'd
Speaker 5:  Be great. I would love that. Ooh
Speaker 5:  something related to wifi.
Speaker 2:  No, no, no.
Speaker 5:  HDR. No. I'm gonna start using
Speaker 2:  Listing words. Those are just features of the TV
Speaker 4:  Bulbs.
Speaker 2:  All right. Samsung Tail. Yeah. Enables real time video
Speaker 2:  consultation with a vet in the comfort of the user's home. See, we
Speaker 2:  were close from basic care tips to advanced advice.
Speaker 2:  Dr. Tail has a range of questions covered. Users
Speaker 2:  connect with veterinary experts in real time whenever they need. This is
Speaker 2:  a startup that Samsung saw at like a Samsung dev day and they're like, yeah,
Speaker 2:  Dr. Tail, you're part of The TVs now. And now it's just part of The
Speaker 2:  TVs.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 4:  That's so good. That's so good. The most Samsung thing. Do
Speaker 4:  you remember when Samsung had all those apps called like milk? Yeah. You
Speaker 4:  could get milk music. Yeah. Yeah. And it's just like Samsung sees a weirdly
Speaker 4:  named startup and it's like, yes, that's it. Let's do it. That's like a,
Speaker 4:  on our gadgets, that's
Speaker 5:  A good business model. You just like come up with a startup that's wouldn't
Speaker 5:  make sense. Put a weird name on it and be like, Samsung.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Do you want it? Would you like to bundle this on the
Speaker 2:  Android phone? Look, big tech companies, very few of them can buy companies
Speaker 2:  anymore. All right. This is a problem. Lena Khan's really ruin it, unless
Speaker 2:  it's Dr. Tail and Samsung tv, in which case she's fine.
Speaker 2:  Last piece of Samsung News, speaking of frame, such a hit, Samsung
Speaker 2:  is expanding the franchise. They've made a frame speaker,
Speaker 2:  which I still find utterly perplexing because it's just a
Speaker 2:  speaker behind a picture.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's it. I mean, it really is like, imagine you took a
Speaker 2:  Picture
Speaker 4:  Bluetooth speaker and just hi it behind a
Speaker 4:  painting, is
Speaker 2:  What I'm saying. Samsung
Speaker 5:  Did it for you.
Speaker 4:  Right. So I'll be honest, I I don't hate this at all. It does
Speaker 4:  not need to exist. Yeah. But I love that it does. It's like IKEA makes some
Speaker 4:  of this stuff too, where they're like, what if our lamp was also a sono speaker?
Speaker 4:  And I'm like, what if, what if Ikea, it's a great question. It does
Speaker 2:  Seem like Samsung has made one turn more
Speaker 2:  innovative than Sonos and Ikea in that it appears you
Speaker 2:  can pick your own picture in the Samsung frame speaker,
Speaker 2:  which don don't know if you've been following frame technology key
Speaker 2:  element in the analog frame world.
Speaker 5:  Huge fan of that
Speaker 2:  IQ was like, nah, this is just one, one picture of sparkles. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It was like, do you want it to look like a hotel room in your house all the
Speaker 5:  time? We got you. Let's go.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So that's TV news. It's again, I wouldn't, and
Speaker 2:  I'm not saying there's like one standout TV here apart from the transparent
Speaker 2:  one. It's not like the year that like plasma TVs were introduced to the year
Speaker 2:  that, you know, OLED kind of broke and we're like, oh, this is the future.
Speaker 2:  I do think you're
Speaker 4:  Right though that this is like, we're gonna look back at this as like the,
Speaker 4:  oh, this was the year we saw all the mini LED TVs. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And then I think this is the year that TV sizes starts to get bigger.
Speaker 2:  And I think that's fascinating. Like if you are running a movie theater chain
Speaker 2:  and you're looking at people buying 98 inch TVs for their house, that look
Speaker 2:  really good. don don't know man. What
Speaker 5:  Do you put that on though?
Speaker 2:  102 inch wall.
Speaker 5:  I'm just like, I'm thinking of the furniture situation there. I need a
Speaker 5:  m like I basically, for me specifically, I just need a much larger credenza
Speaker 5:  to put a TV that big on it. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That sounds right. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  We'll come back next week for the AV Furniture Show. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Houses shop for credentials here
Speaker 5:  In Vegas. Well, for the measuring tape.
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta take a break. The frame is a monopoly. All right. I'm
Speaker 2:  just telling you right now. If you are out there, you're a TV maker. Put
Speaker 2:  some competitive pressure on Samsung. This thing needs local dimming tomorrow.
Speaker 2:  We'll, right back
Speaker 1:  for more details.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Bir has CES one, the Kia connected
Speaker 2:  home, gazing out. I don't see Dieter out there with
Speaker 2:  Shake.
Speaker 4:  My, my fist. We over, we told he was there at some I
Speaker 5:  I a hundred percent saw Dieter out there earlier,
Speaker 2:  Shaking my fist in the direction in the Google booth. Lots of other
Speaker 2:  gadgets here at cs. Lots. Alex, you've been paying a lot of attention to
Speaker 2:  laptops, monitors the, the gaming gadgets. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  What's what's, what's going on in Windows world? Well, gaming
Speaker 4:  First of all has been kind of like, weirdly, the story of CES gaming has
Speaker 4:  been
Speaker 5:  Really here, like used to, you could have one person kind of cover
Speaker 5:  gaming stuff reliably. And now it's like, Ooh, Ooh, maybe I need to assign
Speaker 5:  more people to cover this next year because,
Speaker 1:  And it also kinda felt
Speaker 4:  Like gaming stuff was always sort of off on its own. It was like, here's
Speaker 4:  like the gamer section of CES. Yeah. But now it feels like even these, like
Speaker 4:  extremely mainstream brands are mostly making gamer
Speaker 4:  things.
Speaker 5:  Yes. They all are like HP's doing it and, and, and Dell, and I mean
Speaker 5:  they were already doing it, but Lenovo like is even kind of leaning more
Speaker 5:  into their gaming stuff. They, they even introduced another one of those
Speaker 5:  external GPUs that everybody does every couple of years. And we're all like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, this will be the year. And it's never the year. But Lenovo was,
Speaker 5:  Lenovo was out there doing it. I think they remaining thinking more for professional
Speaker 5:  reasons, like using the GPUs for ai. But I think that's also why we're seeing
Speaker 5:  more gaming stuff is because you need really powerful GPUs
Speaker 5:  for AI and also for gaming. And so it's like interesting.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Yeah. And that would also explain, I guess why it seems like a lot
Speaker 4:  of all this gamey stuff is getting slightly less
Speaker 4:  gamey. Like my theory with gaming stuff has always been that it's just those
Speaker 4:  are the people willing to spend money on fancy things and high end stuff.
Speaker 4:  Oh
Speaker 2:  No. I have a way Spier take. Oh yeah.
Speaker 4:  What's your spicier take?
Speaker 2:  If you wanna make a young person buy a Windows computer, it has to be a gaming
Speaker 2:  computer.
Speaker 4:  Yep. Well that's interesting. And that's why
Speaker 5:  Like all, all the gaming laptops,
Speaker 2:  That's like 25% spicier that needs to be, please direct your emails to Alex
Speaker 2:  Duck Cranz in the recycle.
Speaker 5:  I agree with him. I totally agree with him. But
Speaker 5:  no, so we saw like a lot of gaming laptops this year and they were all like,
Speaker 5:  I wouldn't feel weird pulling it out at a coffee shop. Like, I'm older now,
Speaker 5:  I don't really wanna pull out something and it's got a bajillion lights on
Speaker 5:  it. It goes ah,
Speaker 4:  When you turn it on.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You could hear it from space because it sounds like it's about to go
Speaker 5:  into space. I'm trying to like avoid that in my life now. And
Speaker 4:  But you still wanna play sick games at the coffee shop. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  I get it. I still wanna play Boulder's game forever at the coffee shop until
Speaker 5:  they ask me politely to leave. And it feels like that's much more possible
Speaker 5:  now. One, because the processors have gotten better, the CPUs are a lot better.
Speaker 5:  The GPUs have gotten smaller and are are very efficient. The batteries are
Speaker 5:  getting a little bit better. And two, they just are making these
Speaker 5:  laptops and, and thinking about the rest of us. Or more
Speaker 5:  specifically, they're thinking about, as I heard over and over and over again,
Speaker 5:  this will work really well in your dorm room. And I was like, oh yeah, my
Speaker 5:  dorm room. Okay. Mine. No, not mine. Someone's dorm room. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And, and so that, that's really what they're positioning for. It's for the
Speaker 5:  college kids who, who are coming in and they don't want like
Speaker 5:  an adult, the laptop their parents have. Right. But they also don't necessarily
Speaker 5:  want like neon green lights and stuff all over their laptop.
Speaker 4:  They wanna like play games but also take the thing to class.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And so we're seeing a lot of laptops. A lot of them have new white
Speaker 5:  colorways. That was a big thing for, I think both HP and Legion were both
Speaker 5:  introducing laptops that were like white and they look really, really nice.
Speaker 5:  And you can turn the, you can, you know, you've got RGB keyboards and then
Speaker 5:  if you don't want that, you can turn it off. And that just seems really,
Speaker 5:  really nice. But we saw one from Legion, or we saw one from Lenovo. We saw
Speaker 5:  one from HP Alienware that the Dell one, they actually,
Speaker 5:  they used to have a really big exhaust fan on the back and they still do
Speaker 5:  for their more powerful ones. But the, the new, the M 16 R two,
Speaker 5:  they got rid of the butt. There's like a big butt on the back of the laptop.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And they just said, Nope.
Speaker 2:  Classic Alienware move. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They like
Speaker 4:  Chop in the butt, chop
Speaker 5:  In the butt.
Speaker 4:  Alienware.
Speaker 2:  Well first you add the butt Right. Get, they've got two moves. The CEO's
Speaker 2:  like, this is the butt year and then the next year he is like, get rid of
Speaker 2:  the butt. but it
Speaker 5:  Really
Speaker 2:  Is, it's like, you know, they used to make the iPod like skinny then fat,
Speaker 2:  then wide and narrow
Speaker 4:  And pull it every
Speaker 5:  Year. Yeah. It's actually very accurate. That is what happens a lot of times.
Speaker 5:  They're like, the butt got too big, we have to shrink the butt. And so this
Speaker 5:  year they like, they took it completely off. They've still got it for their,
Speaker 5:  for their higher end ones, but for like the 40, 70 and below, they were like,
Speaker 5:  we don't actually for the Nvidia 47 and below, they were like, we don't actually
Speaker 5:  need to have all of that exhaust. We don't need all that heat and stuff.
Speaker 5:  We're fine. You can do enough for gaming. And and that's true. Like most
Speaker 5:  games nowadays aren't as demanding. Like the really popular
Speaker 5:  ones, you know, the Fortnite, the Boulders Gate, just not as demanding.
Speaker 4:  It feels like after all these years of trying to make like the one laptop
Speaker 4:  that could be all things to all people ultra powerful
Speaker 4:  and ultra portable and everything, they're finally finding like a pretty
Speaker 4:  good middle ground. Yes. That isn't for anybody at either side, but actually
Speaker 4:  hits like the middle 80%. Yeah. In a way better way. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And like I consider myself a gamer. I play a lot of video games. I don't
Speaker 5:  want the huge giant laptop. Right. I like, I
Speaker 5:  don't wanna carry it. It's super heavy. I don't wanna try to power it. Some
Speaker 5:  of the times you can't even bring the chargers on the plane. Like I want,
Speaker 5:  I want something that I can play most of my games at reasonable enough. That's
Speaker 5:  why I like the Steam Deck. Yeah. That's why it's a really fun device. That's
Speaker 5:  why we're seeing a lot more of these like little handheld PCs where you can
Speaker 5:  play that. Like the MSI Claw was the new one this time. Right. Which I really,
Speaker 5:  really like. Not as much as Sean. Sean loves the MSI Claw.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But also I, I don't like it because the controls on it. Have
Speaker 5:  you seen the controls? I
Speaker 2:  Haven't seen it. Okay.
Speaker 5:  So Steam like the Steam Deck has the little, the little touch pads and you
Speaker 5:  can control it and, and It works like a mouse. Everybody else who's doing
Speaker 5:  this right now has just joysticks and, and a dpa. Mm.
Speaker 5:  And it's just not as good. I'm like, part of why I like the Steam Deck is
Speaker 5:  I have a bajillion inputs and now it's like, and they're
Speaker 4:  All super customizable. Yeah. So you can do any kind of weird thing you want
Speaker 4:  with your Steam Deck.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Instead they're now like, okay, what we're gonna do is pack in like
Speaker 5:  a little Intel processor. We're gonna make this thing really, really fast
Speaker 5:  and not give you super great controls, but you are getting much better displays.
Speaker 5:  Like the MSI one, the MSI Claw has like a variable refresh rate.
Speaker 5:  It's got a decently sized battery and it's got the, the Hall
Speaker 5:  effect joystick. So You don't get the the drift and stuff.
Speaker 2:  Wait, so there's some like Intel processor news, you said that the clause,
Speaker 2:  it's got a newer Intel processor in it. Right. Intel's got its new 14th Gen
Speaker 2:  mobile processors here. That's sort of Yeah. They making all these gaming
Speaker 2:  laptops go. They
Speaker 5:  Announced it like, I think a week ago, two weeks ago they announced it right
Speaker 5:  before CES. Yeah. And it's the new media, like, and they're just really,
Speaker 5:  really good processors. I feel like for the last couple of years, you
Speaker 5:  would always go to an event and everybody would be like, we're gonna make
Speaker 5:  really thin laptops next year, like fan free, really cool laptops just like
Speaker 5:  Apple and it's gonna be awesome. And it never happened. Yeah. And now
Speaker 5:  it's like, oh no, they can actually do it. Like Meteor Lake gives you these
Speaker 5:  really, really thin laptops. It's giving you these really, really cool handheld
Speaker 5:  gaming devices where you can actually have a lot of power in a fairly
Speaker 5:  small thing and, and still have the good thermals. Because that's also the
Speaker 5:  big limitation. Like you can't do really fast gaming if
Speaker 5:  the processor overheats, which it will,
Speaker 4:  If your device is on fire, it doesn't play games very
Speaker 5:  Well. Yeah. If your hands are melting, holding onto it, that's bad. And,
Speaker 5:  and they, they've, they've, it seems like with with Meteor, like they've
Speaker 5:  finally found that balance. And like I'm, we haven't gotten to check out
Speaker 5:  a lot of these things. Really
Speaker 4:  Interesting. I was gonna feel like I've heard that specific story so many
Speaker 4:  times. Yeah. Yeah. And Qualcomm is out here being like, we did it guys. But
Speaker 4:  I think it's our batteries last 37 hours.
Speaker 5:  I think the difference is typically the laptop makers
Speaker 5:  don't like buy into that hype. Like the proce the Intel will come out and
Speaker 5:  tell you this is a year. And then laptop makers generally will be like, this
Speaker 5:  is not the year. We may release like one as like a pity.
Speaker 4:  Right. They'll often run like a whole generation behind. Yeah. Just for that
Speaker 4:  reason. Because they're like, we don't trust this new thing. We're, we're
Speaker 4:  gonna wait this out a minute. Yeah. Because it doesn't,
Speaker 5:  But they're the ones that are gonna get yelled at.
Speaker 4:  Everybody is Yeah. Ready.
Speaker 5:  But this year everybody jumped on it. Yeah. Everybody has stuff. They're
Speaker 5:  really, really embracing it. So it feels like we're finally like, I think
Speaker 5:  it was 20 17 20 18 where I was seeing these super thin laptops
Speaker 5:  and they'd be like, next year this is gonna come out. We're gonna show you
Speaker 5:  this for real. And I'm like, cool. And it never happened. And then this year,
Speaker 5:  like it really feels like it's happening. And it's not just with the gaming
Speaker 5:  ones too. It's also like Lenovo's got a new think book, 13
Speaker 5:  XI believe it's called. And it is just like, it's super, super skin thin.
Speaker 5:  It only weighs like 2.2 pounds. It's got a magnesium body,
Speaker 5:  so it's like stainless magnesium. So it doesn't get
Speaker 5:  fingerprints at all. Everything else in the Lenovo booth was covered in fingerprints.
Speaker 5:  And that one, that one worked. I was like, Hey, it does work. And it was
Speaker 5:  just like, it feels like a toy, but it was a full laptop. And I was like,
Speaker 5:  I I just covered this. I just wanna own this laptop now because it is so
Speaker 5:  thin and so light. It was like the old MacBook. Yeah. And it was like, oh
Speaker 5:  it's, it's that.
Speaker 4:  I really hope that's true. 'cause it's like I want that to be true. It's
Speaker 4:  to me, running around looking a bunch of these laptops, there's been this
Speaker 4:  sort of normal, normal CES glut of
Speaker 4:  just like weird ideas about laptops. Yeah. Where there's some that they're
Speaker 4:  like, what if we had foldable screens and you saw a Lenovo one that runs
Speaker 4:  Windows and Android and sometimes they're just like, what if
Speaker 4:  everything about the laptop? We just moved six inches to the left and then
Speaker 4:  that was a laptop. But there's also just a bunch of them
Speaker 4:  this year that they're just like, oh no, we just made a better laptop. That
Speaker 4:  is good. Yeah. And it feels like, especially what the last three years, apple
Speaker 4:  has just like run away with the best laptop to use every
Speaker 4:  day as a regular person. This
Speaker 2:  Is what I'm saying about the gaming pieces. If you want someone, if you want
Speaker 2:  to knock someone off the default of buying a MacBook error,
Speaker 2:  you need to show up with video games. Right.
Speaker 4:  Which is I think part of why Apple is now pushing the Mac as a gaming platform.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Harder than ever because they're trying to undo that a little bit.
Speaker 4:  But that only works for the Windows manufacturers
Speaker 4:  to the extent that you have also made a pretty good laptop. Yeah. Because
Speaker 4:  like, I'll figure out another way to play games and like Microsoft is doing
Speaker 4:  Game Pass, which is gonna be playable on these other devices. So like that
Speaker 4:  specific thing is gonna fall apart if these Windows manufacturers can't figure
Speaker 4:  out how to make just like an everyday very good laptop that is also better
Speaker 4:  for gaming. And like that is, it's starting to spin back.
Speaker 2:  But let ask Alex laptops about the most incredible device here at
Speaker 2:  css. It's the Lenovo think book, which I believe
Speaker 2:  you've seen.
Speaker 5:  I've seen all of the Lenovos. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Sorry, can I just, can I just stop you real fast? Yeah. It's called the Think
Speaker 4:  book plus Gen five Hybrid.
Speaker 2:  Please. It's very important.
Speaker 2:  My apologies. The Gen five hybrid family. I'll be releasing this
Speaker 2:  as a notes Gen four can
Speaker 4:  Get outta
Speaker 2:  Here. As you know, I've always valued the contributions
Speaker 2:  of the Gen five hybrid family. I, I meant no disrespect.
Speaker 2:  I have so many Gen five hybrid friends.
Speaker 5:  Your best friend is Gen five.
Speaker 2:  It's like, somehow I'm gonna take this joke actually canceling
Speaker 2:  myself. I don know how but it's coming. No, you saw this thing. The Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Gen vibrate. It is literally two computers. It's just two
Speaker 2:  computers attached with a hinge. Yeah. Wait, really? Yeah. Yeah. What So
Speaker 2:  it has a Qualcomm processor in the screen and an Intel processor in the base,
Speaker 2:  right? Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's on the base of it is, is just a Windows machine. And then
Speaker 5:  the top of it is, is a tablet. And when you pick it up, you're like, oh yeah,
Speaker 5:  that's a tablet up there because it kinda like has that little wobble. It's
Speaker 5:  not as bad as sometimes remember the early, the early ones where they put
Speaker 5:  the tablet up and then the, the horrible little keyboard and you'd pick it
Speaker 5:  up and you'd be like, I could never use this. It's a little more balanced
Speaker 5:  than that, but it's still got that like, heft to it because it's got a 14
Speaker 5:  inch tablet, like in the top of it. And what was interesting was
Speaker 5:  you really just like pull it off. You don't, you don't have to press a button.
Speaker 5:  You don't have to do anything. You just like grab it and yank because
Speaker 2:  It's its own computer. Yeah. It's its own batteries have two batteries. It's
Speaker 2:  got
Speaker 5:  Two batteries. So it's like
Speaker 2:  I, the, this is, I love this product. It's just
Speaker 4:  Do you remember the the Microsoft Surface book? Yeah. That was one of those
Speaker 4:  things that like, I don't think anyone bought it except for like six people.
Speaker 4:  But those six
Speaker 2:  People, people, my niece and nephew had Surface loved
Speaker 4:  It. Bizarrely. I was like, that had like a rabid fan base of people. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Who liked it for exactly that reason. It's like, but
Speaker 2:  The base had a battery and a GPU, right? Yeah. So this made
Speaker 2:  this the base of the Lenovo think book plus Gen Fair hybrid. That's
Speaker 2:  fair. It's a Windows computer is just a full on Windows computer.
Speaker 5:  Just a whole one.
Speaker 4:  I actually really love this.
Speaker 5:  It's like, it's a weird fun idea. They're like, oh, we
Speaker 5:  were, we asked, Hey, can you communicate between the two? Like if
Speaker 5:  you're working on something and you pull it off the, pull the the tablet
Speaker 5:  off, you can keep working. They're like, no, it's, it's two
Speaker 5:  computers.
Speaker 2:  It's like a
Speaker 4:  Full Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You will have to transfer all of your files in order to do, it's
Speaker 2:  Fantastic. They didn't build like an app to fake it.
Speaker 5:  They're they're, they're working on that. They're working, they're working
Speaker 5:  on that. There was also like the separating the two is a little difficult
Speaker 5:  'cause it's, it's a, it's, it's a sample. It's, it's not ready for release
Speaker 5:  yet. Yeah. They said it's absolutely gonna be better when the, when the thing
Speaker 5:  finally comes out. So I'm excited to try that out.
Speaker 2:  Out $2,000, $2,000
Speaker 4:  And somebody
Speaker 2:  Computer and they haven't figured out two computers. They haven't figured
Speaker 2:  out the detach. I mean, just read from Alex. She's being nice.
Speaker 2:  This is very nice. The converting process was also dead simple. Just yank
Speaker 2:  on the tablet until it disengages. The sample version I tried would sometimes
Speaker 2:  need some coaxing to separate
Speaker 4:  Just
Speaker 5:  A little. I was like, at one point I was like, Maybe, it just doesn't come
Speaker 5:  off. Maybe like, this isn't the laptop I'm supposed to be looking at.
Speaker 2:  Maybe this isn't the Gen five hybrid.
Speaker 5:  And then, then the guy came over and was like, no, no
Speaker 4:  M like you just gotta want it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That's
Speaker 5:  Great. And then it worked fine after that. I guess
Speaker 2:  This is a classic CS product. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It was as somebody who like rode really hard for the Asus
Speaker 4:  transformer lineup Yeah. For years. Where you could dock your phone
Speaker 4:  into a tablet and then dock that tablet into a keyboard and it was just all
Speaker 4:  the devices all at once. Yeah. I'm so happy this thing exists. This
Speaker 2:  Is CSS exists again to sell TVs to the unwitting masses
Speaker 2:  and also to have the Motorola, what was it? The Axiom, the Atrix
Speaker 4:  Atrix. The greatest phone of all to
Speaker 2:  Which they had a laptop in the open. Oh, what? It's so bad. And the, the
Speaker 2:  transformer and then this guy just, if you can shove two
Speaker 2:  computers into one computer Yes. CSS is the place for you.
Speaker 4:  I was describing CES to somebody this morning as half
Speaker 4:  just a place to show off things that Best Buy might want to buy.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And then half just companies saying, is this anything?
Speaker 4:  It's, it's just, they're just like, V song wrote a whole thing
Speaker 4:  about like a wood paneled litter box that will also weigh your cat. It's
Speaker 4:  like, that is the most, is this anything gadget I've seen in forever?
Speaker 4:  And I love CSS for that. I have a I have a question you just walk by and
Speaker 4:  it's people who are like, I'm from France. Is this anything?
Speaker 2:  Does it weigh your cat before and after? Like given the nature
Speaker 2:  of a litter box? That's
Speaker 4:  A really good question. Mm.
Speaker 2:  By all accounts, you're, you could also back into weighing something else,
Speaker 2:  right? Know
Speaker 4:  That's a really good question.
Speaker 2:  I don't know what that data iss for.
Speaker 4:  Why
Speaker 5:  Would you need I just don't, her cat's apparently too large to use it.
Speaker 4:  Samsung tail will tell you my
Speaker 2:  Apologies. She's
Speaker 5:  Yeah. She's gonna be old enough. Samsung tail.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So. I. Wanna ask about two more things every year? Razer usually
Speaker 5:  They do a thing.
Speaker 2:  They do a thing, right? It's like a project, da da. but it seems like they're
Speaker 2:  pretty chill this year. Pretty
Speaker 5:  Chill. They did have like a, a pad that you can like sit on for your seat
Speaker 5:  and it will like kick you in the butt when you play video games.
Speaker 4:  You would say it's it's a haptic cushion. Yeah. I think they called it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And
Speaker 5:  This Sean, Sean was kind of impressed by it. He was like, this is fun. But
Speaker 5:  that, that technology's been around for a while. Like a lot of people have
Speaker 5:  done that before. And as with a lot of these Razer CES things,
Speaker 5:  they, they never come to fruition.
Speaker 2:  They're very good at getting attention. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  They're very, I mean I love it. This anything. Yeah. Like the year they brought
Speaker 5:  in the Razer laptop and it had three screens and I was like, next year this
Speaker 5:  is gonna exist. It never.
Speaker 2:  No. All
Speaker 4:  Right. Speaking of things you'd love to take into chemistry class. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Hell
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And then there's a Samsung flip phone called the Flip Bull.
Speaker 2:  What is this called
Speaker 4:  Once again Eli? I am in the position of having to correct you on very important
Speaker 4:  naming things. There are two new Samsung display
Speaker 4:  folding screens. I am on the record as I believe flip phones are
Speaker 4:  the future. And folding phones are mostly stupid. Samsung has two new flip
Speaker 4:  phone concepts, both of which basically go not quite
Speaker 4:  360 degrees 'cause it runs into each other. but it like folds all the way
Speaker 4:  open one. It's called the flex in and out
Speaker 4:  all one word. Yeah. And the other is called we should, we
Speaker 4:  should talk about this.
Speaker 2:  The
Speaker 4:  Other one is either called the Flex Lipel.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Or
Speaker 4:  The Flex
Speaker 2:  Lipel. I just wanna point out that Flip is a better name. It
Speaker 5:  Is a hundred is a better name. Better.
Speaker 4:  It is, I believe a port manto of the words light and simple.
Speaker 2:  Oh
Speaker 5:  No. So lip bulb has to be it because lip bulb's hysterical.
Speaker 4:  It does have to be lip bulb. Yeah, you're right. Lips. Better bulb sounds
Speaker 4:  more like a medical condition that you'd have. It's not better.
Speaker 5:  But
Speaker 2:  Like lip bulb sounds like a medical condition
Speaker 4:  Doctor.
Speaker 5:  Lip bulb like is what you take for your heart lips. Like the thing you get
Speaker 5:  diagnosed with.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think that's right. but it, these things are like,
Speaker 2:  It also rhymes with something. Yeah. It out there. But just acknowledge,
Speaker 2:  we all
Speaker 5:  Know risk getting diagnosed when you have lip. Okay.
Speaker 5:  We all know what part of the body's getting diagnosed.
Speaker 2:  We got David, we broke David. We do, no, it's day one of the CSS show. We
Speaker 2:  broke David Pierce.
Speaker 2:  It's
Speaker 4:  Gone. I just,
Speaker 2:  But so you, you like the phones as much as
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You, you like them? The L-I-P-L-E?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Just again, it's like on the in is this anything
Speaker 4:  scale? Everybody comes every year to CES. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  it's just like, look at this crazy thing. We made a screen do LG has a
Speaker 4:  big booth of the bending oles. The competition for like
Speaker 4:  wildest array of screens this year is kind of a bummer
Speaker 2:  Actually. Yeah. Yeah. They really toned it down. LG and Samsung have really
Speaker 2:  toned it down. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Normally they're just like, we have a wave of 600 televisions. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That you can walk through. And this year LGS thing was just like don
Speaker 4:  don't know. 20 of the transparent TVs that just move back and forth. Not
Speaker 4:  a
Speaker 5:  Single tunnel. Not that cool.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Very exciting. And So I. Think Samsung is doing stuff with phones
Speaker 4:  that I continue to think is really interesting. And part of the appeal of
Speaker 4:  something like this is that because it can fold all the way around,
Speaker 4:  you don't need an outside screen and an inside screen, which could in
Speaker 4:  theory make this thing cheaper and easier to manufacture.
Speaker 2:  What? But then what happens to the inside when you unfold it,
Speaker 4:  It becomes the outside. So
Speaker 2:  It's just nothing.
Speaker 5:  You can customize it. Yes. Beautiful pictures of will. I am in this Mercedes.
Speaker 2:  I do. And we'll, we'll talk about this on Thursday. Alex is doing some
Speaker 2:  important foreshadowing here. Yes. Will. I am wrote a song about infotainment
Speaker 2:  systems css. Everybody.
Speaker 4:  We have until Thursday to figure out a fair use way to play the whole song
Speaker 4:  on The Verge cast.
Speaker 2:  All right. We gotta take a break. We, we should talk about the vision pronouns.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, we should. It did hit this week. We'll be back. We'll talk about that
Speaker 1:  for more details.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. CSS Day one day.
Speaker 2:  It's day one. One-ish. Yesterday was day zero. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 2:  I get this wrong every year. I've been coming here. This is like my 15th
Speaker 2:  year and I still don't quite know what day of the show it is. I think it's
Speaker 2:  day one. Lots to talk about css. We've got another show coming later
Speaker 2:  this week with all the rest of it. There's still news happening. We should
Speaker 2:  end though this episode by talking about the thing that didn't happen
Speaker 2:  here. But that will probably dominate the year in tech coverage no
Speaker 2:  matter what the Apple Vision Pro. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Which is a screen gadget and thus fits, which, just a screen, the rubric
Speaker 4:  of our episode, which is a, it's like mini
Speaker 2:  Screens, the most screens. Right. I heard a rumor. Like I said at the top
Speaker 2:  of the show, people at CSS are just full
Speaker 2:  of speculation over the screens, the Vision Pro, how much this thing costs
Speaker 2:  to build, whether Apple is making any money on it, whether or not making
Speaker 2:  any money on it. So we already knew the price. Yep. Industry
Speaker 2:  should take note from Apple. Apple announced things. They're like, here's
Speaker 2:  a price in a release window. They said early 24 and
Speaker 2:  they meant it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So they said early 2024 and they meant it end of January. They announced
Speaker 2:  February 2nd, this thing shipping. Yep. 34 point 99.
Speaker 2:  Three 500 bucks for a 256 gigabyte model.
Speaker 2:  Unclear if you need more storage in your face computer. Who
Speaker 2:  knows.
Speaker 4:  To be fair, that's gonna be like four minutes of spatial video as far as
Speaker 4:  I can tell.
Speaker 2:  Spatial video and iPhone where you can record it right now. Yeah. It's 130
Speaker 2:  megabytes per perman. It's real
Speaker 4:  Big. Yeah, that's, it's not small.
Speaker 2:  That's a, that's a, you know, you
Speaker 4:  Gotta think in TikTok minutes, not like, I see. That's fair. Okay. Real minutes.
Speaker 4:  Right. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I would say that the press release announcing Vision Pro Deeply
Speaker 2:  Confusing does not have any AR or MR. Apps really
Speaker 2:  mentioned. Apps mentioned in the press release include Fantastical
Speaker 2:  and Slack.
Speaker 4:  It really seems like this is an iPad for your face.
Speaker 4:  And what we've heard from developers is that Apple
Speaker 4:  is going way out of its way to tell them, not to call
Speaker 4:  it AR or VR or MR. Or
Speaker 4:  XR or any of the other thousands of things. Like Apple is very specific that
Speaker 4:  these are spatial computing apps. Yeah. And I don't
Speaker 4:  think that's gonna work. I've been wrong about Apple's ability to
Speaker 4:  make things into buzzwords before, but that one doesn't really work for me.
Speaker 4:  but it really does seem like, at least at the beginning, I've been talking
Speaker 4:  to developers really for the last six months about this and the number
Speaker 4:  of folks that I've talked to who are either sitting it out at the very
Speaker 4:  beginning because they haven't spent enough time with it and aren't sure
Speaker 4:  what to do with it, and don't want to ship a crappy app just to have something
Speaker 4:  there the first day. Or people who are saying basically everything we're
Speaker 4:  doing is based on an iPad app. Anyway, that's kind of the starting point
Speaker 4:  for these Vision Pro apps. We're just gonna ship the iPad app and we'll figure
Speaker 4:  it out from there. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  But I just wanna give you the list. So Apple's own press release, I'm just
Speaker 2:  going off very directly. Here's how Apple is communicating about the
Speaker 2:  Vision Pro. They say it's shipping, it's coming out Revolutionary New operating
Speaker 2:  system and user interface vision. oss, you can use your, you pinch, you
Speaker 2:  pinch. So select things. Eye tracking. Eye tracking. What I saw it looked
Speaker 2:  was amazing. Then they're like, you can immerse yourself in environments,
Speaker 2:  which is a straight up VR feature. Yep. Right. That's interesting.
Speaker 2:  The first thing that they tell you about it is that you can put yourself
Speaker 2:  somewhere else. So it's a VR headset. A fascinating to consider. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's the first thing they say. Then they say, here's all the stuff you can
Speaker 2:  do. Bullet list, an infinite canvas for productivity, first
Speaker 2:  bullet in the list, fantastical freeform, jig space,
Speaker 2:  Microsoft 365 and Slack. It's like, all right, here's what I'm gonna do.
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna go to Holly Acala and I'm gonna Slack.
Speaker 4:  Right.
Speaker 2:  Like if you just read the press release, that's where you land. Yeah. In
Speaker 2:  Apple's own messaging on the, it's, I think this is fascinating. Maybe this
Speaker 2:  is the best Slack experience anyone has ever had in their entire life. It's
Speaker 2:  just interesting that this is what they're landing on. Then the ultimate
Speaker 2:  entertainment experience. So, you know, they're very proud of these displays.
Speaker 2:  More than 4K TV for each try Apple TV plus Disney plus max other
Speaker 2:  services on a screen that feels a hundred feet wide. Okay. That's with
Speaker 2:  HDR R video tell you big tv,
Speaker 4:  Big conspiracy theory I have about this, which is that Apple deliberately
Speaker 4:  doesn't mention Netflix because Apple and Netflix are beefing over all the
Speaker 4:  stuff in the Apple TV plus app. You have no evidence for this. That's how
Speaker 4:  I feel. I would believe
Speaker 2:  That a hundred percent users can also enjoy new
Speaker 2:  interactive experiences like Encounter Dinosaurs, VR app.
Speaker 2:  So I'm just, again, I'm just reading their press release. I don't,
Speaker 2:  I'm not saying these things are good or bad, I'm just saying if you just
Speaker 2:  read how they're talking about it, they have described to you a VR headset.
Speaker 2:  Yep. Yes.
Speaker 2:  Fascinating. Then gaming experiences, access games in the app store, including
Speaker 2:  2 50, 250 titles on Apple Arcade. This is where I think the iPad for your
Speaker 2:  face comes in. Yeah. Because what, what do we know about the Quest? The thing
Speaker 2:  that sells a Quest is games, fundamentally Games and Supernatural,
Speaker 2:  which is a fitness game. Yep. That's what the even Meta refers to the
Speaker 2:  Quest as games console. It is by far that you might think the Vision Pro
Speaker 2:  is gonna blow the Quest away, but it is currently the market leader. So it's
Speaker 2:  the thing you compare to Super Fruit Ninja. What the golf, these are
Speaker 2:  iPad games, right? Like Yeah. It's just, I'm just, and then the next one
Speaker 2:  is Memories brought to Life spatial videos and photos. This is fascinating.
Speaker 2:  The people I know who've tried this thing say it is very convincing. I'm
Speaker 2:  very excited to try it. I've been taking some spatial videos, excited to
Speaker 2:  try it when we get our hands on one of these things. But that's limited to
Speaker 2:  people who own an iPhone 15 Pro. Right? So that very like, it
Speaker 2:  mean the thing costs $3,500, I'm assuming that's a pretty Yeah. Big overlap
Speaker 2:  of of Apple customers and then it's the the then it's the stuff, right?
Speaker 2:  Spatial FaceTime where you get your avatar you can talk to, but you need
Speaker 2:  two vision pros to pull this off. Fascinating. I mean, if a user is
Speaker 2:  wearing Vision Pro while on FaceTime, they appear as their persona while
Speaker 2:  others joining from Mac ipo, iPad or iPhone appear in a tile. Okay. Like
Speaker 2:  we just have to see this stuff work. But that's still like this is the cutting
Speaker 2:  edge stuff and you can't really use it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Because you yourself will not experience this. Right.
Speaker 4:  Right, right. It's actually possible
Speaker 2:  You'll be the persona to someone else. Right.
Speaker 4:  If you're on a Vision Pro and everybody else is on
Speaker 4:  a different Apple device for face, you get tiles, it's, it's actually not
Speaker 4:  gonna be a great experience. Right. It'll be fine. But like it won't be,
Speaker 4:  again, it's, it's a face iPad. That's what that will feel like. What will
Speaker 4:  you look
Speaker 2:  Like? And then that's it by the way. Then, then we get breakthrough design
Speaker 2:  and we can talk about that stuff. But that, in terms of experiences, you
Speaker 2:  can have in the headset, that's Apple's list.
Speaker 4:  So
Speaker 7:  IPad stuff and VR
Speaker 2:  Stuff and it's, yeah. It's just funny that the, the first thing to describe
Speaker 2:  is you will go somewhere else, totally VR and then they describe
Speaker 2:  productivity. Then you can play games from the app store and then you,
Speaker 2:  and then this personas thing. You know, like I, again, I've worn one of these
Speaker 2:  things. It was very compelling when I wore it. It's the best VR experience
Speaker 2:  I've ever had. Yeah. But if Apple wants to break through into the spatial
Speaker 2:  computing and they think the future is augmented reality,
Speaker 2:  actually very unclear where the augmented reality part of this headset comes
Speaker 2:  in. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I think the productivity is probably gonna be the closest thing that we
Speaker 4:  see there. Yeah. I mean, and one thing I noticed, and again, it's possible
Speaker 4:  this is just like the way that it's written in the press release is Apple
Speaker 4:  mentions that there are sort of specific
Speaker 4:  spatial games like Made for the Vision Pro and doesn't say that
Speaker 4:  about any other app. So it's like, I think there's a decent chance that what
Speaker 4:  we're gonna get is like fantastical with a different border in
Speaker 4:  the Vision Pro. And I think that's gonna be a lot of these apps where like
Speaker 4:  translucent, they're just gonna get rid of the Chrome in their apps so that
Speaker 4:  it feels more like a floating rectangle. And that's gonna be the Vision Pro
Speaker 4:  app. Yeah. And I think this question of like, what does a spatial
Speaker 4:  calendar look like is gonna take a while. And I don't know if that's
Speaker 4:  a thing people want or if that's worth working on, or if it's gonna be
Speaker 4:  meaningfully better than an iPad app in front of your face. but it
Speaker 4:  doesn't seem like anyone has really cracked
Speaker 4:  that. Yeah. And I think Apple is betting that some
Speaker 4:  combination of FaceTime and just like the interface
Speaker 4:  is gonna be the killer app for people. Because like to your point, the eye
Speaker 4:  tracking is awesome.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  The pinchy pinch thing, at least in the demos that we've gotten, is fantastic.
Speaker 4:  Like, it's just fun to use the thing. And I think for at least this
Speaker 4:  first version of a $3,500 gadget that might get
Speaker 4:  Apple far enough.
Speaker 2:  So Yeah, my theory is that Apple does not really want people to buy this
Speaker 2:  one, like at scale, right? They're gonna make 500,000
Speaker 2:  maybe. I think that's the rumor I heard in terms of like, I was like,
Speaker 5:  That's a lot. It seems like
Speaker 4:  A lot. That's the thing I've been hearing a bunch this week, is how many
Speaker 4:  does Apple think it's gonna sell? Yeah. That that's the other number everybody's
Speaker 4:  talking about.
Speaker 2:  And the, the thing I heard yesterday is they're actually capped by how many
Speaker 2:  displays that can be made. We'll see. Right. They, they're, they're the bleeding
Speaker 2:  edge of display tech. So we'll see. I just think that Apple does
Speaker 2:  not want this to be a ma this version of this thing to be a mask consumer
Speaker 2:  device.
Speaker 5:  Right. Because it's, it's a developer's kit. Like
Speaker 2:  Yeah. They just polished it up to Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That that's why we don't, that's why everything in it is, is kind of weird.
Speaker 5:  And, and we don't know what the killer app is 'cause they don't know what
Speaker 5:  the killer app is. So they're like, here's our thing. Please don't call it
Speaker 5:  VR or AR even that, that's what it is. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And, and I, I get why they're doing that. They, they want to like, they're
Speaker 5:  late to that game and so they don't wanna be, feel like they're late to that
Speaker 5:  game. So spatial computing is the thing and it sounds like it is really,
Speaker 5:  really cool, but it's also just very clear that they don't know what they're
Speaker 5:  doing entirely.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And so lemme just tell you what you get for your 3,500 bucks. You get
Speaker 2:  the headset, you get the solo knit band and the dual loop band
Speaker 2:  sick, which are the headbands put around your head. Appreciate that. A light
Speaker 2:  seal and two light seal cushions. The light seal seems like a thing that
Speaker 2:  you gotta to finagle with and get exactly right. 'cause you gotta block out
Speaker 2:  all light. The Vision Pro cover very important polishing cloth.
Speaker 2:  Don't
Speaker 4:  Just skip over. That's, that's like 20 bucks.
Speaker 2:  It's a lot. Oh yeah. Wow. Free polish cloth. The battery, the USPC
Speaker 2:  charging cable and the US PC adapter. I think we continually forget
Speaker 2:  Vision Pro is two and a half hour battery life with an external battery pack
Speaker 4:  That you wear on in your pocket. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Not cable. I, I'm just telling you like, I agree with you. I think this is
Speaker 2:  a developer kit. I think they need developers to get their hands on this
Speaker 2:  thing. They need people to start using it. They need to collect some data
Speaker 2:  about what it's for, why it's, why it exists. And I think that
Speaker 2:  is just the most, unlike Apple, I've seen any product in quite a while. Even
Speaker 2:  the watch, which I criticize heavily at the beginning, and it took them three
Speaker 2:  tries to figure out the watch. Yeah, yeah. And now it's a huge success and
Speaker 2:  everybody know it's a huge success. But the, the watch was like a shotgun
Speaker 2:  blast of ideas about what you could do with a computer and your wrist
Speaker 2:  down to you will flirt with people in school by sending them your heartbeat.
Speaker 2:  But that was like a complete Johnny Ive thought. Yes. Yeah. Not a
Speaker 2:  good thought.
Speaker 4:  It's a fun
Speaker 2:  Thought. Not a thought that landed anywhere, but he was like, here's what
Speaker 2:  you're gonna do. You're gonna put your fingers in your wrist, then you're
Speaker 2:  just gonna read your heartbeat and someone else is gonna feel your heartbeat.
Speaker 2:  And they will know that you want to go to the movies. The
Speaker 4:  Vision Pro is like comparatively a little, is this anything? Yeah. E
Speaker 4:  that
Speaker 2:  Way it's, it's got that vibe. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And I, you know what's weird is there's nothing at CES trying to compete
Speaker 4:  with it. Like
Speaker 2:  Around, there's a couple of things. So many ounces, a fake headset that doesn't
Speaker 2:  exist
Speaker 5:  In real, but that,
Speaker 4:  That they're just imagining is like a content creation device. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's it's a camera more than it is anything. But then yeah, we saw X reel,
Speaker 4:  which is making the sort of like AR display glasses.
Speaker 4:  It's doing more like degrees of freedom and they can see depth and all this
Speaker 4:  stuff. Like they're pushing towards this thing, but everybody else is still
Speaker 4:  on this. Like, we're gonna take something that looks passively like glasses
Speaker 4:  and then try to make it more and more powerful over time. No one, at least
Speaker 4:  as far as I've seen, is trying to do the whole swing so far.
Speaker 5:  I mean, Meta is very clear, like Meta is right.
Speaker 4:  Oh sure. But Meta's not really here doing stuff either. They're like,
Speaker 5:  I think the thing is Apple, we're, we're looking at it as like, oh is Apple,
Speaker 5:  why is nobody competing with Apple here? And that's because Apple is late
Speaker 5:  to the party and Apple has to actually compete
Speaker 2:  With everyone else. Yeah. Everyone else already launched their failed VR
Speaker 2:  headsets two years ago. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And three and four and five years ago. Yeah. Yeah. But no, and I also think
Speaker 4:  what I've heard from a bunch of people this week that the fact that the
Speaker 4:  RayBan met up Smart Glasses, the ones that actually look like real glasses
Speaker 4:  have been such a hit with people is changing. A lot of folks' mind about
Speaker 4:  actually the way to approach this, and I've gotten a lot of confidence from
Speaker 4:  people over the last couple of months, but even including at this show,
Speaker 4:  who think the Vision Pro is wrong in a way that people don't usually bet
Speaker 4:  against Apple products and are convinced that if we can take something
Speaker 4:  that is closer to looking like a normal thing you'd wear out at a
Speaker 4:  place like CES and not a pair of ski goggles on your face, we can get
Speaker 4:  that to Powerful faster than Apple can get Division
Speaker 4:  Pro to like socially cool. Yeah. And I think Apple usually
Speaker 4:  wins that race, but this is kind of the hardest it has
Speaker 4:  ever had to try to do that. And I just think it's gonna be so fascinating.
Speaker 4:  But I am sort of bummed that no one here, like this is the year Samsung should
Speaker 4:  have been like,
Speaker 2:  There's a rumor that Samsung Google are gonna do's.
Speaker 2:  It doesn't have local dimming, but it'll show you artwork. Right.
Speaker 2:  Anywhere you want. There's a rumor saying Google and Samsung are gonna do
Speaker 2:  something again. Yeah, we'll
Speaker 4:  See, because that went great the last time here. Everybody had one of those.
Speaker 2:  We've run this, we've run this experiment before maybe we'll
Speaker 2:  see. But that is, I will say where CSS is great. I love the gadgets. I'm
Speaker 2:  talking about TVs and laptops that are actually two laptops
Speaker 2:  bolted
Speaker 4:  Together,
Speaker 5:  Put 'em together. Exhibit would be so happy.
Speaker 2:  But I, I suspect we're gonna spend the year talking about the Vision Pro.
Speaker 2:  I think that's right. Yeah. Because it really, you know, Apple's betting
Speaker 2:  on it. It's their big new category. A lot of ideas contained in that thing.
Speaker 2:  And I agree. I think there's something to the fact that the Meta glasses
Speaker 2:  are doing well and people like them in a way that we, I usually don't see
Speaker 2:  this. Sean Holser is here. He is taking a lot of videos at a lot of the,
Speaker 2:  the little events. He's been wearing a phone sort of like on a Chest mount
Speaker 2:  so he could like show people with his hands and our commenters on TikTok
Speaker 2:  and all the social platforms are assuming they're, he's taking with the Meta
Speaker 2:  glasses. Oh, interesting. Which is super fascinating. Like they've already
Speaker 2:  broken into consciousness such that people think that that's the camera he's
Speaker 2:  using. And we, and like ve in our director is like, nah, that's
Speaker 2:  a iPhone I don.
Speaker 2:  All right. I think that's it for the, it's day one. It's day one, Liam Day
Speaker 2:  one day one of css. It's always day one.
Speaker 2:  There's lots more on the show. We gotta do an entire show about not screens.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And Alex has to talk about TC screen 0.0 some of have screens,
Speaker 2:  some of the non screens. We haven't talked about a car yet, right? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And they're all, it's all cars here at css, which
Speaker 2:  have, are not screens for David's Rubrik. They're not
Speaker 1:  Screen
Speaker 2:  Gadgets, but they do have screens. Shut up. Don't worry about it. It's gonna
Speaker 2:  be fine. Things that rolling and things that don't. That's the new split.
Speaker 2:  We'll be back a little later this week with that episode. In the meantime,
Speaker 2:  if there's stuff you want us to go check out at css, you have questions about
Speaker 2:  some of the stuff you're seeing. We're here, like I said, from a tech reporter
Speaker 2:  standpoint, this is Vision and Barrel. We can go find out almost anything
Speaker 2:  you want except what the Vision Pro is for. That'll be for later.
Speaker 2:  All right. That's it. That's for our cast rock roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Verge Cast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next
Speaker 1:  for more details.