# Transcript
ID: 2c2d5895-bc16-4e93-878f-02f2f0711035
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-3028386712359205687/1412775986284796380/s93290-US-4045s-1733657203.mp3
Description: Welcome to our two-part preview of the year to come! For the first installment, Nilay, David, and Wall Street Journal columnist Joanna Stern bring all the predictions for 2025 — their mildest, medium-est, and spiciest ideas about the year to come. Each host presents their take on TikTok bans, social platforms, smart homes, streaming services, and more, and the others get to decide whether they agree. Whoever gets the most right at the end of the year will win a big prize. (There's a points system for determining all that, but we'll figure that out later.)
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (10 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of extremely
Speaker 2:  mild, very hot takes. I'm your friend David Pierce, and I
Speaker 2:  am Christmas shopping. I have my whole list. I'm very organized this year.
Speaker 2:  I have all the people that I need. I know roughly what I'm getting them.
Speaker 2:  I had like a big self brainstorm of ideas, but do you know what I
Speaker 2:  discovered? For me at least, the single hardest thing
Speaker 2:  to buy is like a pretty good $20 gift.
Speaker 2:  The things for like secret Santa parties or colleagues at work,
Speaker 2:  or just this like list of people in the world. You need to get
Speaker 2:  something but you don't know them well enough to
Speaker 2:  really get something like super personal. And also, it might be weird If
Speaker 2:  you did and you don't wanna spend a ton of money. I think this is why
Speaker 2:  I end up both like giving and receiving a lot of Starbucks gift cards every
Speaker 2:  year. It's just a pretty universally useful thing that people like.
Speaker 2:  But I don't want to do that so much anymore. I just don't know
Speaker 2:  what else to do. I'm sort of lost on this idea of like, what is a good
Speaker 2:  $20 relatively safe and
Speaker 2:  universally liked gift to give? If you have the answer, I want
Speaker 2:  to know, please tell me. Sincerely, you will make everything about my holiday
Speaker 2:  planning for forever better and easier. So get at me.
Speaker 2:  Anyway. This episode is the first in a two-part series. We're doing
Speaker 2:  about 2025. It's the end of 2024. We're doing some looking
Speaker 2:  back on this show, but we thought it would also be fun to spend some time
Speaker 2:  looking forward. 2025 is gonna be a big year in tech. We have
Speaker 2:  a new administration coming into office that is gonna change the way that
Speaker 2:  we think about a lot of politics and regulation and has a lot of feelings
Speaker 2:  about big tech. Frankly. We have this AI
Speaker 2:  bubble slash hype cycle slash
Speaker 2:  takeover of the world that is still ongoing. We have all
Speaker 2:  kinds of questions about antitrust and big tech and what's gonna happen
Speaker 2:  to the venture capital world. There's just a lot going on and
Speaker 2:  it feels like in so many ways, 2025 is going to
Speaker 2:  be maybe not a turning point, but a moment in certain
Speaker 2:  ways. So we figured we'd just look ahead and see what we could guess
Speaker 2:  about what's coming. I grabbed Ne Patel and the Wall Street Journal's, Joanna
Speaker 2:  Stern, two of my favorite people to speculate wildly about tech with,
Speaker 2:  and we spent some time doing it for this first episode. We each came with
Speaker 2:  predictions. I gave them both the homework to come with three different predictions
Speaker 2:  ranked in order of spiciness, and we're just gonna go around and talk about
Speaker 2:  it. We invented a little game that, if I'm honest, only like half makes
Speaker 2:  sense to me at this point, but we're gonna figure it out as we go. It's gonna
Speaker 2:  be very fun. All that is coming up in just a second, But first,
Speaker 2:  I guess I'm just buying Starbucks gift cards. This is life now. Merry Christmas.
Speaker 2:  Everybody have some Starbucks. This is The Verge cast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Neil Patella is here. Hello, Joanna Stern.
Speaker 2:  Hello, hello. We're all in the studio. This is so exciting. I'm very, this
Speaker 2:  guys very so
Speaker 3:  Happy. I know we're, I'm gonna look at you or I'm gonna look at both of you.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  We have spent like a lot of time in rooms together over the years and not
Speaker 2:  in a very long time. This is very exciting. Okay, here's how this is gonna
Speaker 2:  work. Okay? I have told both of you to come with three predictions
Speaker 2:  for 2025 in increasing level of spiciness.
Speaker 2:  Not necessarily like less likely to come true, but like
Speaker 2:  I want your victory lap for each one to be successively bigger. Does that
Speaker 2:  make sense? Like If you, your third take should be the one that If
Speaker 2:  you are right, you're gonna, you're gonna tell a lot of people about how
Speaker 2:  you were right. Oh good. Okay. Okay. So
Speaker 2:  we're gonna go around, we're gonna talk about them. And then the way that
Speaker 2:  this game plays is after each one of us gives a prediction, we're gonna talk
Speaker 2:  about it. The other two get to decide if they wanna like co-sign
Speaker 2:  that prediction at the end of the year. You get a
Speaker 2:  point if that prediction comes true. I guess you lose a point if it
Speaker 2:  doesn't 'cause otherwise you should just sign on to all of them so you
Speaker 4:  Can end up with negative points.
Speaker 2:  I think you have to be able to end up with negative points. Okay. So there
Speaker 2:  should be some consequence for picking all of them. So I'm just making up
Speaker 2:  the rules as we go here. Yeah, so you, you lose a point.
Speaker 2:  We'll do half points. I'm just kidding. You lose a point If you pick a prediction
Speaker 2:  and it's wrong, but you get a point If you pick a prediction and it's right
Speaker 2:  at the end of the year, this episode and the next episode next week, which
Speaker 2:  we're gonna do more 2025 stuff, we're gonna total all the points and whoever
Speaker 2:  wins The Vergecast is going to buy you the
Speaker 2:  most cool gadget of 2025. What will it be?
Speaker 2:  How much will it cost? Who knows? But we're gonna do this again. This
Speaker 4:  Is a room full of people that does not need help acquiring
Speaker 2:  This.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I was, I'm gonna have already bought that.
Speaker 4:  Can I just get the cash value? You can
Speaker 3:  Have, have the cash value. Can
Speaker 2:  The cash value is of this prize is one 100th of a Senate?
Speaker 3:  Well, it depends.
Speaker 2:  All right. So this is what we're doing. We're gonna make it work. I'm excited
Speaker 2:  about it. Joanna, you're the guest. You get to go first. But we're, we're
Speaker 2:  gonna start small and build up to it. Okay. So what is your, what is your
Speaker 2:  mildest prediction for 2025?
Speaker 3:  I have two. Of course you do. Is that, would I lose a point already
Speaker 3:  for having two? Okay. I lose a point. It's fine. Starting at negative. Negative,
Speaker 3:  perfect. Okay. It's 2026
Speaker 3:  at the end, or we're at the end of 2025 and I am
Speaker 3:  still posting to 500 different social media accounts.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, because social media is still more fractured.
Speaker 3:  Wait,
Speaker 4:  I have a question. A clarifying question. Do you mean
Speaker 4:  Twitter, like social media accounts?
Speaker 3:  Yes. T yes. And also TikTok.
Speaker 4:  'cause like TikTok, TikTok and an Instagram post are different.
Speaker 3:  Actually this was another one in here. Okay. TikTok survives. So I'm still
Speaker 3:  posting there. Okay. I actually don't post there that often, but maybe I
Speaker 3:  should. Maybe I will. So TikTok survives, but also
Speaker 3:  we've got blue Sky, we've got threads, we have something else. We've got
Speaker 3:  masted on 0.3 0.0, we've got X
Speaker 3:  Instagram.
Speaker 4:  Right. I'm just saying that the Twitter likes Facebook are
Speaker 2:  One. Yeah. Let's just keep it to the Twitter likes for this one. This is,
Speaker 2:  yeah,
Speaker 3:  I mean mostly I'm talking about the, the Twitter likes. Yeah. Because
Speaker 4:  There's no chance the short form video ones are gonna consolidate
Speaker 4:  like no Instagram reels and TikTok and YouTube
Speaker 3:  Short. No, I'm just saying there's more it, it's just more, there's just
Speaker 3:  more of 'em. Like there was, yes, there, there was.
Speaker 4:  You're, you're yelping for days. This is
Speaker 3:  This, you know, there is years, you know, it was like 2022 where it was like
Speaker 3:  the backlash to social media. Next year people are gonna spend more time.
Speaker 3:  No, next year we are more on social media and yeah, I am
Speaker 3:  still posting every day to 500 different accounts
Speaker 3:  and my AI agent,
Speaker 4:  Are you gonna still post to x
Speaker 3:  Is also coming. But that my AI agent also that that's one of the things it
Speaker 3:  has to do is, is keep posting. Do
Speaker 2:  You think it's the same set that you're posting to now?
Speaker 3:  There could be more. There's probably gonna be more. Okay.
Speaker 2:  So you think the number goes up?
Speaker 3:  I don't think the number goes down and that is my prediction. Okay.
Speaker 3:  That is just not gonna get any better.
Speaker 4:  I'm not signing onto this one. Oh,
Speaker 2:  I a hundred percent am You're not. I'm ex what? What goes away? Yeah,
Speaker 3:  What wins?
Speaker 4:  I think that the ability
Speaker 4:  to hit one button and post to multiple Twitter likes Okay. Will go up
Speaker 4:  and that will, you will experience that as going down.
Speaker 4:  Does that make any sense?
Speaker 3:  Yes, it does. But where am I gonna look at all the replies?
Speaker 4:  Probably, probably, probably one of those clients. 'cause of the whole point
Speaker 4:  of these except for X, which I, I will say probably stubbornly
Speaker 4:  remain in like a walled garden. Everyone else is gonna
Speaker 4:  pick a way to interoperate.
Speaker 3:  That's a nice solution. Even like
Speaker 4:  Socials of the world.
Speaker 2:  He does get the point. And it is true if, if like if the Fedi verse wins
Speaker 2:  Yep, it counts as one. It's now.
Speaker 4:  So that's the whole
Speaker 2:  Point. No, but that's the whole point because the fedi verse is many things,
Speaker 2:  but it is one thing you only have to post to one place and it posts everything
Speaker 2:  to everywhere. That's the whole point of the fedi verse, right? Yeah. So
Speaker 2:  what you're saying is like, yeah, these things will come together in such
Speaker 2:  a way that makes it actually more but feel like less.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And that will enable more to exist. Right? Which, So
Speaker 3:  I think we're saying kind of the same thing, but you win. I think this point,
Speaker 3:  I don't even know how the game works, frankly. Sorry you don't have to, but
Speaker 3:  you went 'cause you gave a solution to my problem.
Speaker 4:  Well see, I don't know. I dunno what's gonna happen. I just know that even,
Speaker 4:  I think
Speaker 3:  You're right. I think both of our things are gonna happen.
Speaker 4:  Truth social is a Mastodon clone. It's actually very funny.
Speaker 4:  They just copied the open source Mastodon code base and the license of
Speaker 4:  is so restrictive that true social has to publish its own source code.
Speaker 4:  This is a real thing and they obfuscate it. So now there's like other people
Speaker 4:  who try to un like clear it up and explain what's going on through. It's
Speaker 4:  very funny. All that's very funny. But the point is,
Speaker 3:  I didn't know you were such a truth social user. So, well
Speaker 4:  I'm just keeping track of how you would build new social products. And the
Speaker 4:  obvious way to do it is to take the open source projects, right? So if
Speaker 4:  that's just the way that people begin to build new things, then they're gonna
Speaker 4:  interoperate. 'cause those things are already built to interoperate. I don't
Speaker 4:  know that's gonna play out. There's a, there's like, you know Yeah. A greater
Speaker 4:  than nothing chance that blue sky's like, oh wait, everyone's on blue sky
Speaker 4:  and they just shut it down. Yeah. And they become a walled garden. I don't
Speaker 4:  think that's gonna happen. That's not how they talk. But I just don't dunno
Speaker 4:  what's gonna happen six months from now. But my, my belief,
Speaker 4:  the reason I'm not signing onto this prediction is that just at the user
Speaker 4:  level, you'll, for the Twitter likes, you'll push a button post everywhere
Speaker 4:  and collect all the replies in one place. Mm.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I hope you're right. I don't think you're, I kind,
Speaker 3:  I was bundling TikTok in there too because I, I wanted one of them to be
Speaker 3:  that like TikTok survives. So I was trying to get everything in one that
Speaker 3:  social media is just still a mess and it's fractured and we're
Speaker 3:  everywhere and we still have a million apps on our phones that we're opening.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I'm just making the split between the things that look like Twitter
Speaker 4:  and the video platforms. Yes. Smart. The video platforms. Smart. Smart. I
Speaker 4:  agree. Will proliferate. Let's,
Speaker 2:  Let's take TikTok out because I, we're gonna come back to TikTok. Yeah, sure.
Speaker 2:  I have an odd feeling we're gonna come back to
Speaker 4:  TikTok.
Speaker 3:  I, I'm
Speaker 2:  Sure. Okay. So I'm I'm in on that one with Joanna Neli out and
Speaker 2:  is wrong. Neli, what's yours? You go
Speaker 4:  First. It's extremely mild. Okay. This is,
Speaker 2:  We will still have computers.
Speaker 4:  This is like, I didn't put any seasoning on the stock code. Do you know what
Speaker 4:  I'm saying? I think when they do the Alexa
Speaker 4:  ai, it will be okay. That
Speaker 3:  Is okay.
Speaker 4:  That's pretty good.
Speaker 2:  I was gonna say that's not as mild a take as it would've been six months
Speaker 2:  ago.
Speaker 4:  Well, here lemme explain why. So the stakes for Amazon
Speaker 4:  are so low, right? They're not Google where they, it
Speaker 4:  has to be good and they have to get it out in the future of all
Speaker 4:  search depends on Gemini. They're not Apple where
Speaker 4:  they're like, look at this glowing idiot. And they have to fix
Speaker 4:  it and they are advertising the products against it. They're just like, yeah,
Speaker 4:  this thing that does timers is already in your house.
Speaker 4:  What if it was better? Right. And they have Infinity to solve
Speaker 4:  that problem. Like there's no pressure to solve that problem.
Speaker 4:  And I think Panos will wait. I think he's very
Speaker 4:  comfortable waiting to solve that problem. And so that's, that's
Speaker 3:  It's Will he wait till after 2025? He
Speaker 4:  Could, yeah. My whole prediction is it'll be okay.
Speaker 4:  I'm not saying it'll, it launched. Who knows
Speaker 3:  In this year.
Speaker 4:  Huh? I I think it'll come in the next year.
Speaker 3:  See, my second mild was gonna be Apple Intelligence gets
Speaker 3:  better because it can't get any worse. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That's also pretty kind of in the exact same vein like thing that sucks.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Sucks slightly less. No.
Speaker 4:  See, I, So I would counter yours. I think it will get way worse.
Speaker 4:  I think Apple's going to feel the pressure of the other products doing stuff.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Yeah. And they're gonna try to make it do a bunch more stuff and it
Speaker 4:  can't do those things as we've all already experienced.
Speaker 2:  But don't think Amazon's gonna feel that pressure. No, because that same
Speaker 2:  pressure is coming from Amazon,
Speaker 4:  But they don't have a business based on that pressure. Right? Right. If one
Speaker 4:  person switches from an iPhone to a Pixel, because Gemini can do
Speaker 4:  something that's like, they have a meeting, right? Like Tim Cook is like,
Speaker 4:  everybody get in here like, what is going on? Where are
Speaker 2:  Robots? It should be kill RCS. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's right. There's a whole thing that happens. It's bad. Amazon is like,
Speaker 4:  what are you gonna do? You're gonna get a Google assistant. Like no, you're
Speaker 4:  not like you're lazy. Use it to Right. To play a time, play music and, and
Speaker 4:  set timers. So that's, that's their mildest prediction I have. They will
Speaker 4:  wait. Okay. I could be wrong.
Speaker 2:  It's a pretty mild prediction. I'm actually out on that one. Okay. I think
Speaker 2:  If you had made this prediction in July or like this time
Speaker 2:  last year, I would've been with you. But now I feel like the longer it goes
Speaker 2:  and every new headline that is like, actually the new
Speaker 2:  Alexa sucks. It does feel like the pressure is getting higher.
Speaker 4:  Well there isn't a new Alexa yet.
Speaker 2:  The new Alexa that they announced over a year ago. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  They've announced it forever
Speaker 2:  And haven't shipped. It's like it's, it's, we know what it is. They told
Speaker 2:  us what it is and then they didn't ship it. And it feels like, but
Speaker 4:  It has to arrive. That's what I'm saying. It has the best shot. Maybe I'll
Speaker 4:  revise my prediction of all of these. It has the best shot of being Okay.
Speaker 4:  It it,
Speaker 2:  That's probably true. Think I
Speaker 4:  Would agree with that. They have the most ability to wait. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Do do think the new Alexa is gonna to get a lot of people fired?
Speaker 2:  That's my, that's my other take.
Speaker 3:  Well, that's my thing. I kind of want it to not be okay. It will
Speaker 3:  be so funny if it's not. Okay. This
Speaker 4:  Is your, can you
Speaker 2:  Imagine? 'cause they, especially they have this giant install base of regular
Speaker 2:  people who use these things all the time. I regular
Speaker 3:  People. That's like the Apple intelligence stuff. It's so funny when you
Speaker 3:  see these things happen. I, yeah. I'm, I'm actually, I'm with Neli
Speaker 3:  because, well, no, I'm not with you.
Speaker 4:  I'm not with you.
Speaker 3:  I'm not with you because I want it to not be Okay.
Speaker 4:  You just want the headlines.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I think the headlines we just,
Speaker 2:  You're imagining the video you're gonna make about terrible Alexa and you're
Speaker 2:  like, it's much better if it sucks than if it's good. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  We were home for Thanksgiving and every time my mom set a timer on our Alexa,
Speaker 4:  it played an audio clip from the movie The Wild Robot. And she, and she had
Speaker 4:  not seen this movie, max and I have seen this movie. Yeah. And so the thing
Speaker 4:  would be like processing beep boop bop and then it would like set the timer
Speaker 4:  and my mom would be like, what's wrong with Alexa?
Speaker 3:  Wait, Amazon just built that in as like a fun thing. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  She's like, every time you do, so it's like, it's like processing. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like it does the thing that the robot does in that movie. And Max is like
Speaker 4:  losing her mind. She thinks it's the cutest thing in the world. And my mom
Speaker 4:  is like, why is my Alexa so much stupid than
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 2:  Was? Wait, that's actually such a perfect example of why ambient computing
Speaker 2:  is so impossible. Like what a perfect low stakes example of like, you have
Speaker 2:  to build a thing that makes sense to everyone in the room. Yeah. Right? And
Speaker 2:  that's so hard to do.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It was just like out of context. It made no sense except for the
Speaker 4:  6-year-old was like, I love that movie.
Speaker 3:  Wait, they did, they rolled this out to everyone.
Speaker 4:  I they rolled it out to my mom. That's
Speaker 3:  Not smart.
Speaker 4:  She didn't turn it on on
Speaker 3:  Purpose. That's absolutely not smart.
Speaker 4:  I know. Did he? Well, I mean, I thought it was delightful. Yeah. How
Speaker 4:  in many ways my mother's experience of computers is exactly the same as Max's
Speaker 4:  experience of computers in that things happen until they stop happening and
Speaker 4:  they ask me to fix them. Right. And then I have to deduce what happened here.
Speaker 4:  And I don't know that she ever went down.
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna call my mom mom and talk and ask her to talk to Alexa with me on
Speaker 3:  the phone today to see if she got this.
Speaker 4:  You
Speaker 3:  Know, they have it in the kitchen. They have like,
Speaker 4:  That's that's what it's for. And I'm telling you they just, they just have
Speaker 4:  to wait. Right. People are gonna keep using 'em, set timers and then one
Speaker 4:  day they're like, you're Alexa way smarter. And then everyone's gonna fall
Speaker 4:  in love with their kitchen timer.
Speaker 3:  Okay. David, what's yours?
Speaker 2:  All right. That's a good one. Joanna and I are both out, so we'll see. Okay.
Speaker 2:  I'm actually out Joanna. It's just crossing our fingers and hoping. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Mine is that, I think this is, this gets milder by
Speaker 2:  the day. I think cable TV is going to pretty much totally die in
Speaker 2:  2025. Like the idea that you are going to
Speaker 2:  have a cable box through which you get television
Speaker 2:  and it's a bunch of linear channels and that's what you pay a lot of money
Speaker 2:  for. And mostly watch is going to be essentially completely out
Speaker 2:  of style.
Speaker 4:  I have a number of follow-up questions. Okay.
Speaker 4:  When you say pretty much die there, there,
Speaker 4:  there won't be any anymore.
Speaker 2:  There will be some, but it'll be, it'll be like the people
Speaker 2:  who still get a OL discs in the mail and
Speaker 4:  Pay for, which sustained AOL for years.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's, there are still people who do it. Right. Like it's, it's still
Speaker 2:  a thing that exists, but it, but
Speaker 4:  We work at aol. There are people who are like, you know, this whole company
Speaker 4:  runs on CDs in the mail. Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And there are still, I'm sure some, you know, hundreds of
Speaker 2:  thousands or millions of people who pay for America online, they
Speaker 3:  Pay for their email address.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And so that I think will continue more or less forever,
Speaker 2:  but like it's going to die to the extent that it is no longer an interesting
Speaker 2:  business to the companies that run it. Like the thing that
Speaker 2:  Comcast is doing where it's spinning off all of its cable channels.
Speaker 2:  Everyone is going to do that and they're going to just absolutely run away
Speaker 2:  from
Speaker 4:  Cable. Okay. So second follow up question. Yeah. YouTube, TV and FUBU
Speaker 4:  and Sling, you're over the top cable bundles. Are they included?
Speaker 2:  They don't count in this. And I, I grant that this is,
Speaker 2:  I'm, I'm like splitting hairs on that one, but they are
Speaker 2:  meaningfully different products.
Speaker 3:  So you're talking about like the Xfinity
Speaker 4:  The box offering
Speaker 2:  The the box Yeah. Is
Speaker 3:  Really the same, the Xfinity box, the guy that comes to your house. Right.
Speaker 2:  Third follow question. The, the cable that I buy from my internet provider,
Speaker 2:  which is essentially what it is now, is gone.
Speaker 4:  So third, third follow up question. Yeah. You can really tell that. I was
Speaker 4:  just in my parents' house. They don't have Spectrum boxes anymore. They have
Speaker 4:  an insane Spectrum app on their Apple TVs. Yeah. Which
Speaker 4:  does not, it's it's not great.
Speaker 4:  It's not, it
Speaker 2:  Has a grid in the Nest channels.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You know what I mean? Yeah. It's like, it's super there.
Speaker 3:  So they're paying spectrum for those channels. Right. And they, that's everything's
Speaker 4:  Strange. Yeah. And then is it broadly the same as YouTube tv? She
Speaker 4:  can watch it on her iPad wherever she's So that's like a big win. Does that
Speaker 4:  count?
Speaker 1:  No,
Speaker 2:  But I can't explain why. Oh wait, no, that counts as cable.
Speaker 2:  I think that is the thing that is
Speaker 3:  Dying too broad
Speaker 4:  Here. But that's not YouTube tv. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Let me, let me say this more the, I can be more
Speaker 4:  Specific. You're
Speaker 2:  Killing, I'm killing everything except YouTube TV and Hulu with live tv.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I'm killing all of it except those two things.
Speaker 4:  Okay. That's where I'm at. I'm super out in this prediction. You're out on
Speaker 2:  This one.
Speaker 4:  I win this round. I think, I think inertia,
Speaker 2:  Again, not debt varies but, but completely uninteresting
Speaker 2:  to everyone in including the people that run these services.
Speaker 4:  My parents also have an illegal Indian IP TV box that gets every channel
Speaker 4:  for free, including locals in 4K. And that is, and
Speaker 2:  They pay for the Spectrum app on their
Speaker 4:  IPads? No, they pay some guy the on Venmo over the phone once a year.
Speaker 4:  What? These things, you should write a column. This, there's an entire economy,
Speaker 4:  these things. Wow. What? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. That's fantastic. This,
Speaker 3:  I was gonna say, this episode is, I think that
Speaker 2:  Counts Eli visits. I think your parents are on my side.
Speaker 3:  I was gonna say
Speaker 4:  That It's very entertaining.
Speaker 3:  The title of this episode was gonna be Neli Goes to visit his parents. No,
Speaker 4:  I just blew,
Speaker 3:  It's actually Neli gets his parents arrested. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  No, no. I just blew up like the entire Indian uncle economy here.
Speaker 4:  This is what they talk about. They all know a guy. They are scams.
Speaker 2:  It's fantastic. It's great. Alright, so Eli's out. Joanna, are you in or
Speaker 2:  out?
Speaker 3:  I'm still not sure I understand. So I'm out. Yes, you do.
Speaker 4:  Do you think she thinks traditional cable's going away except for YouTube?
Speaker 2:  Joanna just keeps getting more cable boxes. By
Speaker 4:  The way, this implies
Speaker 3:  That No, I don't have cable boxes and my parents don't have cable boxes.
Speaker 3:  Anyway, I'm, I'm in this, I'm just not talking about my parents as much as
Speaker 3:  Eli because I didn't feel like this was Joana. I love my parents, I love
Speaker 3:  my parents
Speaker 3:  and they have a lot of the same commonality with your, let's get our parents
Speaker 3:  together. Let's bring our parents to this podcast.
Speaker 2:  Done.
Speaker 4:  Done. No thank you.
Speaker 3:  But I, I guess I'm in. Okay,
Speaker 2:  Great. Love it. Joanna. Just picking it random. Are you writing these down?
Speaker 2:  I am writing these down. Where?
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  In I have a doc.
Speaker 4:  Every cable company, except for YouTube TV is going outta
Speaker 2:  Business. Every cable. Not going outta business. Don't just irrelevant. We're
Speaker 3:  Just not getting them.
Speaker 4:  Are they already irrelevant?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, that's the thing. No, So I think it's already happened. We've
Speaker 2:  Been doing this thing where they all invest in streaming and bank the
Speaker 2:  money from cable. That's been happening for a very long time. And everybody
Speaker 2:  thought it was gonna happen for a really long time and then it isn't. And
Speaker 2:  I think it's going to the, the speed of that death of
Speaker 2:  the cable money is going to increase so fast that by
Speaker 2:  this time next year. Oh I see. It's to be essentially
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Spicy time. Let's
Speaker 2:  flip the order. Not spicy t just spicy or
Speaker 2:  neli you go first this time. What's your, what's your most medium prediction
Speaker 2:  for 2025?
Speaker 4:  Medium.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Walmart buy TikTok.
Speaker 2:  Walmart.
Speaker 4:  Walmart Buy TikTok. This is your medium taste. Medium.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna be Amazon or
Speaker 2:  This Likey, but you're not.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I I think there's only two. This is like
Speaker 2:  The third question on Hot ones level of, of spice is what we're talking about.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Well so the, he like Donald Trump has said, I won't shut it down.
Speaker 4:  He, one of his big benefactors, a major investor in TikTok, but he can't
Speaker 4:  overturn the law that Congress already passed that says TikTok has to go
Speaker 4:  and App Source have to kick it out. So the number of options are very limited
Speaker 4:  and I don't think that he cares what happens. And I don't think
Speaker 4:  the people on TikTok actually care what happens. Right. So if he's, as
Speaker 2:  Long as TikTok continues to exist,
Speaker 4:  As long as TikTok continues to exist. So there's this very natural out which
Speaker 4:  is they should sell it. Right? Which is the thing the law is sort of designed
Speaker 4:  to force into happening. And then Trump loves a deal
Speaker 4:  whether or not those deals are real. Whether or not LCD factories actually
Speaker 4:  get built. We love talking about deals. So then who are you gonna sell it
Speaker 4:  to? Amazon is terrified of TikTok because it's basically QVC.
Speaker 4:  But even then I think you get some weird antitrust concerns. The other big
Speaker 4:  tech companies will basically say no. So you're kind of stuck with
Speaker 4:  the other big store
Speaker 4:  because that's all TikTok is, is a funnel into TikTok shop. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And hasn't the biggest sticking point in the algorithm that
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's like who controls it Right In Like what
Speaker 3:  Makes you, what makes you think that by dance is gonna say okay,
Speaker 3:  we're given it all, we'll sell it all.
Speaker 4:  What makes anyone think that people can perceive the quality of an
Speaker 4:  algorithm?
Speaker 4:  Like that was a very important, very good question. Sticky like
Speaker 4:  it when TikTok was growing, this was important. Right? Right.
Speaker 4:  Because it was finding you interest, it would like be really, really valuable.
Speaker 4:  And now it's kind of like, yeah man, you can make that thing 20% worse and
Speaker 4:  all the people are already on it. Yep. Yeah. And really all you're trying
Speaker 4:  to get 'em to do is shop and we can watch Elon Musk just like dial a
Speaker 4:  Twitter algorithm at Will and it doesn't seem to matter to that audience.
Speaker 4:  So I, I think there's less danger there than anyone thinks.
Speaker 2:  It does feel anecdotally like the sort of perceived
Speaker 2:  quality gap in like how well the platform knows me
Speaker 2:  between Yeah. Reels, shorts and TikTok has gone away.
Speaker 3:  Has gotten much smaller. Yeah, I agree.
Speaker 2:  Like I agree. I think I, for so long it was like
Speaker 2:  Reels was old tiktoks and Shorts was just like over here doing something
Speaker 2:  else that everyone hated. I feel like they're all the same thing now. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And
Speaker 4:  A bunch of the creators have figured out how to post the same stuff to the
Speaker 4:  same platforms without getting dinged. But that's, this is my medium take.
Speaker 4:  I don't actually know what's gonna happen but I if you're gonna sell it,
Speaker 4:  which seems like the most likely outcome. Yeah. 'cause otherwise they have
Speaker 4:  to overturn a law that a bunch of Republican members of Congress passed.
Speaker 4:  It's still hard. Even why
Speaker 2:  Isn't it Amazon though? I feel like it's Amazon
Speaker 3:  Because I think he's right on the antitrust stuff. Like
Speaker 4:  How is Amazon company? I think Meta and Google and Apple all get mad about
Speaker 4:  this.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And same for all of those other companies. What if it's Netflix?
Speaker 2:  What if Netflix is just like, what's up short form video. We own TikTok now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I could see it. I don't think Netflix super wants to be in that business.
Speaker 4:  Like they don't wanna be in a user-generated, isn't
Speaker 2:  It Netflix is like specifically pitting itself against all of those companies.
Speaker 4:  Right? And also it's, they're, they're not gonna convert into
Speaker 4:  Netflix subscriptions, which is the only thing they sell. Right. Walmart's
Speaker 4:  like here's some garbage. I saw a man on TikTok yesterday
Speaker 4:  trying to sell me a wall-mounted hose reel as an innovation
Speaker 4:  that I should buy for my family for Christmas. And I was like, my dude,
Speaker 4:  my dad bought that shit already at Menards in 1982. Like
Speaker 4:  what are we doing on this platform right now? And that, that's just
Speaker 4:  where we are on TikTok. It is just
Speaker 3:  A store. Totally. Yeah. No and that's like, there was a point where my whole
Speaker 3:  entire feed was just hair products. I was like, I already have a hair
Speaker 3:  iron because, and
Speaker 4:  You're like, my mom bought these at Menards and they,
Speaker 3:  My current hair iron, what I bought at Menards.
Speaker 3:  Google's Menards. Great deal.
Speaker 4:  See
Speaker 3:  Because
Speaker 2:  Menards a real thing. What
Speaker 3:  Is Menards?
Speaker 2:  Is this like a Midwest thing? Do we need to talk
Speaker 4:  About this? I gotta stop hanging out with East Coasters. This is like the
Speaker 4:  most deeply Wisconsin store in the
Speaker 3:  World. Is that your version of Home Depot?
Speaker 4:  It's it's Superior Depot.
Speaker 3:  It's your version of Depot,
Speaker 4:  Lowe's, home Depot's corporate. Yeah. Yeah. This is like I knew Menards when
Speaker 4:  they like first album.
Speaker 2:  I see. Does Menards to
Speaker 4:  Home Depots. The Chainsmokers. I wanna be very clear about
Speaker 4:  to comparison I'm making here.
Speaker 2:  Okay, that works for me. Yeah, I'm actually in on this one. I like it.
Speaker 2:  I think somebody is going to buy TikTok. Yes. And I feel like Walmart's as
Speaker 2:  good bet as any, so I'm, I'm in on this one
Speaker 3:  And I just believe TikTok survives. So Sure.
Speaker 4:  That's your medium take. No,
Speaker 3:  That was my like take. Yeah, the take that
Speaker 2:  Was take would've TikTok survives.
Speaker 3:  That was my mild take. It was like all the social media survives and we get
Speaker 3:  more. Right? Sure. Walmart seems nice. All right. Let until
Speaker 2:  You in we're all in. Sure I'm in. I love it all. I'll go next. My
Speaker 2:  medium prediction, which I actually think might be spicier than I realized
Speaker 2:  is that someone in 2025 is going to make an AI gadget that like actually
Speaker 2:  kicks ass and it's gonna be a huge hit. Ooh,
Speaker 4:  This is your medium. This
Speaker 2:  Is my medium
Speaker 4:  Compared to my mild of Alexa is Okay.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like I don't know, it probably won't be
Speaker 2:  the rabbit R two or the Humane ai pin two
Speaker 2:  or so. But like maybe it's the next meta RayBan
Speaker 2:  smart glasses that go like deep into more AI stuff.
Speaker 2:  Maybe it's like AirPods something. So I don't know.
Speaker 2:  Somebody is going to make a gadget that is like explicitly about AI and it's
Speaker 2:  gonna be awesome and tons of people are gonna want it.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Actually mine is similar to that. Yeah. My medium take. But
Speaker 3:  we should all vote on yours first. Okay.
Speaker 4:  No, no.
Speaker 2:  Is not gonna happen. What about this sale? The Johnny I thing This is
Speaker 4:  Deeply related to I don't think the Johnny,
Speaker 3:  I think's coming
Speaker 4:  At this year. I have three spicy takes and this is deeply related to one
Speaker 4:  of them. Okay,
Speaker 2:  Well then you're not gonna give it to me. So what was your spicy take that
Speaker 2:  you're
Speaker 4:  Oh sure. Yeah. Well I'll I'll just do it now. I'll do it now. Roll this.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. This is a rebuttal. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  With
Speaker 3:  It. Okay. That's a good order.
Speaker 4:  AI conclusively proven to be a bubble. Ooh.
Speaker 2:  Okay. It
Speaker 4:  It's Bluetooth. I pr it's just, it's Bluetooth next year
Speaker 4:  Bluetooth is gonna be great. AI
Speaker 2:  Is Bluetooth.
Speaker 4:  AI is Bluetooth ai. Everyone talks about it the same way. They make the same
Speaker 4:  lofty predictions about Bluetooth is gonna do. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  When did they do that?
Speaker 4:  All the time. They're like, these headphones are gonna rule and then you're
Speaker 4:  like, well Apple had to hijack the entire Bluetooth product call and make
Speaker 4:  their own Bluetooth.
Speaker 2:  Isn't it more that
Speaker 3:  No one else can, a different memory of Bluetooth Isn't
Speaker 2:  AI 5G?
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  In that case,
Speaker 4:  Sure, sure. Whatever garbage wireless protocol you want to use,
Speaker 4:  whatever garbage, wireless protocol you want to use, go for it. Sure. But
Speaker 4:  Bluetooth in particular was like an enabling technology that never
Speaker 4:  pan out. Right. That you would have an ecosystem Yep. Of
Speaker 4:  products all over around you that were all Bluetooth together. The smart
Speaker 4:  home would run on Bluetooth, low energy, all that stuff exists.
Speaker 4:  It's there. Yeah. 'cause
Speaker 3:  That's where I was thinking you were going with like you can go to the
Speaker 4:  Bluetooth conference,
Speaker 3:  You can go to the B Can you still Yeah.
Speaker 4:  The sig. Do you remember that Rocket
Speaker 3:  Sig still around?
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Do you remember what everybody was obsessed with? The like retail Bluetooth
Speaker 2:  where you would walk into a store and Oh no. Just like it would like Bluetooth.
Speaker 2:  All the coupons on Apples gonna
Speaker 4:  Do that. Yeah. Yeah. Oh yeah. The they still do that by the way, just to
Speaker 4:  track you. That is super happy. It's still there every time you walk through
Speaker 4:  the door of a store in the mall, it's like we found you again. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  then people wonder why it sound seems like everyone's listening to them.
Speaker 4:  No, it's just 'cause you existed with your phone and Bluetooth,
Speaker 4:  which again the core benefits of Bluetooth
Speaker 4:  pretty mild because Apple had to invent their own special Bluetooth to make
Speaker 4:  AirPods work. Okay. Which is what
Speaker 3:  Most, I have a lot of feelings about what he's saying.
Speaker 4:  Do you see what I'm saying? AI is on the exact same trajectory as
Speaker 4:  Bluetooth only 10,000 times more expensive. Okay. Okay.
Speaker 4:  There's not one product that is bigger than chat GPT that
Speaker 4:  you can make with AI today.
Speaker 3:  Okay. I'm not with you and I'm not with you. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Okay then where are you? I
Speaker 4:  Like that you just keep announcing this. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Where are you? That that's
Speaker 3:  My job here. No and no where
Speaker 4:  Mine was just a rebuttal. It's on a prediction. You
Speaker 3:  Did your prediction now. Well,
Speaker 2:  But if yours is true, mine can't be
Speaker 4:  Okay.
Speaker 2:  Right. Because if if, if we get to that is
Speaker 3:  Your spicy, you chose your spicy. That's what
Speaker 2:  Not spicy. That's not spicy. That's a reject spicy that he's rebutting.
Speaker 3:  Oh, so now you are getting two spicy.
Speaker 4:  No, no. That's not a prediction. No point. If AI is a bubble, I get no points.
Speaker 4:  Which is, I'm giving that up now in order to rebut David who says the
Speaker 4:  humane pit is gonna be
Speaker 3:  Good. You kind of a restaurant is this, you got so
Speaker 2:  Mila's just sneaking dishes in here.
Speaker 3:  This is my new restaurant called Menards. No, he
Speaker 4:  Say he made his prediction there would be a good AI gadget. And I'm saying
Speaker 4:  that requires B boost
Speaker 3:  To be good. Yeah. But now you're gonna get too spicy.
Speaker 4:  I'm just explaining why I'm not signing up. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Okay. I don't, I don't think we're gonna get a great AI gadget that
Speaker 3:  everyone buys. Okay. I'm gonna, can I do my medium now? Sure,
Speaker 3:  please.
Speaker 2:  I So you're both out on mine.
Speaker 3:  I would like to respond to you just pick that as you're spicy. 'cause then
Speaker 3:  we can come back to it. Okay,
Speaker 4:  Fine. I'll add that to my spicy. Okay. Least pretty spicy and
Speaker 4:  appetizer
Speaker 3:  A chili's too.
Speaker 3:  Okay. My medium was that meta
Speaker 3:  releases another pair of the smart, the RayBan smart glasses.
Speaker 3:  But it has a display in it. It's like a heads up display. There's been rumors
Speaker 3:  of this and I guess the like more spicy
Speaker 3:  version of this is that meta continues to outpace apple
Speaker 3:  in the race for smart glasses.
Speaker 2:  Oh I'm extremely in on that one. I'm like, every day I become
Speaker 2:  more radicalized that Meta did this right. And Apple did this wrong. Like
Speaker 2:  the, the story of 2024 with
Speaker 3:  That, I'm writing a column about that right now and I believe that I'm, I
Speaker 3:  love the Raybans. I think the path they are taking is better than the path
Speaker 3:  Apple has been taking.
Speaker 4:  Okay. I agree with meta continues to outpace Apple. Yeah, yeah. Yeah. You,
Speaker 4:  I don't agree
Speaker 3:  With me on something.
Speaker 4:  I don't think the Raybans are, I sent mine back.
Speaker 2:  You
Speaker 3:  Don't how to use them.
Speaker 2:  You've a big head.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You don't know how to use them. That's not,
Speaker 2:  That's not
Speaker 4:  Fault. Are different ideas. You can't agree with him
Speaker 2:  What she said big head. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  If you have a big head and you know, know how to use that,
Speaker 4:  You're dumb. There's big head, tiny brain. I get it. I understand what you're
Speaker 4:  saying. Yes. Look, all of those things might be true
Speaker 4:  but I use them and this is some Apple stuff, right.
Speaker 4:  Where they won't let the photos automatically go to your phone. If you have
Speaker 4:  iOS, they will let you on Android course. Fine. I think the camera's like
Speaker 4:  just fine. Fine. The AI stuff is like extremely medium.
Speaker 3:  I could, I could take the rest
Speaker 2:  it actually, it not only doesn't add more appeal, it actually kills a bunch
Speaker 2:  of appeal. Because the thing that's nice about the ones now is they are mostly
Speaker 2:  just sunglasses.
Speaker 3:  Totally. I think they, they have to do something in between
Speaker 3:  what they've been showing with Orion and what they're, they've been doing
Speaker 3:  with the smart glasses. Yes. And that is very basic
Speaker 3:  information in your line of eye. And so
Speaker 2:  Just show me a text message. Right. That's
Speaker 3:  It. And that's where I think there's going to be AI potential. I don't think
Speaker 3:  that's a killer. I don't think people buy them because they're, they have
Speaker 3:  ai. Okay, that's fair. I's with you a little bit on the, like these gadgets
Speaker 3:  are gonna get better and I've said repeatedly the meta glasses are the best
Speaker 3:  AI gadget you can get because they're not only about ai.
Speaker 2:  So, okay. Wait for you. We're gonna move on from this, but we should move
Speaker 2:  on. But the, the, the raybans, it feels like it's the three things are
Speaker 2:  camera, mic slash speaker. Yep. Ai,
Speaker 2:  AI rank those three things for you personally.
Speaker 3:  Camera,
Speaker 3:  ai, audio.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. So for me it's audio first by a mile. Oh, and that's what things
Speaker 2:  and then camera and then ai. Yeah. Like I love them as like a pair of headphones
Speaker 2:  or for making, thats what they say for making calls and stuff like, and,
Speaker 2:  but I've found other people that are like, why would I just want to shout
Speaker 2:  air into the air when I have Yeah. I can just wear AirPods. It'll be fine.
Speaker 2:  Neela sent his back. So you don't get, you don't get to answer
Speaker 4:  That. You don't think that this is gonna run into the I use it to play music
Speaker 4:  and set timers problem.
Speaker 3:  No, I think it might,
Speaker 2:  But there are, there are worse things
Speaker 4:  Like smart speakers we're supposed to do all these things and
Speaker 4:  it's music and timers and you're like, oh, then this category kind of just
Speaker 4:  died.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And now it's on my face. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like I don't know if there's a worse thing than the, we spent a lot
Speaker 4:  of money to set Timer problem
Speaker 2:  Fair. And I mean, Amazon has been trying to find places to put Alexa on your
Speaker 2:  body for a long time and has not found it. Yeah. So, all right. We're, we're
Speaker 2:  all in on the specific one of Meta is going to continue to outpace
Speaker 2:  Apple on classes
Speaker 4:  But only 'cause Apple's not gonna launch
Speaker 2:  All right. We're back. Spicy takes, these are the ones, again,
Speaker 2:  there should be a chance that this comes true, but if it does come true,
Speaker 2:  you're not gonna shut up about it. Yep. Okay. Good. Yep. Everybody feel good?
Speaker 2:  All right. I guess I get to go first this time.
Speaker 2:  My spicy take for 2025 is that
Speaker 2:  everyone is gonna give up on matter and bail on the smart home.
Speaker 2:  And we're just gonna get to the end of the year and we're gonna
Speaker 2:  have like, individual smart gadgets and that'll be fine. But this idea of
Speaker 2:  like the, the big beautiful, interconnected smart home is going to cease
Speaker 2:  to be interesting to almost everybody. Okay.
Speaker 4:  Joanna, do you wanna respond to this As someone who just fixed your garage
Speaker 4:  after weeks of effort?
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah. We should talk about this actually. Oh, not garage. Can we just,
Speaker 2:  let's do, told you I wouldn't let do, let's just do a one minute Joanna interlude
Speaker 2:  on the garage because the, the people do want to know.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Can we get a music? Yeah. Can we get a music track under here?
Speaker 4:  You just assume there's music playing now.
Speaker 3:  Okay. It's happy. Like it needs to be a happy track. Like a
Speaker 3:  little bit like whimsical. You don't
Speaker 2:  The Six Flags theme
Speaker 4:  Song. I'll pick the music at a later time. You tell
Speaker 2:  I'm
Speaker 3:  Producing, I'm producing, I'm producing right now.
Speaker 3:  It happened.
Speaker 3:  My garage now opens. I can't say it because if I do
Speaker 3:  my, my phone will open my garage at
Speaker 3:  home. But when I say, hey blank,
Speaker 3:  open the garage. It happens. This is
Speaker 3:  after many weeks of texts to Eli
Speaker 3:  who responded three minutes Exactly after because
Speaker 3:  he scheduled them. Yep. This is after many weeks of people
Speaker 3:  responding on threads. Thank you all your all to all your
Speaker 3:  listeners.
Speaker 2:  We got a lot of feedback on the garage
Speaker 3:  Door, which Yes. And I would like to apologize.
Speaker 2:  Which range from you idiot. This is simple to, this is the hardest problem
Speaker 2:  in the history of the universe.
Speaker 4:  Outright conspiracy theories about cred FI's garage. Yes.
Speaker 3:  Well I believe those now I I've come to, I I
Speaker 3:  understand this landscape better than anybody. Yes. Maybe not as well as
Speaker 3:  you.
Speaker 3:  And it is a very hard problem to solve. So those people that call me an idiot,
Speaker 3:  you are actually an idiot,
Speaker 3:  but I just thank you to the listeners. You did it though. I
Speaker 4:  Did it. What'd you have to do?
Speaker 3:  Oh, we can't, it's too long. It's longer than a minute.
Speaker 4:  Just explain the little adapter that they sang.
Speaker 3:  Okay. I got the Miros Miros. What? How do you
Speaker 3:  pronounce it?
Speaker 4:  I think I always say Miros.
Speaker 3:  Miros. Okay. I got the Miros adapter. I get up on a ladder. I sent Eli a
Speaker 3:  picture. I was wearing my meta ray bands for both music and
Speaker 3:  for just taking photos and video of it. Therapy. Therapy.
Speaker 3:  It was using the calm app. Then we should get them as a sponsor.
Speaker 3:  That's a good idea. Yeah. I get up there, I get everything all set,
Speaker 3:  plug in into the sensor, put the sensor on the door. There's the whole complicated
Speaker 3:  kind of wiring, not that and it doesn't work. And
Speaker 3:  it turns out because my lift master is a newer
Speaker 3:  lift master from 2018, it is using some proprietary
Speaker 3:  protocol to talk to the door opener on the wall and it will not work. So
Speaker 4:  Dudes, they have DR md the garage door button and they have
Speaker 4:  labeled it a security feature.
Speaker 3:  And
Speaker 4:  It's very good. I, because I'm opening the door as a security feature.
Speaker 4:  Your garage door button.
Speaker 3:  I guess there was a way I could have known this earlier. Yeah. But I didn't
Speaker 3:  like go through all the support forums to know, because my learn button on
Speaker 3:  my lift master is yellow. And it turns out If you have the yellow button,
Speaker 3:  you cannot use this.
Speaker 4:  Then you have a DRM.
Speaker 3:  But Miros, the geniuses at Miros who I've not gotten
Speaker 3:  in touch with, but you are great people,
Speaker 3:  great people. They made a little adapter, which is really
Speaker 3:  just the opener, like the opener you'd put in your like car.
Speaker 3:  It's a hacked opener that connects to the Miros. And So
Speaker 3:  I didn't, I get it. They sent it to me in the mail and one week, again,
Speaker 3:  thank you to the people at Miros. Please sponsor this podcast.
Speaker 3:  I just love them.
Speaker 4:  Apparently they don't have enough money.
Speaker 4:  They're, they're making one hacked garage door repair a time,
Speaker 3:  One a day for me. Anyway, they send this to me, I set it
Speaker 3:  up and it works perfectly. Now
Speaker 4:  I just, can I, can I explain what's happening? I sent Joanna like a paragraph
Speaker 4:  excited paragraph of nerd speak. So they're like, okay we can't
Speaker 4:  Yeah, push the hardwired button 'cause it's dmd. Yes. But we can take a regular
Speaker 4:  garage door opener that is DRM
Speaker 4:  compatible with this and we'll just put a wire in the actual button
Speaker 4:  of that garage door opener. Oh wow. So that when you tell Siri to
Speaker 4:  I open the thing. Yes. It just does that. We'll push the button on the garage
Speaker 4:  door opener. So I just that from start coming out a garage door opener should
Speaker 4:  done from 'cause that is crazy. Can you imagine Craig Federighi
Speaker 4:  knowing any of this information when he's like, the future of
Speaker 4:  AI is my smart home. This is validating data.
Speaker 3:  I just wanna entire prediction tell that I told you I wouldn't do this and
Speaker 3:  I did not wanna go down this route. I just wanted to thank everyone and tell
Speaker 3:  them about my success.
Speaker 4:  She's very proud of her. I'm psyched
Speaker 3:  For, I'm very proud of myself. I now have Can
Speaker 4:  You, can you explain the, the one bug that you had to explain to me, which
Speaker 4:  is perfect. It didn't work right away. And why?
Speaker 3:  Well that was with the, oh no, that was with that.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 3:  Very good. Okay. So I go away. Well I don't even know why I was, I was in
Speaker 3:  LA and I set everything up and I thought it's working perfectly.
Speaker 3:  But yet the garage door keeps opening and closing randomly.
Speaker 3:  And my wife is texting me saying, who is opening and closing the garage door?
Speaker 3:  And I'm like, I, not me. It should be working. It turns out
Speaker 3:  when I pressed the learn button, it started picking up some signal
Speaker 3:  from someone around the neighborhood. So whenever they opened their garage,
Speaker 3:  oh my God, it opened my garage, which almost
Speaker 3:  led to divorce. So I had to get a garage guy
Speaker 3:  who then came to the house, helped me
Speaker 4:  Fix it. He's very, the song perfect.
Speaker 3:  And now it all works perfect.
Speaker 2:  All because you can't be bothered to push the button Yes. When you pull into
Speaker 2:  the driveway. But
Speaker 3:  You know what the amount, like this is where we need some music.
Speaker 3:  The amount of happiness and true pride. I feel now
Speaker 3:  when I pull out of my garage and say, Hey
Speaker 3:  Siri, open the garage door is, I may
Speaker 3:  have never felt it before.
Speaker 2:  And then 15 minutes later it just starts randomly closing and opening on
Speaker 2:  its own.
Speaker 3:  That hasn't happened in at least two weeks. That's,
Speaker 2:  I'm thrilled for you. We really, the smart home is getting to the point
Speaker 2:  of humanoid robots to stand in your garage and push buttons. And that
Speaker 4:  Is stupid. Yeah, that's by the way, this is door bot. Yes. You could have
Speaker 4:  just put a door bot on the actual garage door button.
Speaker 3:  But just back to what you're saying, this is why I don't think, I mean
Speaker 4:  Switch bot, not door bot,
Speaker 3:  I don't think Matter disappears. I think we actually see these tech companies
Speaker 3:  double down on it. I think they're all gonna start talking about how AI is
Speaker 3:  gonna be great for the smart home. And we're gonna hear it with that Alexa
Speaker 3:  announcement. It's just like all these things and this is the dream and our
Speaker 3:  robots and the, and the house is connected and none of it is actually
Speaker 3:  really material to real people because they have old
Speaker 3:  shit and they have different standards. And
Speaker 3:  there's DRM in the freaking button on the wall
Speaker 3:  and it doesn't work. And I think we're gonna hear from Apple this year because
Speaker 3:  they're apparently working on this home tablet. And I think they're gonna
Speaker 3:  push matter and they're gonna say it's, they have
Speaker 4:  To push, they have no choice but to push matters. Right.
Speaker 3:  And no becausecause,
Speaker 4:  They not an e system of these devices matters.
Speaker 3:  And a lot of these devices don't even have matter.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 3:  Anyway.
Speaker 4:  You just think they're gonna give up. You think,
Speaker 2:  I don't know that they're gonna, I just think everyone is going to stop caring
Speaker 2:  in in every me like I
Speaker 3:  Think they did. Stop caring maybe.
Speaker 2:  But I, I like even the companies themselves who have been making these
Speaker 2:  long elaborate bets that eventually the smart home is going to become a thing
Speaker 2:  that is like mainstream useful. I think everybody's just gonna start walking
Speaker 2:  away from that next year. It's 'cause it's just not gonna happen.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean when you get a new house
Speaker 2:  Light switches kick ass, it's probably fine. We've probably solved light
Speaker 2:  switches. I don't know that we need to worry about them anymore.
Speaker 4:  No. Enough of the light switches in our house are are smart and
Speaker 4:  do things. Yeah. Just all on their own. That
Speaker 4:  actually, once you get used to it, you're like, oh, this rules. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 4:  Like there's one level up, we're like, oh this is great.
Speaker 2:  My Rube Goldberg machine works really well is like a perfectly viable,
Speaker 4:  It's not a Rub Goldberg machine. It's, it's, they're just, I just bought
Speaker 4:  some Lutron Cas and put them in the wall and now when the sun sets
Speaker 4:  our house slice,
Speaker 3:  Will they sponsor this podcast?
Speaker 4:  I don't know. Well, they, they have so much money that they own a custom
Speaker 4:  slice of RF spectrum, which is why their products work the best. Oh, there
Speaker 4:  go. It's a real thing, but I don't know if they wanna spend the money.
Speaker 3:  You like those don't even go on sale. Black Fri they just don't go on sale.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. 'cause they have their own RF spectrum and they have the best problem.
Speaker 2:  What are you gonna do?
Speaker 4:  This is a real thing. They bought their own slice of RF spectrum that Brendan
Speaker 4:  Carr Trump's new commissioner of the FCC is gonna turn over to Elon Musk
Speaker 3:  When you interview him. I want you to ask about Lutron Casitas.
Speaker 4:  Brendan, if you're listening and I know you are, come on the, come on the
Speaker 4:  show. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I'd, we'd love to have you tell
Speaker 4:  Me how your garage door works. All right.
Speaker 3:  You If you own a house. I do. You own a house? Yeah. Okay. I was gonna say
Speaker 3:  like, if this is the year 2025 that David buys a house,
Speaker 4:  Actually a good, a good prediction here, like an ancillary prediction to
Speaker 4:  yours is no one will come up with a smart home idea that compels you,
Speaker 4:  David Pierce, owner of the most garbage TV in America
Speaker 4:  to do any smart home thing. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I love that. Right.
Speaker 4:  That's the, because like I have a whole smart home. It's just doing stuff
Speaker 4:  all the time.
Speaker 3:  And I'm slowly trying to be neli like he's my, he's
Speaker 3:  my mentor of the smart home.
Speaker 2:  Neli has never once described a use case and an amount
Speaker 2:  of work to get to that use case that has ever made sense to me.
Speaker 3:  I just described the garage to you and it is perfect.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's super not good enough.
Speaker 3:  It is so good. What do you mean? I just sat next
Speaker 2:  To you. My wife texted me and said, why is the garage door
Speaker 2:  opening and closing by itself?
Speaker 3:  But then our wives
Speaker 2:  Can talk to each other. It not applicable solution to my house.
Speaker 4:  You don't, you don't want to build a relationship on that. That's not the
Speaker 4:  foundation of relationship. That's good for anyone's marriage.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's bad times all the way around. Alright, so you're, you're both
Speaker 2:  out on mine. This is great,
Speaker 2:  Joanna. I do
Speaker 3:  Be, I mean, I do believe it's gonna be a big topic next year. So
Speaker 3:  that's,
Speaker 2:  I hope So. I mean,
Speaker 4:  To be clear, David's prediction is everyone walks away from matter. That's
Speaker 4:  your specific prediction. I, I'm out. Yeah. I
Speaker 3:  Don't think that matter.
Speaker 4:  They're,
Speaker 3:  They're all in on it. Great. Yeah, they can't, they have nothing else to
Speaker 3:  do. I wish. I mean, I don't wish, I don't, I, anyway, okay. My spicy
Speaker 3:  one,
Speaker 3:  the Mac gets a touch screen.
Speaker 4:  Oh, we've done this like every year. I know. Every time we've done predictions
Speaker 4:  together, someone has done this. I know.
Speaker 3:  And we'll go, I think I'm trying to find The Vergecast transcripts of the
Speaker 3:  time I predicted and I can't find it, but I believe I said by the end of
Speaker 3:  2024,
Speaker 4:  I think the last time we did this, we, we set timelines and we were all wrong.
Speaker 3:  We were, Dieter was on the, on the podcast. Yeah. And, but I,
Speaker 3:  I, I, I think we are coming towards that time.
Speaker 3:  One day we will get there and I I think
Speaker 2:  25, is it just a Mac as you currently imagine it, but
Speaker 2:  it's a touchscreen? Or does it change more meaningfully than that?
Speaker 3:  They'll have to do something.
Speaker 2:  What do they do?
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 2:  Don't know. Does it run iPad apps?
Speaker 3:  It already runs
Speaker 2:  IPad apps. Well, like, like does it just get the iPad app store natively?
Speaker 3:  Mm. No, I think they just keep it that way. Okay.
Speaker 2:  I'm just looking at these touch targets being like, eh, I don't really want
Speaker 2:  to poke my menu bar that. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I don't think they do it until they know why they're doing it. I wanna scroll
Speaker 4:  and I don't know that they even know why they make the iPad. Right.
Speaker 4:  Do you like the I the iPad is an application environment. They're not like,
Speaker 4:  here's why. They're just like, well, that keeps happening.
Speaker 4:  And they, I don't think they're gonna add cost and complexity to the Mac
Speaker 4:  unless they have like a great reason to do it. And they seem to
Speaker 4:  be selling enough Macs. I'm walking this all the way back. 'cause I thought,
Speaker 4:  but you don't think were gonna do it. I thought I, the last time we did this,
Speaker 4:  I thought that they had reached a point with the Mac and the iPad where
Speaker 4:  bringing them closer together was the only choice. Yep. And they have not
Speaker 4:  only resisted that, they pulled them further apart to the point where everyone's
Speaker 4:  just like turned this iPad into a Mac.
Speaker 2:  I think Apple silicon changed that. Like I think if, if Apple
Speaker 2:  hadn't solved like laptop processing,
Speaker 2:  it would've been different and the Macs would've started to look more like
Speaker 2:  the iPads and vice versa. But now, like the, the
Speaker 2:  Mac lineup is easily the best it's ever been. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  is so compelling to so many people. Like Yeah. I I tend to
Speaker 2:  agree. I, I years ago would've thought that eventually the
Speaker 2:  MacBook and the iPad in particular would eventually be the same product.
Speaker 2:  I don't think that anymore.
Speaker 4:  I think i I the spicy follow up,
Speaker 4:  whatever that is, the dip conman hot sauce.
Speaker 4:  If, If you could turn your Mac into an
Speaker 4:  iPad and gain touchscreen support Yes. Or you could turn
Speaker 4:  your iPad into a Mac in the lose touchscreen support, which one would you,
Speaker 4:  which one would you pick?
Speaker 3:  I can take my Mac. What was the first option?
Speaker 4:  So you have your Mac sitting right here. Yes. And I can take it up and I
Speaker 4:  can push a button and be like, now this is an iPad and you get a touch screen
Speaker 4:  and I
Speaker 3:  Can take the screen off.
Speaker 4:  No. Whatever. It's, it's just that it can run iPad apps, but it has a touchscreen.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's an iPad. And the other one is you got an iPad and a keyboard case
Speaker 4:  and you're like, boom, hit a button. It runs Macs but the touchscreen
Speaker 4:  stops working.
Speaker 2:  It's that,
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 4:  Guess that, see what I'm
Speaker 2:  Saying? I want a dockable iPad much more than I want a Touch Mac.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And there's a bunch of stuff you have to do. Like, it, it would have to essentially
Speaker 2:  like run the two operating systems side by side. No,
Speaker 4:  I'm saying I'm, I'm, I'm making this hardcore. Okay. You push
Speaker 4:  the button. This is now runs iPad os Yeah.
Speaker 2:  With a touchscreen. With
Speaker 4:  A touchscreen. With it Doesn it's a Mac. Right. But
Speaker 3:  Then when you run Mac os it disables the touchscreen.
Speaker 4:  No, it doesn't run Mac os I'm saying this just becomes an iPad. Mm.
Speaker 4:  Or you could take your iPad and you can run Mac Os and it disables the touchscreen.
Speaker 4:  Which
Speaker 2:  One? It's definitely an iPad with Mac os.
Speaker 4:  See what I'm saying? And I think,
Speaker 3:  No
Speaker 4:  Question. Same. This is just the end of the argument I think for a long time.
Speaker 4:  'cause they don't know why any, they don't know why any of these products
Speaker 4:  have touchscreens.
Speaker 2:  Right.
Speaker 4:  Except for the iPhone. I I know why the iPhone has a touchscreen. They have
Speaker 4:  not yet solved the problem of why the iPad
Speaker 3:  Has. So maybe I'm changing mine to that the iPad can
Speaker 3:  run Mac os.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's the only rational answer.
Speaker 3:  Okay. But that to me, it seems the same thing. Mac gets a touchscreen still
Speaker 3:  Mac os getting a touchscreen. I'll
Speaker 2:  Give, I'll give you both as one prediction. Okay. That, that one of those
Speaker 2:  two things will happen. That the, the, the Mac, Mac I, Mac, I mean it's really,
Speaker 2:  it's like the Venn diagram, the Mac, that's why Mac and the iPad smash into
Speaker 2:  each other. I
Speaker 4:  Think they have figured out they can sell a lot of both. Yes. And they don't
Speaker 4:  have to solve this problem and there's no pressure on them to solve the problem
Speaker 4:  until there's some sort of Windows tablet or Android tablet
Speaker 4:  that print provides an ounce of competition to the iPad. And I know, like
Speaker 4:  I know there are Windows tablets and people like them and the surface exists
Speaker 4:  and that's a whole thing. They're not competition to the iPad. There are
Speaker 4:  competition to the MacBook,
Speaker 3:  To the Mac. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Until there's one sliver of competition for the things that people use
Speaker 4:  iPads for, they are just gonna stay exactly the way they're
Speaker 2:  I didn't agree. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I was my other spicy one.
Speaker 2:  You can't talk yourself out of your own connection.
Speaker 3:  No, no. My other, no, I really want that to happen. That's why it's spicy
Speaker 3:  and that's why it's there. But my other spicy was gonna be that Tim Cook
Speaker 3:  steps down and then they, the Mac gets the touchscreen.
Speaker 4:  Ooh. Tim Cook can't step down, I don't think
Speaker 3:  On president. Don't think I know. It's like, it's, it's really
Speaker 4:  He's gotta call him every day and be like, like, I need you to not
Speaker 3:  Do these tariffs. No, I think they just broaden.
Speaker 4:  Do you understand what I'm saying, Donald? That this time you cannot do tariffs.
Speaker 4:  You like your iPhone, right? I can turn that off. No tariffs. And he's just
Speaker 4:  gotta do that every single day.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. All right. Last, and these has to stay Neli. What is
Speaker 2:  your spiciest prediction?
Speaker 4:  This is
Speaker 2:  Wild. Full spice. This is wild. Hit me with it. Google
Speaker 4:  Breaks itself up.
Speaker 2:  Oh,
Speaker 4:  Okay. They're just like, you know what? This is not worth it anymore. We're
Speaker 4:  just gonna, we're gonna, we're gonna spin off our own companies.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  This is the opposite of merger mania, which is a thing big
Speaker 4:  companies do to create shareholder value. Sure. When they're out
Speaker 4:  of ideas, I think Google is just gonna look at the marketplace
Speaker 4:  and say that we're under a lot of regulatory pressure. And you know what
Speaker 4:  if we just spun off YouTube,
Speaker 4:  just put it over there, signed a big lucrative AI training data
Speaker 4:  deal for Google AI and let this thing go be cable, the future
Speaker 4:  of cable television and compete with TikTok and whatever.
Speaker 4:  And we'll, that'll go public and the stock will go up and Google stock will
Speaker 4:  go up and everyone's stock will go up. And that's all anybody cares about.
Speaker 4:  You can make the argument today absent the antitrust pressure and
Speaker 4:  you get to take YouTube away from the antitrust pressure. Right. And the
Speaker 4:  regulatory pressure, because now it's just
Speaker 2:  YouTube. Does that solve? But does that Yeah. Google's antitrust problems
Speaker 2:  though.
Speaker 4:  I have no idea. This is my spicy take. Okay.
Speaker 2:  But like,
Speaker 3:  Does that solve the scrutiny of Chrome and the ad?
Speaker 4:  Right. So all that's noise, right? It doesn't solve those problems. It
Speaker 4:  just takes YouTube away from them.
Speaker 2:  Hmm. Right. And it lets Google say we've made ourselves
Speaker 2:  smaller and less powerful because now the second most powerful search engine
Speaker 2:  on the internet doesn't belong to us anymore. Yeah. It's over here. It's
Speaker 4:  YouTube and we can, you know, the fact that we all work together and we're
Speaker 4:  friends and sometimes I call each other on the phone and who knows what messaging
Speaker 4:  app we're using that's communicate because we want not only delete all of
Speaker 4:  our records, we have too many messaging apps for you. And see there's a,
Speaker 4:  that's my spiciest take is Google solves this problem the way that
Speaker 4:  big conglomerates solve this problem.
Speaker 2:  What if Google does all of its like secret messaging just on
Speaker 2:  aloe because they know no one is paying attention. You don't even have like,
Speaker 2:  no lawyer would ever think to like subpoena the aloe messages.
Speaker 2:  So that's just where Google is
Speaker 4:  Now. Yeah. They're just like one of their, this is why they've had so many,
Speaker 4:  right. It's
Speaker 3:  Long game Was a before Duo Chat or meet?
Speaker 4:  No, it was after Duo
Speaker 2:  Was Alo was with Duo. They launched Alo and Duo together and Alo was Duo
Speaker 2:  was the first one that was like, we're gonna put AI inside of your chats.
Speaker 2:  So when you say, do you wanna go to the movies, it's like, oh, would you
Speaker 2:  like to buy movie tickets? And that was a super good idea that everyone liked
Speaker 2:  and it went really well for Google. That was
Speaker 2:  10 years ago, ages ago. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  The number of Dieter Bone we have sorted out Google's messaging strategy
Speaker 4:  stories that we bring. Yeah, it has, here it is. Here's the
Speaker 4:  plan by Dieter.
Speaker 4:  None of them came to bass. That's my spiciest tick.
Speaker 2:  That's pretty good. I'm out on that one. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It no one should set up my mistake.
Speaker 2:  I think, I think If you had said,
Speaker 4:  But to your point, if I, if I'm right. No, everyone will. Oh, you'll never
Speaker 4:  hear the end of this.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. You, they have to make you the CEO of YouTube if, if, if
Speaker 2:  you're right now officially they have to do it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I think, I think If you had said Google breaks up in 2025,
Speaker 2:  I might have thought long and hard about signing on, but Google does it of
Speaker 2:  its own volition.
Speaker 4:  That's why it's I love it. But someone breaks up Google. Yeah. Fine. It's,
Speaker 4:  it's, it's, we're headed that way. Google itself is like, you know what,
Speaker 4:  this is really hard. Yeah. It's just YouTube. You go have fun,
Speaker 4:  create some shareholder value.
Speaker 2:  It's for the good of the people. Yeah. All right. This is great stuff. All
Speaker 2:  right, let me review and then we're gonna get outta here. Joanna's predictions,
Speaker 2:  her mild prediction is that a year from now, we're all still gonna be posting
Speaker 2:  to a million social accounts. I'm in on that. Neil's out.
Speaker 2:  Your medium take is that meta is going to continue to outpace Apple on glasses.
Speaker 2:  Neela and I are both in. And your spicy one is that the
Speaker 2:  touchscreen Mac and the iPad with Mac os some
Speaker 2:  smashing together thing is gonna happen there. Neela and I are both
Speaker 2:  out. I hope to, the one I most hope I'm wrong about is that one, because
Speaker 2:  I want that to happen so bad. If
Speaker 3:  That happens and we're at an event together, I will stand up and cheer.
Speaker 2:  I I deservedly so that will be a good victory that for Yeah, like imagine
Speaker 2:  if Apple had made a television, how insufferable Gene Munster would've been.
Speaker 2:  Like, that's what I want for you if
Speaker 3:  This happens. I have never clapped at an Apple event. I believe the on, sorry,
Speaker 3:  I'll take that back. I believe I might have clapped when they announced multiple
Speaker 3:  timers and I've never ever clapped at an Apple event
Speaker 3:  other than that. But I will clap. I will,
Speaker 2:  But then you have to say out loud, to be clear, I'm clapping for myself.
Speaker 2:  Yes. And then
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Right. Okay.
Speaker 3:  Journalism.
Speaker 2:  I love it. All right. NE's predictions, the mild prediction Alexa is going
Speaker 2:  to be fine. Yeah. Yeah. I even put the ellipsis in here. It's
Speaker 2:  gonna be fine. Fine. That's fine. I'm out and Joanna's out.
Speaker 4:  That's rough.
Speaker 3:  I think it's probably true, but I'm hoping, I'm betting against
Speaker 2:  The medium take is Walmart is gonna buy TikTok. Strangely, Joanna and I are
Speaker 2:  both in on this. I love it. And the
Speaker 2:  spicy take is the Google breaks itself up.
Speaker 3:  We are not in,
Speaker 2:  I'm giving you all versions of breakups, even though you specified
Speaker 2:  YouTube. I think, oh,
Speaker 4:  Any, any Google
Speaker 2:  Breaks itself up in any meaningful way. Okay. That's nice to idea. Spicy
Speaker 2:  enough that I'm giving you the whole take as
Speaker 4:  Long as it's by its own volition. Correct.
Speaker 2:  Okay. That's nice. And Joanna and I are both out,
Speaker 4:  But I, I will, that means I will take any little thing. Yep.
Speaker 4:  Right, because Google is also Alphabet.
Speaker 3:  That's right. So if Waymo
Speaker 4:  Right, if they're, yeah. Waymo.
Speaker 2:  Waymo's not part of Google.
Speaker 3:  It's part of Alphabet. And I, I don't think that's ridiculous.
Speaker 4:  You have to decide.
Speaker 2:  No, I'll, I'm, I'm still out and I'll so give it to you. Okay. Any, any
Speaker 2:  alphabet company, but not, not one of the stupid moonshots that loses billions
Speaker 2:  of dollars. I'll give you Waymo. That's basically the only other one I'm
Speaker 2:  willing to give you. Fine. My predictions are, my
Speaker 2:  mild prediction is that cable TV is going to pretty much totally die.
Speaker 2:  Eli's out Joanna's in.
Speaker 4:  I still don't know what that means. I'm in, if, if the most generous reading
Speaker 4:  is like we stop talking about
Speaker 2:  It. If I just, if I just make it the cable box, business
Speaker 2:  is dead and boring, would would you be into it? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But that because it's already true. Like we should all just take the point
Speaker 4:  today. It's though,
Speaker 2:  It's not true. All right. It's boring already, but it's not dead.
Speaker 2:  And, and I think it, it, it got boring faster than anybody expected and I
Speaker 2:  think it's gonna get dead faster than anybody expects.
Speaker 4:  I think our minority investor Comcast requires me to tell you the Xfinity
Speaker 4:  X one box is cool.
Speaker 2:  Also, disclosure Neli produced a Netflix show.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Something. Subscribe to The Verge. I don't know. It's pretty,
Speaker 4:  It's pretty
Speaker 2:  Good. Yeah. All right. Do you want to end on this one? This is your last
Speaker 2:  chance.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'll, I'll take it.
Speaker 2:  Keep in mind that I'm deciding. Yeah, I know.
Speaker 4:  You're gonna give yourself this point somehow and it's like fine.
Speaker 2:  All right. Neli. Joan's in my medium take is that
Speaker 2:  someone is gonna make an AI gadget that actually kicks ass. You're both out.
Speaker 2:  Yep. And my spicy take is that the industry and the world are going to
Speaker 2:  collectively give up on matter and you're both out,
Speaker 4:  Out, super
Speaker 2:  Out. Love it. Alright.
Speaker 4:  I think a thing that I don't understand is how many points have we all potentially,
Speaker 4:  I don up
Speaker 3:  Understand, Don understand this game at all.
Speaker 2:  Who's to say I got 12 months to figure out the answer to that question? What
Speaker 2:  do you win If you win?
Speaker 4:  I'm saying if Google breaks itself up, I win. Yeah. Whatever that is. If,
Speaker 4:  if I call that one right, Google
Speaker 2:  Does voluntary
Speaker 4:  Spin also there
Speaker 2:  Be more points for spicier takes. Yes.
Speaker 3:  But if, yeah, he had so many spicy takes and then he also had that spice,
Speaker 3:  I think that should be disqualified. The Joanne
Speaker 2:  Ai Joanna's so mad at how much you got to talk.
Speaker 4:  I've already,
Speaker 3:  The AI means nothing and AI is a failure of what it was. Your other one?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, the bubble pops. The bubble pops. No,
Speaker 4:  That's not on the list.
Speaker 2:  No. Neli doesn't get to have that one. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Okay, good. That's
Speaker 2:  Just
Speaker 4:  AI is Bluetooth. Not, we
Speaker 3:  Should delete from the podcast. AI is Bluetooth. Yeah, Bluetooth. That's
Speaker 2:  Too spicy for this
Speaker 4:  Podcast. Delete it. It's funny 'cause Bluetooth like never had a bubble that
Speaker 4:  popped. Everyone was just kind of like, yeah, it's just not happening.
Speaker 3:  I think a lot of people think Bluetooth happened.
Speaker 4:  Do you find one person who thinks Bluetooth happened? Like in the way
Speaker 4:  that people thought it would happen?
Speaker 2:  Right. Bluetooth happened in the sense that it's here and you use it. Right?
Speaker 4:  Sometimes it works in your car and some people have one of those
Speaker 4:  ee boom speakers.
Speaker 2:  But like,
Speaker 4:  And that's it.
Speaker 2:  Is there a hundred billion dollar Bluetooth startup out there? Like probably
Speaker 2:  not. Right?
Speaker 2:  If that is you, please email me. I
Speaker 4:  Wanna know there like Bluetooth was at the point where there were like meaningful
Speaker 4:  Bluetooth security threats.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Remember there was like Blue Snaring.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I do rem I think there was a whole CES where it was really just
Speaker 4:  Bluetooth stuff.
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth stuff. The Happy Fork.
Speaker 4:  Yep.
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth.
Speaker 4:  And it just didn't happen.
Speaker 3:  It was Bluetooth. Yeah. I mean, but some of it really did happen.
Speaker 4:  I once sat through an entire press event where they told me that they would
Speaker 4:  combine Bluetooth and wifi so that you would use Bluetooth to pair to
Speaker 4:  a gadget that would then provision it for wifi and you would get the best
Speaker 4:  of both worlds and
Speaker 3:  Look at Apple's whole
Speaker 4:  Strategy. And maybe that sort of worked and maybe it exists, it did not.
Speaker 3:  I know that you wanna say like, okay, yes, apple added their things to
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth to make it better clearly, but AirPods,
Speaker 4:  Right? They made up a fake, fake Bluetooth and layered it on top of Bluetooth
Speaker 4:  and no one else gets to use it. But without
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth
Speaker 4:  And their entire, their entire explanation for why they have
Speaker 4:  locked down the, what's it now they're onto like the H two chip Yep.
Speaker 4:  Is because Bluetooth isn't good enough. So they had to make their own
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth, but there's Bluetooth in there. Apple
Speaker 2:  Would love to get rid of Bluetooth and, and just connect the Apple devices
Speaker 2:  to the Apple head front.
Speaker 3:  The Apple watch, I mean, these are massive businesses that Bluetooth were,
Speaker 3:  I get what you're saying.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Apple made a set of proprietary extensions to Bluetooth in order to
Speaker 4:  make those things happen. There's
Speaker 3:  A Bluetooth underpinning.
Speaker 4:  All right. And, and maybe one day there'll be an AI underpinning.
Speaker 2:  I'm giving us all,
Speaker 4:  But the
Speaker 2:  AI is, Bluetooth is a take. We're all in
Speaker 3:  AI's not Bluetooth. It's,
Speaker 2:  It's out
Speaker 4:  A, the bubble will pop on. AI is actually the thing, and I'm just making
Speaker 4:  a
Speaker 2:  Comparison. I'm saying, okay, AI is Bluetooth, we're all in. And the specific
Speaker 2:  comparison is,
Speaker 3:  So we're not putting that in. That's not even a spicy cake. It's not allowed.
Speaker 4:  And all that's gonna happen is we're gonna, we're gonna be here next year,
Speaker 4:  we're gonna talk about this take. And someone's gonna say, well, it'll be
Speaker 4:  better next year, which is all they ever said about Bluetooth. That's the
Speaker 4:  only comparison that makes. Okay.
Speaker 3:  Okay. That
Speaker 2:  I like it. All right. We're gonna do the Smart Home. We're gonna do one more
Speaker 2:  of these next week. We have some other fun 2025 prediction stuff to do,
Speaker 2:  but for now, we're done. Thank you all. Appreciate you guys doing this with
Speaker 2:  me. That's
Speaker 1:  Me. Classic. I already won.
Speaker 2:  All right. That's it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to Neli and Joanna
Speaker 2:  for playing this very silly game with me. And thank you as always for listening.
Speaker 2:  There's lots more on, frankly all of the stuff we've been making predictions
Speaker 2:  about all over The Verge dot com. I'll put some links in the show notes,
Speaker 2:  as many as I can think of. But keep it locked on the website. Clearly.
Speaker 2:  2025 is gonna be a year. We have a subscription now. Fun Time to
Speaker 2:  subscribe to The Verge. There's just a lot that is coming. And as always,
Speaker 2:  check out the homepage. It's free, it's awesome. Have a peek and If you haveve
Speaker 2:  thoughts, questions, feelings, or other predictions for 2025, you'd like
Speaker 2:  to get off your chest, you can always email us at Vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com or call the hotline eight six six VERGE one one. We truly love
Speaker 2:  hearing from you. Thank you to everybody who's called in with questions for
Speaker 2:  the meta hotline that's running on Tuesday. Tons of fun stuff. That's a really
Speaker 2:  fun episode. Really enjoyed doing that. And If you have more questions, keep
Speaker 2:  'em coming. We have a backlog of really, really fun ones. We have plans to
Speaker 2:  do stuff with. Hit me up. I'm ready for it. This show is produced by Liam
Speaker 2:  James Wil Pour and Eric Gomez. Vergecast is VERGE Production and part of
Speaker 2:  the Vox Media podcast network. We'll be back on Tuesday with the meta episode
Speaker 2:  that we've been talking about for a while, and then back to our regularly
Speaker 2:  scheduled programming for a couple of weeks before the end of the year. We'll
Speaker 2:  see you then. Rock and roll