# Transcript
ID: 99da5fa0-a0d6-412a-9d16-773d89845f5a
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/9219709712048301942/8809756417545686388/s93290-US-5756s-1705672946.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Victoria Song, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss the Apple Vision Pro demo, the Samsung Galaxy S24 announcement, and more of this week's tech news.
Watch the video here
Speaker 1:  The enduring appeal of Donald Trump explained by fan
Speaker 1:  culture.
Speaker 2:  It's human nature to, to love being in a community of people who are all
Speaker 2:  excited about the same thing you are. Whether that's people getting excited
Speaker 2:  about Jesus on a Sunday morning, or people getting excited about Taylor
Speaker 2:  Swift on a Saturday night.
Speaker 1:  What happens when supporters become stands? That's
Speaker 1:  this week on the weeds.
Speaker 4:  The Great Pacific garbage patch is made up of over a trillion pieces of
Speaker 4:  plastic. But two scientists recently stumbled on
Speaker 4:  something else, something that seemed impossible.
Speaker 2:  Both of us were just like, you know, like what?
Speaker 5:  It was an
Speaker 2:  Uhoh moment. It blew our minds
Speaker 4:  This week on unexplainable. What do you do when the garbage threatening life
Speaker 4:  in the ocean becomes its own ecosystem?
Speaker 4:  Listen to unexplainable new episodes every Wednesday.
Speaker 6:  Hello and Welcome. To Vergecast, the flagship podcast, spatial Computing,
Speaker 6:  A form of computing that is all around you at all times.
Speaker 6:  And see center
Speaker 8:  It sneaks up on you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's Apple's Dream is to have
Speaker 6:  just Eddie Van Halen just creeping, creeping
Speaker 6:  eruption. Hi, I'm Mila. I'm your friend. David Pierce is here.
Speaker 8:  Hi don. Don't know how to follow eruption, but here we are. I
Speaker 6:  Guess. I mean, isn't that, that's the, that's the goal of all computing.
Speaker 6:  The purpose of computers is to make great art and emotional experiences.
Speaker 6:  I strongly believe this to be true. And what you, to do that most
Speaker 6:  effectively, you have to design state of the art.
Speaker 6:  4K ole displays, micro ole displays, two micron pixels.
Speaker 6:  You have to convince the entire music industry to support Dolby Atmos.
Speaker 6:  And then you have to convince people to wear the ski goggles so that
Speaker 6:  Jimmy Page can just creeping, creeping.
Speaker 6:  Think about it,
Speaker 6:  you know, like 20 years from now, that reference won't make any sense. And
Speaker 6:  we'll be like, and then Halsey will be creeping. Creeping. And that will
Speaker 8:  NELI. I gotta tell you, none of what you just said made any sense. Now
Speaker 6:  So,
Speaker 8:  So we're, we're starting. I
Speaker 6:  Just imagine today's pop stars in the context of that joke. Like
Speaker 6:  the point of technology is for Taylor Swift to just creep
Speaker 6:  up on you from behind. Alex. Cranz is here. Hi Alex.
Speaker 7:  I'm just wondering what the shoe situation is like. Like do they have to
Speaker 7:  think about the shoes they wear when they creep up on you? Is that part of
Speaker 7:  the spatial audio experience?
Speaker 6:  Yes, it's a hundred percent true that Jimmy Page has to wear very
Speaker 6:  quiet ninja shoes. The shoes with the toes.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. In Bill Atmos, for some reason Victoria's Song has
Speaker 6:  chosen to join us today.
Speaker 9:  I, I'm here and I don't know why Radiohead isn't doing the creeping.
Speaker 6:  They were, I mean like Shoegaze was a, a very quiet
Speaker 6:  form of
Speaker 6:  the shoe. I mean like they had to look at their shoes. That's the joke that
Speaker 6:  I'm trying to make.
Speaker 6:  That's, that's what I'm saying. Because they had so many guitar pedals. This
Speaker 6:  is an entire genre of music that was named after
Speaker 6:  Nerds looking at their feet.
Speaker 8:  Apple and Apple's bringing it back. Apples. That's, that's, that's where
Speaker 8:  we got
Speaker 6:  Her. Alright. Quite a lot happened this week. Actually. The real reason Victoria
Speaker 6:  is here is 'cause she and I went and saw the Vision Pro.
Speaker 6:  I saw it for the second time. Victoria saw it for the first time. There's
Speaker 6:  a lot to talk about with that demo
Speaker 6:  why Apple gave a whole bunch of the same demo over again to a lot of people.
Speaker 6:  Then Samsung had Galaxy unpacked. They announced the S 24, which is full
Speaker 6:  of ai. There's a smart Ring v covers,
Speaker 6:  wearables we gotta talk to to her about the smart ring. I got a lightning
Speaker 6:  round by the way, mark Zuckerberg just sort of appeared on our website this
Speaker 6:  week creeping, creeping and announced that Meta is the purpose
Speaker 6:  of Meta is now to build a GI, which you will recall. He
Speaker 6:  renamed the entire company Meta to build the Metaverse. Didn't rename the
Speaker 6:  company this time, but he just sort of appeared and said, Alex Heath, it's
Speaker 6:  a GI now. And Alex said what? We'll talk about that as well.
Speaker 8:  Can you imagine how cool a move it would be if he just renamed the company
Speaker 8:  like AI Incorporated? Yes.
Speaker 6:  That's all in want. I mean we're not, we're not far off.
Speaker 9:  It took me so long to call it Meta from Facebook. It's
Speaker 9:  not gonna make it a second Leap to AI be amazing incorporated.
Speaker 6:  There's some moves you only get to pull once in renaming the
Speaker 6:  company is one of those moves. Like you gotta this clock restarts.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, you got another 15 years before you can be like, you know what, actually
Speaker 6:  Meta was the wrong name, but we can talk about all that. Let's start
Speaker 6:  with the Vision. Pro.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Well and I actually, I, I think we should start with your experience
Speaker 8:  having this experience NELI Envy because this was a
Speaker 8:  weird hands-on experience. Like we, we get a lot of these
Speaker 8:  where we sit in a room and somebody gives us a demo of a thing. But the two
Speaker 8:  of you had this odd experience where for the first time,
Speaker 8:  this is very strange and I hadn't really thought about it until it happened.
Speaker 8:  Regular humans were photographed wearing the Vision
Speaker 8:  Pro and so all over the internet this week, this has like become a meme of
Speaker 8:  a bunch of like reporters doing the pinchy pinch gesture.
Speaker 8:  And there's been like, you know, drips and drabs of information about how
Speaker 8:  this actually went. But I think the way Apple is rolling this thing out and
Speaker 8:  showing it to people is actually really interesting. So can you guys just
Speaker 8:  sort of tell the story of your day with the Vision Pro V It was your experience.
Speaker 8:  So like walk us through it to begin with here.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, so you know, I had read Eli's writeup of the
Speaker 9:  demo he got at WW DC So I
Speaker 8:  Eli's Fever Dream Hands, hands-on,
Speaker 9:  You know, this is my fever Dreams hands-on this time around. 'cause
Speaker 9:  literally 24 hours after it happened I was like, did that actually happen
Speaker 9:  or did I fever dream this all up? I, I wasn't entirely
Speaker 9:  sure but I felt like the imprint, the ghost imprint of the Vision Pro
Speaker 9:  on my forehead for a full 24 hours afterwards. So
Speaker 9:  yeah, it did happen. But yeah, NELI was the only one who wasn't pinchy pinching
Speaker 9:  in the photos. So can
Speaker 6:  I, I'll just, I'm just gonna say this very directly. The purpose of this
Speaker 6:  is very clear. Apple wanted to be in control of the first photos of
Speaker 6:  people wearing the Vision Pro. I am fundamentally
Speaker 6:  uncomfortable with the trade that we made here and that everyone else made
Speaker 6:  because we went to the thing. They didn't tell us they were going to give
Speaker 6:  us photos to walk out with. We did the demo. Demo is really interesting.
Speaker 6:  I'm always excited to see a new piece of technology. There's an enormous
Speaker 6:  amount of new ideas in the Vision Pro to contend with fun to look at it again.
Speaker 6:  And they're like, oh we're gonna take your picture. Do you want a photo?
Speaker 6:  And I was like, yeah. And it didn't occur to me until I walked outta there
Speaker 6:  that Apple took my photos. They selected which
Speaker 6:  photos they were gonna airdrop to me and then they did the same
Speaker 6:  thing for everyone else. So we ran the photos. I think it is interesting
Speaker 6:  to look at pictures of people in the headset. No one has seen
Speaker 6:  that outside of Apple's marketing before. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And this has been kind of a closely guarded thing for seven months now. We
Speaker 8:  really have not seen pictures of people in the headset until now.
Speaker 7:  We have. but it was all like models in a gorgeously lit home.
Speaker 6:  Well excuse me, Alex.
Speaker 8:  Well right. We've seen ads of people in a headset. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Neela and I are gorgeously lit models still models like,
Speaker 7:  Sorry, sorry to all the models on this podcast.
Speaker 6:  All I was saying is we were in a gorgeously lit home. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  You were. It was
Speaker 6:  Beautiful. But there's something weird there, right? Especially 'cause it's
Speaker 6:  a picture of me and I, there's a and a picture of V and everybody else.
Speaker 6:  There's some assumption there that that is our photo.
Speaker 6:  Right? That right. but it is Apple's photo. It's an Apple's photo of me
Speaker 6:  that they got to pick. Right. And I know, you know, I know a bunch of other
Speaker 6:  people who had this experience, they were trying to make funny faces. They
Speaker 6:  were doing funny hand gestures and Apple just didn't give those photos to
Speaker 6:  them. Weird. That's a weird thing that is part of this. And it's because
Speaker 6:  Apple wanted to con, wanted to control those first set of photos.
Speaker 6:  That's fair. That's Apple's prerogative. It's their product. It's not launched
Speaker 6:  yet. I will just remind everyone, once
Speaker 6:  people buy this thing, all betts are off. Right. And like so this is
Speaker 6:  that pre-moment. Yeah. Where everyone's getting excited about an idea
Speaker 6:  that has a boundary. Right. And the boundary is still being very much set
Speaker 6:  by what Apple is saying and doing and allowing to be seen about this thing.
Speaker 6:  And eventually that boundary will disappear. And that to me, that's the
Speaker 6:  fun part. I keep saying that is actually the fun part. Some dummy is gonna
Speaker 6:  try to drive a cyber truck with a Vision Pro on their face. I know it's gonna
Speaker 6:  happen. I know the economics of YouTube and I know what it, that platform
Speaker 6:  rewards and like that will be crazy. And that is totally not
Speaker 6:  contemplated by what it's now. And so you're filling all the space between
Speaker 6:  what you are seeing and the dummy on YouTube driving the cyber truck with
Speaker 6:  Vision Pro with like your imagination. Which is the best part of any product
Speaker 6:  that is, by the way, the same thing is happening to the Rabbit R one right
Speaker 6:  now. That is a product that people are paying money so their imaginations
Speaker 6:  can run wild and then the actual product will do something or not do something.
Speaker 6:  Yep. So I, just having like worn it once and then
Speaker 6:  worn it the second time and then seeing that explosion of imagery.
Speaker 6:  I was like, oh, apple got what it wanted out of this. It got to control this
Speaker 6:  first set of photos. And some of the photos legitimately look extraordinarily
Speaker 6:  cool. Like the dude from Cool Hunting and the hoodie. Yeah, yeah. It's cool.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I I think those were in la I think they did demos in New York and LA
Speaker 6:  and I, I'm, I'm just gonna say this, I the
Speaker 9:  LA got the better, they got the better photos. All the all like we,
Speaker 9:  we saw our photos and we were like, oh, oh okay. You know, these are our
Speaker 9:  photos. Yeah, sure. And then we saw the LA photos and I was like,
Speaker 9:  excuse me. They have like really cool angles and everything like that. I
Speaker 9:  just look like, I look like I'm saying one does not simply
Speaker 9:  walk into virtual more door that is like, that is
Speaker 9:  what I look like in that thing. But you know, NELI was
Speaker 9:  the only one in New York who looked remotely cool because he was just sitting
Speaker 9:  there refusing to pinchy pinch.
Speaker 6:  I did not, I loved it. There are two things I didn't play along with. And
Speaker 6:  if you look at these photos you can, you can just see that I'm a bratt.
Speaker 6:  I didn't do the hand gesture and I refused to tuck the cable
Speaker 6:  behind my back. Which did they ask you to tuck the cable behind your back?
Speaker 6:  They're when do you wanna tuck the cable? And I was like, no, I'm gonna hold
Speaker 6:  the battery pack in my hand. And they, what photos did we
Speaker 6:  receive? You cannot see me holding the battery pack in my hand.
Speaker 6:  The guy in the hoodie that cable was running down the back of his hoodie,
Speaker 9:  He legitimately stuck that battery pack down his hoodie just because like
Speaker 9:  you can't see the wires. Like that was immediately the first thing I clocked
Speaker 9:  in his photo besides like, wow, why does he get to look like Kylo
Speaker 9:  Ren in vr? And I look like I'm telling
Speaker 9:  hobbits that they can't walk into virtual mortar
Speaker 6:  Anyhow. I I don't wanna like over index on it. Again, it is Apple's
Speaker 6:  product. It is their launch. That's how they wanna communicate about it.
Speaker 6:  Ev like I keep saying eventually people are gonna get the things and all
Speaker 6:  betts are off and that's fine. Like that's the gap. And I, I
Speaker 6:  personally think that this, this period in between
Speaker 6:  is when people get the most excited and I'm certainly not gonna tell people
Speaker 6:  not to be excited. Right? Sure. But I do think it is,
Speaker 6:  it's just important to note like, oh that is that I didn't take that photo.
Speaker 6:  That photo is not editorially controlled by me. We were given the photos
Speaker 6:  and you know, I'm a huge snob about these things as everyone knows all the
Speaker 6:  time. I'm constantly talking about what a huge disclosure. I didn't take
Speaker 6:  that photo. Right. The second piece and I'm actually, I
Speaker 6:  think this is where the gap between the experiencing it for the first time
Speaker 6:  and me experiencing it for the second time. There's some people who have
Speaker 6:  gotten this demo four times now. Wow. Is Apple is basically running the same
Speaker 6:  demo over and over again. They're not meaningfully different than the last
Speaker 6:  time. So the second time I found myself paying way more attention
Speaker 6:  to the hardware. Like the first time I was like, oh my gosh, the eye tracking
Speaker 6:  works that is extraordinarily impressive. Like I'm just, I've got my hands
Speaker 6:  on my sides, I'm clicking my fingers together. That just works. That is crazy
Speaker 6:  impressive. And this time I was like, okay, I'm wearing a headset on my
Speaker 6:  face. I'm absolutely looking at a screen and I'm
Speaker 6:  wondering what this thing can do and where its limits are. And they're, that
Speaker 6:  second time they were just more perceptible. I still dunno what they are.
Speaker 6:  'cause I was in a totally controlled 30 minute demo loop
Speaker 6:  with like a lot of people watching me and people around me watching what
Speaker 6:  I was watching on their iPads. Which is just a weird way to live
Speaker 6:  and
Speaker 8:  Kind of coming in and out of your vision as they want to. That's always fun.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But the, the part where it's like you're, you're using the computer
Speaker 6:  and they can see what your eyes are looking at. Yeah. 'cause they're, they're
Speaker 6:  monitoring you on the iPad. It's like I didn't, I didn't push the
Speaker 6:  boundaries of the Vision Pro in that experience. I was like, yeah, I know
Speaker 6:  I'm looking at it. And that's a webpage. But It works like that. Things
Speaker 6:  still works even when you're trying to perceive the limits of
Speaker 6:  the hardware, which is really interesting. V I'm curious, how did you, you
Speaker 6:  this was like your first blush at it, you had kind of a different experience.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, so like, like I said, I read your thing about it,
Speaker 9:  but actually experiencing it for yourself, you're not prepared for two 4K
Speaker 9:  like screens being zoomed into your eyes and just like your
Speaker 9:  brain trying to like square that. There was
Speaker 9:  like a large part of it where I was like, oh my God, I can actually see where
Speaker 9:  my eyes are going. And like cognitively that was very
Speaker 9:  strange. And then, you know, a lot of it I just felt like,
Speaker 9:  you know, they were laughing at me 'cause I kept feeling like turning my
Speaker 9:  head all around and trying to move through the space and they were like,
Speaker 9:  ha ha you know, doesn't it look lifelike? And yes, but
Speaker 9:  also there were parts where my eyes started going
Speaker 9:  into overload. Like overload. My eyes were just darting around all of the
Speaker 9:  places. And that's when I think I started coming up against some limitations
Speaker 9:  that you were talking about where I realized, oh this is a screen
Speaker 9:  because you know, foveated rendering it's a thing and if your eyes are
Speaker 9:  going at 20 million miles a minute, it's very hard for it to catch up with
Speaker 9:  you. So there were parts where I was like, oh, I don't understand
Speaker 9:  why it looks so blurry when I'm looking at this one thing.
Speaker 9:  Oh it's because it hasn't caught up to my eyes going 20,000 miles a a
Speaker 9:  minute. 'cause I, I literally was just going like,
Speaker 9:  like my eyes hurt after a while because it was going
Speaker 9:  so fast. 'cause there was just so many different things to look at and trying
Speaker 9:  to see if, like, if I look at it a different way, is it gonna change? Oh
Speaker 9:  yes and no. So it's, it's really hard to describe what
Speaker 9:  it's like and what you're seeing in there, but it's,
Speaker 9:  it's very high res is one thing I can say.
Speaker 8:  I mean vi that kind of makes it sound like you didn't have a super good time
Speaker 8:  inside of this thing. Like I think there's an interesting thing for us
Speaker 8:  as, as reporters where you go in being like, I'm gonna ask questions of this
Speaker 8:  thing where like if I'm just like a regular person who bought it, I'm just
Speaker 8:  gonna put it on my head and see what happens. Did you? But like I
Speaker 8:  feel like most people's first experience, like NELI you were talking about
Speaker 8:  comes away with like the holy shit that was cool
Speaker 8:  and the like just the sheer technology, the, the pinchy pinch gesture,
Speaker 8:  the eye tracking. Like you just come away from being very impressed. It doesn't,
Speaker 8:  I didn't get the read that you came from it sort of blown away by your first
Speaker 8:  experience with it.
Speaker 9:  I think it's 'cause I had time to sit with it. Right. It's like when you're
Speaker 9:  in the moment you're just kind of like, oh my God I can see
Speaker 9:  the texture of the rock on this volcano that I'm sitting on. That
Speaker 9:  is not something I was expecting. I literally was just like, oh my God that
Speaker 9:  rock is so textured. Not a thing I was thinking about. But
Speaker 9:  then, you know, and I think it also has to do with the physicality
Speaker 9:  of the device. The longer the demo goes on, the more
Speaker 9:  aware you are that you're wearing something on your face. 'cause it's quite
Speaker 9:  heavy is what I'll say. Like I, at the end of my 30 minute
Speaker 9:  demo, I started getting a tension headache because I really did feel
Speaker 9:  it just like pressing on my face. And if you look at the pictures of the
Speaker 9:  journalists and if you look right here where the nose
Speaker 9:  meets like your nasal labial flow folds is like the correct term.
Speaker 9:  But if you look at that part right underneath the ski goggles, you can see
Speaker 9:  it pressing on a lot of people quite hard. You can see it in my photos
Speaker 9:  and you can see it in quite a few people's photos. So
Speaker 9:  like that was just a thing that kept bringing me back to the, to the
Speaker 9:  fact that I was wearing something on my head and taking me out of like
Speaker 9:  the wonder of all of it. Because there are parts where you're just blown
Speaker 9:  away. Like it is, I'm a Star Wars nerd, it is kind of cool to be in the
Speaker 9:  Disney Plus app and be like, oh I'm on tattooing Ooh, I'm watching a new
Speaker 9:  Hope. And that's kind of cool. But then you know, you think about it
Speaker 9:  for a bit, right? And it's sort of like, oh you kind of come down and I'm
Speaker 9:  curious NELI, for your experience be being the second time around, did
Speaker 9:  it just like wear off that quickly? 'cause I saw Marquez brownie's tweet
Speaker 9:  where he was like, first time, oh my god, wow. Second time still cool and
Speaker 9:  wow. But wow it's a little heavier. And the third time all he was thinking
Speaker 9:  about was the weight of it on his, on his head. So I'm just curious,
Speaker 6:  I'm so hesitant to say
Speaker 6:  fully formed thoughts about this thing because no one
Speaker 6:  has ever spent time with it without a babysitter ever.
Speaker 6:  And I, you know, this was in our comments and this is like the oldest thing
Speaker 6:  in the world and it's on threads. People are like, these reviews are great.
Speaker 6:  I'm like, these are not reviews at all. Like, not even a little
Speaker 6:  bit. This is the most highly controlled experience you can have in the best
Speaker 6:  possible circumstances. And yes, some people have had the experience more
Speaker 6:  than once. So they are beginning to form thoughts. Like
Speaker 6:  Marquez I think has had the experience four times. Other people
Speaker 6:  who did the spatial video demos earlier, or I guess
Speaker 6:  late last year, they've had the experience four or five times. Like
Speaker 6:  yes, you can begin to form some thoughts even if you just repeat an experience
Speaker 6:  over and over again. But I still don't know what it's like
Speaker 6:  to virtual screen a Mac into it and try to use this as a
Speaker 6:  computer monitor, which is a thing they really want you to do. I still don't
Speaker 6:  really know what it's like to browse the web in it. And they showed us, I,
Speaker 6:  we v and I both got to open Safari and go to The Verge by punching the dumb
Speaker 6:  virtual keyboard that makes no sense. Which we should absolutely talk about
Speaker 6:  more. And so I'm just very hesitant to say,
Speaker 6:  okay, this is what I'm beginning to think because that the
Speaker 6:  circumstances are, were so deeply controlled
Speaker 6:  that it's like, yeah, I think the thing's heavy, but I wasn't doing anything
Speaker 6:  like that immersive. Right. I wasn't, we are constantly context shifting.
Speaker 6:  Even in the demo. They're like, look at this thing, look at that thing. Here's
Speaker 6:  an F1 car. Take the wheels off you're done with the F1 car. Like they're
Speaker 7:  Moving you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They're just like showing you all the things you can do.
Speaker 9:  It's like taking a tour, you know, it's like, and now look at this and now
Speaker 9:  look at that and now look at this. So like just it, it is hard to sit
Speaker 9:  with any one experience more than like for a hot second because
Speaker 9:  you're getting shepherded through like a tour of what they
Speaker 9:  want you to see.
Speaker 6:  For example, they showed us photos and videos that were shot on the Vision
Speaker 6:  Pro in, in spatial video. And who am I, what, where am I
Speaker 6:  instinct. I was like, I'm gonna evaluate the quality of this camera. And
Speaker 6:  then seven seconds later we were onto the next thing, right? And I was like,
Speaker 6:  I have some feelings about this but I haven't spent any time with it. Right.
Speaker 6:  Like that, that's weird. And I just don't want to like, I'm trying very hard
Speaker 6:  to, to be careful. But the one thing I will
Speaker 6:  say is, boy is it obvious you're looking at a screen?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I
Speaker 6:  Do have. Which is the thing they don't want you to think about.
Speaker 7:  I do have one evaluation question for you though. Joanna mentioned that she
Speaker 7:  was using a different strap this time and it felt a little lighter.
Speaker 7:  It was a little more pleasant for her to use. Joanna Stern friend of ours
Speaker 7:  from Washington Wall Street Journal, were you guys using the same strap?
Speaker 7:  Like no. Were you using a different strap this time?
Speaker 9:  No. So like, it was weird because they gave me the fabric
Speaker 9:  strap because when you set the thing up, you do like the face id thing
Speaker 9:  where you move your head around in a circle twice and that supposedly like
Speaker 9:  scans and gives you an estimate of like the fit for the light seal.
Speaker 9:  And so when I walked into the room, it was ready for me. I did not get a
Speaker 9:  choice as to which head strap I was gonna use. And I got the fabric strap,
Speaker 6:  The solo strap. The big, yeah,
Speaker 9:  Yeah, the solo strap. They showed me the other strap that
Speaker 9:  Joanna was and some of the other people were wearing. But I didn't
Speaker 9:  get to try it out. All I got told was that one gives more support,
Speaker 9:  which by the end of the 30 minutes I was like, I could have used more of
Speaker 9:  that support. Yeah. 'cause my hair was just
Speaker 7:  Yeah, because that's what you guys used when you tried it out at WWDC and
Speaker 7:  David. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Well and that's, I mean, that, that's true of, of all the headsets
Speaker 8:  we've tried, right? Like you're, you're definitely making a compromise
Speaker 8:  between something that looks better and is easier to
Speaker 8:  adjust and put on versus something that ultimately lands in a more
Speaker 8:  comfortable place. Like the quest, you can, you can either get the
Speaker 8:  one strap or the strap that goes overhead or you can get the elite strap.
Speaker 8:  That's even more like, I think ultimately the answer is probably lots of
Speaker 8:  different versions of this, of this. And so it's, it's odd that Apple has
Speaker 8:  controlled it in the way that it has. But Neil, to your point, I think
Speaker 8:  your, your instincts are good and fair and right
Speaker 8:  except that there's now a huge number of people as you're listening to this
Speaker 8:  podcast are having to decide whether to spend $3,500 pre-ordering this thing.
Speaker 8:  There are likely to be supply constraints. There's not gonna be a lot of
Speaker 8:  them. So for us to just say, oh wait a few weeks until everybody has it and
Speaker 8:  then you'll be able to get one is actually not helpful because by a few weeks
Speaker 8:  from now, it might be months from now before you can actually get one.
Speaker 6:  I feel like the people who are gonna spend $3,500 in the newest Apple gadget,
Speaker 6:  that money is already committed. They
Speaker 8:  Already know.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You know, like, I, I think that, I mean
Speaker 6:  v is an actual reviewer. Like the, the thing that reviews do
Speaker 6:  now in 2024 is not always help people make
Speaker 6:  purchase decisions like some, sometimes it is. But for something like this,
Speaker 6:  it's actually the, to put it in a cultural context almost as much
Speaker 6:  as help people decide whether to buy it. 'cause there's Infiniti, there will
Speaker 6:  be infinity content about it.
Speaker 8:  I don't know that I agree in this case though. 'cause I think whether you
Speaker 8:  should buy a new phone or not, people mostly know the answer, right?
Speaker 8:  Like you're, you're gonna buy what you're gonna buy. And I think if there's
Speaker 8:  something like wildly new and different, we have a responsibility to talk
Speaker 8:  about it. In this case, it's like we've been talking about most people have
Speaker 8:  no context for this thing. They have no experience of it. They have no idea
Speaker 8:  what it is.
Speaker 6:  I totally disagree with you. I totally disagree with you. Okay. Because Apple
Speaker 6:  has been extraordinarily successful. It making sure people don't talk
Speaker 6:  about this thing like a VR headset. And it is
Speaker 6:  absolutely a VR headset. I just look at it, look at the
Speaker 6:  pictures. You can, there are pictures now I
Speaker 8:  Feel like you just agreed with what I said. People have no idea what this
Speaker 8:  thing
Speaker 6:  Is. No, they absolutely do. The Quest two, there are Quest twos everywhere.
Speaker 6:  The Quest three is not as popular as it should be. The Quest two is all over
Speaker 6:  the place all the time. I've put people in Quest
Speaker 6:  in our Quest two that I own and watched them get blown away by how textured
Speaker 6:  the dinosaur is. Like this is not so out there.
Speaker 6:  So
Speaker 8:  You're saying even people who don't think they know what this thing is, know
Speaker 8:  it more closely than they realize.
Speaker 9:  I, I'm gonna 100% agree with NELI on that because I walked into
Speaker 9:  the going like I don't know what to expect. And the more I spent time
Speaker 9:  with it, I was like, oh, I've used a bunch of Apple products before. Actually
Speaker 9:  this feels quite familiar. Like I kind of do know what I'm using because
Speaker 9:  like you have the digital crown on the Vision Pro.
Speaker 9:  I have worn every single Apple watch since the Apple Watch series two.
Speaker 9:  So that was super familiar. And then, you know, on the other side there's
Speaker 9:  a flat side button that you use to take spatial photos and video that's just
Speaker 9:  the side button from the Apple watch. Like everything inside the, the
Speaker 9:  experience as well. It's like, it's like launching launchpad on your
Speaker 9:  Mac. If you've used Apple products, you kind of know Yeah what
Speaker 9:  it's like it's just Apple but make it vr. That's
Speaker 9:  kind of what what the Vision Pro is.
Speaker 6:  I point out, by the way, you should read that as a compliment to Apple's
Speaker 6:  designers, right? They took this very esoteric concept, they took the
Speaker 6:  best of their concepts from other products, they married them together and
Speaker 6:  they made it all seem very obvious it's Apple at its best. Like that's what
Speaker 6:  that company is good at. But I'm saying just conceptually, if you have
Speaker 6:  worn another VR headset, and I'm confident that people listening to the show
Speaker 6:  have worn other VR headsets. We have been covering these products for a
Speaker 6:  decade, right? There's a decade of context for this thing.
Speaker 8:  Sure. But then how do you explain the fact that Apple is giving people 30
Speaker 8:  minute demos in a store in order to be able to do this? Like I just don't
Speaker 8:  because
Speaker 7:  Oh no, no I know this because not everybody has used VR headsets.
Speaker 7:  They are really like in, if you don't have access to one, if you don't have
Speaker 7:  a friend, if, if you don't have a friend who works at The Verge, you probably
Speaker 7:  don't have access to one. You probably haven't tried it. And so for a lot
Speaker 7:  of people, this will be one of their first experiences with VR outside of
Speaker 7:  like the horrible experience you see at a mall
Speaker 7:  or an arcade. And for it sounds like it is probably
Speaker 7:  one of the best VR experiences that you guys, that everybody on this call
Speaker 7:  has experienced. Including like those, what was it, the Vijo that's like
Speaker 7:  a thousand dollars, $1,500 headset. Like talk
Speaker 6:  About things people have no experience with. Right. You know the Vijo,
Speaker 7:  That's the only one I've used. I don't use any other headset before.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. This is better than that. Thank you. I can say fairly confidently,
Speaker 7:  It's just me out there using my bar Jo. But, but it, it's like a lot of people
Speaker 7:  probably they understand VR conceptually they might have used like a, a,
Speaker 7:  a garbage version and Apple is hoping that their version is so advanced
Speaker 7:  it's so much improved that that it's something different. don don't
Speaker 7:  know if that's true. I haven't tried it. I don't know if that's true. It
Speaker 7:  sounds like so far from every one of you got your experiences
Speaker 7:  it's better, but it's not like, well we don't even need to call this
Speaker 7:  VR anymore, which is what Apple very much wants us to all hope.
Speaker 8:  I So do not buy the premise that most people understand VR conceptually.
Speaker 8:  I just don't,
Speaker 7:  No, don don't think they I don't think they do. I I I agree with you there
Speaker 7:  where I think like people probably understand conceptually this is a VR headset
Speaker 7:  but also don't understand conceptually what vr
Speaker 6:  Isn. Wait lemme try to split the difference. Let me, lemme try
Speaker 6:  don don't know if I'm gonna be successful. Lemme try. Okay. I think people
Speaker 6:  understand VR headsets. That's where I disagree with David. I think Ready
Speaker 6:  Player one is a movie that Steven Spielberg made. Like that's
Speaker 6:  a real thing that exists. People understand it. You can, Meta sells these
Speaker 6:  things. Every Christmas people buy VR headsets and they play
Speaker 6:  games. A few,
Speaker 8:  A few people do.
Speaker 6:  A few people.
Speaker 7:  40 million. 40 million I think
Speaker 6:  Quite a lot in the scheme of things, right? Like we've talked a lot on, on
Speaker 6:  the show about how supernatural is the thing that drives the
Speaker 6:  most me Quest sales to women and people over 40. Like sure
Speaker 6:  that's a growing business for them. So much so that the FTC tried to stop
Speaker 6:  them from buying it. So like there's just a thing there that is interesting,
Speaker 6:  right? There is some acknowledgement of the product category
Speaker 6:  by by some larger group of people and it has been around for a long time
Speaker 6:  and there is culture built around it, like Ready Player one other things.
Speaker 6:  Then there's Apple saying this is not a VR headset, this is spatial computing,
Speaker 6:  this is the future. It is, you know, I, one of the things that
Speaker 6:  I'm curious to think about when we actually get these things outside of control
Speaker 6:  is like, what is the delta between
Speaker 6:  $400 Quest three and a $3,500
Speaker 6:  Vision Pro? I, it is impossible to know right now. Like we, you
Speaker 6:  have to just like sit there and look at both of them and experience both
Speaker 6:  of them and find out
Speaker 7:  It's the Vargo,
Speaker 6:  It's the var the thing right in the middle is the VJO a thousand dollars.
Speaker 6:  But you know, the, the, the Quest line is basically a
Speaker 6:  mid-range Android smartphone on your face. The Vision Pro
Speaker 6:  is an M two processor on your face. They're different. They're gonna have
Speaker 6:  different capabilities. Are the screens meaningfully different? I, I don't
Speaker 6:  know the answers to these questions,
Speaker 6:  but Apple's positioning this thing is not competing with the Quest three.
Speaker 6:  And the thing that jumped out at me in these demos is how few of
Speaker 6:  them were actually ar, right? Like they, the the Disney
Speaker 6:  Plus app, they're putting you on tattooing, they're putting you in the Avengers
Speaker 6:  Tower. Those are straight up VR experiences. It doesn't matter what room
Speaker 6:  you're in, when you watch a spatial video that you, I
Speaker 6:  brought in some spatial video that I shot of Max on my iPhone 15
Speaker 6:  Pro. You can watch it or you can like put it in like a theater setting. And
Speaker 6:  I was like watching like video and hala like, and it was awesome,
Speaker 6:  right? Like the thing they do in that demo, you're watching a
Speaker 6:  video and it will take this, the highlights of that video and
Speaker 6:  reflected onto the clouds below the mountain. It's so,
Speaker 6:  it's like so cool still a hundred percent a rendered VR
Speaker 6:  experience. Like where I'm like,
Speaker 6:  where's the ar? And they're like, here's a full-size F1 car in the room with
Speaker 6:  you just rip
Speaker 9:  Off the car, the the wheels off the ar the Alpha Romeo.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They're like here's an Aston Martin F1 car in Jig space,
Speaker 6:  which is a cool app. And it's like, well one, okay, So I need a room that's
Speaker 6:  big enough to hold a car and then I'm gonna look at this car.
Speaker 6:  What now? Like where's the stuff, like where's the thing
Speaker 6:  where you're augmenting reality, where you're creating computing in space?
Speaker 6:  I would point
Speaker 8:  Out Apple's also not calling it an AR headset,
Speaker 6:  Right? They're saying spatial computing, Apple's
Speaker 8:  Trying to invent this other thing that currently means nothing.
Speaker 6:  Well it has some sort of definition, right? It's,
Speaker 6:  it's been around for a minute. Apple
Speaker 7:  Is spinning one, I just wanna correct I said Meta Quest two sold
Speaker 7:  40 million headsets. I'm wrong. It's sold 20 million as of
Speaker 7:  2023. So half of that.
Speaker 6:  All right. So my argument's a little weaker than it was before.
Speaker 7:  Sorry. Sorry about that. 20 million people have tried it at least probably.
Speaker 7:  I mean we could say up to 40 if you count like the virtual boy
Speaker 7:  and the Quest one, David's like, no, we're not doing that math.
Speaker 7:  Refuse.
Speaker 6:  Putting
Speaker 9:  That aside, just putting that aside. How many people have tried iPhones?
Speaker 9:  How many people have tried MacBooks? Like I, what I really think Apple is
Speaker 9:  selling here is the apple ness of it. Like by calling it, you know, apple
Speaker 9:  always does stuff. It's like they give a different name for something that
Speaker 9:  we already know by another name. So by calling it spatial computing, they're
Speaker 9:  just going like, oh, but Apple's doing it now. Right? Can
Speaker 6:  I, but let me just, can I 20 million is, I, I understand it's not everybody.
Speaker 6:  The Xbox One, as of September, 2023 has
Speaker 6:  sold 33 million units and there's not a person on
Speaker 6:  earth that you're like, do you know what an Xbox is? And they're like, what
Speaker 6:  are you talking about? Yeah.
Speaker 8:  'cause we've had video game consoles for 40
Speaker 6:  Years and you've had VR headsets for a decade and
Speaker 8:  No one has tried them.
Speaker 11:  Like
Speaker 7:  20 million people
Speaker 8:  Six months after Atari came out. You think everybody on Earth knew what a
Speaker 8:  game console was?
Speaker 6:  Maybe. I mean, look, I wasn't born, they made the movie The Wizard about
Speaker 6:  the first.
Speaker 8:  I just, I think like a, I think the way Apple markets its products
Speaker 8:  at the beginning has next to nothing to do with what those
Speaker 8:  products ultimately are. Like if you go back to 2007 and the iPhone 2010
Speaker 8:  and the iPad 2015 and the Apple Watch, like the way they talk about those
Speaker 8:  products Yeah. Is nothing like what they became, it just isn't.
Speaker 8:  And So I think I I posted after you guys posted your pictures
Speaker 8:  just being like saying basically if Apple can make these things cool to wear
Speaker 8:  in public, it'll be the marketing coup of the century. And I got, I mean,
Speaker 8:  dozens of replies from people being like, Apple's not marketing that way.
Speaker 8:  I was like, I don't give a shit what Apple is marketing it with. Like, I,
Speaker 8:  the five minutes after that thing goes on sale, somebody is going to take
Speaker 8:  this thing into a coffee shop and go on a run where, and that's like, that's
Speaker 8:  how this stuff works. You buy it, you do whatever the hell you want with
Speaker 8:  it. And I like, we have so
Speaker 8:  few answers still about what you're going to do inside of this thing
Speaker 8:  or how you use it or what it's like, or if it's a better monitor than my
Speaker 8:  monitor
Speaker 7:  Now David, that's not true. We're gonna have Fruit Ninja
Speaker 11:  Disney
Speaker 7:  Plus Disney plus. Yeah. Like a wealth of
Speaker 7:  opportunities.
Speaker 6:  Fantastic. How?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I will say that I do think they expect people to take it
Speaker 9:  out into the world just because when I was getting my demo, like one of the
Speaker 9:  use cases they were ta talking to me about, I was like, you're gonna be on
Speaker 9:  a plane and you're still gonna be able to interact with your stewardess when
Speaker 9:  she asks you for whether you want a drink or a snack.
Speaker 6:  I'm dying to wear this thing on a plane. I've never wanted to do anything
Speaker 6:  more. I'm gonna go on like a status run just to collect my
Speaker 6:  whatever horrible new system Delta is doing now and wear, wear this headset
Speaker 6:  and
Speaker 8:  You're gonna have to charge it six times.
Speaker 6:  So we should talk about that. The, the, this is the stuff that is legitimately
Speaker 6:  new and like, honestly like a little silly and like in
Speaker 6:  the best way. So you're in a VR experience and we should just call it that
Speaker 6:  you're in a virtual environment inside the headset. You know, someone walks
Speaker 6:  up to you and you look at them, they just sort of fade into
Speaker 6:  view and then you
Speaker 9:  Can see it. It's really weird.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's odd in this actually this very funny moment in my demo,
Speaker 6:  I was like playing with this, right? Right. 'cause there's, I'm sitting on
Speaker 6:  a couch, there's people around me, the Apple people are around me and I forget
Speaker 6:  that they're all watching what I'm doing. So I just kept looking at
Speaker 6:  them to make them fade into view. And eventually one of them was just like,
Speaker 6:  looked up at me like, what are you doing? Because I was just staring at them.
Speaker 6:  You'd be like, are you, are you gonna appear? And they're like, and then
Speaker 6:  they appeared and they were looking at me.
Speaker 7:  How, how similar is it to that moment in Lord of the Rings where Gandalf
Speaker 7:  just slowly appears in like from the whiteness in front of
Speaker 9:  It. It's kind of like that. Like I just, the thing that came to my mind was
Speaker 9:  a Casper, the friendly ghost, just very slowly ghost of
Speaker 9:  VR future coming into your, into your periphery.
Speaker 9:  And it's very strange. Like don don't Hello
Speaker 7:  Devon Sowell,
Speaker 9:  They're kind of semi-transparent and just floating in the middle of
Speaker 9:  a volcano. Yeah. And it's, it's weird. But then
Speaker 9:  like viewing it from the outside because you know, we can't see ourselves
Speaker 9:  like the, I think the photo is the only like concept that I have of what
Speaker 9:  I look like in that thing. But you, we did get to see another person using
Speaker 9:  it and get a look at eyesight and that was just,
Speaker 9:  I I I'm still processing what eyesight looks like.
Speaker 7:  That's the, that's the, the, the eyes appearing on the front of the display.
Speaker 6:  And so the reason we weren't able to do that is to, to do that they've gotta
Speaker 6:  create what's called a persona for you. This is your, your virtual head that
Speaker 6:  will appear in FaceTime calls. don don't. That's the only way
Speaker 6:  to describe what it is. And then that virtual face, when
Speaker 6:  you are in the headset and you start talking to someone, your eyes
Speaker 6:  show up on the front display of the headset.
Speaker 8:  It's fancy googly eyes. Like we we get it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's it's, it's weird. It's weird 'cause it's obviously a render of
Speaker 6:  eyes
Speaker 9:  And it's like a render of your eyes. Yeah. So like when you blink, it
Speaker 9:  blinks when your eyes are open, they're open. Did
Speaker 6:  You try to make eye contact with the person who's giving you the demo? I
Speaker 6:  I have never stared in another person's eyes the way that I stared into
Speaker 6:  that person's eyes and they were virtualized and I was like, are you looking
Speaker 6:  at me? Because I'm looking at you.
Speaker 9:  Huh? It's, it's, it's weird and like there's different cues that
Speaker 9:  happen with eyesight. So like if they're looking at
Speaker 9:  you, you can tell they're looking at you, but if they're not looking at you
Speaker 9:  but their googly eyes are looking at you, you can kind of tell because there's
Speaker 9:  like a blue flash that comes up and that's supposed to signal to you that
Speaker 9:  they're not focusing on you. They're doing other things within the headset.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. And if they're fully immersed, you don't see the the eyes at all. It's
Speaker 9:  just like that shimmer. This is that appears
Speaker 6:  Creating all new ways, unsettling ways to be rude to someone at a bar.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  But Apple's marketing says no one's gonna take it to a bar. Eli. Sure. No
Speaker 8:  one's gonna do that.
Speaker 9:  They're 100% gonna take it to a bar.
Speaker 6:  Here's
Speaker 8:  The thing, Eli specifically is going to take it
Speaker 6:  To a bar. I'm gonna be hammered in this headset 24 7 on a plane. I live in
Speaker 6:  the sky now. Everybody just flying around wasted.
Speaker 6:  I'm dying to see two people in two headsets try to communicate
Speaker 6:  to each other. Yes. Like just think about the enormous amount of signal
Speaker 6:  processing that that needs to take place in order for those two people to
Speaker 6:  make eye contact. Right. You've gotta put on two headsets.
Speaker 6:  They both have to capture a virtual depiction of you.
Speaker 6:  Then it has to take a real time video of your eyes, process
Speaker 6:  that into a 3D model of your face, display that on
Speaker 6:  a front screen, which is then captured by a camera in the second
Speaker 6:  headset, which then has to re-render that into reality to
Speaker 6:  display it to someone else's eyes, which are in turn being captured and displayed
Speaker 6:  on a 3D rendering of that. And it's like, you could just take the headsets
Speaker 6:  off, but I'm dying. I'm absolutely dying to make this
Speaker 6:  happen and just be like, this was a lot of work.
Speaker 9:  So like if we were in the room and we were both wearing the Vision Pro and
Speaker 9:  talking to each other, would we just like materialize in each other's
Speaker 9:  screen while and would you be
Speaker 6:  Wearing the headset
Speaker 9:  On the screen? Would we be wearing the headset and would I be seeing you
Speaker 9:  wearing the headset with your eyesight on in my screen
Speaker 9:  that's just like, it's breaking my brain. Or would it
Speaker 6:  Be the digital avatar when I say these were tightly controlled 30 minute
Speaker 6:  demos. What I mean is I asked to have that experience and I was met with
Speaker 6:  almost dead silence.
Speaker 6:  Nope. That's just not a thing that we're gonna, and I was like, okay, like
Speaker 6:  I understand like eventually I keep saying this, eventually people are gonna
Speaker 6:  get them. We will get a review unit by hook or by crook and we will
Speaker 6:  spend time with this thing asking some questions right now that
Speaker 6:  fill the gap between everyone's imagination
Speaker 6:  and reality. And that gap. I I just gonna keep
Speaker 6:  underlining it. That gap is magical. Like that's the fun part of
Speaker 6:  like liking technology. You're like, you can imagine what these things can
Speaker 6:  do. And I'm, the reason I keep pointing at VR
Speaker 6:  headsets is like there's actually something you can ground these experiences
Speaker 6:  with that exists today at scale. They might not be as good,
Speaker 6:  but the gap between, I have a Quest Pro sitting here, the gap between
Speaker 6:  a Quest pro, which we did not give a good review to, and the Vision Pro
Speaker 6:  we, that's the thing to evaluate. It's not here's a magical new
Speaker 6:  experience. No, that's a headset. You can look at the pictures and you can
Speaker 6:  say, okay, this is a VR headset that contains a lot of ideas about the future
Speaker 6:  of computing for sure. but it very much has some of the
Speaker 6:  limitations that are inherent to this form factor. Like for example,
Speaker 6:  having to be on your head.
Speaker 6:  Like that's just a limitation of this form factor that is easily
Speaker 6:  comparable to everything else that's ever been in this form factor.
Speaker 9:  I think one other question I have is like with the experience, like we're
Speaker 9:  grounding it in VR headsets that we've had, right? But the thing is that
Speaker 9:  most of like 900000% of my experiences in
Speaker 9:  regular regular VR headsets is gaming. And there was
Speaker 9:  not a single gaming demo to be had in the Vision Pro. So
Speaker 9:  that's kind of one thing that's been in the back of my head is just like,
Speaker 9:  okay, the obvious use case for VR is gaming in
Speaker 9:  this point in time. But I don't think we've heard a lot about
Speaker 9:  gaming in the Vision. Pro. We've heard about it like as entertainment and
Speaker 9:  some sort of productivity platform. But are am
Speaker 9:  I really gonna do that?
Speaker 7:  Well Meta bought all the good gaming companies for That's true. That's real.
Speaker 7:  So so that's part of it. And then like we we're getting Fruit Ninja and I
Speaker 7:  have no doubt Fruit Ninja is gonna have you with a virtual sword
Speaker 7:  cutting the stuff yourself, right? No, it's
Speaker 9:  Gonna be pinching. I'm gonna be pinching the fruit, pinching,
Speaker 7:  Pinching the kiwi. But like that's, that's what I, because I was looking
Speaker 7:  at that too. 'cause that's what I care about. No disrespect to everyone who
Speaker 7:  wants to have all of their meetings in a room with everybody wearing a headset.
Speaker 7:  You cannot wait. I, I I, I wanna, I wanna spend $3,500 on a sick gaming
Speaker 7:  headset. I don't but games.
Speaker 6:  It's called Vargo Games and it's now Alex.
Speaker 7:  Oh my God. I'm gotta go get a Vargo. The best experience.
Speaker 8:  I love that we're getting away from the pronunciation of that product just
Speaker 8:  a little bit. Every single time we say it, it just gets a, we get a little
Speaker 8:  further away from it.
Speaker 7:  Virgo. That's actually the day.
Speaker 8:  Love it. Yeah, it's the Virgo headset. It's the, it's the Vigo Morstein
Speaker 8:  headset. All
Speaker 6:  This is, as much as we know about the Vision Pro we got, we did get to see
Speaker 6:  the Disney Plus app. There are some other drama. Netflix is not gonna make
Speaker 6:  an app for this thing that news broke this week. They're just like, use the
Speaker 6:  web browser. That's fine. That's weird. It sounds
Speaker 6:  like app developers as a whole have not rushed to this platform yet,
Speaker 6:  which is fine. The platform doesn't
Speaker 6:  exist yet. I I wouldn't expect a bunch of app developers to be ready to ship
Speaker 6:  on day one, but there are some big questions about what this
Speaker 6:  thing is for how it actually works. It's $3,500 to get one.
Speaker 6:  You have to go, you have to either go to a store or upload your prescription
Speaker 6:  after scanning your face. Like there's a lot of steps between now
Speaker 6:  and lots of people having them. And I I think there's just a lot of caution
Speaker 6:  in the, in the middle of all of that.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And I think for the, the funny position Apple is in right now is it,
Speaker 8:  it's having to reckon with the fact that it's Apple and it's very
Speaker 8:  hard for Apple to quietly launch a product. But
Speaker 8:  fundamentally this is, this is like a public beta of a thing, right? Like
Speaker 8:  Apple does not think this is the final version of this. It's not
Speaker 8:  what anyone believes is going to be where we're headed
Speaker 8:  overall in a decade. And this is the kind of thing that like
Speaker 8:  Snapchat would call like the next Rev of spectacles and still be like, this
Speaker 8:  is just a fun thing we're messing around with. And Apple because it's, apple
Speaker 8:  has to come out and say this is the future. We've solved everything. This
Speaker 8:  is perfect. And it just puts you in a funny position as a marketing enterprise.
Speaker 6:  Here's a question I'll leave everyone because again, we, none of these reviews
Speaker 6:  stop calling them reviews. It's driving me bananas. Clearly
Speaker 6:  you people actually have to review them, whether it's us or whoever, whatever
Speaker 6:  reviewer you trust, like whatever independent reviewer you trust to spend
Speaker 6:  a lot of time with something and give you an opinion, go trust them. I hope
Speaker 6:  it's us. You know, we, we try really hard, but whoever, it's the question
Speaker 6:  that's gonna be embedded in all those reviews is if
Speaker 6:  Apple thinks the future is ar, which Tim Cook has said over and over and
Speaker 6:  over again and then this is a simulator of an AR
Speaker 6:  device, which is kind of the framework that I'm just gonna start with, right?
Speaker 6:  This is a simulator of the thing they want to make. Well then showing
Speaker 6:  us all these VR experience, having a light seal
Speaker 6:  blocking you off from the real world and putting you on top of the volcano
Speaker 6:  or an Avengers tower, that's not ar right? That is,
Speaker 6:  those are VR experiences and there's a real tension in this product
Speaker 6:  between the things a VR headset is inherently good at, especially when you
Speaker 6:  spend all the money on it and the AR simulator it might wish to
Speaker 6:  be. And I, I truly do not know how they will pick those paths.
Speaker 6:  'cause if you just want a pair of glasses or you just wanna a pair of contact
Speaker 6:  lenses, which you know is the end state that they have talked about
Speaker 6:  in the past,
Speaker 6:  wow, you're not gonna be able to block off flight and put everybody in Avengers
Speaker 6:  Tower.
Speaker 6:  So like how, how do you, how do you get from here to there if everything
Speaker 6:  good about this product is vr?
Speaker 7:  I mean that's the same challenge that Meta's facing, right? Who's who said
Speaker 7:  the same thing, AR is our future, this is where we're going. All of this
Speaker 7:  stuff is just a step on the way to ar I think they're just, I think
Speaker 7:  meta's just more open about this than, than Apple is. I think Apple is in
Speaker 7:  the exact same place Meta is with only their high-end
Speaker 7:  headsets gonna probably sell better and perform better.
Speaker 7:  But otherwise, I think ultimately it's, it's, it's very similar space of
Speaker 7:  we we're not there yet. The, the technology doesn't exist. The things we
Speaker 7:  wanna do to make AR cool isn't possible yet. So we're gonna do
Speaker 7:  the, we're gonna do a really good VR headset because that's the way you start
Speaker 7:  to normalize the stuff that's gonna be necessary for ar. But
Speaker 7:  Apple's much quieter about it because they want us all to think that they've
Speaker 7:  created a new form of computing when everybody knows they just made a really
Speaker 7:  cool VR headset.
Speaker 6:  Well, no, if you listen to David, no one on earth has ever heard of a VR
Speaker 6:  headset before.
Speaker 8:  That's definitely what I said. That's right. Well and ultimately
Speaker 8:  this is the first VR headset anyone has ever tried on in the history of the
Speaker 8:  universe. Apple actually invented the term vr. Just this. No,
Speaker 8:  I think ultimately what, what all these companies seem to be saying is that
Speaker 8:  VR is a feature of ar, right? Like those two things are not mutually exclusive
Speaker 8:  and ultimately you want both. But the
Speaker 8:  thing we can do right now is pretty good vr, there's not
Speaker 8:  much evidence yet that we can do pretty good ar And I think,
Speaker 8:  I think to Alex's point, like Meta's pretty open about that. Some of the
Speaker 8:  other headset makers are pretty open about that. And Apple, just by virtue
Speaker 8:  of the way the company operates, is not allowed to say it's
Speaker 8:  bad at anything. So instead it's going to keep imagining new futures
Speaker 8:  that it has invented even as it goes through the same stages as everybody
Speaker 8:  else. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I feel even that we had demos, we replay this thing again, I'm just
Speaker 6:  gonna keep repeating this and we should move on to talk about what's going
Speaker 6:  on with the Apple Watch and the Galaxy ring. Yeah. 'cause we, we do have
Speaker 6:  V here, but we don't know anything yet.
Speaker 6:  Even the people I know who, who've worn this thing five times, they don't,
Speaker 6:  they don't know anything. It's, we have to take these things outside of
Speaker 6:  Apple's control. We have to try to wear them on airplanes and
Speaker 6:  behind cyber truck wheels. Can you imagine the cyber truck wiper in this
Speaker 6:  thing? Do you think the cyber truck wiper moves too fast for the Vision Pros
Speaker 6:  cameras? I'm dying to know
Speaker 6:  there's a whole other thing that happens when a product is actually released
Speaker 6:  that is the important thing and that I'm just gonna keep everybody focused
Speaker 6:  on that because you, you cannot know right now. And that to me
Speaker 6:  is utterly fascinating. Like it is kind of the best moment. 'cause
Speaker 6:  anything is possible and everyone can have all the dreams they want. And
Speaker 6:  then you're gonna put on the headset in your weird rendered eyes, you're
Speaker 6:  gonna look into the eyes of someone you love and you're gonna be like, am
Speaker 6:  I still cool? And there's gonna be an answer
Speaker 7:  If you ask that question. No.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. This is what I do with every piece of new technology. I just look at
Speaker 6:  someone directly in the eyes and say, am I still cool?
Speaker 6:  And that person is always Becky and she's always like, you never were.
Speaker 11:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  All right. Very quickly, let's talk about what's going on with the Apple
Speaker 6:  Watch, which it's somewhat simple I guess V
Speaker 9:  Walk,
Speaker 6:  Its band again. It's banned again. It's
Speaker 9:  Banned again. So, you know, it's just been kind of a back and forth
Speaker 9:  where, this is really funny again because usually I think Apple is so
Speaker 9:  used to winning that it, the fact that it's losing a lot
Speaker 9:  against Massimo right now is just kind of very
Speaker 9:  fascinating to watch. Just because, so earlier this week Bloomberg
Speaker 9:  was suggesting that, you know, apple is going to drop the
Speaker 9:  blood oxygen feature from the Watches in order to get around the
Speaker 9:  ITC ban. And that basically US Customs and
Speaker 9:  Borders was like, yeah that works, that's cool. That totally awesome. But
Speaker 9:  that wasn't confirmed right at the beginning of this week. And then yesterday
Speaker 9:  basically we heard that the Federal Appeals Court was like, yeah, we're not
Speaker 9:  gonna extend the stay on this ban. So starting today 5:00 PM
Speaker 9:  ban's back on, you can't sell this stuff. And then, you know, late last
Speaker 9:  night, apple was like, haha, guess what guys? We're gonna sell versions without
Speaker 9:  the blood oxygen feature. So that's how we're getting around that those went
Speaker 9:  on sale today. So that's, that's currently where we're at
Speaker 9:  with the Apple Watch band. And it's just, it's just like, just
Speaker 9:  pay Massimo. Like you could just end this, you could license this.
Speaker 6:  A deeply funny cline of this story is it Massimo added a new
Speaker 6:  board member this week and it's Bob ch Oh yeah. X Disney,
Speaker 6:  CI. That's about, it's fantastic. It's pretty good. He's gonna make it tech,
Speaker 6:  it's pretty good. He's gonna make it tech's pretty good. He, since leaving
Speaker 6:  Disney, his, I, I think he was always bald, but he's gotten more
Speaker 6:  aggressively bald in a particular way. The photo of him that's like he's
Speaker 6:  joining Mass Award is like, oh, Thanos is on the board now. Like that's
Speaker 6:  very much the vibe.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's pretty good. This is just a Right, the, the
Speaker 6:  ban is still temporary 'cause Apple has an appeal going
Speaker 6:  and the hardware is still in there. It's just not accessible by the software.
Speaker 6:  And the, your point has always been like this is the least useful piece of
Speaker 6:  the Apple
Speaker 9:  Watch. It is. It is the least useful as of right now.
Speaker 9:  Piece of tech in most smart Watches to be quite frank because
Speaker 9:  like what are you using blood oxygen for, right? And
Speaker 9:  COVID, everyone was all on pulse oximeters because you could tell whether,
Speaker 9:  you know, you were, your lungs were working, whether they were breathing.
Speaker 9:  But the thing that people have to realize is that these are not
Speaker 9:  FDA cleared pulse oximeters, right? They're wellness gadgets. You are
Speaker 9:  taking a spot check at any given second
Speaker 9:  as to how much blood oxygen you have in a second, you have
Speaker 9:  to sit there for 15 seconds. Still. You can't move for it to
Speaker 9:  tell you what this estimate of your blood oxygen is. And for the vast
Speaker 9:  majority of people who are not having any kind of lung issues
Speaker 9:  or whatever, if you're a healthy 99.9% of the time
Speaker 9:  is it's gonna be over 95. And you're gonna find out I don't have to worry
Speaker 9:  about anything. The other use case for pulse,
Speaker 9:  pulse oximeters within these smart Watches is to tell you
Speaker 9:  whether you have breathing disturbances at night. So you're just gonna get
Speaker 9:  an average in the morning of what your SP O2 level was.
Speaker 9:  And for 99% of people who are healthy, you are gonna see that it's either
Speaker 9:  above 95%, you're good, or it's gonna be below that and you're
Speaker 9:  gonna be like, oh, I'm a side sleeper, so it messed up. Therefore,
Speaker 9:  I can't really trust that because if you are a side sleeper, it is going
Speaker 9:  to tell you that it's lower. Like Garmin tell me regularly that my SPO
Speaker 9:  two level at night is 91%, which is, that's, that's like
Speaker 9:  you should be going to the hospital if you start getting to those levels.
Speaker 9:  So it is not really all that trustworthy. The only thing
Speaker 9:  is, like in the mid to long term, these companies are looking at Pulse
Speaker 9:  oximeters as a way to detect sleep apnea. The only company that's
Speaker 9:  remotely close is Withings. And even they're not saying it's sleep apnea,
Speaker 9:  right? They're saying breathing disturbances, which may indicate
Speaker 9:  at some point that you may be inclined to sleep
Speaker 9:  apnea, so maybe you should go to a doctor. So it's, it's really not that
Speaker 9:  serious of a feature right now. It's, it's just not So
Speaker 7:  Keep buying the wa If you were planning to buy a watch the Apple Watch, you
Speaker 7:  can still just go buy it,
Speaker 9:  You can still go buy it, it's fine. The SE is not impacted.
Speaker 9:  And you know, it's really funny 'cause whenever I recommend products
Speaker 9:  for most people, I say, you're gonna be fine with the se, you're, it's totally
Speaker 9:  good for you. And they're all, they just have fomo. They just want all the
Speaker 9:  stuff. Yeah, it's cool looking. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  What if I need to light up an 80 decibel siren in the middle of the woods?
Speaker 7:  Come on. Se can't do that.
Speaker 9:  No, no, I can't do that. But neither can the regular series nine.
Speaker 9:  It's only the Ultra that's gonna be doing that for
Speaker 6:  You with it. What, what do think have Victoria?
Speaker 9:  Well, I know you have the Ultra, I know you have the Ultra,
Speaker 6:  The, you also got to try the actual Massimo smartwatch at CSS with
Speaker 9:  The features. Yes. So they're calling it the Freedom, which is just like,
Speaker 9:  okay, are you serious? That's a wow. Yes. It's called the Freedom. It's 46
Speaker 9:  millimeters. It's a big chunky boy. And they told me like a bazillion
Speaker 9:  times So, I have to say it, it's an early prototype. It might not look like
Speaker 9:  this when it comes out later this year, but you know, it's
Speaker 9:  kind of the, they, they, they were very much telling me that
Speaker 9:  they're putting out a smart or smartwatch. So this is a smartwatch that's
Speaker 9:  gonna have timers, it's gonna have notifications, it's gonna work with your
Speaker 9:  phone more fluidly, it's gonna have a better app experience. It's gonna have
Speaker 9:  health tracking experiences, which sounds a awful lot like an Apple Watch,
Speaker 9:  right? So they keep telling me that the reason they're putting out this
Speaker 9:  watch is so that it can tout its sensor accuracy because
Speaker 9:  all these companies be out here according to Massimo with
Speaker 9:  sensors that are not accurate, that are not giving you the, the actual
Speaker 9:  results that you can trust. But they're gonna give you the health results
Speaker 9:  that you can trust and it's gonna be smarter. So, you know, you sit there
Speaker 9:  and you're like, so you're trying to kill Apple, right? This is the Apple
Speaker 9:  Watch killer. And they're like, no, this is, this is about us. This is about
Speaker 9:  us and our sensor accuracy. And you know, of course they have to say that,
Speaker 9:  but you just look at this thing and you're like, I see you are coming
Speaker 9:  for the consumer wearable space. And they're not the only medical tech company
Speaker 9:  doing that. You know, at CES I saw Murano. Murano is a medical
Speaker 9:  tech company and they're coming out with a smart ring that has also got,
Speaker 9:  you know, they're in the last stages of FDA clearance for their particular
Speaker 9:  sensors. In the past, I've seen medical tech companies come out with
Speaker 9:  like Omron, they had a blood pressure smartwatch at
Speaker 9:  CES. So it's, it's not the first time that the medical community has been
Speaker 9:  like, we can try hardware, we can make that work. Yeah. But
Speaker 9:  it's, it's just very interesting given the backdrop of the Apple Watch band
Speaker 9:  that massimo's out here and they're like, Hey, we got hardware too.
Speaker 7:  Well, speaking of rings, there was also the big Samsung announced that
Speaker 7:  they're gonna do a smart ring. Now, is it gonna be as cool as, as
Speaker 7:  Aura and Ano and everybody else hopping in the space now?
Speaker 9:  Well the the cool thing about the Galaxy ring is that they were like, hello,
Speaker 9:  we're here. And then there's a ring and it's spinning in space and there's
Speaker 9:  stars on it and it looks gorgeous. And they're like, the
Speaker 8:  Video was sick. Yeah, if you haven't seen the video, you should go watch
Speaker 8:  it. The little like reveal video of it is, is pretty badass.
Speaker 9:  Very cool. And then they're like, and we will give you no details. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  And, and I, you know, and I was looking at that. I was like, okay, but
Speaker 9:  also this is clearly gonna be a sleep tracking or a
Speaker 9:  competitor just because, you know, at CES and I wrote the story
Speaker 9:  at CES, there were a buttload of smart rings, more smart rings than
Speaker 9:  I've ever seen in my life at CES at all different price points
Speaker 9:  at all different like feature sets. So for Samsung to come out here
Speaker 9:  and be like, yeah, we're also getting on the Smart Ring train.
Speaker 9:  I think this is the year of the Smart Ring. I really do. And you know, it's
Speaker 9:  one thing to go to CES and say ano nobody, unless
Speaker 9:  they read my work, nobody knows what ano is.
Speaker 9:  If I say Zep and Amaz Fit or a Maze Fit this budget
Speaker 9:  thing that has basically replaced Fitbit in that, for that market,
Speaker 9:  they're coming out with a smart ring, people are like gonna be like, okay,
Speaker 9:  you wearable nerd. Sure, sure. You're saying
Speaker 6:  No, no, this episode of Virgin Cast, we got Vargo, we got Marano.
Speaker 6:  I want to call out Shelly, it's a DIY smart home company. We're just name,
Speaker 6:  let's just name little companies.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. So you know, like if I say that there's a bunch of small companies
Speaker 9:  out here that are putting out smart rings, this is gonna be a thing. People
Speaker 9:  are gonna be like, okay, v Pat, pat, you know, you're a wearable nerd. Of
Speaker 9:  course you think that's gonna happen. So for Samsung to come out and be like,
Speaker 9:  hi guys, we got a Galaxy ring. I'm just super vindicated
Speaker 9:  in my seat over here just going like, yes. See I told you, I told you
Speaker 9:  smart rings are gonna be a thing. This is a thing that people are really
Speaker 9:  thinking about and it's because there's a huge segment of the population
Speaker 9:  that is really mad that they have to charge their smart Watches
Speaker 9:  if they want sleep tracking. So the obvious answer here is that you
Speaker 9:  have a smart ring, which is gonna be more accurate for that
Speaker 9:  anyway because the bottom of your finger is more accurate for heart rate
Speaker 9:  tracking. It's more accurate for blood oxygen tracking and the battery's
Speaker 9:  gonna last longer than your Galaxy watch that lasts maybe two days if you're
Speaker 9:  really good about battery management. So, I really
Speaker 9:  think that this is their answer to that.
Speaker 6:  Also, just from a market perspective, the wrist has been claimed.
Speaker 6:  Yep. Yes. You cannot replace the thing that's on many people's wrists. So
Speaker 6:  you're like, ah, let's try fingers. Ah,
Speaker 9:  There's that. And I, I am just curious because the one thing
Speaker 9:  at CES that stood out to me was a maze fit with their ring was just like,
Speaker 9:  this is gonna be a standalone, but also it could be a companion
Speaker 9:  wearable for your wearable. So it's gonna work with their smart Watches.
Speaker 9:  And I think if s Samsung really wants to be smart about it, they'll do
Speaker 9:  the same. They'll be like, okay, this is your smart ring and it's gonna work
Speaker 9:  with your smartwatch. We've spent the last two years ready
Speaker 9:  working really, really
Speaker 6:  Hard ready? Can I just tell you on the sleep track? Can my, my, my graph
Speaker 6:  of the wearable success formula, it's just 15 more axes
Speaker 6:  just sprouted off that graph. I was diligent and I
Speaker 6:  didn't, I didn't say anything about the Vision Pro and the graph,
Speaker 6:  but now we're like, we got wearables on top of wearables, the
Speaker 6:  we need exponent in this thing.
Speaker 9:  I'm telling you, this is where we're headed because not everyone wants a
Speaker 9:  wearable that's gonna be, you know, an extension of their phone. Right.
Speaker 9:  A lot of people who are going for the smart ring, they don't want the
Speaker 9:  notifications, they don't want their kind of, I think it's the next evolution
Speaker 9:  of the fitness band, which is like RIP. Yeah, it's gone. The smartwatch has
Speaker 9:  devoured it completely.
Speaker 6:  I'm telling you. So, so the, the, the dorkiness cost is going down the curve
Speaker 6:  see, and then the, the cost cost is low. Smart
Speaker 6:  rings we're up in the upper right depending on how they look and whether
Speaker 6:  or not you have to refer to them as the Galaxy ring, which depending on who
Speaker 6:  you are, either a huge positive or a huge negative
Speaker 9:  From like the, the one person who I saw online who got to see the actual
Speaker 9:  prototype. It's supposedly very light. It supposedly looks nice.
Speaker 9:  We'll see the render. It looks like an aura ring, but yeah, make it
Speaker 9:  Galaxy. So we'll, we'll see. 'cause a lot of people will look at an aura
Speaker 9:  ring and be like, oh that looks really cool. And then other people will be
Speaker 9:  like, that is so chunky. Get it the f away from me.
Speaker 9:  Absolutely not. But you know, on the design front, I think smart
Speaker 9:  rings are starting to evolve a bit. I saw the EV ring. It's very cool. It
Speaker 9:  has a little gap up top. So when you're bloated and you can't
Speaker 9:  get your ring off, it can still come off. That's I'm just saying Samsung,
Speaker 9:  that's right out there. You can copy that and make the Galaxy ring next
Speaker 9:  level. So
Speaker 6:  Well that's the Galaxy ring to powered by ai. Alright, speaking of AI and
Speaker 6:  Galaxy S, we gotta let you go. We gotta take a break. We found way
Speaker 6:  over in the first segment. That's how we're doing today. bvi, thank you so
Speaker 6:  much for coming on. We're gonna take a break. We're gonna be back and talk
Speaker 6:  about the rest of Galaxy unpacked and the S3 four. We'll be right back.
Speaker 12:  Something strange is happening in Hollywood. I'm not talking
Speaker 12:  about that guy that got to host the Golden Globe. Yo, I got
Speaker 6:  The
Speaker 12:  Gig 10 days ago. I'm talking about the secret musicals.
Speaker 6:  What was that? The lord? It's the Queen Bee Regina George. Don't look her
Speaker 6:  in the eye.
Speaker 13:  You could be really hot if we change like everything.
Speaker 12:  A new Mean Girls movie comes out today. It promises it is not your
Speaker 12:  Mother's Mean Girls, which rude. But also what does that mean?
Speaker 12:  The trailer never tells you. But check out this footage from a recent screening
Speaker 12:  that audience groaning when not Lindsay Lowen, Katie
Speaker 12:  Heron starts singing. They're bummed because they didn't want a musical,
Speaker 12:  they didn't necessarily know they were getting a musical, but they got
Speaker 12:  a musical. And it's not just Mean Girls Why Hollywood
Speaker 12:  is hiding its musicals this week on Today Explained.
Speaker 6:  All right, we're back. There's more Samsung to talk about. You. ready?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I'm ready. Phones.
Speaker 6:  Phones. So it's fascinating that Samsung chose to do the Galaxy event
Speaker 6:  a week after CES.
Speaker 7:  I is
Speaker 6:  It, it's fascinating. Google showed up at the Samsung event more
Speaker 6:  assertively, I guess more loudly than they did at cs. Yep.
Speaker 7:  Yes, that's true.
Speaker 6:  Just quite a lot of dynamics there, right? Yeah. Samsung can attract a bunch
Speaker 6:  of attention without css, so it makes sense, but it, Google put a lot of
Speaker 6:  its AI features in the S 24 this year, which is really interesting.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Empowered by the Google Gemini, right? Like the, the the large language
Speaker 7:  model that a lot of the generative stuff is gonna be doing is Google Gemini,
Speaker 7:  which I don't think is surprising. I know some people were like, why wasn't
Speaker 7:  it chat GPT or, or Microsoft, whatever Microsoft is doing, and it
Speaker 7:  makes sense, Google makes Android, they work closely together.
Speaker 7:  Why wouldn't they use the people who are already doing this stuff in their
Speaker 7:  own phones?
Speaker 8:  Google and Samsung also desperately need each other to compete with Apple.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Like neither, neither one of them can beat Apple on their
Speaker 8:  own. They've both tried and both have failed and
Speaker 8:  the way to do it is together and it's working pretty well. But
Speaker 8:  my big takeaway from this event is I am super, super bearish on
Speaker 8:  the future of the Pixel now. Yes, same Google clearly
Speaker 8:  believes Samsung's phones are the flagship Android phones now
Speaker 8:  and that it should treat them as such. That,
Speaker 7:  That was my vibe too.
Speaker 6:  I just wanna point out that Samsung strikes so little fear into
Speaker 6:  Apple's heart that Tim Cook refuses to pronounce the name Samsung
Speaker 6:  correctly.
Speaker 7:  What, what does he
Speaker 6:  Say? He says Samsung every time. Every time. And
Speaker 6:  I can't tell if it's, it's a diss. I can't tell if he just doesn't know.
Speaker 6:  I, it's just go listen to him say it sometime.
Speaker 7:  That's a
Speaker 6:  Diss. Tizen has caused no fear in this man's brain like
Speaker 6:  that you can do the EEG and you're like, Tizen and nothing lights up.
Speaker 7:  He's like, Tizin.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. That's like, that's like a a a, an older southern person does. They
Speaker 7:  always like to be like, oh I just forgot the name. Is that how you're supposed
Speaker 7:  to pronounce it? And they never, they refuse to learn.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's very good. Yeah. Anyway. But I agree with you David, is that's
Speaker 6:  my way of saying I agree with you. Like it needs to be the combo platter.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. And I think Apple, there's a lot, you know, between Apple and
Speaker 6:  Google and the search deal and all this stuff, but on their own, I think
Speaker 6:  Apple's like what And that's, they, they are both still very reactive to
Speaker 6:  Apple in that particular way. But we should talk about the S 24 'cause it
Speaker 6:  is meaningfully ahead of the iPhone in certain ways. Yeah. Alex
Speaker 8:  And this will almost certainly be the Android phone of 2024. Right, right.
Speaker 8:  Like it's wild to say that the second week of January, but I think we can
Speaker 8:  fairly,
Speaker 6:  This will be the benchmark, at least the United States. This will be the
Speaker 6:  benchmark. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. 'cause they don't, they don't do the note, like the note isn't kind
Speaker 7:  of the big landmark anymore for them. It is, it is this S series. And so
Speaker 7:  we got the S 24, which is continues to be kind of the smallest one.
Speaker 7:  It's small, it's 6.2 inch display, like that's
Speaker 7:  enormous. But, and then there's the S 24 plus, which is
Speaker 7:  6.7 inch display and then the S 24 Ultra,
Speaker 7:  which can't have the same size display. So it is
Speaker 7:  6.8 inches. Way bigger. Just, just yeah,
Speaker 7:  just a tiny, tiny bit bigger. Same with the batteries. Like the S 24 is like
Speaker 7:  a 4,000 milliamp battery. And you're like, okay cool. And the S 24 plus is
Speaker 7:  4,900. Cool. And then just a little bit
Speaker 7:  bigger, the S 24 ultras at 5,000
Speaker 7:  and, and big, big cameras here. Like I'm, I'm curious for you guys, you guys
Speaker 7:  geek out, you in particular DLI geek out about these cameras a lot more than
Speaker 7:  I do. The, the backside of the S 24 and the S 24 plus
Speaker 7:  is both a 50 mega sal wide camera
Speaker 7:  with a 12 megapixel Ultra wide and a 10 megapixel
Speaker 7:  three x optical zoom and the 30 x space zoom. So you're getting kinda the
Speaker 7:  same camera package in both of those. And then the S 24 Ultra
Speaker 7:  is totally, it feels totally different. It's a 200 megapixel wide,
Speaker 7:  same Ultra wide, same tele zoomo, but then a 50
Speaker 7:  megapixel tele five x zoom instead of the space zoom. Which
Speaker 7:  like that feels cool.
Speaker 8:  And that's the one, so one of the things that Samsung said about that Zoom
Speaker 8:  camera is that because they took it from the S
Speaker 8:  23 Ultra, which had a 10 x zoom, they actually took it down to five. But
Speaker 8:  because they upped the resolution so much, what Samsung claimed, at least
Speaker 8:  to Alison Johnson on our team is that you'll get more image quality at 10
Speaker 8:  x zoom just because you have so many more pixels to play with. even that
Speaker 8:  you're doing digital cropping and digital zoom is not a
Speaker 8:  thing, it's just cropping your photos and
Speaker 8:  everyone should know that. But the, the thesis at least is that you're still
Speaker 8:  getting higher image quality just because it's capturing so much more light
Speaker 8:  in the 50 megapixel sensor. So I think that the math of that is
Speaker 8:  fascinating and I'm really curious to see how that stacks up in reviews.
Speaker 8:  But the cameras are nuts.
Speaker 6:  So, I think there's the math and there's also just the caution
Speaker 6:  to the wind AI processing that Samsung is doing. Sure.
Speaker 6:  Like why will those photos look good? Because Samsung's like, make 'em look
Speaker 6:  good and the AI's like your wish is my command. Here's some shit I made up.
Speaker 6:  What is a photo?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Moon's everywhere
Speaker 6:  We're,
Speaker 8:  This took longer than I expected, honestly.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I was really impressed with Eli. I was like, I should have like a little
Speaker 7:  clock time here.
Speaker 6:  Well, we'll come back to that. 'cause there there's one particular, what
Speaker 6:  is a photo rabbit hole that we should fall down? But there's there's a bunch
Speaker 6:  of other AI stuff here going on.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, yeah. There is like
Speaker 6:  Google powered AI stuff.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. There's a ton of stuff. Like they're, they're going all in on translation,
Speaker 7:  which was for the longest time. That was a really cool Pixel feature was
Speaker 7:  that you could kind of translate things on the fly and, and transcribe things
Speaker 7:  as well. And, and that's coming to, to the Samsung, the S 24
Speaker 7:  lineup. And then on like the image side of things, there's a lot
Speaker 7:  of photo editing that you're gonna be able to do. Now you're, you can just
Speaker 7:  like circle something and it should get rid of it. Kind of that Photoshop
Speaker 7:  demo we see all the time now on the S 24, which is
Speaker 7:  both cool and hilarious 'cause people were like using it to circle out like
Speaker 7:  watermarks.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Samsung's own attempt to make, you know, things are AI copyright or
Speaker 6:  AI generated was to put a watermark and then you can tell the AI to remove
Speaker 6:  the watermark. It's
Speaker 7:  Beautiful. Perfect. No, no, it's beautiful.
Speaker 7:  Those were like the kind things that I was particularly excited about just
Speaker 7:  because I love to not have to open Photoshop anymore. The
Speaker 7:  the, the longer I can go without opening it, the better for me.
Speaker 8:  I will say the one that really got me was the idea of being able to make
Speaker 8:  a 120 frames per second slow motion video out of anything.
Speaker 6:  This is the rabbit hole.
Speaker 8:  It was this your rabbit hole. This is the rabbit hole. Oh, I thought the
Speaker 8:  rabbit hole was gonna be the thing where you can, you can move the horizon
Speaker 8:  on a photo and it'll fill the edges instead of having to crop the edges.
Speaker 8:  When you take your, like you take a rectangular photo and you turn it a little
Speaker 8:  to correct the horizon, you're gonna have these empty spaces in the corners.
Speaker 8:  The S 24 will generatively fill those corners to
Speaker 8:  make it still feel like a rectangle. Yeah. But
Speaker 7:  I can do that in Photoshop. Like I definitely never, ever done
Speaker 7:  that in Photoshop.
Speaker 8:  Alex we have had the, can you do this in Photoshop and does that negate all
Speaker 8:  of this argument? Yes. So many times, and I'm bringing it back and I think
Speaker 8:  that it does, but we have to let NELI have this
Speaker 6:  No filling in the edges. Like whatever, because the edges are usually not
Speaker 6:  the subject of your photo. Right. So like, am I lying about
Speaker 6:  whether there's a little bit more water there? Maybe
Speaker 6:  I'm lying, maybe who cares? Right? Like it's
Speaker 7:  A little more all, what
Speaker 8:  Is it? This is so much more like blase than you were about the Pixel
Speaker 8:  eight.
Speaker 6:  I've been beaten down, man, I
Speaker 8:  Can move someone over on a bench. That's outrageous. But there's more water
Speaker 8:  over there. Yes.
Speaker 6:  They keep, they keep moving The light are levels of outrage. I'm, this is
Speaker 6:  nuance real time nuance is being developed also. That's so boring.
Speaker 6:  I do think that's not a photo. It's just not I trying to gin someone up
Speaker 6:  into an outrage cycle over, there's a little more water even. I can't
Speaker 6:  do that. But all right.
Speaker 7:  The a hundred frames per
Speaker 6:  Second, I, I took 50 frames and I made all the people look at me in a way
Speaker 6:  that never happened. It's still dangerous territory to me. Yeah. The
Speaker 6:  the Ultra slow motion. The most dangerous territory.
Speaker 6:  Because now this thing is generating entire frames that
Speaker 6:  never happened. Right. Entire frames and
Speaker 6:  creating a video, a slow motion video, which people are more
Speaker 6:  attuned to thinking is real than any. Watch this back in slow motion, let's
Speaker 6:  see what really happened. And every other frame is a lie.
Speaker 6:  Right? If you, if you go from 30 frames a second to
Speaker 6:  120 frame slow motion over the same duration, boy that's, that's
Speaker 6:  a lot of frames that never happened. And, and Samsung's
Speaker 6:  like, yeah, we put a watermark on it and then you can be like, yeah, I get
Speaker 6:  rid of the watermark. It goes away. Like this is,
Speaker 6:  when I say this is the, what is a photo apocalypse? Like this is more apocalyptic.
Speaker 6:  What is a photo shit?
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna throw a wrench in this because the TV companies weren't they already
Speaker 7:  doing a lot of this already? Yeah.
Speaker 8:  This is just what interpolation is. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Just making up frames and sticking them in there. Only it's now the people
Speaker 7:  who are like, we're gonna invent the moon. Well
Speaker 6:  Wait, wait, it, it really depends. Like there's a lot, there's a lot of different
Speaker 6:  ways TV companies have done this. The dumbest way they've done it is like
Speaker 6:  three, two pull downs where you have a refresh rate on a TV of 60 hertz whatever,
Speaker 6:  and you're throwing 24 frames per second content up there and you just double
Speaker 6:  the frames. Right? Right. You do three frames of something, then two frames,
Speaker 6:  that's a three, two pull down. Like that's fine. You're just showing sort
Speaker 6:  of double the frames to match your refresh rate. Then there's a little bit
Speaker 6:  of the AI upscaling that is occurring on TVs right now.
Speaker 6:  Fine. That's weird. But there, like,
Speaker 6:  there's something else happening there that is not this thing
Speaker 6:  where you're like, I am gonna capture this video or I'm gonna insert any
Speaker 6:  video into this editor and it will now create a slow motion video.
Speaker 6:  It will actually generate outside of real time other frames.
Speaker 6:  Whereas a TV is like, I'm gonna play back this video to you and
Speaker 6:  in real time and an ephemeral way, I will throw away this data when I'm done
Speaker 6:  with it. Create new detail or create frames in the middle. Like there are
Speaker 6:  very few TVs in the market today. None I think that
Speaker 6:  you can just feed a video signal to, and it will create a slow motion video
Speaker 6:  and claim that that is a correct slow signal.
Speaker 7:  So is the difference for you. One goes real fast and one goes real slow.
Speaker 6:  The difference for me is this thing generates files that you can then pass
Speaker 6:  around. Okay. As information. Whereas a TV is just doing
Speaker 6:  dis different display tricks.
Speaker 8:  In theory, if you scroll frame by frame through one of these 120 frames or
Speaker 8:  second videos, you will land on a series of frames that never
Speaker 8:  existed in the world. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You will land on a series of moments that are entirely generated.
Speaker 6:  Right. And you will not be able to trust those moments.
Speaker 8:  And that trips over some line that like, it takes
Speaker 8:  the eyes from this photo and the eyes from this photo and the eyes from this
Speaker 8:  photo and puts them all into one photo because that's where all the eyes
Speaker 8:  looked best. Like that at least is those pixels were real and
Speaker 8:  captured and existed in the world. Putting them together is one thing,
Speaker 8:  but with this, you're actually creating something no Pixel of which
Speaker 8:  was captured in the real world.
Speaker 6:  Yes. 0% of those pixels that were captured. I'll just give, I I,
Speaker 6:  I'll give you an example. It's the NFL playoffs.
Speaker 6:  Was it a catch? Right? Like, here's a real thing that like people argue about
Speaker 6:  all the time. What is this a catch and what do we do? We crop in, we slow
Speaker 6:  motion and now we're like, we're gonna let a computer
Speaker 6:  decide whether that ball hit the ground somewhere in the middle and
Speaker 8:  It's gonna have to guess where a football went, which is not following a
Speaker 8:  normal trajectory. I feel like
Speaker 7:  That's not gonna happen.
Speaker 6:  Why not? Wait, I'm sorry. If you, if football fans are gonna like,
Speaker 6:  like literally on the
Speaker 7:  Football plans, it's
Speaker 8:  Not convinced until you said that example.
Speaker 6:  Now they're gonna hold up there in Samsung phones to the tv, capture the
Speaker 6:  video of the replay and say, make this slower. And they're gonna post that
Speaker 6:  to wherever and argue about a bunch of fake images.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But
Speaker 6:  Aren't they literally fake images
Speaker 7:  Also? But there's gonna be a ref who's gonna have a very fancy camera
Speaker 7:  who would be like,
Speaker 6:  That's wrong there. Those refs
Speaker 7:  Are not too trust. Do I trust refs too much?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That's like just one example. I'll just, it's the lowest stakes example.
Speaker 6:  Although given the prevalence of sports betting also a very high stakes
Speaker 6:  example. Right now America, that's just one thing. It's an election
Speaker 6:  year, right? What if don don't know, Trump stumbles over some stairs or Biden
Speaker 6:  stumbles over some stairs or appears to stumble over some stairs and a bunch
Speaker 6:  of people on either side want to take video of that and then create a bunch
Speaker 6:  of fake frames. Or it looks like they stumbled more than they did, or they
Speaker 6:  slow it down. And as we know, things in slow motion appear way more dramatic
Speaker 6:  than real time. And you send that out and now you have a slow motion video.
Speaker 6:  Many of the frames of which never happened. Like
Speaker 6:  that is the apocalypse. 'cause people are inclined to trust
Speaker 6:  slow motion video to say what really happened. And here
Speaker 6:  there's nothing, there's no, all the stuff we've heard about content, authenticity,
Speaker 6:  all the whatever, Samsung's like, whatever, you can just do it.
Speaker 6:  No watermarks, no cryptographic signature, none of this other stuff. Like
Speaker 6:  it's just, here's some AI stuff and it just had like heatless
Speaker 6:  and what I keep saying, the what, what is a photo apocalypses here? It's
Speaker 6:  like, oh, it's this stuff. Yeah. Where actually the end state is no
Speaker 6:  one trusts any media because they all know how easy it is to generate anything.
Speaker 6:  And then now you're, that's a really weird place to end up.
Speaker 8:  We're getting there really fast. I see. I think too, I've, I've, I've just
Speaker 8:  consistently been amazed by how quickly just in my own life
Speaker 8:  people are adopting that sort of reflexive skepticism of like, oh, this
Speaker 8:  is a picture. It's probably fake. It's like the burden of proof is now
Speaker 8:  like proof that it's real, not proof that it's fake. It's very strange.
Speaker 6:  Right. This is a deep fake. Yeah. This is just a, people argue all the time,
Speaker 7:  It feels bad, but also at the same time, if it means we never have to see
Speaker 7:  the shark swimming in the highway water ever again. Like, oh,
Speaker 6:  You will. Oh yeah. It's not that people aren't just gonna hit like on social
Speaker 6:  media or there won't be grifters. Like Yeah. If we could get to a place
Speaker 6:  of pure skepticism where that stuff faded fine, but this
Speaker 6:  stuff is already out there. I'll give you an example. In during the
Speaker 6:  Kyle Rittenhouse trial, which was in Wisconsin, So I paid attention to it.
Speaker 6:  Kyle Rittenhouse, his lawyers argued that some of the photographic evidence
Speaker 6:  could not be used because the iPhone
Speaker 6:  has AI in it. Right. We co I think we covered this on the show and they,
Speaker 6:  they won like the, you know, the, the local prosecutors in Kenosha, Wisconsin
Speaker 6:  were not ready for that argument. Surprise, surprise. And they were just
Speaker 6:  like, yeah, we're gonna exclude this evidence because we're not ready to
Speaker 6:  have a bunch of experts come in here and say, what is a photo? That's years
Speaker 6:  ago, this happened years ago, and now we have
Speaker 6:  Samsung phones that can take any video and
Speaker 6:  interpolate frames that never happened. What are you
Speaker 6:  gonna do when that stuff hits a courtroom? What are you gonna do when that
Speaker 6:  stuff, when there, when there is like dramatic amounts of money
Speaker 6:  in sports books on the line and you want to claim that the refs are
Speaker 6:  rigged. Like there, there's no responsibility here. Like
Speaker 6:  we are just past the point of no return with what is a photo. Because the
Speaker 6:  answer for a Samsung video is like, these are not, these are not videos that
Speaker 6:  you can trust.
Speaker 8:  Right? No, no. I I think you're right. And I, I do think we're pretty clearly
Speaker 8:  past the point of no return on this. And I think we
Speaker 8:  have to figure out what the next thing is, right? Whether it's a watermark,
Speaker 8:  whether it's the cryptographic stuff you're talking about, like we've been
Speaker 8:  threatening to do the metadata episode for forever and like that's the thing
Speaker 8:  because it, it we're, we're long past the
Speaker 8:  thing where you can
Speaker 8:  straightforwardly trust every single thing that you capture just because
Speaker 8:  it's light projecting onto sensors. Right. Like, we've been past that for
Speaker 8:  a long time. And I think I I, this strikes me as
Speaker 8:  I, like I take your point about the football example, which I actually think
Speaker 8:  is a really good one. Like a ball is moving unpredictably,
Speaker 8:  literally the camera is going to guess where it went and it's gonna get
Speaker 8:  it wrong sometimes. And that's bananas. But I
Speaker 8:  don't know, this doesn't strike me as like an entirely new field of
Speaker 8:  scary stuff in this way.
Speaker 7:  I kind of agree with NELI in that it does feel like the, the,
Speaker 7:  the bar has been raised on like this or lowered the bar
Speaker 7:  has moved significantly in one direction or another, depending on,
Speaker 7:  on your point of view in that it's a, it's now so, so much easier
Speaker 7:  to make fake stuff with your phone. Like, like this phone, the S
Speaker 7:  24 Sure. Has put Photoshop in your pocket in a way that wasn't there
Speaker 7:  before. And Photoshop has often been like that. That's been a massive tool
Speaker 7:  for misinformation since, since it's inception. And, and now
Speaker 7:  anybody can go and they can circle something and get rid of it or they can
Speaker 7:  film something and have a computer decide which way the ball goes.
Speaker 7:  And that just wasn't possible before this. So it's like
Speaker 7:  really cool stuff. I'm really excited about it from like a personal
Speaker 7:  perspective as someone who likes to make stupid things horrified
Speaker 7:  for it on like a societal
Speaker 8:  Level. Yeah. I also think one of the, one of the debates we had around the
Speaker 8:  Pixel was there where the sort of ease threshold is. Yeah. 'cause I think,
Speaker 8:  and this is where the Photoshop thing comes in, right? Just because you can
Speaker 8:  do complicated things in Photoshop, it changes it when it
Speaker 8:  is just a button you can press in the camera app on your phone. I think we
Speaker 8:  all agree on that. Yeah. And the thing about this one is it's, it's gonna
Speaker 8:  be just complicated enough to do what you're describing NELI. That I think
Speaker 8:  that might be the reason it bothers me less is like, not only do you have
Speaker 8:  to shoot this video, you're gonna then have to run it through
Speaker 8:  this process to get you the 120 frames per second thing. You're gonna have
Speaker 8:  to find a frame that looks good that was generated, which it usually won't.
Speaker 8:  'cause if you shoot something at 120 fan for a second, each individual frame
Speaker 8:  usually kind of looks like shit. And then you're gonna have to take that
Speaker 8:  thing, isolate it out, and then go do something with it. And that, that to
Speaker 8:  me is like more steps than the pick somebody up off a bench and move them
Speaker 8:  over there. That that second thing actually alarms me
Speaker 8:  more just because it is so simple and straightforward to do that people
Speaker 8:  will do it and a lot.
Speaker 7:  But that's spoken from someone who probably doesn't have like a thousand
Speaker 7:  dollars writing on the next Green Bay Packers game.
Speaker 6:  I don't, I don't gamble. I spend all my money on, on limousines. You know,
Speaker 6:  there's
Speaker 7:  People out there is
Speaker 6:  Much better use of money
Speaker 7:  Who Who knows who those folks are. But, but there is like, like I think the
Speaker 7:  incentives are low enough probably gonna be a low enough for a lot of folk
Speaker 7:  or high enough for a lot of folks that that little extra effort isn't gonna
Speaker 7:  be as big an impact for them. And we're seeing the same thing with DeepFakes,
Speaker 7:  right? Like DeepFakes were something that we kind of could be like whatever.
Speaker 7:  It's it's, it's hard to do and it's gotten so much easier to do a
Speaker 7:  deep fake now Oh yeah. To do a really good one. That, that that misinformation
Speaker 7:  potential has really skyrocketed. And it feels like the S 24
Speaker 7:  brings us to that place in a beautiful package brought to you by
Speaker 7:  Samsung. That was my Tim Cook impression.
Speaker 8:  That's good. That's gonna work. Yeah. Samsung, I think you have to hit song
Speaker 8:  harder. Samsung.
Speaker 7:  Sorry, Samsung I listen. It's like people
Speaker 8:  Who say say tv,
Speaker 6:  I'm just telling you go listen to it.
Speaker 6:  Other little bits and bobs, AI wise of the S 24 line,
Speaker 6:  Google is bringing a bunch of Gemini model stuff to it. You can have circle
Speaker 6:  stuff to search on the phone, which is finally,
Speaker 6:  finally used for circling.
Speaker 7:  I love that It called Allison out. Like she tried to get,
Speaker 7:  she tried to like cheat it. She's like, aha, try a picture of like
Speaker 7:  this fake plant. You're gonna tell me it's real. And it's like, that's a
Speaker 7:  fake plant. It costs $9. And she's like, rude
Speaker 8:  Dude. Google lens is really good. Yeah. Like it's, it's a remarkable
Speaker 8:  part of Google search that I feel like doesn't get talked about as, as an
Speaker 8:  AI product in the way that it should. It's really good now. And they now
Speaker 8:  have the multi search stuff where you can take a picture and then ask a question
Speaker 8:  about that picture and it'll like the, the example they gave is like, you
Speaker 8:  take a picture of a backgammon board and say, how do I play this game? And
Speaker 8:  it'll figure out that it's backgammon and then use Gemini to tell you how
Speaker 8:  to play backgammon. That stuff is cool.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And that's real like future of search stuff. And that's where all, so the
Speaker 8:  circle search comes in, you're like, oh, I see this bag in a video that seems
Speaker 8:  cool. Circle the bag, send it to Google, buy the bag. What's
Speaker 6:  Interesting to me, all the generative AI stuff here is either image
Speaker 6:  editing, which comes with its own obvious philosophical dilemmas or
Speaker 6:  it's like
Speaker 6:  sort of LLM stuff, right? Like search for something. It'll talk to you about
Speaker 6:  it. You can, there's Magic compose and all this stuff in here. The middle
Speaker 6:  piece that Samsung was kind of reaching for with Bixby
Speaker 6:  is not here. Right. Which is what we saw with the rabbit R one at
Speaker 6:  css where it's like you tell your phone to do something and it just like
Speaker 6:  does it, and if you will recall
Speaker 6:  Samsung's attempted differentiation with Bixby, its voice
Speaker 6:  assistant whose name sounded like a dog wearing shoes was that you would
Speaker 6:  be like, set some settings and Bixby would go like set some settings for
Speaker 6:  you in a way that Siri and Google Assistant kind of can't. And it's, it's
Speaker 6:  striking to me they have not closed this loop on that phone. 'cause that's
Speaker 6:  what you would expect because
Speaker 7:  We saw it wasn't just Rabbit. We saw this with like, a lot of the TV companies
Speaker 7:  were like, we've got AI in our tv. Oh really? What does it do? It makes your,
Speaker 7:  your picture prettier. Right. Figures figures it out. And so you'd think
Speaker 7:  Samsung would do this. And I I I'm kind of like, is there, is there something
Speaker 7:  happening with Google and the relationship with Google that's like kind of
Speaker 7:  restricting that? Or is it just they haven't gotten there yet?
Speaker 8:  I think it's just harder work than people reckoned with. Like the, the idea
Speaker 8:  that I could tell my phone to
Speaker 8:  whatever turn on Bluetooth doesn't seem that hard. but it is
Speaker 8:  actually, it's, it's a Leap beyond just understanding what Bluetooth is,
Speaker 8:  right? You have to have a different kind of access to my system and a different
Speaker 8:  kind of access to the tools and the stuff that I actually wanna do.
Speaker 8:  And this was the problem with a lot of these things that, that have come
Speaker 8:  out first, the tech sucked, but Right. Like they had it built in the right
Speaker 8:  direction, but it wasn't very good. And now we have LLMs, which are much
Speaker 8:  better at understanding what you mean, but are
Speaker 8:  not connected to the metal in the same way. And I think the, the
Speaker 8:  next phase of this is to put those two things together, right? Like yeah,
Speaker 8:  Google has made a lot of noise, noise about Gemini being built into Android
Speaker 8:  more and more over time. And I'm, I'm sure that's coming. But right now
Speaker 8:  Gemini is like built into Google photos more than it is built into
Speaker 8:  Android. And so the next phase of that is to just pull it down a level in
Speaker 8:  the stack. But that's just, it's harder work than it seems like it ought
Speaker 8:  to be. but it is sort of surprising that no one has really gotten there yet.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I just haven't closed the loop. It's like, I need, I want you to
Speaker 6:  play this song and it's gonna like click around in Spotify for you. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  This is the device where that actually makes sense. The rabbit I think captured
Speaker 6:  a lot of imagination, but that's still what it is doing.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And So
Speaker 7:  I got a clicky wheel,
Speaker 6:  Right? What if I just still had my big screen in great camera and it could
Speaker 6:  still do that for me? Yeah. I'm eager to see that we're closed. Okay. We
Speaker 6:  should take a break. We are just way over. We just, it's
Speaker 6:  just ridiculous. Show this week we're gonna take a break. We're gonna come
Speaker 6:  back with the lightning round and then we're gonna go for another, another
Speaker 6:  hour or so. We'll be, actually be great.
Speaker 8:  We
Speaker 6:  All right. We're back. It's time for a lightning round. I'll tell you
Speaker 6:  sme, the obscure refrigerator company that Cranz called out last week
Speaker 6:  did not sponsor us this week. So now upsetting. We're just gonna name some
Speaker 6:  other companies as we go.
Speaker 7:  I'm going all in on Iowa, which was like a stereo company.
Speaker 7:  Oh, I like that. I didn't know they were around anymore.
Speaker 6:  That was, that's the Sony Subbrand. Yeah, they did. They get spun off.
Speaker 7:  I don't know if they spun off, but they were, they had a big presence at
Speaker 7:  CES and Liam and I both were like, they're still around. That was my first
Speaker 7:  stereo. It was a big moment for us. Call
Speaker 6:  Sony. Well I've now clicked on a button labeled Iowa Legacy.
Speaker 6:  Oh, they spun off from Sony. Literally when you click on Iowa Legacy
Speaker 6:  it says our company has no association with Sony Corporation.
Speaker 7:  Well that, so so you guys like, come on, get your name out there.
Speaker 7:  Hit us up. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Lightning round. Sponsored by Could be you Iowa, very
Speaker 6:  precious about, you know, disclosures and all that sort of thing. This I
Speaker 6:  will sell
Speaker 8:  Except in the lightning
Speaker 6:  Round. Except in the lightning round. We will sell it to anyone first come,
Speaker 6:  first served. All right, Cranz, what's your lightning round?
Speaker 7:  So CNN is had a major restructuring this week and normally
Speaker 7:  that doesn't feel like a Vergecast thing, but a lot of this, this
Speaker 7:  restructuring was because they realized people use their phones a lot and
Speaker 7:  they're not watching cable TV as much and that's a virgie thing. So
Speaker 7:  they are combining all the different news apparatuses or news
Speaker 7:  operations. So that means their digital operation, their TV
Speaker 7:  operation and their so, or their streaming operation are all gonna be
Speaker 7:  combined into one big mega operation. And then they're gonna have a spinoff
Speaker 7:  of like, what are the other places we can advance ourselves? And also
Speaker 7:  we gotta figure out the phone. That seems really important.
Speaker 6:  You should put CNN on phones. It's pretty good. It's
Speaker 8:  Just bundling and unbundling ma Yeah. Bundling. Bundling. Giving a few years
Speaker 8:  in every newsroom is gonna start to be like, we need specific teams for each
Speaker 8:  of these. What's our Vision Pro strategy? Like that's, we're it's, we're
Speaker 8:  headed back down that road before too long. I'm I'm sure of it.
Speaker 6:  So there, there's some context here. One reason that CNN is always a ver
Speaker 6:  story is that the modern CNN is owned by Warner Brothers Discovery, a company
Speaker 6:  that came into existence from the merger of Warner Brothers in Discovery,
Speaker 6:  surprise Warner Brothers sold to Discovery by at and
Speaker 6:  TA company that used to own CNN
Speaker 6:  That was cool.
Speaker 7:  They could have had it on the phones.
Speaker 6:  They could at and t bought all of Warner Brothers in a Pitch
Speaker 6:  that they described as quote a vision deal. And the vision was
Speaker 6:  that they would preload garbage Warner Brothers apps into mid range
Speaker 6:  Android phones in at and t stores. This is true. I'm not making
Speaker 6:  this up. Yeah. Anyway, they sold it to, they sold, they
Speaker 6:  got conned into making a grayscale four three Justice League by Zach
Speaker 6:  Snyder. They, they sold the whole kitten caboodle to, to discovery.
Speaker 6:  Who installed this guy, Chris Licked, who was supposed
Speaker 6:  to revitalize CNNI would say that was a disaster. But now they
Speaker 6:  have a new guy, Mark Thompson, who used to be the CEO of the New York Times.
Speaker 6:  He led the big digital transformation there. He hired another executive from
Speaker 6:  The Times and they're going to, now they're going figure out phones.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's, it's not like super encouraging that in his memo
Speaker 7:  announcing this big restructuring and, and their, their need to focus on
Speaker 7:  phones was, he said, I don't think anyone's yet cracked the code on how that
Speaker 7:  translates truly translates to a new, to a great news
Speaker 7:  experience. That's not kind of what you wanna hear from the guy who's like,
Speaker 7:  we're gonna fix things with phones. But he, he seems to also recognize that
Speaker 7:  he hasn't figured it out yet and he's working on it. So Don
Speaker 7:  don't know. I like the honesty. I appreciate the honesty personally.
Speaker 7:  So I, I'm excited. Like given what he did with the New York Times app,
Speaker 7:  that's, that's honestly one of my favorite apps that I use on my phone pretty
Speaker 7:  much daily. I I'm, I'm willing to, to see what happens. I'm,
Speaker 7:  I'm curious.
Speaker 8:  C CNN is weird because CNN is on one hand
Speaker 8:  wildly successful digitally like cnn.com. However big you
Speaker 8:  think it is, it's much bigger than that. Yeah. cnn.com is huge.
Speaker 8:  Yep. but it doesn't feel sort of crucial
Speaker 8:  in the way that some other news sources feel crucial. Like the New York Times
Speaker 8:  has done a really good job of making itself like central to the universe.
Speaker 8:  And I think if I'm Mark Thompson, that's probably
Speaker 6:  What's Wait what's that? They, they don't need to know that you feel that
Speaker 6:  way. Alright. They're fine, they're doing fine. Their own people do the
Speaker 6:  crossword every day their own.
Speaker 8:  But, and I think the idea that they feel like no one has cracked
Speaker 8:  mobile devices is really interesting. 'cause I also kind of feel like that's
Speaker 8:  true. Everybody just built apps and you can have good apps and push notifications
Speaker 8:  are the best thing anybody has found to get people in. But like I now
Speaker 8:  get a push notification from the New York Times every time anyone on Earth
Speaker 8:  dies it feels like. Yeah. And the, we're just in this weird place
Speaker 8:  of like, what is the push, what is the pull, what is the experience supposed
Speaker 8:  to look like? Is it just a list of articles whenever I open the app, like
Speaker 8:  I think it's cool that they're coming at this from the idea that no
Speaker 8:  one has solved this and the answer is not just like send more push notifications
Speaker 8:  so people open our app more often. don don't know what the answer is either.
Speaker 8:  But I think it'll be fun to watch.
Speaker 7:  I mean if they improve on what AP News does where it te sends you a push
Speaker 7:  notification and then you click on it and then they're like, we don't have
Speaker 7:  a story up yet. Here's our front page. Oh perfect. My favorite
Speaker 7:  experience with a push notification for news, I'll be happy. Like
Speaker 7:  the bar is kind of low. I I think if they put a some
Speaker 7:  thought into it and do something cool.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And especially CNN has gone through this weird thing where there was
Speaker 8:  CNN plus where they were gonna do a whole streaming service that died immediately
Speaker 8:  when the Warner Brothers Discovery thing happened. What was it? Was it
Speaker 8:  around for like a
Speaker 7:  Couple of weeks? It was around for a week, right? It was a week. Okay. It
Speaker 7:  was like a week and then it got Zv was like this is stupid and got rid of
Speaker 7:  it. And then now there's CNN max, which is on max
Speaker 7:  the streaming channel and it has all the things that, whereas
Speaker 7:  CNN plus was like, we think you'll really like the CNN brand and we're not
Speaker 7:  gonna carry anything over from
Speaker 8:  The channel. Jake Tapper had a book club on CNN Plus like Sure. Right. I
Speaker 8:  don't think that was gonna work, but I wish we had gotten to see a little
Speaker 8:  bit more of it Play out.
Speaker 7:  Yes. CNN max is like, we're just gonna put like CNN
Speaker 7:  on your TV and I appreciate that as someone who cuts the
Speaker 7:  cords
Speaker 8:  Good. But I think the idea of like, we're just gonna stream a cable channel
Speaker 8:  to your phone and that'll do it is also not the answer. Right. And I think
Speaker 8:  every content company is going to have to come up with some version of that
Speaker 8:  answer and they're having to do it very quickly. So I, think it's TikTok,
Speaker 8:  CNN coming at this from like, we are a gigantic digital presence. How do
Speaker 8:  we turn that into TV money? It's gonna be really interesting
Speaker 8:  and I have no idea what it looks like.
Speaker 7:  Same. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Alright. David, what's your lightning round?
Speaker 8:  Mine is, so Apple and Epic have been fighting for a
Speaker 8:  very long time. The Supreme Court just declined to hear it. I promise we're
Speaker 8:  not gonna talk about this for a long time. So basically what happened is
Speaker 8:  that, that for all intents and purposes is now over
Speaker 8:  Apple has to allow developers to link to other places
Speaker 8:  that people can pay for apps. But what Apple did is put in rules
Speaker 8:  that say, even if you do that, we're now going to collect 27%
Speaker 8:  of what people buy when they click on the link and go pay you somewhere else
Speaker 8:  instead of 30%. And so all the people who are mad about Apple's 30%
Speaker 8:  tax are now predictably just as mad about Apple's 27% tax
Speaker 8:  when you pay for something else. And it's gone into this fascinating place
Speaker 8:  where it's like App Apple has always said, we don't think this is just
Speaker 8:  a payment processing thing. We think you're paying us 30% for all of the
Speaker 8:  other things that we provide and all the other people who make these apps.
Speaker 8:  At
Speaker 6:  This point it's you're paying, you're paying the money for the right to have
Speaker 6:  an application on their phone.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, no, that, that's, that's basically Right. And Apple would not say it
Speaker 8:  quite like that, but that's basically the argument. It's
Speaker 6:  Our phone. They, they feel very strongly it's their phone. But
Speaker 8:  All these companies from Epic to Spotify to, you know, everybody else in
Speaker 8:  this coalition for app fairness, match.com and all these other folks, they
Speaker 8:  are equally pissed. And so we're just gonna have this same fight
Speaker 8:  again with slightly different rules, which is now, instead of paying
Speaker 8:  in an app and giving Apple 30%, you pay on the web in
Speaker 8:  an app and you pay 27% and that
Speaker 8:  is just, it's just going to start this whole fight all over again. And I
Speaker 8:  think it's fascinating. Oh
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So Epic is going just to walk through the procedural
Speaker 6:  nightmare here. Yeah. There was the trial which we covered, apple
Speaker 6:  won almost all of the claims except the one California state law
Speaker 6:  claim that basically made their anti steering
Speaker 6:  provision illegal. The thing where you can't tell anyone else that you can
Speaker 6:  go buy stuff elsewhere. Right. Apple appealed that Epic appealed that they
Speaker 6:  got all the way to appealing the Supreme Court, which said, no, we don't
Speaker 6:  want to, we, we've got other things in our minds, the
Speaker 6:  Supreme Court ladies and gentlemen, that means the case is over and this
Speaker 6:  one ruling that Apple lost, you cannot have the anti steering provision
Speaker 6:  exists. Right. And Apple is basically doing what you would call malicious
Speaker 6:  compliance. Right. They have, they have found a way to comply with
Speaker 6:  the letter of the law and absolutely not its spirit. By doing this
Speaker 6:  27% thing, if any purchase happens on the web within seven days of someone
Speaker 6:  clicking that link, you have to audit it. It's great. I mean, it's crazy.
Speaker 6:  And so Epic is mad and they have said they're gonna go back to the
Speaker 6:  trial court and say, this is not what you intended to have happening. Right.
Speaker 6:  Like, this cannot be the outcome you anticipated when you wrote that ruling.
Speaker 6:  And we'll see what happens.
Speaker 8:  Malicious compliance is exactly the correct way to put it. Yeah. It's it's
Speaker 8:  delightful. It's so petty. It is ridiculous.
Speaker 6:  Look, I, I get that there's like lots of money involved here and, but
Speaker 6:  Apple is like doing, they're doing some stuff that is dangerous for their
Speaker 6:  reputation. Yeah. With app developers here with, with these games. And I
Speaker 6:  Ooh I there's something, there's something there that's dangerous.
Speaker 8:  Well, and that's happening while like do the, the whole hey thing That
Speaker 8:  became a fiasco, what two summers ago is that was a
Speaker 8:  mini fiasco again, this time because Apple rejected Hay's Calendar app,
Speaker 8:  there have been rumblings that an antitrust case against Apple is coming
Speaker 8:  sooner rather than later this year. Like the, the,
Speaker 8:  the smoke is pretty ugly when it comes to the Apple versus developers
Speaker 8:  fight at this moment in time. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  We'll
Speaker 8:  See. And it's gonna get, we're gonna get a lot more fairly quickly I
Speaker 7:  Think, which is not great when you have a giant new totally
Speaker 7:  like architecture that you're trying to get people to adopt. Yeah. And
Speaker 7:  develop for probably not the best time to piss off all your developers.
Speaker 6:  And by the way, the argument from app developers has always been yes, the
Speaker 6:  phone is very valuable. We are the ones who made it valuable. Right?
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like there's an app for that is a real way that they market the phone. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  We'll see. Okay. Mine is, I just wanna call out Alex
Speaker 6:  Heath interviewed Mark Zuckerberg on the site that published literally today
Speaker 6:  as we were, we were setting down to tape this episode. Zuckerberg's thing
Speaker 6:  is beta's pivoting to building a GI, artificial
Speaker 6:  general intelligence. He's doing that pretty obviously to make
Speaker 6:  sure that Meta can compete for talent. This is like
Speaker 6:  the thing that all these companies are thinking about. All the hottest talent
Speaker 6:  in the industry is going to go build a GI somewhere or the other. And Meta
Speaker 6:  wants to be in the game and I just wanna call this out,
Speaker 6:  he, part of their cell is, he's like, we have more Nvidia H
Speaker 6:  one hundreds than anyone. They have 340,000 Nvidia H one
Speaker 8:  Hundreds, which is nuts.
Speaker 6:  And I just think it is incredible. We have arrived at a place where the CEO
Speaker 6:  of a company like Meta is like, we have more GPUs than anyone else. You should
Speaker 6:  come work here. I
Speaker 8:  Think that's, come play with my GPUs.
Speaker 6:  I think that's pretty good. I just, I, there's a part of me that's like,
Speaker 6:  that's the funniest part of this whole story is part of the Pitch is like
Speaker 6:  they've got, they've got more GPUs. We
Speaker 7:  Got so many GPUs in this office. You come right over.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Pretty good. But you should read the whole thing. There is, you know,
Speaker 6:  Alex rightfully pushed back. He said, look, you, you just changed the name
Speaker 6:  of the company to Meta.
Speaker 6:  Zuckerberg's answer to this is like, it's not the huge change.
Speaker 6:  It's that in the virtual world to connect with other people. Maybe you'll
Speaker 6:  be talking to Agis in virtual characters and and don don't know man. You
Speaker 6:  can go read it yourself. Well
Speaker 7:  You need to talk to somebody in there and there's not a lot of people.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Here's a quote, I don't know how to more unequivocally state that we're
Speaker 6:  continuing to focus on reality labs in the Metaverse. They're still spending
Speaker 6:  $15 billion a year on it and Zuckerberg sees the future
Speaker 6:  when virtual worlds are generated by AI and filled with AI characters in
Speaker 6:  a company. Real people.
Speaker 7:  So ready player one
Speaker 8:  That tracks for me. I really don't think that is a
Speaker 8:  justification from Zuckerberg. I mean it's a small one but I, I don't think,
Speaker 8:  I don't think the company's saying we're in on the metaverse and then saying
Speaker 8:  we're in on AI means like 180 degree
Speaker 8:  pivot you to make the Metaverse work is going to require
Speaker 8:  a huge amount of really sophisticated ai. I don't know if it
Speaker 8:  involves Tom Brady playing a character who will talk with me in
Speaker 8:  a messaging app. But like again, I think a thing
Speaker 8:  I've been saying a lot is like we need more terms than just ai. We call everything
Speaker 8:  AI and actually AI is a million different things and
Speaker 8:  having a lot of GPUs you can use to do stuff is gonna be pretty useful in
Speaker 8:  the metaverse.
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna start putting how many GPUs we have in our trouble station?
Speaker 6:  There's like five. It's they're good. 1440 p
Speaker 6:  You're gonna like it.
Speaker 6:  I agree. I just think the idea that the top line is not still a metaverse
Speaker 6:  is really interesting.
Speaker 8:  Oh yeah. Yeah. To
Speaker 6:  Build a great metaverse we need to build basically a GI is a coherent story.
Speaker 6:  We're ag we're we're doing it now is like there's, there's a little
Speaker 6:  bit of flip floppiness.
Speaker 8:  Oh totally. And he is definitely saying we're an AI company that is also
Speaker 8:  building the metaverse. Not we're a metaverse company that is building AI
Speaker 8:  in order to get there. And that's like, that's the thing you say because
Speaker 8:  the Metaverse has been real bad for your stock price over the last couple
Speaker 8:  of years
Speaker 6:  And because Apple's about to put out the Vision Pro Yeah. Which it feels
Speaker 6:  like the next turn. Like it's more if you thought
Speaker 6:  we talked about the Vision Pro too much today. Just wait until we actually
Speaker 6:  get one.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And we surround ourselves with Iowa speakers and Smeg refrigerators.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. When does this thing go on sale? February 2nd.
Speaker 6:  February 2nd. Okay. Yeah, it's
Speaker 8:  Coming at some point in the near future we're going to have a lot more to
Speaker 8:  say about this and I'm sorry in advance.
Speaker 6:  Alright. Please send us an email if you think people have heard of VR headsets
Speaker 6:  before, you can address them to David at The Verge dot com And we would love
Speaker 6:  to know Verge has at The Verge dot com would be great. I
Speaker 8:  Will respond with NE's credit card number so you can buy him a Vision Pro.
Speaker 6:  That'd be great. If someone wants to stand in line from here, whatever, that'd
Speaker 6:  be amazing. That's it. We have quite a lot to talk about next week.
Speaker 6:  It's, there's just a lot going on. The year is fully kicked off. Oh
Speaker 6:  yeah. So we gotta wrap this one up, but we'll be back next week. We'll see
Speaker 6:  it. That's where chess buck will.
Speaker 15:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 15:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One. The Vergecast is the
Speaker 15:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 15:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.