# Transcript
ID: 4086414c-a7fe-470a-bef6-c816c0b3cfed
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-6262567075647277836/-1141071691611677046/s93290-US-6318s-1708072529.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss Apple fans starting to return the Vision Pro, Xbox exclusive games, Super Bowl streaming troubles, and more.
Speaker 7:  Hello And Welcome to To Vergecast, the flagship podcast of perceiving the
Speaker 7:  World through screens. Oh yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That,
Speaker 7:  That's the thing I told you about.
Speaker 5:  It's accurate
Speaker 7:  That no one believed me about.
Speaker 8:  So does that mean our podcast is like very good at first and then sort of
Speaker 8:  slowly gets more annoying over time? Yeah,
Speaker 7:  You
Speaker 5:  Fluctuate, you
Speaker 7:  It's magic until it's not. It's To
Speaker 5:  Vergecast.
Speaker 7:  That's very good. Quite a lot going on this week. Yeah. As we're
Speaker 7:  recording, we are expecting breaking news from Microsoft about The future
Speaker 7:  of the Xbox.
Speaker 8:  Yes. Yes.
Speaker 7:  So we're just gonna react to that in real time and then we'll have Tom Warren
Speaker 7:  come on the next show to explain what's going on. But we'll react to
Speaker 7:  that in real time. I promise you. I'm your friend Neil. I, David. Pierce
Speaker 7:  is here. Hi.
Speaker 8:  I should warn everyone that I have a deeply sore
Speaker 8:  throat. So the like sexy smoldering thing I'm doing is just a
Speaker 8:  one time thing and it will not be this good to listen to me every time.
Speaker 7:  No, you should keep it. We're gonna, we're gonna do an AI that we're gonna
Speaker 7:  do a sexy smolder ai. I love this. OpenAI dot com slash sexy smolder
Speaker 7:  Alex Cranz is here.
Speaker 5:  Deeply disappointed. I don't also have a cold right now. You can
Speaker 7:  Vague big.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I, I could, I could drop it a little lower. I don't even know how far
Speaker 5:  to go. This
Speaker 7:  Is when, when we first started podcasting with the in Graduate podcast ages
Speaker 7:  ago, I was like, I should have a podcast voice. Yeah. But gave up on
Speaker 7:  that immediately.
Speaker 5:  You have to, otherwise you forget about it and then you're like, oh, how
Speaker 5:  are you? This is my normal voice. And people are like, Jesus,
Speaker 7:  You went with Mickey Mouse.
Speaker 5:  That's my normal voice. You don't, I I actually do a Verge voice
Speaker 5:  at home. I talk like this all the time. Oh
Speaker 7:  My God.
Speaker 8:  Can you do an impression of your podcast voice for us? Just real fast.
Speaker 7:  I think decoder is my fake podcast voice. Oh,
Speaker 5:  Interesting.
Speaker 7:  Oh, it's, it's a pseudo NPRI
Speaker 8:  Think of that as like NELI Patel in his study swirling a brandy.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. That's about Eli Decoder. That's
Speaker 7:  The same. Yeah, that's the same voice. That's
Speaker 8:  Right. That makes sense.
Speaker 7:  Okay. It's drunk Ira Glass. That's the decoder voice. That's what I
Speaker 7:  got for you.
Speaker 8:  Okay. I love this for you.
Speaker 7:  We gotta start with some housekeeping. This is our first
Speaker 7:  Vergecast back on the main Verge YouTube channel.
Speaker 7:  I, I am told this is a complicated move, but it should be simple to
Speaker 7:  experience. David, can you explain what's going on?
Speaker 8:  Yes. Okay. So there are now two channels on which you can
Speaker 8:  experience The Vergecast. We have The Verge main YouTube channel, which is
Speaker 8:  youtube.com/ The Verge or search for The Verge. That's where all the
Speaker 8:  full episodes are gonna live. We just wanted to
Speaker 8:  have the show and the rest of our stuff kind of be closer to each other,
Speaker 8:  easier to find. And with all the stuff YouTube is doing with
Speaker 8:  podcasts right now, it actually makes sense to have those things a little
Speaker 8:  closer together because now you can subscribe to just a single playlist.
Speaker 8:  If all you want is the podcast, you can subscribe to the channel and get
Speaker 8:  everything in YouTube and get the podcast and YouTube music. It's all a little
Speaker 8:  weird right now because Google is still sorting out how all of
Speaker 8:  the podcast stuff works.
Speaker 7:  It's very in character for Google. I just wanna be clear about that. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  So like all of this is stuff that I think we are doing
Speaker 8:  correctly and just slightly ahead of Google. So hopefully this
Speaker 8:  will continue to make more sense as time goes on. But basically all the full
Speaker 8:  episodes are gonna be on the Verges YouTube channel from now on. And then
Speaker 8:  we're gonna do like clips and extras and silly stuff where we make fun of
Speaker 8:  NELI off the show on The Vergecast channel. Good. So that's where all that
Speaker 8:  stuff will live. I promise there
Speaker 8:  was a lot of weirdness as we moved all of this stuff. Liam, our
Speaker 8:  producer, did like a heroic job to get all of this done.
Speaker 8:  It was messy because YouTube is messy, but I think it's done now. People
Speaker 8:  seem to have like found The Vergecast again in all the YouTube platforms.
Speaker 8:  So it should work. And If, you don't listen to this podcast on YouTube. Don't
Speaker 8:  worry about it. Literally nothing else will change.
Speaker 7:  I hope this makes more sense as time goes on. Should be Google's motto. I
Speaker 7:  just wanna be a hundred percent clear on that.
Speaker 8:  We have a product team focused on making this make sense. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I hope this makes sense as time goes on, is how
Speaker 7:  Google approaches product strategy at a very high level.
Speaker 7:  I'll give you one, but one example, and I don't know why this
Speaker 7:  Threads post did the numbers It did, except I think it spoke to people's
Speaker 7:  very souls. I bought a big silly
Speaker 7:  Sony tv. I'm very happy with it. Yeah, it's a 95 0 1 Ooh.
Speaker 7:  Very, very pleased with this televis. It looks amazing. It came with a webcam,
Speaker 7:  which I think is just representative of how deeply overcharged I was for
Speaker 7:  this tv. Yeah. They were like, it's, we made so much money. Here's a camera
Speaker 7:  fine. So I'm like, what can this webcam do? No, nothing.
Speaker 7:  They can watch you while you watch TV and adjust the settings. Oh,
Speaker 7:  that's a hard no. Yeah. And then it it, there's a Zoom client
Speaker 7:  and there's a Google Meet client. So I was like, fine.
Speaker 7:  Oh, it has gesture controls, which are after the vision Pros fake. I'm just
Speaker 7:  not doing gesture controls. I
Speaker 8:  Know what happened. Oh my God. This is the best. If this goes where, I think
Speaker 8:  this is about to go. This is my favorite thing.
Speaker 7:  I I clip the camera to the top of the tv. Yeah. And I launched Google
Speaker 7:  Meet to sign into our staff meeting and basically
Speaker 7:  be a brat at our staff meeting. And I'm like, where do I type in the code
Speaker 7:  and you can't. And I was like, okay, where do I
Speaker 7:  switch accounts to my work account? And you can't.
Speaker 7:  Oh. And so they've made a Google Meet client for Android,
Speaker 7:  which this television runs.
Speaker 7:  They can't join meetings.
Speaker 5:  But
Speaker 7:  It can, it can just call, you can just call people with your phone number
Speaker 7:  from your television. A thing that everyone wants to do.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. No
Speaker 7:  David, I'm curious for your guess on what happened here because I think I
Speaker 7:  know. So
Speaker 8:  What happened was Google, in its infinite wisdom
Speaker 8:  decided that Duo and Meet should not be different things. Because when you
Speaker 8:  call one person and you call another person, it should be the same
Speaker 8:  thing. So what they did was they renamed
Speaker 8:  Duo to meet and then renamed
Speaker 8:  Meet to Meet original. And then
Speaker 8:  I think I have this right. And then the old duo now meet
Speaker 8:  became Google Meet. But I'm guessing what never happened is that your
Speaker 8:  TV never got an update. So you still have Google Duo with a different
Speaker 8:  name.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It, it didn't get an up. There's no update, a avail. It's not my TV
Speaker 7:  didn't get an update. My TV is hardwired to the router. This is a very insane
Speaker 7:  TV situation. Well,
Speaker 8:  Okay, you're right. Google forgot that this TV exists,
Speaker 7:  Exists. Google forgot to update the me client so
Speaker 7:  that it could join meetings.
Speaker 8:  Right. It changed the name but forgot to change
Speaker 7:  The app. There's a, there's a Kanban board in Mountain View
Speaker 7:  labeled, we hope this makes sense over time
Speaker 7:  and update the meet clients so it can join meetings as a card
Speaker 7:  on that board
Speaker 5:  Far.
Speaker 7:  It just hasn't moved in over a year.
Speaker 8:  NELI, I have to tell you, they, they scrum this and they didn't. They
Speaker 8:  decided that updating Eli's TV was not a corporate
Speaker 7:  Priority. It's an Android app.
Speaker 8:  Your TV was a zero rate phenomen,
Speaker 7:  Like TV's just a giant tablet. You don't even remember when they were like,
Speaker 7:  Android tablets are back. We're gonna try hard again.
Speaker 7:  Remember that.
Speaker 5:  It'll make sense over time. Don't worry about
Speaker 7:  It. It makes, we hope this makes sense over time.
Speaker 5:  Don't worry about it. Come
Speaker 7:  Anyway. I I had to audio only join this staff meeting. It's like I was
Speaker 7:  like, I don't even, I can't join from my phone here.
Speaker 5:  I had all the power. It
Speaker 7:  Was great. It was great. Truly. Alright,
Speaker 7:  so we're, we're on YouTube. The upshot of that is one I can't join meetings
Speaker 7:  for my television and two, we are now available on the main YouTube channel.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Is that about right? That's right.
Speaker 8:  Pretty
Speaker 7:  Much. Alright, let's talk about the news. There's quite a bit of news. Let's
Speaker 7:  start with the Vision Pro. It is two weeks after the Vision Pro hit,
Speaker 5:  Which means everybody has to return it. Now
Speaker 7:  You gotta make the big return decision. Right? I look a lot of influencers
Speaker 7:  brought the Vision Pro to make a bunch of Vision Pro views on YouTube and
Speaker 7:  now they've returned the Vision Pro. Yes. Because why would you keep it?
Speaker 7:  but it if that, if that's your goal, like why would you keep it? Yeah. Right.
Speaker 7:  Like you, you've, you've milked that for all it's worth. That's
Speaker 5:  That's how you used to be able to do like reviews and stuff. Once upon a
Speaker 5:  time you just be like, yeah, I definitely want this very expensive product.
Speaker 7:  Right. I would just say there's a, a clout element to Vision Pro
Speaker 7:  discourse that we keep pointing out. Like
Speaker 7:  Vision Pro thrown at a cyber truck subscribe to my
Speaker 7:  newsletter. Like that is a whole,
Speaker 5:  Well that one can't be returned.
Speaker 7:  Well If, you get enough newsletter subs. That's true. Signups. There's, there's
Speaker 7:  just a whole universe of that discourse that I think we can just set aside.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. As a family we can agree we're gonna set aside the the clout chasing
Speaker 7:  part of the coverage. Then there's a bunch of people who are happy with
Speaker 7:  it and they're keeping it and it works for them and they're excited and they've,
Speaker 7:  they've got big lonely TVs to watch. That's great. We can talk about that.
Speaker 7:  'cause I think some of that is coming into focus as well.
Speaker 7:  Then there's the people who the hype balloon for them popped
Speaker 7:  and they are genuinely returning it for a variety of reasons.
Speaker 7:  All of which seem fairly predictable. Yes. And I think that
Speaker 7:  it's the gap between the hype and reality that is really disappointing a
Speaker 7:  bunch of people here. So people are returning it 'cause it's not
Speaker 7:  comfortable to wear, people are returning it 'cause it makes their eyes hurt.
Speaker 7:  They're getting headaches. People are returning it because they are lonely
Speaker 7:  in it or the pass through isn't what they thought it was gonna be. It it
Speaker 7:  feels like.
Speaker 5:  But the Windows management was one I saw
Speaker 7:  Someone returned it over window management. Yeah. There
Speaker 5:  Like it was one of many reasons but like a big factor for them was like,
Speaker 5:  yeah I can't like manage the windows properly. It doesn't feel
Speaker 7:  If. you are a person who had enough feelings about window management to return
Speaker 7:  a $3,500 computer. Please we should hang out. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  We love you.
Speaker 7:  Just come on over. Like we should talk. But that,
Speaker 7:  that's how I would diagnose it right. Is the things that was promised to
Speaker 7:  do
Speaker 7:  and then the things it can actually do and the product it is now, there is
Speaker 7:  a pretty staggering gap between those two things.
Speaker 8:  Yes. And I think the, the thing we've really spent the last week
Speaker 8:  kind of discovering as a society is that it turns out
Speaker 8:  that Apple having a long history of making these things work and having
Speaker 8:  a presumably very cool roadmap doesn't mean anything for the
Speaker 8:  thing on your face. Right? Like this is what we talked about when we did
Speaker 8:  this review. Right. Like you can talk all you want about where this
Speaker 8:  is going and who's right about The future and the big ideas behind all of
Speaker 8:  this and Apple's ability to execute. And I, I still have not changed
Speaker 8:  my mind on any of that. I think If, you were to bet on a horse in this race.
Speaker 8:  You'd be crazy not to bet on Apple just historically. That is true.
Speaker 8:  It doesn't change anything for the fact that you just bought a very expensive
Speaker 8:  thing that is uncomfortable to wear for a lot of people. Doesn't
Speaker 8:  do that much for most people's use cases
Speaker 8:  and is $3,500
Speaker 7:  Like
Speaker 8:  And So I think we saw a really normal thing happen,
Speaker 8:  which is a lot of people tried it, it's super cool. Like you went through
Speaker 8:  this too, NELI like the first time you put it on, you spend a couple of hours
Speaker 8:  in it, you take it off and you're like Oh my God, that is the most impressive
Speaker 8:  thing I've ever seen. And then the fifth time you do that you're
Speaker 8:  like, well it's, I'm not doing this 'cause it's cool. I actually need something
Speaker 8:  out of this. And the entertainment side of
Speaker 8:  things seems to be holding up like the people who want to watch
Speaker 8:  a large screen look at cool panoramic pictures they've taken
Speaker 8:  whatever that seems to be working for people. But the question of a
Speaker 8:  is that enough for this $3,500 headset and B can I
Speaker 8:  do that comfortably? Like literally physically, comfortably.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Is is turning out to be a higher bar I think than a lot of people who
Speaker 8:  bought this thing expected.
Speaker 7:  I want to stay focused on that use case.
Speaker 7:  I would submit to you If, you take your
Speaker 7:  $3,500 and you go and buy the
Speaker 7:  biggest TV you can get for that money, you will be happier in the long run
Speaker 7:  than owning a first generation vision pro. Yeah. 'cause you can do TikTok
Speaker 7:  at the same time because you can do TikTok at the same, you can watch the
Speaker 7:  show with someone else, which everyone keeps forgetting. Like maybe you're
Speaker 7:  a solitary person and we've heard from a lot of people like this and you
Speaker 7:  never have people over to watch TV the one time you
Speaker 7:  want to and your only option is the vision pro. You're gonna be like Huh.
Speaker 7:  There's also just being able to move around not having the weight on your
Speaker 7:  face. There's just something about that that's different.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. The thing you'll lose out on is the audio side of it. 'cause the
Speaker 7:  Vision Pro is very convincing with facial audio. Especially If, you wear
Speaker 7:  good headphones with it like AirPods Pro, that's very convincing. And
Speaker 7:  as a travel device on an airplane, I've seen a lot of people wear this thing
Speaker 7:  on airplanes and say I love, like for a long haul flight, you're flying
Speaker 7:  New York, San Francisco and you do the immersion and you're just like in
Speaker 7:  space and it, you just don't feel cramped anymore. Great.
Speaker 7:  $3,500 external battery pack. Like you're still a generation or
Speaker 7:  two behind from that thing being valuable I would say.
Speaker 7:  But if that's the whole value proposition, you're really
Speaker 7:  missing out on a lot that you should be getting from a computer that can
Speaker 7:  put Windows everywhere in your space. Yes. And I keep seeing apps that like
Speaker 7:  could be really cool. There's one V song and I were laughing at last night.
Speaker 7:  It's basically a virtual Peloton. So you have
Speaker 7:  any exercise bike, preferably one with like Bluetooth that compared to a
Speaker 7:  thing over Ant or whatever protocol that is. And it just
Speaker 7:  mounts a big virtual screen in front of you and then you go on a bike ride.
Speaker 7:  That's cool. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  That is cool. I love
Speaker 7:  That. Yeah. Super cool. And then it's like you have to wear Vision Pro in
Speaker 7:  your head to do it with an external batter pad with a sweat. Yeah. It's like
Speaker 7:  none. It's not made for that. Yeah. Like it just isn't made for that. And
Speaker 7:  then there's the other app that everyone keeps talking about, which is the
Speaker 7:  Mac display. And I thought it was utterly
Speaker 7:  fascinating that a lot of the first conversation you saw from Vision Pro
Speaker 7:  owners was the killer app for this thing is my Mac.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Which is wild. Like just wild.
Speaker 7:  Like the application model has nothing to do with spatial computing. It's
Speaker 7:  just a big window into your Mac. The Mac is notably much more open
Speaker 7:  than an iOS or iPad always based device. So what you want is your Mac applications
Speaker 7:  and then you have this big screen and Apple keeps billing
Speaker 7:  it as a 4K screen. And then over time you started seeing people say, this
Speaker 7:  is actually kinda a little blurry. This isn't as sharp as I thought it was.
Speaker 7:  And it's because Apple is making a 5K like an
Speaker 7:  iMac display or a studio display. They're that resolution, they're, they're
Speaker 7:  making a virtual one of those at that resolution and
Speaker 7:  then they're down rising it to 4K and sending a 4K video stream of
Speaker 7:  that
Speaker 8:  Lies, which you can then scale infinitely to whatever weird size
Speaker 8:  you want.
Speaker 7:  And So I called this out in the review and it was just like one of those
Speaker 7:  things like, so hard to explain it. So much of this device
Speaker 7:  is once you see it for yourself, you get it, but it is really hard to explain.
Speaker 7:  You're looking at the screen that seems sharp and then
Speaker 7:  underneath it are like five scaling operations. Mm.
Speaker 7:  And then on top of it there's Foveated rendering. So you've made
Speaker 7:  this huge Mac display that is already fuzzy because of
Speaker 7:  the scaling steps in between the virtual display that's created, that's
Speaker 7:  5K that's being scaled down to 4K and sent to the headset and then you've
Speaker 7:  made it really big. And then If, you look at the center of it, the edges
Speaker 7:  of it are blurry because of the Foveated rendering. And so people
Speaker 7:  are just sort of running into the reality of what that screen really looks
Speaker 7:  like. And they're like, oh, my application model is still the Mac.
Speaker 7:  I should just use my Mac.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Right. And I think the other part of that is also to your point about,
Speaker 8:  it's not super clear until you see it. The actual
Speaker 8:  interaction of the Mac apps on my Mac,
Speaker 8:  the Vision Pro apps that are actually optimized for this spatial
Speaker 8:  computing and the iPad apps that run in the Vision Pro is
Speaker 8:  not good. Like you, you can technically have all of those things but
Speaker 8:  the world you want, and I think the world a lot of people expected is one
Speaker 8:  where all of my apps are just all of my apps and some of them run on my
Speaker 8:  device, some of them run on my Mac, but I can just sort of put them all anywhere
Speaker 8:  and they all interact and that's pretty cool. That is not at all how
Speaker 8:  it works. And I think that like the people who are mad about the window management
Speaker 8:  are the ones who are like, well either the idea of being able to leave
Speaker 8:  my email in the other room is actually like not a good thing.
Speaker 8:  It's neat but it's stupid. And why would I want that? Or
Speaker 8:  this thing about like, okay, I, I've been promised something like sort of
Speaker 8:  world scale app multitasking and this
Speaker 8:  is actually a tiny little slice of that plus a bunch of other
Speaker 8:  slightly confusing things to me. This is like when they put stage manager
Speaker 8:  on the iPad and you're like, I can see what you were going for here. You
Speaker 8:  just missed it by about 30%. And it kind of kills the whole premise. For
Speaker 8:  me,
Speaker 7:  The two things that I think would make that much better. And you can see
Speaker 7:  them and I think that's the 30% one,
Speaker 7:  they have to make it smaller. Like
Speaker 7:  the hardware is not ready for the software. Yes. Like I, I have come back
Speaker 7:  to that several times. Like one way to think about this is that this is a
Speaker 7:  simulator for the hardware they want to build. And you can see putting windows
Speaker 7:  over your house and like having digital objects everywhere would be amazing.
Speaker 7:  But then you, you have to wear a vision pro. And every time I see a cool
Speaker 7:  Vision Pro app, I think yes. But to have this experience, you've gotta put
Speaker 7:  all that weight on your head. And for some people that's fine. I I don't
Speaker 7:  wanna discount the people who are like, that's great. But the re the reality
Speaker 7:  of it is then you degrade real, like literally degrade reality.
Speaker 7:  You, you are wearing a vision pro on your face and the world around you is
Speaker 7:  a lot grainier and there's an ocean blur and the pass through isn't good.
Speaker 7:  And you are prioritizing the digital world over the real world. And
Speaker 7:  I, I just don't think that's an appropriate show.
Speaker 5:  And the moment you walk into a dark room, you just see mud. Right?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I mean it's it's a camera. Yeah. Like you just cannot overcome
Speaker 7:  cameras. Right. And I have now talked to because in the review
Speaker 7:  I basically called the top on pastor. I was like, it can get better
Speaker 7:  but it can't get 5000% better. Right. And If
Speaker 7:  you did like by the time you get that much better, some other technology
Speaker 7:  will come along and be disruptive and very smart people disagree with me
Speaker 7:  on this. I fine. you know, like Who knows. But we
Speaker 7:  all agreed that the timeline for that is 10 years out. Yeah. And I am
Speaker 7:  just not making any predictions on what happens in 10 years of technology
Speaker 7:  development. Well and
Speaker 5:  I like, I think we, a bunch of us in the office have been talking about how
Speaker 5:  would you shrink this headset? Like did they make a design mistake? And,
Speaker 5:  and a lot of people are like, well why didn't they just take that computer
Speaker 5:  and put it with a battery pack? Right? Yeah. And just take a lot of that
Speaker 5:  weight out. But then If, you put it with a battery pack, you'd effectively
Speaker 5:  be carrying around like a Mac Mini in your pocket with a battery
Speaker 5:  attached to it.
Speaker 7:  Backpack, full Apple backpack, backpack,
Speaker 5:  Big
Speaker 7:  Puffy white straps.
Speaker 5:  You'd need fans to cool it. Who knows if it can like
Speaker 5:  actually be fast enough along that wire to, to do all the stu all the incredible
Speaker 5:  processing it's doing. Yeah. It's like, no it's actually a really com
Speaker 5:  like I keep going back to it. It's a really fascinating device 'cause it
Speaker 5:  is so complex. It is such like exquisitely
Speaker 5:  designed device that doesn't do a whole lot,
Speaker 7:  But that part of it where it doesn't do a whole lot. That's because it's
Speaker 7:  new. Like there's no apps for it. Yeah. We saw a report this week from Immersive
Speaker 7:  Wire, I wanna say it was that most vision apps hit
Speaker 7:  a ceiling of 1000 downloads. Hmm. Like very few people have
Speaker 7:  this product V like vanishingly few people have this product.
Speaker 7:  Vanishingly few app developers have started building apps that are made for
Speaker 7:  it. That's that's a cycle that Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That and that's a cycle that's gonna continue because if no one's making
Speaker 5:  apps for it, then nobody's buying it. And if no one's buying it, then no
Speaker 5:  one's making apps for it.
Speaker 8:  I do think what's clear is that this is a repeat of the, you can't
Speaker 8:  just blow up an iPhone app and have it work on the iPad problem, which Apple
Speaker 8:  thought that ecosystem would buy it a ton of time and
Speaker 8:  that it didn't. Like luckily Apple was able to get the iPad ecosystem going
Speaker 8:  very quickly because the, you will just two x your iPhone app and it'll be
Speaker 8:  great was a total non-starter. And I think we're going through that again
Speaker 8:  where it turns out iPad apps are not the answer. Like we, we,
Speaker 8:  what we have seen overwhelmingly so far is people being like, there's some
Speaker 8:  cool stuff. Even Apple now is going into Apple Arcade and saying here's some
Speaker 8:  of the stuff you can actually use for spatial. It's cool this idea that
Speaker 8:  you know, you have access to this giant set of apps and it will get us there
Speaker 8:  and buy us enough time to get to the next thing I'm less convinced of
Speaker 8:  every day. Yeah. Because it just doesn't seem to be wor it, it doesn't seem
Speaker 8:  to be sort of satiating people that way.
Speaker 7:  So I wanna talk about one more limitation that I think the community has
Speaker 7:  discovered of this thing and then I want to talk about Mark Zuckerberg reviewing
Speaker 7:  it. Yes. Yes.
Speaker 5:  That
Speaker 7:  Was the best. Which is deeply un as a professional reviewer, all
Speaker 7:  I could think of is, boy I hope more CEOs try to take my business.
Speaker 7:  Like just get out there soon. Dar Phai, just start reviewing stuff. Be like,
Speaker 7:  review the pixel. He should review the pixel soon. Dar
Speaker 7:  phai pick up a pixel challenge, pay attention to the pixel
Speaker 7:  challenge
Speaker 7:  the other limitation that I think is really weird and add a piece on
Speaker 7:  this, on the site. By the time you're listening to this, the people in the,
Speaker 7:  like the Vision Pro subreddit and the people that I've seen in other places
Speaker 7:  online do not think Apple's default fitment is good.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Right. So they're like, you go in, you get your face scanned or you
Speaker 7:  do the iPhone scan and you get a light seal and all of them are like, get
Speaker 7:  a smaller light seal. Some people are like, take the lights off and mash
Speaker 7:  it against your face, which I tried. It is very convincing in terms
Speaker 7:  of field of view, get a huge field of view. I felt like I was underwater.
Speaker 7:  Like the ones that are not designed to be smashed directly against your eyeballs,
Speaker 7:  but they're like, get a different light seal. Make it smaller. Like mess
Speaker 7:  with the fit because they don't think that the fit that Apple is giving
Speaker 7:  people is Right.
Speaker 8:  Which we've discovered Apple really does not want you to do. Right. Like
Speaker 8:  it's, it's,
Speaker 7:  They really don't want you to do that.
Speaker 8:  You can't just walk in and buy three light seals and see which one you like
Speaker 8:  the best. Right, right. Because they're
Speaker 5:  $200.
Speaker 7:  Well they're $200. But, so like I'll just, I'll make that concrete for if
Speaker 7:  you're listening. We have a review unit, we want more people
Speaker 7:  on our team to use it. We want to make more videos or we have ideas on how
Speaker 7:  to cover it. Even if we bought another one, even if we sent the review unit
Speaker 7:  from Apple back and we just bought one in order to be fair in
Speaker 7:  coverage, as more people use the thing, we have to make sure it fits them
Speaker 7:  because if it doesn't fit right, the eye tracking goes completely wonky and
Speaker 7:  people get headaches. So, okay. I told Owen,
Speaker 7:  our video director, let's just go to the Apple store, just like buy a bunch
Speaker 7:  of light seals. Turns out there are 17 sizes, they're $200
Speaker 7:  a piece and Apple won't let you just buy some. Yeah. You cannot go
Speaker 7:  to an Apple store and just buy some, they
Speaker 5:  Keep him in a drawer behind. Like you have to ask someone and then they'll
Speaker 5:  be
Speaker 7:  Is Owen who made the Vision Pro video with like Owen is on
Speaker 7:  that team, he edited that video. They made him sit for the demo,
Speaker 7:  the full half hour demo and then they let him buy one in his size.
Speaker 7:  And it's like, why? Like just we wanna give you money. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Up to $4,000. Like
Speaker 7:  If, you walk into any store and you're like, I'll just, here's $4,000. Just
Speaker 7:  gimme one of everything. Few stores in America will be like, no, you
Speaker 7:  just actually there's a process here. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  Aires would be like, get out. You get one.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And when you think of the Vision Pro Light Seal, you immediately leap
Speaker 7:  to Hermes.
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent. Same experience. Same. Like I walk in, I'm like, Ooh,
Speaker 5:  do I have enough money to be in here right now?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. It's Barney's Aires and the Vision Pro Light Seal
Speaker 7:  in terms of luxury purchasing experiences. You can't just buy a Ferrari.
Speaker 7:  You gotta buy a bad Ferrari first. Yeah. You can't just buy a vision for
Speaker 7:  a light seal. You gotta sit down for 30 minutes first.
Speaker 7:  So that is annoying on its face. If, you buy
Speaker 7:  it for enterprise use. I've seen a lot of designers, like we want bought
Speaker 7:  one for our office so we could like share it as a 3D modeling tool. And they're
Speaker 7:  like, this is just like not designed to be shared If. you spend
Speaker 7:  $3,500 to have it as a cool tv.
Speaker 7:  It is challenging to get it to fit the other people.
Speaker 7:  That's just physically Yeah. You can accomplish the goal. but
Speaker 7:  it is challenging to be like, this computer is available for someone in this
Speaker 7:  office to use. Here's a selection of things that make it fit your head.
Speaker 5:  It's so consumer hostile.
Speaker 7:  Th so the, there's a, I think there's a connection except here. Yeah. I
Speaker 7:  I it's too new. Yeah. I think they just shipped the thing. There's
Speaker 7:  like, you know, you all know how I feel about headphone jacks? Like yeah,
Speaker 7:  that was a hostile move. This is like, the product isn't ready
Speaker 7:  to support that thing. And the way that it's in particular
Speaker 7:  not ready is iOS and iPad os have no
Speaker 7:  affordance for multi-user support. Yeah. So the vision pro
Speaker 7:  it, it has optic ID in it. It can scan your eyes and log you
Speaker 7:  in. It should be able to scan my eyes or your eyes or David's
Speaker 7:  eyes or someone else's eyes and be like, here's your account. You're you,
Speaker 7:  we know you're you. Here's your account and here's your stuff. And
Speaker 7:  it has nothing. And like on top of it, it has none
Speaker 7:  of the like
Speaker 7:  recalibrations stored. So if I have one, if I have a
Speaker 7:  vision pro and I lend it to you, thanks. Every time I lend it
Speaker 7:  to you, you have to recalibrate. I have to put it in guess mode and you have
Speaker 7:  to recalibrate it for your eyes.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's stupid.
Speaker 8:  That has to, that was a deliberate choice though, right? That has to have
Speaker 8:  been a deliberate choice by Apple to make it hard for you
Speaker 8:  to share this thing with people. Because why, for all the reasons you've
Speaker 8:  been talking about that the hardware is not set up for success
Speaker 8:  for you to be sharing this
Speaker 5:  Thing. But why?
Speaker 5:  That's why I think it's a hostile because they never, 'cause
Speaker 8:  It's not finished,
Speaker 7:  But they cannot possibly like it's hostile when like, I don't think it's
Speaker 7:  like Apple is hostile. Okay. So let me explain why think the headphone jack
Speaker 7:  is hostile. Let me rewind this conversation. They took out a headphone jack.
Speaker 7:  They didn't need to, especially as the funds started getting bigger, they
Speaker 7:  did that because they wanted AirPods to succeed. AirPods are a huge success.
Speaker 7:  I know people love their AirPods. I know people think we were wrong about
Speaker 7:  AirPods.
Speaker 7:  They basically created a market for proprietary headphones. Yes.
Speaker 7:  AirPods are proprietary headphones. Yes. Like I know they run Bluetooth,
Speaker 7:  but they actually run a special version of Bluetooth.
Speaker 5:  Kinzie's Kinzie gets you on that one. They, they, they're, they're all like,
Speaker 5:  can you believe they, they got rid of the headphone jack who allowed that.
Speaker 5:  And I'm like, we wrote about it all the
Speaker 7:  Time. I I did my best. But like that was straight and hostile. Like they
Speaker 7:  created a market for Proprie headphones and they flooded the market with
Speaker 7:  their own iPads. Yes. I'm aware that people really like them. Whatever. It's
Speaker 7:  a thing that happened not allowing multiple users on the iPad at this
Speaker 7:  point in the iPad's history a little bit Hostile. Hostile. Yeah. You
Speaker 7:  have families, people share their iPads, schools there,
Speaker 7:  there's some enterprise support. Yeah. For shared accounts on iOS devices
Speaker 7:  if you're in a school or a business. But a regular person who spends five,
Speaker 7:  six, $700 on iPad that is not a family device by any stretch of the
Speaker 7:  imagination is locked to one user. Yep. Because Apple wants you to buy multiple
Speaker 7:  iPads. Right. They want everyone in your family to have an iPad. Okay. There's
Speaker 7:  some just raw capitalistic user hostility there. Yeah, fine. They're the
Speaker 7:  richest company in the world. What a shock. I think with the Vision Pro there,
Speaker 7:  there's no expectation that a family of four is gonna
Speaker 7:  buy four Vision Pros. No, I agree. And I, I think that that's why I'm like
Speaker 7:  not ready to call it. I I I don't think, I think they just shipped the product
Speaker 7:  that was done.
Speaker 5:  I think it was hostile design. I don't think it's necessarily like
Speaker 5:  Apple was set out to, to had a big vision here. I think it was just,
Speaker 5:  well we wanna make this thing as cool as possible and that means we need
Speaker 5:  to make it as finicky as possible regardless of what that means for like
Speaker 5:  use cases for other people. Because we wanna make it as cool as possible.
Speaker 5:  And that's hostile to the users because then they can't share it. They can't
Speaker 5:  do anything with it. They have to, they do have to go buy another one or
Speaker 5:  they have to go buy a $200 light seal if they wanna have that experience
Speaker 5:  And like, I don't wanna say the Quest Pro is a good product,
Speaker 5:  but that part of it,
Speaker 7:  I just remind everyone we gave the Quest Pro a four. Yeah. And the headline
Speaker 7:  was, get me out of here.
Speaker 5:  But could you put it on like, when you put it on your head, did it fit?
Speaker 5:  Did you have to go buy a $200 light seal to make sure it worked?
Speaker 8:  Oh no. So I. I, I don't buy that premise at all honestly. Okay.
Speaker 8:  Like if, have you ever put on somebody else's headset and you spend 15 minutes
Speaker 8:  screwing around with the lenses and the strap to get it to fit your head?
Speaker 8:  Like it's, there's just
Speaker 5:  No awkward. I love that
Speaker 8:  World. Which awkward. Which you have a good experience using these things.
Speaker 8:  Ironically, it's one of the reasons I think Meta
Speaker 8:  Ray band strategy is closer to the right one because that's just a pair of
Speaker 8:  glasses that is Yeah. Much closer to a thing you can just put on anyone's
Speaker 8:  head and it will more or less work. Yeah. You might look stupid in them,
Speaker 8:  but it's just a pair of glasses. Whereas something like
Speaker 8:  this is just by definition, so
Speaker 8:  individual user-centric that I think for Apple to say, oh,
Speaker 8:  share it with your friends, they're gonna have a trash experience in it.
Speaker 8:  It's actually a bad idea. Like I think if If you get to,
Speaker 5:  No, I think it was a bad idea. What I'm saying is go further back. I think
Speaker 5:  it was a bad idea to design a product. Well
Speaker 8:  You're just arguing it was a bad idea to ship the Vision pro, which is fine.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I just don that's just that that ship's
Speaker 5:  To say, Hey we we're gonna charge you $200 for a light seal. Hey we're gonna
Speaker 5:  make it so extraordinary for one person and no one else. I think that's just
Speaker 5:  inherently hostile design.
Speaker 8:  I will say I do think an interesting question that is becoming more and more
Speaker 8:  open is whether Apple overshot, and
Speaker 8:  this is where we should get into Mark Zuckerberg's review of this thing because
Speaker 8:  it's part of the case that he made, which is that Apple basically came out
Speaker 8:  and said, we are going to make the best, most
Speaker 8:  impressive, most incredible thing possible. Every other
Speaker 8:  consequence be damned. Right. And it did that by all accounts. Like I
Speaker 8:  don't, I don't think it missed in terms of doing the best anyone possibly
Speaker 8:  can at, at this moment in time on very many fronts,
Speaker 8:  is doing that a better idea than making
Speaker 8:  something that is 85% as good and maybe half the weight?
Speaker 8:  Dunno. Like is, is it something that Apple
Speaker 8:  should have shipped that was much closer to just a screen
Speaker 8:  and an entertainment device as opposed to trying to do all of this other
Speaker 8:  stuff? These, I think this roadmap Apple has set
Speaker 8:  itself on where it made the best thing possible and it's just gonna try to
Speaker 8:  bring it down in all of those ways over time towards people is a
Speaker 8:  strategy. But I think it's, it's less and less obvious to me that
Speaker 8:  it's the right one because it's like you, you want that to be the luxury
Speaker 8:  thing that not everybody can afford, but everybody who can really loves.
Speaker 8:  And even that is not what it's getting right now. Right. It's not like the
Speaker 8:  Tesla Roadster or the super expensive first luxury
Speaker 8:  item you see from a lot of companies. It's not even working for those
Speaker 8:  people. It's
Speaker 5:  Not the the Samsung flip phones, right? Yeah. Like, like that was, that was
Speaker 5:  the thing. It was like, okay, there's a lot of flaws in this If, you peel
Speaker 5:  this part off, it will destroy it and then Samsung will not be happy.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But like it still worked pretty well and
Speaker 5:  more, I mean yeah, more than one person could use it, but it actually did
Speaker 5:  the it it delivered on the promise. And this feels like it doesn't always,
Speaker 7:  But the promise there was just it unfolds. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It was a much simpler
Speaker 7:  Promise. Right. The promise that Apple is making is we will intermediate
Speaker 7:  reality for
Speaker 5:  You. And that was perhaps too big a promise to make.
Speaker 7:  I think David said this Yeah. A couple weeks ago, which is with the Apple
Speaker 7:  Watch. And so, so many people have compared the Vision Pro to the Apple Watch,
Speaker 7:  which I'm just gonna remind everyone I got right in that review
Speaker 7:  too.
Speaker 7:  But the a watch underwent drastic, drastic changes. But
Speaker 7:  David, I think it was, you said this a couple weeks ago, they got the form
Speaker 7:  factor, right? Yes. Everyone knew that this is how it should look and all
Speaker 7:  you're doing is refining the thing around
Speaker 7:  the shape that it should be. And here it just seems
Speaker 7:  obvious that the form factor isn't right. Right. That they shouldn't
Speaker 7:  do pass through in this way. That what you want is all you want glasses.
Speaker 7:  So I think that does bring it to the Zuckerberg review, which
Speaker 7:  again, I think every CEO should just review their competitors' products like
Speaker 7:  head on a hundred percent. David, do you want to tell us what's going on
Speaker 7:  with Mark?
Speaker 8:  Sure. Okay. So let me, let me just briefly set the scene for you here. So
Speaker 8:  Mark Zuckerberg and his newly long hair, which that's beautiful,
Speaker 8:  shocked we have not talked about in this show yet, but we'll just leave that
Speaker 8:  sitting on a couch in a, in a, you know, dark long sleeve
Speaker 8:  shirt I think with an immaculately fluffed pillow behind
Speaker 8:  him. Lovely setup. Did a, I don't know
Speaker 8:  what, maybe five minutes or so just kind of riff on his
Speaker 8:  experience with the Vision Pro, how he feels about the Quest three compared
Speaker 8:  to the Vision Pro. 'cause there were a lot of people remember when this came
Speaker 8:  out who were like, oh, the Quest is dead. Meta actually
Speaker 8:  rushed to launch the Quest three ahead of the Vision Pro.
Speaker 8:  These two things have been very closely pitted against each other as sort
Speaker 8:  of opposite ends of this strategy for a very long time. And
Speaker 8:  he sat down and, and basically we should just play a clip here, but he
Speaker 8:  basically said at the end of his experience, he thinks not only is the Quest
Speaker 8:  three a better value, he thinks it is straight up a better product than the
Speaker 8:  Vision pro. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Pull over in your car and just look at this man's hair and then listen to
Speaker 7:  his voice.
Speaker 9:  I think the Quest is the better product period. And you know, the different
Speaker 9:  companies made different design decisions for the headsets. They have different
Speaker 9:  strengths, but overall Quest is better for the vast
Speaker 9:  majority of things that people use mixed reality for.
Speaker 7:  And that's a good line. Right. Beautiful hair too. It's great.
Speaker 7:  It it is look illustrious. That's what punching other men in the face will
Speaker 7:  get. You
Speaker 7:  just gets the, the follicles going. Yeah. He's just rocking healthier than
Speaker 7:  ever. By the way, do you know mixed martial arts is listed in Meta as risk
Speaker 7:  factors with investors? Yes. Our so good. Our CEO made made
Speaker 7:  deeply injure himself fighting other humans. Very good. Anyway, so
Speaker 7:  the point there, right, is everyone thought, okay, could, does
Speaker 7:  $500 get me 85% of a Vision Pro And? honestly,
Speaker 7:  in the review, we didn't talk about the Quest a lot in our review
Speaker 7:  'cause they, they feel very different. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And I think now what Zuckerberg is trying to do is actually make them more
Speaker 7:  competitors. So
Speaker 8:  I don't even know if I agree with that. I think You don't, part of his take
Speaker 8:  I think is that they're actually very different things
Speaker 8:  that everybody wants them to be trying to do the same thing and
Speaker 8:  sort of compete on what they can do for different people. And it's like,
Speaker 8:  oh, I wanna do X, Y and Z. Should I buy a Quest or a Vision Pro? And his
Speaker 8:  whole point is kind of, you can't do any of that stuff on the Vision
Speaker 8:  Pro,
Speaker 7:  Like the,
Speaker 8:  The Quest. And I will say the single funniest thing about this whole video
Speaker 8:  to me was the moment where the camera flips around and
Speaker 8:  it becomes clear that he's filming this thing on a Quest three.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Which just means there is a person sitting there very still
Speaker 8:  just staring at him with the headset on. Just
Speaker 7:  Like you do with the Vision Pro at your child's birthday party.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, exactly. Like next time we make a video NELI, I'm just gonna stare
Speaker 8:  into your eyes the whole time. It's gonna be incredible. But he,
Speaker 8:  it's, it's a big part of what he talks about and I think is the most compelling
Speaker 8:  part of Zuckerberg's case here is that for all the stuff people
Speaker 8:  actually want to do in a headset like this right now, we can talk
Speaker 8:  about 10 years from now, we can talk about the big far future of headsets
Speaker 8:  for everybody. But in terms of like right now what people wanna do inside
Speaker 8:  of a headset, there's just more of that in the Quest.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. There's more games, there's more apps. There are, there is. You can
Speaker 7:  do three Mac Windows If, you want to, although setting that up
Speaker 7:  is a Byzantine nightmare of so like what I call
Speaker 7:  software dongles. Oh yeah. You don't want, it's not great. You have to
Speaker 8:  Download a bunch of apps that just sound like malware in order like it's
Speaker 8:  bad.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. The and and you're like, I'm, so I'm sending my entire screen to Meta.
Speaker 7:  No thank you sir. I don't care what your hair looks like today. No.
Speaker 7:  So you're not actually sending your entire screen to Meta. But you understand
Speaker 7:  what I'm saying. It's a nightmare of weird applications and
Speaker 7:  Mark actually calls it out like their eco Apple's ecosystem is great, but
Speaker 7:  If, you wanna play a bunch of games or you wanna do fitness If, you want
Speaker 7:  to control the thing. You have high resolution controllers, which he's calls
Speaker 7:  out very specifically and the heart of what he's getting at. And I think
Speaker 7:  this is really interesting because you rarely see CEOs
Speaker 7:  acknowledge this. He's like, we made different tradeoffs than Apple.
Speaker 7:  Yep. And we think our tradeoffs make a better
Speaker 7:  product period. Not just a cheaper product, not just a better product
Speaker 7:  at our price point. And I, he comes back to that over and over again and
Speaker 7:  you If, you go listen to any CEO ever talk about their products.
Speaker 7:  I talked to a lot of CEOs and a lot of decoder like, you made this trade
Speaker 7:  off, how'd you make that choice? And they're like, we didn't make any trade
Speaker 7:  offs at all. Right. All the time. Yeah. Like all the time,
Speaker 7:  especially Apple refuses to acknowledge that they made tradeoffs. Right.
Speaker 7:  Like in the review process we're like, why is the battery over here? And
Speaker 7:  they're like, Hey, we wanna save wait on your head and that is as much of
Speaker 7:  a tradeoff as you can. 'cause
Speaker 8:  It is meant to be over here.
Speaker 7:  It's
Speaker 8:  Like Jesus wanted it that way
Speaker 7:  And it's like there's that one you can't avoid. But everything
Speaker 7:  else, they're like, these are the best displays ever made. Yeah. And then
Speaker 7:  Mark is there being like, we've looked at these displays and they are all
Speaker 7:  lead displays and they have exactly the kind of motion blur that you would
Speaker 7:  expect from all that displays. Our lenses are better. The, the
Speaker 7:  Meta really believes the Quest three is pancake cleansers are better, they
Speaker 7:  have a wider field of view. So we lose X from the displays,
Speaker 7:  the resolution that Apple has in their displays, but we gain X in the
Speaker 7:  lenses. I'm not saying these are the right trade offs. I'm not saying these
Speaker 7:  are trade offs that make you make you buy anything. I'm saying a CEO
Speaker 7:  acknowledging the trade-offs in a product category is
Speaker 7:  wild. Like fully wild. And
Speaker 7:  I dunno, If, you saw this XA lot of people were like, this is
Speaker 7:  Zucks Balmer moment. Oh interesting. Where Balmer was like
Speaker 7:  $500 fully unsubsidized of the plan. I like our phone better.
Speaker 7:  And that's, there's an element of that to what Zuck was
Speaker 5:  Doing. Oh no, I, I, I disagree. I thought I, it felt more like a victory
Speaker 5:  lap, like a legit victory left.
Speaker 7:  Wow. Okay. That's how you took it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, because I, you know, v put up a, a story this week that I
Speaker 5:  worked with her on about the, the visions of these two companies, because
Speaker 5:  they're both, the end game for both of 'em isn't vr, it's ar. Right? Like
Speaker 5:  both of these companies are waiting, eventually the technology's gonna get
Speaker 5:  there and they're gonna do face computers and that's what everybody wants.
Speaker 5:  Still computing
Speaker 7:  After 15 days of the Vision Pro. Okay. Excuse me. Can we say everyone wants
Speaker 7:  a face to
Speaker 5:  Meet? That's what everyone in Silicon Valley wants. That's what all the VCs
Speaker 5:  want. Yeah. But, but I think like their, their strategy
Speaker 5:  is a much smarter strategy. And I think when you think about how you have
Speaker 5:  to normalize these products because they are really big, really wild and
Speaker 5:  really insane, you have to normalize that. Like it's, it's gonna be, require
Speaker 5:  a cultural shift. And Meta has, is moving with much smarter
Speaker 5:  purpose in that direction than Apple who is like face computer that looks
Speaker 5:  like ski goggles. Put it on your face. It's way too heavy and you might throw
Speaker 5:  up, it'll be fine. And, and meta's like, okay, well we've got like these
Speaker 5:  glasses that just look like glasses and you can't do as much, but you can
Speaker 5:  still do like, you can still like scan photos and stuff like
Speaker 5:  that, which is really, really cool. And and they've got the VR headsets that
Speaker 5:  actually like do vr. Well, yeah. Which like,
Speaker 5:  I think that's just a better strategy. I I think, I think he's right. And,
Speaker 5:  and when I was watching it, I was like, oh, this is him just taking this
Speaker 5:  victory lap and also making some egregious
Speaker 5:  claims. Like Meta is gonna be the open ecosystem.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Which is bananas. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Are they gonna let Lenovo build quests? I
Speaker 5:  I was like, I was like, oh, are you just announcing that everybody's gonna
Speaker 5:  be making headsets for, for Meta os
Speaker 7:  What they, what they mean from what I understand is that they, you can side
Speaker 7:  load applications on a Quest. Okay.
Speaker 8:  No. What Meta means is If, you build something cool, we'll just buy your
Speaker 8:  company. And that's, that's an open model
Speaker 5:  That counts. Yeah. It's an open ecosystem. 'cause you get rich.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. What they, they mean in every phase of computing there's Apple being
Speaker 7:  weird. Yeah. And then there's everyone else being like, what if we work together?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And then as Apple being weird.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That part I was like, oh, I feel like you're like you, you had me this
Speaker 5:  whole time. Your hair looks great. You're like, you're speak, you're saying
Speaker 5:  the things that I really do think about this whole field and now you've just
Speaker 5:  lied.
Speaker 7:  He does keep saying that they will be the open player in vr and it really
Speaker 7:  unclear with
Speaker 5:  That. I was like, I really wanna sit him down with like a computer historian
Speaker 5:  to explain to him computer histories so that he understands that what he's
Speaker 5:  saying is not true.
Speaker 7:  Oh, I'm sure he has access to computer historians. He
Speaker 5:  Probably does. He probably, but he doesn't listen. He
Speaker 7:  Should listen. I think there's a, there's just a way of positioning yourself
Speaker 7:  up against the big bad of Apple that he's taking advantage of. But I think
Speaker 7:  right now what they have is side loading apps. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  But I will say also to your point Alex, I think one thing
Speaker 8:  I'm really starting to realize is how significant Meta's
Speaker 8:  lead is just having been at this in public for a decade.
Speaker 8:  Yep. Because again, like Neil, I go back to the Apple watch you, you
Speaker 8:  launch the thing and then you wait around for a couple of years for people
Speaker 8:  to tell you what they want from it. And then it's your job to kind of chase
Speaker 8:  that and figure it out. Right. And Apple is good at that
Speaker 8:  generally and does it very quickly and relies on its developers to do it
Speaker 8:  for them. Meta's been at that for 10 years now. Like the thing where
Speaker 8:  here's a thing on your face, it's kind of ugly and you'll probably throw
Speaker 8:  up like, you know what that sounds like is the first three Oculus products.
Speaker 8:  That's just what it was. And it turned off a lot of people and we all, you
Speaker 8:  know, hemmed and hot about whether a whole generation was being turned off
Speaker 8:  by their first experience in VR because it was so bad. But now
Speaker 8:  it's been at this long enough that it's pretty good at it and it has a pretty
Speaker 8:  clear sense of what people want right now. And I think that's where
Speaker 8:  things like the Meta Ray band stuff come from. It's like, oh, people want
Speaker 8:  super immersive and that's either like gaming or the fitness stuff. They
Speaker 8:  want to be in another world or they want as little technology as possible.
Speaker 8:  And so it, they've pushed to both ends of that and I think are able to do
Speaker 8:  it. Whereas Apple very much just put out a tech demo and we're like, is
Speaker 8:  this anything? Like it's starting at that road now. Yeah. And Meta has been
Speaker 8:  on it for a long time.
Speaker 7:  I would say that there's a, there, I think there's a little bit of a danger
Speaker 7:  of the bomber problem. Mm. And that Apple is relentless. Yes. And they do
Speaker 7:  stay focused. The difference The difference and they
Speaker 8:  Have all the money in the universe
Speaker 7:  Is that Mark Zuckerberg is not Steve Almer. Yes.
Speaker 7:  I just, just an observation that I've made over time. I've studied these
Speaker 7:  two men very carefully.
Speaker 7:  I think Meta is more reactive to consumers and that
Speaker 7:  bomber's, Microsoft was much more reactive to enterprise. Yeah, that's a
Speaker 7:  hundred percent. And so, and they just, and that version of Microsoft, not
Speaker 7:  Microsoft now, but that version of Microsoft in particular was addicted to
Speaker 7:  making the ugliest shit possible. Yes. They're just like, it's Windows Mobile
Speaker 7:  6.5, it's the same Windows mobile that you've hated all this
Speaker 7:  time. But now the stock launcher is a honeycomb also that won't
Speaker 7:  be there. And carriers can do whatever garbage they want and it's like, this
Speaker 7:  isn't a good idea.
Speaker 8:  We made the icon smaller.
Speaker 7:  The worst. This is bad. Yeah. And Apple was able to, for and So I think there
Speaker 7:  are some meaningful differences here because they have been in market with
Speaker 7:  a complete consumer product. I'm not saying I have a Quest two I
Speaker 7:  Yeah, you have a Quest like lots of Quest twos out there, some Quest threes,
Speaker 7:  Apple's coming at this from a different direction. I'm not saying they won't
Speaker 7:  succeed, but I think after two weeks with this thing
Speaker 7:  like the, the barriers are are
Speaker 7:  just crystal clear. Yeah. In a way that the barriers
Speaker 7:  to the Quest are also crystal clear and I, they're gonna
Speaker 7:  converge more than they don't. But saying like Apple revitalizes market I
Speaker 7:  think is we can generous. Yeah. And with the watch they
Speaker 7:  had a huge advantage, which was no one else could make a watch.
Speaker 7:  Well no, I mean like literally like the iPhone does not allow other
Speaker 7:  watches. Oh that's true. Yeah. You like Pebble existed and like I was just
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 10:  I was just, I was like Pebble
Speaker 7:  Was a great walk. No, but if If, you wanna do the thing where like you get
Speaker 7:  a text message and you just respond. Yes. Like Pebble was not allowed to
Speaker 7:  do that. Yeah. You'd be like, oh okay, lemme pull my phone out. So we'll
Speaker 7:  see. Is there anything else I wanna
Speaker 8:  Say? No, we've talked enough about the Vision Pro. I like that we just spent
Speaker 8:  40 minutes being like, everybody's returning this product. Let's talk about
Speaker 7:  It. Oh, I did. It is the most fascinating product. It is Apple's first big
Speaker 7:  bet. I wanna talk about it. I just want to end on this. I want
Speaker 7:  everyone to do this homework and send me your evaluation. We've talked a
Speaker 7:  lot about my theory of wearable bullshit,
Speaker 7:  whatever that is. Where the chart is value on one axis
Speaker 7:  and then like fiddly ness. Yeah. And then a 10 x multiplier
Speaker 7:  if it's on your face. That's as far as I've gotten on this. So an Apple
Speaker 7:  Watch started really fiddly with not a lot of value. Eventually crossed the
Speaker 7:  line and now people really like Apple watches. We all
Speaker 7:  have one. Yeah. AirPods not very fiddly at all. Super
Speaker 7:  valuable. People really like 'em. Face computers historically
Speaker 7:  below the line. Very fiddly, enormous social
Speaker 7:  cost. Not a lot of value. Yeah. Where do you think the Vision
Speaker 7:  Pro is on the graph? Send me your graph. We will, we will just go through
Speaker 7:  'em. I'm dying to know what you all think after this. It's gonna be because
Speaker 7:  that's
Speaker 7:  fids. No, it's a value on the, the values on the
Speaker 7:  Y axis. Fids on the X and then
Speaker 7:  a 10 x multiplier for on your face. That's it. Those
Speaker 7:  are, that's what I think it is. There's an entire episode where we go through
Speaker 7:  this. So I'm just, you go back and look at that one. If, you want more versions
Speaker 7:  of the graph, but just send me your graphs. I, I'm dying to know what you
Speaker 7:  think about the theory of wearable bullshit as applied to vision Credit.
Speaker 7:  Alright, we have to take a break. We'll be right back.
Speaker 12:  safely.
Speaker 7:  We're back as we've been recording Vamping
Speaker 7:  to fill time with the Vision Pro. Microsoft has been
Speaker 7:  quietly making announcements in the background on a, on a podcast, I believe.
Speaker 7:  Yes.
Speaker 8:  The weirdest way ever to announce things.
Speaker 7:  We've been recording a podcast while they have been publishing a podcast
Speaker 7:  and now our podcast will be about what they said on their podcast.
Speaker 8:  Does it, do we now directly compete with the Xbox? Yes.
Speaker 5:  Download ours. Don't, don't download the Xbox.
Speaker 7:  Phil Spencer just went on a podcast and said everything The Verge said is
Speaker 7:  true and always has been. All right. Alex,
Speaker 7:  what is going on in the news over there?
Speaker 5:  Okay, so there's been rumors for the last few weeks that Microsoft
Speaker 5:  was gonna take a couple of games and that are exclusive for
Speaker 5:  the Xbox and make them not exclusive, put 'em on the switch, put 'em on the
Speaker 5:  PS five fans. Were not pleased about that.
Speaker 8:  Can you explain that to me? Actually, I have realized in all of this chaos
Speaker 8:  that I don't understand why people would be so up in arms about that. Well
Speaker 5:  I think If, you go and you spend a lot of money on a product and you invest
Speaker 5:  a lot of time and energy into it and like buying a lot of games for it and
Speaker 5:  then, and you're like, yeah, I don't get like the last of us and
Speaker 5:  I don't get Horizon zero dawn and I don't get all these cool PS five games,
Speaker 5:  but I get, was it Starfield? And, and I get see of Thieves
Speaker 5:  and then they say, okay, now Starfield is gonna go off and be
Speaker 5:  on on PS five. I would probably like, I'd probably
Speaker 5:  be a little miffed.
Speaker 8:  So you're like, maybe I should have just bought a PlayStation and now I get
Speaker 8:  all
Speaker 5:  The games. Right? Like, why did I even buy an Xbox to begin with? Okay, I
Speaker 5:  get that. 'cause they're like five, $600. That's expensive. So Starfield
Speaker 5:  is not coming to the PS five. But see Thieves Grounded. Hi-Fi
Speaker 5:  Rush and Intimate are coming to the PS five and the Switch
Speaker 5:  first. Hi-Fi Rush and Intimate. Then see if Thieves and Grounded,
Speaker 5:  see if Thieves is like a really pretty popular Xbox game where you can
Speaker 5:  like be a pirate and you go play with other pirates. It's cute, it's fun.
Speaker 5:  It's a big, like it's almost an M-O-R-P-G but not quite.
Speaker 5:  These are, these are pretty popular games for Xbox and now they're gonna
Speaker 5:  be on PS five and Nintendo Switch
Speaker 5:  and it's
Speaker 7:  Can Wait, can I just say something about this? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Microsoft has not actually officially confirmed those four games. What
Speaker 7:  Tom,
Speaker 5:  Tom has Con
Speaker 7:  Has reported and knows that it's those four games. Yeah, but Microsoft won't
Speaker 7:  confirm that those are the
Speaker 5:  Four. So weird. They're just saying four games, but they are not, they, they've
Speaker 5:  pretty clearly said it's not gonna be Starfield and it's not
Speaker 5:  gonna be the rumor at Indiana Jones video game that's
Speaker 8:  Coming out. So it's not any of the big games.
Speaker 8:  I mean like real like, yeah Microsoft, Microsoft is a handful of like
Speaker 8:  gigantic things in its arsenal now. And none of the games you just named
Speaker 8:  are those games. Yes. Like
Speaker 5:  Xbox fans, please don't come for me, but, but if you're not like a big
Speaker 5:  hardcore Xbox fans, these are are probably not the biggest games in the world.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's no nowhere compared nothing compared to like the last of Us are
Speaker 5:  Uncharted or some of PlayStations exclusives.
Speaker 7:  I'm horrible at video games and all of these sound like fun names for
Speaker 7:  Thieves and a comic book. Yeah. I'm Penman
Speaker 7:  I'm a Sea of Thieves. Like,
Speaker 8:  Like Rejected Musketeers. Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 7:  Oh no, it's HiFi Rush. Like,
Speaker 5:  But it's, it's, this was like a, this has been a big deal for the community.
Speaker 5:  Tom actually got to talk with Phil Spencer about it. There was a big interview
Speaker 5:  and I've definitely been maybe editing
Speaker 5:  that, that little idea, looking at that stuff I maybe I maybe knew a little
Speaker 5:  ahead of the podcast what was, what was coming or not coming
Speaker 5:  spoilers. And I thought what was really interesting was
Speaker 5:  he was very evasive in in the interview with us about like what games were
Speaker 5:  coming and what games weren't coming. He wasn't really commit to anything.
Speaker 5:  He, and when asked specifically about Starfield and Indiana Jones, which
Speaker 5:  are the ones I think fans are most concerned about losing that,
Speaker 5:  that access to or losing that exclusive access to. He said,
Speaker 5:  you know, I don't think we should as an industry ever rule out a game
Speaker 5:  going to any other platform which is,
Speaker 5:  you know, If, you just wanna be able to play any game like you NELI who's
Speaker 5:  bad at games and probably doesn't wanna own every system. That's great news
Speaker 5:  for you. If you're really invested in one ecosystem that's less great news
Speaker 5:  because like the console Wars. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  So a really interesting thing here that I am hoping you can explain
Speaker 7:  to me. I have for years now assumed
Speaker 7:  that the Microsoft strategy is game streaming.
Speaker 7:  Yes. Right. They're slowly moving to Xbox game streaming. They bought
Speaker 7:  Activision, they, they want to be everywhere.
Speaker 7:  And Phil Spencer has said to me like, we are bad. We are,
Speaker 7:  we're the number three player in video games and The future in consoles.
Speaker 7:  In consoles and If. you look broadly, all the action is on phones and
Speaker 7:  we gotta go there. Yeah. And it has always felt like a hint of we're gonna
Speaker 7:  go do game streaming now there's the Digital Markets Act. Apple
Speaker 7:  has to open up different stores. Apple has said they're gonna allow game
Speaker 7:  streaming. So you look at this shift and it is not that
Speaker 7:  they're not putting Xbox Game Pass on the PS five.
Speaker 7:  Right. They're just porting four titles to the PS five.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And people were that upset about it, but
Speaker 7:  That's the part that I don't get. It's like why that's a lot of work.
Speaker 7:  Like isn't the point that we're gonna stream the titles over there?
Speaker 7:  It's
Speaker 5:  Not like, given that the architecture of these consoles now Yeah. It's not
Speaker 5:  as hard of work as it used to be because they both run on the same like a
Speaker 5:  MD kind of architecture. It's it's different enough that it's like, it's
Speaker 5:  not like just point and click Sure. And you immediately transfer, but, but
Speaker 5:  it's not as hard as it used to be. I think this is all kind of part of showing
Speaker 5:  that they're friendly and that they're not going to
Speaker 5:  create a monopoly in gaming. Because right now they, they
Speaker 5:  own Activision Blizzard, which was like one of the largest game companies.
Speaker 5:  They are effectively one of the largest game companies in the world right
Speaker 5:  now. Right, right. Like I think Tencent, maybe Nintendo are the only thing
Speaker 5:  that might even come close to them. So just absolutely enormous.
Speaker 5:  And if they wanna say, okay, no more Call of Duty on PS five in 10
Speaker 5:  years, they can do that. So this
Speaker 7:  No, but they ran around the world Right. Promising any government official
Speaker 7:  Yeah. That they would ship Call of Duty for at least five more years. Right.
Speaker 7:  Like
Speaker 5:  10, 10 10. Yeah. So, so they're like committed for the next 10 years stuff.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 7:  Mean they're like futile lords in European countries you've never heard of
Speaker 7:  that have secured a 10 year commitment for Call of Duty
Speaker 5:  And they're trying and like a futile lord. They're trying to show how magnanimous
Speaker 5:  they're right. They're trying to show. Yeah. Yeah. We, we we got you. We
Speaker 5:  wanna be everywhere all at once. But we also don't wanna destroy all of our
Speaker 5:  competition because we need them to sell games. Oh
Speaker 8:  Man. That is so charitable and so wrong. Yeah. Oh
Speaker 8:  man.
Speaker 5:  Where do you, what's your read on it?
Speaker 8:  So we we should It's, I you're probably right, honestly, but don don't know.
Speaker 8:  We should, we should cut off here because I think we're gonna have Tom
Speaker 8:  on the show on Tuesday. That's true. Who knows clearly more about what's
Speaker 8:  going on than anyone at Microsoft. So Tom's going to explain what's going
Speaker 8:  on here. But NELI, I would just point you to the Xbox
Speaker 8:  one and the thing where Microsoft said, Hey, here's a console that plays
Speaker 8:  all of your games, but we're doing it in a slightly new way. And also a different
Speaker 8:  thing happens when you turn on your TV and gamers just about
Speaker 8:  burned the buildings down at Microsoft. Yeah. Like this business is
Speaker 8:  too big to screw up. And if you're Microsoft and you're out here
Speaker 8:  saying, game streaming is The future, we're, we're moving these three games
Speaker 8:  you've never heard of and see of Thieves over. And people lose their
Speaker 8:  minds like Microsoft is going to play this the
Speaker 8:  slowest possible way because it is desperately afraid of losing
Speaker 8:  this little bit of love that it has in the gaming community. Like
Speaker 8:  I, I do actually agree with Alex that there are some reasons to be worried
Speaker 8:  about the antitrust ramifications of just running roughshod over the gaming
Speaker 8:  industry, which in theory Microsoft could afford to do, but also
Speaker 8:  pissing off gamers goes real bad for everybody and Microsoft knows that better
Speaker 8:  than anybody. Yeah. And so it is, it is going to take this the slowest. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  It feels like it can afford to take this
Speaker 5:  I think, which is why there's a lot of rumors. We, we wrote a piece this
Speaker 5:  week, like Tom really thinks a handheld is coming. He'll talk more about
Speaker 5:  it with David on next week. Sean also fully
Speaker 5:  wants, he wants to manifest a handheld that's like a steam
Speaker 5:  deck with Xbox built in. Like, I am rooting for Sean. 'cause I think that'll
Speaker 5:  be cool too. But they, they did tease some like unique hardware coming. They've,
Speaker 5:  they've teased some bigger hardware is coming down the line. Phil
Speaker 7:  Spencer keeps liking tweets about
Speaker 5:  Yeah. He keeps liking tweets about handhelds and they ke in, in this
Speaker 5:  conversation he had with Tom, he said, yes, unique stuff's coming. So like
Speaker 8:  A handheld is coming like
Speaker 5:  Yeah, a hand held is coming. Is it gonna be like a good handheld or is it
Speaker 5:  gonna be more like what? Sony like farted out. We'll see.
Speaker 5:  All right. Yeah, sorry.
Speaker 7:  We'll come back. Tom will be on the show. We'll unpack all of it. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I'm legitimately confused about why
Speaker 7:  Port four games to another console.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna like If you we're
Speaker 7:  Gonna, your strategy is to be everywhere and the problem is phones, we're
Speaker 7:  gonna
Speaker 5:  Throw you into the Xbox like Reddit and just, I think the
Speaker 5:  confusion will go
Speaker 8:  Away. Can I, can I interest you in gamers?
Speaker 7:  Oh no, it's Hi-Fi rush. Okay.
Speaker 5:  They were mainly con confirmed. I think they were more concerned about Starfield,
Speaker 5:  which it sounds like is not gonna be in this initial run. So to be fair,
Speaker 5:  that was the one they were really passionate about. 'cause it just came out.
Speaker 5:  They're like, don't do this like this.
Speaker 8:  But I would bet you $10 that if Microsoft had its druthers and was
Speaker 8:  not afraid of the ramifications, Starfield would be in this.
Speaker 5:  Oh a hundred percent.
Speaker 8:  Like Microsoft's strategy includes Starfield and Indiana Jones
Speaker 8:  being available everywhere. Yeah, it just does.
Speaker 5:  It's coming. It's just, they're gonna be like six months from now they'll
Speaker 5:  be like, oh, it came out. Don't worry about it.
Speaker 8:  Don't worry. Yeah. Phil Spencer is just like quiet quietly tiptoeing
Speaker 8:  in slippers towards The future that he's promising. Like that's, that's
Speaker 8:  where we're at here.
Speaker 5:  High up on the tip piece. Exactly.
Speaker 8:  Oh my
Speaker 7:  God.
Speaker 5:  High heels on the tip.
Speaker 7:  Yep. Yep. I know.
Speaker 5:  There we go. I said it all the way to work today's That's how I walked to
Speaker 7:  Work. It's the next line. That's the real problem. I'm
Speaker 5:  Not gonna
Speaker 8:  Finish it. Let's just move on.
Speaker 5:  We're good. We're good here. I love TikTok.
Speaker 7:  All right. That's, that's Microsoft. And again, Tom will be on the show and
Speaker 7:  we'll, we'll try to figure out what all this means. We should talk about
Speaker 7:  AI briefly before our lightning round. By the way, two more people have asked
Speaker 7:  me how to sponsor Lightning Round and the answer is that for all my jokes
Speaker 7:  about taking your money, that's not my job. I don't know how,
Speaker 7:  that's not what we do here.
Speaker 5:  Just Venmo in
Speaker 7:  The influencers know how to take money. They, but we are, we just
Speaker 7:  do disclosures and other people take the money. So we'll figure it out.
Speaker 7:  I promise someone else is gonna take your money. But we talk about AI quickly
Speaker 7:  and then do a lightning round.
Speaker 7:  We mentioned at the top of the show that Google's strategy is very much we
Speaker 7:  hope over time this makes sense. I would say that my understanding of
Speaker 7:  the Gemini product roadmap right now fits perfectly
Speaker 7:  into over time. We hope this makes sense because they
Speaker 7:  announced Gemini Ultra, which is 20 bucks a month. And then David you
Speaker 7:  just wrote about Gemini 1.5 Pro, which they're like
Speaker 7:  is as good as Gemini Ultra. What it's, it's fantastic. What is going
Speaker 7:  on here?
Speaker 8:  So Google, in case you've wondered if Google is good at
Speaker 8:  naming things now because they decided to name everything Gemini and that
Speaker 8:  seemed like it made sense. Don't worry my friends Google still sucks
Speaker 8:  at naming stuff. There are I think four
Speaker 8:  different product names between the Gemini product
Speaker 8:  that you use and the Gemini subscription that you pay for. There are four
Speaker 8:  different product names, but at any rate, so
Speaker 8:  Gemini 1.5 is basically Google's new next
Speaker 8:  model. It makes sense. Everybody's always working on these next models.
Speaker 8:  I was talking to Sun their CEO about this yesterday and one of the things
Speaker 8:  that he told me was he thinks that over time eventually these numbers
Speaker 8:  won't matter to people and all of this stuff will just sort of happen in
Speaker 8:  the background. He compared it to Google search where like search doesn't
Speaker 8:  get new version names. It just kind of gets better over time. I
Speaker 7:  Wanna point out that Sam Altman said that a million times before announcing
Speaker 7:  GBT four, just saying
Speaker 8:  Oh sure. And there's 3.5 and there's 3.5 Turbo and there's GPT-4 and now
Speaker 8:  GPT five is apparently a thing even that he said it wouldn't matter. Like
Speaker 8:  all of this is insane but we're gonna get to that point
Speaker 8:  eventually. But right now we're very much in this arms race. And I think
Speaker 8:  especially the way you have to understand the arms race is these two companies
Speaker 8:  in particular, OpenAI and Google are in a massive
Speaker 8:  land grab for developer resources, right? Like if, if every company on earth
Speaker 8:  is at some point going to have an AI strategy and at this moment that's what
Speaker 8:  it looks like, there are basically two players
Speaker 8:  right now they can give a whole lot of money to. And
Speaker 8:  there is a lot of money in winning that. Like think about what AWS did for
Speaker 8:  Amazon, right? Because it was early to, we're very good at giving you developer
Speaker 8:  resources in the cloud. There is now a belief that the market for AI is gonna
Speaker 8:  be even bigger and happen even faster. So these companies are just running
Speaker 8:  as fast as they possibly can and they honestly don't care all that much if
Speaker 8:  the version numbers don't make any sense to us as users. But so Gemini
Speaker 8:  1.5 is coming out and at some point it will just sort of wholly
Speaker 8:  replace Gemini 1.0 and
Speaker 8:  there's the three sizes of it. There's Ultra, which is like the big full
Speaker 8:  model, all the epic stuff. The Pro which is the middle one, which is the
Speaker 8:  one that most consumers see. And then there's Nano which is specifically
Speaker 8:  designed to run on people's devices. Google hasn't talked much about Nano
Speaker 8:  yet on any of its Gemini stuff, but that's an I think,
Speaker 8:  interesting piece of it. The big thing with Gemini 1.5 is that
Speaker 8:  its context window is much bigger. And essentially what that means is you
Speaker 8:  can just put a lot more stuff into it at a time
Speaker 8:  when you, there's a bunch of like weird complicated math to do, but
Speaker 8:  typically they say it's like three quarters of a word is a
Speaker 8:  token and Google's context window for Gemini 1.5 is
Speaker 8:  a million tokens, which is a lot of words you can do hours
Speaker 8:  of video, hours of audio, all kinds of different stuff. So you can just plug
Speaker 8:  all this in and then ask questions about it, do stuff with
Speaker 8:  it. And they have, they have big ideas about what people might do with this
Speaker 8:  huge context window and there's a lot coming.
Speaker 5:  So we could put like the entire B movie in there
Speaker 5:  and then find out like if we were supposed to really think there was a romance
Speaker 5:  between a human woman and a be
Speaker 7:  That is a great question to ask a computer actually. Yeah. It was like do
Speaker 7:  you detect love? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I really wanna do
Speaker 7:  This. Let me have the difficult for
Speaker 5:  You If, you do this, please, please email me.
Speaker 7:  There's a great exchange in David's report on this where I think
Speaker 7:  Sundar says you could fit the entire Lord of the Rings movie into the context
Speaker 7:  window and David's like, that means that's happened to Google.
Speaker 8:  He said it so without thinking that he was just like it was, it was as
Speaker 8:  if he had like left the Lord of the Rings meeting right before talking to
Speaker 8:  me.
Speaker 7:  It's just like
Speaker 8:  This definitely happened. Right.
Speaker 7:  It's very good.
Speaker 7:  What's fascinating to me about all of this is yes there's an arms race for
Speaker 7:  developers. There are still, I, I think we're hitting the same
Speaker 7:  place with AI in a slightly longer time frame as people
Speaker 7:  are hitting on with the Vision Pro in a slightly shorter timeframe where
Speaker 7:  you're like, it's really cool, fastest consumer adoption history and now
Speaker 7:  we've all just run into the limits. That's right.
Speaker 8:  Yes.
Speaker 7:  Right. And I think developers love it 'cause they can build new apps, they
Speaker 7:  can certainly go get funding from VCs. You can write code with it, which
Speaker 7:  I think people really love to do and sort of everywhere else it's like what
Speaker 7:  I can do is produce spam at a higher rate than spam has ever been
Speaker 7:  produced before. Yeah. And turn the internet into a feted swamp.
Speaker 5:  Oh the the corporate folks love it. Yeah. 'cause they're
Speaker 5:  like, yeah, I can just have it do all my emails when I have to do a memo,
Speaker 5:  I just have it write the first draft of my memo for me. And you're like,
Speaker 5:  well you shouldn't do that don't you? You should write.
Speaker 5:  That's important.
Speaker 7:  Oh, I, I actually, I think sending corporate emails with ais, I
Speaker 7:  don't actually send a lot of emails. Same. I refuse to use enterprise software.
Speaker 7:  Same.
Speaker 5:  Well not that part but the
Speaker 7:  Thing about me.
Speaker 7:  But like the idea that some transactional email
Speaker 7:  is better written by AI than fine, but like that is a pretty small
Speaker 7:  use case on the grand order of things. Yeah. I'm
Speaker 7:  wondering like David, as you looked at this model as you played with Ultra
Speaker 7:  as you've played with the other ones, do you see that next set of big uses
Speaker 7:  showing up?
Speaker 8:  No, I think there there's going to be an increasing kind of
Speaker 8:  creative state of the art. Like one of the other things that happened this
Speaker 8:  week was OpenAI launched Sora, which is its text to
Speaker 8:  video model and So I think the kind of state of the art of stuff you
Speaker 8:  can make creatively. There's a just massive
Speaker 8:  room left to go and there's gonna be all kinds of cool stuff on that front.
Speaker 8:  But I think we've been talking about on the show for a while now, when
Speaker 8:  is the sort of novelty of using these AI chatbots going to
Speaker 8:  wear off? And we're there. I think it's happening and, and one of the
Speaker 8:  other things I'm starting to see all over social is a lot of people who started
Speaker 8:  paying for copilot from Microsoft and are now canceling it and
Speaker 8:  people are starting to sign up for Gemini Advanced with $20 a month, people
Speaker 8:  are starting to goof around with it. And you, you look at it and it's like
Speaker 8:  the thing so many people keep saying about the Vision Pro is like amazing
Speaker 8:  technology.
Speaker 8:  I, I took it off and kind of never had a reason to put it on again. And I
Speaker 8:  think a lot of people are starting to feel that way, especially in the sort
Speaker 8:  of one-to-one consumer use case about
Speaker 8:  AI stuff. And also I think that's why all these companies are going after
Speaker 8:  companies because if I'm already signed up for this stuff through
Speaker 8:  my organization, like yeah, I'll use it to make it easier to make
Speaker 8:  charts or whatever.
Speaker 5:  I mean that was Microsoft's whole strategy, right? Like get copilot out so
Speaker 7:  Right. Yeah. But copilot is 20 bucks a month to make charts easier. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But you're like a IT guy with endless budget
Speaker 5:  at a big company.
Speaker 7:  The days of endless IT budgets are over Who knows, right? You can see all
Speaker 7:  these companies are contracting and they're like not spending lots of money.
Speaker 7:  Like I, that to me is like this is the big gap. I will say
Speaker 7:  that I recently set the action button on my iPhone 15 Pro to
Speaker 7:  open the chat GPT voice assistant, just the cheap one, 3.5, not four, not
Speaker 7:  the one you have to be for. And it is like, oh they should just make Siri
Speaker 7:  this. Yep. Like they should throw Siri away and they should just
Speaker 7:  make Siri this. It is revelatory
Speaker 7:  when you're like, the other day we had to reheat chicken wings from the super
Speaker 7:  Bowl and I just asked my phone and it said an answer to me. Was
Speaker 7:  that answer correct? Did it lie?
Speaker 5:  How? How were the,
Speaker 7:  Did it hallucinate the temperature and the time? It was fine because
Speaker 7:  the stakes were so low. Yeah, I asked it. I asked it twice.
Speaker 5:  Chicken wings is high stakes though.
Speaker 7:  Like no, they're not reheating. Well it's true. It's,
Speaker 5:  I was like reheating. That's yeah, that's fair.
Speaker 7:  Does it? Because I asked it twice and the first time I said 350 degrees the
Speaker 7:  second I said 3, 7, 5 and I was like, this doesn't matter. Boop,
Speaker 7:  the stakes are very low here and I didn't have to trawl the
Speaker 7:  SEOed internet. Yeah. And Siri, I asked Siri and Siri
Speaker 7:  was like, I don't know like just
Speaker 5:  If it's a 200, would you have been like in there be like, this feels wrong
Speaker 5:  but I'll go with it.
Speaker 7:  That's how I describe the cha g BT use case. you know that old Stephen Colbert
Speaker 7:  word truthiness? Yeah. Like if you're comfortable with something that
Speaker 7:  just feels right, I really encourage you to set cha GBT to
Speaker 7:  your action button. So,
Speaker 8:  But actually that's a really good like example of
Speaker 8:  the problem that all these companies are having, right? Like Google is
Speaker 8:  essentially ripping and replacing Google Assistant with Gemini for the same
Speaker 8:  reason. Yeah. Like this stuff is going to be better at those things. Would
Speaker 8:  you pay $20 a month for the thing that you just described? Like no, absolutely
Speaker 8:  nobody would. And so there's going to be this like
Speaker 8:  mainstream use case for this stuff that no one will pay for
Speaker 8:  and then there's going to be a ton of money. At least that's what these companies
Speaker 8:  are betting in the business use cases. But to me it feels like we
Speaker 8:  are quickly hitting something like
Speaker 8:  a ceiling of what people actually wanna do with these things day in and day
Speaker 8:  out. Like a million token context window does not make you better
Speaker 8:  at chicken wings. It just doesn't. And So I think that
Speaker 8:  next thing for regular people is gonna have to come from somewhere else.
Speaker 8:  And there's a bunch of different ways these companies are trying to do it.
Speaker 8:  OpenAI has been making a bunch of tweaks to like how it builds
Speaker 8:  its models to try and make them sort of smarter and more efficient. It also
Speaker 8:  launched a thing this week called memory where it can actually remember things
Speaker 8:  about you and what you like and your preferences so that it should sort of
Speaker 8:  interact with you in a more human and like friendly way over time.
Speaker 8:  That's the stuff that I think is gonna be interesting. Just building bigger
Speaker 8:  models to do more high-end stuff is like purely a business play.
Speaker 8:  And I think you're right that $20 per person per month is more money than
Speaker 8:  most companies have to spend at this moment in time. Yeah. So Don don't know.
Speaker 8:  I don't know which of those things is gonna catch up first. Can you
Speaker 5:  Imagine spending $20 a month for like
Speaker 5:  possibly right? Possibly wrong chicken wings, reheating instructions.
Speaker 7:  I mean I think If, you just buy chicken wings at restaurants.
Speaker 7:  You're always, it's always, you've already, you've already, are they gonna
Speaker 7:  be good? Yeah. If your chicken wings budget is 20 bucks a month, it's a gamble
Speaker 7:  every time. True. That's
Speaker 5:  Fair.
Speaker 7:  Chicken wings are a big deal. They
Speaker 5:  Are very important.
Speaker 7:  I want to talk about the other side of the AI debate real quick. David, you
Speaker 7:  wrote about robots txt this week. I did Sora Jong and I talked about the
Speaker 7:  copyright battles that are facing all these AI companies
Speaker 7:  on decoder. There's something else here, right? These companies
Speaker 7:  are forging ahead with ever bigger models, ever. More
Speaker 7:  use cases, higher prices. And the
Speaker 7:  sort of underlying question of is it okay to take all this stuff to make
Speaker 7:  the models remains extraordinarily unresolved? The
Speaker 7:  Sora Silverman case, a group of authors including Sora Silverman suing Open
Speaker 7:  Eye, they just had a setback in their case, all of the claims
Speaker 7:  except direct copyright infringement, which is a big deal, but all the other
Speaker 7:  claims are thrown out. The judge seemed very skeptical there. There
Speaker 7:  are some like specific concerns in there that are pretty wonky, so we don't
Speaker 7:  have to go into them, but that case is getting whittled down. I
Speaker 7:  think the Times case against OpenAI is a little bit stronger. So we'll see.
Speaker 7:  But we don't know if these companies can even do it. Like
Speaker 7:  whether this is copyright infringement such that the courts just shut down
Speaker 7:  the entire notion of this to begin with. Or if that payments that they're
Speaker 7:  required to make become so high that the business models don't work out
Speaker 7:  all open questions. Right. And then David, I want you to talk about robots
Speaker 7:  txt because there's this little handshake agreement of a text
Speaker 7:  file on every website and that handshake agreement is like
Speaker 7:  one hand is just crushing the other one and it's like this thing can't
Speaker 7:  support the weight of it, I don't think.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So, I got, I got sort of obsessed with this years ago when I first
Speaker 8:  started talking to people about Google Amp for a story I wrote, which is
Speaker 8:  basically like, what is the value exchange on the internet,
Speaker 8:  right? And it turns out that a lot of the sort of policing of the internet
Speaker 8:  happens in that file. You named robots txt If. you go to almost any website
Speaker 8:  and then just put a slash robots txt, it'll pop up a text
Speaker 8:  file that you can see that basically decides which
Speaker 8:  crawlers from around the web are and are not allowed to go
Speaker 8:  onto a website. So crawlers exist for lots of reasons. Many of them are from
Speaker 8:  search engines, which are indexing the web in order to be able to send search
Speaker 8:  results. Amazon has a crawler that checks for pricing around the web for
Speaker 8:  what the government would say are extremely nefarious reasons. And Amazon
Speaker 8:  would say are for legitimate business reasons, you might run a crawler to
Speaker 8:  check all the links on your own site to make sure that they're still live.
Speaker 8:  Like there are a lot of reasons to run crawlers, and this is like a technology
Speaker 8:  from the early nineties that basically a bunch of people on a
Speaker 8:  mailing list, including like Tim Burners Lee and Mark Andreessen and a bunch
Speaker 8:  of like early internet optimists decided is
Speaker 8:  like, okay, you're just gonna put up this thing that says essentially who's
Speaker 8:  in and who's out. And everyone else who makes one of these crawlers is gonna
Speaker 8:  abide by those rules because we want the internet to work. We're all cool
Speaker 8:  people, this is gonna be great. That works pretty well for a
Speaker 8:  surprisingly long time. And now what's happening is If, you run an AI company
Speaker 8:  and you wanna get a bunch of training data. You know what's full of training
Speaker 8:  data is the internet. And so you just go, you crawl the whole internet, you
Speaker 8:  pull all that stuff in, you dump it in and you train your model on it. That's
Speaker 8:  how you get recipes. That's how you get all this stuff. Like you just base
Speaker 8:  it on all the stuff that exists on the public internet. And so now if you're
Speaker 8:  a person who runs a website or a recipe
Speaker 8:  blog or any number of other things on the internet, you have to
Speaker 8:  go in and decide who's in and who's out with a thousand
Speaker 8:  new crawlers, a bunch of companies of varying levels of
Speaker 8:  decency. And Sketchiness, OpenAI has been in a bunch of like
Speaker 8:  media coverage about this because it actually told people how to block
Speaker 8:  GPT bot and promise to abide by it and by all accounts is doing. So
Speaker 8:  a huge portion of websites on the internet, including I believe all of Vox
Speaker 8:  Media blocked GPT bot, the New York Times did a lot of publishers have.
Speaker 8:  But there are a lot of things out there that are either too small
Speaker 8:  for now to even be known to these publishers
Speaker 8:  or just don't care. They just don't have to respect this little tiny
Speaker 8:  text file that has no legal or technical authority. And
Speaker 8:  so any AI that wants to come in just can, and that's just where we are.
Speaker 8:  And we have just like broken this basic give and take that
Speaker 8:  the internet ran on for so long. And like I talked to Tony Stubble mine
Speaker 8:  at the CEO of Medium who has been a big proponent of
Speaker 8:  kicking out the bots in, in this particular way. And what
Speaker 8:  he said is basically like we're, we're getting nothing out of this exchange.
Speaker 8:  They're just taking everything from us and telling us that,
Speaker 8:  you know, it's for the good of society and like, screw that. That's not,
Speaker 8:  that's not how the internet works. That's not what we're after. And I think
Speaker 8:  everyone on the internet now is starting to have to make that exact same
Speaker 8:  set of decisions.
Speaker 7:  And what's fascinating is OpenAI only made
Speaker 7:  GPT bot blockable after they had scraped the
Speaker 7:  internet.
Speaker 8:  Correct. It's
Speaker 7:  Like, and I, I honestly think that they did that so that media
Speaker 7:  organizations, and I have, I'm not privy to what Vox Media does
Speaker 7:  at that level. I don't know why they did that or didn't do that. Yeah. But
Speaker 7:  I'm pretty sure they did it. So media organizations, companies could block
Speaker 7:  OpenAI and then and feel like they had some control and then
Speaker 7:  OpenAI could go make a deal, right. And be like, oh no, we're you took the
Speaker 7:  control away from us. No,
Speaker 8:  That is, I I will say that is precisely why. Yeah. I mean I talked to the
Speaker 8:  open chief strategy officer who said basically that exact thing that, that
Speaker 8:  it is, this is a way to signal that you would like to make a commercial deal
Speaker 8:  and let's do it. And that is a pretty
Speaker 8:  wild way of, of backing into something like that. But yeah, it is,
Speaker 8:  it's not an accident that OpenAI didn't tell people about
Speaker 8:  GPT bot until it had already been pretty far down the road. Yeah. Because
Speaker 8:  without doing what it did, it GPT-4 and chat
Speaker 8:  GPT wouldn't be as good as they are. Like that that is the trade. But then
Speaker 8:  the question is, who experiences the downside of
Speaker 8:  that? Like, is that bad for the internet? Is it bad for the world or is it
Speaker 8:  just bad for OpenAI? It's like, that's the question now.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And I think individual creators are feeling the pain of this
Speaker 7:  very deeply. Yeah. Even when we just write about neat
Speaker 7:  AI tools, we get people who are sort of morally outraged that we would
Speaker 7:  acknowledge that some of them are neat because it's built on
Speaker 7:  something, it's built on some taking and whether or not you think that taking
Speaker 7:  is fair or not is sort of divorced from whether it's legal or not.
Speaker 7:  And I, I don't know that anyone has quite figured that out. Right. Somebody
Speaker 5:  Needs to pop it into, am I the asshole on Reddit? Like it's a,
Speaker 7:  It's, that's what he needs to do.
Speaker 5:  It's a perfect one. Right.
Speaker 7:  And then answer all of that into the million token
Speaker 7:  Gemini field's, like, is this correct? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And then we, we send it to the judges and we're like, look, we figured it
Speaker 5:  out. The robots figured it out. They, they talked to each other. We got this,
Speaker 5:  we know who the asshole is. That means who legally is. Right.
Speaker 7:  Again, I keep, I keep coming back to what I I I refer to as the end
Speaker 7:  game post. Yeah. Which is a person who's like, I love podcasts, but I don't
Speaker 7:  have time for them. I just feed them into an AI and then it's ri and it's
Speaker 7:  like, dude, you just want articles? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Just
Speaker 7:  Go read those. What you want is articles. Like just go read articles made
Speaker 7:  by people who care about you.
Speaker 7:  Like it's a very simple, very simple way of getting what you want from the
Speaker 7:  internet. Read, read, like people would like to read.
Speaker 7:  It is amazing that the, the broad future of computing is like more
Speaker 7:  reading. Yeah. After all these anyway, doesn't matter.
Speaker 7:  I think that the turn for these AI companies, for OpenAI, for example,
Speaker 7:  you can signaling want commercial deals, but they're being sued. So If, you
Speaker 7:  go out and make a bunch of deals, you're kind of admitting that you need
Speaker 7:  the deals and the New York Times is gonna, or whoever else is suing
Speaker 7:  OpenAI Getty's suing stability is gonna say, look, you know
Speaker 7:  that you should pay money for this stuff you didn't pay us
Speaker 7:  to begin with. So you're on the, and I that is a
Speaker 7:  strategic nightmare for these companies.
Speaker 8:  It is. And I think James Kwan, the, the chief strategy officer at OpenAI
Speaker 8:  I was talking to, one of the things he said is, and this kinda goes back
Speaker 8:  to what we were talking about before, is that OpenAI feels very strongly
Speaker 8:  that chat GPT should be mostly free for most people
Speaker 8:  for exactly that reason. Like that's the value they believe they deliver
Speaker 8:  back to the world is that by giving to
Speaker 8:  this system, you then get access to this system and the, the
Speaker 8:  increase in quality of this system is good for the world and you can have
Speaker 8:  it and it will make your life better. And I think you can view that as like
Speaker 8:  dystopian black mirror nonsense or you can view that as like a fair
Speaker 8:  trade in the way that Google search was a fair trade. But like that is the
Speaker 8:  dynamic that we're about to reckon with in a lot of really, really
Speaker 8:  messy ways. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And what is the most fascinating about all this? We can bring it all
Speaker 7:  the way back around to Google. No one is gonna block the Google bot. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Correct. Like no one thinks it should be invisible from search. You can
Speaker 7:  block current sites, probably would, I don't know what those are.
Speaker 7:  Alex's Plex server continues to rock and roll in the background. No one's
Speaker 7:  blocking Alex's Plex server use net to block. You can block Google with
Speaker 7:  some gradations. You can block Google search, which no one will do. And then
Speaker 7:  you can block the other stuff. Right? You can block Google's AI training,
Speaker 7:  but no one is willing to say, I'm so mad at Google for scraping all of our
Speaker 7:  stuff that we're gonna block search. And I think that's when that one
Speaker 7:  flips and people are like, it is worth it to be invisible to Google. Like
Speaker 7:  the architecture of the internet changes. Yes. All right, we gotta take a
Speaker 7:  break. We're gonna come back the lightning round sponsored by you.
Speaker 15:  It's been a big week for Taylor Swift and Drake, but they weren't
Speaker 15:  playing on one of their biggest platforms. Not a single one of their songs
Speaker 15:  was on TikTok. Instead we've got stuff like this.
Speaker 15:  Oh,
Speaker 14:  It's shame by your body,
Speaker 14:  the feeling, God,
Speaker 14:  it's,
Speaker 15:  And this, it's
Speaker 13:  Like my bear right? Whoa, my man
Speaker 13:  back at me sing it.
Speaker 15:  And good heavens this
Speaker 14:  Together
Speaker 14:  on
Speaker 15:  What on Today explained, we're looking into why the biggest record label
Speaker 15:  in the world is picking a fight with the app that's constantly promoting
Speaker 15:  their artists and why we are all caught in the middle.
Speaker 7:  We're back. Do you remember when Time Magazine said the person of the year
Speaker 7:  was you? Ugh. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it was the, the like little mirror. It was in a real mirror just
Speaker 5:  like
Speaker 7:  That was when print magazines had budget to put mirror on the cover of
Speaker 7:  magazines in every grocery store in America and be like, that person here
Speaker 7:  is you. you know, it was like a foggy people like holding their
Speaker 7:  carrots be like, what?
Speaker 5:  It was all like curvy warp looking. Oh
Speaker 7:  That's not me. I was here for milk, not conceptual print ideas.
Speaker 7:  So you're
Speaker 8:  Saying y'all didn't frame yours and put it up next to on the Wars? Is
Speaker 8:  that not that's not what you did. That's weird.
Speaker 7:  Donald Trump has like the fake one and I'm like, this
Speaker 7:  one's real like it's me, you guys.
Speaker 5:  He looks at it everywhere. Kidding.
Speaker 7:  It's like it's me. I was for real that time. Alright.
Speaker 7:  I feel like all of my lightning on it entries are just complaining about
Speaker 7:  streaming the super Bowl. So Cranz, do you wanna first
Speaker 5:  Mine is like, I just find it fascinating. The, the big
Speaker 5:  big turn in the, the whole DMA thing with the
Speaker 5:  European Union, iMessage is not found to be a,
Speaker 5:  what is it? They call it Gatekeeper. Yeah. I iMessage is not found to
Speaker 5:  be a core platform service so that you, they're not
Speaker 5:  gonna make it open up, which feels probably right given that no one in the
Speaker 5:  EU
Speaker 7:  Well this is the trade Apple. Yeah. They've notably made the trade of saying
Speaker 7:  we will support RCS and I think this is what they got in
Speaker 7:  return.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So, so they're free and clear, as are my personal favorite.
Speaker 5:  Microsoft's Edge browser is not considered a core service
Speaker 5:  and Bing search was found to not be a core
Speaker 5:  service.
Speaker 7:  I don't think anybody has ever found Bing search to be a core service.
Speaker 5:  No, I I just, I really loved that it was like, okay, iMessage
Speaker 5:  like damn it and then Edge and then
Speaker 5:  Bing, you know,
Speaker 7:  Not even the bureaucrats of the European Union to bring themselves to regulate
Speaker 7:  Bing.
Speaker 5:  I wonder if they just like chuckled. They're like, oh no.
Speaker 7:  One thing that is really interesting in the mix there
Speaker 7:  is is Apple broke web apps in the EU.
Speaker 7:  So for a minute it looked like Apple would support what's called progressive
Speaker 7:  web apps in the iPhone where you have a web app, you can save it to your
Speaker 7:  home screen, you push the button, it loads up in a wrapper and it feels
Speaker 7:  just like an a normal app. This is great. Yeah. I think this is
Speaker 7:  like in terms of out, like
Speaker 5:  Out, that's how I do The.
Speaker 7:  Verge. Yeah. That's how I do The Verge. That's how I do our cms. When I want
Speaker 7:  to post a quick post really fast Ooh That's smart. A quick link that just
Speaker 7:  opens up a web wrapper. It's not in safari. And Apple broke it two
Speaker 7:  betas ago in iOS 17 and they didn't say anything about why.
Speaker 7:  And then today they finally released a statement on their developer portal
Speaker 7:  that's like, well we have to support other browsers in iOS now their browser.
Speaker 7:  And as you know, they all have to be equal. So how could we possibly
Speaker 7:  re-architect all of iOS to support launching a web app and another browser
Speaker 7:  engine from the home screen. So we just shut it off and it's like, dude,
Speaker 7:  stop doing malicious compliance.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like that was just like, like kicking and screaming. Like that's just
Speaker 5:  a hissy
Speaker 7:  Fit. Like do you know what platform supports PWAs and allows other browser
Speaker 7:  engines and Android? It's right there. Yeah, you can just look at
Speaker 7:  it.
Speaker 5:  It's just whiny. It's
Speaker 7:  Like don't be whiny. It's the most popular operating system on earth.
Speaker 8:  Meanwhile, the other browser makers have spent the last few weeks making
Speaker 8:  very clear to everyone that Apple has actually, if anything, made it harder
Speaker 8:  to be a browser maker in the EU now because you essentially have to run many
Speaker 8:  different versions of your app inside your one app and
Speaker 8:  it's just going to make everyone's life impossible.
Speaker 5:  Apple, come on,
Speaker 8:  Great job. Apple.
Speaker 7:  Look, we don't talk about this aspect of companies very often. We treat companies
Speaker 7:  as sort of singular entities. There's a real split inside Apple right now
Speaker 7:  between the, the suits basically the policy and the
Speaker 7:  business folks and the very idealistic
Speaker 7:  engineers who make the products. Yeah. Yeah. And I think that that this
Speaker 7:  EU thing is really pushing on that split in a way that, you know, apple
Speaker 7:  is a very well run company. They're, they are mission driven in their
Speaker 7:  way. But I'm wondering how much of this stuff
Speaker 7:  where it's like a bunch of pretty bad faith responses
Speaker 7:  to a law that's designed to make computers feel more like computers. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  You just wonder, you know, like someone had to like write the code to
Speaker 7:  break all the web apps in the EU
Speaker 5:  Just like furiously Yeah. Just like, like suit standing over their shoulder.
Speaker 5:  Just like, I hate you so much right now, but I'm gonna write the really good
Speaker 5:  code.
Speaker 7:  Right? Like Yeah. Some lawyer is like do the malicious compliance. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  you know, and they like file the Jira ticket and the Jira ticket is just
Speaker 7:  labeled malicious compliance. That's kind of suck. That's all
Speaker 7:  I'm saying. Yeah. Like on the on on decoder, I'm always asking about how
Speaker 7:  decisions are made, but like how a decision actually gets implemented is
Speaker 7:  equally interesting to me. It's like someone had to file the Jira ticket.
Speaker 7:  It's like per DMA break web apps that
Speaker 7:  just,
Speaker 8:  There's three levers in Tim Cook's office. one of them says ship the thing,
Speaker 8:  the other one says buy that company. And the third one just says
Speaker 8:  malicious compliance
Speaker 8:  and he just pulls it and just like lights start flashing all over Apple Park.
Speaker 8:  And that's how everybody knows.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I don't know, there's something weird there that I, you know, I, again,
Speaker 7:  we usually think of companies as like singular entities. Yeah. Like there's
Speaker 7:  Tim Cook in the arms, you know, like and like Tim Cook is in control of all
Speaker 7:  the arms or the sooner we're try in arms and the arms are like, who are you
Speaker 7:  like,
Speaker 7:  like you made a messaging app. But these companies are tens of
Speaker 7:  thousands of people if not a hundred thousand people when they're at their
Speaker 7:  biggest Yeah. And they are not singular in that way. And I,
Speaker 7:  this is the sort of thing that I think I get that Apple's very mad at the
Speaker 7:  Europeans. My caution is this is the sort of thing that breaks a very idealistic
Speaker 7:  culture because you have to make everyone believe that you are totally
Speaker 7:  right. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And that this little move, which is not a very, which is a very
Speaker 7:  cynical kind of move, is actually is actually somehow idealistic in turn.
Speaker 7:  That's just complicated.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  All right. I basically did a lightning round under your lightning round,
Speaker 7:  but it was great but
Speaker 5:  It was good sub. Well yeah, we have like an aftershock, there's like a sub
Speaker 5:  lightning round under it.
Speaker 7:  You can sponsor an aftershock. I don't know if I take too.
Speaker 8:  I was just meant to
Speaker 7:  Say that.
Speaker 7:  Alright David, what's yours?
Speaker 8:  Mine, well I'm gonna, I'm gonna aftershock when we start complaining about
Speaker 8:  the super Bowl, so I'll come back to that. Mine was just, there was
Speaker 8:  this news this week from a Wall Street Journal report that Walmart might
Speaker 8:  buy Vizio. Yeah. Which I just find deeply
Speaker 8:  fascinating and also kind of to be a bummer. I feel like it wasn't that long
Speaker 8:  ago that we thought Vizio had a chance to be a really interesting forward
Speaker 8:  thinking player in
Speaker 7:  TVs. Yeah. That was 2011. I wrote a profile of Vizio in 2011. Was that
Speaker 8:  2011 was
Speaker 7:  It was like when we launched. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It was, it was was supposed to buy Visio what, 2017? Yeah. And then
Speaker 5:  after that it just kind of started to slow
Speaker 7:  The echo. I totally forgot. Remember
Speaker 8:  That fell
Speaker 5:  Apart And they came and they were like TV and then they disappeared and then
Speaker 5:  I could not get them to take the TV back. Didn't
Speaker 8:  They make a car at one point?
Speaker 7:  Yes. Yes. Yeah. That was a truly weird, yeah like, oh my God, that was just
Speaker 7:  a psyop. That was a Chinese government psyop.
Speaker 5:  I loved that company. That was a good time.
Speaker 7:  But anyway, but you remember the 2011 I wrote the profile Vizio. This guy
Speaker 7:  Matt McCrae was the CTO. He was a lot of fun. Do you remember they put out
Speaker 7:  Windows laptops and he kept saying they were bone stock. Oh yeah.
Speaker 7:  It was great. Loved that. All that was great. And they, they kept on trying
Speaker 7:  to expand by doing like fan service and the TV business was just their business.
Speaker 7:  Matt is now the CEO of Arlo cameras.
Speaker 7:  And I think physio is just like, really? They tried so many interesting
Speaker 7:  things. Remember when the TVs were just Chromecast? Yep.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I have one of those. Oh
Speaker 7:  Boy. But that's what everybody wanted
Speaker 5:  In practice.
Speaker 7:  This is like actually
Speaker 5:  They
Speaker 8:  Had like reveal that was the remote,
Speaker 5:  Right? I know. Yeah. I don't know where it is if,
Speaker 7:  But this is what I mean about
Speaker 5:  Revealed s it's fired my house one day.
Speaker 7:  Everyone in our audience is like, I don't want a smart tv, I just want a
Speaker 7:  panel. The and then the like ship the thing.
Speaker 5:  But it had no remote. We wanted a remote. I still wanna be able to turn up
Speaker 5:  the volume without having to charge my
Speaker 7:  Damn. Everyone was like, I just want a dumb tv. I don't want da da da. And
Speaker 7:  and then they shipped it and they're like, no, I don't want that. Yeah, I
Speaker 7:  want giving a smart tv. I
Speaker 5:  Like the day the update came and I like, I I didn't even, it must've come
Speaker 5:  months in advance and I turned that TV on 'cause it's like my bedroom TV
Speaker 5:  so it's never on. Yeah. I turned it on and I was like, oh my Visio is smart
Speaker 5:  now And it was much more usable. Yeah. And then I was very upset 'cause I
Speaker 5:  was like, that wasn't the promise. Yeah. It got
Speaker 7:  Bummed, it revealed preferences man, everyone wants to run some weird data
Speaker 7:  tracking smart TV operating system. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  So $2 billion Walmart wants to buy Vizio.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And it just feels like that's a lot of money
Speaker 8:  also to basically improve its house brand of
Speaker 8:  TVs, which is essentially what Walmart would be doing. Yeah. I would remind
Speaker 8:  you that it's existing House brand is called on with two ends.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So I would spend $2 billion to not have on with two ends as my
Speaker 8:  house brand of anything like
Speaker 5:  Vizio Hass kind of gotten embodied by TCL in, in high sense in the last
Speaker 5:  few years in the budget TV market. So it's Yeah, like
Speaker 8:  What a bleak statement though, right? Yeah. Like that like the fact that
Speaker 8:  that is true and that is true. Yeah. Is so, it's such a bummer.
Speaker 5:  It's so yeah. The place the TV market is right now go from like,
Speaker 5:  it was such a good company because okay, you could get the TV in and it wouldn't
Speaker 5:  necessarily be like, like you'd have to fiddle with it. You'd have to mess
Speaker 5:  around, but then it could look really, really pretty and you'd be like, oh
Speaker 5:  Helly crap. I spent like half of what I could have spent on an LG and I have
Speaker 5:  a great looking TV and now that's just not quite the
Speaker 5:  case anymore.
Speaker 8:  First and now the whole TV business is collecting data on people who watch
Speaker 8:  you while you put up your webcam. The first Yeah. Vizio
Speaker 8:  is is has been doing that being
Speaker 5:  Sued. Yeah. Like Vizio is, Vizio was a, was a really
Speaker 5:  a thought leader in that department for a while there. Unfortunate
Speaker 5:  for all of us.
Speaker 7:  Well that's how they made the TVs cheap. I mean this was Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That was their sub. Like they, they essentially subsidized it and, and, and
Speaker 5:  then Roku came in and was like, we can do it better because
Speaker 5:  our, our operating system is actually usable. And, and
Speaker 5:  that's why Roku like partnered with Hisense. That's why they partnered with
Speaker 5:  with TCL and, and now Roku is this really dominant
Speaker 5:  force in advertising and in TVs And Vizio
Speaker 5:  is off in the corner being like, let go. I blame you for every
Speaker 8:  Well Roku also came to people and said, we have an advertising business that
Speaker 8:  we'll give you a cut of. And that has become a business for Walmart
Speaker 8:  that it thinks it can do more like it's just all, this is a lot
Speaker 8:  of money being thrown around for big deals and big companies and none of
Speaker 8:  it is about making good televisions. And that just sucks.
Speaker 5:  That sucks.
Speaker 7:  You know, it's a great television. It's Sony 8 9 5
Speaker 8:  That watches you while you're,
Speaker 7:  I trying to watch tv I the camera and I turned all this stuff off
Speaker 5:  Was like, try to do it another meeting with that tv. Tell us how great it's,
Speaker 5:  it's not
Speaker 7:  Gonna happen. We're we're done messing with the features of the
Speaker 7:  television. Did you have to like
Speaker 5:  Go and put the webcam back in a box? Oh
Speaker 7:  I, the webcam was just like quickly discarded. Yeah I've got like, I've
Speaker 7:  got a drawer that I just think of as the e-waste drawer. Yeah. And it's like
Speaker 7:  maybe one day I'll be like, where is that webcam and I'm gonna open the EWA
Speaker 7:  drawer. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 8:  Speaking of, let's complain about the Super Bowl.
Speaker 7:  Alright. I have a lot to say about this whole situation.
Speaker 7:  It is an embarrassment that in America on the
Speaker 7:  most washed super Bowl ever Oh
Speaker 8:  Lord.
Speaker 7:  Where America's sweetheart
Speaker 7:  did something with Travis Kelsey on that field. She won the super Bowl, she
Speaker 7:  won the super Bowl. Actually can I just say this other, you know there's
Speaker 7:  a video clip of them running to each other after the super Bowl and she like
Speaker 7:  hug each other and then finally the clip with the audio came out 'cause he
Speaker 7:  was micd up. Yeah. And he is like, I love you, thank you for coming. I appreciate
Speaker 7:  you. Thank you for flying halfway around in the world. And then he says,
Speaker 7:  was it Electric? And she's like, it was unbelievable.
Speaker 7:  I have asked Becky if shit was Electric like 50 times a day
Speaker 7:  since I've seen that clip. Like I'm like pouring the coffee. Like was it
Speaker 7:  Electric easily the best thing to come outta the entire Taylor Swift Travis
Speaker 7:  Kelsey story for me. Fantastic. It's just constantly asking Becky if things
Speaker 7:  are and she's like, no, she's, she does not think
Speaker 7:  it was unbelievable.
Speaker 5:  She shut down immediately.
Speaker 7:  No. Anyway, so, so you were not streamed in
Speaker 7:  4K but kind of streamed 4K So I Paramount Plus I think David, that's
Speaker 7:  where you watched it. That is where I
Speaker 8:  Watched it. That's
Speaker 5:  Where I watched 30 minutes of it.
Speaker 7:  They only gave a 4K stream to cable companies.
Speaker 7:  So nothing direct from CBS. So If you had cable or
Speaker 7:  DirecTV, you could switch to a 4K
Speaker 7:  CBS channel, which was upscaled 10 80
Speaker 7:  PHDR. So it already looked weird.
Speaker 7:  one of the most vibrant cable companies in America is YouTube.
Speaker 7:  So you YouTube tv, you can pay for the 4K add-on which I turned off of ages
Speaker 7:  ago 'cause it was not worth it. So I paid the 10 bucks for
Speaker 7:  4K for the month and I go to watch it and the
Speaker 7:  bit rate keeps crashing on YouTube tv just like I'm watching my
Speaker 7:  router. It starts, you know, like, yeah, 15 or 20 or whatever the 4K
Speaker 7:  stream would be at not even that high. It's like eight and then it just
Speaker 7:  like, just dropped like a stone. That's brutal. And I
Speaker 7:  kept switching back to the 10 80 p feed on CBS and it looked great. Why didn't
Speaker 7:  you switch over So? I saw my internet
Speaker 5:  Switch over to Nickelodeon.
Speaker 7:  Everyone told me Nickelodeon stream looked great.
Speaker 5:  It was a, it looked beautiful. Yeah. Dora the explorer explained what illegal
Speaker 5:  holding is. Fantastic. And now I
Speaker 7:  Know and at the end they, they slimed everyone I believe on the feed. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  it was good. Just a disaster. And some people thought
Speaker 7:  it was working great, but I post on threads like this bit rate keeps crashing
Speaker 7:  and too many people agreed with me. Yeah. That it was a bad experience for
Speaker 7:  me to think that it was like my internet. I switched from the Apple
Speaker 7:  tv, YouTube TV app to the Android app on the Sony tv
Speaker 7:  assuming Google would, you know, like a good gatekeeper. Yeah. Would preference
Speaker 7:  its own service on its own operating system. It worked for slightly longer.
Speaker 7:  It worked for five minutes before it crashed but then it, then it crashed.
Speaker 8:  Well we hope it will make sense over time. Eli
Speaker 5:  Is Max Sports or whatever this new super sports streaming service
Speaker 5:  called, is that gonna save the super Bowl once
Speaker 5:  it once out
Speaker 7:  The super Bowl does not need to be saved. Well,
Speaker 5:  You know, like save it from bad streaming experiences.
Speaker 7:  I I just think it is fundamentally embarrassing that we as a
Speaker 7:  nation cannot figure this out. Look, you go to watch soccer
Speaker 7:  in in England and they're like, it's 10 4K feeds anywhere
Speaker 7:  you want to be. It's free. And also there's free healthcare and like what
Speaker 7:  are we doing?
Speaker 5:  As you said that I saw like an American flag drop behind you and I just like
Speaker 5:  heard the, the the American music.
Speaker 7:  Oh yeah. Someone's getting mad at me for not being sufficiently patriotic
Speaker 7:  that we have to watch upscale 10 80 p No,
Speaker 5:  No. I thought that was the most patriotic thing I've seen
Speaker 7:  In a while. You have to figure this out. Fix the super
Speaker 5:  Bowl. I also, speaking of, of sports, I, I made a, a
Speaker 5:  big gaff last week because I, I mistakenly said that
Speaker 5:  Fox sports channels are owned by Disney
Speaker 5:  and that is only true and I believe Argentina in some parts of South America,
Speaker 5:  that's
Speaker 8:  Where all the listeners are. It's fine.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It is not owned by Disney in
Speaker 5:  America where it is owned by Fox.
Speaker 7:  Fox, right. Rupert Murdoch. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's it's still owned by Rupert. I, I forgot but but Disney does own it.
Speaker 5:  Just, just not in this country.
Speaker 5:  I'm sorry. I would
Speaker 8:  Just like to say two things about that. One, we screwed that up and it was
Speaker 8:  complicated.
Speaker 5:  It was very embarrassing. I was annoyed. But
Speaker 8:  Two, it makes this whole thing even funnier because it now is even more
Speaker 8:  like Hulu. It is
Speaker 7:  Three
Speaker 8:  Direct competitors being like, let's be best friends. We'll figure this out.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, it's fantastic.
Speaker 5:  It's so good. And, and If you, it's also very funny, If, you go and look
Speaker 5:  at Fox Sports on like the Wikipedia page and it says current owners and there's
Speaker 5:  a list of like six current owners depending on what region you're in. I was
Speaker 5:  like,
Speaker 7:  That's good. Help out.
Speaker 5:  Come on Fox. Like just one company owned the company,
Speaker 5:  please.
Speaker 7:  No, that's not Ripper's breaking up his empire. Yeah. And by the way, you
Speaker 7:  need Fox Sports because you have to have Fox Sports because of football.
Speaker 5:  I mean I don't but
Speaker 7:  But look, the cable companies do. Oh yeah, that's true. And to get Fox sports,
Speaker 7:  you have to carry Fox News. Right. That's a real thing. They leverage each
Speaker 7:  other. Fox News.
Speaker 5:  I mean, it
Speaker 7:  Is like, I have a lot of feelings about Fox News, Fox D's on its own popular,
Speaker 7:  but they are a bundle deal.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. They are unstoppable.
Speaker 7:  You can't get football without taking the other thing. Yeah. That's not,
Speaker 7:  that's not a choice for you. Right. Which many cable operators have always
Speaker 7:  sort of like been aware of. Yeah. That's America. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  All I'm saying is we could stream it in forehand. How was Paramount Plus,
Speaker 7:  I know you watched on Paramount Plus.
Speaker 8:  Okay. I would just like to briefly complain about this. I try not to use
Speaker 8:  The Verge as a place to be annoyed at customer service things. But
Speaker 8:  Paramount plus sucked for me during the Super Bowl and I'm very upset about
Speaker 8:  it. So for a while it just didn't work at all. It would throw up
Speaker 8:  like a mysterious, a bad thing happened, we don't know, try again.
Speaker 8:  And then I would try again and it wouldn't work. But eventually it worked
Speaker 8:  and it actually streamed fine and looked fine. But this incredible thing
Speaker 8:  kept happening, which is that the audio would get about
Speaker 8:  eight seconds ahead of the video. And so literally
Speaker 8:  every single time the play would've just finished
Speaker 8:  before I saw the play. So Jim Nance would be like shouting about how
Speaker 8:  Brandon IU caught it for 20 yards, right. As their snapping ball.
Speaker 8:  It made it so unpleasant to watch this game. It was like So, I literal,
Speaker 8:  literally stopped looking at it for a while. I was like, I'm gonna listen
Speaker 8:  to this like it's radio and Tony Romos just gonna say nonsensical
Speaker 8:  things at me. but it was just, I kept, I would like p
Speaker 8:  try to pause and you can't because it's live and it's illegal to pause things
Speaker 8:  or something. I would go out of the app and come back in and it would work
Speaker 8:  fine. And then go back to being off by about the same amount. I rebooted
Speaker 8:  my TV at one point. I did the whole Roku reboot at one point.
Speaker 7:  That's bad. Oh,
Speaker 5:  You were on a Roku. See there was your problem.
Speaker 7:  Those letters bouncing at you when you wanna watch TV and, and it's like,
Speaker 7:  do do.
Speaker 8:  Oh my gosh.
Speaker 5:  You like, you got your food right in front of you. Nightmare.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I'm telling you, watching those letters bounce when you reboot a Roku
Speaker 7:  and you're just trying to get there. And was there anyone else in the room
Speaker 7:  with you? It's like they're taunting you. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I also think this was also a little bit like Paramount was getting back at
Speaker 5:  David particularly because he makes fun of how much I enjoy Paramount. Plus
Speaker 8:  I have said a lot mean things about Paramount plus So. I did deserve this.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. But like, we're square now. Paramount little car. Listen, Sherry Redstone,
Speaker 8:  we're cool.
Speaker 7:  Now What, what, what, what heartened me was the number of people
Speaker 7:  responding to my complaints about streaming sports and internet by telling
Speaker 7:  me to get an antenna. And I thought of you Alex. Aw. I did not dig out.
Speaker 7:  Antenna with, yeah. 15 people in my home.
Speaker 7:  Like I've already switched operating systems. I'm, we're not doing
Speaker 7:  antenna up runs right now. That's
Speaker 5:  Great. It's a good time.
Speaker 7:  We did watch the halftime show at the low bit rate, 'cause I couldn't switch
Speaker 7:  it to the other stream in the middle. Did
Speaker 5:  You watch Apple? Oh, can I complain
Speaker 8:  About another version about Paramount Plus? Yeah. Yeah. So I,
Speaker 8:  like the genius that I am, opened up Paramount Plus,
Speaker 8:  after one of my many reboots clicked on the thing that said the
Speaker 8:  football game, and it took me to a separate channel where they were talking
Speaker 8:  about the football game. So I was like, oh, this is just the halftime show
Speaker 8:  before the thing. And then Anna, my wife gets a text from her friend being
Speaker 8:  like, oh, are you watching Usher? He's sick. And I'm sitting there telling
Speaker 8:  her that it must not have started yet. And it turns out that when I clicked
Speaker 8:  on football, it didn't click on football. It clicked on something else for
Speaker 8:  me. And didn't So I missed like three quarters of Usher because it didn't
Speaker 8:  select the thing that it was supposed to select.
Speaker 5:  You. You can watch it on the Apple TV app.
Speaker 7:  You're doing great, David.
Speaker 8:  I'm still angry.
Speaker 7:  I feel like a lot of your choices are your fault. Like my
Speaker 8:  Archer took his shirt off NELI and I missed it. I
Speaker 7:  Missed it. My You did, you did.
Speaker 8:  I did see the roller skates though, so it was
Speaker 5:  Okay. The roller skates were sick. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Can I just say it was Electric?
Speaker 7:  I wanna just do a Quick Atmos music update for everyone. We installed
Speaker 7:  the big home theater. Yeah. In our house. It's done. Or we,
Speaker 7:  if you've been listening to Virtual House since September when we moved into
Speaker 7:  our new house in the background has been construction sounds every time I
Speaker 7:  record from my house. 'cause we've just been renovating. It's done now.
Speaker 7:  Only two things that need to be done. Who knows if they'll ever get done,
Speaker 7:  but the, it's done and the TVs are done and we have a 5.1 0.4
Speaker 7:  Atmos system. It's, it's cool. Yeah, I like it. And
Speaker 7:  So I texted a friend who believes in Atmos music more than
Speaker 7:  I do. And I said, this is as much of a chance as I can ever give
Speaker 7:  this boondoggle. And he sent me a list of things to listen to. Random
Speaker 7:  Access Memories by Def Punk, the Dua Lipa record
Speaker 7:  a bunch of other stuff. And So I like listened to it. I was also told that
Speaker 7:  Amazon music is better. It's, it, they, their
Speaker 7:  codec is better than Apple. So I. I compare, I'm doing my best. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Really running into ground
Speaker 7:  two things I've discovered. One,
Speaker 7:  the only idea anyone has is putting percussion
Speaker 7:  accents behind you.
Speaker 7:  Like someone cowbell, someone rings a cowbell and it's like, behind you,
Speaker 7:  it's like, like every song with anything like that. Like a Tom Phil
Speaker 7:  that's going around you. And that's, that's what we got. Yeah. And we've
Speaker 7:  solved that problem. Like in the manual of how to remix a song for Atmos.
Speaker 7:  It's like, if there's any sort of percussion accent,
Speaker 7:  get it back there. Two, and I've been joking about this
Speaker 7:  for, I want to say over a year in the Atmos remix
Speaker 7:  of Come Together by the Beatles.
Speaker 7:  George Harrison sneaks up behind you playing the guitar.
Speaker 7:  This is your dream. You've been waiting for this. Was it Slow Sneak, was
Speaker 7:  it? No, it, yeah, it, it, it, it's at the very end.
Speaker 7:  you know, there's like little, just like a little guitar like Yeah. Happening
Speaker 7:  come together and it starts behind you and then it comes
Speaker 7:  in front of you. It was like he was in the room with you. Like each successive
Speaker 7:  one gets closer and closer and then it's in front of you at the end. And
Speaker 7:  you have to understand, I'm like, I'm like listening to this at like 11:45 PM
Speaker 7:  alone. Just cracking up, just
Speaker 7:  losing my mind. Like, this is the funniest thing that's happened. It's so,
Speaker 7:  it's just like me rewinding come together over and over again and be like,
Speaker 7:  no, that's real.
Speaker 7:  It's very good. I encourage everyone to listen to it. The we we're
Speaker 7:  done here at Atmos has been completed. You've solved it.
Speaker 7:  It actually happened.
Speaker 7:  It's, it's, it's very funny. This is huge for, you know, it's like deeply
Speaker 7:  meaningfully funny. If you know of any other
Speaker 7:  songs where the guitar player sneaks up from you, please let
Speaker 7:  me know. It is my now my Go-to demo song.
Speaker 7:  Dare I say. It's Electric.
Speaker 7:  All right, we got, we gotta end this show. Tom will be on to talk about some
Speaker 7:  actual news that happened with Microsoft soon.
Speaker 7:  We are now on the main YouTube channel. So go listen there. I want to call
Speaker 7:  out, we started the second episode of Decoder. So we have two
Speaker 7:  every week now. We, on Mondays we do the big interviews, CEOs and so on.
Speaker 7:  And then on Thursdays we run an explainer with Virgin
Speaker 7:  reporters and other friends of the show. Just figurine out big topics this
Speaker 7:  week was AI and copyright law, which is why I'm bringing it up with Sora
Speaker 7:  Jung, who is wonderful.
Speaker 8:  It's a good one. And it's like, it'll anyone who has been listening to us
Speaker 8:  rants and rave about that will enjoy that. You should go.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, that's a good one. And then David, you've got a big right to repair
Speaker 7:  story on the Tuesday episode of Vir this week,
Speaker 8:  Right? Yeah. So Will Poor, our newest producer has been running around basically
Speaker 8:  trying to figure out what in the world, all of this right to repair stuff
Speaker 8:  actually means. And he's gonna spend a bunch of time this year
Speaker 8:  telling us sort of different stories from different parts of the right to
Speaker 8:  repair world. And his first one is coming on Tuesday. So the episode's gonna
Speaker 8:  be that. And Tom, it's gonna be fun episode. Definitely stay tuned.
Speaker 7:  Will's just gonna fix stuff, so mail him your broken gaskets. The
Speaker 8:  End of this is definitely Will Opens a repair shop. Like there's just no
Speaker 8:  question. That's not how this ends. It's gonna be amazing.
Speaker 7:  Finally, finally, we're on one of those, those kiosks in the mall
Speaker 7:  that can change your badge. It's always been our dream. And then
Speaker 8:  He'll sponsor the lightning ground.
Speaker 7:  Should we call 'em Aftershocks or Shock Waves? Let us know. Vergecast at
Speaker 7:  The Verge dot com. That's it. That's Vergecast Rock and roll.
Speaker 17:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 17:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The Vergecast is the
Speaker 17:  production of the Virgin and Vox Media Podcast network. Our show is produced
Speaker 17:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.