# Transcript
ID: b777ea50-ae13-48b8-b5a7-9c993fc80a4b
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7531127006055381790/2542259861709541661/s93290-US-1657s-1715505552.mp3
Description: In episode two of our Five Senses of Gaming miniseries, David Pierce dives into the world of hearing with audio-only video games with Paul Bennun, who has been in this space longer than most. Years ago, Bennun and his team at Somethin’ Else made a series of games called Papa Sangre that were among the most innovative and most popular games of their kind. He explains what makes an audio game work, why the iPhone 4 was such a crucial technological achievement for these games, and more.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (10 ads detected)
Speaker 3:  episode. This week's sense is hearing sound and I
Speaker 3:  wanna start by telling you about a game I've been playing a lot over the
Speaker 3:  last few weeks. It's called Blind Drive
Speaker 4:  Start driving.
Speaker 4:  What the hell wait.
Speaker 3:  Here's the story of Blind Drive, which is available for lots of platforms,
Speaker 3:  but I've been playing it on my phone. You're the main character. You thought
Speaker 3:  you were taking part in a scientific study, but suddenly you find yourself
Speaker 3:  driving a car against traffic with a blindfold on. You
Speaker 3:  can't see anything. The only way to survive is by hearing the cars,
Speaker 3:  trucks and cops and bikers and whatever else coming at you and then tapping
Speaker 3:  on the phone screen to steer away from them. The longer you make it, the
Speaker 3:  higher your score and the happier you make this scary sounding guy on the
Speaker 3:  phone.
Speaker 4:  Okay, good.
Speaker 3:  I've never played a game quite like this before. It's really intense and
Speaker 3:  really fun and I find myself way more focused on it because
Speaker 3:  it's all based on sound. I'm on edge all the time playing it.
Speaker 3:  It's kind of a lot. Honestly, it's been fun to play this too because it
Speaker 3:  feels so different than what I'm used to. We live in such visual
Speaker 3:  times right now. We scroll vertical video, we look at our TVs,
Speaker 3:  we put on VR headsets, we play these huge gorgeous open world
Speaker 3:  games. There's just always so much to look at all the time, but
Speaker 3:  there's something really powerful and different about audio. I mean, you
Speaker 3:  get it, you listen to podcasts. Podcasts are proof of how cool and
Speaker 3:  powerful audio can be, but I'd never really even thought about audio as
Speaker 3:  more than just a feature of video games. It's a way to make explosions
Speaker 3:  sound more real or at the very most alert you to when someone is
Speaker 3:  sneaking up behind you. But there's actually a rich history of audio games,
Speaker 3:  video games without the pictures and some reasons to think those games
Speaker 3:  might be coming back. One of the people responsible for a big part of that
Speaker 3:  history is this guy.
Speaker 5:  That's right, and to as a baby on A B, BC model. B because
Speaker 5:  I'm that old and wrote it was my first game isn't,
Speaker 5:  you know, in quotes, my first video game,
Speaker 3:  Paul's route into audio games was a windy one that actually makes
Speaker 3:  perfect sense in retrospect. He was really into games as a kid. He was writing
Speaker 3:  code on A B, BC model B in the eighties by actually
Speaker 3:  copying it out of a magazine. That was how you wrote code back then. Then
Speaker 3:  Paul got into the music business and the broadcast radio business and then
Speaker 3:  he actually ended up directing a video game version of the Game show. You
Speaker 3:  don't know Jack,
Speaker 6:  It's time for the show where high culture and pop culture
Speaker 6:  collide. Yeah, woo. Alright. We got
Speaker 6:  ourselves 1, 2, 3 players on board the flight today. Making
Speaker 3:  That game he told me was mostly about making the audio.
Speaker 5:  All of the effort of that game sort of went into phenomenal writing, good
Speaker 5:  game design and smoking mirrors that would make it seem like you were
Speaker 5:  talk that you, the player were inside a live TV
Speaker 5:  game show and doing that kind of reawaken my, my
Speaker 5:  love for technology and creative technology and I've, I've really been doing
Speaker 5:  that ever since.
Speaker 3:  At this point Paul had built lots of different kinds of games, but he had
Speaker 3:  always thought it would be cool to make one that was all audio for
Speaker 3:  a couple of reasons. Actually,
Speaker 5:  There was a broadcaster in the UK called Channel four. They were
Speaker 5:  originally sort of looking for for games that were accessible, the
Speaker 5:  games that could be played by communities who were generally excluded from
Speaker 5:  from playing games. And so I didn't wanna make a game
Speaker 5:  for people with a quote disability. I wanted to make games
Speaker 5:  that everyone could play and that everyone would love without any
Speaker 5:  compromise.
Speaker 3:  Eventually he decides to do just that, build an audio only
Speaker 3:  game. At this point it's about 2010, which is important because
Speaker 3:  there was a big technological development that happened in 2010. The
Speaker 3:  iPhone four came out, it had a bunch of new features like the retina display
Speaker 3:  and the selfie camera and it eventually was the one that went through all
Speaker 3:  that antennagate stuff. Remember that the whole Steve Jobs, you're holding
Speaker 3:  it wrong thing. But for Paul there was a significantly less
Speaker 3:  publicized new feature that really, really, really mattered.
Speaker 5:  IPhone four was the first of Apple's devices that had hardware acceleration
Speaker 5:  for floating point math. Now why is that important? It's important
Speaker 5:  because we were doing real time
Speaker 5:  binaural synthesis on a mobile device. So let's talk about binaural audio.
Speaker 5:  I have two ears, most people have two ears, but not everyone has two ears
Speaker 5:  and you might think that that therefore that we listen in stereo. Well we
Speaker 5:  don't. The shape of your, the fleshy bit of your ear, the pinner has got
Speaker 5:  these folds in it, these lumps and folds.
Speaker 3:  You probably know the basics of this sound hits your ears at different
Speaker 3:  times. Your brain does a huge amount of work to both make all of that
Speaker 3:  sound. Makes sense. And also to intuit where that sound is coming from
Speaker 3:  based on when it hits all those lumps and folds,
Speaker 5:  What it turns out that you can do is that you can get an artificial head
Speaker 5:  with two good microphones where the ears would be and you can
Speaker 5:  blaze some white noise at that head from lots and lots of different
Speaker 5:  directions and you can work out how the human head
Speaker 5:  hears those sounds from different sources and you can express that in terms
Speaker 5:  of a big table of numbers. Now what I can do is I can take away the white
Speaker 5:  noise and I can apply those numbers to an arbitrary bit of
Speaker 5:  audio, an arbitrary audio file, and I can get the right bit of the right
Speaker 5:  number from where I want this sound to sound like where it's coming from.
Speaker 3:  I'm way oversimplifying here. But basically, once you can map sound, the
Speaker 3:  way Paul's describing, you can manipulate it, delay sound coming
Speaker 3:  from a spot on the right, just a tiny bit and it'll sound like the thing
Speaker 3:  over there is further away increase sound in the front and decrease it
Speaker 3:  behind and boom, you have something right smack in front of your face. This
Speaker 3:  is a simple enough concept, but it's really, really tricky math.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, and you're gonna do that by the way, 44,000 times a second
Speaker 5:  or 48,000 times a second because that's a typical sampling
Speaker 5:  rate for for digital audio. So as you can see, that requires a lot of
Speaker 5:  math. Pre iPhone four, there wasn't a device that could do it and
Speaker 5:  Apple helped us out a lot by the way, with with the accelerate framework,
Speaker 5:  which which came in at that point, which enabled us to, to do this. So
Speaker 5:  it's actually pretty simple to, it's the same as in any video game, right?
Speaker 5:  Imagine there's, you've got an X and y coordinates, you've got a grid in
Speaker 5:  front of you, there's X and y, and as objects move relative to the player,
Speaker 5:  you can change the x axis and you can change the yxi and you can calculate
Speaker 5:  where the object is. So it's just the same in that regard between
Speaker 5:  a video game and an audio game. In a video game you're just saying, well,
Speaker 5:  you know that the monster has walked diagonally away from you. So now I can
Speaker 5:  change the x axis and the Y axis position and I, I can just render that object
Speaker 5:  and you know, I'm watching it on my screen. Everyone's happy. And you can
Speaker 5:  do exactly the same thing with, with audio games. It's just that instead
Speaker 5:  of rendering it using whatever technique you are using to, to render an
Speaker 5:  object in, in a in video, you are just applying a bit of
Speaker 5:  math to the the frequencies of the audio and now all of a sudden the human
Speaker 5:  being hears it, it really hears it. The pictures are better on radio
Speaker 5:  as they say, what
Speaker 3:  He's describing I should say is super normal. Now it's just
Speaker 3:  spatial audio. The idea that you can anchor something in place and then as
Speaker 3:  you like turn your head or the object itself moves, the sound moves
Speaker 3:  with it, lots of devices have this now and you can use it to all
Speaker 3:  kinds of good and dumb effects, but at the time it was revolutionary,
Speaker 3:  especially when you also had a mobile phone with you that could accurately
Speaker 3:  track your movement in space.
Speaker 5:  We had to have an input scheme, an input control scheme in terms of changing
Speaker 5:  the relative position of the player and the audio that was incredibly
Speaker 5:  precise. You could do it with a mouse, but there was some drawbacks to that.
Speaker 5:  It's far, far better. The human being themselves is doing the turning,
Speaker 5:  like the head is turning itself or the body is turning and
Speaker 5:  with Vision Pro and with the current generation of spatial
Speaker 5:  AirPods and so on, well we're used to that now we actually understand that
Speaker 5:  now back in the day that didn't exist. So we kind of had to kind of
Speaker 5:  create the hardware effect that you get from specialized
Speaker 5:  headphones without the existence of specialized headphones. And the only
Speaker 5:  way that we could really see to do that was with the accelerometer and the
Speaker 5:  magnetometer inside iPhones.
Speaker 3:  So with all of this suddenly possible Ben and his team at a company
Speaker 3:  called something else set out to build an audio only game. They ended up
Speaker 3:  calling it Papa Sangre.
Speaker 8:  Now do as I say, or very soon
Speaker 8:  you'll forget everything and everyone you've ever known,
Speaker 3:  The plot of Papa Sangre is pretty simple. I'd feel bad spoiling it
Speaker 3:  for you, but the game is 13 years old and you literally can't download it
Speaker 3:  anymore. So here it goes, you're dead. You're stuck in Papa
Speaker 3:  Sangres kingdom and the only way out is by completing a journey through five
Speaker 3:  different palaces. All the bad guys and monsters are everywhere
Speaker 3:  and they're trying to stop you. All those bad guys and monsters respond to
Speaker 3:  sound. So you have to move as quietly as you can while also
Speaker 3:  looking for clues and talking to characters and generally trying to figure
Speaker 3:  out what's going on and where to go because you can't see anything,
Speaker 3:  there's nothing to see.
Speaker 8:  The ice is thin. You need to be careful
Speaker 3:  Making a game like this. Work is on one level, not that complicated.
Speaker 3:  You can sort of do anything you want in audio. You can make audio
Speaker 3:  pong just by using spatial audio to help you understand where the paddle
Speaker 3:  and ball are.
Speaker 3:  You can make audio Tetris Paul also says, which seems wild,
Speaker 3:  you can kind of make audio anything In the second version of Papa Sangre,
Speaker 3:  there was even a duck hunt style shooting game where you just followed the
Speaker 3:  sound of the ducks and you turn and shoot the ducks at the right moment.
Speaker 3:  Paul and his team built a few of these games over time before deciding
Speaker 3:  that wasn't what they wanted to do. It didn't feel right. We gotta take a
Speaker 3:  break and then I'll tell you why
Speaker 3:  Welcome back. So at this point in our story, it's right around
Speaker 3:  2013 after working on Papa Sangre, the team at
Speaker 3:  something else made a game called Audio Defense, which is just a
Speaker 3:  straightforward shooter game. This is the kind of thing Paul meant when
Speaker 3:  he talked about audio pong and audio Tetris. It's just a normal game with
Speaker 3:  normal mechanics but with no pictures. In audio defense
Speaker 3:  there are waves of bad guys coming at you, you shoot them, that's the
Speaker 3:  whole bit and it's all done just in audio.
Speaker 9:  There are zombies, you can hear them but you can't
Speaker 9:  see them turn carefully until the zombie sound is in front of you.
Speaker 5:  It was a very interesting game in in that regard. It was a, a much more
Speaker 5:  sort of casual game sort of pickup put down and it was effective and it
Speaker 5:  worked. I think what what we realized after releasing that
Speaker 5:  game was that the natural benefits of audio games
Speaker 5:  meant that more artistic, more carefully considered
Speaker 5:  more complex experiences, certainly for our team with with
Speaker 5:  our skills, would probably find a better market fit than that game. You
Speaker 5:  would think that that game, if people like the other, the other Papa Sangre
Speaker 5:  games, the audio defense would just find a a larger audience. After all,
Speaker 5:  it's the same kind of mechanic, but it's much, much more simple and it's
Speaker 5:  much easier to understand. Funnily enough, that didn't happen, the game
Speaker 5:  didn't do as well as the other games.
Speaker 3:  There's something else team really thought audio defense was gonna be huge.
Speaker 3:  But in retrospect, Paul seems to think that it kind of makes sense that it
Speaker 3:  wasn't because the best audio games aren't just audio versions
Speaker 3:  of video games. There are some cool accessibility upsides to that
Speaker 3:  for sure, letting more people get access to these kinds of games. But he's
Speaker 3:  more intrigued by the idea of what you can only do in an audio
Speaker 3:  game.
Speaker 5:  It's related to the fact that the earliest way that that humans
Speaker 5:  told stories to each other would've course be round, you know, be verbally,
Speaker 5:  orally, round, round the campfire and there is a mode and a pacing
Speaker 5:  to that kind of storytelling and a way that
Speaker 5:  words can be used to conjure up images and ideas in the
Speaker 5:  listener that all of a sudden If you are just purely concentrating on in
Speaker 5:  terms of an audio game. You can also use and a
Speaker 5:  story told orally is very different to a story
Speaker 5:  told graphically. There are reasons of pacing, there are reasons
Speaker 5:  of how different ideas are introduced and and worked
Speaker 5:  on, but mainly again, it's because there's a complicity between
Speaker 5:  the listener and the storyteller that has a different kind of
Speaker 5:  suspension of disbelief or a different kind of enactment of belief, a different
Speaker 5:  kind of purposeful volition on on the part of the audience. And
Speaker 5:  it means that you have a, I'm not gonna say it's better or worse, I personally
Speaker 5:  think it's more interesting. You have a broader power of things that you
Speaker 5:  can do. Again, I've sort of sort of said it's more like a novel kind
Speaker 5:  of the, the subtlety and the complexity of the ideas that that you can introduce
Speaker 5:  and develop are just different from what you contend to do in,
Speaker 5:  in video games.
Speaker 3:  There's this longstanding debate in gaming about the role of storytelling.
Speaker 3:  There are those who think it's super important that cut scenes are crucial,
Speaker 3:  that you can do as much or more good narrative work in a game as you
Speaker 3:  can in a movie. And then there are those who just smash the A button to get
Speaker 3:  through cut scenes. I should confess I'm mostly one of those people, but
Speaker 3:  in an audio game there seems to just be more space, more freedom
Speaker 3:  to just let the story be the whole thing. Really you have no choice
Speaker 3:  but to be more thoughtful about it or the whole thing will just devolve into
Speaker 3:  chaos.
Speaker 5:  So if I'm playing a video game, think about how many different pieces of
Speaker 5:  information I can have on that screen at the same time. You know, If, you
Speaker 5:  think about something like any modern, highly polished AAA game.
Speaker 5:  You've typically got n numbers of different things about the status of you
Speaker 5:  as a, as a, let's say it's a first person shooter or a first person game
Speaker 5:  anyway, you've got n number of things that demonstrate the status of your
Speaker 5:  avatar of you, of you in the game. Plus you've got the ER position of
Speaker 5:  n number of different objects, plus you've got the different choice of weapon
Speaker 5:  or object in your, in your hand. There's just hundreds of different pieces
Speaker 5:  of information, you know, relative position of your other players and so
Speaker 5:  on. And human beings aren't that great when it comes to
Speaker 5:  discriminating usefully, discriminating lots of different sound
Speaker 5:  sources at the same time. We tend to try and focus on a small amount,
Speaker 5:  one or two sound sources at the same time. And there's an upper limit to
Speaker 5:  how many you can really have simultaneously before the human being just gonna
Speaker 5:  goes. Well you know, I, it's fine if I'm at a dinner
Speaker 5:  party or I'm a in a nightclub or if I'm on the street because I have a
Speaker 5:  bunch of other things in terms of situational context knowledge, contextual
Speaker 5:  knowledge that help me focus on the different things that are actually important
Speaker 5:  at that moment. But if I'm creating an entirely artificial
Speaker 5:  experience, then I have to be much, much more directed and much, much more
Speaker 5:  careful in terms of what I'm presenting to the player for them to,
Speaker 5:  to be able to focus on and get information which is gonna help them
Speaker 5:  enjoy the system because it needs to be fun and
Speaker 5:  trying to, you know, playing a game of what should I be listening to now
Speaker 5:  is is not fun.
Speaker 3:  Normally when you get to a big moment in a video game, there is so much going
Speaker 3:  on at all times, but here is a climactic moment in Papa
Speaker 3:  Sangre, just listen to how it goes.
Speaker 10:  We feed the hogs chicken meat, not your flesh.
Speaker 3:  This all sounds like kind of a niche thing now, but Papa Sangre
Speaker 3:  was a big hit and Papa Sangre too, even more so when
Speaker 3:  that second game the sequel came out in 2013, it was one of the
Speaker 3:  best reviewed games of the year with a 92% score on meta
Speaker 3:  critic
Speaker 5:  For most of the year. It was literally the best reviewed iPhone game of the
Speaker 5:  year and folks who classified themselves as blind
Speaker 5:  lost their shit. Someone had gone out and had tried to
Speaker 5:  assemble a, a team of talented people to make an experience
Speaker 5:  that had absolutely no compromise in terms of
Speaker 5:  its playability and its enjoyment.
Speaker 3:  I just went back and looked by the way, and it was actually tied for number
Speaker 3:  one in mobile games that year. The company behind it, Paul's company something
Speaker 3:  else, made a couple of other games and ended up selling to Sony and then
Speaker 3:  Sony for
Speaker 1:  promo code VERGE 20 to receive $20 off your first month for
Speaker 1:  listening to this podcast.
Speaker 3:  Welcome back. So let's go back to 2010 when the iPhone four
Speaker 3:  came out and it was this perfect confluence of technology that made a really
Speaker 3:  cool spatial audio game possible for the first time. Remember that moment?
Speaker 3:  Well Paul Benon thinks we're at another one of those moments right now.
Speaker 5:  You know, I've genuinely, I've never been more excited about the possibilities
Speaker 5:  for spatial audio and games. I really haven't. There was this alchemy that
Speaker 5:  happened at the beginning of the Papa Sangre. Titles were creative idea and
Speaker 5:  technology and just kind of the ecosystem around it sort of came
Speaker 5:  together to make those gains happen. And there's another point like that
Speaker 5:  right now. Spatial computing, for example, in quotes, VR
Speaker 5:  meta has sold more Quest threes than Xboxes in the last couple of years.
Speaker 5:  The the hardware is out there for experiences like this. And
Speaker 5:  by hardware I also mean things like small headphones that have
Speaker 5:  really good noise canceling.
Speaker 3:  You're the first person I've ever talked to who thinks about the Vision Pro
Speaker 3:  as an audio device. Yeah and I love that. But I'm, I'm curious kind of how
Speaker 3:  you think about what that could be.
Speaker 5:  So I, I think it's interesting If, you look at the difference, like the philosophical
Speaker 5:  difference between something like Vision Pro and Meta
Speaker 5:  Excellent Hardware, which has, you know, got lots and lots of benefits different
Speaker 5:  ways, but the overall difference where Apple has really concentrated
Speaker 5:  has been on being able to, to bring virtual
Speaker 5:  objects into the space that you are in, that really literally is spatial
Speaker 5:  com. You know, spatial computing is their shtick and it's very good at that.
Speaker 5:  And those objects don't need to be visual. They can be audible and
Speaker 5:  still be in line with Apple's design philosophy and If. you think about what
Speaker 5:  the, the early Papa Sangre games were about, that's what they were about.
Speaker 5:  They were about objects that you couldn't see in the physical space that
Speaker 5:  you were in. You know, that's how those games worked. It's literally
Speaker 5:  how those games worked and that fits very closely
Speaker 5:  with Apple's design principles, provision Pro. It doesn't
Speaker 5:  exclude it from things like Quest as well. And I'm, I'm sure that if, if
Speaker 5:  and when the Quest Pro two comes out or the the new
Speaker 5:  hardware that we know that's licensing Horizon os I'm sure that some of that's
Speaker 5:  gonna ha gonna be able to compete in terms of low latency, high definition
Speaker 5:  pass through video. So we'll see how long that that advantage is
Speaker 5:  maintained. But these devices are great for the kind of thing that we're
Speaker 5:  talking about, I would say. I think they're phenomenal. They're a little
Speaker 5:  heavier, right? Sure. And you don't, you don't need to have that thing strapped
Speaker 5:  to your head. The AirPods Pro that I'm wearing right now, an ideal
Speaker 5:  solution for this kind of thing.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. What are the kind of specs that matter there? I mean, you know,
Speaker 3:  again, as we talk about screens, we're in this incredible GPU
Speaker 3:  race and everybody's trying to make the higher density screens with higher
Speaker 3:  refresh rates. I'm sure there are other kind of measurable specs that are
Speaker 3:  getting better over time, but what are those things that you would look at
Speaker 3:  as sort of raw technical advancements?
Speaker 5:  I think that we've reached a stage where that's no longer an issue. Okay,
Speaker 5:  in terms of speakers in your ears, that's no longer an issue. Bluetooth's,
Speaker 5:  like I mentioned earlier on, that you need to have an output that's proportional
Speaker 5:  to input and latency is very important, but you know, apple
Speaker 5:  is targeted, I think it's 1212 milliseconds or it might be eight milliseconds
Speaker 5:  or something like that in terms of response to, to input. And
Speaker 5:  that is fine, it's fine.
Speaker 3:  It's more than just the audio stuff too. Think about what you can do with
Speaker 3:  great voice recognition and generative AI that can create a
Speaker 3:  personalized game script on the fly. Or the fact that your phone's
Speaker 3:  location services work indoors now. So you can actually move through a game
Speaker 3:  by moving through your living room and think about what's even possible in
Speaker 3:  multiplayer gaming when instead of rendering someone's weird avatar
Speaker 3:  with no legs or a crazy looking face, you can just bring their
Speaker 3:  voice into the space with you
Speaker 5:  To stumble across your friend in a space and find out that that they're
Speaker 5:  there is the kind of surprise and the kind of magic that would be
Speaker 5:  phenomenal in one of these games. And the ability to, to shout to your friend
Speaker 5:  that you need some help. And not just like if you're playing Call of Duty,
Speaker 5:  but in a way that's weirdly more practical because it's the only
Speaker 5:  way that you can communicate. Like if I'm playing Call of Duty, of course
Speaker 5:  I can leave some, I can leave some loo for anyone for a random person. But
Speaker 5:  if I'm running out of ammunition or something or you have a resource which
Speaker 5:  I need to unlock this door in the next five seconds and I have the resource,
Speaker 5:  the tension of me throwing that object to you or getting over to you to give
Speaker 5:  you that object is a set of really interesting things that are fun to explore
Speaker 5:  in, in a playful experience. And they're absolutely on the roadmap.
Speaker 3:  One game I think a lot about in this context is Zombies Run, which is sort
Speaker 3:  of a hybrid of an exercise app and a video game. The idea is that the
Speaker 3:  game tells a story as you run and then when the zombies get
Speaker 3:  too close, you have to pick up the pace and run faster and the game actually
Speaker 3:  knows and responds to how fast you're moving. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  Go raise the gates, please. You know what, just raise the gates.
Speaker 11:  All righty
Speaker 3:  There. I love Zombies Run by the way. Cannot recommend it highly enough.
Speaker 3:  And now I'm just imagining like an audio ar game that
Speaker 3:  follows you around as you go about your day and then every once in a while
Speaker 3:  just adds zombies and makes you hide or run away. I don't know, maybe your
Speaker 3:  whole office could play together and it would interrupt all your meetings.
Speaker 3:  This sounds awesome to me and it only works in audio. There
Speaker 3:  really haven't been a lot of great audio games in recent years. People
Speaker 3:  in the community still talk a lot about Papa Sangre actually and how sad
Speaker 3:  they are that it's gone. There are a few games out there though, as I mentioned
Speaker 3:  earlier, blind Drive is pretty fun. And I also played one called Fear,
Speaker 3:  FEER. That is another of those endless runner style games
Speaker 3:  like Subway surfer or Temple Run where you dodge enemies and obstacles
Speaker 3:  and just try to make it as long as you can. But the trick here is of course
Speaker 3:  it's all audio.
Speaker 3:  These games are really different from what I'm used to, but they're really
Speaker 3:  fun and at least If you believe, Paul, the audio game is due for a
Speaker 3:  comeback.
Speaker 5:  It's a thing which we know about now. It's a thing that we are
Speaker 5:  culturally ready for in a way that we weren't. And you've also identified
Speaker 5:  the fact that visual culture, visual entertainment on the
Speaker 5:  same device that we would be putting this on or similar devices is also much,
Speaker 5:  much more addictive and much, much harder to compete with. So all those
Speaker 5:  things are true. I think that the scale, the sheer volume
Speaker 5:  of devices and hardware that's in the market, but
Speaker 5:  we can't compete with TikTok, but we can compete with podcasts, we can compete
Speaker 5:  with audio, and we can also be a part of the gaming
Speaker 5:  economy, ecology, landscape. So all of that
Speaker 5:  makes me think that it absolutely is worthwhile doing.
Speaker 5:  Exciting to explore.
Speaker 3:  Alright, that's it for us today. Thanks to Paul for being here. And thank
Speaker 3:  you as always for listening. This is the second in our four part series about
Speaker 3:  the five senses of gaming, so make sure you heard the Touch episode from
Speaker 3:  last week. In the meantime, we'll be back on Tuesday and Friday with our
Speaker 3:  regularly scheduled programming. This show is produced by Andrew Moreno,
Speaker 3:  Liam James, and Will pour The. Vergecast is The Verge production, and part
Speaker 3:  of the Vox Media podcast network. We'll be back on Tuesday to talk about
Speaker 3:  iPads right to repair and a question from The Vergecast hotline. We'll see
Speaker 3:  you then. Rock and roll
Speaker 1:  month every month. Taxes and fees included. Use promo code VERGE 20
Speaker 1:  to receive $20 off your first month for listening to this podcast.