# Transcript
ID: c0e22bb2-6ae0-42a0-a3b3-2c747f82a5a3
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5530490106562420082/1613597738025832947/s93290-US-5191s-1713256346.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of undersea cable management:
04:10 - The Verge’s David Pierce and Josh Dzieza discuss the industry of laying and maintaining undersea cables that connect us to the internet.
The invisible seafaring industry that keeps the internet afloat
43:43 - Tom Warren and Joanna Nelius join the show to discuss the future of Arm chips on PCs and whether or not we’re about to get a huge jump in performance on most laptops.
Microsoft is confident Windows on Arm could finally beat Apple
Microsoft to hold a special Windows and Surface AI event in May
Microsoft’s first AI PCs are the Surface Pro 10 and Surface Laptop 6 for businesses
Qualcomm claims its Snapdragon X Elite processor will beat Apple, Intel, and AMD
Qualcomm says most Windows games should ‘just work’ on its unannounced Arm laptops
1:11:18 - Alex Cranz answers questions from the Vergecast Hotline about e-readers and the latest Kobo devices.
Kobo announces its first color e-readers
The best ebook reader to buy right now
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (22 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Undersea Cable
Speaker 2:  Management. I'm your friend David Pierce, and I am sitting here
Speaker 2:  after a bunch of travel doing what it turns out I do like a few times
Speaker 2:  a year, which is basically get bored with all of my gadgets and instead of
Speaker 2:  buying new gadgets, I try to just like change everything
Speaker 2:  about the ones that I have to make them more interesting. So like
Speaker 2:  I just took the monitor on my computer off of a stand, which I've had
Speaker 2:  it on for a while and put it onto a monitor arm. Does that make any
Speaker 2:  difference? No, but it feels new now and that's very exciting. Like I
Speaker 2:  changed the lock screen on my phone and I switched it from dark
Speaker 2:  mode to light mode. Suddenly feels like a new phone. The real best version
Speaker 2:  of that, by the way, is buy a new case or take the case off. All of a
Speaker 2:  sudden it's like you have a completely new device and it only cost you a
Speaker 2:  few dollars or absolutely nothing at all. I also change the watch face
Speaker 2:  on my Apple watch. I tend to like go from one pair of
Speaker 2:  headphones to another pair of headphones for a while. I'll change the wallpapers
Speaker 2:  on all of my devices. It just kind of makes everything feel new and exciting
Speaker 2:  without actually making any meaningful changes because otherwise if I let
Speaker 2:  this feeling go on long enough, I end up buying something I
Speaker 2:  absolutely do not need, or like upgrading my perfectly good computer
Speaker 2:  just out of sheer, like need to have something new.
Speaker 2:  So I figure a wallpaper is probably easier and definitely cheaper.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, we have an awesome show coming up for you today. We're gonna do two
Speaker 2:  things. First, we're gonna talk to Josh Jeza, who has spent a long time
Speaker 2:  reporting a big story for The Verge about undersea cables and
Speaker 2:  what that means basically about the infrastructure of the internet, that
Speaker 2:  the way that we connect to the world is just a bunch of cables
Speaker 2:  in the ocean that is both more interesting, more important and more
Speaker 2:  unstable than you might realize. So we're gonna talk about how all of that
Speaker 2:  works and what it takes to keep it working. We're also gonna talk to Tom
Speaker 2:  Warren and Joanna Nelius about the Chip race that seems like it's
Speaker 2:  coming for us. Pretty soon. Microsoft has been making noise about
Speaker 2:  how it thinks this next generation of Qualcomm chips could bring
Speaker 2:  Windows computers on par performance wise with the latest
Speaker 2:  max from Apple, which would be a big deal. And if Qualcomm chips are
Speaker 2:  finally as good as they've been promised for a really long time, it could
Speaker 2:  change the PC landscape in huge ways. We also have a
Speaker 2:  Hotline question about e Inc and E-readers because this is The Vergecast,
Speaker 2:  of course we do. And lots of other stuff to get to also. It's gonna be super
Speaker 2:  fun, really fun episode. All of that is coming up in just a second,
Speaker 2:  but I've now been using light mode for like three minutes and I hate it.
Speaker 2:  I'm going back to dark mode. Gotta make that switch. This is The Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Over the last few years, one of those ongoing news stories
Speaker 2:  that always makes me stop and think is whenever a company
Speaker 2:  usually Google or Meta recently announces that they're starting a
Speaker 2:  project to build a cable between countries or continents or across
Speaker 2:  the ocean. Like in 2022, both those companies announced these big
Speaker 2:  plans to build cables pretty much all the way around the African
Speaker 2:  continent. The diagrams of them alone are mind blowing. Just imagine
Speaker 2:  you were sort of loosely tracing your way around Africa three or four
Speaker 2:  times all the way around. That's what it looks like. Thousands of miles of
Speaker 2:  cable underneath the ocean hitting land at these various points all around
Speaker 2:  Africa. And increasingly, this is what the whole world looks like.
Speaker 2:  The whole internet is just right there underneath the ocean all over the
Speaker 2:  world. The VIRs, Josh Jeza has been reporting on these cables for months
Speaker 2:  and he's found himself inside a whole huge industry that really
Speaker 2:  nobody ever knows or talks about, which is the folks tasked with laying
Speaker 2:  and just as important, maintaining and fixing these undersea cables.
Speaker 2:  If you're hearing this on Tuesday as this podcast goes live, his story
Speaker 2:  just also went up. We might have actually beaten him by a couple of hours,
Speaker 2:  so keep an eye on The Verge dot com. So we figured we'd have him on the show
Speaker 2:  to talk about it and explain this whole under the sea world to us.
Speaker 2:  Josh Dzieza, welcome back to The Vergecast. Thank you. You have spent
Speaker 2:  however many months at sea learning about
Speaker 2:  the weird machinations of the internet. Yes. Unfortunately
Speaker 6:  An import, but I guess it's still technically the sea.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's good enough. So I want to like talk through
Speaker 2:  this big story that you've been working on and just publish for us. But I
Speaker 2:  also want to kind of explain the infrastructure of the internet in a
Speaker 2:  way that I think you're now sort of uniquely set up to do. And
Speaker 2:  my sense is what you've discovered, if we're just going to start from the
Speaker 2:  very beginning, is that like yes, in fact the internet is just a series
Speaker 2:  of tubes?
Speaker 6:  Absolutely. It is a series of tubes. I was surprised at actually how
Speaker 6:  tube-like they are. Like you imagine, at least I imagine, I feel
Speaker 6:  like a lot of people imagine kind of big pipes at the bottom of the ocean,
Speaker 6:  but it's actually just little garden hose with tubes
Speaker 6:  running between continents. They have some Fiverr optic cables in the middle,
Speaker 6:  basically just strands of glass that's lasers pulsing
Speaker 6:  through in code data and that is how data travels around the world.
Speaker 6:  So
Speaker 2:  Give me kind of the big picture way to think about this
Speaker 2:  infrastructure. Like I know it's lots of very long cables,
Speaker 2:  but like how, how sort of big and sprawling is the undersea
Speaker 2:  cable universe?
Speaker 6:  It's huge. It's, there are 500 or
Speaker 6:  so cables around the world, around 800,000 miles of
Speaker 6:  cabling. Often going through between sort of big
Speaker 6:  population centers. So you have a lot going from uk, Western Europe
Speaker 6:  to New York, New Jersey. On the other side you
Speaker 6:  have various parts of California going to Japan or
Speaker 6:  other locations in Asia. And that is how, you know,
Speaker 6:  you think about these big global networks. You are, even if
Speaker 6:  you're not always, like, if two people in America in the US
Speaker 6:  are emailing, they're probably just on terrestrial cables. But the
Speaker 6:  second you're accessing data that's overseas in some capacity, If,
Speaker 6:  you are watching YouTube videos that were posted from somewhere overseas.
Speaker 6:  It's cached locally at a data center, but it got there using an undersea
Speaker 6:  cable from some other data center somewhere. And If, you of course zoom or
Speaker 6:  email or whatever with someone overseas, it's going through one of these
Speaker 6:  cables. Right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. How would you think about in the sort of day-to-day life of a normal
Speaker 2:  person, how important are these cables, do you think?
Speaker 6:  I would say they're very important, but they might not be
Speaker 6:  directly accessing them every day. If you're on a big continent like North
Speaker 6:  America, you're largely traveling over a terrestrial network, but services
Speaker 6:  you interact with are dependent on these
Speaker 6:  cables. So you have like big global platforms like YouTube and TikTok. That
Speaker 6:  content is reaching you. Like the last mile
Speaker 6:  is gonna be terrestrial, but it got to North America
Speaker 6:  using a subsea cable. A lot of financial data, any
Speaker 6:  kind of international transfer is happening on a subsea cable.
Speaker 6:  Anytime you call customer service and you're talking to someone
Speaker 6:  overseas that's on the subsea cable and then you have kind of the
Speaker 6:  bits of the internet, you have, you know, my own website,
Speaker 6:  it might seem like it's local, but you have, you know, software
Speaker 6:  libraries and various things that could be stored somewhere else that it's
Speaker 6:  calling on and you don't necessarily know where it's coming from.
Speaker 6:  So I would say every day you're doing something that
Speaker 6:  maybe on a secondary tertiary level relies on these cables.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. And undersea cables, if, if I understand correctly, are
Speaker 2:  not like a new internety idea, right? The idea of
Speaker 2:  having a cable that connects the United States to Europe and Europe
Speaker 2:  to Africa and Africa to Asia or whatever, we know how to do
Speaker 2:  this at this point, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. One of the surprising things to me in doing this story is
Speaker 6:  how little this has changed over the years. And I'm not just talking like
Speaker 6:  the decades of the internet, but like a lot of these companies trace their
Speaker 6:  lineages back to the telegraph era. And a lot of the practices are, are date
Speaker 6:  from the Telegraph era. Like you lay cables, you repair cables pretty much
Speaker 6:  how you did in the 19th century.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. We're talking like mid 18 hundreds, right when the telegraph was starting
Speaker 2:  to kind of move around the world. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You read these accounts of the early telegraph people and, and it's quite
Speaker 6:  a lot of, it's trial by air. It's quite exciting. It's people, they don't
Speaker 6:  really know how electricity works, they don't really know what the bottom
Speaker 6:  of the ocean looks like and they're just sort of setting out, being like,
Speaker 6:  well, we strung a cable over through the English channel, like
Speaker 6:  why not do the ocean? And it's
Speaker 2:  Just more
Speaker 6:  Water. It goes terribly for, for several decades before they eventually figure
Speaker 6:  out how to do it.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So today, what does it take to keep all these important
Speaker 2:  garden hoses safe and working?
Speaker 6:  So they're breaking all the time. They break 200 times a year.
Speaker 6:  It's like every other day a cable breaks.
Speaker 2:  So we have 500 cables and 200 of them break every year. Right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Wow. They get 200 breaks. Sometimes they're on the same cable. It's
Speaker 6:  complicated. But yeah, basically a good chunk of them are breaking,
Speaker 6:  there's enough redundancy in the system that data can be routed
Speaker 6:  around on alternate paths. So you don't really notice, but
Speaker 6:  you know, if they, if 200 cables were to stay broken, you would notice things,
Speaker 6:  very bad things would happen. So yeah, these breaks happen all the time,
Speaker 6:  200 times a year. And when one breaks traffic
Speaker 6:  is rerouted along alternate paths and while that's happening, one
Speaker 6:  of this small band of ships will sail out with some spare cable
Speaker 6:  and fix the break. you know, as the internet has become more important there,
Speaker 6:  there was a report that was interesting a couple years ago that talks
Speaker 6:  about how cables have not become more vulnerable in recent years.
Speaker 6:  It's just that our dependence on them has grown exponentially.
Speaker 6:  Hmm. So say in the nineties there's an a massive break. Some
Speaker 6:  things break it, it's not bad. You might not notice in your day-to-day life
Speaker 6:  now everything breaks, you know, banks stop working,
Speaker 6:  companies can't function, supply chains, break websites don't load. We rely
Speaker 6:  on it for everything. But the industry that repairs it keeps things
Speaker 6:  running is basically the same. It's just sort of handled by private
Speaker 6:  companies that have a bunch of contracts with cable
Speaker 6:  owners and they have this arrangement that is sort of,
Speaker 6:  you know, days back half a century maybe, where everyone kind of
Speaker 6:  pays into a organizing body that has a couple
Speaker 6:  ships that stand by and repair any cables that break in a
Speaker 6:  big zone. And like the zone is the Atlantic ocean.
Speaker 2:  It's a big, big zone. Yeah. So how do these cables break?
Speaker 6:  Overwhelmingly, it's people break them, specifically
Speaker 6:  fishing vessels break a lot of cables. You have these
Speaker 6:  dredging nets, traw fishing, they
Speaker 6:  scraped these big hooks across the bottom of the sea with a
Speaker 6:  net and they snap cables all the time.
Speaker 2:  So it's not like a targeted attack on the cable, it's just sort, this gets
Speaker 2:  caught up in the phishing net and snaps kind of thing. Yeah. One
Speaker 6:  Of the interest there, there's been hardly any proven hostile
Speaker 6:  attacks on a cable. It's almost all just sort of accidental damage.
Speaker 6:  You have a fishing, fishing vessel, you have like a ship drags
Speaker 6:  its anchor in the wrong place, things like that. And then you have natural
Speaker 6:  disasters, you have like landslides under the ocean basically earthquakes,
Speaker 6:  volcanoes, weird currents, things like that. And then, you
Speaker 6:  know, if there have been cable breaks that people suspect could maybe be
Speaker 6:  from a malicious actor, but it's never really been proven. The one
Speaker 6:  case I've seen cited was like during World War I when
Speaker 6:  various the UK and and Germany sort of sent people a
Speaker 6:  short of cut telegraph cables with axes. Other than that, there
Speaker 6:  hasn't really been any documented cases of a, of attack on a cable
Speaker 6:  world
Speaker 2:  War i a lot of fights over TikTok and World War I. Right, right. From, from
Speaker 2:  what I remember. So you, you mentioned the, the maintenance industry here.
Speaker 2:  What does this industry look like? This feels like this incredibly
Speaker 2:  important gigantic job. Like is this, is this a
Speaker 2:  huge teaming industry of huge teaming multinational
Speaker 2:  corporations fixing the internet?
Speaker 6:  It's really not. It's actually quite a small industry like
Speaker 6:  ballpark, maybe a thousand or so people in the direct sort of maritime
Speaker 6:  side of maintenance you have for
Speaker 2:  All 800,000 miles of undersea cables.
Speaker 6:  That's right. Wow. So you have, there's about 70 cable ships in the world,
Speaker 6:  but most of them mostly do installations, which pays better. You have like
Speaker 6:  22 or so dedicated maintenance vessels
Speaker 6:  and they are stationed around the world, you know, a handful per
Speaker 6:  ocean basically. And their job is to,
Speaker 6:  you know, like firefighters stand ready 24 hours a day
Speaker 6:  to sail out within 24 hours of being notified of a cable fault. So
Speaker 6:  they belong to these consortiums. They, you know, maybe a couple different
Speaker 6:  minutes providers have a ship in a given ocean
Speaker 6:  and they cover the whole area. And if you're a cable owner, you call the
Speaker 6:  maintenance provider and say, Hey, I have a cable broken. Send a ship out.
Speaker 6:  And they send a ship app to fix the cable is basically how, how
Speaker 6:  it works.
Speaker 2:  Wow. It's like, it's like an adventure story every time they're like, we
Speaker 2:  have to, we have to go explore the depths of the ocean to find a
Speaker 2:  broken garden hose and figure out what to do with it.
Speaker 6:  It really is like drop everything. We go to a random
Speaker 6:  place in the middle of the ocean often.
Speaker 2:  Wow. 22 ships strikes me as not a lot of ships
Speaker 2:  to cover a all of the problems you've described and b, just the
Speaker 2:  sheer size and scope of all of this. Can they do it with
Speaker 2:  22 ships?
Speaker 6:  So they have done it with 22 ships.
Speaker 2:  Okay, fair. I guess Yeah, the internet still works. We're still here. Okay.
Speaker 6:  I think the, the, the concern is that a lot of these ships are getting pretty
Speaker 6:  old. They're like several decades old. There's not a lot of money coming
Speaker 6:  into the industry. And if there were to be a big event
Speaker 6:  like a big earthquake or a deliberate attack on a cable
Speaker 6:  choke point or something like that, then you could have a real disruption.
Speaker 6:  So the ships are really this critical component of the
Speaker 6:  internet that so far have been able to
Speaker 6:  keep things running, but it's pretty lean if there were a major event that
Speaker 6:  it would be challenging I think in some cases for them to, to do the job.
Speaker 6:  Okay.
Speaker 2:  And who are these people? Is this like a, is this a sort of manual
Speaker 2:  labor kind of job on a ship? Is this like a incredibly
Speaker 2:  technically complicated job on a ship? Like who, who are these folks doing
Speaker 2:  this work on these ships?
Speaker 6:  It's both manual labor and very technically complicated. You have a mix
Speaker 6:  of, you have crew who are sort of seafarers and run the ship and then you
Speaker 6:  have cable engineers who kind of come from all the kinds of different
Speaker 6:  backgrounds. But the job requires, you have
Speaker 6:  to be quite good at geometry and, and
Speaker 6:  angles and forces and sort of ocean engineering stuff to
Speaker 6:  know how to, you know, pull up a cable from several miles to
Speaker 6:  the bottom of the ocean without things snapping. You're dealing with these
Speaker 6:  big metal hooks that are used to catch the cables, high tensions. It's like
Speaker 6:  quite physically demanding work. And then at its heart
Speaker 6:  it's these various technical tasks that involved with
Speaker 6:  figurine out where the fault is splicing the fibers, which is
Speaker 6:  just ultra precise work that's done. you know, you're
Speaker 6:  fusing two strands of glass end to end with as perfect as you
Speaker 6:  can get a connection. And that stuff is, it's, you know, it's like
Speaker 6:  neurosurgery. It's, it's extremely delicate
Speaker 2:  And you have to do it on a ship in the middle of the ocean,
Speaker 6:  Right? Yeah. On a, on a rocking ship that is in the middle of the ocean.
Speaker 2:  This is like everything possible on incredibly hard mode at all times.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. It's pretty, as you see the, the workshops and it's just like
Speaker 6:  in the belly of a ship sort of surrounded by tarps, it's really not, you
Speaker 6:  know, it's not this fa precision factory that you would wanna be doing this
Speaker 6:  work in.
Speaker 2:  So now I can't help imagining the, the like montage
Speaker 2:  action scene of everybody snapping into action. One of these things happening.
Speaker 2:  So like, walk me through the process a little bit. I'm in port in some
Speaker 2:  centrally located city somewhere waiting for a call. I get a call
Speaker 2:  from, I'm assuming it's like Google and Meta who seem to be the companies
Speaker 2:  that own more and more of these cables over time. They
Speaker 6:  Own a lot of the cables. They've, a lot of the newly built cables are coming
Speaker 6:  from the big, big tech companies, Google and Meta
Speaker 6:  primarily. And then you have cables that are owned by, you know,
Speaker 6:  dozen, sometimes
Speaker 6:  ISPs and telecom companies and things. Got it. Okay. And so
Speaker 6:  each cable will have someone who's in charge of maintenance
Speaker 6:  and you know, they'll get a message from their
Speaker 6:  network operation center saying, Hey, we've got a cable down, here's what
Speaker 6:  we know about it. That person will then call someone at the
Speaker 6:  repair organization. They can be public or private, but it's one of these
Speaker 6:  consortiums usually.
Speaker 2:  I was really hoping there would be like a big red button on somebody's desk
Speaker 2:  that's like cable down and the alarms start going off in the ship somewhere.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It, there are alarms and big red warnings, but then it's a lot of people
Speaker 6:  calling people around the world at weird hours. So they call someone
Speaker 6:  at the, on the maintenance side, that person then calls the ship and says,
Speaker 6:  you know, get ready, we're gonna need X miles of spare
Speaker 6:  cable for this cable system. We think it's here, we think this, cut it,
Speaker 6:  whatever information they have. And then they, and then they kind of plan
Speaker 6:  out what the repairs gonna look like.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And what, what does a repair normally look like? Like walk me through
Speaker 2:  a little bit of what it would look like actually on the boat trying to do
Speaker 2:  the repair.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so the First thing you do is you need to locate where the fault is
Speaker 6:  approximately. And that's done on either end of the cable.
Speaker 6:  Basically you have people in the landing station on
Speaker 6:  either end of the cable, so you on opposite sides of the ocean,
Speaker 6:  shoot a laser down there and it hits, the brake reflects
Speaker 6:  back, and the time it takes to come back will tell you pretty much where
Speaker 6:  along the cable the, the brake is.
Speaker 2:  So like wherever the signal dies, that's, that's the point you send them
Speaker 2:  to?
Speaker 6:  Exactly. Okay. And so you sail out to there with a
Speaker 6:  certain amount of spare cable in your ship and a bunch of these big hooks
Speaker 6:  that are called grappl mills, which
Speaker 2:  I Googled by the way, and they just straight up look like Batman's grappling
Speaker 2:  hooks. Like that's just, that's just what they are.
Speaker 6:  That's exactly what they are. And there's a bunch of different kinds. You
Speaker 6:  have like multi grapple things. You have ones with giant
Speaker 6:  arms and blades, depending on what the ocean bottom looks like, whether
Speaker 6:  it's muddy or rocky or what cables are laid with such little slack
Speaker 6:  on the seabed that you can't just, you know, hook it and pull it to the surface.
Speaker 6:  Ah, it's too hot. So the First thing you need to do is you need to cut the
Speaker 6:  cable somewhere near where it's broken using one of these grappl metals,
Speaker 6:  but one with a big blade in the middle. So you drag this blade across
Speaker 6:  where you think the cable path is, and then you turn
Speaker 6:  around with one of these gr mills and catch one end of the cable,
Speaker 6:  pull it to the surface, attach it to a buoy, go back to the other
Speaker 6:  side, catch the other side of the cable, bring it to the surface, and
Speaker 6:  then you do the splicing. So you splice like a piece of spare cable to that
Speaker 6:  end, go back to the other side that's attached to the buoy, splice it to
Speaker 6:  that end, and then test it. And you should have a working cable that then
Speaker 6:  you have to lower back down to the ocean floor.
Speaker 2:  So it's basically like you're fishing for cables on the ocean
Speaker 2:  floor, right? Like how do they know if they've caught one?
Speaker 6:  That's exactly right. Like fishing based on just the, the
Speaker 6:  tug on the line. In this case, you have this enormous
Speaker 6:  metal hook that you're dragging along the ocean floor. And as that's
Speaker 6:  happening, someone is in the bridge watching this one
Speaker 6:  dial called the tension meter and watching it waver back
Speaker 6:  and forth. And one of the interesting things about it is it's an analog dial.
Speaker 6:  It's not an ultra precise digital readout because
Speaker 6:  you want that kind of fuzziness to, to, to be
Speaker 6:  able to judge intuitively what's happening is tension rising or falling
Speaker 6:  is a rising and falling fast or slow that you can't get from a bunch of numbers
Speaker 6:  jumping around. And so you're watching this dial, and if it's moving up
Speaker 6:  slowly kind of wavering, maybe you're going through some mud,
Speaker 6:  if it jerks up quickly, maybe you hit a rock and you, what
Speaker 6:  you want is this slow increase, slow steady increase in intention
Speaker 6:  that shows you've hooked this cable and you're dragging it along the ocean
Speaker 6:  floor. And that's when you know it's time to reel in.
Speaker 2:  Interesting man, that's such a inexact science, but it, that's like you
Speaker 2:  just described like an art form more than a piece of sort of data analysis.
Speaker 6:  It really is one of the, one of the engineers I was talking to in Japan.
Speaker 6:  It's, it really is this act of kind of reading what's happening on the ocean
Speaker 6:  floor imagining based on this dial, you know, oh, I'm, I'm going,
Speaker 6:  I am going over a trench. I'm, I've hit a rock. That's
Speaker 2:  Wild. And how long does that process take?
Speaker 6:  Like days to weeks to to months, even if it's hard to find the cable?
Speaker 6:  Everything here is at just a massive scale. So like
Speaker 6:  if you're in deep water, the garden hose is several miles
Speaker 6:  down and just the act of like lowering it down to the ocean floor and hauling
Speaker 6:  it up can take, you know, nearly a day because it's so deep. And then
Speaker 6:  so each step of this process takes several days, splicing
Speaker 6:  the cable takes about a day. It's just incredibly time consuming. And then,
Speaker 6:  so it's like If, you don't catch the cable on first try then, you know, several
Speaker 6:  more days to try again and it adds up pretty soon. You're like, you're
Speaker 6:  outta sea for weeks.
Speaker 2:  It just keeps reminding me of one of those movies where there's like, there's
Speaker 2:  the one shark that they're trying to catch and they're like, we, we think
Speaker 2:  we found it. It's over here. And then they go and they don't get it and it's
Speaker 2:  like, oh, okay, well we, we think we know where it'll be next. And it is
Speaker 2:  this like sort of perpetual cat and mouse game that you're playing with this
Speaker 2:  thing, trying to get it into your arms and then you can do something with
Speaker 2:  it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's, it's remarkable how little visibility, you know, they have onto
Speaker 6:  the ocean floor and what's happening down there. Yeah. you know, there are
Speaker 6:  times when people are doing, you know, a dozen passes back and
Speaker 6:  forth being like, well that wasn't there, maybe it's a mile that way and
Speaker 6:  let's try over here. And that's,
Speaker 2:  That's nuts. Why don't we know better? This is one of the things I, I found
Speaker 2:  myself wondering, reading your story is I feel like I could make
Speaker 2:  a solid argument that the location of these cables should be like,
Speaker 2:  closely held state secrets that no one knows that
Speaker 2:  because they're so important to the way that the world works that they should
Speaker 2:  be, you know, it should be like the, the bunkers where the
Speaker 2:  president goes. Like you just, it just should be all classified information
Speaker 2:  on the other side. I can imagine a world in which we should do much more
Speaker 2:  work to have much better knowledge of how these things work and where they
Speaker 2:  are and what's going on with them because they're so important and because
Speaker 2:  laying them and fixing them needs to happen so quickly. But it,
Speaker 2:  it seems like we're in sort of a weird middle between those two things. We're
Speaker 2:  like, we kind of know, but not really.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's a trade off. So you can go and you can see, tell
Speaker 6:  geography tracks, cables. You can see kind of broadly where they are in the
Speaker 6:  ocean. If you're like a sea captain, you
Speaker 6:  get charts that have cable areas marks, you know, with some degree
Speaker 6:  of precision. And that makes a lot of sense because the biggest
Speaker 6:  actual threat to cables is someone accidentally dropping an anchor on them.
Speaker 6:  And so If, you are worried about an in attack and you make the most secret,
Speaker 6:  you're probably gonna increase the number of accidental cable breaks. On
Speaker 6:  the other hand, they are vulnerable. It would be fairly,
Speaker 6:  you know, you don't need a low tech attack, you can just drag an anchor across
Speaker 6:  the ocean floor. In practice the network is redundant enough, you're still
Speaker 6:  talking about like a really small thing in a big ocean. So it's not quite
Speaker 6:  that easy to attack. It would take a pretty sophisticated antagonist to
Speaker 6:  actually cause a catastrophic cable outage. So, so far
Speaker 6:  it's been fine, but it is a topic of active debate, I think
Speaker 6:  in, in, in governments, what should we do? How should we protect these cables
Speaker 6:  that are, are so important
Speaker 2:  And for the people whose job it is to actually maintain them over
Speaker 2:  time, what is life like? You talk to a bunch of people who are sort of in
Speaker 2:  this industry and in some cases have been for a very long time. Right. What's
Speaker 2:  it like to be a sort of superhero keeping the internet running?
Speaker 6:  It's a very strange job. People, you know, when they join they
Speaker 6:  tend to kind of stumble into it. It's not a very well known
Speaker 6:  industry. And so you have people who are working as cable engineers in some
Speaker 6:  other area or you know, in Merchant Marines or, or something
Speaker 6:  like that. Geologists in optics. And they sort of
Speaker 6:  stumble into it and you know, if they, if they stay for a bit,
Speaker 6:  they tend to stay for a long time, like decades, a lot of the work is earned
Speaker 6:  on, learned on the job. And so people tend to sort of move around between
Speaker 6:  different roles. But it's not an easy job. It's
Speaker 6:  a weird lifestyle. You rotate in and off ships, you're often
Speaker 6:  far from home out of contact. you know, this is changing now
Speaker 6:  a bit with starlink, but like when you're on board one of these ships historically
Speaker 6:  you're pretty much cut off. You don't have great internet
Speaker 6:  connections. You can't stream things or, or FaceTime or anything
Speaker 6:  like that. You
Speaker 2:  Have the fast internet literally in your hands. You just can't do anything
Speaker 2:  with it.
Speaker 6:  Right, exactly. It's a difficult job. Just the lifestyle is hard,
Speaker 6:  but people come to love it because it takes you to very
Speaker 6:  unusual places. It's exciting and a lot of them have like
Speaker 6:  a real sense of purpose. They're maintaining this infrastructure that the
Speaker 6:  modern world runs on, even if no one actually knows about it or what they
Speaker 6:  do. Knowing
Speaker 2:  You as I do, I'm, I'm confident that at some point in reporting this story,
Speaker 2:  you tried to live the cable maintenance life yourself and you were like,
Speaker 2:  yes, I will live the ship life. How close did you get?
Speaker 6:  Not that close. I did try, you know, when I first heard about this
Speaker 6:  industry, I was like, well, I should go on board for repair and was basically
Speaker 6:  laughed out of the room several times, you know, for various reasons. The
Speaker 6:  big one was security. It's a, it's a secretive industry. They just
Speaker 6:  can't have a journalist hanging out on a cable ship in most cases. And then
Speaker 6:  the other very compelling reason was that they don't know how long they'll
Speaker 6:  be gone. So like, yeah, you can come along, but maybe we'll be gone for a
Speaker 6:  week or two and maybe we'll get called off to another repair and you'll be
Speaker 6:  at sea for months. Which is just, you know, hard to really plan around. That's
Speaker 2:  Fair. So were you, were you able to get any kind of firsthand glimpse into
Speaker 2:  this life?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so I ended up going to Japan to talk
Speaker 6:  to people who work at KCS and going aboard the
Speaker 6:  ocean link, which was the ship that repaired a lot of the cables
Speaker 6:  in Japan after the 2011 earthquake and tsunami.
Speaker 6:  And so it was in port for a period of time and I was able to go there and,
Speaker 6:  and visit the crew and, and get a tour of the ship. What
Speaker 2:  Was the ship like?
Speaker 6:  It was fairly big, like 400 foot long sort
Speaker 6:  of tall working ship. It's from the nineties, it's kind of
Speaker 6:  old at this point, but, well-maintained,
Speaker 2:  I'm imagining sort of a big fishing vessel, but instead of
Speaker 2:  like nets and containers, it just has a massive spool of cable
Speaker 2:  that's
Speaker 6:  Basically right. It essentially is a massive spool of cable. Like the
Speaker 6:  middle of it are these, I think three big empty
Speaker 6:  tanks that are just kind of spindles of wound spare cable. The interior
Speaker 6:  is really empty. It's kind of like a, it's built kind of like an aircraft
Speaker 6:  carrier or something where there's no sort of beams or, or struts or anything
Speaker 6:  because it's all just, you have to string cable outta these tanks
Speaker 6:  to the workstation and then out to the front where there's kind of a rolling
Speaker 6:  pulley kind of thing where it goes over and into the ocean.
Speaker 2:  Got it. So it pulls it up and then you sort of spool from the middle boy.
Speaker 2:  It's what a complicated system.
Speaker 6:  It's counterintuitive how the, how the ship is put together and how it all
Speaker 6:  works, but then makes sense. So it's, you're working with a material that
Speaker 6:  is thousands of miles long and it just creates all these weird logistical
Speaker 6:  problems.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So you mentioned the, the Fukushima incident in 2011 in Japan,
Speaker 2:  which was a big part of the story that you wrote, kind of how they repaired
Speaker 2:  and the reaction to all of this. What was it about those repairs that was
Speaker 2:  sort of different? I feel like you, you found one of the hardest cases you
Speaker 2:  could have to tell this story about what happened in that case.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so there are a few, there have been a few major, major cable
Speaker 6:  events. This was one of them. They tend to be earthquakes that caused the
Speaker 6:  most damage. So, so in this case there was this very, very large earthquake
Speaker 6:  off the coast of Japan. It sent a large tsunami that caused immense
Speaker 6:  devastation and part of that, that tsunami knocked out the
Speaker 6:  Fukushima nuclear reactor causing a nuclear meltdown. So you have this disaster
Speaker 6:  on top of a disaster and then you have the other disaster, which is not
Speaker 6:  really well known but happened at the same time, which is that the earthquake
Speaker 6:  caused all of these summering avalanches that wrecked
Speaker 6:  the majority of the cables Japan uses to connect to North America. Oh wow.
Speaker 6:  And the rest of the world. And so while the earthquake
Speaker 6:  tsunami recovery was happening, while Fukushima was, you know, people were
Speaker 6:  trying to bring Fukushima under control, the ship had to set
Speaker 6:  out and try to fix these cables as fast as possible while
Speaker 6:  contending with the fact that there may or may not be a cloud of radiation
Speaker 6:  over them. So
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean again, it just feels like so much of this process is just unknowns
Speaker 2:  on top of unknowns on top of unknowns. It's just going out and trying to
Speaker 2:  figure out, okay, something happened to these cables, we don't know what
Speaker 2:  or where or what it's gonna take or how we're gonna fix it.
Speaker 2:  And just bit by bit they just solve it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's really just, it's very methodical. Like you, like you've just
Speaker 6:  gotta kind of follow the steps and so they ki they, they looked at the
Speaker 6:  cable map, they figured out, okay, based on the timing of these faults, you
Speaker 6:  know, interestingly a lot of them happened hours after the tsunami. Like,
Speaker 6:  like that night basically you have these big debris flows that
Speaker 6:  sort of barrel down these canyons and, and ended up wrecking the cables.
Speaker 6:  And from the timing of the brakes, they figure out that's probably
Speaker 6:  what happens. The seabed is probably very transformed. They're gonna
Speaker 6:  need a lot of spare cable and typically you figure out,
Speaker 6:  you know, it's not usually up to the maintenance provider, which cables they
Speaker 6:  fix first. It's usually kind of first come first served from the cable owners,
Speaker 6:  whoever calls in their fault first. But in this case the cable owners are
Speaker 6:  like, you guys figure it out, like whatever, whatever cable you can
Speaker 6:  fix, fix it. And so they settled on, you know, the one farthest
Speaker 6:  from Fukushima. 'cause the other thing is that normally in a big event like
Speaker 6:  this, other ships arrived to help, but there
Speaker 6:  was so little known about what was happening with Fukushima and no one felt
Speaker 6:  comfortable sending their crews into that. And so they were sort of the only
Speaker 6:  ones doing it for the first, the first period of time. So,
Speaker 2:  And then there was a moment in the Fukushima
Speaker 2:  response where they had pulled the cable up and then couldn't figure out
Speaker 2:  what to do with it. Right. Am I what what happens here? You get the cable
Speaker 2:  up above the ocean and then you have to figure out what to do. What did they
Speaker 2:  do?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so this was the first repair. They hooked this cable and they
Speaker 6:  start reeling it in and it's under an unusual amount of tension.
Speaker 6:  And basically what happens, you know, they, they start reeling in very, very
Speaker 6:  slowly because every cable has a certain amount of tension. You don't wanna
Speaker 6:  exceed it 'cause the cable could snap. And so they're just moving very, very
Speaker 6:  slowly and it takes them nearly a day to get it to the surface. Wow. And
Speaker 6:  what they learn when it gets there is that it's in just
Speaker 6:  been completely mangled. And, and what they think happened is some
Speaker 6:  enormous landslide happened. It dragged the cable, it buried it
Speaker 6:  under a bunch of debris. And now they've been slowly pulling it tighter and
Speaker 6:  tighter and tighter until it reaches the surface. Now they can see it,
Speaker 6:  it's on the front of the ship, it's on the, the four deck and it is
Speaker 6:  hooked around one bar with the grapnel and totally stripped and mangled
Speaker 6:  and under a huge amount of tension. And so you
Speaker 2:  Basically at this point have like a thousands of miles long bungee cord like
Speaker 2:  sitting on your boat.
Speaker 6:  Exactly, yes. Exactly. Attached to a heavy metal hook that if the
Speaker 6:  bungee cord snaps, which it's being strained, sort of each
Speaker 6:  wave and, and and swell, it will fly across the ship, kill anyone,
Speaker 6:  it hits smash into the cable control room, just do immense
Speaker 6:  damage. And so, but the priority becomes, you know, you can't repair a cable
Speaker 6:  under this kind of tension that's this damaged. They need to get it off the
Speaker 6:  ship. And so they do this sort of complicated
Speaker 6:  precarious procedure where they, they hook chains around each
Speaker 6:  side of the cable, swap the grapnel out for a bladed
Speaker 6:  grl, lower it back over the bow of the ship while they've evacuated the area.
Speaker 6:  And then once it's under the water, they release the chains, the cable is
Speaker 6:  cut and goes back to the bottom and, and they start over.
Speaker 2:  That feels like a really interesting test case. 'cause you know, like you
Speaker 2:  said, these cables go back a century, but 2011 is very much
Speaker 2:  like the internet. And as we've learned, you know,
Speaker 2:  catastrophes happen, things like this happen all the time in lots of
Speaker 2:  places. That was a particularly bad one. But like earthquakes happen, we
Speaker 2:  just had one in New York. Like, these are things that happen. Did that, were
Speaker 2:  there any sort of lessons learned from that? Like do you, do you feel like
Speaker 2:  whatever, 13 years after that we're in a different era of
Speaker 2:  how we think about undersea cables?
Speaker 6:  Yes and no. I mean, it's interesting to look back on the coverage of 2011.
Speaker 6:  Like a lot of the, when the internet was mentioned, it was usually that,
Speaker 6:  you know, this is remarkable. The internet fared remarkably well. It stayed
Speaker 6:  up.
Speaker 2:  Oh really? So for all the, for all the issues, the internet stayed up in
Speaker 2:  Japan.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And, and so you have these reports and, and people were basically
Speaker 6:  just, you could only use the internet to communicate in the immediate aftermath.
Speaker 6:  People were sending emails, they were tweeting, people were posting videos,
Speaker 6:  other telecommunications were cut out. Like the, the terrestrial cables were
Speaker 6:  cut, the cell towers were wrecked. And so they were really reliant on the
Speaker 6:  internet. But you talk to the people who were at the operation centers and
Speaker 6:  on the ships and it was so much more precarious than people knew.
Speaker 6:  Basically they had succeeded in rerouting all the traffic over the
Speaker 6:  remaining cables. But if one of those cables had gone down, you
Speaker 6:  would've started to see a real degradation in service. You would've, you
Speaker 6:  know, things would've started to drop. It would've been difficult to communicate.
Speaker 6:  And so it was sort of right on the cusp of being a, a communications
Speaker 6:  disaster. And the lesson that the industry learned from that is,
Speaker 6:  is largely around redundancy. There's not like a real geographic
Speaker 6:  reason unlike the Red Sea or the Luon Strait or something.
Speaker 6:  There's not a geographic reason why all the cables were in one
Speaker 6:  place there. It was just sort of habit. Like we'd always put cables
Speaker 6:  there. Sure. And they always kind of landed at the spot. And so that makes
Speaker 6:  sense. And so you had this, these sort of choke points that then when a
Speaker 6:  landslide comes through, it wrecks a bunch of them and there's
Speaker 6:  more of an awareness that you need multiple landing points. But in practice
Speaker 6:  that doesn't always happen because it's, you know, cheaper to follow known
Speaker 6:  routes or, or whatever.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So where, where does it feel like this industry is right now? Obviously
Speaker 2:  it's as critical as ever, if not more so. Like the world relies on this
Speaker 2:  stuff more than we ever have. And I feel like purely anecdotally,
Speaker 2:  I've heard more about undersea cable projects
Speaker 2:  just in the last couple of years I feel like than I ever have. And
Speaker 2:  that might just be because I pay attention to companies like Google and Meta
Speaker 2:  and they're doing a lot of this stuff. But is there, is there energy in
Speaker 2:  this space to increase from, you know, 500 cables and
Speaker 2:  800,000 miles to, are we gonna have more than that or multiples of that
Speaker 2:  over time, do you think?
Speaker 6:  There we are in a cable boom right now. There's a lot of new cables going
Speaker 6:  in. Whether that means the net number of cables goes up is a
Speaker 6:  debate debated topic because the cables are also higher
Speaker 6:  and higher capacity. So some think maybe there'll be fewer
Speaker 6:  of cables, they'll just be really, really, really high bandwidth. But, but
Speaker 6:  there are a lot of new cables going in that's driven by the tech companies
Speaker 6:  pri primarily, which starting a couple years ago decided,
Speaker 6:  you know, rather than purchase bandwidth on these cables, let's have our
Speaker 6:  own cables. And so they started laying their own systems
Speaker 6:  largely between their data centers. And the reason for that is that they
Speaker 6:  need a ton of capacity to kind of sync all of their data centers around
Speaker 6:  the world to keep these like huge content libraries up to keep their cloud
Speaker 6:  services running. And so they want to just kind of that all under their own
Speaker 6:  umbrella. But that hasn't really spilled over into the
Speaker 6:  maintenance side yet. It's mostly kind of the installation side. I
Speaker 2:  Was gonna say, are we still at, we're still at 22 ships.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Still not a lot of new ships there. And, and you know, while the new
Speaker 6:  cables do provide a lot of redundancy, you also don't want, you know,
Speaker 6:  your handful of super high capacity cables to go down. 'cause it, it's
Speaker 6:  difficult to, to sort of move that track traffic over onto other routes.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Did as you were talking to people, did you get a sense that there are
Speaker 2:  new kinds of threats to these cables too? Whether it's some of the ones
Speaker 2:  that have been there a long time getting old and not getting replaced quickly
Speaker 2:  enough or climate change or like the geopolitics of the internet, which
Speaker 2:  are becoming a bigger and bigger deal all the time. I, is there a sense that
Speaker 2:  this could get worse rather than better as we fight about
Speaker 2:  undersea cables?
Speaker 6:  Geopolitics are the big thing. Climate change will make certain things harder.
Speaker 6:  All these cables all land on the coastline, which is eroding and
Speaker 6:  and sinking and that will be a problem. But part of the reason you're also
Speaker 6:  hearing more about cables is the geopolitics around them have become really
Speaker 6:  sensitive. Largely that has been China
Speaker 6:  US conflict. You have the US saying we don't want Chinese
Speaker 6:  owned cables landing in the US and China
Speaker 6:  also denying repair permits for the South China Sea or, or
Speaker 6:  sort of slowing them down and concerns about
Speaker 6:  routing cables through China's waters or into Hong
Speaker 6:  Kong has caused this kind of reconfiguration of
Speaker 6:  the, the network. You have alternate routes going through the Philippines
Speaker 6:  or a lot of cables landing in Singapore or China
Speaker 6:  trying to build up its own cable maritime industry so that
Speaker 6:  it doesn't have to rely on, on, on the west. And these changes
Speaker 6:  are making it, it's not necessarily harder but very
Speaker 6:  different. It's just a period of change in the industry and and kind of one
Speaker 6:  that is increasing, getting, increasing attention from, from
Speaker 6:  various governments that more governments are saying we need to control this
Speaker 6:  infrastructure in some way.
Speaker 2:  So, and as you talk to people in this small kind of under
Speaker 2:  talked about and under-resourced industry, is the sense that given
Speaker 2:  all of that it is just change and this is stable and this is how we're gonna
Speaker 2:  keep doing things? Or did you, do you run into people who are like, screw
Speaker 2:  all of this, the answer is satellites and we have to get there as quickly
Speaker 2:  as we possibly can or like, is this just what it is and we have to figure
Speaker 2:  out how to do it better?
Speaker 6:  There's a fair amount of concern I think about the long-term
Speaker 6:  sustainability of the industry. It can't all be satellites. That was the,
Speaker 6:  the other thing that everyone reminded me of. Satellites
Speaker 6:  can carry like half a percent of the global traffic. It's, it's gonna be
Speaker 6:  cables, they're, they're just way more efficient and cheaper to
Speaker 6:  transmit data. There's a sense that they will have to navigate this. I think
Speaker 6:  the industry has been pretty stable for
Speaker 6:  decades and there's some anxiety about these changes. The
Speaker 6:  big tech companies coming in, governments taking a greater interest,
Speaker 6:  the sort of geopolitical jockeying around cable,
Speaker 6:  cable routes that are just gonna be tricky. I think
Speaker 6:  a lot of the anxiety comes from kind of the market
Speaker 6:  forces involved. Like the big tech companies, they have so
Speaker 6:  much buying power, they can drive down prices and so they can negotiate lower
Speaker 6:  rates. And so well that means maintenance companies can
Speaker 6:  operate year to year and maybe it means they don't have enough to invest
Speaker 6:  in a new vessel. And so you have this kind of slow degradation, which also
Speaker 6:  means that they have trouble recruiting 'cause no one wants to join this
Speaker 6:  sort of aging fleet. Sure,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Having done this whole process of, of reporting and
Speaker 2:  sort of understanding how this world works, has it changed the way you think
Speaker 2:  about the internet? Like I feel like the more I learn about the actual
Speaker 2:  infrastructure of the internet, the more remarkable it seems that any of
Speaker 2:  this ever actually works. And, and I feel like I got some of that sense
Speaker 2:  from your story that on the one hand this is this incredibly robust, incredibly
Speaker 2:  impressive group of people working on this thing that we understand
Speaker 2:  and have worked on for a long time. On the other hand, the internet is forever
Speaker 2:  like one wayward anchor away from falling apart.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's really, it's one of these cases I feel like you hear about everybody
Speaker 6:  so often. Like the ways in which the internet is just sort of this
Speaker 6:  cobbled together apparatus is way less
Speaker 6:  stable
Speaker 1:  Welcome
Speaker 2:  Back. A couple of weeks ago on the show we talked with the VIRs Tom Warren
Speaker 2:  about Microsoft's whole AI vision and specifically this idea
Speaker 2:  of AI. PCs still not really sure what that means, but Tom
Speaker 2:  mentioned that Microsoft believes that a new generation of chips coming out
Speaker 2:  from Qualcomm might bring Windows PCs up to par
Speaker 2:  with Apple's latest max at least performance wise and that that might be
Speaker 2:  a really big deal. Since then, Tom has been doing more reporting on all of
Speaker 2:  Microsoft's plans and I haven't been able to stop thinking about what might
Speaker 2:  happen if we really did get that kind of huge junk in
Speaker 2:  PC performance. So I asked him to come back on along with the verges laptop
Speaker 2:  reviewer, Joanna Nelius to talk about what's coming and what it might mean.
Speaker 2:  Tom, hello.
Speaker 9:  Hello again.
Speaker 2:  Joanna welcome.
Speaker 9:  Hello. Excited to be here.
Speaker 2:  This is gonna be great. Okay, so let's talk about laptop chips, the coolest
Speaker 2:  sexiest thing in technology, basically, Tom, you and I a couple weeks ago
Speaker 2:  yeah, talked about what Microsoft is up to with AI PCs and this idea that
Speaker 2:  like we're about to get this kind of massive uptick in the
Speaker 2:  performance of laptops and everything is gonna be wonderful and solve all
Speaker 2:  of our problems forever. I wanna talk about what that actually means. So
Speaker 2:  Joanna, you're a laptop reviewer, Tom, you, you cover all of our Microsoft
Speaker 2:  stuff and between us we're gonna figure out The future of Windows laptops.
Speaker 2:  Does that sound good? Does this make sense? But somehow, we'll
Speaker 9:  Maybe, yeah, I gotta get my crystal ball. Hold on.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, we are once and for all going to decide what an AI PC is and we're
Speaker 2:  gonna do the world a great service. But Joanna, I wanna start with you because
Speaker 2:  I feel like we have been talking about this idea of a
Speaker 2:  Qualcomm powered PC being sort of a new and different and
Speaker 2:  better thing for a long time and that has not really come
Speaker 2:  to pass. Is that fair? Like is this, am I the only one who has been dreaming
Speaker 2:  about this for a very long time?
Speaker 9:  I mean, no, I think that's really fair to say.
Speaker 9:  Now it kind of looks like it may actually come to pass.
Speaker 9:  The jury is still out on whether or not it's going to
Speaker 9:  overtake let's say Apple M chips or anything
Speaker 9:  else. But kind of based on like what I've been reading and what I've seen.
Speaker 9:  I think it will compete very heavily with
Speaker 9:  everything else that is in the space. I don't think it's gonna be
Speaker 9:  like, yes, this is not the best thing ever. I think it's nice that we're
Speaker 9:  going to get another viable option and further
Speaker 9:  just kind of differentiate what actual chips are in the
Speaker 9:  systems that that we use and perhaps our
Speaker 9:  future purchasing decisions will be based on what we actually
Speaker 9:  need the laptop for and what Chip is in it, rather than just getting like
Speaker 9:  an X 86 chip in everything.
Speaker 2:  Right.
Speaker 9:  So yeah,
Speaker 2:  So that's actually a good way to think about this, right? And I think even
Speaker 2:  just backing up a few years, like explain sort of the difference in even
Speaker 2:  like the promise between the two. 'cause I feel like there's the kind of
Speaker 2:  Intel X 86 world and then Qualcomm has been trying to carve out
Speaker 2:  a different kind of computer for a while now. Like how
Speaker 2:  would you frame the differences between the two?
Speaker 9:  Oh goodness. I think for that, like I think we gotta look
Speaker 9:  at Intel A MD Apple and now Qualcomm because
Speaker 9:  they're all doing different things with X 86 and
Speaker 9:  arm architecture. So Intel X 86, but it
Speaker 9:  has the big little core difference. The performance cores and
Speaker 9:  efficiency cores. Apple does the same thing, but on arm
Speaker 9:  A MD it's just traditional X 86, it's, it's fine.
Speaker 9:  Qualcomm is on arm but it doesn't have the big little arc
Speaker 9:  architecture. Right. And I think
Speaker 9:  what's really kind of exciting and cool about all those
Speaker 9:  differences is that because we have been able to
Speaker 9:  shriek the transistor sizes on the actual ships so
Speaker 9:  small, the historical sort of
Speaker 9:  issues that came with either clock
Speaker 9:  based instruction sets or what is it,
Speaker 9:  RISC versus C-I-S-C-X
Speaker 9:  86 has always been more hard hardware based. So
Speaker 9:  with the drive into AI and you know, Moore's law kind
Speaker 9:  of hanging in the balance, I think like there comes this
Speaker 9:  question of, well if we want our chips to handle these AI workloads,
Speaker 9:  right, we gotta move into an architecture that's more software based rather
Speaker 9:  than hardware. And also I think it could potentially
Speaker 9:  maybe lower prices a little bit. Like you can get,
Speaker 9:  you know, like I hate, I hate to use the term but word bang for your
Speaker 9:  buck from like, you know, an arm architecture. But like all these
Speaker 9:  AI models like still needs something that's really, really
Speaker 9:  fast in order to be able to run them. So
Speaker 9:  I think Qualcomm's approach is very interesting in that aspect 'cause it
Speaker 9:  has a long history in the mobile space of kind of doing
Speaker 9:  the same thing. So maybe it's
Speaker 9:  gonna be, you know, great right, right out the gate. But if you're still
Speaker 9:  sticking on the X 86 platform, I don't know how much longevity
Speaker 9:  that is going to have with Moore's Law and everything else since it's a
Speaker 9:  hard, a hard hardware based system. So that's my my very
Speaker 9:  nerdy answer. So
Speaker 2:  No, it's a good one. And Tom, I feel like Microsoft specifically
Speaker 2:  has tried harder to make this work than just about anybody. Yeah, and
Speaker 2:  it's possible I, that might be my own bias. 'cause like I, I find the surface
Speaker 2:  line fascinating. So maybe this is a bigger windows push than I'm realizing,
Speaker 2:  but I feel like for way too many years now, Microsoft has been like,
Speaker 2:  Qualcomm chips in surfaces, it's gonna be sick. You're gonna love it. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  everything's gonna be great.
Speaker 10:  I have that turn out and
Speaker 2:  It's just a lie. Like why is Microsoft so invested in this?
Speaker 10:  Well because it's the way that the industry's heading, right? Apple has
Speaker 10:  pioneered with their own silicon like a, a transition like we haven't
Speaker 10:  really seen before and they, they did it without emulation, right? So that
Speaker 10:  they did it by translating those instruction sets. So
Speaker 10:  essentially translating the way that app works. So you tell it to do one
Speaker 10:  thing and use one piece of hardware and it Rosetta, which is Apple's thing,
Speaker 10:  translates that and, and makes it run natively on,
Speaker 10:  on that particular CPU. So might as well tried this emulation
Speaker 10:  stuff about a decade ago with Windows RT and Surface
Speaker 10:  rt. you know, there's that first, the first iteration of Surface was, oh
Speaker 2:  Wow. I remember that one
Speaker 10:  Was an arm push, right? That didn't really work out. It was very slow. There
Speaker 10:  wasn't enough apps. There was this confusing desktop interface. It was just
Speaker 10:  all, yeah, it was just a bit of a messy transition really, because they,
Speaker 10:  they tried to go this, like Steven Sinofsky was in charge of Windows and
Speaker 10:  he really saw the vision of the iPad, the full screen apps, and really wanted
Speaker 10:  to impress that on Windows. That didn't really work out. So then they kind
Speaker 10:  of went to Qualcomm with their tail between their legs essentially and
Speaker 10:  teamed up with them to, as an exclusive partner, to then do Windows 11
Speaker 10:  and Windows 10 sort of on arm stuff. It's better than those,
Speaker 10:  the dark days of Windows RT in that, that confusing mess.
Speaker 10:  But it's still not quite there because the, the Qualcomm chips just have,
Speaker 10:  haven't really delivered the sort of performance and like obviously I wrote
Speaker 10:  about internally at Microsoft, they're thinking these latest chips, these
Speaker 10:  Snapdragon X Elite will sort of bridge that gap of performance.
Speaker 10:  But the key thing I think will be the thing that Apple's really nailed is
Speaker 10:  the performance per what and the efficiencies there. And that's really important
Speaker 10:  because you, you, you get really good performance, but it's not hitting
Speaker 10:  your battery life. So you don't have like, you know, a five hour battery
Speaker 10:  life you'll get all day Battery life is, is what they're saying. But
Speaker 10:  what that translates into, but if they can get close to like the M
Speaker 10:  three battery life and performance, then it's gonna be pretty interesting
Speaker 10:  time for Windows on arm. Especially as there's, there's like rumors of
Speaker 10:  cheaper variants of the X Elite. So story loss week, like x
Speaker 10:  plus or something like that. So that could also open it up to
Speaker 10:  more and more laptops. 'cause these have been pretty high priced items
Speaker 10:  so far.
Speaker 2:  It is very important that if you're going to, you know, copy apple's
Speaker 2:  silicon strategy, you have to have a series of very confusing names that
Speaker 2:  don't actually make any sense to anyone in terms of buying their chips. So
Speaker 2:  I'm glad to hear that Qualcomm is just gonna name everything a bunch of words
Speaker 2:  that don't make any sense. But it seems to me like I personally, the
Speaker 2:  reason I have always kind of rooted for the Windows on Arm thing to
Speaker 2:  work is that it feels like there was this dream we were promised,
Speaker 2:  maybe not all the way back to the Surface rt, but almost that far back
Speaker 2:  of like a very thin Yeah. Always connected with
Speaker 2:  the cellular connection that you get with Qualcomm stuff, right? Laptop slash
Speaker 2:  tablet that is more portable and lasts forever. Like I, I feel like it was
Speaker 2:  years ago that they were promising like 24 hours of battery life outta some
Speaker 2:  of these things. And it's like, well sure it lasts forever. It will, it will
Speaker 2:  do one thing in the 24 hours that it lasts because the performance sucks.
Speaker 2:  But Joanna like that sort of triumvirate of like power battery
Speaker 2:  life and connectivity feels like it kind of doesn't exist in the Windows
Speaker 2:  world right now. Right? Like, is it, am I giving, am I not
Speaker 2:  giving it enough credit?
Speaker 9:  Like it's gotten a lot better. Okay. Like for sure the last maybe
Speaker 9:  like five years or so, maybe four,
Speaker 9:  like there's been a greater focus on power efficiency
Speaker 9:  one. I think to Tom's point, like it's very much being driven
Speaker 9:  by Apple when they brought the their M chip to market,
Speaker 9:  you know, then it was like, oh, now it's game on. Like we really
Speaker 9:  gotta do this. And then there's sort of like the broader scope
Speaker 9:  of like being eco-conscious and conserving energy
Speaker 9:  and everything else. That's kind of also falling into it,
Speaker 9:  especially with a lot of news reports that come out and they talk about
Speaker 9:  like how much power, like data centers just
Speaker 9:  suck up. Sure. And how much power is needed to run like
Speaker 9:  AI processes in the cloud, right? So what
Speaker 9:  we're already kind of seeing is that companies are starting
Speaker 9:  to rethink like, okay, well we need to like give people
Speaker 9:  the ability to, you know, like run AI models like on their
Speaker 9:  local device. Right? 'cause that's what's going
Speaker 9:  to give more longevity to what, to what it is
Speaker 9:  that they're trying to do.
Speaker 2:  I confess as we've been talking about this, Tom, and in your piece you wrote
Speaker 2:  basically that Microsoft feels very confident that it's new line of devices
Speaker 2:  with the Snapdragon stuff is going to match the M three on
Speaker 2:  performance. Yeah. Match or exceed, right. That they feel good that it's
Speaker 2:  going to be a real competitor. My immediate reaction is like, cool,
Speaker 2:  that's actually not the thing I care the most about in my laptop.
Speaker 2:  Like If, you could give me something that ran Windows and got
Speaker 2:  85% of the m three's performance and 105% of its
Speaker 2:  battery life. Like I'd rather have that. Yeah. Personally.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I think we
Speaker 2:  All would. But I also like Joanna, your point is really interesting that
Speaker 2:  like maybe what we're actually heading towards is a gigantic
Speaker 2:  leap in the performance we ask of our laptops if we're gonna start running
Speaker 2:  these local AI models. Yeah. If this idea of an AI PC is going to become
Speaker 2:  true, then like I I, I sincerely believe that it's been a
Speaker 2:  decade since most people were running up against the performance limits of
Speaker 2:  their computer. Yeah. But maybe we're headed back towards that
Speaker 2:  and Tom, maybe that's why Microsoft cares so much about this at this particular
Speaker 2:  moment.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Like it is, it's interesting the way that they're, they're thinking
Speaker 10:  about it internally because it, it's, it's, it's a battle between Qualcomm
Speaker 10:  and, and and Intel for, for all this sort of AI processing. And Microsoft
Speaker 10:  shipped a laptop last year, the Surface laptop studio
Speaker 10:  too. That one had like some really custom NPU from Intel
Speaker 10:  'cause they hadn't obviously put it on the, on the, on the, the main core
Speaker 10:  ultra chips that they've started shipping. But even, even that one is not
Speaker 10:  very powerful. Like it can do the sort of basic background noise
Speaker 10:  removal stuff that's integrated into Windows. What I found
Speaker 10:  fascinating about that push was that they didn't really explain what the
Speaker 10:  NPUs really there for beyond that. And I think that's the key thing that
Speaker 10:  I wanna see in May at this Microsoft event is like, what is
Speaker 10:  the NPU actually gonna be used for for these local tasks? Like they're obviously
Speaker 10:  gonna have their own Windows features, but I'm more curious how devs will
Speaker 10:  be able to like leverage this and software and stuff. And speaking to
Speaker 10:  Intel, they, they, they did some, some recent stuff with
Speaker 10:  some software developers where it can scam malware local on your machine
Speaker 10:  so it doesn't take up your CPU, which is, yeah, I mean that that sort of
Speaker 10:  stuff's kind of interesting. If, you can offload that, but then what else
Speaker 10:  do you offload? Like how much is too much and Yeah. Like it's,
Speaker 10:  it's gonna be interesting to see how that that works. Exactly. But I think
Speaker 10:  more interestingly, the way they count this is by T
Speaker 10:  ops or tops or however you wanna, you wanna say tops. Yeah. Yeah. And
Speaker 10:  I think the Intel one, the Intel core ones that they call themselves
Speaker 10:  as a I PCs are like 10 of that unit. And the ones in
Speaker 10:  the Snapdragon X Elite and stuff are like 40. So a Forex
Speaker 10:  Oh wow. Yeah. Like a, a four times bump on that. And then the next gen ones
Speaker 10:  after that are obviously gonna be even more so, so they're actually Microsoft
Speaker 10:  actually calling the Qualcomm snapdragon ex elite
Speaker 10:  laptops that are coming next Gen co-pilot PCs.
Speaker 10:  So that's quite a, that's where they're thinking is right? Because they're
Speaker 10:  obviously, they don't wanna come out and say Intel's core ultra ones just
Speaker 10:  aren't gonna cut it. But they obviously don't have quite the same performance
Speaker 10:  of, of, for the AI tasks as, as the upcoming Qualcomm stuff. Which makes
Speaker 10:  sense. 'cause it's, it's not on native. So, and Qualcomm's been doing the
Speaker 10:  NPU stuff for, well, for, for years, so for quite some time.
Speaker 10:  But I think that's gonna be an interesting battle about where do they offload
Speaker 10:  this local AI stuff rather than push the, the copilot cloud
Speaker 10:  stuff. The previous aspects, like we spoke about the AI Explorer stuff,
Speaker 10:  where it's essentially gonna be a timeline feature on your PC where you
Speaker 10:  can just say to it, what was I doing last week when I was searching
Speaker 10:  for hotels? Like what tabs did I have? And it'll be like, here's all your
Speaker 10:  tabs. So, and it it, it speaks to sort of like some of the way
Speaker 10:  that we're seeing AI more broadly in devices like you
Speaker 10:  view the humane, the AI pin, right? Like tho those sort of devices that
Speaker 10:  leverage local compute or go to the cloud for queries that
Speaker 10:  hybrid mix or however these companies approach that. And when they get
Speaker 10:  more powerful, it's gonna be super interesting to see how like Windows changes
Speaker 10:  in a, in a world where there's devices that are suddenly doing a bunch of
Speaker 10:  stuff that you normally would've picked up a mouse and keyboard to do, but
Speaker 10:  you can just use your voice with and it's always been that promise, right?
Speaker 10:  Right. Like, and it's never, it's never really got there, but it does feel
Speaker 10:  like we're on the, on the edge of that potentially happening.
Speaker 2:  Well, but at the same time we're in this like in impossible moment
Speaker 2:  for kind of all computing. But I think Windows hits this maybe harder than
Speaker 2:  anybody is, the Windows challenge has always been that there are a lot of
Speaker 2:  people who wanna do new stuff on Windows and you can give people new stuff
Speaker 2:  on Windows, but there are a lot of people who do stuff that hasn't been updated
Speaker 2:  since 2001. Yeah. And they need it to work on their computer. And I
Speaker 2:  think this is where you're talking about, you know, the Qualcomm stuff and
Speaker 2:  the Windows Unarm stuff that has been challenging over the years is it's,
Speaker 2:  you can make the computer run and even If you make the computer run, making
Speaker 2:  the old apps that people need to do their jobs is a whole separate
Speaker 2:  problem. Yeah. And I, I feel like now you're gonna
Speaker 2:  tack on all this AI stuff and it's like, okay, if we were to just tear it
Speaker 2:  all down, start over and build PCs made for
Speaker 2:  the AI stuff that you're talking about, that's one problem to do that
Speaker 2:  that also runs the weird accounting software that no one
Speaker 2:  has thought about in 20 years, but is crucial to how I do my business. Strikes
Speaker 2:  me as a whole nother can of worms. And like
Speaker 2:  Joanna, you, you've been covering this stuff for a long time. Like Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Is that a Bridgeable gap? Like I, I'm sort of, I think the thing we've been
Speaker 2:  burned about with all of this stuff on Windows for years is that it is possible
Speaker 2:  to do all of those things at the same time. And I still am skeptical.
Speaker 9:  The issue we're running into is not like
Speaker 9:  necessarily like speed or anything like that,
Speaker 9:  it's use cases. Hmm. Right. So if we like
Speaker 9:  go back way in history when Apple was trying to design,
Speaker 9:  it's like first, what was it? The power pc, but
Speaker 9:  they were trying to do an arm PC like decades
Speaker 9:  ago. Right? But the reason why it never caught on then was because
Speaker 9:  developers didn't wanna port their stuff over. Right. And it was so much
Speaker 9:  harder to do that back then because of the speed
Speaker 9:  limitations of both architectures, right. Not to mention
Speaker 9:  ARM with its different instructions set relied on more
Speaker 9:  lines of code. And it also relied on a lot more ram
Speaker 9:  to be able to do all, all of that stuff. Now
Speaker 9:  the industry is like caught up with itself and hence why Apple
Speaker 9:  came out with its with its MM chips now I feel like we're
Speaker 9:  kind of seeing more of the same, we got these
Speaker 9:  AI chips with their neuro processing units in it
Speaker 9:  that can do a variety of things at varying
Speaker 9:  speeds. Right? But it's like the use cases that, that
Speaker 9:  I'm seeing, for instance, like generating music
Speaker 9:  from a text prompt. Like okay, that's cool.
Speaker 9:  Like an actual, like musician isn't gonna go and do that most likely.
Speaker 9:  So who's, who's it for? Like, and I think all these
Speaker 9:  like generative AI stuff, we're still trying to
Speaker 9:  figure that out. So there seems to be a, a mismatch
Speaker 9:  between what the tech industry wants to do and
Speaker 9:  what laptop users basically want their laptops to do.
Speaker 9:  So
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I I do think we are, we are due for a bunch of years of there
Speaker 2:  being all of this really interesting new horsepower
Speaker 2:  on these computers and a lot of people being like, what are we gonna do with
Speaker 2:  this? Yeah. But then, like Tom, to your point about background noise removal,
Speaker 2:  like that is the sort of thing that you can just sort of offload off of your
Speaker 2:  computer onto this other Chip that you never really have to think about it.
Speaker 2:  That just like instantly makes your computing life better. And if we can
Speaker 2:  find a bunch of those, like I suddenly get very excited about The future
Speaker 2:  of laptops. Yeah. And I get the sense Microsoft is heading down that
Speaker 2:  road with Windows kind of as fast as it possibly can.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, it seems like it. And it, it, it's also interesting the way that they're
Speaker 10:  potentially positioning their arms surface devices
Speaker 10:  for consumers and the Intel ones for, for businesses that kind
Speaker 10:  of suggests for the first time that they, they are, they are thinking about
Speaker 10:  like, like you were talking about previously, the the, the legacy of these
Speaker 10:  support, these applications and stuff. They, they're starting to think of
Speaker 10:  that as a consumer versus business thing. 'cause obviously predominantly
Speaker 10:  businesses need that legacy support and it's great, right? You can still
Speaker 10:  run like a, a MS DOS application or a game from like the
Speaker 10:  nineties like on your pc. It just opens, it works great. Like
Speaker 10:  of any company that that builds software, Microsoft has always done a very
Speaker 10:  good job of supporting that and that's probably one of their, their greatest
Speaker 10:  traits of even on the export side as well. But yeah, like it, it does seem
Speaker 10:  like they are starting to think how do we split that up? And the
Speaker 10:  last time they did that was obviously Windows eight. So which
Speaker 2:  Went super well. No,
Speaker 9:  No. Windows eight
Speaker 10:  Actually don't think too drastic. But, but are they gonna
Speaker 10:  redesign Windows for an era of ai? Like at the moment they've just
Speaker 10:  shoved a copilot chatbot into Windows 11, which doesn't, not much
Speaker 10:  ambition there, right? Like that's, that's not as ambitious as I'd expect
Speaker 10:  'em to be. Maybe AI explorer is kind of a more of a hint to okay,
Speaker 10:  how AI could really change how you actually use your pc.
Speaker 10:  'cause you've literally been able to type into a prompt and bringing up
Speaker 10:  your search history or whatever you've used on your PC is kind of wild.
Speaker 10:  If that works in, in reality and that could Yeah, like where,
Speaker 10:  where they change the design of Windows and apps in The future
Speaker 10:  would shift pretty big if, if they can leverage it. Well
Speaker 9:  At least for me in, in an ideal world, I just wanna talk
Speaker 9:  to my AI chat bot. Like I don't wanna type to it, right?
Speaker 9:  And it's an accessibility thing for me
Speaker 9:  because like talking requires so much less brain power
Speaker 9:  than like writing does. So if I wanna go look up, you
Speaker 9:  know, my search history, I don't wanna type that in.
Speaker 9:  I know where to go find it and I just wanna, you know, like, oh here's
Speaker 9:  the little thing in my browser for history that I can see. I can just
Speaker 9:  click on it and then I can like go through it all. Now If, you have
Speaker 9:  like a long search history and you have like
Speaker 9:  no idea when you found that thing or what even what that thing
Speaker 9:  was. Yeah, I can definitely see that being useful. If you were, remember
Speaker 9:  what you're trying to find. So yeah. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  it's, it seems very similar to
Speaker 9:  going into a search engine and furiously typing, like trying to
Speaker 9:  find the article that you found. Now
Speaker 9:  for me, I don't save any of my search history. Like if I need to go find
Speaker 9:  something, I bookmark it and I have a little folder for it. So I know
Speaker 9:  like I'm gonna go back and find that. So
Speaker 9:  philosophically it feels like there's
Speaker 9:  this organizational method that I use and then
Speaker 9:  there's tools for people who maybe
Speaker 9:  don't organize the same way like I do. And that's kind of like where
Speaker 9:  AI is heading.
Speaker 2:  I as someone whose entire organizational strategy is just to open several
Speaker 2:  thousand tabs and then close them when my computer collapses Your way sounds
Speaker 2:  better. Alright, before I let you go here, let's, let's just wildly
Speaker 2:  prognosticate for a couple of minutes. So let's assume these
Speaker 2:  Qualcomm chips come out and they are, everything they are promised to be,
Speaker 2:  the efficiency is unbelievable. The performance is outta control. They are
Speaker 2:  like they, they finally did the thing. Are we gonna get like
Speaker 2:  a whole new generation of new kinds of PCs as
Speaker 2:  a result? Like if this is what we think, does it stand to sort of
Speaker 2:  change what our computers are or is this
Speaker 2:  just like bringing windows kind of up to
Speaker 2:  par with some of the best of what you can get from Apple right now?
Speaker 10:  No, I like, I don't think so. The hardware will still be pretty much the
Speaker 10:  same. We've already seen the, the limits of what they can do with
Speaker 10:  the, the chassis anyway. Like the Surface pro X is pretty much as thin as
Speaker 10:  you're gonna get this sort of hardware at this sort of stage until, until
Speaker 10:  it really gets shrunk down even further. But, so I don't think it's going
Speaker 10:  to change much on the hardware side. Yeah you might get some thinner and
Speaker 10:  lighter designs and all that sort of stuff. It will
Speaker 10:  change the battery life. Like that sort of situation I think would be greatly
Speaker 10:  improved. But I think it's really gonna be on the software side of things,
Speaker 10:  how Windows leverages the NPU, like we've been talking about that that software
Speaker 10:  side is really gonna be what differentiates these devices versus the
Speaker 10:  the laptops that you've got to of today. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  My great hope is that you're totally wrong and that actually we're gonna
Speaker 2:  go back to that phase we were in 10 years ago where everybody was just like,
Speaker 2:  what if a laptop was different? Yeah, maybe. But I kind of think that went
Speaker 2:  so badly for everybody that there's going to be real reluctance to do that
Speaker 2:  again. Because like I think, who was it Acer that was just like, what if
Speaker 2:  we put the track pad above the keyboard and everybody's like, that's the
Speaker 2:  stupidest thing I've ever heard in my whole life. And I think it the road
Speaker 2:  to like wildly try to change what a PC looks and feels like
Speaker 2:  is probably much longer than it once was. Even if we can do
Speaker 10:  It. Yeah, that was like the Windows a era where there was a lot of Right
Speaker 10:  experimentation in hardware should we say. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Which I think no one is eager to repeat.
Speaker 10:  No. Yeah, no I think, I think it's gonna be, it's gonna be pretty timid
Speaker 10:  but I do hope we see Ner and lighter, like the surface prox, that
Speaker 10:  sort of device is, is really nice. If, you can get more of that. That'd
Speaker 10:  be nice.
Speaker 2:  Joanna, what about you? Any, are you, are you expecting wild experimentation?
Speaker 9:  Absolutely not. But if we can
Speaker 9:  make chips just as powerful, but that also run cooler,
Speaker 9:  we can make even thinner and lighter laptops. The
Speaker 9:  issue that we're running into now is like thermals, right? And
Speaker 9:  what happens when the processor gets too hot,
Speaker 9:  hot are the, the other components get too hot. Like that just means
Speaker 9:  it's drawing in a lot of power. And what is it doing? It's using more energy.
Speaker 9:  It's depleting the battery life, right? So
Speaker 9:  a lot, there are companies who have figured out like a nice balance
Speaker 9:  with that. Like I find Lenovo does
Speaker 9:  a really good job at balancing power and
Speaker 9:  their battery life. So until we can like make chips that
Speaker 9:  run cooler, I think that we won't
Speaker 9:  like one see as many use cases on the software
Speaker 9:  side of things. And then we also like will be
Speaker 9:  limited to what sort of like new laptop form factors can come out.
Speaker 9:  Like I would love to see one of these qual
Speaker 9:  Qualcomm chips in a dual OLED display
Speaker 9:  laptop. Yeah, like the Zen book or the Lenovo yoga
Speaker 9:  book. I think that if it goes
Speaker 9:  like the best way
Speaker 11:  kidding me? My man and I, we attempted to move out. Yeah, that'll be
Speaker 11:  $1,600 for a studio apartment. Not including Rosie,
Speaker 12:  Not including last fall, the National Association of Realtors released data
Speaker 12:  showing that housing affordability had fallen to its lowest point since
Speaker 12:  the 1980s for reasons of economy,
Speaker 12:  comma American,
Speaker 13:  There just aren't a lot of home sales going on.
Speaker 13:  And there's really kind of a standoff right now between buyers and sellers
Speaker 12:  That standoff leads to another kind of standoff.
Speaker 14:  It's always fun being 40 something years old and having to live with your
Speaker 14:  parents again. And I know it's all my fault,
Speaker 12:  Sir, I don't know your life, but on today explained a Tupac series on how
Speaker 12:  it might not be your fault.
Speaker 14:  And I'll tell my mom, mom, I'm gonna the bathroom, I'll be back if I'm not
Speaker 14:  out in like three minutes. Dog. She's like knocking on the door going,
Speaker 14:  everything okay in there? Yeah, mom, everything's cool, dog.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the Hotline as always. The number is
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 Verge one one. The email is Vergecast at The
Speaker 2:  Verge dot com. We love hearing all of your questions and we try to answer
Speaker 2:  at least one on the show every week. This week we have a question from Tony.
Speaker 17:  Hi Bridge casters. This is Tony. I'm in the market for a new e-reader.
Speaker 17:  I have books on Kindle epub formats and p devs. I've been
Speaker 17:  thinking about getting a books Palmer, but the price and it being kind of
Speaker 17:  stuck on Android 11 maybe be obsolete too quickly
Speaker 17:  is holding me back. So I just go the normally route and buy a Kindle.
Speaker 17:  Also, how's a new Kobo color and why do I feel more complete when
Speaker 17:  I buy a new gizmo and gadget? Any help you could gimme would be great. So
Speaker 17:  yeah,
Speaker 2:  All of the existential questions of To Vergecast rolled into one. There is
Speaker 2:  only one person on earth who is the most qualified to answer this Alex
Speaker 2:  Krantz, hello.
Speaker 12:  Hey. Yeah, I, I know
Speaker 18:  Why I feel better after I buy a gizmo. It's just like
Speaker 18:  retail therapy's just, it's magic.
Speaker 2:  It's, there's just something where you're like, I have now acquired this
Speaker 2:  and I'm going to, I'm gonna use it. Well yeah, and it's gonna make me better,
Speaker 2:  especially with reading gadgets. There is something to like, ah, I've really
Speaker 2:  fallen off on, you know, deep classic fiction and this is the
Speaker 2:  thing that's gonna get me back into it and it never is. But, so I wanna,
Speaker 2:  I wanna answer this question kind of in reverse. Okay. Tell me about the
Speaker 2:  Kobo. You've now had it for a few days early thoughts.
Speaker 18:  I like it. It's, so I've got both the Libra and Nico Clara
Speaker 18:  and I've been using the Libra more. In fact, right after I finished
Speaker 18:  recording this, running over to the library to update my library card Nice.
Speaker 18:  So that I can get some books on it because it's got overdrive built in,
Speaker 18:  which is really exciting. But it's also a Kobo e-reader,
Speaker 18:  so it's like built for Cobos bookstore and stuff. So it's a little more
Speaker 18:  difficult to use. Like you, you know, it's a little more difficult to
Speaker 18:  get all your books on it if you're not already in the Kobo ecosystem.
Speaker 18:  Right. But it's still really good and it's super light and it's just
Speaker 18:  like, it moves fast. It just like, I'm like, Ooh, I had, I make that noise
Speaker 18:  every time. I like turn it on. Just like, oh, it's just, it's just going,
Speaker 2:  I really just, the one screenshot I keep seeing of the home screen of
Speaker 2:  the color where you can actually see the color on all the book covers, I'm
Speaker 2:  just like, ugh, I want that.
Speaker 18:  It's wonderful. But also it is in no way perfect. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I believe
Speaker 18:  It. Kaleido three, the, the technology they're using is, is really
Speaker 18:  good and it is in so much better than previous
Speaker 18:  iterations of color e Inc, but it's still like the
Speaker 18:  colors aren't as vibrant as, as you're used to on, on other
Speaker 18:  displays or even just like print magazines.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's fair. And I think to some extent that's fine. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 2:  Like I think, I don't know, I've, I've now used these devices long enough
Speaker 2:  that I think anybody who is like mad about the pixel density of EIN
Speaker 2:  is kind of barking up the wrong tree. That's just not the point. I think
Speaker 2:  it's good enough in most cases. But then it's weird because color does introduce
Speaker 2:  a thing where like when it's just sort of black on gray,
Speaker 2:  you don't notice it quite the same way. But I can imagine when you have theoretically
Speaker 2:  lots of colors, you're gonna notice the things that don't look good more.
Speaker 18:  Yeah. And I, you really notice that on like the Android e
Speaker 18:  Ink tablets that do color like it is really, really noticeable. It's, it's
Speaker 18:  a lot easier on this one and, and I think for most people, if you're ready
Speaker 18:  to dip your toes into color ein, I need more time with it.
Speaker 18:  But I suspect Kobo is the way I'm gonna push people for a little while.
Speaker 18:  'cause it's just like it's a nice ass reader
Speaker 18:  so far. Yeah, I'm enjoying it. But yeah, it's not
Speaker 18:  quite iPad worthy. Okay. So if you're still like, I want it to be an iPad,
Speaker 18:  I'm sorry.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I, I do think I've, like the first question I ask people now who
Speaker 2:  ask what e-reader to buy is, are you sure the correct answer isn't an iPad
Speaker 2:  mini? Because I think for a lot of people the correct answer is an iPad mini.
Speaker 2:  It's also like three times the price in a very, very different battery life
Speaker 2:  story and all of that. So yep. Let's just leave that one aside for now. Like
Speaker 2:  Tony, ask yourself the question, is the right thing an iPad mini? And if
Speaker 2:  it's not, let's keep going. So keep going. The question of which
Speaker 2:  e-reader to buy is, I feel like you and I talk about this every time we talk
Speaker 2:  about this. It's like weirdly a lifestyle decision because you're like, okay,
Speaker 2:  if I buy a Kindle, I am in on Amazon because Amazon stuff has
Speaker 2:  gotten a little more open over time and you can upload PDFs and you can upload
Speaker 2:  epub stuff and it's a little better, but only a little and it's kind of
Speaker 2:  a pain in the ass. And If, you want to just like buy or download a book,
Speaker 2:  you are gonna do it through Amazon and Kobo, which I think used to be
Speaker 2:  a little more open and I was excited about things like the pocket integration
Speaker 2:  has lost a little bit of that. So they're coming towards this middle of like,
Speaker 2:  you're kind of just picking your poison either way, right?
Speaker 18:  Yeah. It's kinda like, I I think a lot about the Apple
Speaker 18:  antitrust thing here because it, it's the same thing where you're like,
Speaker 18:  oh no, I have to make this decision of like ecosystem pretty early
Speaker 18:  on because moving to a new ecosystem is hard
Speaker 18:  and it's EAs it's certainly easier with an e-reader, but you still have
Speaker 18:  to go download Collibra. You still have to go look up a bunch
Speaker 18:  of tutorials and load it all up and, and, and pull all your books over and
Speaker 18:  then transfer over. Right?
Speaker 2:  You've just lost 99.5% of people, right? Like just right there. Yeah.
Speaker 18:  Most people don't wanna do that. So you really do have to say, okay, do
Speaker 18:  I wanna go Kobo, do I wanna go Amazon? And I think Kobo is doing
Speaker 18:  more interesting stuff in the space right now, right? If you're looking
Speaker 18:  for just a straight e-reader not thinking about it. But, but that's not
Speaker 18:  what Tony Tony's thinking about like the books Paulo, which is a Right
Speaker 18:  just no color. Black and white. I think it's like six inch
Speaker 18:  phone.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's an, it's an E Ink phone basically, right? Is like, it's a little,
Speaker 2:  it's a little tiny tablet that does e ink stuff. And actually I have one
Speaker 2:  on its way to me right now and I'm so excited about it because I don't dunno,
Speaker 2:  If you notice this, but it's like a, a little thing that just is percolating
Speaker 2:  around the internet as like the internet's favorite gadget. Like Craig Mod,
Speaker 2:  who is a newsletter writer and author who I love is like obsessed with his
Speaker 2:  bunch of people are getting it and being like, this is the exact thing that
Speaker 2:  I need. I'm very enthusiastic about it as a little tiny pocketable
Speaker 2:  reading device, but it does make me nervous. And part of the reason I wanted
Speaker 2:  to do this with you is to sort of check in on where we're at with books because
Speaker 2:  we've been, I think, enthusiastic about their potential for a while now,
Speaker 2:  but it doesn't feel like we've gotten kind of the breakthrough device
Speaker 2:  yet.
Speaker 18:  I think the, the Palmer feels closest. Right. Okay. And and Tony's concern
Speaker 18:  was that they, it's on Android 11, it might not get upgraded
Speaker 18:  books has actually been really good in the last couple of years about upgrading.
Speaker 18:  Oh, okay. Pretty consistently. Is it always gonna be to the newest, latest
Speaker 18:  flavor of Android? No,
Speaker 2:  But also for what you're using these devices for. It's like if, if what you
Speaker 2:  need is the latest download of the Netflix app, like you're buying the wrong
Speaker 2:  device,
Speaker 18:  Don't, don't buy this for that. Right? Yeah. I think like if
Speaker 18:  you're looking at the Palmer and your only concern is that it's on
Speaker 18:  Android 11, just go get the Palmer, you're gonna have a great time. It's
Speaker 18:  gonna get updated at some point. Like you'll be fine.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think that's right. And I mean, I'm just thinking about this as you're
Speaker 2:  talking that like, this is one case where Android being so
Speaker 2:  fragmented actually helps you because like on on iOS, I would be much more
Speaker 2:  worried about sending you to a device that's a few years old because you're
Speaker 2:  gonna start to get outdated software that won't support old versions of the
Speaker 2:  software on Android. A lot of these developers don't have a choice but to
Speaker 2:  support wide swaths of Android. So the odds
Speaker 2:  of you being able to use even Android 11 with like the
Speaker 2:  Kindle app and the Barnes and Noble app and your favorite reading app probably
Speaker 2:  pretty high for a while. Yeah,
Speaker 18:  Yeah. You're you're gonna be using it for a while. Yeah. I bought a books
Speaker 18:  e-reader back in like 2019. It's still getting system
Speaker 18:  updates, it's still getting software updates, like it's still cruising.
Speaker 18:  I can still use all the main e reading software on it. So if
Speaker 18:  that's kind of what you're looking at, Tony, just go get it.
Speaker 2:  And books, we should say is more like, it's, it's basically an EIN tablet
Speaker 2:  that runs Android, right? Is that a reasonable explanation? Yeah,
Speaker 18:  It is an, it's, it's an EIN tablet, it's an Android EIN tablet.
Speaker 18:  They do their own kind of custom launcher and stuff. And you could theoretically
Speaker 18:  go do it your own launcher but stick with theirs. Yeah. Because
Speaker 18:  it's, it's built for ein and that's, that's the really big friction you
Speaker 18:  notice with those Android e Inc tablets is they're using apps that weren't
Speaker 18:  built for ein and it just, you just run into little hiccups and quirks.
Speaker 18:  But
Speaker 2:  The flip side is you get all the apps, right? Like that's, and I, I
Speaker 2:  can't think of any other meaningful e-reader out there.
Speaker 2:  If there is one, people tell us, Vergecast the virgin.com send
Speaker 2:  us links to all of the cool cross platform e-readers that exist. I don't
Speaker 2:  think we're gonna get very many emails, but that's the pitch right, with
Speaker 2:  the books is they're just like, you can have all the apps.
Speaker 18:  Yeah, exactly. That, that's the pitch. Because there's, there's a couple
Speaker 18:  other folks out there who, who are primarily there. They're Chinese based
Speaker 18:  companies who are doing this as well and everybody's kind of settled on,
Speaker 18:  okay, I guess we'll go with Android and, and do like a weird custom
Speaker 18:  build of Android. But then they run into a problem of doing weird custom
Speaker 18:  builds of Android is hard and, and it's hard to maintain and everything,
Speaker 18:  which is why books is kind of ahead, because they're a bigger company and
Speaker 18:  they can just maintain it better. But yeah. And then all the other kind
Speaker 18:  of small e-reader companies, you have to side load and you're just
Speaker 18:  stuck side loading everything, which is fine. That's what I did to get,
Speaker 18:  to start reading on the Kobo this weekend. 'cause I need to buy more Kobo
Speaker 18:  books. That's not everybody's bag.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I mean, again, I think the good news is that with a little bit
Speaker 2:  of work, if what you have is a library of
Speaker 2:  PDFs and stuff, you can get those onto most e-readers now. Like
Speaker 2:  it is, it's not easy, but it is doable.
Speaker 18:  If you've got Collibra, you can use any e-reader you want. Yeah. With a
Speaker 18:  little work. Right?
Speaker 2:  Right. Has speaking of books has, has books. I feel like they put out a new
Speaker 2:  thing like every two weeks have they shipped anything cool and
Speaker 2:  new recently?
Speaker 18:  Nothing Super cool. They, they've been a little quiet. We've seen a lot
Speaker 18:  of, they've just been putting out like color versions of a lot of their,
Speaker 18:  their products at the moment and a lot of just movement around the
Speaker 18:  books. Palma, I, I see. Like I'm seeing that thing everywhere and I really
Speaker 18:  wanna get it, but at the same time I know exactly what it is. And I was
Speaker 18:  like, I have enough books, devices in my house. I was like, do I need another
Speaker 18:  one that's just a little smaller? I've used smaller a, a readers like that.
Speaker 18:  I just, it's not my cup of tea personally.
Speaker 2:  I, I was always the like pocket sized six inch Kindle person
Speaker 2:  and I recently got a Kindle scribe, which is the one with the, the stylist
Speaker 2:  for taking notes. I love that thing. It's still very light,
Speaker 2:  so I can like hold it in one hand in bed without dropping it on my face.
Speaker 2:  But having, having just a little more space, especially for things like
Speaker 2:  PDFs, which don't often render super well on those smaller
Speaker 2:  screens, way better. Huge fan.
Speaker 18:  It's nice. Well, that's why I like the Libras because it's got that side
Speaker 18:  that you can just hold. It's basically got a handle built in and, and I
Speaker 18:  am all about that. Like I saw that with the original Oasis and was like,
Speaker 18:  oh, I've now had my platonic ideal form factor for an
Speaker 18:  e-reader. And I never wanna escape that. If it doesn't have a, like, just
Speaker 18:  a little handle on the side for me to hold a larger bezel on one side, then
Speaker 18:  I don't want it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Give me buttons or give me death is what I always say. I could not
Speaker 2:  agree
Speaker 2:  this thing,
Speaker 2:  worth your time. There's lots more on everything we talked about at The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com. We'll put some links in the show notes. But as always, read The
Speaker 2:  Verge dot com. The news is crazy and is only gonna keep being crazier for
Speaker 2:  really the next several months. So check it all out. As always, If you have
Speaker 2:  thoughts, questions, feelings, or want to talk about the location of
Speaker 2:  undersea cables near you, you can always email us at Vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com. Call the Hotline eight six six Verge one one. we love hearing
Speaker 2:  from you. Send us all your thoughts and questions and ideas for what we should
Speaker 2:  do on the show. This show is produced by Andrew Moreno, Liam James, and Wil
Speaker 2:  Pour The. Vergecast is a Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast
Speaker 2:  network. NELI, Alex and I will be back on Friday to talk about more AI news.
Speaker 2:  Some new gadgets coming this week and lots more. We'll see you then. Rock
Speaker 2:  and roll