# Transcript
ID: ad612a29-d090-499f-b860-4a7d74a3b5b4
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5233728684333340090/-8259516495246455184/s93290-US-3005s-1728813645.mp3
Description: Danny and Steven Sanicki are twins, competitive golfers, and suddenly the biggest names in online mini golf. They started making mini golf content on TikTok about a year ago, and it took off; since then they've been trying to ride the viral wave and also turn it into something that lasts. For this episode, the first in a miniseries we're calling How To Make It In The Future, we talk to the Sanickis about their journey to turn putt-putt into their life's work — without killing the fun in the process.
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast
Speaker 2:  of making this putt right now. I'm your friend David Pierce and I
Speaker 2:  am playing mini golf. I am at the East Potomac mini golf
Speaker 2:  course in I. Don't know, it's like an island between Virginia and
Speaker 2:  dc. There's really fun golf course over There, but the real fun is this mini
Speaker 2:  golf course and the key is If. you get out here early enough in the morning,
Speaker 2:  A, nobody notices you're missing work. And B, there's nobody
Speaker 2:  else here. So, I. Just get out, crush some 18. We're good to go.
Speaker 2:  Anyway. The reason I'm doing this here and right now is because
Speaker 2:  this episode we're about to do is actually all about mini golf. This is
Speaker 2:  the first episode in a two part mini series that we're doing that we've been
Speaker 2:  calling how to Make It in the Future and basically the idea is we wanna
Speaker 2:  talk to people and tell stories about different ways people are trying to,
Speaker 2:  well make it different kinds of creators, different kinds of businesses,
Speaker 2:  different kinds of strategies on how to be successful in this
Speaker 2:  world we live in. And for these two episodes, What we're re gonna talk about
Speaker 2:  especially is content people whose businesses make content
Speaker 2:  and people for whom that content becomes their business. And then how you
Speaker 2:  figure out how to make all of that makes sense in a way that feels
Speaker 2:  good and works well for you for a long time. Today's story, believe it or
Speaker 2:  not, is about mini golf So I figured this is work
Speaker 2:  today. Let's give it a whirl.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we got a lot to get to But first we're gonna take a quick break
Speaker 2:  then it's mini golf time. This is The Vergecast, we'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  three are Steven and Danny Sin and their friend Matthew.
Speaker 2:  Steven and Danny are twins. They're competitive golfers and at the time they
Speaker 2:  had just recently graduated From, the University of Wisconsin Parkside.
Speaker 2:  They all step up to the first hole. It's a pretty simple one, one of those
Speaker 2:  ones that's a little wavy but If, you just hit it down the middle,
Speaker 2:  you'll be fine. It's like the perfect first mini golf hole just to get you
Speaker 2:  warmed up. Steven steps up and goes first
Speaker 5:  Nearly with a hole in one on the first hole.
Speaker 2:  Then it's Matthew's turn,
Speaker 5:  Matthew's tee shot
Speaker 5:  off the wall into a good bounce but not
Speaker 5:  enough speed
Speaker 2:  And then it's Danny,
Speaker 5:  My part to take the lead on a good line.
Speaker 5:  Lips out, brutal.
Speaker 2:  At the top of the screen the whole time they're playing, there's a neon blue
Speaker 2:  line of text that just says Mini golf tournament underneath it in like
Speaker 2:  Microsoft paint level graphics, it says each of the guys' names
Speaker 2:  and updates the score underneath it after every hole. It's So
Speaker 2:  low budget. It's kind of delightful honestly, all the names
Speaker 2:  are in different fonts and colors. They're not aligned at all.
Speaker 2:  Danny's score in the middle is smaller on the screen for some reason, but
Speaker 2:  there's something about it that just kind of works and it's kind of riveting.
Speaker 2:  On the second hole, Danny steps up and calls his shot that he's gonna get
Speaker 2:  a hole in one and then he doesn't. The first two
Speaker 2:  holes are both pretty straightforward mini golf holes, but then the guys
Speaker 2:  play a third hole at this course underneath a waterfall and with a
Speaker 2:  few posts in the way, like imagine playing mini
Speaker 2:  golf underneath a deck that's kind of What this one looks like and
Speaker 2:  every time somebody hits their first shot, the camera clearly a
Speaker 2:  smartphone camera just does that abrupt zoom to follow the ball. The camera
Speaker 2:  is always behind the person in the tee box and then just sort of whoof
Speaker 2:  zooms to follow the ball towards the hole. None of it is
Speaker 2:  you would say well shot or beautifully produced. And
Speaker 2:  as you can hear, Danny's commentary isn't exactly like high
Speaker 2:  production value.
Speaker 5:  Corner There have some work left There Steven
Speaker 5:  or Matthew here
Speaker 5:  off the wall. The shot rolls out,
Speaker 2:  But it works, right? It really works for me. I really enjoy this video,
Speaker 2:  but more importantly it worked after the guys played the
Speaker 2:  round. Danny added all those crude scores, overlayed the commentary in
Speaker 2:  one take basically just by watching the video and talking about it
Speaker 2:  and posted it the next day
Speaker 6:  And we were kinda like, eh, that was kinda lame. Like I don't know
Speaker 6:  how that's gonna do but I'll post it anyways, I posted it. The
Speaker 6:  first tournament we posted got 6.8 million views on TikTok and we were
Speaker 6:  like all, well let's go film another one.
Speaker 2:  That's Steven by the way, as we're talking, he's sitting at his
Speaker 2:  computer right next to Danny and they both Look and sound a lot alike.
Speaker 2:  It's confusing but we're gonna get through it. They're twins. It's complicated.
Speaker 2:  Oh, I should also mention, by the way, that 6.8 million number, he says
Speaker 2:  it's not just that one video that got 6.8 million views. Danny
Speaker 2:  actually posted six videos From that round over the next two days. They showed
Speaker 2:  the whole round three holes per video all in a row.
Speaker 2:  Ultimately Danny won the round pretty handily
Speaker 5:  Calling an early victory, missed it like Scotty Scheffler at
Speaker 5:  the masters. We're gonna tap this in here to secure the
Speaker 5:  victory. I shot 40, Matthew 42, Stephen 48. Thanks for
Speaker 5:  following along. Next tournament coming soon.
Speaker 2:  It's really funny to watch those six videos in order now.
Speaker 2:  Danny edited them all back to back, but you can literally see him getting
Speaker 2:  better as he goes by the sixth video. All the scorecards are
Speaker 2:  even and the same color and Danny had stopped making scoring mistakes
Speaker 2:  like he did that you just heard there's still a lot of jump cutting and rack
Speaker 2:  focusing, but that seems to be part of the Look rather than kind of not
Speaker 2:  knowing What, you're doing So. Yeah, six videos, two days,
Speaker 2:  6.8 million views. Danny and Steven I don't think realized that
Speaker 2:  this series was gonna do numbers but they did understand pretty quickly
Speaker 2:  What, most creators understand pretty quickly you gotta just
Speaker 2:  keep posting. They'd been making golf content together for a while,
Speaker 2:  Steven said and they had been planning for a while to make some kind of
Speaker 2:  career out of it.
Speaker 6:  We started about three and a half years ago, actually about three
Speaker 6:  years ago now, and we were doing golf
Speaker 6:  simulator stuff at our school when we were in college.
Speaker 6:  We were kind of getting interested in social media.
Speaker 2:  If you've ever seen a golf video on TikTok, you know roughly What, those
Speaker 2:  early videos Look like people hitting balls into a screen
Speaker 2:  indoors, which simulates where they go on a real course or playing on
Speaker 2:  actual round of golf with the shot tracer and all that good stuff.
Speaker 2:  Golf content is huge all around the internet and the snicky are good
Speaker 2:  golfers but in like a relatable way So, it certainly seems
Speaker 2:  plausible that they could have pulled it off. Danny even had one video of
Speaker 2:  his regular golf game go slightly viral.
Speaker 6:  I had posted one video of me golfing in high school that my high
Speaker 6:  school golf coach took and it started getting a bunch of views
Speaker 6:  overnight and I showed Steve and I was like Look at this and we were like,
Speaker 6:  wow, like What What. Can we do to expand So? We started off with doing
Speaker 6:  our golf stuff.
Speaker 2:  Did you think on that first video like, oh I'm gonna post this in, a lot
Speaker 2:  of people are gonna watch it because a lot of people like golf content like
Speaker 2:  What, I, I feel like that I would not personally have
Speaker 2:  guessed that like I posted a random video, From my high school golf career
Speaker 2:  is like how you launch a social media universe. But maybe I'm wrong, like
Speaker 2:  did you, did you have high ambitions when you posted that first video? Well
Speaker 6:  I I probably posted about 25 videos before and nothing did that well,
Speaker 6:  okay, So I didn't think anything different of this post, although it was
Speaker 6:  a little bit cooler of a post There were a lot of people in the background
Speaker 6:  watching I made The putt, So I didn't think anything
Speaker 6:  was gonna do well with it, but when I woke up the next morning and it had
Speaker 6:  a bunch of views, I was like, well maybe we found
Speaker 6:  something. But We didn't have many more clips to post From high school 'cause
Speaker 6:  we were in college and So. It kind of just took off From There
Speaker 6:  and then We started doing our live streaming on TikTok
Speaker 6:  and we were kind of thinking We were, we enjoyed live streaming but we
Speaker 6:  wanted to find a way that we could just be content creators
Speaker 2:  Other than a couple of those little pops and the sort of consistent live
Speaker 2:  streaming stuff, the golf content wasn't exactly exploding for the
Speaker 2:  guys. You won't know this If, you don't care about golf, but There are a
Speaker 2:  lot of golf creators out There and increasingly like the
Speaker 2:  pros are becoming creators themselves. Hey
Speaker 7:  Guys, this is Bryson de Shambo and welcome back to my channel.
Speaker 2:  That right There is Bryson de Shambo who is one of the best
Speaker 2:  pros and most famous golfers on earth right now and
Speaker 2:  he has used YouTube in part to totally rehab his image
Speaker 2:  as a pro. He's actually become hugely popular on YouTube and
Speaker 2:  TikTok playing golf with creators with other pros with
Speaker 2:  Donald Trump. Honestly, we could do a whole episode about his
Speaker 2:  arc as a creator and maybe we should kind of a fun idea, but Anyway,
Speaker 2:  the point is the golf space is extremely competitive
Speaker 2:  and full honestly the mini golf space
Speaker 2:  less So So, maybe it's not surprising that it was the mini golf videos that
Speaker 2:  first popped for the sies, but the thing is, after a few years
Speaker 2:  of making videos trying and trying to find the thing,
Speaker 2:  having a big hit feels pretty great even when it's not the one
Speaker 2:  you expected. That first hit also brings up one of the moments that
Speaker 2:  a lot of creators go through I think you start out making the kinds of stuff
Speaker 2:  you wanna make, the things you've been planning and thinking about for forever,
Speaker 2:  then something you make takes off. Sometimes it's exactly What you'd always
Speaker 2:  wanted and planned and hoped for. Sometimes frankly, I think more often it's
Speaker 2:  like a weird throwaway joke or something you just made on a
Speaker 2:  whim and didn't think about. You're always making content. You post something,
Speaker 2:  it goes nuts, the internet and the algorithms are unpredictable that way,
Speaker 2:  but then it happens and now you're left with a question, do you keep doing
Speaker 2:  What? You were doing What, you kind of came here to do, or do you go with
Speaker 2:  What works? Do you double down? Do you triple down
Speaker 2:  and If you decide to do that. How do you take this thing that for some
Speaker 2:  unknown, maybe unknowable reason, pleased the algorithm
Speaker 2:  gods and turn that thing into your Life and is
Speaker 2:  turning that thing into your Life, even What you want, I'm making this sound
Speaker 2:  kind of existential because I think it is and I think very few creators
Speaker 2:  see this moment coming, but it always seems to come. My
Speaker 2:  favorite example of this is all the people who were like video game
Speaker 2:  streamers on YouTube but then during the Johnny Depp Amber Heard trial in
Speaker 2:  2022 started putting up daily recaps of the trial.
Speaker 2:  They didn't do this because they had deep passion for Johnny
Speaker 2:  Depp. Amber heard trial coverage, they did it because it worked. You see
Speaker 2:  other people getting views with trial takes you do a trial, take some
Speaker 2:  subscribers might think it's weird to see it on your channel, but it gets
Speaker 2:  views and So you keep going and at some point you have to Look at yourself
Speaker 2:  and say, okay, am I a video game streamer or am I a much more
Speaker 2:  successful court reporter? It's a tough question to answer because There
Speaker 2:  are big costs and big trade offs on both sides of that.
Speaker 2:  To be fair, the syn didn't have to make quite that intense a decision.
Speaker 2:  They went From regular golf to mini golf, you know it's like a much straighter
Speaker 2:  line and they could keep making regular golf content on their
Speaker 2:  channels and it would still make sense in context. So in that sense. It was
Speaker 2:  actually a pretty easy transition
Speaker 6:  Right after that first tournament. We both looked at each other and
Speaker 6:  we were like, this is it. Like let's do it. And
Speaker 6:  it's fun because it is a form of golf and
Speaker 6:  it's intense and it's all of our videos kind of
Speaker 6:  revolve around a competition or a challenge. So
Speaker 6:  we knew right There that hey, we're gonna enjoy mini golf
Speaker 6:  and let's do it So,
Speaker 2:  Were you like mini golfers? Anyway like I feel like every golfer plays mini
Speaker 2:  golf, right? It's like I I like mini golf I just played the Tiger Woods mini
Speaker 2:  golf thing for the first time. That was bananas.
Speaker 2:  But like is this like a thing you guys would normally do or
Speaker 2:  do you like wake up one day and you're like, let's go make a video at mini
Speaker 2:  golf and and see.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I would say we weren't too into mini golf
Speaker 6:  prior to starting to film and then we
Speaker 6:  started to figure out all the courses in the area, all the good
Speaker 6:  courses around the country and, but
Speaker 6:  no, it was just more of a thing we'd maybe
Speaker 6:  do once a year, twice a year.
Speaker 2:  It's like a vacation thing. I feel like you, you like go, you play mini golf
Speaker 2:  when you're like on family vacations and that's kind of it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, exactly. Okay. So. Yeah, no it wasn't
Speaker 6:  What We thought, but We wanted to try something new because
Speaker 6:  it's always nice to give your viewers something fresh or something
Speaker 6:  new. So, we tried it and it turned out to
Speaker 6:  be our niche and it's also more competitive than
Speaker 6:  golf. I would say some of the people that We play mini golf with
Speaker 6:  don't really have a chance against us in golf, but in mini golf
Speaker 6:  it's a lot more competitive and anybody can win
Speaker 2:  So. Yeah, they pretty quickly decided to go hard on mini golf content
Speaker 2:  they did and do still make a lot of regular golf content too, but they knew
Speaker 2:  immediately that people loved watching mini golf So. They filmed another
Speaker 2:  round, posted it, got views, filmed another posted it got views, theory,
Speaker 2:  proven kind of, but then this is another moment you get
Speaker 2:  to as a creator where you have to figure out not just whether to keep doing
Speaker 2:  the thing that got views but why it got views in the first place.
Speaker 2:  That requires understanding at a deep and specific level
Speaker 2:  and a replicable level for that matter. What makes something work on
Speaker 2:  the internet and that is really, really hard to do.
Speaker 2:  Like If, you were to try and explain why this video
Speaker 8:  Go crazy every time that you do. Oh you gotta give him that hawk to and spit
Speaker 8:  on that thing
Speaker 2:  Became the hottest thing on the internet in many years and tried
Speaker 2:  to back that into a formula that you could repeat again.
Speaker 2:  I bet you couldn't do it. I really do I. Don't think you could do it. I mean
Speaker 2:  the video's funny, but There are a lot of funny things out There and would
Speaker 2:  you have guessed frankly the first time that you saw this video that Hay
Speaker 2:  Welch the hawk to a girl herself would now have a giant hit podcasts
Speaker 2:  and still be famous all these months later? If, you would have
Speaker 2:  call me I, have lots of questions for you. The difference between getting
Speaker 2:  it right and getting it wrong in those moments when you're taking off
Speaker 2:  is the difference between being a meme forever and being a
Speaker 2:  celebrity forever. People will either know you as the name of your meme,
Speaker 2:  like you're the scumbag Steve Guy or the kombucha girl or
Speaker 2:  the meme just becomes part of the story of how you became like Lil
Speaker 2:  Nas X. It can go one way or the other and there's
Speaker 2:  not that much wiggle room between, but figuring out why people
Speaker 2:  liked your videos is hard. Even when it's just three guys playing
Speaker 2:  mini golf. It can be tempting in a lot of ways to not think about it and
Speaker 2:  just kind of keep doing What you're doing and trust that it'll keep working,
Speaker 2:  but eventually you do have to try and sit down and figure out What are we
Speaker 2:  doing that works? I asked the guys about this and Danny said he
Speaker 2:  has a theory.
Speaker 6:  I think that just like how the video was produced,
Speaker 6:  it could have just been a video of us mini golfing with no
Speaker 6:  voiceover or anything on top of it, just us hitting a ball,
Speaker 6:  but I think What added to it was the voiceovers kind of
Speaker 6:  making you feel like you're There like something's on the line. This is super
Speaker 6:  intense, just it really adds a lot to the videos.
Speaker 6:  So, I, I, I don't know a hundred percent What, it was I mean it wasn't
Speaker 6:  anything crazy, it wasn't a special tournament, nothing
Speaker 6:  insane happened but I think just the voiceover kind of
Speaker 6:  brings people in and really makes them understand what's kind of
Speaker 6:  going on in the videos and also having every shot
Speaker 6:  recorded clearly you see every pot where it ends up So.
Speaker 6:  It's not like, oh is maybe
Speaker 6:  cheating or this isn't legit So I think just
Speaker 6:  the way that it was produced and kinda edited
Speaker 6:  with clear scores on top and to see where everybody stands
Speaker 6:  and who's gonna win was thrilling to
Speaker 6:  viewers.
Speaker 2:  Steven also has a theory right
Speaker 6:  Now. I would say our bracket style tournaments are
Speaker 6:  sort of our best performing I. Think head-to-head matches
Speaker 6:  are something that a lot of viewers like So. We try to post those at the
Speaker 6:  start of a month in hopes that they perform the best
Speaker 2:  And Danny actually has another theory. If
Speaker 6:  Someone makes a hole in one at the start of a video, I'll and someone
Speaker 6:  else's ball isn't on the screen. I'll try to put that first. Maybe
Speaker 6:  I like to think that a hole in one sometimes brings the viewers in a little
Speaker 6:  bit more and might help the algorithm. So just kind of
Speaker 6:  experimenting with different clips and sometimes people get mad like he
Speaker 6:  wasn't supposed to go first There, but I mix the clips up when we're playing,
Speaker 6:  it's all right, but sometimes when I edit it, things
Speaker 4:  Get a little mixed
Speaker 2:  Around whatever it was in that video, whether it was the way it was produced
Speaker 2:  or the way the tournament was put together or the way the scoreboard looked,
Speaker 2:  it worked. So, the guys kept doing it more and more and more of it all the
Speaker 2:  time and it kept working. We'll talk about What that looks like and I also
Speaker 2:  have a theory on why it all worked as well as it did. But. first we have
Speaker 2:  to take a break. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  Support For. this episode comes From AWS. With the power of
Speaker 4:  AWS generative AI teams can get relevant fast answers
Speaker 4:  to pressing questions and use data to drive real results,
Speaker 4:  power your business and generate real impact with the most
Speaker 4:  experienced cloud.
Speaker 2:  play it at big puts, which is their local course. In Greenfield, Wisconsin,
Speaker 2:  every hole There seems to be visual in an unusual way.
Speaker 2:  On one you have to hit the ball through a halfpipe with skateboards in the
Speaker 2:  middle as obstacles. There's another one where there's a loop that you have
Speaker 2:  to smash the ball through and that loop is made out of a huge truck tire,
Speaker 2:  which is really cool. One hole makes you hit the ball through two
Speaker 2:  different sets of bowling pin obstacles and the hole is in the
Speaker 2:  middle of all the bowling pins. I've never played a course like that or
Speaker 2:  that course for that matter, but it's really fun to watch this course and
Speaker 2:  I find myself sitting There thinking about where I would hit the ball to
Speaker 2:  try and get the angle just right. It's not like the NBA or the NFL,
Speaker 2:  you know where you're essentially watching another species play the game.
Speaker 2:  I can play mini golf. I can totally get a hole in one. I could beat those
Speaker 2:  guys. That last part, by the way, I think matters a lot. Both
Speaker 2:  Danny and Steven told me that they get a lot of comments, From people basically
Speaker 2:  trash talking about how they could beat them on a course, which is part of
Speaker 2:  What keeps it fun and exciting. People being too good at things
Speaker 2:  might be bad content. The more I think about it and the more I watch,
Speaker 2:  the more it actually doesn't surprise me at all that mini golf would work
Speaker 2:  on social. It is fundamentally a vertical screen game.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, that's all really easy for me to say in retrospect, having watched
Speaker 2:  a year of this content now, right when the Syne first posted their
Speaker 2:  mini golf tournament to TikTok, they definitely didn't think it was going
Speaker 2:  to be huge. The best evidence I have for that, by the way, is that they posted
Speaker 2:  it on Danny's personal channel, not their more official twin
Speaker 2:  tour golf channel, but also maybe because they assumed it wasn't
Speaker 2:  gonna do well and they didn't want to cause any problems for the main channel.
Speaker 2:  Uploading videos that don't work is death, but it did do well
Speaker 2:  and suddenly the at Danny Syn account became synonymous with twin
Speaker 2:  tour golf and with this huge increase in views for mini
Speaker 2:  golf. Steven swears he's not jealous that it's Danny's name
Speaker 2:  on the channel, but I don't think I believe him. Anyway. At first it
Speaker 2:  was just Danny's TikTok doing all these mini golf numbers, but the guys
Speaker 2:  took this whole thing cross platform pretty fast.
Speaker 6:  So when We saw Danny's account kind of taking off,
Speaker 6:  we were like, wow. And then we weren't posting
Speaker 6:  that on Instagram, YouTube, Facebook, We weren't posting
Speaker 6:  it right away, and I'd say it was about three weeks
Speaker 6:  after that first tournament when We were like, we
Speaker 6:  gotta start putting this on all the other platforms to
Speaker 6:  help those grow as well. So. Then we started putting it onto
Speaker 6:  Instagram, doing long form videos on YouTube
Speaker 6:  and then we started to get monetized on YouTube and
Speaker 6:  it really started to pick up So. Just pushing our
Speaker 6:  content onto all platforms was our next step after
Speaker 6:  about three weeks of seeing the numbers that Danny's TikTok was doing.
Speaker 2:  Now Steven says the goal is to post roughly 20 videos a day across all
Speaker 2:  platforms. They aim for three tiktoks a day, lots of posts on
Speaker 2:  Instagram, Facebook, and the rest, and 28 long forum
Speaker 2:  YouTube videos a month 28. And in putting out
Speaker 2:  all of this stuff, they've sort of by accident built a whole
Speaker 2:  system for trying new things, seeing What works, testing
Speaker 2:  algorithms and relentlessly optimizing their whole content
Speaker 2:  operation all the time.
Speaker 6:  What's So fun about our YouTube page is people watch whatever
Speaker 6:  content we put on There So, just kind of experimenting with
Speaker 6:  some new challenges, some new style of videos,
Speaker 6:  but continuing the mini golf seasons
Speaker 6:  and everything on TikTok, short form content and
Speaker 6:  just being able to experiment with new ideas. and we also have Steven's
Speaker 6:  page for if we wanna implement new challenges, mini
Speaker 6:  golf challenges, we can post them on his account without getting in the way
Speaker 6:  of all the mini golf tournaments. We've just seen too much success
Speaker 6:  with it to change it up. So, it's nice to have multiple accounts,
Speaker 6:  my account just continuing to be the tournaments and then
Speaker 6:  experimenting on other platforms and then also this
Speaker 6:  winter, unfortunately in Wisconsin it gets cold and
Speaker 6:  courses close So, we'll travel, it's like
Speaker 6:  What We did last year. We found spots where we could go
Speaker 6:  mini golf So, we'll definitely be doing some travel. We have some courses
Speaker 6:  that we wanna hit in like Myrtle Beach is
Speaker 6:  like the mini golf capital So just traveling around
Speaker 6:  and continuing to get our content over the winter and then we always have
Speaker 6:  the indoor course by us as a backup and a
Speaker 6:  course that I'm sure we'll be at quite a bit this winter.
Speaker 2:  That's such an interesting description of the whole social media world, isn't
Speaker 2:  it? YouTube is the place where people are able to most closely connect with
Speaker 2:  the channels. They like So. If you're a creator, you have fans and they'll
Speaker 2:  see and watch the things that you publish. Everything else everywhere else
Speaker 2:  is mostly just about playing the games of the algorithm,
Speaker 2:  but If, you play the games and lose them on your main channel, you could
Speaker 2:  end up in real trouble. So, you have to build a whole pipeline that
Speaker 2:  eventually lands the best stuff and only the best stuff on your most
Speaker 2:  important platform and for the syn, that most important platform
Speaker 2:  that leads when it comes to the mini golf is TikTok.
Speaker 6:  Really everything just gets posted to TikTok first and then
Speaker 6:  Steven will take it From, TikTok, throw it onto Instagram,
Speaker 6:  and then when we do post it on YouTube, it's a
Speaker 6:  fresh voiceover, it's a new voiceover So. It's pretty
Speaker 6:  similar but maybe a few different talking points
Speaker 6:  for our YouTube viewers, but really it just kind of gets posted all
Speaker 6:  the same to all different platforms and it's interesting to see how
Speaker 6:  each one grows. Sometimes a video on Instagram will go viral
Speaker 6:  but it won't go viral on TikTok, but sometimes
Speaker 6:  usually we see the same thing. If a video does well on TikTok,
Speaker 6:  it most likely performs well on Instagram and then
Speaker 6:  YouTube is just pretty consistent, just we're
Speaker 6:  continuing to grow our YouTube page and we're starting to see more success
Speaker 6:  with it as we go. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Have you, have you developed a pretty good theory of what's gonna work and
Speaker 2:  What doesn't like when you post something, can you usually predict whether
Speaker 2:  it's gonna hit big or not?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I would say So, although right now on Instagram
Speaker 6:  there's a match between Steven and Carter that
Speaker 6:  there's two videos with a bunch of views like 800,000
Speaker 6:  and 300,000 and on TikTok it didn't
Speaker 6:  perform as well as that So. It's all kind of a
Speaker 6:  gamble and I, sometimes I like to think I know, but then I'm like,
Speaker 6:  wait, maybe I don't know.
Speaker 2:  Carter is another new entrant to the twin tour universe. He won
Speaker 2:  a tournament, the guys threw for some fans who wanted to play with the twin
Speaker 2:  tour guys, like I said, people like talking trash to Steven and Danny and
Speaker 2:  telling them that they're better So, they gave him a chance to be better,
Speaker 2:  the tournament went great and they want to do more of them both as a way
Speaker 2:  to make money and as a way to generate even more content to put on their
Speaker 2:  channels because as I said, the only thing that is always true about
Speaker 2:  every content platform is that There is no such thing as too much content.
Speaker 2:  Over the course of the last year, Steven and Danny have really started
Speaker 2:  to think more strategically about What they're doing, not just
Speaker 2:  making mini golf content and putting it out, not even just making lots of
Speaker 2:  mini golf content and putting it out, but really trying to set this thing
Speaker 2:  up to succeed in a much bigger way for a much longer
Speaker 2:  time. Because really in any moment when you as a creator
Speaker 2:  are having that first viral hit moment,
Speaker 2:  you can kind of pick two things. You can either do one or the other,
Speaker 2:  you can keep the thing going as long as possible knowing that nothing on
Speaker 2:  the internet lasts forever. Or you can try and leverage that
Speaker 2:  moment of virality to build something more
Speaker 2:  sustainable. Steven and Danny tried to do both pretty quickly.
Speaker 2:  They decided to make their golf content their full-time jobs and they started
Speaker 2:  to structure their lives in a way that could make that work.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, So. Typically Monday through Wednesday
Speaker 6:  well wanna film a U, at least a YouTube video
Speaker 6:  and we shoot for a a few regular season tournaments early
Speaker 6:  in the weeks and then kind of the schedule of everyone
Speaker 6:  that plays with us, they have jobs, they have other things
Speaker 6:  going on. So, we typically try to film
Speaker 6:  after work or on a weekend if it's a big major or
Speaker 6:  a bracket style tournament where we're, we have eight players in the field,
Speaker 6:  we'll try to do those on the weekend, but other than that,
Speaker 6:  So, we try to find times that work for everyone and then when we're not
Speaker 6:  filming we're always editing or doing
Speaker 6:  voiceovers and uploading all the content.
Speaker 2:  This all sounds like a lot of work to me. I tried a bunch of different times
Speaker 2:  in our interview to get the Syne twins to tell me how grueling and terrible
Speaker 2:  this job is, but they just wouldn't do it. I genuinely think they're having
Speaker 2:  a good time, but they did acknowledge how helpful it is to have each other
Speaker 2:  and that they found a pretty good two-man balance to get all of this
Speaker 2:  done.
Speaker 6:  So, we've figured out day to day So Danny only
Speaker 6:  edits the mini golf tournaments and posts 'em on his page and then he'll
Speaker 6:  do all the long form mini golf voiceovers for
Speaker 6:  YouTube and then I'll take everything and put 'em onto
Speaker 6:  Instagram, YouTube shorts and then I'll
Speaker 6:  do my golf content and I'll record and edit
Speaker 6:  all of that. So we found timing What takes Danny
Speaker 6:  at the same time that it takes me to do my work. So We We
Speaker 6:  split it pretty much What We think 50 50
Speaker 6:  to continue to upload content
Speaker 2:  That makes sense, which is easier to shoot mini golf or regular golf.
Speaker 6:  Probably mini golf because it's So quick or or a
Speaker 6:  lot quicker than golf content. And then golf when we're recording, if
Speaker 6:  we're waiting on a group in front of us or the course is
Speaker 6:  super busy and we're kind of like, oh, like let's go like
Speaker 6:  somewhat gets stressful, but that's why we always find times when
Speaker 6:  it's not gonna be busy. So, we always film during the week
Speaker 6:  when we can, especially golf content. We'll never
Speaker 6:  film on a weekend when everyone's out. There
Speaker 2:  Danny is really the one in charge of the mini golf tiktoks, which are currently
Speaker 2:  the centerpiece of the whole operation and over the last year he and Steven
Speaker 2:  have been thinking a lot about how to improve the way they film the tournaments
Speaker 2:  too.
Speaker 6:  So, every clip we've filmed since September 4th of last
Speaker 6:  year has been done by either Danny or I. We film
Speaker 6:  all the mini golf tournaments passing the phone back and forth
Speaker 6:  to record.
Speaker 2:  Is that why you're hardly ever playing at the same time? Yep. I was wondering
Speaker 2:  about this. Okay,
Speaker 6:  And then people think Danny and I are the same person
Speaker 6:  because you never see the other person behind, right?
Speaker 6:  So, but no, we We know how We want
Speaker 6:  the camera to Look the angles and we always have to leave
Speaker 6:  some room at the top for the scoreboard, So just making sure
Speaker 6:  everything is recorded how we want it.
Speaker 2:  How do you want it d just like sort of describe as best you can. What, you
Speaker 2:  want that to Look like
Speaker 6:  Yeah, So you always, we want the ball in the middle of the screen when
Speaker 6:  it's rolling and never too far down
Speaker 6:  So the scoreboard covers the hole and you can't see a shot or something.
Speaker 6:  So and always, yeah, we just have our angles and
Speaker 6:  we know From playing courses. What angle
Speaker 6:  to start the hole on if you're behind the hole, behind the
Speaker 6:  player ha at the halfway point of the hole
Speaker 6:  just So. We don't miss anything at all.
Speaker 6:  So. And also just make sure the ball never goes out of frame.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. What, do you ever like sneakily retake a shot if you're like, oh, I
Speaker 2:  missed it, I didn't move the camera fast enough like take, hit that one again.
Speaker 6:  Like there's been a time where you, you think it might be recording,
Speaker 6:  someone hits a shot and then you realize it's not recording and
Speaker 6:  we'll go grab the ball. So it's like, hey, it would've ended up here.
Speaker 6:  It's like, nope, we don't know where it would've stopped but
Speaker 6:  we hardly now that we've been doing it for over a year
Speaker 6:  run into many issues.
Speaker 2:  Would you ever like, is There a next level up? Like you,
Speaker 2:  you could, you know get out, go out and get a person with like a fancy camera
Speaker 2:  and a steady cam to be like running after you as you go down the course.
Speaker 2:  Like is that, would, would that help? Is that even a a thing you would
Speaker 2:  want to do
Speaker 6:  I? Think for our YouTube content possibly for filming
Speaker 6:  horizontally I, think maybe someday
Speaker 6:  we'll upgrade to a camera, but with how much content we're pumping out the
Speaker 6:  phone and just being able to edit on my phone,
Speaker 6:  export it, From my phone up to YouTube, TikTok, whatever, it's just everything
Speaker 6:  So quick, it's saves time. So right now and I think the
Speaker 6:  iPhone camera is unbeatable.
Speaker 2:  I actually I. I've also I, I've started to believe that especially
Speaker 2:  on social like Instagram and TikTok, that actually There is such
Speaker 2:  a thing as like it can Look too good and and it feels weird
Speaker 2:  when you see So something that is like clearly professionally shot on TikTok.
Speaker 2:  You're like, why is this, why'd you try So hard? Like just, just shoot it
Speaker 2:  on your phone, it'll be fine
Speaker 6:  You, yeah, So, we We did use the
Speaker 6:  camera a little bit before We started mini golf for our long form
Speaker 6:  YouTube videos, but now just Danny
Speaker 6:  believes in the iPhone and he's got me to believe that it's
Speaker 6:  our best option, especially for the short form content like you said,
Speaker 6:  with just having a normal phone video for a TikTok
Speaker 6:  rather than a very high quality, something that looks
Speaker 6:  out of place on the short form apps.
Speaker 2:  Danny really does do the whole thing on his phone, all the editing, the
Speaker 2:  voiceover, the scoreboards, it all just happens in the Cap Cut app and
Speaker 2:  Danny has developed a very specific way of doing everything, especially his
Speaker 2:  commentary.
Speaker 6:  Every voiceover is really at this point I try to do
Speaker 6:  'em in one take. Just kind of what's kind of keep it natural, what's
Speaker 6:  What I'm thinking What I'm seeing and not trying to make it perfect.
Speaker 6:  It could be There for hours and hours with how much content we post.
Speaker 6:  It's just really I try to do it in one take. I will, I'll probably mess up
Speaker 6:  one every three but then I'll just go back undo something and
Speaker 6:  start From, There, So. It's fun trying to do 'em in one take
Speaker 6:  and I know that Danny does read a lot of the comments.
Speaker 6:  So he'll get ideas, From, What people are commenting or
Speaker 6:  stuff like that to implement in his voiceover.
Speaker 2:  What's one you've added? Do you have like a new catchphrase or work shopping
Speaker 2:  right now?
Speaker 6:  I? Honestly, it's not. There's nothing really stirring right now.
Speaker 6:  No, but before What was popular and still is, is
Speaker 6:  Bella's pumped up? I I. Don't know how I thought about that, but
Speaker 6:  she's really, she doesn't Look pumped up but she is pumped up.
Speaker 2:  Bella by the way, is Steven's fiance and is one of the main
Speaker 2:  recurring characters in these tournaments. She often shows up
Speaker 2:  in scrubs and she seems somewhere between kind of disinterested and
Speaker 2:  entirely annoyed about being There and then frequently just dominates everybody.
Speaker 2:  If you believe the comments and the twin tours, merch sales of the Bella's
Speaker 2:  pumped up T-shirts, she's everybody's favorite player to root for. She's
Speaker 2:  definitely my favorite player to root for. There are a few other folks who
Speaker 2:  pop up in these videos a lot. There's Eddie and Wolf and Matthew who
Speaker 2:  was the one in that very first video and now also helps the sneaky with some
Speaker 2:  of the behind the scenes process and If, you watch long enough you can
Speaker 2:  actually see in the comments people picking their favorites and each player
Speaker 2:  actually developing their own character in the series like Eddie I love
Speaker 2:  Eddie. Eddie always starts great and always just collapses at the end. Wolf
Speaker 2:  is super up and down. Bella is just a quiet killer in the
Speaker 2:  best way. These people are now part of the twin tour golf universe
Speaker 2:  in a way that is I think increasingly strategic and it
Speaker 2:  is designed to make sure that this thing can last. Making that thing last
Speaker 2:  by the way is the whole game now. More on that coming right after this break.
Speaker 2:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  Support For. this episode comes From, A-W-S-A-W-S.
Speaker 4:  Generative AI gives you the tools to power your business forward with the
Speaker 4:  security and speed of the world's most experienced cloud.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. So. You can pretty easily imagine how a bunch of mini
Speaker 2:  golf videos would get boring over time, right? Same guys, same course
Speaker 2:  over and over. It eventually just gets old and repetitive. There's a reason
Speaker 2:  you see creators of almost any kind start to do wild challenges
Speaker 6:  one for third, and then we pile up all the player
Speaker 6:  of the year points for the whole year,
Speaker 6:  which runs From September to September.
Speaker 6:  Now So we're through one year. Danny was player of the year in year
Speaker 6:  one he had the most points and then
Speaker 2:  It feels like cheating. Give yourself player of the year, I don't I, don't
Speaker 2:  know,
Speaker 6:  But now it all reset and we just are in our first season
Speaker 6:  of the new year.
Speaker 2:  There's a really delicate content balance in There. They're trying
Speaker 2:  to both keep viewers hooked and make them wanna watch the next one, but also
Speaker 2:  to get new viewers interested on TikTok in particular. You're not gonna land
Speaker 2:  on the first one of these, you're just gonna find a random three holes
Speaker 2:  of a random tournament and that has to be captivating too.
Speaker 2:  So for the twin tour guys, the whole system resets every month and they're
Speaker 2:  always looking to add new players to freshen things up, but There is still
Speaker 2:  that big annual payoff, which genuinely does feel like a real
Speaker 2:  capstone if you've been watching all their videos all year. The
Speaker 2:  guys didn't wanna tell me exactly how much money they're making From all
Speaker 2:  the stuff they're posting now except to say that it is working as their full-time
Speaker 2:  job. Most of the money that they're making comes From monetizing
Speaker 2:  directly on the platforms. That means ad splits on YouTube, creator funds
Speaker 2:  on TikTok, that sort of thing. That works to a point, but as you get
Speaker 2:  bigger and I think, especially as you realize how finicky those platforms
Speaker 2:  can be and how dangerous it can be to depend on them for your entire livelihood,
Speaker 2:  everybody ends up wanting to diversify So far. One
Speaker 2:  of the coolest things that I've seen From, the twin tour golf guys, is that
Speaker 2:  they found one very clever way to bring some new money in.
Speaker 2:  They started asking people to Venmo them money to contribute to a prize for
Speaker 2:  each tournament winner.
Speaker 6:  It kind of, it happened last winter.
Speaker 6:  We were traveling a lot and it was getting
Speaker 6:  expensive and it was kind of a thought that
Speaker 6:  came by. If we do a full season, we're putting in hard work
Speaker 6:  and If you win and if you're a viewer and you enjoy the content,
Speaker 6:  maybe you've watched the entire season So far, you're like, wow, thanks
Speaker 6:  for the entertainment I, appreciate you guys. You guys helped me on
Speaker 6:  my lunch break, you guys get me through my day. Whatever it is they
Speaker 6:  send some money in and it kind of gives us something to play for but also
Speaker 6:  rewards those that play well and helps cover costs of
Speaker 6:  travel for these people that come with us and whatnot.
Speaker 6:  So, it's really kind of just a tip, like a thank you for the entertainment
Speaker 6:  and then it also helps, it does on our end. It puts a
Speaker 6:  lot of pressure on it knowing, hey, I'm playing for
Speaker 6:  this and if I play well, it's mine. Or if
Speaker 6:  I don't play well, it's kind of gonna hurt.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's kind of a lot of money for a round of mini golf in in some of
Speaker 2:  these. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Oh it's pretty cool and kind of wanted it to make it feel like a true
Speaker 6:  tour, like the PGA tour, they have all the money for the players
Speaker 6:  So kind of just making it a tour feel and
Speaker 6:  competitive and something's on the line.
Speaker 2:  It's a good way to get the players paid and since Danny and Steven win a
Speaker 2:  lot, it gets them paid too, but it also feels different than them
Speaker 2:  just being like pay $5 a month to access all of our content. It makes
Speaker 2:  fans feel involved like they're sponsors of the event and it makes them feel
Speaker 2:  like they're directly contributing to the game itself and not just to some
Speaker 2:  business entity somewhere. So far, it's not a lot of money. I've
Speaker 2:  seen the purse So far as high as like 1700 bucks, which is not
Speaker 2:  pro athlete money, but to be fair is kind of a lot to win for a round of
Speaker 2:  mini golf. The fan tournaments and the Venmos will help, but
Speaker 2:  ultimately the twin tour guys do want to do the typical brand deals, but
Speaker 2:  those are easier to do in regular golf than in mini golf. Like
Speaker 2:  every golf creator eventually gets sponsored by a big golf brand.
Speaker 2:  There's a whole path There, but I'm not sure who the big name in mini
Speaker 2:  golf is. You know? Plus at some point every sufficiently big
Speaker 2:  creator becomes a product person. You put your name on a makeup line or
Speaker 2:  an energy drink or a weird Lunchable competitor or gadget
Speaker 2:  accessories or your own golf bag. I'm not sure What that thing is here,
Speaker 2:  but I do have some ideas. Is the next step like the the
Speaker 2:  twin tour mini golf putter.
Speaker 6:  That would be pretty cool.
Speaker 6:  I I feel like a lot of people If, you go mini golfing,
Speaker 6:  you're just using the putters, There, So, maybe a custom
Speaker 6:  putter for people, but We haven't really thought much about it yet.
Speaker 2:  Would you ever, would you wanna design a course?
Speaker 6:  We have talked about that and Big putts, the course
Speaker 6:  that we play has talked about opening up another
Speaker 6:  location, So potentially partnering with them
Speaker 6:  and they've given us freedom to design
Speaker 6:  holes and From all the courses we've played. Figure out What
Speaker 6:  We, like What Hole. We would wanna see There, but
Speaker 6:  it would be a fun thing to set up our own mini golf course someday
Speaker 6:  and have it somewhere we can film content whenever
Speaker 6:  and not just filming content but promoting our own business, our own course,
Speaker 6:  So. It's definitely something we've been thinking about and maybe someday
Speaker 6:  we will do
Speaker 2:  What is, What is the like ideal hole for great
Speaker 2:  content. Mini golf as far as you guys are concerned, like What does it need
Speaker 2:  What has to happen.
Speaker 6:  I think for performance on social media. I think something that kind of
Speaker 6:  takes some time to get down to the hole while also having
Speaker 6:  a smooth green So. Something that kind of takes maybe about
Speaker 6:  eight seconds to see whether or not it's gonna be online. If it has
Speaker 6:  a chance to go in for a hole in one So a little longer
Speaker 6:  hole with the suspense, you have five to
Speaker 6:  eight seconds of like, oh this could go in, this might not go in, you still
Speaker 6:  don't know. And then you see it miss or go in the hole. So.
Speaker 6:  I, just like the holes that are typically a little bit longer and
Speaker 6:  courses that have a little quicker greens I feel tend
Speaker 6:  to perform well.
Speaker 2:  That's interesting. I thought you were gonna say like cool looking obstacles
Speaker 2:  and weird stuff that's hard for people to figure out, but the time actually
Speaker 2:  makes sense and there's the I, forget where it was, but there's the one course
Speaker 2:  you guys have played a bunch of times where it has like the three-tiered
Speaker 2:  green I feel like that's like exactly What you're talking about. Like it
Speaker 2:  takes forever to figure out if they hit a good shot or not in a way that
Speaker 2:  is actually pretty compelling.
Speaker 6:  Yes, and we've noticed with like obstacles, if
Speaker 6:  there's a windmill in the middle of the hole, it it's just
Speaker 6:  kind of hard to record because it goes through, it disappears
Speaker 6:  for a little bit and then comes back out. So
Speaker 6:  kind of when they have those
Speaker 6:  interesting designs on a hole where it's just like a straight
Speaker 6:  hole with an obstacle in the middle, they just don't tend to perform
Speaker 6:  as well as a clear hole with some slope on it
Speaker 6:  and the ball heading towards the hole.
Speaker 2:  I've been watching the twin tour mini golf stuff for almost as long as the
Speaker 2:  Syne have been making it and I really do love watching strangers play
Speaker 2:  mini golf Way more than I expected and frankly I'm psyched to know I'm not
Speaker 2:  the only one, but I've also really enjoyed over the course of the last year
Speaker 2:  seeing the twin tour golf guys go through kind of the whole
Speaker 2:  creator journey, one video and three holes at a time. The
Speaker 2:  videos get a little more polished, they never too polished. There are more
Speaker 2:  hashtags. Over time the graphics get better. Promotional merch starts to
Speaker 2:  appear. They're now tagging the courses in the description and actually both
Speaker 2:  Syne say that they're starting to drive new people to courses all over the
Speaker 2:  place. There are new players that show up and then those players get their
Speaker 2:  own tiktoks and their own branches of the story. They're starting to push
Speaker 2:  people to YouTube because I think YouTube is just the most stable of these
Speaker 2:  platforms for a lot of reasons. But one thing I really like is that the
Speaker 2:  videos, the videos are still pretty much the same.
Speaker 2:  Here's What, it sounded like a year ago,
Speaker 5:  I shot to tie Steven on one, rolled it in,
Speaker 5:  Matthew, here's still some work left. Got it all tied through one
Speaker 2:  And here's What. It sounds like now at the most recent tournament, the same
Speaker 2:  first hole almost exactly a year after that first video, Eddie
Speaker 5:  Number one spot in the player of the year standing
Speaker 5:  trying to keep it that way. Gonna tap it in for his two.
Speaker 5:  Steven Infer two. Matthew, thank you to everyone
Speaker 5:  that's contributed to this. Major's Purse
Speaker 5:  means a lot to us, a lot on the line. My pot got it for
Speaker 5:  my two and Bella for all twos on the first hole rolls
Speaker 5:  it in, all tied through one on,
Speaker 2:  You know, What I love about that. If anything, it sounds worse. But in general
Speaker 2:  for all of the changes that they're making around these videos. The point
Speaker 2:  is they're not messing with What made this video work the first time,
Speaker 2:  even down to things as simple as the music. You may have noticed it's the
Speaker 2:  same song. It is the same song just about every time. It's
Speaker 2:  literally a track called Epic Music, which is hilarious. It's been used
Speaker 2:  158,000 times on TikTok and a lot of them are
Speaker 2:  golf clips. I'm pretty sure you can blame the twin tour guys for that.
Speaker 2:  At some point though, I do wonder how long this one thing can
Speaker 2:  keep going. There's not a ton of other mini golf content out There
Speaker 2:  right now. Both Danny and Steven actually said they're surprised they don't
Speaker 2:  have more competition, especially given how much golf content There is on
Speaker 2:  the internet, but There will be competitors eventually, especially if I'm
Speaker 2:  right that it is like the perfect internet spectator sport and maybe
Speaker 2:  tiktoks algorithm will like those better. Maybe tiktoks algorithm won't always
Speaker 2:  like mini golf. Will TikTok even be around long enough for us to find out
Speaker 2:  this is What I mean, this stuff is fragile. I don't know the answers to those
Speaker 2:  questions and neither do the Sinis, which is the thing that struck me the
Speaker 2:  most actually about What they're doing. They don't really seem to be super
Speaker 2:  tied to the idea that they are like mini golf content guys.
Speaker 2:  They're really invested in doing this as long as it works, but I got the
Speaker 2:  sense over and over that this is all just an excuse to play golf with their
Speaker 2:  friends and honestly, I kind of love that. We talk a lot on this show
Speaker 2:  and everywhere about the biggest creators on the internet, the ones starting
Speaker 2:  giant production companies and hiring tons of people and making millions
Speaker 2:  of dollars and becoming a-list celebrities, but the Twin Tour guys seem to
Speaker 2:  be happy just being a small business, like a lifestyle business instead of
Speaker 2:  a unicorn startup. They're playing a sport they like, they're hanging with
Speaker 2:  their friends and they're paying the bills in the process. They have some
Speaker 2:  plans to grow and expand and do more stuff, but maybe that's enough.
Speaker 2:  The one thing I do wonder is if turning golf into content is making them
Speaker 2:  worse golfers, and it turns out Steven wonders about that too.
Speaker 6:  The other day we went out and golfed and played really well and then
Speaker 6:  yesterday We went and played and recorded and
Speaker 6:  we didn't do too well compared to the time when we weren't recording.
Speaker 2:  But then he thought about it and he said he figured it's probably okay. Mr.
Speaker 2:  Stupid putts is pretty good content.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that's it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to Steven and Danny
Speaker 2:  for being on the show, and thank you as always for listening. As always,
Speaker 2:  If you have thoughts, feelings, questions or sick mini golf courses that
Speaker 2:  we should go to for official vergecast business. You can always email us
Speaker 2:  at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or call the hotline eight six six VERGE
Speaker 2:  one one. we love hearing from you. Send us all your thoughts and questions.
Speaker 2:  This show's produced by Liam James Weour and Eric Gomez. The Vergecast is
Speaker 2:  The Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. We'll be
Speaker 2:  back with our regularly scheduled vergecast on Tuesday and Friday. We have
Speaker 2:  a really fun show coming up on Tuesday and oh So much news to get to on Friday.
Speaker 2:  We'll see you then. Rock and roll