# Transcript
ID: 757fb691-543b-44ed-970f-7d9ac6c09c82
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-1489343431803301402/7019356727457142107/s93290-US-5414s-1720788238.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss the announcements from Samsung's Galaxy Unpacked event, Redbox shutting down, and more tech news from this week.
Speaker 5:  I am. I am far away from the hurricane. We didn't even get any rain here.
Speaker 5:  Okay. It sucked. Sorry to everybody who doesn't have power, it's not
Speaker 5:  good that that also sucks. Stay cool
Speaker 2:  If You can, if You can please or you know,
Speaker 2:  talk to your local elected door officials that are power cred. There's a
Speaker 2:  lot to say there. My favorite story of the hurricane, if You can have a
Speaker 2:  favorite story from a giant hurricane, has caused a great deal of harm. Bold
Speaker 4:  Way to start a story. Yeah, go
Speaker 2:  On. Is is the people like the Texas Power Utilities don't have
Speaker 2:  apps. So people are using the Whataburger app. I saw to find
Speaker 2:  what areas still have blackouts because the, what? Burgers are offline
Speaker 5:  And rules.
Speaker 2:  It's life finds away. Do you know what I'm saying?
Speaker 2:  Life finds away. Alright, well hopefully we can be a little ray
Speaker 2:  of sunshine in this time. If you are stuck down there. There's a lot of gadget
Speaker 2:  needs. Talk about Samsung did have unpacked a bunch of phones. Motorola has
Speaker 2:  new flip phones, which Allison reviewed. There's a bunch of streaming news.
Speaker 2:  Alex today was once again horny for David Zav in Slack
Speaker 2:  quite openly. That was a real thing that happened today. Days,
Speaker 5:  It's all days
Speaker 2:  And we got a lightning round. Unsponsored is always, I'm trying to sell
Speaker 2:  our soul here. People, we get a lot of inquiries. I will say this,
Speaker 2:  we get a lot of inquiries at price points that are entirely too low for my
Speaker 2:  soul.
Speaker 2:  Just keep that in mind. We're
Speaker 5:  Reasonable cost for your soul.
Speaker 2:  We're trying to buy boats. All right. Not dinghies. That's the lighting,
Speaker 2:  right? Everybody.
Speaker 4:  Boat's not dinghies. That's, that's going on a shirt. I don't know what,
Speaker 4:  I don't know what it's advertising, but we're putting that on
Speaker 2:  Her shirt. I was gonna say, I can buy my own unicorn floaties for my daughter.
Speaker 2:  I I don't need your help.
Speaker 2:  Alright, let's get into it. David, tell us about unpacked. It was like a
Speaker 2:  big one.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I sort of, this is a very weird year. So
Speaker 4:  Samsung I think probably tries the hardest
Speaker 4:  of any tech company to have cool events. Would you guys say
Speaker 4:  that's fair? Like Apple has the big ones, but they're increasingly, like
Speaker 4:  at Apple Park in a theater, they make a video. We like kind of know how they're
Speaker 4:  doing it. Samsung is like tr Samsung tries
Speaker 4:  so hard. Like so hard.
Speaker 2:  So I can explain this 'cause we've been talking about this for a long time
Speaker 2:  and it, it's gotten weirder in a weird way. Like the weirdness of it is
Speaker 2:  getting weirder
Speaker 4:  Is itself weird. Yeah. Okay. Do
Speaker 2:  You know what I mean? Like the mechanism of weirdness is getting weirder.
Speaker 2:  So Apple for the longest time had like
Speaker 2:  massive cultural influence. Like Steve Jobs was like, I don't know, here's
Speaker 2:  Coldplay. They're gonna tell you how good the iPod is. Yeah. Bono was on
Speaker 2:  stage one year, famously scrubbed from the internet.
Speaker 2:  Kanye West closed out a ww DC by playing Gold digger. Is that
Speaker 2:  true? And let me tell you, that audience did not scream
Speaker 2:  Prenup. Dead silence. Boy.
Speaker 2:  Like it is impossible to find this video that it is removed. Apple just
Speaker 2:  deleted it.
Speaker 4:  Wow.
Speaker 2:  But Kanye was like, H we want prenup. and it was just like, we do not sir.
Speaker 2:  We're good.
Speaker 4:  One Apple play just goes, I'm under NDA.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It was so weird. The weekend has played at a
Speaker 2:  wwc just straight singing about cocaine at 10 30 in the morning.
Speaker 2:  Weird. But Apple is able to do it. Like their brand has the
Speaker 2:  cultural capacity for these moments
Speaker 2:  and now they don't, which is weird. Like they've gotten
Speaker 2:  so corporate, they're making infomercials. They're like, I tried to use these
Speaker 2:  AI tools and I couldn't like, you know, it's like, it's weird. It's like
Speaker 2:  QVC, but they still have the cachet. Samsung has been trying to buy it
Speaker 2:  for years. So they're like, I dunno, here's a Broadway play about how
Speaker 2:  women can't use phones, which is a real thing they did. Yep. That's a
Speaker 2:  real story. Here's more famous people. Sidney Sweeney was at this event,
Speaker 2:  which we, we should talk about. Yes. Very odd moment with Sidney Sweeney
Speaker 2:  at this event. So they keep trying to buy celebrities and influencers
Speaker 2:  to get to the level of cultural relevance that Apple
Speaker 2:  has long had. But Apple doesn't actually, they're
Speaker 2:  not that company anymore. They're just bigger. Yeah. They're like a nation
Speaker 2:  state. And
Speaker 4:  I will say to Samsung's credit, I mean speaking of nation state's, Jesus,
Speaker 4:  but to Samsung's credit, it
Speaker 4:  is still very invested in doing these things live in a way that Apple has
Speaker 4:  gone full. Let's all sit here and watch a video. Samsung is like
Speaker 4:  trying to create spectacle in a way that I, I kind of appreciate,
Speaker 2:  I appreciate you, but that's what I mean by the mechanism of the weirdness
Speaker 2:  is getting weirder. Yeah. Like that's been the disconnect is like Apple's
Speaker 2:  the cool and then Apple and Samsung's trying to buy the coolness. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  now it's like Apple doesn't even try to be cool. Like
Speaker 2:  whatever. It's like, like
Speaker 4:  You have no choice. Which, you know, one thing about being cool, that's how
Speaker 4:  to actually be cool.
Speaker 2:  They're just like over it. And Samsung is like, here's even more, more
Speaker 2:  stuff like more hype, more
Speaker 5:  Spec. Here's Sydnee Sweeney,
Speaker 2:  Here's Sydnee Sweeney having like being forced to react
Speaker 2:  to like a deep fake herself. It's truly bizarre though. Let's,
Speaker 2:  let's
Speaker 4:  Come back to that. So, but this one was, they did it in Paris, which on
Speaker 4:  the one hand makes a certain kind of sense because Paris is, it's where the
Speaker 4:  Olympics is happening the summer. It's a big deal. All that stuff on the
Speaker 4:  other hand makes no sense because it's two weeks until the Olympics. It's
Speaker 4:  not like it's the middle of the Olympics. Like it's this
Speaker 4:  long break Olympics. Like, it's just weird that Samsung picked to
Speaker 4:  do this, but whatever. They did it in Paris. Lots of people went, they seemed
Speaker 4:  to fly in a ton of like creators and influencers and people, lots of folks
Speaker 4:  in Paris. We didn't have anybody there, but lots of folks were there and
Speaker 4:  had I what seemed like a giant like warehouse sized
Speaker 4:  theater thing, it was like the Samsung event and then like a,
Speaker 4:  like a really dirty rave was like the vibe I got from this building.
Speaker 2:  So Paris.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's fair. Touche. and
Speaker 4:  it was, it, the reason I'm so hung up on the Apple comparison
Speaker 4:  here is because Samsung basically got up and launched a bunch of Apple products
Speaker 4:  like, like in a very direct, real way.
Speaker 4:  Launched a bunch of Apple products and they launched phones that I think
Speaker 4:  are cool and interesting and we should talk about and
Speaker 2:  The ring. But there are two in particular where you're like, oh
Speaker 5:  Thanks Apple.
Speaker 4:  And, and it's just Samsung is like doing
Speaker 4:  a weird thing where it is becoming less
Speaker 4:  Samsung all the time and it's doing Google AI plus Apple
Speaker 4:  hardware and, and kind of pretending that that is Samsung.
Speaker 4:  And I think that's bizarre.
Speaker 5:  Isn't that what happens when you work on Saturdays? You just say, what if
Speaker 5:  we take these two and swish 'em together? Well,
Speaker 2:  If we cut our costs by just firing the design teams entirely. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I don't know. Let's just do the two Apple ones first. 'cause the other products
Speaker 2:  are fundamentally more interesting. Right? So it's the Galaxy Buds and the
Speaker 2:  Galaxy Buds Pro, which just fully look like AirPods and AirPods Pro.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They used to look like little beans. Yeah. And they were kind of cool.
Speaker 5:  Like I wouldn't buy them, but they were kind of cool. And now they look like
Speaker 5:  AirPod pros. Air Pods just,
Speaker 2:  Well they, they're, they're the stems. They they got stems. They're a little
Speaker 2:  bit more angular. They do have LEDs on them. Yep. Which I, i is
Speaker 2:  where has listeners know I appreciate more than almost any other thing You
Speaker 2:  can add to your tech pod.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You know, what you want is LEDs right next to your ear canal where
Speaker 4:  you'll see them all the time. It makes perfect sense
Speaker 5:  Where everyone else can too. You're
Speaker 2:  Right. I think people should be be like that dude's listening to tunes.
Speaker 5:  You should just know that only if it like pulses with their music. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You want like RGB
Speaker 2:  Lighting for your ear basically. Where is the party speaker effects for these
Speaker 2:  headphones so no one else can see them and you can't,
Speaker 2:  no one else can hear what you're listening to and you can't see the lights.
Speaker 2:  That's the place for party speaker LEDs. So, you know, we're
Speaker 2:  at this weird place in headphone V where
Speaker 2:  the best headphones to buy for your phone are often the one that
Speaker 2:  the phone maker makes. Yes. Because they have all co-opted
Speaker 2:  Bluetooth as a standard and built proprietary features for their own
Speaker 2:  products. We can do this forever. They've all done it. Like whether or not
Speaker 2:  you think that's good or bad, they have all done it. Apple has done it with
Speaker 2:  the AirPods where they use Bluetooth, but then there's a bunch of proprietary
Speaker 2:  features Samsung has done with the Galaxy buds. Google has done it with pixel
Speaker 2:  Buds just down the line. Everyone's approach to this is if you
Speaker 2:  want the coolest stuff, you have to buy our proprietary earbuds.
Speaker 2:  And if God help you, if you want to use the Galaxy Buds with an iPhone, they're,
Speaker 2:  they're just gonna fall back to Bluetooth. Yeah. So if you're a Galaxy owner,
Speaker 2:  like if you have a Samsung phone, I think the question is whether you want
Speaker 2:  to advertise it with the stuff in your ears.
Speaker 4:  Well, I say it slightly differently. I I think if you're Samsung, there is
Speaker 4:  a perfectly reasonable set of decisions you make to land on.
Speaker 4:  We should just make AirPods, which is, they, they
Speaker 4:  cited the evidence and there is some evidence out there that that basic
Speaker 4:  shape is actually more comfortable for more people with
Speaker 4:  the, the stem. It balances the weight, it also points a microphone towards
Speaker 4:  your mouth instead of the microphone just sort of pointing out to the side
Speaker 4:  of your head, which a lot of these things do. But also
Speaker 4:  I, I'm curious if you guys feel this way, but in, in my circle
Speaker 4:  at least, there is AirPods and there is knockoff AirPods. And that is,
Speaker 4:  that is the perception of wireless headphones. Everybody knows what AirPods
Speaker 4:  are and then all the other ones are like, oh, those aren't AirPods. And I
Speaker 4:  feel like if you're Samsung you're like, okay, well we want something that
Speaker 4:  integrates and if it happens to at a
Speaker 4:  glance look like AirPods and so people think they're AirPods, that's actually
Speaker 4:  not the worst thing in the world. And I think like, maybe it is that simple.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no, I I think we're saying the same thing in slightly different ways.
Speaker 2:  Like do you want your headphones to advertise they're not from Apple
Speaker 2:  and that means you don't have an iPhone. I
Speaker 4:  Think a lot of companies have killed themselves trying to differentiate from
Speaker 4:  Apple.
Speaker 4:  We are not, apple turns out to be like a pretty bad branding exercise most
Speaker 4:  of the time. And I
Speaker 5:  Don't think, I don't think Samsung's ever done that. They've always kind
Speaker 5:  of been like, yeah, we're Apple, but for Android, like, oh, you live in any
Speaker 5:  other part of the world where Apple doesn't make sense or it's too expensive
Speaker 5:  or whatever.
Speaker 2:  No Samsung waxes and wanes on it. Does the We are not Apple does. I agree
Speaker 2:  with that. But there have been times of maximum, we are not Apple from Samsung
Speaker 2:  and I think this is a low point.
Speaker 5:  It's pretty strong. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like this is very much a low point in Samsung's like, are we totally differentiated?
Speaker 2:  Like every, for years they had bigger phones and they were just
Speaker 2:  like, they were making the ads that, you know, people stand in line for the
Speaker 2:  iPhone and then someone would come by with like a surfboard sized St. Samsung
Speaker 2:  phone.
Speaker 2:  So the point that that that marketing actually worked against Apple, it came
Speaker 2:  up in various lawsuits that like Apple executives were saying like
Speaker 2:  Samsung's branding was causing market share
Speaker 2:  loss. Like very famous. Like Phil Show was like screaming at Apple's ad agency
Speaker 2:  because that was working and it turned out it was just the screens were bigger
Speaker 2:  and people love big cheap screens. And then Apple was like, here's the iPhone
Speaker 2:  six, six. and it just stopped being a problem.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, and it, it's worth pointing out that all of this is incredibly
Speaker 4:  cyclical, right? Like Apple spends most of its time building features into
Speaker 4:  the iPhone that already exist on Android devices. Apple got bigger
Speaker 4:  phones way after the whole Android universe. It like everybody is just
Speaker 4:  perpetually shoving towards each other at all times. Yeah. It's just
Speaker 4:  particularly jarring when you see it in
Speaker 4:  something as simple a shape as these headphones. 'cause it's not just
Speaker 4:  like a slab of glass in the way that all phones are a slab of glass. There
Speaker 4:  are a lot of shapes that headphones can be. And I don't know that there is
Speaker 4:  necessarily like a perfect correct way for headphones to
Speaker 4:  be, but we've just decided that AirPods are the thing. And it's very
Speaker 4:  clear that Samsung looked at it and said, AirPods are the thing. And the
Speaker 4:  best smartest thing we can do is just make AirPods.
Speaker 2:  I'm just gonna point out that the shapes of headphones, the designs of headphones,
Speaker 2:  the sound quality of headphones, all much more varied and competitive.
Speaker 2:  When the headphones Jack was still on phones, just just gonna say it out
Speaker 2:  loud, when there was an open interconnect that allowed for high quality audio
Speaker 2:  to pass from your device to the headphones, the variability in the market,
Speaker 2:  the variability in styles was, was real. It was big.
Speaker 4:  Also, as someone for whom AirPods don't feel great in my ears, it's a real
Speaker 4:  bummer that this is what we've decided. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So we'll see there, there's the, there's the two sides on the Galaxy
Speaker 2:  Buds. There's the pro which are in ears, and then there's the regular ones
Speaker 2:  which are more air potty, which are like, just shove it. They
Speaker 4:  Just hang. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  They're just like in there, you know, we gotta do the tests, we gotta try
Speaker 2:  'em out. I I'm, I'm always curious to see if anybody's actually managed to
Speaker 2:  make Bluetooth call audio sound good. Here in
Speaker 2:  New York City, the number of people who use wired headphones all day long,
Speaker 2:  it, it feels like it's just going up. Yep. I think people are just like over
Speaker 2:  it, which is interesting. But that's New York. It's not everywhere. So we'll
Speaker 2:  see. We're gonna review the things. The other major Yep. You just made an
Speaker 2:  Apple product is the Galaxy Watch Ultra. This
Speaker 4:  I think is actually the worst offender of the group.
Speaker 5:  It's so bad.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean it's called, first of all, it's called the Ultra. They've added
Speaker 2:  the icons, like the menu switcher dealie, the home screen
Speaker 2:  is the Apple Watch home screen. They even launched it with an orange band
Speaker 4:  And a quick button
Speaker 2:  And a quick button, which is orange. The colors are the same.
Speaker 2:  Weird, just weird all around.
Speaker 5:  It's yeah, it's just like a full on copy.
Speaker 5:  Right? Like the, I think the only, it feels like the only really big difference
Speaker 5:  is the Squirkle shape, which I absolutely hate that word and
Speaker 5:  want it to die. Yes. Agreed. But our And
Speaker 4:  The crown doesn't turn
Speaker 5:  And the crown doesn't
Speaker 4:  Turn. Well it does, but it doesn't scroll.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Which sure like, the, the fact that it doesn't scroll, but it
Speaker 5:  turns is just like mind boggling to me.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I just, I don't know, I'm, I'm so torn on this yet again because
Speaker 4:  I think on the one hand what we've learned in the last couple of years is
Speaker 4:  that Apple got the watch ultra really right. In a lot of ways,
Speaker 4:  right? Like it, it went super hard on this idea that this is a thing
Speaker 4:  for people who are going to use it aggressively outdoors. So we're gonna
Speaker 4:  optimize for battery life, we're gonna give you extra information about how
Speaker 4:  you're doing. We're gonna add some like GP sy stuff into it. We're gonna
Speaker 4:  make it more rugged for you to do more rugged things. And all of that has,
Speaker 4:  I think largely proven right, but has also just proven
Speaker 4:  popular. Like there are a lot of people, including a lot of people who don't
Speaker 4:  need all of that stuff here I am who wear ultras, right?
Speaker 4:  And, and so I think if you're part of me is like,
Speaker 4:  it's, it's a real sort of abdication of like creative responsibility for
Speaker 4:  Samsung to not find something more interesting to do. But also it, it looked
Speaker 4:  around and it was like, oh no Apple, apple maybe just got this one right?
Speaker 4:  And maybe we'll just go do that and build it into Samsung e stuff because
Speaker 4:  ultimately that's what people are asking us for, right? Like the thing
Speaker 4:  you hear all the time is like, where is the Apple watch for Samsung?
Speaker 4:  and it has like steadily moved towards that and this just feels like they
Speaker 4:  just went the hallway and we're like, you know what? Screw it. The Apple
Speaker 4:  Watch alter is pretty good. Let's do it. But
Speaker 2:  I want to say one thing, there's one very important differentiator
Speaker 2:  here. It is vastly unclear.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The Squirkle,
Speaker 2:  It's not even the Squirkle, it's like got a round face on a squirl body with
Speaker 2:  like a weird, the weird touch ring that they do.
Speaker 4:  It's one too many bezels.
Speaker 2:  It's a chunk, it's a chunk in a way that the ultra is a trunk, but the
Speaker 2:  ultra feels like a singular idea. And this is just
Speaker 2:  like Yeah. One too many bezels. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's like, it's, it's likes a case inside of a case, inside of a case in
Speaker 4:  a way that just feels tacky. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I do sort of like some of the color combinations. Like
Speaker 4:  if you, the, some of the pictures we've seen with some of the
Speaker 4:  like really aggressive like information dense watch faces,
Speaker 4:  you look at them and it's like, okay, there's a certain amount of like, I
Speaker 4:  could control a smart city from my watch with this and like,
Speaker 4:  could I be Batman with this watch on? Like, potentially. But it is,
Speaker 4:  it is. I think it, it feels it's either over designed or under
Speaker 4:  designed and I genuinely can't tell which one it's does
Speaker 5:  Does the screen feel like too much screen to y'all in a way that the
Speaker 5:  See, I feel the way with the Ultra does the Apple, yeah, the Apple Ultra
Speaker 5:  I feel doesn't quite scream screen at me as much as this does,
Speaker 5:  but I have neither, so I don't,
Speaker 4:  I I think the ultra is too much screen. I think they're both too much screen.
Speaker 4:  Like anytime I'm around somebody with an ultra both, dear God, you're right.
Speaker 4:  Anytime I'm around somebody with an Apple Watch Ultra, I'm like, I
Speaker 4:  can just sit here and read your email. Like you get a text message. It's
Speaker 4:  like we both got that text message, like it's just, it's a lot of screen
Speaker 4:  and this, this is I think very clearly gonna be the same thing. But
Speaker 4:  people seem to be fine with that. Like I guess that's just a thing we're
Speaker 4:  getting comfortable with.
Speaker 2:  There is some other Samsung stuff here in that,
Speaker 2:  you know, Samsung is just a weird company with weird ideas and they
Speaker 2:  like to be ahead of the curve. So they've added like
Speaker 2:  new sensors for health stuff and the, the best part is that
Speaker 2:  the, they call it the bioactive sensor and they're like, what if we just
Speaker 2:  add more colors of LEDs to the sensor and measure more things. And the the
Speaker 2:  funniest one here is like no one can quite do
Speaker 2:  the blood sugar measurement, which everyone wants to do. Like apple's struggled
Speaker 2:  with it. Samsung is obviously struggling with it, but like there's a lot
Speaker 2:  of people out there who would love an ongoing blood sugar measurement. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  For a variety of reasons. So they've just added something called the
Speaker 2:  experimental advanced glycation end products index metric,
Speaker 4:  Which
Speaker 5:  Is nothing to do. Hold on,
Speaker 4:  Hold on. Say that one more time. One more time.
Speaker 2:  The experimental advanced glycation end products.
Speaker 2:  Index metric.
Speaker 4:  It sounds like a like third rate stock exchange.
Speaker 2:  That's a pretty stock, it's an index of everyone's blood sugar is what it
Speaker 2:  is. It's like I ate a cookie. The A GEI went
Speaker 2:  down,
Speaker 2:  but so it's not it's not, yeah, it's not supposed to be that.
Speaker 2:  It's, you were not supposed to read at that. But Samsung says it looks at
Speaker 2:  your diet and lifecycle to reflect your overall biological
Speaker 2:  aging process, which is worse.
Speaker 5:  There's so much, it's like, who's the billionaire that's just slowly turning
Speaker 5:  himself younger?
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah, yeah. This the Vapi blood guy Peter Thiel is like, I gotta get this
Speaker 2:  Samsung, go
Speaker 5:  Watch all trucks. Like why I need this immediately. But no one else
Speaker 2:  Does. But this is, this is the differentiation in this market. Like
Speaker 2:  everyone figured out watches are either you want a big screen 'cause you
Speaker 2:  have a big screen like me, or you want all these health and fitness features,
Speaker 2:  or maybe you just want notifications and two factor codes.
Speaker 2:  But at the high end it's all health and fitness. Yep. Like that's what sells
Speaker 2:  the extra watch features to people. There's a reason that new health
Speaker 2:  specific features are not coming out at a high rate. Like one the tech isn't
Speaker 2:  quite there. Two, there's a bunch of regulatory hurdles. Three, they have
Speaker 2:  to make sure they're actually safe and say what they say they're gonna do.
Speaker 2:  Great. That means you, you end up with like fake like wellness
Speaker 2:  health features, like the advanced experimental,
Speaker 2:  the like the experimental advanced glycation end products result. and it's
Speaker 2:  fine, but there's always the danger that people take that stuff
Speaker 2:  way more seriously than they should. Yeah. Just like 10 th like people take
Speaker 2:  10,000 steps very seriously and like that just made up
Speaker 2:  like people just made that up and like here we are and like
Speaker 2:  there's a piece of this puzzle where I think these watches are gonna end
Speaker 2:  up being more samey because the thing that ultimately differentiates them
Speaker 2:  is kind of caught up in a lull of innovation and
Speaker 2:  regulatory behavior and all that stuff.
Speaker 4:  And famously like aggressive lawsuits against Apple from other
Speaker 4:  companies. No, I think that's right. And there's the, what was it, the, is
Speaker 4:  it the health score? Is that what Samsung calls it? This this like all in
Speaker 4:  one tracking thing that they're doing with the watches to basically
Speaker 4:  give you sort of an overall picture of your score. But
Speaker 5:  Like everybody's doing that right now, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But I think it, it fits exactly what you're talking about neli. That
Speaker 4:  it's, it's the sort of thing that as a, as a
Speaker 4:  very casual data point is helpful, right? Where it's like, okay,
Speaker 4:  like I was just looking at this weather app, it's called lazy weather and
Speaker 4:  its whole job is to tell you is it going to be warmer or colder than yesterday?
Speaker 4:  Right? Like based on the assumption that like that's actually all you really
Speaker 4:  need to know. And that is to that extent a
Speaker 4:  health score is useful, right? It's like am I, am I, am I better or worse?
Speaker 4:  Like how, how am I doing? And that's like it gives you that answer. But all
Speaker 4:  these things, as we get more of these sensors and more of this data, all
Speaker 4:  you're actually doing is giving people tools they don't understand with
Speaker 4:  which to do things that may or may not be helpful. and it feels
Speaker 4:  like we are so deep down the road of like here's some numbers without
Speaker 4:  giving people real ability to like do things with
Speaker 4:  them.
Speaker 5:  Well and this age index in particular feels like it is trying to
Speaker 5:  ride on the like ride the wave of continuous glucose monitors. It's trying
Speaker 5:  to sound like, oh yeah we kind of care about glucose monitors and and
Speaker 5:  diabetes and all of that. But also we can't legally do any of that because
Speaker 5:  none of that actual technology exists in a safe way. So
Speaker 2:  It should be clear, Samsung would not explain what the experimental
Speaker 2:  advanced glycation end products index is.
Speaker 5:  I was reading up on it all like as soon as I saw that word, I've been very
Speaker 5:  into continuous glucose monitors right now 'cause I've got a diabetic in
Speaker 5:  the family and as soon as I saw that I was like, what is that metric?
Speaker 5:  That's not the one I talk with the doctors about. Yeah. And just immediately
Speaker 5:  was like, oh this is, oh I don't wanna say bullshit, but like
Speaker 5:  close to it. Right?
Speaker 2:  All, all Samsung will say, just to repeat this, all
Speaker 2:  Samsung will say is that it looks at quote your diet and lifestyle
Speaker 2:  to reflect your overall biological aging process.
Speaker 2:  Sure. This is why I'm happy to announce a line of Vergecast supplements
Speaker 2:  which will bring your biological age lower.
Speaker 2:  Well if I only, if I had 10% more grift in my body
Speaker 2:  June spot out to the lightning round ho for lightning round sponsorships,
Speaker 2:  you,
Speaker 4:  You're by the way, supplements
Speaker 2:  Would do way, we, we will not allow supplement companies to advertise the
Speaker 2:  lightning round. I'm I'm putting that out there. Unless the price tag is
Speaker 2:  high enough price
Speaker 4:  Unless they're like really good supplements
Speaker 2:  Unless they rule. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But no, I mean I think even the, one of the big things Samsung announced
Speaker 4:  with these watches is that they have FDA de Novo
Speaker 4:  clearance for sleep apnea stuff. Yeah. And that's another really good example,
Speaker 4:  right? Because what that doesn't mean is that this will tell you if you have
Speaker 4:  sleep apnea. It's very hard to not understand it as that.
Speaker 4:  But that is not what this is. What it means is this is
Speaker 4:  a, a device that will give you data that is not harmful and potentially
Speaker 4:  interesting and that you should take that data and take it to a medical professional
Speaker 4:  who can help you make sense of it. And that is kind of indicative of
Speaker 4:  like the best of most smart watches. And this is true of Apple and Google
Speaker 4:  and basically everybody in this space right now that they're all so
Speaker 4:  careful to remind you constantly like these are not medical devices, this
Speaker 4:  is not medical advice. These things are just indicated as ways to give
Speaker 4:  you information that might be helpful in a certain context and you should
Speaker 4:  take it to your healthcare provider and consult with them like over and over
Speaker 4:  and over. That's the thing. But what it's actually doing is it's gonna pop
Speaker 4:  up a thing being like, you didn't sleep well. What do you think that's about?
Speaker 4:  and it's like,
Speaker 2:  Are
Speaker 4:  We, what problems are we really solving for people
Speaker 2:  Here? So I come from a family of doctors and they all talk
Speaker 2:  about, you know, like there are laws in most states now
Speaker 2:  that say you have to have access to your medical records right away. And
Speaker 2:  a thing that is real is you go in for tests and then you get the result of
Speaker 2:  your test before the doctor gets it. Mm. And then people don't
Speaker 2:  wait. They start furiously googling numbers and
Speaker 2:  they call the doctors having already formed conclusions and
Speaker 2:  the doctor's like, hold on. You have no idea what you're talking about.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Apparently I didn't have kidney failure, I just needed to drink more
Speaker 5:  water. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  This is like a real thing that happens like all the time. Yeah. And I think
Speaker 2:  that's fascinating in this context, right? Where you were like, you're just
Speaker 2:  putting on people's wrists for a couple hundred bucks being like, this is
Speaker 2:  good at hikes also it will terrify you and I
Speaker 2:  I'm saying like the, the bleeding edge of these devices is health features
Speaker 2:  and we're just kind of at a place now where they can't make the real claims.
Speaker 2:  So they're just making up other ones. We'll see how it goes. In
Speaker 2:  any case, it looks exactly like an Apple Watch Ultra. Yeah. Except uglier
Speaker 2:  in like a real way. All right. I mean so that's the two copies,
Speaker 4:  Right? Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like the, you put in, you put the AirPods through chat GBT, it's spit back
Speaker 2:  AirPods with LEDs like done and done. Nailed it. Yeah. Then there's the other
Speaker 2:  stuff we should talk about the ring. 'cause the ring is easily the most interesting
Speaker 2:  product they have. Yes. and it is the one where a apple has nothing.
Speaker 2:  Although we've heard about some attempts, some research projects at that
Speaker 2:  company, but there are other, you know, the or ring exists but it seems like
Speaker 2:  Samsung is, has a shot here.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think it does because the aura ring is really like, it's kind of
Speaker 5:  one size. Most of the other ring makers are kind of like, yeah we do one
Speaker 5:  size You can get different sizes of the ring, but ultimately the battery,
Speaker 5:  everything else is the same. Samsung is doing what most big tech
Speaker 5:  companies do, which is like, we're gonna have multiple sizes. So like the
Speaker 5:  largest ones have a little bit more battery than the smaller ones 'cause
Speaker 5:  they can put more in it. And that's just cool and smart. But also it
Speaker 5:  just sounds a lot like an aura ring with better integration for Samsung
Speaker 5:  specifically in a way that's like exciting. And they have smaller ones.
Speaker 5:  This is like, I think Victoria Song, our, our wearables writer
Speaker 5:  said that this might be one of the s like smallest available smart rings
Speaker 5:  for people.
Speaker 2:  It still looks gigantic on her hand. It does in the, but she has,
Speaker 4:  She, she will be the first to tell you she has small hands and is she does
Speaker 4:  a, a super indicative also shout out to V who I believe wore four
Speaker 4:  other rings to the HandsOn with the galaxy ring. Like
Speaker 4:  that is, that's,
Speaker 2:  That's some straight from Mafi right there just like,
Speaker 4:  Like brass knuckles. But it's all smart rings. Like I, hell yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's so good.
Speaker 2:  I'm either going to a Samsung event or the Jersey Shore. We're gonna find
Speaker 2:  out. I might buy the ring sizer 'cause You can just buy
Speaker 2:  Samsung's ring sizer for 10 bucks and you figure out what
Speaker 2:  your ring size is, which is useful and then you get a credit when you buy
Speaker 2:  the ring. I think that's really smart. Like compared to the other, you have
Speaker 2:  to wear this on your body. Fitbit and ideas we've seen like Apple making
Speaker 2:  you go to the store. Yeah. Like this is actually very clever. It's obviously
Speaker 2:  easier with a ring than a thing that you have to wear on your face and wear,
Speaker 2:  you know, prescription lenses and all that with the Vision Pro. But I think
Speaker 2:  it's very clever that as we kind of go into wearables
Speaker 2:  world fitting stuff to your body becomes an
Speaker 2:  interesting challenge and it's not solved. So that, I thought that part was
Speaker 2:  really cool, but the part where it's, it's the same product as
Speaker 2:  everyone else, but it's more integrated in the system. 'cause Samsung owns
Speaker 2:  the operating system. I I can't, I don't know how I feel about that at all.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Well one thing that is better about it is that it also has like an
Speaker 5:  actual case instead of just a little dongle, you have to periodically find
Speaker 5:  and stick the ring on and the case looks
Speaker 5:  interesting. Did you guys look at the case for it?
Speaker 2:  The the case is, is it gigantic? I can't tell if this case is
Speaker 2:  gigantic or not. It
Speaker 5:  Feels like gigantic and also so much fake crystal.
Speaker 2:  Yes, yes, yes.
Speaker 4:  It's like a Claire's jewelry case.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I love it so much.
Speaker 4:  I don't mean that as an insult. Like it, it just is what it is. And, and
Speaker 4:  it is true that it's better that it is a case than what you get
Speaker 4:  from Aura and others, which is essentially just like a puck that sits on
Speaker 4:  your desk, which is fine for what it is, but is easy to lose and
Speaker 4:  doesn't travel very well. And I think a case that is properly a case makes
Speaker 4:  a lot of sense. And I think actually the thing I'm most excited about,
Speaker 4:  about the Galaxy ring is that Samsung seems to have gotten
Speaker 4:  the ring wearing experience closer to right
Speaker 4:  than just about anybody that we've seen. Like the thing is pretty light,
Speaker 4:  it's pretty thin, it's, it's concave, which will make it a little easier
Speaker 4:  to wear and like bang around on a desk and stuff than some of the other sort
Speaker 4:  of convex ones that we've seen. It's, it's, it comes in
Speaker 4:  a bunch of different sizes. Like the battery life is long, it seems like
Speaker 5:  No additional subscription,
Speaker 4:  Right? There are like little bits and pieces of what it's gonna be like to
Speaker 4:  own this that I think are going to be really important because we're still
Speaker 4:  very much at a moment where like, unless you are a psycho who wants to
Speaker 4:  track their sleep and no shade to those psychos, there's lots of them out
Speaker 4:  there. Unless you are that person, there are not a lot of compelling reasons
Speaker 4:  to wear a ring. So we have to figure out like
Speaker 4:  what, what, what is this thing for? And the smart thing that Samsung did
Speaker 4:  is be like, this is gonna be a nice thing to wear before you really have
Speaker 4:  a hundred reasons to use it.
Speaker 2:  It's just a bunch of sensors, right? Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It does heart rate tracking, it does a skin temperature sensor. Ve
Speaker 2:  often wondered what my skin temperature is and then it had a bunch of sleep
Speaker 2:  features like
Speaker 2:  the watch we just had this whole conversation about like they're adding more
Speaker 2:  kinds of sensors to the watch ahead of their ability to actually tell you
Speaker 2:  what they mean. It feels like, well we also need a bunch of 'em smaller now
Speaker 2:  we can just put 'em in a ring. Well
Speaker 4:  They're also better on a ring, right? Like the having that stuff on your
Speaker 4:  finger 24 hours a day is a vastly better data collection
Speaker 4:  system than having it on your wrist sometimes. Right? Like it if if you are
Speaker 4:  the person who wants that data and cares about it and is going to take it
Speaker 4:  to your medical professional, a ring is is just a better venue
Speaker 4:  for that in almost every way. Yeah. I want smart rings to work.
Speaker 4:  Like I really, I really do.
Speaker 2:  If you had a smart ring, would you give up on your watch?
Speaker 4:  No, and the reason I don't have a smart ring frankly, is because every time
Speaker 4:  I wear an aura, I wear an aura for three days and I'm like, what on earth
Speaker 4:  is the point of me having this thing on? Because I'm not like at,
Speaker 4:  at that if you're like a nine or 10 out of 10 on a,
Speaker 4:  like how much do I care about tracking my body sensors
Speaker 4:  person? A ring is great. I'm not that. And so like
Speaker 4:  having it tell me I got bad sleep when I wake up tired is like not
Speaker 4:  interesting to me. So I ended up just putting the aura back in a drawer and
Speaker 4:  the ring is still, the galaxy ring is is gonna have that same problem too.
Speaker 2:  So this brings me to Neil Patel's theory of wearable bullshit. Okay,
Speaker 2:  just wanna be clear. So if you remember this, by the way, this theory still
Speaker 2:  needs a better name I'm in the market for, but if you remember
Speaker 4:  It's important that it has NE's name in it though. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It it's mine.
Speaker 2:  That's how You can, You can buy You can I'll sell you naming rights to the
Speaker 2:  theory of what wearable bullshit. This is the Samsung Exxon theory of
Speaker 2:  wearable bullshit presented by Citibank. There you go.
Speaker 2:  So the the x axis right is
Speaker 2:  value and then the Y is fids. Like how much you
Speaker 2:  have to care about the thing or it's the other way around, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 2:  Those are the two axes.
Speaker 4:  Well there's also a z that you refuse to acknowledge, but that's okay.
Speaker 2:  Many people have sent us many versions of this chart. Right? And
Speaker 2:  so my, my my the paradigm object on
Speaker 2:  the chart of things you attach to your body is regular glasses,
Speaker 2:  which are a little bit fiddly. You had to clean 'em, you gotta carry 'em,
Speaker 2:  you can't lose them, but they, if you need them, provide you an immense amount
Speaker 2:  of value. So you're like, I'm gonna put these on my face all the time.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. 'cause they allow me to see and then I will deal with having to clean
Speaker 2:  them and owning a microfiber cloth and all the rest of the stuff that you're
Speaker 2:  supposed to do with glasses,
Speaker 7:  You just use your shirt.
Speaker 2:  Right. That's what, right. Like somewhere on that list is like
Speaker 2:  the original Apple Watch, which was too fiddly required a lot of care
Speaker 2:  and didn't do well as a product. Then there's the current Apple Watch,
Speaker 2:  which actually is pretty good bad it life doesn't require a lot of care and
Speaker 2:  has a lot of value for people like exceeded the, the, the line.
Speaker 2:  Then there's a vision pro, which is very like anything that goes on your
Speaker 2:  face, the fids is off the charts and it can't deliver as much value. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like face computers just can't deliver the value to make this worthwhile.
Speaker 2:  Right. You just keep going down and down the list. The ring has a problem
Speaker 2:  in that it delivers no value to you. It is a totally passive computer
Speaker 2:  that you have to fiddle with and put on your body. And then
Speaker 2:  all the value that's delivered is like at some later point
Speaker 2:  you will look at some data that was collected. Well and
Speaker 4:  I think if you're, if you're the kind of person who has a, like a
Speaker 4:  preexisting thing for which that is useful, great. Like if you
Speaker 4:  are someone who knows you struggle with sleep and you're trying things and
Speaker 4:  actually collecting that data on an ongoing basis helps you. Great. That
Speaker 4:  makes total sense. A ring is gonna be really useful and the upside of a ring
Speaker 4:  is that the FIDS score is much, much lower. Like a thing that you wear
Speaker 4:  in your index finger and take off once a week to charge while you shower
Speaker 4:  super low on the FIDS meter. But the
Speaker 4:  problem is that even its potential to do more stuff is not that high.
Speaker 4:  Like I
Speaker 2:  Don't think it's that low on the fids meter. You don't think I I wear a ring
Speaker 2:  every day. Yeah. I I've never think I pick it up when I leave the house.
Speaker 2:  It serves an important function, which is
Speaker 2:  my ladies that I'm taking. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's a symbol of my ongoing devotion to my divorce lawyer of a wife
Speaker 2:  and I, I just never think about it. I I take it, I put it on, I take it off.
Speaker 2:  I I never think about charging it, whatever. It has a obviously
Speaker 2:  important societal emotional function
Speaker 2:  that it does. It's like symbolic but there's it's
Speaker 2:  zero fit. Like anything over zero is actually the standard.
Speaker 2:  I
Speaker 5:  I think that is probably only some of our
Speaker 5:  audience has that issue. 'cause a lot of their audience probably also enjoys
Speaker 5:  to wear a little couple of different rings, replaced rings like I wear.
Speaker 2:  But they're also zero.
Speaker 5:  No, because you take, like, I cannot tell you it's jewelry, right? Like jewelry,
Speaker 5:  you're, you're constantly, a lot of people are constantly fiddling with their
Speaker 5:  jewelry. Do you
Speaker 2:  Think Galaxy watches jewelry
Speaker 5:  Fundamentally is, it's not jewelry I wanna personally
Speaker 5:  wear.
Speaker 2:  Well that, but it doesn't have the function. No,
Speaker 5:  It does. It's it's a ring. It's showing, it's it's putting that extra
Speaker 5:  bling on your hand. Correct. And I think a lot of people do like to have
Speaker 5:  that extra bling. The
Speaker 4:  Aura ring has definitely attained like status, symbol
Speaker 4:  status over the years. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's it's got like a, it's got like a bling kind of quality to it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And I think the rings in a way like the Apple watch quickly became,
Speaker 5:  went from fashion. We all laughed at it being fashion and immediately
Speaker 5:  into,
Speaker 2:  But it, it failed as a fashion. Yeah. Famously failed as
Speaker 5:  A fashion. Yeah. Famously we were all like, that's stupid. And we all just
Speaker 5:  stopped treating it like fashion and it just became a watch on your wrist.
Speaker 5:  The ring is still, I think both more capable of it. So if
Speaker 5:  you're someone who doesn't wanna have a giant watch on your wrist and you
Speaker 5:  do want those metrics, like, okay, You can put on the rig the ring and You
Speaker 5:  can still wear your brightling or your Rolex or whatever. Yeah. Yeah. Show
Speaker 5:  that off. And I think that's who this is for. That's
Speaker 2:  The, the market.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. This is for like people with $6,000 watches that
Speaker 5:  that they don't wanna replace it.
Speaker 2:  This is why Silicon Valley billionaires love the door.
Speaker 5:  This is, this is my aspirational
Speaker 2:  Ring. I I just figured this out. I guess when I say is it jewelry? I agree
Speaker 2:  with you that like it's jewelry. Yeah. I meant does it look no
Speaker 2:  like jewelry. The aura ring actually they tried very hard to make it look
Speaker 2:  like jewelry. Yeah. And one of the only reasons that I
Speaker 2:  wouldn't just swap out my wedding ring for it is You can, I think You can
Speaker 2:  only wear it on your index finger, right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You're supposed to only wear it on your index. So
Speaker 2:  It's it like it doesn't do the other thing. But there's a world and once
Speaker 2:  you just infuse my existing jewelry with a tech and it looks good enough
Speaker 2:  and that's fine. I think that the Samsung one doesn't, doesn't.
Speaker 2:  But wait,
Speaker 4:  The ne the Neli Patel theory of wearable bullshit does not have a fashion
Speaker 4:  scale.
Speaker 5:  That's the Z axis. Now
Speaker 4:  You've, you've Yeah. This is, this is about fids
Speaker 2:  And those, those are same
Speaker 4:  Thing.
Speaker 2:  Do you know what's very, if you wanna attach
Speaker 4:  A computer, NELI.
Speaker 2:  All right, look, I can
Speaker 4:  Make this
Speaker 2:  Work man work. I need to think about this for like five more seconds and
Speaker 2:  I'll come up with something.
Speaker 4:  But No, but I, I, I really think the problem is the, the
Speaker 4:  ceiling for what You can do with a ring right now seems really
Speaker 4:  low because like, even, even like the next thing you think of is like, oh,
Speaker 4:  maybe it'll vibrate for notifications. Do you know how insane it would feel
Speaker 4:  to have your, the base of your index finger vibrate every time you get
Speaker 4:  a text message? Like
Speaker 2:  Insane
Speaker 4:  Disaster
Speaker 5:  You'd go to your doctor.
Speaker 2:  Exactly. It'd be like, I have all of this medical information
Speaker 4:  And Samsung is doing a thing where they're like sort of
Speaker 4:  gently pointing it like maybe this is a way to gesture control some stuff.
Speaker 4:  Like they have a little bit of
Speaker 2:  A pinchy
Speaker 4:  Pinch, pinchy pinch stuff going on, but only
Speaker 2:  If you have a Samsung phone. Right.
Speaker 4:  And so there's like, but even that is like probab
Speaker 4:  probably not. I just don't think that's the thing yet.
Speaker 5:  What if, I mean we're hearing a lot more about XR nowadays and
Speaker 5:  And if you is like mixed reality. That's just another word for mixed
Speaker 5:  reality and what if that's a like kind of their way
Speaker 5:  of this is how we're gonna control it in the future. I
Speaker 4:  Do think if, if you wanna like Galaxy Brain, take the galaxy ring.
Speaker 4:  I think that's probably,
Speaker 5:  I, that's all I want to
Speaker 4:  Do. Also, I just realized if Samsung comes out with a headset and doesn't
Speaker 4:  call it the Galaxy Brain, I'm gonna be furious.
Speaker 2:  Or its entire AI service suite
Speaker 4:  Should
Speaker 2:  Be called Galaxy Brain. Galaxy Brain. How did we have this idea?
Speaker 2:  David Pierce's Galaxy Brain You can have one. Yeah. God.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we're, we're gonna try out the ring VI think V is very excited to
Speaker 2:  get it. We'll we'll know much more about it soon. The last piece we should
Speaker 2:  talk about are some phones. I just
Speaker 4:  Wanna point out that we're almost 40 minutes into this segment just now talking
Speaker 4:  about the phones, which actually tells you every single thing you need to
Speaker 4:  know about these new phones.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, they're more expensive.
Speaker 4:  I'm so disappointed in these new phones. Like of all the things like
Speaker 4:  I can understand why you would copy Apple in making certain things. I can
Speaker 4:  understand why you go all in on AI even before there are a lot of really
Speaker 4:  compelling use cases. But this thing where Samsung was so far
Speaker 4:  ahead in foldable phones and Flip phones and seems content to
Speaker 4:  just like squander that in the name of making everything a smidge better
Speaker 4:  and not doing anything new or interesting every year is really starting to
Speaker 4:  bum me out.
Speaker 5:  Well do they have competition in this space? Like is there anybody that's
Speaker 5:  actually pushing
Speaker 2:  Well, so there, there are, we should talk about the Motorola Razor plus,
Speaker 2:  which Allison reviewed this week. Yeah. Which she loved. She just
Speaker 2:  loved it.
Speaker 4:  That thing is one very good camera away from maybe being the best Android
Speaker 4:  phone. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Also, it's got a weird processor. It's like who even can
Speaker 2:  describe the Snapdragon eight s 3M or whatever it's called.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Wait, let me find it. What is it I'm trying to find. It's the
Speaker 2:  Snapdragon eight s gen three, which is just a weird mid-tier rolls
Speaker 2:  processor. Yeah, it's weird. It's it's just a weird,
Speaker 2:  it's one of those where like, will this one last two years or five? Like
Speaker 2:  who, who knows? Right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Allison called it like an entry flagship, which is like Sure. Alright,
Speaker 2:  Here we are.
Speaker 2:  Anyways, talk about the Samsung ones first. The flip six
Speaker 2:  is the one that you know is sort of more interesting. 'cause I think that
Speaker 2:  form factor is more interesting also. It's the thing that's changing the
Speaker 2:  most. Like those are the phones that are changing the most. 'cause the cover
Speaker 2:  screens are getting bigger and bigger. Yeah. But it, it's basically just
Speaker 2:  like a little bit lighter and costs more money.
Speaker 5:  Mm Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Also a little more rugged, which is meaningful, especially for the flip.
Speaker 4:  They're, they're getting better at making that thing into like an actual
Speaker 4:  phone that You can treat like an actual phone
Speaker 5:  A little bit more, right?
Speaker 4:  A little,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Like it doesn't even have dust resistance. Like don't do not
Speaker 5:  take this to
Speaker 4:  The desert. But listen, You can, You can drop it in the toilet. Now that's
Speaker 4:  a victory.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's true. You can drop your phone in the toilet and it'll probably be
Speaker 4:  fine.
Speaker 2:  And then the, the Fold six, boy I couldn't tell you,
Speaker 4:  It's literally like one of the main features they talked about is
Speaker 4:  that when it's flat it's flatter. Like what, what are we doing here?
Speaker 2:  It's
Speaker 4:  Just, and again, i i part of me wonders like
Speaker 4:  what are, are we several physics miracles away
Speaker 4:  from there being a new thing You can do here because Samsung is
Speaker 4:  making little bits of this better. The the cover screen, the, it's, it's
Speaker 4:  a little wider on the outside, which I actually appreciate. It feels less
Speaker 4:  like a TV remote and more like a phone. It's
Speaker 4:  just the same thing though. Like the, the Samsung is not even really
Speaker 4:  like coming up with really cool new ideas about how the software here could
Speaker 4:  work. Which at least Motorola is pushing really hard for how do we make the
Speaker 4:  outer screen useful and the inner screen useful and have them interplay with
Speaker 4:  each other really well. Samsung feels like it is just not pushing
Speaker 4:  that nearly as hard. And so it's like, what, what, what is the case for
Speaker 4:  why I should buy these things? Samsung.
Speaker 5:  I don't think they care.
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 2:  Mean presumably they'd like me to buy their phones.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I think they want us to buy the phones, but, but I think they're, Samsung
Speaker 5:  often feels driven by, by external pressures. It often feels
Speaker 5:  driven by the market and like it's decisions are based in the market and
Speaker 5:  like, oh, we do the folding phone 'cause nobody else is doing it. And we
Speaker 5:  get there first and we get there before Apple. And Apple just
Speaker 5:  hasn't done it, hasn't even talked about doing it. The rumors are are
Speaker 5:  scanned. Right. And so, and that's their primary competitor. Like we wanna
Speaker 5:  say boat roller or Pixel or whatever. Let's be real, their primary competitor
Speaker 5:  is Apple. And if Apple's not doing anything in this space, then
Speaker 5:  why should they invest in making the phone better when they can just rest
Speaker 5:  on their laurels?
Speaker 2:  Well I think also we, we've Alex you mentioned Saturday Samsung.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Their sales are down, they're trying to make more money.
Speaker 5:  Saturday Samsung man
Speaker 2:  Is a thing. They, their efforts are going to marketing
Speaker 2:  and more dollars from the same product. Like of course they're not putting
Speaker 2:  tons of money into making like changing things too much at the same time.
Speaker 2:  Like they still employ the software engineers and designers like they Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Make it more interesting as like a, a totally valid critique here. Like yeah,
Speaker 2:  the phone opens You, can you have a little phone that turns into a big phone?
Speaker 2:  What happens then? Right. Yeah. And that, that seems to be set aside. So
Speaker 2:  that does, I think, bring us to the Motorola phone where Motorola does seem
Speaker 2:  to have a lot of ideas. What would happen when you have a little phone that
Speaker 2:  gets even smaller and you have a big cover screen and like their
Speaker 2:  ideas about how apps even appear on that cover screen and how you might control
Speaker 2:  them all pretty good.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. It's the idea of like, what if you only had to tap on your phone
Speaker 4:  two times to accomplish something on the outside screen is like, I don't
Speaker 4:  know if that is the framework, but that's kind of what it feels like. And
Speaker 4:  there's just little bits and pieces where it's like, okay, this is a screen
Speaker 4:  you're gonna have sort of looking at you all the time. So we're gonna make
Speaker 4:  it fun and cute and animated And, if you wanna like do
Speaker 4:  something, you're probably gonna open up the phone. So in this case, what
Speaker 4:  we need to do is just give you all the things that are like one or two taps
Speaker 4:  and just put it right in front of you so it's like, what's next on your calendar?
Speaker 4:  Get to ai, stop the music. Like I love that. and
Speaker 4:  it, this is like, the thing about flip phones that I'm enthusiastic about
Speaker 4:  is it is I sometimes you should only have access to a tiny
Speaker 4:  portion of your phone and that is how you do it on that outside
Speaker 4:  screen. Like I think Motorola is getting this really right in a way I find
Speaker 4:  very exciting
Speaker 2:  Also, it seems like there, when you unfold it, their screen is less
Speaker 2:  creasey looking than the Samsung one. It's hard to
Speaker 4:  Tell. Yeah. It's only 10 80 p and it's like 6.9 inches. So it's like
Speaker 4:  super long and not that high res and that, that makes me
Speaker 5:  Sense David's face right now. You just looks disgusted. Really enthusiastic.
Speaker 4:  I just,
Speaker 2:  This you love a garbage phone, you're, oh my God, you single-handedly driving
Speaker 2:  all of the sales of the B Palmer.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's, that's been a wild couple of weeks. But wait,
Speaker 2:  One
Speaker 4:  Of the, one of the things that I've heard a bunch of people say about this
Speaker 4:  Samsung launch, and I think this might be true for Motorola and stuff too,
Speaker 4:  is that we're now in Samsung's case six generations
Speaker 4:  into the Flip and Fold universe and
Speaker 4:  anecdotally at least, and based on, you know, talking to people and what
Speaker 4:  we've seen, these are not winning in any meaningful way. Right? Like
Speaker 4:  they're not taking market share away from the Galaxy
Speaker 4:  s Lines and the iPhone and the other popular candy bar
Speaker 4:  phones. And so you wonder if instead of Samsung
Speaker 4:  and others looking at these phones saying, this is how we win,
Speaker 4:  they're increasingly looking at them as just like kind of a sideshow
Speaker 4:  and Yeah, maybe. And, and if that is the case, of course you slow down
Speaker 4:  and you put less interesting resources into doing it. And
Speaker 4:  especially for Samsung, which has a gigantic business selling candy bar phones.
Speaker 4:  Like maybe, maybe we should be less interested
Speaker 4:  in these because the world is less interested in these for Motorola like
Speaker 4:  it, they kind of have nothing to lose by swinging big for something new and
Speaker 4:  the Razor is the best brand Motorola ever had. So like, I get why they're
Speaker 4:  doing this that way, but for Samsung, like, we've been
Speaker 4:  waiting for this to become Samsung's thing for so long now
Speaker 4:  and I wonder if Samsung is increasingly convinced with every
Speaker 4:  generation that maybe it's just not going to be,
Speaker 5:  Is it just too expensive? Is that why it just hasn't become the thing
Speaker 5:  I like, like that's why I haven't gotten one is it's almost $2,000
Speaker 4:  I think for foldable phones. Very much so. Yeah. I think the flip funds you
Speaker 4:  could like maybe have a debate about whether it is
Speaker 4:  meaningfully more useful to have that. I would argue that it is, but I I
Speaker 4:  think you could debate that. Yeah, but the, like the Fold problem is A,
Speaker 4:  they're huge and B, they're twice the price. Yeah. Like I just,
Speaker 4:  it's that is going to be so hard to come back from for any of these companies.
Speaker 2:  But you get three times the screens
Speaker 5:  For twice the price.
Speaker 2:  You do. Yeah. Pixel
Speaker 4:  The dollar ratio is off the choice.
Speaker 2:  That's your Saturday Samsung pitch. Two x the price, three x the screen
Speaker 2:  and
Speaker 4:  They'll give you a TV with it. So you get
Speaker 2:  Na and Cupertino. That's true. You can also get a TV with it.
Speaker 2:  All right. We have talked about everything for too long. We're way over already.
Speaker 2:  We're only halfway through. I think that makes sense. We'll be back
Speaker 2:  with more of our chest.
Speaker 1:  Have a question or need how to advice. Just ask meta
Speaker 1:  AI whether you want to design a marathon training program that will get you
Speaker 1:  race ready for the fall. Or you're curious what planets are visible in
Speaker 1:  tonight's sky. Meta AI has the answers.
Speaker 1:  Perhaps you want to learn how to plant basil when your garden only gets
Speaker 1:  indirect sunlight. Meta AI is your intelligent assistant.
Speaker 1:  It can even answer your follow-up questions like what You can make with your
Speaker 1:  basil and other ingredients you have in your fridge. Meta AI
Speaker 1:  can also summarize your class notes, visualize your ideas and so
Speaker 1:  much more. The best part is You can find meta ai right in the apps
Speaker 1:  you already have Instagram, WhatsApp, Facebook,
Speaker 1:  and Messenger. Just
Speaker 5:  got a story for this. I I got a way to tell. Explain this. All
Speaker 2:  Right Al, I'm just gonna let you drive. Here you go.
Speaker 5:  So, so once upon a time, there was a family, no cost. And, and the dad went
Speaker 5:  out and he put together a huge corporate conglomeration and they called it
Speaker 5:  National amusements, which
Speaker 2:  Is very good.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, great. They're nationally amusing. And in there was
Speaker 5:  CVS and this big storied century old
Speaker 5:  studio, paramount, all of that in there. And then on the other side, there
Speaker 5:  was another family and, and they did something called Oracle. And
Speaker 5:  Larry Ellison made a lot of money from that. And his kids
Speaker 5:  got into to films and they started producing. And his daughter made a lot
Speaker 5:  of good movies and then made some bad ones. And his son made some really
Speaker 5:  successful movies like Top Gun that, you know, the New Top Gun.
Speaker 5:  The New Top Gun, yeah. He, he was a baby when the last, was he even alive
Speaker 5:  when the last one came out? But he did that.
Speaker 2:  We're not gonna find out. We're
Speaker 5:  Not gonna find out. Don't worry about it. This is, it doesn't matter. It
Speaker 5:  doesn't matter. What matters is that there were Z two families and they said,
Speaker 5:  you know what? We should really get together and the tech family
Speaker 5:  should buy the media conglomerates, family's
Speaker 5:  business and just make an even bigger business. And then there was
Speaker 5:  a lot of winging about, there was a lot of like whinging about that. There
Speaker 5:  was a lot of, Ooh, should I do this? I don't know. Sherry Redstone, the current
Speaker 5:  owner of Paramount, was really concerned. She didn't know how she wanted
Speaker 5:  her, she didn't want her dad's legacy ruined, she wanted money.
Speaker 5:  Those are important things. And that's the
Speaker 2:  Plot of succession, everybody. Yeah. This is fully the plot of success.
Speaker 2:  That's
Speaker 5:  What happened. And eventually David Ellison went to his dad and was like,
Speaker 5:  dad, you're a billionaire. Can I borrow a couple of billion, say
Speaker 5:  six of your money and put it and sweetened this pot? And
Speaker 5:  Larry said, I got your son. And now his son owns
Speaker 5:  one of the largest film studios in Hollywood. Well,
Speaker 2:  It hasn't closed yet, so he should Careful
Speaker 5:  It hasn't closed yet. Yeah, that's true. It hasn't closed. He will potentially
Speaker 5:  own it provided the lawsuits that are already cooking
Speaker 5:  up amongst the investors who are mad that they're not getting as much of
Speaker 5:  this pot. Those, those don't screw things up. Provided
Speaker 5:  there is Apollo or another investor doesn't come in and say, actually I can
Speaker 5:  provide even more money than Larry Ellison
Speaker 5:  feel like that's probably not gonna happen. Seeing as Larry Ellison already
Speaker 5:  put 6 billion in, I, I, I feel like this is probably David
Speaker 5:  Ellison's company. And, and we've been seeing that all around
Speaker 5:  Hollywood. We've been seeing that from a lot of the reporters variety. Matthew
Speaker 5:  Bella over at Puck. A lot of folks have been talking about this. Matthew
Speaker 5:  Bella had a really good interview with Ellison about this, where he was like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, I'm gonna do all this tech stuff. And that was really interesting about
Speaker 5:  all of this is he's pitched this as like tech taking over
Speaker 5:  and I think we'd argue that Tech had already took over, given the success
Speaker 5:  of Netflix and, and even smaller stuff like Apple. But this is really officially
Speaker 5:  like tech has taken over Hollywood and he's got big
Speaker 5:  ambitions about using AI for workflows. That that's as much
Speaker 5:  as he said.
Speaker 2:  I can just read you the quotes. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  They're great.
Speaker 2:  The quotes are wild. A slide
Speaker 2:  deck for investors said AI would turbocharge content
Speaker 2:  creation and drive efficiencies in streamlined operations.
Speaker 2:  Terrifying
Speaker 2:  Ellison said the art will challenge the technology and the technology challenges
Speaker 2:  the art, which,
Speaker 2:  okay. Yeah. And then, and then he also said, we believe that understanding
Speaker 2:  the symbiotic relationship between art and technology is essential to be
Speaker 2:  able to meet this moment. There are a lot of technology companies that are
Speaker 2:  rapidly expanding into media. We believe it is essential for Paramount to
Speaker 2:  be able to expand its technology prowess to be both a media and technology
Speaker 2:  enterprise.
Speaker 4:  Those are quotes that come up when you say chat, GPT write me some quotes
Speaker 4:  about like, do you remember the paper that was like, we, we found a
Speaker 4:  huge increase in the, the word delve being used because of chat
Speaker 4:  GPT. Like that's what that sounds like to me. That's a bunch of nothing.
Speaker 4:  Like that's, that's what you say. Well,
Speaker 2:  There are, there are two, there are two things that are real. There are one
Speaker 2:  oh thousand percent the things you would expect all of those words
Speaker 2:  to mean.
Speaker 2:  Ellison proposed upgrading the advertising technology to give marketers more
Speaker 2:  information about what audiences they're reaching.
Speaker 2:  So we're doing some data collection and algorithmic ads and that we are working
Speaker 2:  to improve the algorithmic recommendation engines that Paramount Plus uses,
Speaker 2:  hoping subscribers will spend more time on the streaming service and viewer
Speaker 2:  can. So we're doing engagement. Sure.
Speaker 5:  I I don't think those are actually the actual tech that they're gonna be
Speaker 5:  doing, like investing in. I think, I think the advertising is, everybody's
Speaker 5:  investing in that right now. Peacock, if you talk to anybody at NBC right
Speaker 5:  now, they will not hesitate to be like, have you heard about our, our new
Speaker 5:  ad tech platform? We are really all in on ad tech platforms for streaming.
Speaker 5:  It's great.
Speaker 2:  Can I just read you more words? Yes.
Speaker 4:  I wish you wouldn't.
Speaker 2:  Ellison also said Skydance will work in partnership with Oracle to create
Speaker 2:  a cloud-based animation studio. Skydance used
Speaker 2:  the studio in the cloud to produce part of Spellbound, which is coming out
Speaker 2:  later on. Netflix. We intend to scale that business across all of our production
Speaker 2:  workflows and animation. That's
Speaker 4:  Just, we're gonna buy a bunch of GPUs. Like what are we talking about? Well,
Speaker 5:  I it's also kind of worthless because the guy who runs Skydance animation
Speaker 5:  right now is John Lasseter who famously got punted from Pixar
Speaker 5:  because he couldn't keep his hands to himself. Allegedly. Yes.
Speaker 5:  And that, that's who's running it. They have not had a lot of successes.
Speaker 5:  Most of their other animated properties have not had hit the, like
Speaker 5:  John Lasseter used to have a golden hand. Right? Like he'd look at anything
Speaker 5:  and it would make a billion dollars. It felt like nowadays it's like we barely
Speaker 5:  sold luck to Apple tv. We're making a deal to, to get this
Speaker 5:  thing sold over at Netflix. That all felt like things
Speaker 5:  he was saying to get Sherry Redstone feeling comfortable to do
Speaker 5:  this deal because Sherry Redstone was holding up the deal
Speaker 5:  in, in big ways. And right now everybody in Hollywood has a lot of anxiety
Speaker 5:  about tech companies and about tech infrastructure and how they can compete
Speaker 5:  with stuff like Netflix who has like, for what it's worth,
Speaker 5:  the best algorithms when it comes to streaming and actually getting content
Speaker 5:  in front of people's eyes. and it just felt like, let's alleviate this
Speaker 5:  woman's anxieties by saying AI a bunch.
Speaker 2:  Sure.
Speaker 4:  And giving her many hundreds,
Speaker 5:  Six of
Speaker 4:  Millions more dollars. Yeah. That, that seems
Speaker 5:  Pretty, that probably helped. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, I would just remind you the listener, that these
Speaker 2:  are the things that people say when they buy studios.
Speaker 2:  Famously it's what at t said when I bought Warner Brothers. Yep. Which
Speaker 2:  again, provided the world, the four three Grayscale
Speaker 2:  Justice League.
Speaker 5:  Fine. We, yeah. We don't know what this is gonna look like for
Speaker 2:  What movies will David Ellison remaster as Square
Speaker 2:  in Gray Scale, I think is the only question. It's gonna be
Speaker 4:  Mission Top Impossible movie. It's gonna be six hours long.
Speaker 2:  Mission
Speaker 4:  Impossible. Dead Records Cruise is going to be black and white and square
Speaker 4:  and it's gonna be nuts.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, so this is like the big story in streaming. We haven't talked a lot
Speaker 2:  about it because it hadn't happened, but now it's happened and it, if the
Speaker 2:  deal closes and as Alex said, all these lawsuits get resolved,
Speaker 2:  I think we're, we're looking at a bunch of tech money and tech ideas
Speaker 2:  coming for the studio that famously owns Top Gun coming for CBS
Speaker 2:  coming for famously
Speaker 5:  On Star Trek.
Speaker 2:  Right. Famously on Star Trek. It's gonna be weird. There's,
Speaker 2:  there's a real weirdness coming for this zone because this is just a
Speaker 2:  flood of new money, but also just
Speaker 2:  the ideas that you would expect for the money to have. Yeah. But
Speaker 2:  dressed up in ever larger ambitions.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That that is exactly it. I I'm curious to see what they do. I'm curious
Speaker 5:  to see if they unload any of these properties and, and what kind of
Speaker 5:  like movies and shows. We actually start seeing if Taylor Sheridan gets the
Speaker 5:  boot.
Speaker 2:  I have been, by the way, Goog furiously googling for what studio in the cloud
Speaker 2:  means. and it, it's just a thing they say.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's called a data center. This is the thing. Like, it's like
Speaker 5:  Everybody already does
Speaker 4:  It. This means anything.
Speaker 5:  It's called working remote.
Speaker 4:  This is a rich guy who couldn't build a cool studio, buying
Speaker 4:  a cool studio. Like if I had the money to do it,
Speaker 4:  I would do it. Skydance is like cool, but not that cool. Paramount
Speaker 4:  is cooler.
Speaker 4:  The end,
Speaker 2:  The closest I've come to understanding what Student Cloud means is
Speaker 2:  it's a, it's like a square in the deck that just says Studio in the cloud
Speaker 2:  and it says Skydance animation is building a studio in the cloud. That's
Speaker 2:  the first bullet. Well, it's,
Speaker 5:  It's great. You turn on Slack.
Speaker 2:  The second bullet is transition from on-prem to
Speaker 2:  cloud-based production and hosting infrastructure, which is fine. That's
Speaker 2:  a thing. You know, dentist office across America are
Speaker 2:  switching from on-prem to cloud-based infrastructure. and it
Speaker 2:  feels like Oracle's just gonna get it $6 billion back because it turns
Speaker 2:  out they're building it with Oracle.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Okay. But does it it's gotta mean something.
Speaker 4:  Listen, NELI, we're we're like minutes away from you reading the Salesforce
Speaker 4:  website again and I can't have that in my life. We
Speaker 2:  Need to move on. Fine. Alright, Alex, you got a lot left in the lightning
Speaker 2:  round. What else?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean, what else do we got? Well, so Redbox, we, we had this great
Speaker 5:  story from, from Yanko last week that was all about friend
Speaker 5:  of The Verge about how Redbox was in dire straits
Speaker 5:  and why it was in dire straits and now it's shutting down its
Speaker 5:  parent company. Chicken Soup for the Soul Entertainment. Yeah, that's, that's
Speaker 5:  the real name of the
Speaker 2:  Company. This is the second time in several weeks the Chicken Soup for the
Speaker 2:  Soul has come up. Yeah. You'll recall that we looked at the Crackle website,
Speaker 2:  which is owned by Chicken Soup for the Soul.
Speaker 5:  We'll see. For how long?
Speaker 2:  For now? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  For now. Yeah. They, they got a new CEO last week and his job
Speaker 5:  is literally to come in and fix companies that are in dire straits. And for
Speaker 5:  chicken soup for the soul entertainment, that means red box is toast. and
Speaker 5:  it had already been really bad. A lot of folks probably if you, if you're
Speaker 5:  listening to this and you tried to go rent out a red box in the last couple
Speaker 5:  of months would struggle to get any, anything,
Speaker 5:  a lot of them have been shut down and, and now it's, it's done. RIP red
Speaker 5:  box.
Speaker 2:  So what, what's happening to all the DVDs in the red boxes today?
Speaker 5:  You just go and you break the box open and you take it
Speaker 2:  Sub looting. So Alex is like, do looting.
Speaker 5:  Well the prob the problem is that all of the technicians who, who,
Speaker 5:  who manage those things have all been grounded because all of their cars
Speaker 5:  are getting repossessed because Oh, that's brutal. They haven't been paying
Speaker 5:  the bills for the, the cars that they rent. So
Speaker 5:  like, come like Walgreens seven 11, everybody's just unplugging them
Speaker 5:  and I think you're just gonna start seeing more of these unplugged and just
Speaker 5:  sitting there. And I'm not saying you should loot them, but
Speaker 2:  That's it. That's where that ends. Yeah. Don't t 'em there's no but after,
Speaker 2:  I'm not saying you should loot them.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Just don't, don't do that.
Speaker 2:  I can hear the, the footsteps of the lawyers coming down the hallway right
Speaker 2:  now. Just ha
Speaker 5:  Ha where is she?
Speaker 2:  So do you think this is just straight up streaming killed Red box? Is this
Speaker 5:  That's where I'm at because like when you read Yoko's piece,
Speaker 5:  this all happened. The, like the big turning point for Red Box was when
Speaker 5:  in 2021 when everybody said we're gonna stop releasing
Speaker 5:  everything physically and putting it in theaters and we're just gonna do
Speaker 5:  it all wait to streaming. What
Speaker 4:  Was the other thing going on in 2021, Chris? You
Speaker 2:  Know? Yeah. But
Speaker 5:  But see that's the thing. If they had, if they had said like, there's a,
Speaker 5:  a lot of the people who are buying, who were renting these were in places
Speaker 5:  where they don't have streaming and they would also like to watch whatever
Speaker 5:  King Kong and Godzilla are getting up to in 2021. And
Speaker 5:  those just weren't coming out so they couldn't rent anything. So nobody was
Speaker 5:  renting from Redbox because none of the studios were releasing this stuff
Speaker 5:  physically.
Speaker 4:  Well, right. I but I think I I I think You can make a
Speaker 4:  extremely compelling argument that Covid killed Redbox more so
Speaker 4:  than You can make one that's streaming killed Redbox.
Speaker 5:  But no 'cause co how is Covid gonna do it? Everybody's at home anyway. These
Speaker 5:  things are outside. We didn't
Speaker 4:  Go outside for two years.
Speaker 5:  You still have to go to the grocery store where the red box
Speaker 2:  Is. So yeah, there was a, there was a red box at the CVS in the woods.
Speaker 2:  People, people gazed at it and then they thought, I don't have a
Speaker 2:  DVD player. It went home. I mean there is that. Well, and
Speaker 2:  and
Speaker 4:  Part of Red Box's thing was access for people who
Speaker 4:  didn't have great access to streaming either because it's expensive or because
Speaker 4:  they lived in places without great connection. Or like, there was a, there
Speaker 4:  was a real, this is a compliment to streaming or like a,
Speaker 4:  this is a, a thing you do when you can't do streaming. Not, this is a real
Speaker 4:  competitor to streaming. And so, Alex, to your point, I think as
Speaker 4:  fewer and fewer people didn't have streaming, it's probably true that
Speaker 4:  Redbox didn't fill that need for as many people.
Speaker 4:  But the problem for me is this is also just spectacular
Speaker 4:  corporate mismanagement. Oh, a hundred percent. This company took on a mountain
Speaker 4:  of debt to buy a company. It probably couldn't afford Chicken Soup for the
Speaker 4:  Soul. I think it was like $325 million in debt to buy Redbox
Speaker 4:  banking on. We're gonna make a ton of money back. 1D VD at a time made a
Speaker 4:  bunch of weird decisions and it all fell apart. So part of me is like, maybe
Speaker 4:  streaming killed Redbox, but I don't think we ever actually got to see streaming
Speaker 4:  killed Redbox because I think like Chicken Soup for the Soul killed Redbox.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Well Redbox was like not doing great when, when
Speaker 5:  Chicken Soup for the Soul bought it because it had just, it just done a spac
Speaker 5:  it it just gone public via spac Which
Speaker 2:  Wait, can we just,
Speaker 5:  Sorry.
Speaker 2:  There's, there's, there's like all of that. This company is called Chicken
Speaker 2:  Soup for the Soul Entertainment. Right? Like you already know,
Speaker 2:  like this started as a set of books for Live Laugh Love
Speaker 2:  moms. Right? And they're like, we're a media empire now. At
Speaker 2:  no point we
Speaker 5:  Like crowd funded media
Speaker 2:  Empire. We should change our name. Like you already know that. This is just
Speaker 2:  a bunch of weird, I like zombie media
Speaker 2:  zombie ideas. Like I'm
Speaker 4:  Glad you brought this up because does violate my theory that you can't
Speaker 4:  survive a bad name for your company. And Chicken Soup For the
Speaker 2:  Soul is
Speaker 5:  Entertainment. Please
Speaker 4:  Very much a bad name. Yeah, right. You Chicken Soup for the Soul Entertainment.
Speaker 4:  Thank
Speaker 2:  You. When did this book
Speaker 4:  Come out? People say the fact that I'm
Speaker 2:  Googling Chicken Soup for the Soul as a book is gonna be so bad for me.
Speaker 5:  So this is technically spun. They spun off from Chicken Soup for the Soul
Speaker 5:  for the books. 'cause that's like the book of publishing
Speaker 2:  Signs. They didn't even have the books yet.
Speaker 5:  They spun that off. This is a whole other company.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, this is the entertainment
Speaker 2:  Company. Oh, the books are Chicken Soup for the Soul. LLC
Speaker 2:  We gotta, I gotta end this also the worst website I've ever seen in my
Speaker 2:  entire life. But just that you can't survive a bad name,
Speaker 2:  especially when you're not even connected to the the Live Laugh love
Speaker 2:  books anymore.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You just out there buying companies for too much debt that are
Speaker 5:  already been half killed by Covid and streaming and thinking this'll work
Speaker 5:  and it didn't.
Speaker 2:  Can I say that the the book company has Chicken Soup for the Soul for Kids.
Speaker 2:  It's good. Okay. That's enough. Next lightning round item. Just if you start
Speaker 2:  a company, don't call it Chicken Soup for the Soul. Please don't, I think
Speaker 2:  is the,
Speaker 4:  That is probably the lesson.
Speaker 2:  And also if your entire company is distributing physical media, you,
Speaker 2:  you, you should have a plan B.
Speaker 4:  Well they did. They had a big long plan
Speaker 4:  for how to go digital with all of this. And Redbox has been trying to do
Speaker 4:  a streaming service for like 10 plus years.
Speaker 2:  Correct. But then you're just being being and never you're just, you're just
Speaker 2:  Netflix.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean that's what Paramount's trying to do and we didn't yell at them
Speaker 4:  for that. So.
Speaker 2:  Well I can't wait to see what chicken soups plan to cloud
Speaker 4:  Cloud is. Here's a new idea. Chicken
Speaker 2:  Soup in the cloud for the soul.
Speaker 4:  Larry Ellison buys Redbox. Do you think we're good
Speaker 2:  As, as long as they get off-Prem and I would point out that Red Box,
Speaker 2:  one of the single most on-prem businesses of all time,
Speaker 4:  Red Box in the cloud in so many PREMs. Think about it. What if a red box
Speaker 4:  put in the cloud?
Speaker 2:  All right, what's next Alex?
Speaker 5:  The next is, I'd never pause when I'm watching tv.
Speaker 5:  I learned because I don't get pause ads. Do you guys get those when you're
Speaker 5:  just watching a show and you're like, I gotta go to the bathroom. So you
Speaker 5:  pause it on Hulu,
Speaker 4:  Amazon Prime is the one I notice it on the most, but I think there are other
Speaker 4:  streaming services. Hulu
Speaker 5:  Does it. Who does it? Okay. It Sling TV is now doing it. That's the big news
Speaker 5:  this week. I was like, what is a pause ad? Oh, I'm
Speaker 5:  watching TV wrong is what I learned from all of this. But
Speaker 5:  basically pause ads happen when you pause something and then
Speaker 5:  it just decides to display an ad while you're going to the bathroom. Exactly
Speaker 2:  What I
Speaker 5:  Wanted. Exactly what you want. Sling TV is now doing it, but they also
Speaker 5:  have a little thing at the bottom saying You can go turn this off for how
Speaker 5:  much, which prime and for free, you just go to the settings and
Speaker 5:  turn it off. Which is different than what Prime and Hulu are doing.
Speaker 5:  So good on you Sling like bad on you Sling, but also good on you
Speaker 2:  Is more and more of these companies move into like ad tiers,
Speaker 2:  right? Pay money, but still have ads, which is what they all are now.
Speaker 2:  The desire to get more money is gonna result in more and more ads getting
Speaker 2:  more and more You can just see it coming. It's a tsunami of weird ideas and
Speaker 2:  they're just out of space. Like the goal,
Speaker 5:  When you think we get like a right rail of just ads,
Speaker 2:  Dude You can already get a free TV that is, that has a physical rail
Speaker 2:  of ads on it.
Speaker 4:  That's literally a thing. So I will say I think pause ads are
Speaker 4:  fine. Yeah. Like in, in terms of finding ways to show
Speaker 4:  giant ass ads on my TV in a way that is non interruptive. This is the best
Speaker 4:  one they've ever invented. Because it's like, if I'm pausing my
Speaker 4:  tv,
Speaker 4:  who cares? Like what, what do I wanna see on the tv? It's do I care if it's
Speaker 4:  a frozen like ha moving shot of someone's face
Speaker 4:  or if it's like a Toyota ad, I don't care.
Speaker 5:  I think it's like
Speaker 4:  Fine, it's, I'm getting up to leave the room anyway. Like that's why I paused
Speaker 4:  the joke. I think it's
Speaker 5:  Like when you're having like a phone call, right? Like somebody calls you,
Speaker 5:  you're like, oh, I need a pause. And then it's like Toyota Chandra,
Speaker 2:  Is it gonna wait, it's gonna play a video or
Speaker 4:  Is it gonna, there's sound I feel very differently.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, these are,
Speaker 4:  Most of the Amazon ones at least are just like a static image that is just
Speaker 4:  like you, you press pause of Mr and Mrs. Smith and a thing pops up that's
Speaker 4:  just like Jeep
Speaker 2:  And
Speaker 4:  Then just freezes for as long as you need it to. And I think that's fine.
Speaker 4:  You know what I hate, I'm just gonna complain about ads for a minute here
Speaker 4:  and then we can move on. I love this thing is, there's now a thing that happens
Speaker 4:  on Hulu and probably some others, but I noticed that the most on Hulu where
Speaker 4:  at the beginning of a show it will ask you to choose your ad experience.
Speaker 4:  It's like, which Charmin ad would you like to watch? None
Speaker 4:  of, and you've gotten to the point now where Anna, my wife, will sit there
Speaker 4:  and yell at the tv, I don't care. And I'm always like, Anna, that doesn't
Speaker 4:  accomplish anything. And she's like, but I don't care. And and it'll like
Speaker 4:  linger there for 10 seconds then if you don't it do anything it'll just choose
Speaker 4:  for you and then play the whole ad anyway. And I'm like, no, if you're gonna
Speaker 4:  make me watch ads, you pick, don't make me do the work to pick my
Speaker 4:  own ads.
Speaker 5:  I I agree with that.
Speaker 4:  Use your damn algorithms and show me the ads. We can't
Speaker 2:  Use AI to collect more data about you unless you generate more data. David,
Speaker 4:  Apparently
Speaker 2:  It costs money to go from on-prem to the cloud
Speaker 4:  Drives me nuts. But if I, if I could choose between like
Speaker 4:  in, in like dynamic interstitial ads and pause ads, give me pause ads
Speaker 4:  every time. The problem is it's both and it's gonna be a bunch of other stuff
Speaker 4:  too. Yeah, and
Speaker 2:  They're, they're just gonna send you that way. Like it's, it's coming. All
Speaker 2:  right. One more.
Speaker 5:  Oh,
Speaker 2:  In the streaming lightning round.
Speaker 5:  Do you wanna
Speaker 2:  Talk about, I think we got it. Well actually lemme do it. I'll do it this
Speaker 2:  way. Okay. All right. I, I want to call out one more that isn't
Speaker 2:  technically streaming, but I think is really interesting for our lightning
Speaker 2:  round of video over the internet, which is Adam Ary who runs
Speaker 2:  Instagram, put out a video this week where he is like, I just wanna make
Speaker 2:  it clear we're ne we're not gonna do long form video, which is interesting
Speaker 2:  for a number of reasons. One, he was like, the whole point of Instagram is
Speaker 2:  connect you to your friends. So when you like open a friend's video and then
Speaker 2:  you're like in reels by accident and then you're in reels by accident for
Speaker 2:  two hours, he's like, that's great. That's what we want. Because you are
Speaker 2:  more likely to share a short video with your friend and then they'll watch
Speaker 2:  it and they'll, they'll end up in the we the reels rabbit hole and they'll
Speaker 2:  share some videos and he is like, that's great long videos you won't
Speaker 2:  watch all the way through and you definitely won't share them. And they apparently
Speaker 2:  measure this and they know this. He calls it a symbiotic relationship between
Speaker 2:  connecting your friends and short videos, which is interesting on its face.
Speaker 2:  The second thing that's interesting is that Instagram has super tried to
Speaker 2:  do long form video and compete with YouTube. Before it was called IGTV,
Speaker 4:  I went to the IGTV launch. It was one of the weirdest days of my entire life.
Speaker 2:  And this is the previous administration of Instagram. This is not Myer's
Speaker 2:  Instagram, this is like the previous leaders of Instagram. But they tried,
Speaker 2:  they were like, oh, we'll just be YouTube now. And they utterly failed.
Speaker 2:  And now they, they, you know, they were like, we'll be TikTok now. And they've
Speaker 2:  succeeded. And TikTok is like, we'll be YouTube now. And I
Speaker 2:  dunno how that's going, but it's interesting to see Instagram be like, huh,
Speaker 2:  no, when in fact all of these streamers have to compete with
Speaker 2:  reels and YouTube and like YouTube is growing fastest on TVs
Speaker 2:  actually. So it's interesting to see all of this other action happening
Speaker 2:  and then Missa being like, no, we're gonna, we're staying right here. Short
Speaker 2:  form video.
Speaker 4:  I think it's the right call. And I will say the, the thing you're describing
Speaker 4:  that that like symbiotic thing makes perfect sense to me and anecdotally
Speaker 4:  feels true, right? That like the idea that I'm a going to sit
Speaker 4:  here and watch one single 30 minute video
Speaker 4:  on Instagram and it
Speaker 2:  Send it to a friend,
Speaker 4:  Right? It just feels preposterous. Right? And I think like, I think all the
Speaker 4:  time about, like, when you talk to people about the, the act that you do
Speaker 4:  on TikTok, it's scrolling, it's not viewing, like the thing that
Speaker 4:  you do on TikTok is flip channels that is more important than what is actually
Speaker 4:  on the screen that you're viewing. It's, it's the activity that is the thing,
Speaker 4:  which is what's different from like TV or even
Speaker 4:  YouTube, which is less of a scrolling thing, but YouTube is becoming more
Speaker 4:  scrolly with shorts and stuff like that. Instagram is, has always been scrolly.
Speaker 4:  And I think trying to undo that and be like, this is now a destination
Speaker 4:  that you're gonna spend a half hour at a time without touching your screen,
Speaker 4:  I think was just never gonna happen. It's also like a much harder thing to
Speaker 4:  sell ads against, which is I think a reason. It makes a lot of sense. It's
Speaker 4:  really easy to sell ads that are a video between two other videos that you're
Speaker 4:  scrolling on. And this, this just feels, this feels very obvious
Speaker 4:  to me except that these companies usually can't help themselves from all
Speaker 4:  trying to be each other. So to hear Adam just kosh it entirely was
Speaker 4:  pretty
Speaker 2:  Interesting. It's also funny 'cause it's the money, like YouTube makes a
Speaker 2:  lot of money and they're like, we're not gonna make that money. Which is
Speaker 2:  super, like YouTube just has no competition. It is the place for
Speaker 2:  long form video on the internet, which is weird. Well, it's
Speaker 5:  A place for independent long form video, right? Like, like it is
Speaker 5:  effectively the VHS tape of, of the modern era where
Speaker 5:  it's just like, hey, or cable access. It's just like, Hey, I need a platform.
Speaker 5:  I don't wanna go make a deal with David Ellison. This is what I do.
Speaker 5:  I put it, I just put it on YouTube. Like functionally, that's what YouTube
Speaker 5:  is becoming. And and it's getting more and more like that even though
Speaker 5:  it's UI and stuff isn't like that. And I think it makes sense.
Speaker 2:  Well, right, but a really weird thing is that You can just like rent paramount
Speaker 2:  movies on YouTube. Yes. No one does it, but You can just be like, I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  rent Mission Impossible. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  You can
Speaker 4:  You You can subscribe to streaming services through YouTube. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  You could watch movies on cable access in in in olden times too.
Speaker 5:  Like, and I think Instagram to me is more like, now I'm gonna go
Speaker 5:  just completely switch up the analogy and, and say that
Speaker 5:  Instagram is kind of like the drive through Margarita bars.
Speaker 5:  I don't know if you, I've, they're in Texas and they rule
Speaker 4:  I was gonna say that I I gotta move to Texas.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's, that sounds awesome. You see those in Louisiana and Texas and
Speaker 5:  it's like, yeah, you drive through, you get your, your beautiful treat, you
Speaker 5:  drive home, you have, it's like bam, bam, you're done. and
Speaker 5:  it feels like long form video is like, what if we did fine dining at the
Speaker 5:  drive through Margarita bar?
Speaker 4:  So it's like, I don't want that. What if you went to Sonic but your meal
Speaker 4:  was a hundred dollars? And it's like, that's not, that's not, we're looking
Speaker 2:  For you isn't the plot of the bear. I just,
Speaker 5:  They still serve the sandwiches out the side window
Speaker 2:  Just isn't that the bear People love the bear
Speaker 5:  Instagram. You could be the bear.
Speaker 2:  All right, that is where we need to end this entire
Speaker 2:  look. If you know the people who run Chicken Soup for the Soul Entertainment,
Speaker 2:  bring 'em to us. We, I have a, I have a number of questions. What kind of
Speaker 2:  zombies are they? All right, that's it. We gotta take a break. We'll be back
Speaker 2:  with the actual lightning round.
Speaker 1:  Have a question or need how to advice. Just ask meta
Speaker 1:  AI whether you want to design a marathon training program that will get you
Speaker 1:  race ready for the fall. Or you're curious what planets are visible in tonight's
Speaker 1:  sky. Meta AI has the answers. Perhaps
Speaker 1:  you want to learn how to plant basil when your garden only gets indirect
Speaker 1:  sunlight. Meta AI is your intelligent assistant. It
Speaker 1:  can even answer your follow-up questions like what You can make with your
Speaker 1:  basil and other ingredients you have in your fridge. Meta AI
Speaker 1:  can also summarize your class notes, visualize your ideas and so
Speaker 1:  much more. The best part is You can find meta ai right in the apps
Speaker 1:  you already have Instagram, WhatsApp, Facebook,
Speaker 1:  and Messenger. Just tag meta AI in your chat or
Speaker 1:  tap the icon in the search bar to get started. It's the
Speaker 1:  most advanced AI at your fingertips.
Speaker 1:  Expand your world with meta ai.
Speaker 4:  new smartwatch. And I would say by far, most interestingly,
Speaker 4:  a new phone called the s CMF Phone one. It's
Speaker 4:  $199 Android phone that
Speaker 4:  basically lets you replace the back of the phone with
Speaker 4:  a couple of different accessories and different colors or add like a
Speaker 4:  lanyard. What's the other one? A wallet You can put on? And I think there's
Speaker 4:  one that's a kickstand that You can just stick on through an accessory
Speaker 4:  port.
Speaker 4:  By all accounts, it's kind of a like mid rangey Android phone, but it looks
Speaker 4:  awesome. It's orange, it's 200 bucks. And this is for some
Speaker 4:  reason the Android phone I have been most excited about in a very long time.
Speaker 4:  Like nothing is out there being like, we're gonna make tech more fun again.
Speaker 4:  This is the most
Speaker 4:  interesting thing in that mold that I think nothing has ever done.
Speaker 4:  And it's a $200 Android phone and I'm very excited about it. Like it rules.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, just like what if, what if we tried new things? Right?
Speaker 4:  I I really spending all that time with the books Palmer has gotten me like
Speaker 4:  obsessed with this idea that what if you took a phone and just tweaked two
Speaker 4:  things about it. Like what this, if we, if we take this form factor we're
Speaker 4:  all obsessed with and just turned it a little, can you change that? And that
Speaker 4:  one of those is like, what if the screen folded? One of them is like, what
Speaker 4:  if it was the ink? And one of them, like, I've been obsessed with modular
Speaker 4:  phone ideas for forever and I I really continue to think there is something
Speaker 4:  to like, what if you could make your phone several different things
Speaker 4:  o over time. And this is such a cool version of that. And they did
Speaker 4:  a really like IKEA ish thing here where it has some like
Speaker 4:  exposed screws and You can actually open up the back of your phone and see
Speaker 4:  the inside of your phone. It's just, it's just seems fun. And again, it's
Speaker 4:  like, it's a, it's $200 like yes, more of this please.
Speaker 2:  It's weird because what you want is, what you would expect is that the phone
Speaker 2:  parts of the phone, 15 years into phones
Speaker 2:  more would be a commodity by now, right? Like
Speaker 2:  an Android phone should just be a commodity and then the way it looks and
Speaker 2:  works and feels in your hand and it, that just hasn't played out for, for
Speaker 2:  a million reasons because of carriers 'cause of competition. Because Google
Speaker 2:  what, whatever it is,
Speaker 2:  EIMS like whatever you think has restricted this market, right? From being
Speaker 2:  competitive and the android part, it's
Speaker 4:  Happened with Android parts, like with the other parts of Android
Speaker 4:  phones, like yeah, cameras that go into Android phones are now everywhere.
Speaker 4:  The sensors are everywhere. Android runs everything. But like the phone thing,
Speaker 4:  that hasn't happened. You're totally right.
Speaker 2:  Well, at at least the United States we're gonna, yeah, we're gonna have listeners
Speaker 2:  in other countries, particularly like India and China, who'll be like, no,
Speaker 2:  this, this is pretty competitive out here. Yeah. But it, this
Speaker 2:  is like one of those things where it's like, oh, if only we had a little
Speaker 2:  competition, we'd have way more ideas like this. Yep. It is cool. I'm
Speaker 2:  assuming that it is a very slow phone because it's 200.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But I, like, I, I saw a bunch of reactions from people that
Speaker 4:  were like, they, people were ask, I got a bunch of people asking me like,
Speaker 4:  is this a good reading device? 'cause it has a, it has an OLED screen, it
Speaker 4:  has a, I think 5,000 million battery, which should last a while.
Speaker 4:  It'll run Android apps. And then I saw a bunch of people who were like, this
Speaker 4:  is gonna be a kick ass gaming handheld. And to me it's like, this
Speaker 4:  is, this is the stuff, right? Like we don't, what if we didn't have one device
Speaker 4:  that we demanded to do everything, but instead we could just buy these
Speaker 4:  things that are $200 and actually just like, sort of push them
Speaker 4:  towards one use case or another. And instead it's like an overlapping Venn
Speaker 4:  diagram of things that look like phones. And I think that's super fun. I
Speaker 4:  like that more. I'm gonna buy the hell out of this thing. But also the
Speaker 4:  earbuds and the watch also both look pretty cool. And the earbuds in
Speaker 4:  particular, I think the little dial. Yeah, really great.
Speaker 4:  Like total, I love a little pointless fidget spinner of a dial on a case.
Speaker 4:  Like good job CMF and the ones last year,
Speaker 4:  if I remember correctly, were better than we expected
Speaker 4:  for something pretty cheap. I think these are like, these are,
Speaker 4:  yeah, $59, they're cheap. And for a pair of kind of
Speaker 4:  AirPods e looking things,
Speaker 4:  by all accounts, they've sounded pretty good in the past. So I'm, I'm pretty
Speaker 4:  optimistic here. I'm very excited.
Speaker 5:  I will say it was surprising to me that this week we got two kind of
Speaker 5:  AirPod knockoffs and nothing was the one that didn't have
Speaker 5:  LEDs in it.
Speaker 2:  That's surprise me. You're gonna change AirPods. What's the first thing to
Speaker 2:  do? You had LEDs? Yeah. All right. I'll do mine quick and then Kranz should
Speaker 2:  ends with yours. 'cause yours, you should end on outrage basically. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So I'll, I'll just pick one. I, I had two, but I'll just pick one. You know,
Speaker 2:  we're paying a lot of attention to AI and copyright, like, I think it's
Speaker 2:  kind of asset cards and there's lots and lots of lawsuits. Sarah Silverman
Speaker 2:  is suing ai, AI companies. There's the, the record
Speaker 2:  labels are suing Suo uio, which are AI companies. The
Speaker 2:  New York Times are suing Open ai, on and on and on. The one that
Speaker 2:  I thought was really interesting and kind of like a long shot was a bunch
Speaker 2:  of developers sued over GitHub copilot
Speaker 2:  because it can obviously spit out code. And this is like the main thing that
Speaker 2:  people have been excited about with ai. Most of their claims got tossed out
Speaker 2:  this week except for the one that said they're violating the open source
Speaker 2:  licenses, which is a really weird circle.
Speaker 2:  So they're like, look, the GitHub copilot can just spit out code. They trained
Speaker 2:  on a bunch of our code. They didn't have the copyright to that code. That
Speaker 2:  code is copyrighted and that's copyright infringement. Like,
Speaker 2:  pretty straightforward. The judge was like, none of that makes any sense.
Speaker 2:  This isn't what's really happening. Interesting precedent. And then they
Speaker 2:  said, but it is true that there were software licenses
Speaker 2:  for that code open source software licenses. They didn't abide by them. 'cause
Speaker 2:  the, the code they spit out should have those same licenses. That's how open
Speaker 2:  source licenses work. So now we might have a weird open source legal battle
Speaker 2:  over AI and not a copyright legal battle over ai, which is equally
Speaker 2:  weird because all of those open source licenses absolutely
Speaker 2:  depend on copyright law because that's what they are, they're licenses to
Speaker 2:  copyright work, right? So there's just this weird knot of weird of like
Speaker 2:  copyright law problems happening with this one case.
Speaker 2:  And if you're a really optimistic AI person, you say, look, it was fair use.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like all these games have thrown out. If you're very negative, you
Speaker 2:  say, well that was just a weird one. And the, the big ones to come
Speaker 2:  are still going to define how this whole industry survives or thrives.
Speaker 2:  Does
Speaker 4:  It feel like that's where all of this is headed? That we're, we're starting
Speaker 4:  with we're of a hundred different versions of the same fight and what
Speaker 4:  we're gonna end up with is like two of the most consequential ones and then
Speaker 4:  that will percolate out. 'cause it does feel like, I mean we've talked a
Speaker 4:  lot about a lot of these lawsuits and they're all different, but they're
Speaker 4:  all also kind of the same. And you wonder if we're gonna get
Speaker 4:  to a point where everybody decides like, okay, let's, let's figure out what
Speaker 4:  we're actually fighting about and then fight about that instead of fighting
Speaker 4:  about like a hundred variations of that thing.
Speaker 2:  Well this is America Jack.
Speaker 2:  Like no, it's gonna just be chaos. Like yeah, okay. That's, that's the way
Speaker 2:  our system is designed to work is like there isn't yet
Speaker 2:  a King of America.
Speaker 4:  I mean there is now. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Soon. Soon there might be.
Speaker 2:  But the, the notion that there is just some definitive answer or that
Speaker 2:  everyone will quit their whining so the New York Times can get to
Speaker 2:  like, it's not gonna happen. So what you're gonna get is this like mishmash
Speaker 2:  of precedence until Congress passes a law that unifies all
Speaker 2:  these precedents into like a regulatory framework. Seems unlikely. Or
Speaker 2:  there's a Supreme Court case that I dunno, throws out 50 years
Speaker 2:  of precedent for no reason. That's, they, they love doing that and you
Speaker 2:  just have to like work through the process, but in the meantime, everyone's
Speaker 2:  just gonna take their shots. And I think one of the things that's interesting
Speaker 2:  is like there are so many shots and they're all kind of weird,
Speaker 2:  right? They're all just like picking off at the edges. But again, I've been
Speaker 2:  saying it like only one has to like go through for the bottom to fall out
Speaker 2:  and these companies have to pay. And the thing you're saying is that they're
Speaker 2:  all kind of the same case. It's all the same argument. You took our stuff
Speaker 2:  without permission. Whether or not you need that permission is like
Speaker 2:  the thing that makes the internet go in like the realist
Speaker 2:  way. And so if you change the boundaries of what you need permission
Speaker 2:  for to use or reuse or remix or sample or whatever, you kind
Speaker 2:  of change the economy. Like the whole economy changes around it.
Speaker 2:  Which is why it's kind of wacky that it's just a bunch of shots. Like who
Speaker 2:  knows? Yeah. But this one in particular is interesting 'cause it's gonna
Speaker 2:  end up being an open source contract case. And we haven't had one
Speaker 2:  of those in a very long time.
Speaker 2:  Okay. That was fine. Alex. I bring us home with some pure outrage. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Some pure outrage. So do you guys remember the, what is
Speaker 5:  it, the unofficial Apple web log?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. ua I used to work, I worked at Engadget and they were our sister site.
Speaker 2:  They were
Speaker 5:  Your sister site. Oh yeah. UA was like old school. One of the original Apple
Speaker 5:  blogs used to love reading it. One of my best friends used to
Speaker 5:  work there. One of my best friends got very upset this week because
Speaker 5:  Christina Warren, former, former, she works at GitHub now
Speaker 5:  and she was suddenly writing it to again,
Speaker 5:  she herself wasn't, her byline was appearing at Tua of
Speaker 5:  just next to a bunch of like clearly AI written schlock. And
Speaker 5:  she wasn't the only one. A lot of former reporters from Tua had
Speaker 5:  their bylines appear on the site because earlier this year it
Speaker 5:  seems to have been acquired from Apollo. It it left the Yahoo
Speaker 5:  land for Apollo and, and then Apollo seemed to have sold
Speaker 5:  it to someone else. And that someone else who we still don't entirely know
Speaker 5:  who they are or what they do, were just filling
Speaker 5:  up, filling up this empty blog with content. And allegedly
Speaker 5:  like the, the explanation that they had on their site was on
Speaker 5:  the two oh site was, yeah, we, we don't have any of this content. So we're
Speaker 5:  replicating it with ai so we don't lose these important archives.
Speaker 5:  That's not how archiving works.
Speaker 2:  It's very good, by the way. It's a very good, like what if I made some stuff
Speaker 2:  up? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Just full stop. That's not how any of that works. Nope. People were very
Speaker 5:  upset. Christina Warren was, was among them and she reached out
Speaker 5:  and, and they, they promptly changed the name of her
Speaker 5:  character and changed the, the headshot. So it was no longer her.
Speaker 5:  And it's just a big bummer in the world. It's just a bummer
Speaker 5:  that sites are getting picked up and just filled with AI
Speaker 5:  garbage. I think it is particularly a bummer for those of us who've worked
Speaker 5:  at a lot of these smaller sites and stuff. Who, who
Speaker 5:  knows where my byline could appear next. I'm excited to find
Speaker 5:  out.
Speaker 4:  This is like Google ha did earlier
Speaker 4:  this year, a thing Google normally doesn't do, which is come out and
Speaker 4:  basically say aggressively and clearly
Speaker 4:  that it was making changes to its search algorithm such that this is no
Speaker 4:  longer a good idea. Yeah. Right? 'cause the reason you do this is you, you
Speaker 4:  buy a domain that has real authority in the
Speaker 4:  hopes that it will still rank in Google. You fill it with nonsense. That
Speaker 4:  nonsense ranks well on Google. You sell a bunch of ads, you make some money.
Speaker 4:  It it does work. Like it is, it is a strategy. It's not necessarily a
Speaker 4:  long term.
Speaker 5:  It's a strategy for like half of media online.
Speaker 4:  Right. and it, and it, and it works. And Google has been saying
Speaker 4:  aggressively that it is trying to prevent this from working. And yet it
Speaker 4:  pretty clearly seems to continue to work.
Speaker 5:  I I, I just don't know when Google's gonna be able to do that because this
Speaker 5:  has been like the, the only difference here is the scale of crappy content.
Speaker 5:  Like somebody would've done this without AI as well, right? They would've
Speaker 5:  hired a bunch of people with no name and said, just write a bunch of content,
Speaker 5:  put it on the site. We've seen that happen before. Sure. I think IBT was
Speaker 5:  an example of that. And in this case it happened to be a
Speaker 5:  ai it happened to be this early Apple blog full of like,
Speaker 5:  well-known tech bloggers. And that's just a
Speaker 5:  terrible, terrible move to make in that case.
Speaker 5:  Don't do that. You wanna choose like better homes and Gardens? No,
Speaker 5:  they're still around. They're
Speaker 2:  Still around.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But you know, you wanna choose something maybe not tech adjacent to
Speaker 5:  do this with, if you're gonna be gross. It,
Speaker 4:  It was a weird choice to do it on an Apple blog. Yeah, I will. I I
Speaker 4:  will agree with that. But this is the thing, like MTO on our team wrote this
Speaker 4:  great piece this week about Yeah. The guy behind, I think the company is
Speaker 4:  it called Aon, I think is the name of the company,
Speaker 4:  which is the one that did a lot of the AI stuff that became a huge
Speaker 4:  mess at Sports Illustrated like this. The internet is so quickly
Speaker 4:  becoming this, and I've been thinking a lot about this, like after the
Speaker 4:  MTV archives went away and the Comedy Central archives went away, like speaking
Speaker 4:  of two websites that a lot of people know and trust and would believe if
Speaker 4:  someone bought them and filled them with spam nonsense. Like there's just
Speaker 4:  going to be such a long run of this and it's,
Speaker 4:  it's gonna get weirder before it gets normalized in
Speaker 4:  whatever way it's gonna look like.
Speaker 2:  To be clear, I don't think Google can stop it.
Speaker 5:  I Yeah, I don't think they can. There I
Speaker 2:  And I it's not, and that's not because of antipathy towards Google. I think
Speaker 2:  the problem is so hard and then
Speaker 2:  the internal philosophical reckoning for Google is
Speaker 2:  even harder. So the problem is you have to say a
Speaker 2:  bunch of AI generated sludge is bad. Yes. Right? We're gonna
Speaker 2:  not rank it
Speaker 4:  Sludge that you're charging people $20 a month per person to make. Right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So you're like, okay, like you, you just, there are two
Speaker 2:  wolves, you know, it's like, what are you gonna do? Like you have to
Speaker 2:  say the output of your own models is bad at some point. Like, that is the
Speaker 2:  task ahead of the search team. And I don't know that they can reckon
Speaker 2:  with it fully. Like,
Speaker 4:  We'll see. Well, and let's be real, like what are Google's AI overviews for
Speaker 4:  web searches, if not more or less exactly the same thing. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. We'll see, they, by the way I've been, the overviews have been,
Speaker 2:  they're still, some of them are still very bad. They're also moving them
Speaker 2:  around the page. I dunno if you've noticed this. I have not. They've, they're
Speaker 2:  moving all over the page. Sometimes they're at the top, sometimes they're
Speaker 2:  in the middle, sometimes they're at the bottom. Like they're still doing
Speaker 2:  'em. But they are, they haven't figured out where they go or when they
Speaker 2:  should appear or how they should look. And then one of them, David
Speaker 2:  ml from MKBH D's team and
Speaker 2:  Waveform and everything else, he, he posted
Speaker 2:  that the answer to like, how do you check the film in your camera is getting
Speaker 2:  like much worse. Oh no. Yeah. So it was like, how do you see if there's film
Speaker 2:  in, in some model of film camera and AI overview is just like, open
Speaker 2:  it up in bright sunlight. Yeah. Serious. Like it said serious in bright sunlight.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Oh my God. And he found it on in some red thread, but it's like crazy.
Speaker 2:  It's like, I mean, it would work. What is going on?
Speaker 5:  You wouldn't know afterwards if the film camera, if the camera Yeah,
Speaker 4:  You would That is true. This is
Speaker 5:  Exposed,
Speaker 2:  This is what happens when you're like, the future of of all intelligence
Speaker 2:  is Reddit. It's like, is it? Yeah. All right. That's it. We've
Speaker 2:  we're way over. We're way over. Look,
Speaker 2:  they're all, everything's gonna look like AirPods and then the robots are
Speaker 2:  gonna tell you to do dumb shit to your cameras. That's the future. I'm excited
Speaker 2:  for it. Here at The Verge, we know what we're gonna write about. All right.
Speaker 2:  That's it. That's The Vergecast Rock and roll.
Speaker 9:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 9:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one. One. The Vergecast is the
Speaker 9:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 9:  by Andrew Moreno and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.
Speaker 1:  Have a question or need how to advice, just ask meta AI
Speaker 1:  whether you want to design a marathon training program or you're curious
Speaker 1:  what planets are visible in tonight's sky. Meta AI has the
Speaker 1:  answers. It can also summarize your class notes, visualize your
Speaker 1:  ideas, and so much more. It's the most advanced AI
Speaker 1:  at your fingertips. Expand your world with meta ai.
Speaker 1:  Now on Instagram, WhatsApp, Facebook, and Messenger.