# Transcript
ID: fac8751d-baaa-4631-b098-41f0da86c2ec
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1847393804688015630/-1407792115617416953/s93290-US-5495s-1721994830.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Jake Kastrenakes discuss OpenAI's new SearchGPT product, Amazon's plan to launch a paid version of Alexa, the Samsung Galaxy Z Fold review, and whole lot more.
Speaker 3:  Verge for like 15,
Speaker 5:  Something like that. Yeah, I, I don't, we didn't exist technically 15 years
Speaker 5:  ago, but emotionally I was here back in those days.
Speaker 4:  It's always been here.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I see. In this office it was empty.
Speaker 3:  Just
Speaker 5:  Waiting. Yeah. Financial district was different back then, but
Speaker 3:  Our office used to be the Goldman Sachs building. So this is your fault.
Speaker 5:  I I have a lot to apologize for.
Speaker 3:  This is, that's true story.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  The ghosts of of finance bros haunt us every day in this
Speaker 3:  office. Anyhow, Jake, you don't know this, but last week on the show
Speaker 3:  we were discussing the iPad and David outta nowhere
Speaker 3:  just fired astray and said he didn't believe pilots used iPad
Speaker 3:  minis on planes. And I, I dunno
Speaker 3:  man, he was wrong. David, would you like to defend yourself? So
Speaker 4:  First I would, or apologize,
Speaker 5:  I'm need you to issue a correction here. I would
Speaker 4:  Like, I was miscategorized by Neela Patel's just now what I said
Speaker 4:  was this is like the canonical real
Speaker 4:  world use case for iPads that if you, if you ask anyone
Speaker 4:  at or around Apple about like what is a thing people do with an
Speaker 4:  iPad, they all just want to tell you about Delta pilots. And so why
Speaker 3:  Specifically I've iPad Mini. Yes
Speaker 4:  The iPad Mini, which apparently like, you know, pilots strapped to their
Speaker 4:  leg and do stuff with terrific. I simply,
Speaker 5:  Sorry, tell me about the leg.
Speaker 3:  'cause you're flying a plane. So where are you gonna put the screen?
Speaker 4:  Wait, it's right there. It's a, it's a
Speaker 5:  Right because have they have the entire console of physical buttons?
Speaker 3:  Well no those are mostly not screens as well. We're gonna
Speaker 5:  So my apologies.
Speaker 3:  They're gonna come for you. YouTube. No, this good. You need to be careful.
Speaker 4:  This is good Email Jake and not me.
Speaker 5:  This is why I'm not on the show for five
Speaker 4:  Years with a list of every button on a plane. That's, that's important. Please
Speaker 3:  Do that. I would, I would like to apologize to the entire aviation community
Speaker 3:  at this time.
Speaker 4:  So Nobert,
Speaker 3:  I'm on your team. And, if you can get me into an F 22,
Speaker 3:  I think that would be great.
Speaker 4:  So what I actually heard, which was very cool, is that there
Speaker 4:  is a lot of iPad usage specifically on planes and I heard from
Speaker 4:  commercial pilots, I heard from hobbyist pilots like the whole gamut
Speaker 4:  and there are a lot of uses for it. But it seems like the number one
Speaker 4:  main one is just that flying involves both a lot of
Speaker 4:  paperwork and a lot of reference material. And to take it from a giant
Speaker 4:  like binder in a rolling suitcase down to an iPad makes a lot of people
Speaker 4:  very happy. I heard from a few people that they're now like using them in
Speaker 4:  flight schools. So when you're training to get your pilot license, you actually
Speaker 4:  like are given an iPad in the way that like kids are given a Chromebook.
Speaker 4:  It's just part of the process now and a lot of people take it through. So
Speaker 4:  I, I didn't know and now I know it is apparently a very real
Speaker 4:  thing
Speaker 3:  And that's why the iPad been exists. They
Speaker 4:  Actually, I just took my iPad mini to an airport and they just gave me
Speaker 4:  a pilot license. It was the most insane thing. I just fly
Speaker 3:  Now America Skies are no longer safe. Alright, there's a lot of
Speaker 3:  news this week beyond David and the pilots. As we sat down in the studio
Speaker 3:  opening, it launched search GPT, it's direct competitor
Speaker 3:  to to Google and interestingly Bing, which runs an opening,
Speaker 3:  it's a lot, we gotta talk about that. There's a bunch of gadgets, there's
Speaker 3:  a lot of news about what Amazon is doing with Alexa to talk about.
Speaker 3:  Boy that's been a long time that Amazon's been trying to figure out Alexa
Speaker 3:  and then we got a lightning round un unsponsored. But Jake is here so Jake
Speaker 3:  will be the sponsor of lighting around. Welcome Jake.
Speaker 4:  Thanks for
Speaker 3:  Having me. Yeah. Alright, let's start with search TBT. It is
Speaker 3:  the news. It is the big news. It's the thing that everyone saw coming that
Speaker 3:  might actually shake up the search market. There's other stuff
Speaker 3:  happening underneath it that is interesting like the, the web is
Speaker 3:  being re-architected and we can talk about the deals Google and Reddit are
Speaker 3:  making. But we should just start with search GPT. David, what is going on
Speaker 3:  here?
Speaker 4:  I guess the best way to describe search GPT is as
Speaker 4:  chat GPT. But instead of returning text that it
Speaker 4:  pulls from the internet, it returns text that it pulls from the internet
Speaker 4:  but with slightly more citations. We don't know that much.
Speaker 4:  OpenAI basically put out a, a simple blog post with a
Speaker 4:  couple of pictures. There's a text box that says what are you looking for?
Speaker 4:  And a search GPT icon. and it will, it will attempt
Speaker 4:  to kind of return links to you when you ask a
Speaker 4:  question but also kind of make sense of them in the process. So it seems
Speaker 4:  like it's gonna do some work on like the order in which they appear and trying
Speaker 4:  to kind of tell a story with the links instead of just returning a bunch
Speaker 4:  of links in a row. OpenAI is being very
Speaker 4:  slow about this. I guess it's, I think it's gonna be open to, what was it,
Speaker 4:  10,000 users at first? Yeah. They're calling it a prototype, like
Speaker 4:  really trying to sort of slow play this thing. But we've been talking about
Speaker 4:  you know, the media deals that OpenAI has been making with our parent company,
Speaker 4:  Vox Media and The Atlantic and lots of others. We've been talking about the
Speaker 4:  ways that which OpenAI is like crawling the web and taking
Speaker 4:  data and the all these fights over whether that is a copyright. Like all
Speaker 4:  of that I think in so many ways is actually building up to this like yes
Speaker 4:  O Chad, GPTI still believe this they opening, I
Speaker 4:  won't say it anymore because it got too popular but I sincerely believe that
Speaker 4:  chat GPT was never meant to be the thing. And I think as you
Speaker 4:  look at like the actual products OpenAI wants to build, I think it looks
Speaker 4:  a lot more like search GPT than chat GPT. And I think
Speaker 4:  like we've been building towards this for a very long time.
Speaker 3:  Wait, I I disagree with you in the most minor of ways.
Speaker 4:  Okay.
Speaker 3:  What OpenAI says it wants to build is a world conquering a GI that will put
Speaker 3:  a solid of work and let Sam Waltman live a life of endless luxury.
Speaker 4:  Sure. And he keeps writing op-ed saying it's super fine, don't even worry
Speaker 4:  about
Speaker 3:  It's fair. So that's the goal. I'll give you just to be clear, their goal
Speaker 3:  is like what if a robot did everything? Yes. And you lived in a cave running
Speaker 3:  on a treadmill powering the robot and like f fine. You know,
Speaker 3:  maybe LLMs will get there, maybe they won't. I think they won't. But it's
Speaker 3:  like that's the big goal. Yes. The medium goal is how the hell do we
Speaker 3:  make any money? Which they have basically failed to do. There's some reporting
Speaker 3:  out there, they're in a much more tenuous financial position than they let
Speaker 3:  on, they've obviously have taken on a ton of money. They use a ton of
Speaker 3:  Azure compute all this stuff. And so you gotta make some money in
Speaker 3:  chat PD at 20 bucks a month. It just wasn't the thing. So a
Speaker 3:  search product, if you look at the history of companies that make an awful
Speaker 3:  lot of money, the search company seems to be making an awful lot of money
Speaker 3:  and they're headed towards, so I, I think this is just like a middle step
Speaker 3:  of like how do we fund our like world conquering a GI dreams.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That they're currently spending a lot of money on search
Speaker 5:  GBT. Yeah. They're paying for publisher deals, they're paying for training
Speaker 5:  these models. They're not making any money off of the people who are going
Speaker 5:  to be using search GPT. That's going to be even more money in the whole as
Speaker 5:  they get there. I I, I think you're right. Like there's a very clear
Speaker 5:  monetization model for this,
Speaker 5:  but in the short term it's, it's rough for them.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And you know the idea that they will capture, I dunno, Google ad Sense
Speaker 3:  ads or whatever that like advertisers will pay for opening
Speaker 3:  AI search product instead of who know, who knows. But I, the,
Speaker 3:  the piece of the puzzle where you might move one user from using
Speaker 3:  Google to using search GPT is the first problem
Speaker 3:  which like Microsoft has not solved in over a decade. Yeah. And like
Speaker 3:  the European Union has like tried to legislate a solution to getting
Speaker 3:  people to stop using Google and they can't solve it.
Speaker 5:  I mean it's funny because this is like, it's day one zero people are currently
Speaker 5:  using this. Maybe a few thousand will be by the end of the week.
Speaker 5:  This is a really, really small step. But this is also the sort of
Speaker 5:  explosive moment that everybody's been waiting for. Right.
Speaker 5:  Microsoft was so excited by this technology, they aggressively
Speaker 5:  shoehorned it into Bing. Google was so scared of this technology that
Speaker 5:  they put some sort of disastrous AI results
Speaker 5:  directly into the front page of Google.
Speaker 5:  All of the major players are fearful of what's going to happen with chat
Speaker 5:  GPT and now we finally see the product and
Speaker 5:  you know, it's very, it's very, very alpha. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That's such a good summation of the entirety of the AI product
Speaker 4:  industry right now. Everybody is either super bullish of it
Speaker 4:  or terrified of it depending on where you fall in this sort of current power
Speaker 4:  stack of the tech industry. And all of the products are just,
Speaker 4:  they're there, they're products. And I think the search thing
Speaker 4:  is so interesting to me because on the one hand, You can make a pretty compelling
Speaker 4:  argument that Google has never been more fragile than it is right now. Right?
Speaker 4:  Like it has had all these own goals in a row with all the AI overviews.
Speaker 4:  There is this wide perception that Google search is getting worse and worse
Speaker 4:  and worse. It's getting overrun by ads on and on and on. You could argue
Speaker 4:  that the regulation is coming forward in a real way, like Google search might
Speaker 4:  be more beatable than it has been in 20 years. And
Speaker 4:  yet there is exactly no indication that anyone is making
Speaker 4:  any kind of a dent into Google at all.
Speaker 3:  In fact, there's the opposite indication. Correct. They just had their financial
Speaker 3:  results and they're,
Speaker 4:  Google just keeps winning.
Speaker 3:  They just made $85 billion for the past three months, a
Speaker 3:  14% increase over the last year. Like do Google
Speaker 5:  Do something really interesting in how they've set up the
Speaker 5:  main search GPT screen though? Because Google I think for the past couple
Speaker 5:  years has been like the way people search is changing, people are using
Speaker 5:  TikTok, they're asking full questions and yet Google has not really
Speaker 5:  responded to that. Google search still functions exactly the same way. This
Speaker 5:  is a really small change. But the main search
Speaker 5:  GPT screen, instead of being like a thin little box where you're supposed
Speaker 5:  to type in three keywords, it's a large text box and it says what are you
Speaker 5:  looking for? And I do think there's like a small turn that they're making
Speaker 5:  there. There's almost this idea of, you know, you're supposed to ask
Speaker 5:  a full question here and expect the full answer. I do think that is
Speaker 5:  sort of a differentiator. They're sort of playing into this
Speaker 5:  idea that like we are searching in different ways now. We do need to build
Speaker 5:  a different product for the moment. Yeah. I dunno if this is the product,
Speaker 5:  but
Speaker 3:  Their example search is music festivals in Boone, North Carolina in August.
Speaker 3:  Which if you type that into Google today,
Speaker 3:  it would just be to, it would be a, it would the the SEO garbage that you're
Speaker 3:  used to, but you wouldn't get an actual answer to that query
Speaker 5:  Not, not even close.
Speaker 3:  And so what they're showing, and it, we should talk about the actual product
Speaker 3:  here, right? It's a big, they're showing the larger context window and
Speaker 3:  then you ask it a question with multiple parameters and it
Speaker 3:  answers it, right? Like the answer it provides that query is in August
Speaker 3:  there are several music festivals and events happening in BOE, North Carolina
Speaker 3:  and it has a list. All the lists, all every item in that list has a link,
Speaker 3:  which is really the thing the publishers have asked for. Nick Thompson, the
Speaker 3:  CEO of the Atlantic was just on decoder. And he is like, the thing we wanted
Speaker 3:  in our deal was control over how our links would be displayed and how much
Speaker 3:  of the stuff they would use. So it seems like that's what they're getting
Speaker 3:  here. And then bizarrely You can click a button on the
Speaker 3:  left rail to open a panel of links, which
Speaker 3:  is a much more traditional search result and that you can't even get from
Speaker 3:  Google anymore. Well it's actually kind of interesting that no
Speaker 3:  one has really rethought search interfaces a long time. And in the past week
Speaker 3:  Bing has deeply rethought its interface. Yeah. Because they can just do whatever
Speaker 3:  they want. And then open AI is like, well no one has any expectations of
Speaker 3:  us. Here's a totally rethought, like what if links were a panel
Speaker 3:  as opposed to Google, which has been stuck in the 10 Blue Links paradigm,
Speaker 3:  which they've complained to you about David. Like this is that
Speaker 3:  everyone's expectation, it's not what anybody wants anymore. But then you
Speaker 3:  change it, everyone like freaks out.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean it it, it cuts both ways, right? Like the, the great
Speaker 4:  thing about being Google is that you're Google and the crappy thing
Speaker 4:  about being Google is that anytime you do anything, a gigantic
Speaker 4:  portion of your users are gonna hate it and lose their minds. It's why there's
Speaker 4:  still the buttons in Microsoft Word, right? Like the, it's the famous thing
Speaker 4:  Microsoft always says, right? They're like 1% of people use this but 1% of
Speaker 4:  people is 10 million people. Like what are we supposed to do with that? And
Speaker 4:  I think that's real. And when you don't have any market
Speaker 4:  share and don't have anything to lose, it's a lot easier to take swings like
Speaker 4:  this. That's, that's certainly true. And I think to some extent like Jake,
Speaker 4:  what you're talking about, about this idea of, you know, asking
Speaker 4:  fuller questions and getting fuller answers is real. It's only one part of
Speaker 4:  search and it's actually a pretty small part of search, but it is a real
Speaker 4:  part of search and it is I think where all these companies sense Google is
Speaker 4:  weakest and most beatable. But like this Boo North Carolina thing is actually
Speaker 4:  a perfect example, right? Because all this stuff exists inside of
Speaker 4:  webpages, it's just a gigantic pain in the ass to find it. And
Speaker 4:  what we've all done for forever is you do that Google search, you
Speaker 4:  open up 10 pages and you sort of collate it yourself and you like
Speaker 4:  make that list either in your head as you read or in a
Speaker 4:  spreadsheet or a Google Doc or an email or whatever.
Speaker 4:  This is just doing that for you, which I think is super valuable. Like one
Speaker 4:  thing I do almost all the time is sit down and
Speaker 4:  Google like things to do near me this weekend and holy God is Google
Speaker 4:  bad at serving an answer to that question? You just hope that there is some
Speaker 4:  like local news website or Eventbrite happens to have
Speaker 4:  something. The potential for this to be good at that is
Speaker 4:  vast and very exciting. There are a lot of really interesting questions about
Speaker 4:  what it does to like publishers. 'cause you even look at some of the links
Speaker 4:  in these things. They're links directly to
Speaker 4:  the venues. They're not links to whoever did the like 10
Speaker 4:  fun music festivals in Boone this weekend that OpenAI might be pulling from.
Speaker 4:  I don't know the source of some of this data. I don't know if it's actually
Speaker 4:  parsing the individual venue websites to get the answers. I,
Speaker 4:  I don't know that it matters. I don't know that it's gonna make a difference.
Speaker 4:  But all of that is being abstracted completely away.
Speaker 4:  Potentially better user experience. But super weird different way to
Speaker 4:  think about how the internet works.
Speaker 3:  So, so this, this is like an interesting puzzle to figure out that I'm sure
Speaker 3:  we're gonna hear more about over time because there's only two search
Speaker 3:  indexes. There's Google's, which no one's allowed to use 'cause they're Google
Speaker 3:  and then there's the Bing search index which everyone uses.
Speaker 3:  And all the alternative search engines that we've written about, that David's
Speaker 3:  written about at length, they're all kind of running on the Bing index and
Speaker 3:  then presenting a new front end to you that is maybe more private or whatever.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And so it's pretty obvious that OpenAI is using the big search index
Speaker 3:  mostly. 'cause Microsoft is a huge owner of OpenAI.
Speaker 5:  We asked them and they just sort of vaguely said third party
Speaker 5:  partners are power
Speaker 3:  Well. So, and but then they then there are other indexes You can use and
Speaker 3:  then there are other these publisher partners that they're paying for. Yep.
Speaker 3:  Right. So if you look at this, it's like, do you, do we think that
Speaker 3:  OpenAI is publishing app summer.com, which is not
Speaker 3:  the summer of apps for your phone, but the summer of festivals in Appalachian.
Speaker 3:  Right? Right. Like very different. Like do we think they went out and made
Speaker 3:  that deal? Are they paying Wikipedia doubtful, but are they
Speaker 3:  gonna pay the Atlantic and Vox Media and everybody like yes because we know
Speaker 3:  about those deals. So there's some weirdness here
Speaker 3:  in, well they're using Bing for the big web,
Speaker 3:  like the majority of what they do. And then they have these like priority
Speaker 3:  partners who are getting a revenue share when they appear in the
Speaker 3:  results against what revenue unclear. And you just
Speaker 3:  kinda like spiral into complexity here. And the answer is like, I just wanna
Speaker 3:  know what the music festivals are.
Speaker 5:  Are, are those publishing partners actually to help improve this product?
Speaker 5:  Or is that entirely because 'cause of copyright?
Speaker 3:  I think it's both like fully, I think it's both. And I think that is actually
Speaker 3:  echoed by what Google is doing. Like we, this
Speaker 3:  is the marker I think this week of the next evolution of
Speaker 3:  search on the internet in a huge way. That's right. 'cause this product launched
Speaker 3:  and it's gonna become, whatever it is, Bing is redesigned and it
Speaker 3:  is basically just showing you AI answers first.
Speaker 3:  Like you thought people were freaked out at Google AI overviews. If you look
Speaker 3:  at Bing today, it's like there are no links. It's
Speaker 4:  Actually structurally pretty similar to search GPT. If you
Speaker 5:  Looked at Bing today, send us an email.
Speaker 3:  Right? So again, the risks of these other ones are doing, and then Google
Speaker 3:  that came out this week, Google obviously has a big deal with Reddit now
Speaker 3:  they're paying Reddit for results and Reddit is blocking all of the other
Speaker 3:  search engines.
Speaker 5:  I, in some ways I think this is like the craziest news item of the week.
Speaker 5:  Like this is, this is unheard of. Are there any other major
Speaker 5:  websites that block all search engines
Speaker 5:  as as a
Speaker 3:  Rule, but they don't block Google.
Speaker 5:  They, right. Well yeah, but Google's paying, right?
Speaker 3:  There are lots of big platforms that don't
Speaker 3:  want Google to index them because they want people in their walled garden,
Speaker 3:  but we don't think about the web that way.
Speaker 5:  Right. And this is, I I mean this feels like an explosive moment because
Speaker 5:  of that, right? Reddit has always felt like part of the web in a
Speaker 5:  way that I think Facebook does not, maybe that's not a fair
Speaker 5:  assessment, but I think Reddit is at very least trying to
Speaker 5:  recontextualize what it is right now. And they see that this is
Speaker 5:  the way they're going to be profitable going forward. And so they're playing
Speaker 5:  pretty hard ball with search providers right now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean even, even Reddit's statement to us from
Speaker 4:  Tim RAs said essentially that right? The, there was a sense that the
Speaker 4:  denial was that this is about preferencing Google,
Speaker 4:  but very clearly what that means is actually no, we wanna give it to everybody.
Speaker 4:  It's just that everybody has to pay us the way that Google did. And
Speaker 4:  that's, that's I think going to be an increasingly common position.
Speaker 4:  And what's a bummer is that it was Google. Like I think this actually
Speaker 4:  would've been a much more interesting test case if Reddit had blocked everybody
Speaker 4:  but DuckDuckGo because DuckDuckGo paid first. You know what I mean?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And it's, it's, it's really easy to sort of tow a moral line
Speaker 4:  when the only search engine that matters to your business is the one that's
Speaker 4:  paying you. And so I, I think to some extent
Speaker 4:  everybody gets to kind of have their cake and eat it too here. But
Speaker 4:  this is the fight you're gonna see over and over from these platforms. Right?
Speaker 3:  What I'm saying, this is the big week in internet search. What I'm saying
Speaker 3:  is this is the week that paid search started happening.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Oh I agree with that.
Speaker 3:  Right? All these publishers are paying OpenAI to be in their search product
Speaker 3:  and they are saying to us on the record Nick Thompson on decoder saying
Speaker 3:  loudly, this is all just baby steps towards trying to force Google
Speaker 3:  to pay. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  The like tacit agreement of search, which was that I'm going to let you crawl
Speaker 4:  my data in an exchange you're going to send people to me, I think is this
Speaker 4:  is the week that broke, right? Yeah. Like that is no longer the agreement
Speaker 4:  of the internet.
Speaker 3:  We're definitively on another path now. Yeah. So you've got the
Speaker 3:  publisher, you've got open AI paying the publishers for search GPT, you've
Speaker 3:  got Google paying Reddit and Reddit blocking all the other search engines
Speaker 3:  and you're just gonna see that continue on. And then you've got
Speaker 3:  perplexity in trouble because they built search g PT without any
Speaker 3:  of these deals and they're getting sued just straightforwardly sued. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Conde Nast, which owns Wired and Vogue and all the other big magazines is,
Speaker 3:  is suing perplexity for scraping for scraping insights.
Speaker 3:  Well there you go. Like we're in it. We're, we're in the
Speaker 3:  era where accessing a website is gonna cost money for robots. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And like I just, where the money comes out on the other end is actually up
Speaker 3:  for grabs. Right? Like only Google is making any money in scale
Speaker 3:  and search and they're making all the money. Right.
Speaker 4:  And they're making more and more all the time. Yeah. Despite
Speaker 4:  trying to screw all of that up with the AI overview stuff.
Speaker 4:  And meanwhile the other thing that's happening is the, the rage against the
Speaker 4:  AI companies who are doing this without asking permission is just getting
Speaker 4:  louder and louder and louder. Like there was a big kerfuffle around Anthropic
Speaker 4:  this week because Kyle, Wes who runs, I Fix it,
Speaker 4:  said that Anthropics Crawler was on I Fix
Speaker 4:  it's website, I think it was a million times in a day.
Speaker 4:  And this is like, it, it's an important thing to understand. Like if you
Speaker 4:  get a million page views that costs money, like actual real
Speaker 4:  money, the bandwidth and hosting costs for that stuff is expensive.
Speaker 4:  And to have that happening all the time, which is what these
Speaker 4:  crawlers are trying to do, not only do you have like moral feelings about
Speaker 4:  it and there are copyright questions, it literally just costs money. And
Speaker 4:  so there, there was a whole thing where they had disallowed
Speaker 4:  anthropic in it in their terms of service, but not in their robots that
Speaker 4:  TXT file, which is this thing that has, you know, been very important for
Speaker 4:  a long time and is quickly evaporating as a part of the internet.
Speaker 4:  And so now they put that in and there's a question of like, okay, is that
Speaker 4:  gonna stop? But it seems like all of these AI companies just decided a couple
Speaker 4:  of years ago that they can just run rough shot over the internet for as long
Speaker 4:  as they can and as aggressively as they want to and just ask a lot of
Speaker 4:  forgiveness and not permission. And I think we're, the
Speaker 4:  other thing that's happening this week is that is coming back around on them
Speaker 4:  in a pretty serious way.
Speaker 3:  Two, two things. One Con Nast sent a cease and
Speaker 3:  desist to perplexity. They didn't actually sue them yet, so just clarification.
Speaker 3:  And two, I forced David to write a story about robots, salt xt and I was
Speaker 3:  the rightest decision I've ever made.
Speaker 4:  You didn't force me to write that story. You, you fucked me. I cannot believe
Speaker 4:  you were taking credit for that. That is outrageous. That's
Speaker 4:  unreal. Actually you get half credit. 'cause I was telling you about it and
Speaker 4:  you were like, you should just write that story. And then I did write that
Speaker 4:  story. So I'll give you, I'll give you half credit for that.
Speaker 3:  That's usually how these things go. Yeah. I'll,
Speaker 4:  I'll, I'll live with that.
Speaker 3:  We should actually re up that story. We'll put it in the, the show notes
Speaker 3:  that deal, right? Which was about compute power. Like
Speaker 3:  this file that lives on every website called Robots txt is just
Speaker 3:  says what You can cannot scrape and who and who cannot scrape the website
Speaker 3:  or read the website or index the website. and it was there to manage
Speaker 3:  the amount of server load that websites would have in the beginning as everyone
Speaker 3:  sort of crawl everything. and it became very political. And now you're at
Speaker 3:  the place where perplexity, CEO is like robots.
Speaker 3:  DXT is not a legal agreement and we're crawling you anyway, but you don't
Speaker 3:  understand how the web works. So it's like a real thing that he has said
Speaker 3:  in response to some of these complaints. And it's like, well, can you explain
Speaker 3:  how you think the web works and why you're scraping these sites
Speaker 3:  that don't want your crawlers to scrape them? And that
Speaker 3:  you're right. I think there's a moral argument against AI that is like
Speaker 3:  leaking into the legal argument and the moral argument is like, go away.
Speaker 3:  And then the, the hard or the harder part is like, well maybe You can pay
Speaker 3:  enough money to overcome morals. Like that's capitalism. Yep. And
Speaker 3:  no one knows how much money that is yet.
Speaker 5:  I mean, the Atlantic might they they have right? Like there's our company.
Speaker 5:  That's what those deals are, right? This is, they're trying
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Candidly, I think our executives were a little jealous that we had
Speaker 3:  Nick on the show, but I can't interview my own boss. It's just not how it
Speaker 3:  works. Like nobody, nobody wants that conversation. So you're real smart.
Speaker 3:  Like nobody wants me to do that.
Speaker 3:  But I, I think those deals are even only a couple years long.
Speaker 3:  Right. And they're all betting on whether the times wins a lawsuit or someone
Speaker 3:  else wins a lawsuit and they get to renegotiate. But I just think like the
Speaker 3:  bigger picture here is very much people know there should be
Speaker 3:  a next generation search product. A bunch of companies are trying to
Speaker 3:  build them. It was 18 months ago, right? That there was the Bing launch
Speaker 3:  powered by chat GBT and I, you know, I went to
Speaker 3:  Redmond and Nadella was like, I wanna like Google dance. That's the quote.
Speaker 3:  Whether whether I think he did make Google dance. He succeeded in
Speaker 3:  dancing. Yeah. Dancing occurred whether or not that dancing resulted
Speaker 3:  in any additional market share for Bing remains
Speaker 3:  to be seen.
Speaker 4:  Well what's ironic is every, I think everybody lost, right? Microsoft poured
Speaker 4:  a lot of money and time and energy into making Bing more
Speaker 4:  successful to essentially no avail. And Google
Speaker 4:  got so freaked out by it that it is blowing up its own search project. Like
Speaker 4:  it's, it's just the worst dance of all time.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I'm the one, you one who's usually got there being like competition's
Speaker 3:  good for consumers. And in this case I'm like, what's that? Is, has this
Speaker 3:  gotten
Speaker 5:  Anywhere? I enjoyed the AI overviews. I thought we got a good chuckle
Speaker 5:  before they started hiding them more often. Yes.
Speaker 3:  There's the studies out there that say they don't even show them anymore.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. There is. They're, I mean Google has fought this, but they, they,
Speaker 5:  they appear to be reducing the frequency with which they show up
Speaker 5:  and that that feels right. From my experience, I feel like I was seeing them
Speaker 5:  on just about everything and now either I've mentally blocked them out or
Speaker 5:  they're reducing them and I don't know which it is.
Speaker 3:  So I just did the search for music festivals in Boone, North Carolina and
Speaker 3:  it that is something where you would expect an AI overview, nothing,
Speaker 3:  just didn't get one. Yeah. And yeah, it's random. That's a sample of one
Speaker 3:  that I ran twice, but like they are, they do see me coming and going and
Speaker 3:  they cost more money than the normal search to execute to run
Speaker 3:  the inference. So we'll see. But I, this just feels like,
Speaker 3:  oh, this the, the way we think about the internet, which is like you just
Speaker 3:  search for stuff, it's going away, like just fully going away.
Speaker 3:  But
Speaker 4:  I, I I, I mostly agree with that, but I do think the thing I'm most
Speaker 4:  interested about with search GPT is we are at this place
Speaker 4:  now where everyone is assuming This
Speaker 4:  is the future. Right. But it is, it is very much not
Speaker 4:  the present. Like I think the, the, the thing that Prova
Speaker 4:  Raghavan who runs search at Google said about people going on TikTok is like,
Speaker 4:  you say that because you don't want regulators to yell at you, right? Like
Speaker 4:  it's everybody invents competition that they don't have. Like TikTok is not
Speaker 4:  search competition for Google, it just isn't. It might be, it's a really
Speaker 4:  interesting different way of thinking about the future, but it
Speaker 4:  is, it is not,
Speaker 5:  I do feel like there is something here though, like to, to your point earlier,
Speaker 5:  David, you said, you know, normally on Google you would go and you would
Speaker 5:  read 10 results and you average them in your head and then these tools just
Speaker 5:  average them for you. And those are the kinds of things where I have been
Speaker 5:  trying to use Chachi bt to see if I can get that
Speaker 5:  sort of quick summary.
Speaker 5:  And because the Google product has gotten
Speaker 5:  so disastrously messy in recent years, I don't feel
Speaker 5:  like I'm missing out. Right. I I, the accuracy threat
Speaker 5:  is not really a, a thing I'm unhappy to deal
Speaker 5:  with.
Speaker 5:  So I do think like things are changing. I don't, they certainly have not
Speaker 5:  changed wholesale yet, but I think it's coming. No,
Speaker 4:  I, I agree with that. And I think too, Google's credit with things like
Speaker 4:  voice search and lens and the multimodal search, Google is actually like
Speaker 4:  a much more sophisticated search product than it probably gets credit for.
Speaker 4:  It's just now trying to blow all of that up with AI overviews. But I think
Speaker 4:  to the, my larger point is we're at this moment where like all of these products
Speaker 4:  are way out in front of what they're all assuming is this big behavioral
Speaker 4:  shift and there's really no evidence yet that that
Speaker 4:  behavioral shift is happening. And so all these companies are just flushing
Speaker 4:  money down the toilet being like, the people are coming, this is what
Speaker 5:  Everybody wants.
Speaker 4:  And, and there was like, it's because chat GPT hit so hard.
Speaker 4:  Everybody's like, if that's gonna happen again, we can't miss it again. And
Speaker 4:  I think what we're learning is that actually chat GPT was really cool and
Speaker 4:  really novel and we haven't really found the like
Speaker 4:  mainstream consumer use case that goes beyond, it's really
Speaker 4:  cool and really novel. Right? And like by all indications,
Speaker 4:  the the $20 a month copilot stuff and the $20 a month Gemini stuff's like
Speaker 4:  not taking over the universe yet. There's some really interesting AI
Speaker 4:  like it backend stuff that's happening. There's AI stuff in industry. All
Speaker 4:  of that is cool and interesting and I think that's gonna be where all the
Speaker 4:  interesting stuff is. But the idea of like, I as a person in the world am
Speaker 4:  going to use AI all the time, not nearly as proven as all
Speaker 4:  of these companies would like you to believe. Right?
Speaker 3:  Did we overreact and cause a multi-billion dollar bubble because
Speaker 3:  it seemed like a computer wanted to bang you.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like is is Google going to burn down search because it thinks everyone's
Speaker 4:  going to change even though they're not actually going to change. Like I
Speaker 3:  Would, I would say in the history of the world, it seems like something wants
Speaker 3:  to bang you has caused many mistakes to happen,
Speaker 4:  But also most technological change, to be fair.
Speaker 3:  So there's that.
Speaker 3:  One thing I just wanna end with that seems important here is
Speaker 3:  search. GPT is a search product that runs on
Speaker 3:  Microsoft's cloud infrastructure and Bing is a search
Speaker 3:  product that runs on Microsoft's cloud infrastructure and makes use
Speaker 3:  of open ai, which runs in like, what is going on here? Are these,
Speaker 3:  it does not seem like these companies are as tightly linked as they used
Speaker 3:  to be.
Speaker 5:  I don't know. I mean I I feel like if you had to
Speaker 5:  ask Microsoft to pick one, they're gonna pick Azure over everything else.
Speaker 5:  It's like
Speaker 3:  My my one true. Right?
Speaker 5:  No, it's like, it's the cloud.
Speaker 3:  This is like Hulk Hogan ripping over the American flag to shut Trump's face.
Speaker 3:  Exactly.
Speaker 5:  It's all Azure. It was always Azure. This is what
Speaker 5:  they care about. They don't care if it's them or somebody else. and it is
Speaker 5:  not like they have a lot to lose with Bing.
Speaker 3:  It's true. It's just, I would say after the big opening
Speaker 3:  iku and you know, Nadella being like, Sam's my guy, he's, back
Speaker 3:  then there was Apple might join the board and that went away.
Speaker 3:  Microsoft did this weird acquihire of inflection where they have a new CEO
Speaker 3:  of ai, which is weird. And they hired an entire
Speaker 3:  AI company's worth of engineers. And then Nadella hasn't really said anything
Speaker 3:  about Open, like every other tweet from Nadella used to be about how
Speaker 3:  cool open AI was. Yeah. And Alex Heath has pointed out to me, Nadella hasn't
Speaker 3:  not one post about open ai. Do,
Speaker 5:  Do you, do you think he's, he's upset about their product direction or just
Speaker 5:  worried about regulators because it feels like regulators to me, I feel like
Speaker 5:  it's
Speaker 3:  True. There's, there's a lot of investigation of like, did you, do you actually
Speaker 3:  secretly run a bunch of companies? Sure. But it also, their
Speaker 3:  products aren't directly competitive. Like they both have search products.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And I guess the idea is, well if either one of us takes a
Speaker 3:  percentage of share away from Google, it's still running on Azure.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I
Speaker 4:  I really think that's it. I think Jake's summation is perfect that Azure
Speaker 4:  wins all the way down and the, the enemy is Google and whatever
Speaker 4:  you have to do to take away from Google is fine. And I think for Microsoft,
Speaker 4:  the, we're gonna use AI to make Bing work, ship has
Speaker 4:  sailed. And so you use Bing to like keep doing weird
Speaker 4:  stuff and keep getting press and then you hope search GPT like really wins.
Speaker 5:  We didn't touch on it, but Google was rumored to make this enormous
Speaker 5:  $23 billion purchase of a cloud security
Speaker 5:  startup just to, you know, boost Google Cloud,
Speaker 5:  which is behind Azure, which is behind AWS.
Speaker 5:  So I think this, that is just like a huge opportunity for
Speaker 5:  Microsoft and for all of these companies and that company
Speaker 5:  spurned Google. So it's not gonna happen.
Speaker 5:  But I think that just goes to show how important this market is. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Or or the CrowdStrike thing happened and Google is like, what if we aren't
Speaker 3:  responsible for things like this happen? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It is very, by the way, it is very unclear what happens with that deal. It's
Speaker 3:  a little far field front of our chess, but it seems like some weird, some
Speaker 3:  weirdness there.
Speaker 5:  Agreed. It wasn't clear to me. I I thought that they just were like, oh,
Speaker 5:  we can make more money just IPO-ing capitalism. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Alright, we gotta take a break. Kylie Robinson wrote the whole story about
Speaker 3:  search GP It's on the website. Go read it. We'll, right back we're gonna
Speaker 3:  talk about some gadgets
Speaker 3:  we've come,
Speaker 3:  but Amazon's been at it for 10 years. They've sent $25 billion
Speaker 3:  on it and they have not really made any money. The Wall Street Journal goes
Speaker 3:  into some very boring accounting tricks
Speaker 3:  that they've used to prop up the division, but now Jeff Bezos is gone.
Speaker 3:  Dave Limp, who used to run that whole division is gone. You got an Andy Jassy,
Speaker 3:  you got a Panos pane and they're like, what is this garbage? And
Speaker 3:  they're kind of just shutting it down. It sounds like a, a paid version of
Speaker 3:  Alexa is coming and that's the future.
Speaker 4:  A thing that I've learned a bunch of times over the last couple of years,
Speaker 4:  and for whatever reason this just keeps coming up as I talk to people about
Speaker 4:  products, is that if you work at a big company and
Speaker 4:  you have a product, there has to be someone really
Speaker 4:  high up in the company who cares about it. And without that,
Speaker 4:  if you're not like earth shatteringly successful, your thing will die.
Speaker 4:  And this is, this is true at Google. Like if you don't have a, a
Speaker 4:  sort of executive sponsor who can sit in a meeting and talk about why you're
Speaker 4:  still worth the resources your product dies if you, it, it's true at Amazon.
Speaker 4:  Like I, I think one thing that we're learning about Amazon is that there
Speaker 4:  were a bunch of things that Jeff Bezos in particular really cared about.
Speaker 4:  And we've seen those things start to kind of wither on the vine after
Speaker 4:  Bezos left. And I've heard this about the Kindle, I've heard this about Alexa,
Speaker 4:  that these were things that right or wrong, good business or bad business
Speaker 4:  like Bezos really believed in as, as things
Speaker 4:  that matter both to the world and to Amazon. And without him there
Speaker 4:  it makes sense that if you're Andy Jassy and you're looking around and you're
Speaker 4:  saying, okay, where are we just hemorrhaging money and or wasting
Speaker 4:  resources, you could look at kind as wasting resources. It's a, it's a big
Speaker 4:  team that doesn't make that much money in the scheme vote. Amazon does. And
Speaker 4:  you look at Alexa and you're like, okay, this thing was supposed to be the
Speaker 4:  future. It's been 10 years, we've lost Not only Neli did they lose
Speaker 4:  27, 20 $5 billion, they lost $25 billion in five years.
Speaker 4:  Not even the whole run. The journal's very good reporting. Couldn't find
Speaker 4:  losses earlier than that. But presumably they were very large. Like, this
Speaker 4:  thing is a disaster of a business. And can I just read you
Speaker 4:  what I think is some like truly great knife twisting writing from the journal?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like I used to work at the Wall Street Journal. They're very careful,
Speaker 4:  they're very meticulous. They, they are not prone to like grandiose turns
Speaker 4:  of phrase. But what that means is they will just very quietly,
Speaker 4:  subtly just stab you repeatedly with a story. So it says, while
Speaker 4:  hundreds of millions of customers have Alexa enabled devices, the idea that
Speaker 4:  people would spend meaningful amounts of money to buy goods on Amazon by
Speaker 4:  talking to the iconic voice assistant on the underpriced speakers didn't
Speaker 4:  take off customers actually used Echo mostly for free apps such as setting
Speaker 4:  alarms and checking the weather. We're worried we've hired 10,000 people
Speaker 4:  and we've built a smart timer set a former senior employee.
Speaker 6:  Brutal, brutal.
Speaker 4:  Ugh. But also, yes, correct. That is exactly what it's
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I I I can't think of another company that operated a product division the
Speaker 5:  way that Amazon operated the Echo division, right? For 10 years,
Speaker 5:  what, once a year they would roll out a dozen new echo devices and
Speaker 5:  there would just be different shapes and sizes ever. So slightly like
Speaker 5:  weirder variations on the same thing. And, if you look back over 10 years,
Speaker 5:  how many echo products would you say are essential?
Speaker 5:  Right? IIII really can't think of that many different echo
Speaker 5:  products that are not just variations on the original formula that they
Speaker 5:  identified 10 years ago. And so we talk about $25 billion being
Speaker 5:  wasted. It's like, I I don't know what they got from that. The
Speaker 5:  product just hasn't gone anywhere.
Speaker 3:  Well I'll make this comparison, which I think is, it's a little out there,
Speaker 3:  but go with me on this. This week Meta released the latest version of
Speaker 3:  Llama, which is open source. And Mark Zuckerberg put out this whole thing
Speaker 3:  about why he believes in open source and all this stuff. And he has this
Speaker 3:  line in there. It's like one of my formative experiences was building
Speaker 3:  products limited by what Apple would allow on its platforms. And this is
Speaker 3:  why I believe in open source and You can go read it straight and I'm sure
Speaker 3:  that will cause its own kind of consternation out there in the world. Amazon
Speaker 3:  thought this was the next platform if youll a call. They failed at the fire
Speaker 3:  phone. Yeah. Deeply badly failed at the phone. They are also
Speaker 3:  constrained by what Apple will allow them to do on their devices in meaningful
Speaker 3:  big ways. And they really thought they had it. They really,
Speaker 3:  okay. Ambient computing is gonna be the thing. We're gonna put a, I mean
Speaker 3:  they got one
Speaker 4:  In every single home
Speaker 3:  'cause they gave away for free. Yeah. And then they, this is part of the
Speaker 3:  accounting tricks that the Wall Street Journal is talking about is they,
Speaker 3:  they accounted revenue for purchases that were like not made.
Speaker 3:  They call it downstream impact. And like by putting an Alexa device
Speaker 3:  in your home, people will shop this much or they will stay with Prime or
Speaker 3:  whatever it is. And they made up some money and then you're like, this is
Speaker 3:  brilliant. There's no money. Like that didn't happen. Have
Speaker 4:  You guys ever bought something directly through your Echo?
Speaker 3:  No, actually I moved off the Alexa platform ages ago
Speaker 3:  because I just wanted Google home frames. I wanted the photo frames on the
Speaker 3:  hubs and Amazon finally did this. But they never built a good photo service,
Speaker 3:  which is exactly the problem you're talking about, which is the amount of
Speaker 3:  cost and complexity to build a good photo service is not worth
Speaker 3:  anything in the scheme of Amazon. Right. Google
Speaker 3:  accidented into Google Photos, right? And they have it so they can run Google
Speaker 3:  the Nest hubs, which have the cool photo frame feature.
Speaker 3:  And I know, I know that Alexa devices have that and You can do it and da
Speaker 3:  da da da. But then you gotta use Amazon photos, which is not as good. And
Speaker 3:  it's like, oh, is the money to improve Amazon photos worth
Speaker 3:  it to get even 5% of people to switch away from
Speaker 3:  Google And you just like run the math instead of Amazon. You're like, what
Speaker 3:  are you talking about? We run Amazon like figure
Speaker 3:  out how to sell more shoes. Like stop it.
Speaker 4:  I I've been thinking a lot about the conversation we had around that very
Speaker 4:  first demo of the Humane Pin all those months ago
Speaker 4:  when he stood there and he, he was like, I forget what he was wearing. Did
Speaker 4:  he ordered a book? He like took a picture of the book this Imran Cha the
Speaker 4:  the ceo I think this is right. He was wearing a prototype of the pen, like
Speaker 4:  took a picture of a book and bought it. And we were just sitting there be
Speaker 4:  like, okay, here's the list of questions I have about what just happened.
Speaker 4:  What credit card did you use? Where's it shipping to? Where did you buy it
Speaker 4:  from? What's, what source is it? How much did it cost? All of that stuff
Speaker 4:  has existed with the Echo forever. And with all of this you're like, Alexa,
Speaker 4:  you know, buy me toilet paper if I have to then go check my phone to make
Speaker 4:  sure it worked correctly, which I do. We failed. We, we just
Speaker 4:  accomplished nothing. And I that I think was just never
Speaker 4:  gonna work for Amazon. And and they have, they have tried to back
Speaker 4:  their way into people wanna do this with the, you know, the, the subscribe
Speaker 4:  and save thing has some stuff going for it and they're like, we'll reorder
Speaker 4:  the things and all that stuff and it just doesn't work. And God, this has
Speaker 4:  to have been six years ago now. I was in Seattle in a
Speaker 4:  conference room with a bunch of Amazon executives and I made the joke about
Speaker 4:  like, okay, this thing is for music and timers. What's the third thing? Where's,
Speaker 4:  where's my third thing gonna be? And they gave me this long speech about
Speaker 4:  how oh there are tens of thousands of things, lots of people like to do
Speaker 4:  lots of different things. And I was like, but none of what you just described
Speaker 4:  to me is a killer app that will make you money or
Speaker 4:  any of these developers that you're trying to bring onto this platform. and
Speaker 4:  it is wild to me how many years later precisely nothing has changed.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like they just never found another thing. It got very good at the things
Speaker 4:  it was good at and it never found another thing,
Speaker 3:  It's so funny 'cause there is that subscribe and save stuff. You know,
Speaker 3:  you run out of things in your house and you should be able to be like, Alexa,
Speaker 3:  I'm out of coffee or whatever. And they just couldn't close
Speaker 3:  the loop in that very specific way. Or
Speaker 3:  do you remember the dash buttons they had? Yeah. You would just like push
Speaker 3:  the button and like laundry detergent would show up and like kids were pushing
Speaker 3:  'em too much so they got rid of 'em. They just figured out like automating
Speaker 3:  that stuff and maybe have a little too much overlap is better. And that's
Speaker 3:  how you get to subscribe and save. Like it doesn't really matter. And then
Speaker 3:  anything that you want to buy that isn't something you've already bought
Speaker 3:  a hundred times in a row, you probably wanna do an like an infinite amount
Speaker 3:  of like product research on. And that's just better. And so like,
Speaker 3:  I think they're stuck with this product and the next move
Speaker 3:  is to put an LLM in it to charge money for it
Speaker 3:  and to have it be this thing. But to your point,
Speaker 3:  they thought this was an operating system. They thought it was a platform.
Speaker 3:  They were licensing it out to all kinds of other companies.
Speaker 3:  They they thought they had Windows. Yeah, we've talked about it in the show.
Speaker 3:  It was like, Amazon thinks Alexa has Windows and you're like, the thing You
Speaker 3:  can do with Windows is look at it
Speaker 3:  like, right? Like You can play games on it. Like they, they computers need
Speaker 3:  screens. I think is like maybe the end result of all of this.
Speaker 5:  Them planning to charge for an AI powered Alexa. It feels
Speaker 5:  like a, a very questionable next step. Like it feels, it feels
Speaker 5:  necessary, right? You need to charge for it. 'cause that's what everybody's
Speaker 5:  charging for the premium version of their thing. But it is, you know, after
Speaker 5:  a decade of people being like Alexa could be a little bit better. I think
Speaker 5:  the idea that people are like, you know what, maybe I will pay and get
Speaker 5:  a slightly better Alexa.
Speaker 3:  Well just think about the horrible upsells that are coming for all of us
Speaker 3:  with Alexa leases. Oh yeah. Right. Like even today, like you've,
Speaker 3:  every one out of 10 times I ask Google Home to do something and it's like,
Speaker 3:  you know, I can also do this. I'm like, I don't, I've known that for so long.
Speaker 3:  I I don't, I don't want you to, when with Alexa it's gonna be
Speaker 3:  like, you know, You can pay me to tell you even worse bedtime.
Speaker 4:  That's the thing, right? So like, Jake, to your point, I think to me
Speaker 4:  the question Amazon is about to ask is,
Speaker 4:  is 50% better Alexa
Speaker 4:  actually meaningful 'cause let, let's assume that it is, right? Like I think
Speaker 4:  there's some evidence that if you go from the machine learning tech that
Speaker 4:  we've had before to like LLM powered systems, the, like
Speaker 4:  the, the speech to text gets better, the text to speech gets better, the
Speaker 4:  natural language processing gets better. Like most of that seems like it'll
Speaker 4:  work if Alexa just gets 50% better at every single thing. It already does.
Speaker 4:  Does it, does it become a better product or a better business for Amazon?
Speaker 4:  'cause I don't think so. I can't think of anything that I'm like, oh, if
Speaker 4:  only it were better at this. I'd do it all the time.
Speaker 5:  IIII think if you put chat GPT into Alexa, it
Speaker 5:  would get a lot more usage than it does today. I I think if you charge
Speaker 5:  $10 a month to access chat GPT and Alexa,
Speaker 5:  you're not going to earn that much money.
Speaker 3:  Right. And this is a problem with the, it being a voice first assistant.
Speaker 3:  If you could pay $10 a month to get chat GPT everywhere.
Speaker 3:  Oh that's kinda interesting. Yeah. Right. But you can't, You can pay
Speaker 3:  to get it in their app and then that app runs on your phone where
Speaker 3:  Siri is there.
Speaker 3:  Fine. and it does, it's not gonna run in these voice assistants in your house
Speaker 3:  'cause Google owns them or Amazons them and you actually have this problem
Speaker 3:  where you, you have what is fundamentally an application running
Speaker 3:  into what many, many, many big companies have thought of
Speaker 3:  as an operating system.
Speaker 5:  I mean this is like the starting point though, right? All the grand AI dreams
Speaker 5:  are that these AI tools can actually functionally
Speaker 5:  do things for you, right? They can make the purchase, they can push the button,
Speaker 5:  they can navigate an app for you. And so I, I think if
Speaker 5:  we're talking about Alexa as an operating system, a hundred percent they
Speaker 5:  need to be working on these AI things they need to make that happen. But
Speaker 5:  the last time somebody tried this, it was the rabbit and they sort of made
Speaker 5:  up the fact that they could do any of these things. And so,
Speaker 5:  you know, I I would say I don't have high hopes for V one of this, but
Speaker 5:  it, it, it's, I think very clear that they need to do something.
Speaker 5:  This feels like the start.
Speaker 5:  I haven't seen it yet, but I I it it feels like this is going to be very
Speaker 5:  much first steps Yeah.
Speaker 3:  To this. Yeah. One thing that's interesting about the journal piece, which
Speaker 3:  is indeed very well reported and does, like David say, have many fine
Speaker 3:  turns of phrase in it. Panos Penne who now runs this division did not speak
Speaker 3:  to them. And we, we know Panos, he is a
Speaker 3:  forceful personality. I don't think he's just gonna let it ride like
Speaker 3:  it. See if he, if anything he will provide focus to this and it is
Speaker 3:  unclear what that focus will be if they are gonna launch a paid tier, maybe,
Speaker 3:  you know, maybe that's his project. Maybe there's a new set of hardware coming,
Speaker 3:  but there's another turn coming for this. It just feels like an
Speaker 3:  entire decades worth of Alexa hardware
Speaker 3:  is about to become like, huh.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So what's funny about that is, I think if it weren't
Speaker 4:  for anos, I would have just asked you just now,
Speaker 4:  do you think it's possible that Amazon is just going to decide to get outta
Speaker 4:  the devices business? Because what what this story is about
Speaker 4:  broadly is Amazon's devices business is a disaster.
Speaker 4:  And there was a period not that long ago where Amazon bought Ring, Amazon
Speaker 4:  bought, what was it? Blink It bought Eero. Yeah. It was like, it was deep
Speaker 4:  in the, we are going to be a hardware company in a very real way, especially
Speaker 4:  in the smart home. And obviously Alexa and
Speaker 4:  Echo is the biggest part of that team as Amazon looks at it. But like,
Speaker 4:  there don't seem to be runaway hits here, there is nothing that is like
Speaker 4:  making all of this work. And it's the same for Kindles and Fire tv.
Speaker 4:  Like all of this is baked into that. And so if I'm Andy Jassy and I'm like,
Speaker 4:  okay, we need to, we need to keep growing, we need to put money inside of
Speaker 4:  the stuff that's really gonna matter. It, it doesn't seem that
Speaker 4:  outlandish to look at devices and say this is not a game we wanna play anymore.
Speaker 4:  But if you're gonna do that, you don't hire PAOs Penne, I don't think. And
Speaker 4:  if you're gonna do that, I don't think Pano ISS goes to work for you. Which
Speaker 4:  is why all of this is very confusing to me.
Speaker 3:  Right. And there's a lot of early sort of unsourced roomy
Speaker 3:  reporting that he's like, what have you all been doing this whole
Speaker 3:  time?
Speaker 3:  And so we'll, we'll see.
Speaker 3:  They need a vision. Yeah. Right. The vision, you know, under Dave Limp and
Speaker 3:  You can listen to Dave on our shows or over the years was
Speaker 3:  your house would become a computer and he was just gonna like put microphones
Speaker 3:  and speakers everywhere and then maybe get some satellite internet and like,
Speaker 3:  right. 'cause he ran Project Kuper, their satellite internet that competes
Speaker 3:  with SpaceX. This is a real thing.
Speaker 3:  And so his idea was that he would just sort of like
Speaker 3:  smarten up your house and that would, you would just like add stuff
Speaker 3:  until you like,
Speaker 3:  like a black hole. Like it collapsed until it started giving up light and
Speaker 3:  heat and became alive and turned into a computer. Like, I don't know what
Speaker 3:  that metaphor is, but that's what it felt like. Every time I talked to him,
Speaker 3:  he is like, here's what we're gonna do. We'll add some ring cameras and then
Speaker 3:  ear will run the networking. We'll put a mic and a speaker in every room,
Speaker 3:  and then you'll have a fire tv. Then we'll just keep squeezing until it's
Speaker 3:  alive. And I was always like, but when do they talk to each other? Like,
Speaker 3:  that is the part, like the vision is like they have to do something
Speaker 3:  that is more than the literal sum of the parts. And I don't think they ever
Speaker 3:  got there.
Speaker 4:  And importantly, if you're Amazon makes money at some point,
Speaker 4:  like Amazon just keeps giving hardware away betting that once
Speaker 4:  it's in your house, they'll figure out how to make money off of it. And we
Speaker 4:  are now pretty long into that experiment not working. And
Speaker 4:  you kinda wonder if it's ever gonna start to work.
Speaker 3:  It, it feels like everyone learned the wrong lesson from Apple. Right. Apple
Speaker 3:  turned your phone into a shopping mall and like you blink in an iPhone and
Speaker 3:  Tim Cook is like that 30%. Right. But the hardware is still very
Speaker 3:  expensive. Yeah. Amazon's like, this is the cheapest TV
Speaker 3:  we can make. It's full of ads. Like, and it just did, they
Speaker 3:  didn't get the, they didn't get the, the second part. All right. There are
Speaker 3:  other gadgets to talk about. Do you wanna start with the Z fold six?
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's about it. Right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's my, that's my level of enthusiasm. Yeah. So Jake, I, I
Speaker 4:  wanna know what you think about this. Nila and I have talked a lot about
Speaker 4:  folding phones and I always end up sort of defeated and sad, but I wanna
Speaker 4:  know what you think.
Speaker 5:  I mean, if I had a lot of extra money to spend, I
Speaker 5:  would own like nine foldable phones and, and I would love staring
Speaker 5:  at them. I would love dreaming about how often I'm gonna flip them open and
Speaker 5:  use the huge inner screen. And in reality, everybody I talk to
Speaker 5:  has a, a foldable phone, does not open them all that often.
Speaker 5:  and it, it's really interesting reading Allison's review. 'cause she's looking
Speaker 5:  at this, she's like, this is, you know, it's a great fun. I think they've
Speaker 5:  like pretty much figured it out. You know, they, they ironed out
Speaker 5:  all but the literal crease,
Speaker 5:  you know, it folds flat. Now the screens like touch the edges. Great.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's a really nice looking piece of hardware. And I do think like,
Speaker 5:  we sort of got to, you know, a few years ago there was this question of,
Speaker 5:  oh, okay, is this going to replace the standard phone? And
Speaker 5:  I think now it's very clearly, no, this is just like another offering. And
Speaker 5:  they've gotten really good. And I think what Allison is kind of finding here,
Speaker 5:  and, and this seems right to me from everything I've read, from everybody
Speaker 5:  I've talked to, you have to have a use for it. You have
Speaker 5:  to specifically want this and buy this. And
Speaker 5:  particularly given that these are like twice the price of another phone,
Speaker 5:  you have to really want it. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Our old friend Dan Seaford, who's now at Google, had maybe
Speaker 3:  the funniest reaction to David instigating what I can only describe as
Speaker 3:  the Buc Palmer Wars of 2024.
Speaker 3:  He was like, well, you really want us a folding phone, which is the most
Speaker 3:  damn thing.
Speaker 5:  War
Speaker 3:  Greens the most damn thing to say, oh, I'll you Dan Dan is also one
Speaker 3:  to try to get me to use Samsung decks every day. Which we, how that went.
Speaker 3:  But his point was, you want a device for reading. What
Speaker 3:  you actually want is a folding phone that is a phone most of the time. And
Speaker 3:  then you open it and you have a tablet and you do this thing. And it's still,
Speaker 3:  the argument is what you really want as a tablet most of the time
Speaker 3:  tablet. But it's just, I don't think, but I don't want Android tablets are
Speaker 3:  that compelling yet. Like Yeah. To this day. And so
Speaker 3:  Allison's point here is like, Samsung kind of has no competition here and
Speaker 3:  they're coasting on having invented this. Yeah. And these are totally iterative
Speaker 3:  refinements.
Speaker 4:  I, I think, I think that's true. But I also think if you're
Speaker 4:  Samsung, you're, you are kind of looking at Android and going like, okay,
Speaker 4:  what are you, what are you gonna do for me here? And, and we're now
Speaker 4:  on a pretty long run of Google kind of loudly talking
Speaker 4:  about how it's investing in making stuff better for larger screens. and it
Speaker 4:  has gotten better. Like the basic UI of a larger screen Android
Speaker 4:  device has come a long way. It doesn't feel like
Speaker 4:  somebody just like took the edges of a jpeg and stretched it anymore. Like
Speaker 4:  it's much better. But it's still, it doesn't feel
Speaker 4:  meaningfully different to use the internal screen than it
Speaker 4:  does to use the external screen. And so I think like Jake, to your point,
Speaker 4:  you get a foldable phone and what you realize is mostly what you bought is
Speaker 4:  just a heavier phone that every once in a while you're gonna open up
Speaker 4:  and do something with. It's not like a, every time I
Speaker 4:  sit down to do it, I'm gonna open up the phone. This is the reason I think
Speaker 4:  flip phones are more interesting because I think to me there is a much more
Speaker 4:  natural divide of what you do where on a flip phone. Yeah. And on a fold
Speaker 4:  phone. I think partly just because of the way we've all used phones for so
Speaker 4:  long, you're just gonna sit there and use it as a phone most of the time
Speaker 4:  because all of the operating system, all of the apps, all of our
Speaker 4:  muscle memory has taught us how to use a phone like a phone. And so
Speaker 4:  there's just the case for this larger screen just has not been made super
Speaker 4:  convincingly and Samsung does not seem to every year invent new reasons
Speaker 4:  to make that case. Like the the sketch thing that You can do on
Speaker 4:  there is awesome You can draw an image and it'll make that image for you
Speaker 4:  with AI terrifying for the future. Very cool.
Speaker 3:  You
Speaker 4:  Need like a lot of those, if you're gonna start to sell these things to people
Speaker 4:  in meaningful ways, especially for twice the price of a normal smartphone.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Also, it is still too tall and skinny on the outer screen, which I
Speaker 3:  think is why people instinctively sort of open it every time.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Though, weirdly it seems like Google is heading that direction too.
Speaker 5:  All the rumors about the Pixel nine Pro
Speaker 5:  folds You did.
Speaker 4:  That's really impressive.
Speaker 5:  Hmm. Or that they're going more in this direction, which I think it's crazy.
Speaker 5:  I I thought the old kind of wider more book like
Speaker 5:  format was gonna be a winner.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The the Pixel eight fold. ZF
Speaker 3:  that's
Speaker 4:  The
Speaker 3:  One. Yeah. You can tell Google runs a company where most information is
Speaker 3:  indexed by machines in how they care to name things.
Speaker 3:  But it was like too wide. Like Allison has a photo in review of the one plus
Speaker 3:  open the pixel fold and the new Galaxy Z fold six. And it's like the one
Speaker 3:  plus open is the right
Speaker 5:  Shape. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It's a phone. Like that's the answer is make it a
Speaker 3:  phone and then You can open it to a tablet and every other one is like, it's
Speaker 3:  a book. Right. It's a remote control. And it's like, why don't you just make
Speaker 3:  it the size of a phone? And I get it that it's challenging 'cause you have
Speaker 3:  to optimize the tablet on the inside and you, you're, I don't want to reopen
Speaker 3:  the great aspect ratio debates of The Vergecast of old, but like what is
Speaker 3:  the right aspect ratio for both of these things is kind of an open question.
Speaker 5:  It's 16, 10. Just gonna lock it in.
Speaker 4:  Three, two baby. Let's go
Speaker 3:  It. All right. So that's the Z fold six. You should review
Speaker 3:  Sketch to Image is gonna, you know, probably end democracy as we know it,
Speaker 3:  but it'll be fun while we, while we have it,
Speaker 4:  Wait, can I just say before we move on, if you are a person who already owns
Speaker 4:  a Z fold and you're upgrading to the six, tell us why Vergecast at the
Speaker 4:  version.com? Yeah, I, I'm like, I sincerely wanna know because there are
Speaker 4:  a bunch of little hardware things, there are a bunch of little software things.
Speaker 4:  I wanna know like what are the, what are the new things that make you wanna
Speaker 4:  upgrade your foldable phone? So hit us up. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Let's talk about the Galaxy Ring real fast vs.
Speaker 3:  Analysis of this is, this is an accessory for the Galaxy Watch. Not
Speaker 4:  What I expected,
Speaker 3:  Which is kind of fascinating. Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So basically the, the ring seems to have gotten the hardware
Speaker 4:  basically right? It's light, it's thin, it lasts a long time, it doesn't
Speaker 4:  have a subscription. The charging case is great because it's a charging case
Speaker 4:  and not just like a weird puck that sits on your desk,
Speaker 4:  but it's, it is kind of totally ancillary to
Speaker 4:  everything. It doesn't seem to be wildly accurate
Speaker 4:  in the way that you would hope something on your finger could be more accurate
Speaker 4:  than something on your wrist. It does an interesting job v found of sort
Speaker 4:  of trading data collection between the watch and the ring. So it'll, it'll
Speaker 4:  actually optimize for which device is better at collecting which kind of
Speaker 4:  data through which sensor, which is very cool and potentially good for battery
Speaker 4:  life. But yeah, it seems like it's, it's fine. Like if
Speaker 4:  you don't have a watch and you wanna ring,
Speaker 4:  it'll be fine. It won't be as good as having both. It probably
Speaker 4:  won't even be as useful as the watch, but it'll be fine. But also, like,
Speaker 4:  people who want smart rings probably also have smart watches. I don't know.
Speaker 4:  So I I I land on like, this seems like a good additive thing,
Speaker 4:  but I kind of wanted more out of it. It's also extremely Samsung dependent.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I just Googled it. I can get a Galaxy Watch six for
Speaker 5:  half the price of the Galaxy Ring. And I think like,
Speaker 5:  there's the question, this thing does more, we already know
Speaker 5:  people like smart watches, galaxy Watch six looks pretty good.
Speaker 5:  It, and in these findings, right? The ring is supposed to be better
Speaker 5:  at a bunch of different tracking for el for el stuff.
Speaker 5:  It just wasn't So, at least for this first version, it just doesn't make
Speaker 5:  a lot of sense.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. As much as like the discrete form factor could be nice for people who,
Speaker 5:  you know, wanna wear other stuff on their wrists. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Can I ask if you are deeply in the Galaxy
Speaker 3:  ecosystem, can you talk to us? This is like every now and again, I ask for
Speaker 3:  people who are like d who buy like gaming Android
Speaker 3:  phones. Yeah. No one's ever called us. I just wanna be clear, may and may
Speaker 3:  look not all audiences as we as we know it's a fractured media landscape.
Speaker 3:  Maybe hardcore Android gamers don't listen to The Vergecast. But I suspect
Speaker 3:  if anyone would have that audience, it would be us
Speaker 3:  reveal yourselves. And if you're hardcore in the Galaxy ecosystem,
Speaker 3:  if you're like, we know about our iOS fanboy, right? There are people who
Speaker 3:  are like, I now that iPhone has RCSI believe in
Speaker 3:  rrc s like we know who you are,
Speaker 4:  But we're talking like deep, like if you, if you don't have a
Speaker 3:  Phone, I want that level
Speaker 4:  Loyalty. If you don't, if you didn't buy a Galaxy book just for the connection
Speaker 4:  to your phone, like, I'm out, you, you're not in it enough
Speaker 5:  If you're not using Dicks as Yeah. Your daily driver.
Speaker 3:  I'm sure I, I know. And I, I just want, I I just wanna
Speaker 3:  know you. I just wanna know, just
Speaker 4:  Be your friend.
Speaker 4:  So one thing about V'S review that really jumped out at me was, we talked
Speaker 4:  about this after the Samsung launch, but the, the whole energy score thing,
Speaker 4:  this idea of like collect a bunch of data and it's gonna sort of spit back
Speaker 4:  to you, like this overall measure of how you're doing and also some information
Speaker 4:  about how You can do better. Can I just read you a paragraph
Speaker 4:  from her review? Yeah. Just while I'm reading damning paragraphs about companies,
Speaker 4:  she says the new energy score is also broadly accurate though the AI powered
Speaker 4:  insights forward hit or miss after a punishing long run in 90 degree heat,
Speaker 4:  my energy score dipped 18 points the next day victory. I was told I needed
Speaker 4:  to rest that night. I went to bed, my score jumped 16 points, blah, blah,
Speaker 4:  blah. Except I was also told my sleep was compromised and to stop drinking
Speaker 4:  alcohol or late night eating to ensure quality sleep I don't drink. And my
Speaker 4:  last meal was at 6:45 PM
Speaker 4:  AI baby. That's the thing. Like all of these things that, that
Speaker 4:  Samsung and Apple and everybody else is on this path of like, we're gonna
Speaker 4:  collect as much data about you as we can on your
Speaker 4:  body biometrics. We want all this stuff and we're gonna, we're gonna give
Speaker 4:  it, we're gonna use AI to give it back to you. Right. And the more data you
Speaker 4:  give us, the better the AI will do. I am, I am so skeptical
Speaker 4:  of the idea that these tools are going to be
Speaker 4:  good at reading charts and helping me understand what's going on with my
Speaker 4:  body and helping me try to live better. And
Speaker 3:  This is the future of medicine. David.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I also, in some episode in the last couple of weeks, ragged on
Speaker 4:  people who aggressively sleep track. I'm just, I really am like
Speaker 4:  throwing a lot of strays on this show recently. And I heard from a bunch
Speaker 4:  of people who were like,
Speaker 3:  You're just firing into the air, just seeing where the bullet
Speaker 4:  Down. I heard from a few people who were like, I sleep track
Speaker 4:  intensely and I look at my score and I care very much about it. And I, I,
Speaker 4:  that's all well and good, but still it's to the point of like, okay,
Speaker 4:  if if you're tired, go to bed earlier. Like that's, that's as
Speaker 4:  sophisticated as most of these tools get and there is no evidence
Speaker 4:  in a lot of these that AI is going to make that like meaningfully better.
Speaker 3:  No, no, no. I use the app sleep cycle on my phone, which is a great
Speaker 3:  alarm clock. I pay the subscription, it's a subscription alarm clock app
Speaker 3:  Cool. On my iPhone. It's great. and it will tell you basically
Speaker 3:  like astrology level correlations.
Speaker 4:  All
Speaker 3:  Right. Maybe the real, I just like haven't dug into it
Speaker 5:  Affecting your sleep,
Speaker 3:  But it's like, it, it's like, here's, first of all, it calculates a
Speaker 3:  sleep score, which I don't even know what that is. It's 'cause by
Speaker 3:  listening to you, which is terrifying, and then it will just like correlate
Speaker 3:  it to different things. So it's like you sleep better when it's raining.
Speaker 3:  It's like, do I, and the craziest one is air pressure. It's
Speaker 3:  like, here's the air pressure and it, it's a, it's a curve with two
Speaker 3:  peaks and there's like parts of a barometer that apparently I
Speaker 3:  sleep better in. And I'm like, I don't know if this is real. You
Speaker 5:  Have to optimize. It's like you're missing out.
Speaker 3:  This is why I've hermetically sealed my room and I adjust the air pressure
Speaker 3:  in my room every time. Neil just
Speaker 4:  Vacuum seals himself every night before bed. Now
Speaker 5:  Wirecutter has a great list for, for hermetically Seal the
Speaker 5:  room.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's very expensive, but it's really worth
Speaker 5:  It. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I'm saying once you've used this app that is like astrology level
Speaker 3:  correlation.
Speaker 4:  I do like the idea, I will say of, of waking up in the morning and it's like,
Speaker 4:  ah, you didn't get very good sleep. That's Mercury's fault for sure. Like,
Speaker 4:  that would make me feel better. I would actually pay for that. Like I would,
Speaker 4:  I would like to outsource all of my bad sleep to someone else's problem.
Speaker 5:  Do that with that. I mean, I, I guess my, the, the question I have though
Speaker 5:  is like, I don't, I don't know how much more like a doctor is going to help
Speaker 5:  you. Right? I I I mean if you, if you discover that you actively have
Speaker 5:  sleep apnea, that's very serious. That's a really good thing to learn about.
Speaker 5:  If you just find out that you're waking up a few times in the middle of the
Speaker 5:  night, I don't know, like I feel like a quick Google
Speaker 5:  search asking your friend for some, some advice on
Speaker 5:  if you're partying too much. Like
Speaker 3:  Look, rainy showers is plus 9% sleep quality for me.
Speaker 3:  Actually my favorite in this list is there, is there
Speaker 5:  A word cloud coming
Speaker 3:  Here? It's affected by location so it knows where you are. And I
Speaker 3:  will tell you that if I go to bed in Philadelphia, minus
Speaker 3:  26% people, I don't know what that means.
Speaker 3:  It's not, I've, I've often enjoyed my time in Philadelphia
Speaker 5:  Too much.
Speaker 3:  But the air pressure, I'm just showing Jake the air pressure. It's crazy.
Speaker 3:  I don't,
Speaker 5:  You you have to be careful there.
Speaker 3:  I'm, listen, I'm, there's a lot,
Speaker 5:  There's a lot of red on.
Speaker 3:  I am the pilot and I'm telling David he's wrong.
Speaker 3:  All right, we should talk one more gadget. The as rogue ally X
Speaker 3:  10, however you want. It's whatever you want. Sean loves
Speaker 3:  this thing. Loves it says it's the best Windows gaming handheld there is,
Speaker 3:  except Windows is really bad at going
Speaker 4:  Right. Best Windows handheld is is like the most damning with faint praise
Speaker 4:  thing of all time right now. But yeah, it's by
Speaker 3:  The way, I have to say, I think we gave all of these products sevens and
Speaker 3:  I feel like I need to have a stern meeting sevens
Speaker 4:  Because only the Vision Pro. All of
Speaker 3:  These are
Speaker 4:  Sevens, right? Is that, is that right? Yeah. Only the only the Vision Pro
Speaker 4:  deserves a seven. Nothing else, but
Speaker 3:  We give one seven a year and it's the most damning seven we can get.
Speaker 3:  That's my,
Speaker 4:  I love that. For us, that's
Speaker 3:  The new rule.
Speaker 4:  But yeah, the, the rub on most
Speaker 4:  windows handheld gaming is that it's bad. Like
Speaker 4:  the upside is that it's windows, so it runs everything. The downside is that
Speaker 4:  it's windows, so it ruins everything. Like that's, it's honestly that simple.
Speaker 4:  This one kudos to Jesus, like the, the, it's
Speaker 4:  fast. The battery life is pretty good. The it, the fan is not super
Speaker 4:  loud. It has a variable refreshed screen that Sean really liked.
Speaker 4:  The downside is still windows. It is just not
Speaker 4:  optimized to run well on a screen like this. But I will say
Speaker 4:  we had a whole conversation two weeks ago on the show with Sean
Speaker 4:  and Kranz, because I am like deep in a buying debate with
Speaker 4:  myself about which portable console to buy. And they kind of were like, it's
Speaker 4:  the steam deck unless the the rug LIX can be great.
Speaker 4:  It kind of seems great. Like this kind of seems like the one, it's, it's
Speaker 4:  a little finicky because it's windows, but it'll play all your games and
Speaker 4:  it'll play them all pretty well. and it will last a long time. Like as
Speaker 4:  Windows goes. That's it. This
Speaker 3:  Is the key. It will play all the games, right? Sean is like, the performance
Speaker 3:  can play the most demanding games and the battery life is good.
Speaker 5:  The the other thing I'll say here is like, this is twice the price of an
Speaker 5:  entry. That's
Speaker 4:  The killer part. It's $800. This,
Speaker 5:  This is not the price of buying a gaming pc. Exactly. But this is like a
Speaker 5:  pretty serious console level investment. That is
Speaker 4:  True. It's like more than buying a PlayStation, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Buying the steam deck. You're like, oh, it'd be kind of cheeky. And
Speaker 5:  I think this is, this is like, this is your serious gaming device. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  This is a commitment. But I think
Speaker 4:  That's okay. It like, if it, if it, if it runs as well as it seems to, like
Speaker 4:  Sean is a pretty demanding benchmark Oh, for sure. Of games. So when he,
Speaker 4:  when he says he's happy, I know I'm going to be like ecstatic because Sean
Speaker 4:  is mad about frame rates and I'm like, this looks great to me. What are you
Speaker 4:  talking about, Sean? So
Speaker 3:  This
Speaker 4:  Is why I don't review gaming handhelds, but I, I think I was very encouraged
Speaker 4:  by how encouraged he was even playing, what was it, Alan Wake two
Speaker 4:  that he said is like a bear of a game for any of these systems and seemed
Speaker 4:  to be pretty happy with it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And, and the, the, as these scenes get less and less finicky over time,
Speaker 5:  slowly, I mean it's just making this kind of caliber of
Speaker 5:  gaming more accessible to people who do not want to deal with that on a full
Speaker 5:  fledged pc, which is great.
Speaker 3:  All right, we gotta take a break.
Speaker 4:  Are we not talking about Google's weird Chromecast thing? That's it. That's
Speaker 4:  all I have to say about it. Google has a weird Chromecast thing that hopefully
Speaker 4:  will be more powerful than a Chromecast. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's slow
Speaker 3:  And it's like a wedge. It's like, you know, the people who do finger skateboarding,
Speaker 3:  it's made for them.
Speaker 3:  That's what it's
Speaker 4:  Like. Belkin is gonna make you a finger skateboard for this thing 10 minutes
Speaker 4:  after it launches. But yeah, we don't need to talk too much about this. 'cause
Speaker 4:  all of this stuff is launching in two weeks basically and has just been leaked
Speaker 4:  to death. So we'll have many more chances to talk about this between now
Speaker 4:  and then. But weirdly, of all the stuff I think Google is gonna launch, if
Speaker 4:  they can launch a very good Google TV powered set top box,
Speaker 4:  that might be the thing. I am specifically most excited about it. And I say
Speaker 4:  this to somebody who finally caved and bought an Apple TV to plug into my
Speaker 4:  Roku tv because I'm so tired of crappy streaming software.
Speaker 4:  Just give me something better, right?
Speaker 3:  Sony Pictures Core You can only watch four movies. Three of them are
Speaker 3:  in the Bad Boys series, but they're 80 megabits per second.
Speaker 4:  And number four is Madame Webb,
Speaker 3:  Which
Speaker 4:  Exists. I like to think in the same
Speaker 5:  you. Yeah. So I wanna open with Apple Maps launches on the web,
Speaker 5:  revenge
Speaker 3:  Of the web. This is, we open the show with like, a web is dead. We're closing
Speaker 3:  it with like Apple. It has to do web stuff. Now
Speaker 5:  This is either monumental or just does not matter
Speaker 5:  at all. And I, I am not sure which it is, but there's like a thing
Speaker 5:  happening around Apple Maps where I am, I'm of a
Speaker 5:  generation, my, my, my generation believes that
Speaker 5:  Apple Maps is garbage because that's how it was when it launched
Speaker 5:  in 2012. And then we kept using Google Maps because we
Speaker 5:  u you know, I, I've used Google Maps since its inception.
Speaker 5:  It's a lovely, mostly good product.
Speaker 5:  But I do think more and more people are using Apple Maps. It's the default
Speaker 5:  on the iPhone. People aren't questioning it. And by all accounts it's gotten
Speaker 5:  pretty darn good over the past 10 years.
Speaker 4:  Can I caveat that slightly?
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  Apple Maps is very good at navigation. It's very like if, if you
Speaker 4:  put in an address and you want it to get you to that address, apple Maps
Speaker 4:  is very good. It's actually in a lot of ways better than Google
Speaker 4:  Maps, which I think has like mostly lost its mind as a navigational tool.
Speaker 4:  We can come back to, there are lots of other parts of a Maps app.
Speaker 4:  Apple Maps is trash at most of them, but it is, it is very good at
Speaker 4:  just like A to B directional navigation. Especially if you've watched, do
Speaker 4:  you guys ever use the, the Tappy Tap things? Yeah, I really like that. Not
Speaker 4:  because I remember what the taps do and are supposed to remind me to do,
Speaker 4:  but because it makes me look down at the map so that I actually remember
Speaker 4:  where I'm going. It's just like, Hey, you have to turn soon. Look, look
Speaker 4:  at the screen. It's very hidden.
Speaker 3:  The map, the, the taps, the haptics are like the purest hidden
Speaker 3:  UI of all time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's like six in a row if you're supposed to turn left and like three
Speaker 4:  pairs of two if you're supposed to turn right. Like I really think that's
Speaker 4:  what it is. I cannot figure it out. I just take like my, my wrist starts
Speaker 4:  making noises at me, at me and I'm like, oh yeah, you, it's crap.
Speaker 4:  It's like no one cares enough to figure this out, but Sorry Jake, continue.
Speaker 5:  No. So I, I, so now it's on the web, right? It is on the,
Speaker 5:  the platform that is, it is accessible to everyone. So before now, it's
Speaker 5:  not that Apple Maps was available on the web in some very limited ways, right?
Speaker 5:  They had an API developers could pay for it and embed it into
Speaker 5:  their tools. I believe the infatuation uses it for all of their
Speaker 5:  restaurant maps. Duck, duck go, all the duck duck Go. Heads
Speaker 5:  out there know this, it powers Duck Duck go's maps. So it
Speaker 5:  is not like it wasn't available, but there was no maps.apple.com
Speaker 5:  and now there is, don't go to that address 'cause it might be slightly different,
Speaker 5:  but you know, it is on the web. You can use it. And if you're sick and
Speaker 5:  tired of Google Maps, which I'm sure some people are
Speaker 5:  You can switch to Apple. And I think as they, I think
Speaker 5:  inevitably try to turn this into a services business,
Speaker 5:  the fact that it's on the web is going to matter. So it's not clear to me
Speaker 5:  that overnight anybody's gonna switch their bookmark from Google Maps to
Speaker 5:  Apple Maps on the web, but it feels pretty important that they
Speaker 5:  have brought this to the web eventually so that it is on, you know, the biggest
Speaker 5:  platform in the world.
Speaker 4:  Can I give you my Galaxy brand take on this?
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So Google Maps is fundamentally
Speaker 4:  a search engine, right? Like it is, it is a, it's a local listing
Speaker 4:  of places. That's actually the thing about Google Maps that is the best.
Speaker 4:  It has all the places, it has pictures, it has reviews,
Speaker 4:  it as a, as a database of local things. It is pretty much
Speaker 4:  unmatched. Apple is awful at that. It has a Yelp integration that
Speaker 4:  everybody really hates. It's just Apple is not good at that.
Speaker 4:  But that's where all the money is in maps, right? Like You can be a data
Speaker 4:  provider, which, which Apple is. But if you wanna really do this and
Speaker 4:  do this well, you want to essentially sell ads
Speaker 4:  in local search. And that's a big business. It's a business in which hardly
Speaker 4:  anybody is doing a good job of competing with Google because you kind of
Speaker 4:  need the mapping product to do it on top of And. If you want to do that,
Speaker 4:  you need it to work on the web because you need it to be
Speaker 4:  everywhere. Because like, if I am in the car, what I want is
Speaker 4:  navigation, like, and I need to get somewhere. But if I'm like
Speaker 4:  planning things or I'm looking for places nearby, like that is
Speaker 4:  a, a desktop activity that you do on the web
Speaker 4:  and this is how you get to Chromebooks. This is how you get to Windows. I
Speaker 4:  think like there is a maps app for Mac that I cannot imagine people
Speaker 4:  open ever on purpose, but this is like, this is
Speaker 4:  your way of becoming like a, a tool for
Speaker 4:  advertising and for place search way more than it is like
Speaker 4:  mobile web navigation. And so I think in, no, I think that's a hundred percent
Speaker 4:  right in that respect is a sign that this is something Apple is going to
Speaker 4:  start caring a lot more about as a business is super interesting to me
Speaker 4:  and probably bad for Yelp because you gotta kick Yelp out if you want to
Speaker 4:  do this well
Speaker 5:  And bad for Apple Maps. What, what you're fundamentally describing is they're
Speaker 5:  going to put a bunch of ads. I know
Speaker 3:  That's
Speaker 5:  Really true, which is is the reason that people like it right now that it
Speaker 5:  doesn't do that. But I, that feels like it is the inevitable direction.
Speaker 5:  So use it now while You can.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, this feels like they're teeing that up. If, and
Speaker 5:  you know, being available on a huge platform is, is
Speaker 3:  Right now I'm gonna Galaxy brand it.
Speaker 3:  This is, this is Apple. Knowing that
Speaker 3:  there's big court case about Google default search on its products
Speaker 3:  and that search is all going wonky and people search for places
Speaker 3:  all the time. All the time. And the, the
Speaker 3:  thing after all these years, people expect maps to show up in search
Speaker 3:  results on the web. So you just need to get to a place where you're not
Speaker 3:  kicking people on their MacBooks into a weird map app
Speaker 3:  that You can just display a result of.
Speaker 4:  I thought you were gonna say, instead of taking Google's money for Safari
Speaker 4:  search, it was gonna take Google's money for to like power all the place
Speaker 4:  data in Apple maps just as a way to like make a deal while
Speaker 4:  sneaking around web defaults. Yeah, I like that a lot too. But I think, I
Speaker 4:  think you might be right, and this is, this is a hedge in a lot of ways,
Speaker 4:  right? Like, you have to be good at this if you want to win at any of this
Speaker 4:  stuff. I think that's, I think you're probably right.
Speaker 3:  The web ain't Ted, by the way, as we have been speaking,
Speaker 3:  we have a little Breaking Gadget news. Patrick Spence, the CEO
Speaker 3:  of Sonos released a letter apologizing for the
Speaker 3:  disastrous rollout. I will point out just some
Speaker 3:  chronology here. He says, we know too many of you have experienced significant
Speaker 3:  problems with our new app, which rolled out on May 7th. Today is
Speaker 3:  July 25th. So it's been a minute
Speaker 3:  and I want to begin, not me, this is, I'm quoting Patrick now. I don't wanna
Speaker 3:  apologize to you for anything Patrick says, I want to begin by personally
Speaker 3:  apologizing for disappointing you. This, fixing the app is our number one
Speaker 3:  priority since May 7th. We have released new software updates approximately
Speaker 3:  every two weeks, each making significant, significant and meaningful improvements.
Speaker 3:  And they're gonna keep releasing updates every two weeks. And now they have,
Speaker 3:  they have a schedule. So here's, here's all the things they're gonna fix
Speaker 3:  over the next, every two weeks for the next several months. What a
Speaker 3:  mess.
Speaker 5:  There's only one answer here and it's that your entire
Speaker 5:  audio chain should be analog.
Speaker 3:  I agree.
Speaker 5:  You would have none of these issues.
Speaker 3:  I agree. This is why I have a full vinyl setup in your as every now and
Speaker 3:  again, I play a record. I'm like, no one knows I'm listening to this song
Speaker 3:  and it is the best.
Speaker 5:  That's that's not true. Your phone is listening to it. That's true.
Speaker 3:  True. Mark Zuckerberg and the FBI are like he's listening to that again.
Speaker 3:  Can can
Speaker 4:  We just crisis comms this one for a second? Yeah. This makes no
Speaker 4:  sense to me because there are two things here that Patrick Spence did that
Speaker 4:  I think are are bonkers and nonsensical. One
Speaker 4:  is 10 weeks later remind
Speaker 4:  everybody of the stupid thing that you did,
Speaker 4:  which frankly many Sonos users are reminded of every day because
Speaker 4:  the experience is a mess. Yeah. But like the Sonos initially
Speaker 4:  came out and talked about how it took courage to do this. Like just
Speaker 4:  to it what an incredible million years later own goal.
Speaker 4:  And then the other thing that he does is, is lay out the roadmap,
Speaker 4:  like you said for the next few months, which says among other things that
Speaker 4:  the alarms are not going to get better until September.
Speaker 4:  So now what you've said is, oh, we screwed up, we're so sorry. It's gonna
Speaker 4:  take two or three months before it really, really, really basic
Speaker 4:  things ever start to work again. And so all I'm gonna do as a
Speaker 4:  Sonos customer who came out of this whole period being like,
Speaker 4:  well that sucks. Hopefully it'll get better now I'm like, oh, now
Speaker 4:  they're just sorry, which helps nothing. And all I know is none of this is
Speaker 4:  actually gonna get better anytime soon.
Speaker 3:  Here's what I'm gonna tell you. If you are looking for an alarm clock, You
Speaker 3:  can use this app called Sleep cycle, which tells me that if I get
Speaker 3:  6,000 steps, my sleep is green, but if I get 12,000
Speaker 3:  steps, it's red. But if I get 21,000 steps, it's green
Speaker 3:  again.
Speaker 5:  And you have to pay for the alarm.
Speaker 4:  So you have to exercise none or tons.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But if you do like a good job disaster.
Speaker 3:  Hey look, they've never updated the app and made it not work. You know,
Speaker 4:  Does the alarm go off every
Speaker 3:  Morning? The alarm? It it, it's terrifying. It, it's a surveillance
Speaker 3:  alarm clock. It listens to you sleep, it figures out when you're coming out
Speaker 3:  of REM sleep and then it wakes you up so you actually wake up. I don't like
Speaker 3:  that.
Speaker 3:  I mean, look, it's terrifying and sometimes it it, it
Speaker 3:  claims to have recorded you talking in your sleep. Look, I'm saying
Speaker 3:  I. love it. It's my favorite day. Alright.
Speaker 3:  It is, it is my astrology. All right, leave me alone. I'll take that as,
Speaker 3:  as one of my lightning rounds. Dave.
Speaker 4:  What? Yeah, Jake, I forgot to mention that we do a lightning round in which
Speaker 4:  we all pick one thing and then Neli picks six or seven things. That's just
Speaker 4:  important for you to know. The lightning round is just what Neli talks for
Speaker 4:  a long time.
Speaker 5:  I, I'm honestly, I was stunned. I looked down, I'm like, sorry, NELI doesn't
Speaker 5:  want to complain about the 10 80 p limit
Speaker 4:  On fl. No. He'll, we'll I'm sure we get that
Speaker 5:  Worry. How, how are you gonna let that opportunity go by?
Speaker 4:  It just, yeah, I just wanted to fill you in. I know it's been a while since
Speaker 4:  you've been the shot.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  No it's good. Which, oh, which the other part of that means is my lightning
Speaker 4:  round thing only gets to take about 45 seconds because it's some point the
Speaker 4:  show has to end. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  It's a lightning round. That
Speaker 5:  Is how, yeah, actually I'm really confused about the lightning round actually
Speaker 5:  being
Speaker 4:  It's best not to worry about it. This Yeah, it just, it just helps. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  It's just three things.
Speaker 4:  Jake. When you actually sponsor it, then You can, You can be mad about it.
Speaker 4:  Okay, I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  Make it. That's
Speaker 3:  True. The second we get money, the whole lightning round is gonna change
Speaker 5:  The, we should be talking about these for no longer than 30 seconds. It should
Speaker 5:  be, you should, it should be debate policy style. We were just talking really,
Speaker 5:  really, really fast to get everything
Speaker 3:  Through. Yeah, that's the thing is that's what you're supposed to do is get
Speaker 3:  through all the things as fast as we can. Got it. And somehow we got to,
Speaker 3:  we're just gonna all pick one and talk about them at length. Just like all
Speaker 3:  the other segments, which might be why it's never been sponsoring.
Speaker 4:  'cause as fast as we can is four or five hours do you get,
Speaker 5:  Listen, alright, we ever, guys we can
Speaker 4:  Do this. No, we can't. It's impossible.
Speaker 3:  Wanna be clear? David, what have you got? I just
Speaker 4:  Want to really quickly talk about these new NBA TV deals that just
Speaker 4:  came out. Oh boy. We've talked a lot of the show about how sports deals are
Speaker 4:  like a harbinger of all of what's coming in streaming. The
Speaker 4:  NBA just signed two or three rather new decade
Speaker 4:  long deals. One with Comcast, one with Disney, which are fairly
Speaker 4:  normal TV deals. Some streaming, some tv. But the big new
Speaker 4:  one was with Amazon. And there are now going to be,
Speaker 4:  not a ton of games, but lots of games. 66
Speaker 4:  a year and 20 playoff games a year on Prime video.
Speaker 4:  Amazon's paying almost $2 billion a year for this. It is like, this company
Speaker 4:  is dead serious about being a real player
Speaker 4:  in sports. They are all the way out on gadgets apparently.
Speaker 4:  Like all the, all the Alexa money is just gonna end up getting put into
Speaker 4:  sports rights deals because prime video seems to be the thing. They are
Speaker 4:  like deeply committed to winning in some way, shape or form. And I just find
Speaker 4:  it fascinating. And yet again, the sports watching landscape gets weirder
Speaker 4:  and more confusing. There's gonna be TV deals.
Speaker 4:  ESPN is going to have its own streaming service. It's also gonna have this,
Speaker 4:  this venue sports thing. There's gonna be peacock,
Speaker 4:  there's gonna be prime video. Like God help you if you just wanna watch sports
Speaker 4:  in the next day. I don't
Speaker 5:  Know a ton about the, the sports landscape
Speaker 5:  before all these streaming deals. Was it this fractured and splintered
Speaker 5:  or, or, or could you mostly get one or two channels and find these things
Speaker 5:  Now it feels like just to watch one league, you need to split across
Speaker 5:  nine different streaming services depending on the phase of the moon. No,
Speaker 5:  that's
Speaker 4:  Right. It never used to be this bad. I think the NFL was probably the
Speaker 4:  most spread out. And basically the way it worked was two channels
Speaker 4:  split Sundays and then a third channel had Sunday nights and a fourth
Speaker 4:  channel had Monday nights. And that was, and
Speaker 5:  That was the best,
Speaker 4:  That was the worst, like the most confusing, complicated version of
Speaker 4:  it. Most of the time it was split between one and two
Speaker 4:  networks and then you throw in like regional networks for baseball. And it's
Speaker 4:  always been a little weird, but like right now, so I'm an Arsenal fan.
Speaker 4:  That's how I watch soccer. If I wanna watch every Arsenal game, I have to
Speaker 4:  have five networks. That's a, that's a real number.
Speaker 4:  It's insane. And so like, it's
Speaker 4:  just all of this is broken and it's because there's now so much
Speaker 4:  more money in sports, like the rights have gone through the roof and so
Speaker 4:  these traditional entertainment companies just can't afford the rights anymore.
Speaker 4:  Because like, I mean if you total up, so Disney is paying
Speaker 4:  2.6 billion annually. Comcast is paying 2.45 and Amazon is paying
Speaker 4:  1.93. So seven ish billion dollars. Nobody can
Speaker 4:  afford that on their own a year. These rights have gotten so expensive and
Speaker 4:  they're so important that the competition has just gone insane. And
Speaker 4:  the leagues, I think probably correctly are like, well we can make more money
Speaker 4:  by selling pieces of it to lots of people and then we will let fans
Speaker 4:  solve it for themselves somehow.
Speaker 3:  And the solution is going onto internet message
Speaker 3:  boards and scaling the storm seeds.
Speaker 3:  That's what's happening pretty much. Like eventually it's gonna get so complicated
Speaker 3:  the revenues will come down because people, we'll see. But I agree with
Speaker 3:  you that Amazon is betting very highly on sports because it makes Prime
Speaker 3:  video stickier. It makes it feel more free
Speaker 3:  and it gives you like other than that, then they have to, what are they gonna
Speaker 3:  pay for more seasons of reacher, right? Like is Homeland gonna be even more
Speaker 3:  evil? Well
Speaker 5:  And it all, it all
Speaker 4:  Sort of tracks, right? Like it is, it is. It does the thing for
Speaker 4:  Amazon that actually Alexa doesn't where like You can sell ads against
Speaker 4:  football that a crew back to Amazon in a very real way, right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. There's a lot of AWS ads unless there's an case.
Speaker 4:  Exactly. In a way that all of that stuff, they wanted to connect those dots
Speaker 4:  with Alexa and never did. They're actually pretty well connected on Prime
Speaker 4:  video.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But it's, it is getting insane to watch
Speaker 4:  It
Speaker 3:  Semester. Alright, here's my other one. I am gonna complain about 10 piece
Speaker 3:  streaming. As long as we're on the subject, I'm gonna take this opportunity.
Speaker 3:  Disney launched the bundle of Disney plus Hulu and
Speaker 3:  Max. Interesting. By the way, the ESPN Plus is not part of it. Just
Speaker 3:  a little swap out there. Like no one cares about this sports product
Speaker 3:  because that's moving into the bigger bundle with the other companies.
Speaker 3:  Very weird. Just a lot of weird stuff going on there. None of this really
Speaker 3:  matters except the, the bundle is what, 29? Nine nine a month? 69.
Speaker 4:  9 69 9 a month with ads. 29 99 a month
Speaker 4:  without ads
Speaker 3:  For ad free. So that's cheaper. It's
Speaker 3:  if you were to pay all in just straight up, you'd be paying $48 a month.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So it's cheaper, but
Speaker 3:  10 80 p two streams. And the weirdest part about this
Speaker 3:  is that when we ask Disney to clarify that and make it clear, they refuse
Speaker 3:  to answer on the record. That's so
Speaker 4:  Bizarre.
Speaker 3:  What are you doing? Like usually when we get a refuse answer on the record,
Speaker 3:  it's like controversial. You know, it's like
Speaker 5:  This is controversial.
Speaker 3:  We have like an explosive claim and they're like, no, we're gonna see it.
Speaker 3:  And Disney's like, we just won't tell you it's 10 80 on the record.
Speaker 5:  No one wants their name attached to, to, to bit rates that low.
Speaker 5:  So, so we actually, we, we actually don't know. We know that Max is 10
Speaker 5:  80 p. Yeah, Hulu and Disney plus, they wouldn't say
Speaker 5:  so actually it's the Disney half of this is just stonewalling.
Speaker 5:  The HBO half is like, ah, whatever. Yeah, like yeah,
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Max is like, we,
Speaker 5:  You don't have to care that much.
Speaker 3:  It is very hard. It is very expensive and very hard to get Max and 4K.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You to buy Max Ultimate. And it's just ridiculously expensive and
Speaker 3:  nobody wants it is what I
Speaker 5:  Gather. It's the only streaming service I pay for.
Speaker 3:  You pay all the way you
Speaker 5:  Pay. If I'm paying for it, I want, I want all fix.
Speaker 4:  Wait, really? Wait Jake, be honest. Do you really, you
Speaker 4:  pay the whatever, $700,000 a month that it costs
Speaker 5:  Sarah? It's like $17. It's
Speaker 4:  Not, wait, no. Okay. But the reason I ask is we, we've talked a lot on this
Speaker 4:  show about like price elasticity
Speaker 4:  for 4K because my theory is they're be honest, they're just gonna charge
Speaker 4:  everybody who is dumb enough to pay for 4K streaming
Speaker 4:  until you're paying a hundred dollars a month per service or you just go
Speaker 4:  down to ads. Like those are gonna be the two tiers
Speaker 5:  To to, to be completely candid, I meant to cancel months ago
Speaker 5:  and,
Speaker 4:  Okay, so you're in the neli situation where like, I paid for
Speaker 5:  This. I guess it, it's just, I'm like, I'm probably gonna watch something.
Speaker 5:  I I I'm really not sure what network is the bear on Hulu?
Speaker 3:  Who,
Speaker 5:  Who, yeah. I gotta cancel this. Yeah, it's not good.
Speaker 3:  I'm just saying the fact that of all of them, max, which has the best movie
Speaker 3:  catalog makes it the hardest to get 4K is just
Speaker 5:  Kills me. I watched Dune two on a plane.
Speaker 5:  It was pretty good.
Speaker 5:  It looked all right. I dunno,
Speaker 3:  I still have never done this, but my dream is that when we remove
Speaker 3:  review movies, we don't issue them scores. We issue them where and
Speaker 3:  when to watch. Ooh,
Speaker 4:  That's good.
Speaker 3:  Mm. Right. So like, some of them like go to the theater,
Speaker 4:  We rate it by screen size.
Speaker 3:  This is 85 inch movie. Get to the theater imax, this is an IMAX movie. And
Speaker 3:  then you get all the way down to the end and you're like, for free on a plane
Speaker 3:  if you, there's nothing else, right? And like in the middle it's like, wait
Speaker 3:  for a tit Netflix. Like there's all these things and that is the true mark.
Speaker 4:  That's really good.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  It's on cable with ads and you're hungover fine.
Speaker 3:  You know, we need to come up with a scale
Speaker 4:  On mute in the dentist waiting room. Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 3:  It's fine.
Speaker 3:  I, we gotta figure out the one for Baywatch, which I've seen go
Speaker 3:  viral on Seatbacks. I just, the
Speaker 3:  what's the new Sydney Sweeney Glen Powell
Speaker 4:  One. Anyone but you, I mean,
Speaker 3:  I dont know anyone but you.
Speaker 3:  I watched that go viral on Seatbacks the last time I was on a plane. Whatever
Speaker 3:  that category is is the most complicated category. 'cause it's not wait
Speaker 3:  for a seat back. It's when it happens, it happens to everyone.
Speaker 4:  You know what's tough is, is
Speaker 3:  Which is better than wait for a seat back.
Speaker 4:  So I have my, my new plane gadget is the, the 13 inch
Speaker 4:  new iPad Pro. Very beautiful, very bright, very large.
Speaker 4:  Nothing like a like surprise nudity in a movie
Speaker 4:  on a 13 inch iPad to really make the plane ride
Speaker 4:  awkward for eight minutes. I just do the quick, like, fold the screen down,
Speaker 4:  just sort of keep an eye on it for a couple minutes.
Speaker 3:  It's worse than watching with your parents.
Speaker 4:  Oh, it's
Speaker 5:  Awful. Got Oscar nominated. It's fine. Just
Speaker 4:  It's for art that's just sort of yell to the plane as it's happening. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Yeah. My parents like, let's watch Oppenheimer. And I was like, this isn't
Speaker 3:  supposed to be here. I'm 42 years old. Okay,
Speaker 3:  last quasi lightning round item.
Speaker 3:  We have David caused the Bucs Palmer War of 2024
Speaker 3:  Rivian. CEO rj SC CR caused the great CarPlay debate of 2024
Speaker 3:  to light up. It's real light. People are writing articles, people are yelling
Speaker 3:  comments. David and I are holding a formal CarPlay debate
Speaker 3:  soon on The Vergecast. I just, I'm just letting you know, we hashed it out.
Speaker 3:  It's like rules and like Liam is a moderator. They got heated.
Speaker 3:  Did I won? I'm not telling you what side Heli called
Speaker 3:  me names and they hurt my feelings.
Speaker 3:  It's, it's a reflection of the current political environment in America.
Speaker 3:  Right. That's what I'm saying. All right. I think that's it. There's
Speaker 3:  like a lot of other stuff going on. It's a wild week. We, we, we barely
Speaker 3:  even talked about the other thing that happened this week in the world
Speaker 3:  after we received feedback on our political views last time. You mean the
Speaker 3:  Olympics? I don't wanna say that.
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna wrap this up differently. All right. That's it. There's a lot going
Speaker 3:  on. We have to, you know, there's a new presidential can candidate. She has
Speaker 3:  like a lot of tech policy views that we don't know yet. So all that's to
Speaker 3:  come the Olympics are starting, which also seem very difficult to stream
Speaker 3:  in 4K unless you have a specifically a Comcast cable box,
Speaker 3:  in which case you get a low latency 30 megabits per second stream.
Speaker 3:  Comcast is an investor in V Media. They provided me with none of, because
Speaker 3:  You can tell how much they care for me. I, they did not
Speaker 3:  install Comcast service in my house far outside of their service area to
Speaker 3:  just give me one of these boxes. There's a lot going on. It's all gonna be
Speaker 3:  on The Verge dot com. Jake, this was great. Thanks for joining us, man. Of
Speaker 3:  course. That's it. That's Vergecast Rock and roll.