# Transcript
ID: 797b8eca-422c-4d4d-be69-d264e05f9606
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/2986318099900666798/7434659834380060549/s93290-US-3330s-1734260811.mp3
Description: For the second episode in our two-part 2025 preview, Nilay and David are once again joined by Wall Street Journal columnist (and friend of The Verge) Joanna Stern to talk about what will, and won't, happen in tech next year. This time, David joins us after a quick jaunt to the end of next year, and relays a bunch of things that happened in tech in 2025. But some of them are lies. Joanna and Nilay have to decide which things really will happen next year, and which won't. As always, the hosts get points for good guesses and negative points for bad ones. And once we're all in late 2025, we'll declare a winner.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (10 ads detected)
Speaker 1:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Low Stakes Time Travel.
Speaker 1:  I'm your friend David Pierce, and I am sitting here doing my New Year's resolutions.
Speaker 1:  I discovered a long time ago that if I do my New Year's resolutions, like
Speaker 1:  on December 29th, or more likely like January 17th,
Speaker 1:  they don't actually get done, or I'm just tired. And so my
Speaker 1:  ambitions are like, go outside once this year. And so
Speaker 1:  my goal now is to find a day, usually in December where I'm
Speaker 1:  more present, more active, feeling better, feeling more ambitious, and that's
Speaker 1:  when I do some real goal setting. And I try to think of it like goal setting,
Speaker 1:  not resolutions. I've also learned that I should make them
Speaker 1:  very small and very actionable. So like a couple of years ago, my goal was
Speaker 1:  to read one page of a book every single day just as a way to
Speaker 1:  kickstart some of that energy again. And it was such a small thing
Speaker 1:  that I would feel guilty not doing it. So I actually did it every day that
Speaker 1:  year because it's only one page. But the idea is when you read one page,
Speaker 1:  you read more than one page, and then all of a sudden you're reading a lot
Speaker 1:  more in a way that feels less sort of over your head than
Speaker 1:  the idea of like, I'm going to read 50 books this year, and I read more than
Speaker 1:  50 books that year. Perfect strategy. Absolutely no notes. Anyway,
Speaker 1:  I will share my tech resolutions at some point. By the way, I've done that
Speaker 1:  before and people have said they like it, just having some ideas about how
Speaker 1:  I want to use tech better next year. So I'll share those, but
Speaker 1:  that's for another episode. Still gotta figure some of those out. Use my
Speaker 1:  phone less. Didn't work. So we're gonna try some new things Today. We're
Speaker 1:  doing the second episode in our series, previewing 2025.
Speaker 1:  Like we said last week, 2025 is going to be a big year. There's
Speaker 1:  regulation stuff happening, there's a new administration coming in in the
Speaker 1:  us. There's questions about the Fedi verse. There's questions about ai. Is
Speaker 1:  all of this going to amount to like the next big thing in technology
Speaker 1:  or not? I think 2025 is going to be the year
Speaker 1:  that either things change or they don't. And we're gonna find out in some
Speaker 1:  really interesting ways with pretty high stakes. Last week
Speaker 1:  I had Neela Patel and Joanna Stern on, and they just ran through some predictions.
Speaker 1:  We had mild, medium, and spicy predictions. We talked about them all. We
Speaker 1:  agreed or disagreed. It was a lot of fun. I think I've figured
Speaker 1:  out the points system. We'll lay that out at some point. We got 12 months
Speaker 1:  to figure it out. We'll come back to it for this episode. We're gonna do
Speaker 1:  something slightly different. So I asked all of you to give me basically
Speaker 1:  things that either will or won't happen in 2025. We will
Speaker 1:  land on Mars, don't know yet. By the end of 2025, know the answer.
Speaker 1:  Will there be a new CEO of Google? Don't know. We'll
Speaker 1:  know by the end of 25. So these things that are kind of either going to happen
Speaker 1:  or not going to happen, I made a big list of them and I'm gonna throw them
Speaker 1:  at Neli and Joanna and we're gonna see what we think about all of them.
Speaker 1:  And again, this goes on the same point scoring system. So if you're right
Speaker 1:  by the end of 2025, you get a point wrong.
Speaker 1:  No points. Whoever gets the most points gets a prize. We as a group
Speaker 1:  are going to decide the prize together. So we'll figure that out later on
Speaker 1:  in the year. But the idea is just if I'm a time traveler from the
Speaker 1:  end of 2025 coming back and I have some things to say to you, some of them
Speaker 1:  are true and some of 'em are false, what are we gonna do?
Speaker 1:  It was very fun. We had a very good time and I think you will enjoy this.
Speaker 1:  We agreed more than I wanted to, but we'll make it work. Anyway,
Speaker 1:  All of that is coming up in just a second. But first I'm gonna go read one
Speaker 1:  page of a book because I am now like three years into this resolution and
Speaker 1:  it continues to work really well, and I'm not losing it today. This is The
Speaker 1:  Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  Welcome back, Neil Patellas here again.
Speaker 4:  Again.
Speaker 1:  Once
Speaker 4:  Again, David has dragged me into the studio.
Speaker 1:  If you're all wondering why we're wearing the same clothes and don't look
Speaker 1:  like we've moved, we did. It's been a full week since we recorded this. Don't
Speaker 1:  worry about it. Joanna Sterns also here. Hi
Speaker 3:  Joanna. I looks like I wear this every day.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it's this is, this is my podcast. I sweat.
Speaker 3:  I moved to just basically wearing like I have the same shirt. You're Steve
Speaker 3:  Jobs now. I am. I really am. I have done that.
Speaker 4:  A closet full of the miyaki.
Speaker 1:  Truly, the older I get, the more I understand that person. But
Speaker 3:  Legitimately, I have three of these shirts.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And in one day you're gonna break out the Obama tan suit,
Speaker 4:  full Fox news cycle.
Speaker 1:  Okay, so last week we did our predictions for
Speaker 1:  2025. We all had homework. We all talked it through. We still haven't figured
Speaker 1:  out the point system, but I have a whole year to figure out the point system.
Speaker 1:  I'm probably gonna win. But we'll see. What we're gonna do today is I have
Speaker 1:  written down a, a long list of things that either
Speaker 1:  will or will not happen in 2025. And the way we're gonna set this up is
Speaker 1:  I am a time traveler from the end of 2025, and
Speaker 1:  I'm coming back and I'm telling you a bunch of things that happened. And
Speaker 1:  you have to decide which ones are true and which ones are lies. Does that
Speaker 1:  make sense?
Speaker 4:  All
Speaker 1:  Lies fabulous. Why
Speaker 3:  Are all these games so complicated?
Speaker 1:  It's not complicated. I'm gonna, I'm gonna say a thing that happened at the
Speaker 1:  end of 20. Okay, by the end of 2025. And you have to decide. Did it or did
Speaker 1:  it not happen? Good.
Speaker 3:  You should have done a costume change.
Speaker 1:  I do. I should have,
Speaker 3:  Honestly. 'cause then you could have been like, I am dressed, I'm coming
Speaker 3:  back from, I am David from the end of 2025. Ooh.
Speaker 1:  Like, like jeans get even bigger in 2025, right? So I'm gonna come back.
Speaker 1:  You
Speaker 3:  Have a mustache. Anyway, a
Speaker 1:  Beret. Beret is, this
Speaker 4:  Is what AI is for. Berets
Speaker 1:  Are huge in
Speaker 4:  Tony's when this actually publishes will, we replaced David with ai mustache,
Speaker 4:  seventies. David will be here. Adobe. And the full flares,
Speaker 1:  The only facial hair I can grow is like a pretty like evil goatee. So we
Speaker 1:  could do that. Evil David could be,
Speaker 4:  I don't think the end of 2020 have a choice but to grow an evil
Speaker 1:  Goatee, my friend. Okay. I've
Speaker 4:  Ordered these
Speaker 1:  Loosely into categories, but the categories don't really
Speaker 1:  matter. So we're just gonna blow through as many of these as we can until
Speaker 1:  we have to get outta here. And again, the the, the thing we all have to decide
Speaker 1:  individually is is this true by the end of 2025 or is it not?
Speaker 1:  Thing number one, not only is Tim Cook still the CEO of Apple, all four
Speaker 1:  big tech CEOs are still the same.
Speaker 4:  Oh, absolutely true. Unless Google breaks itself up.
Speaker 1:  Okay. But then would student dar Shai still be the CEO O of Google in that
Speaker 3:  Instance? I, that's the one where I have a question mark.
Speaker 4:  I think right now the only thing that the big tech
Speaker 4:  companies can do is put familiar faces in front of Donald Trump. And
Speaker 4:  anything that disturbs that is a huge risk. Donald Trump saying,
Speaker 4:  Sundar Shai called me to say I was the most important thing on Google is
Speaker 4:  the thing that protects Google from regulatory risk. You change out that
Speaker 4:  face that name, that relationship suddenly Donald's like, I
Speaker 4:  don't like this new guy. And all goes to hell.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I mean, definitely. I there's yeah, true.
Speaker 1:  But you don't think there's, it's possible that one of these CEOs will just
Speaker 1:  decide it's not worth it anymore. That like faced with the prospect of what's
Speaker 1:  coming in so many different directions. It's, they're not just gonna be like,
Speaker 1:  eh,
Speaker 3:  I think they want to, but they're, they're boards to what Eli's saying they
Speaker 3:  can, he
Speaker 4:  Says, are all sharks. They think they can win. That's fair. This, this
Speaker 4:  is not, this is no longer a game about strategy. You don't, Tim,
Speaker 4:  it's a game about personality and deal making and
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I think Tim Cook's getting ready. He's like excited about it.
Speaker 3:  I think Tim Cook's excited to retire.
Speaker 4:  Oh, yeah. Yeah. He's been laying the groundwork to retire for a long time.
Speaker 4:  He's excited. This is why John Turner, his name keeps getting floated. Right?
Speaker 4:  But he cannot, he's sad. Apple is a small country.
Speaker 3:  No, it's sa he's, Tim Cook is sad. I don't know this. I think
Speaker 3:  Tim Cook is sad that
Speaker 4:  I, I would say we published this story about
Speaker 4:  Donald Trump saying Tim Cook had called him about European regulations and
Speaker 4:  the number of comments and responses we got that was like, he would never,
Speaker 4:  oh yeah, he did. This is just salacious slander. I'm like, no, he definitely
Speaker 4:  did. Yeah, he did. Like this man opened a fake factory for Doc Donald Trump.
Speaker 1:  He is good at this game,
Speaker 4:  But If you don't know what that he reopened the Mac Pro factory where they
Speaker 4:  were already making the Mack Pro. And Trump got to go there and pretend they'd
Speaker 4:  open a factory.
Speaker 1:  As long as you cut a ribbon, it's new. You know what I mean? It counts. All
Speaker 1:  right. So we're all, we're all saying yes,
Speaker 4:  By the way, corollary. Do we think Donald Trump knows who Andy Jassy
Speaker 4:  is?
Speaker 4:  No. The CEO of Amazon. Yeah. I think he knows who Jeff Bezos is.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Right. No, he, and
Speaker 1:  I think the fact,
Speaker 4:  This is what I, this is the point. I think, think
Speaker 1:  Andy Chassy's favorite thing in the whole world is probably that everybody
Speaker 1:  knows who Jeff Bezos is. That like Ev people are, people are
Speaker 1:  very mad at Jeff Bezos about things that Jeff Bezos
Speaker 1:  is no longer in control of. And I think if you're Andy Jassy, that's a pretty
Speaker 1:  nice place to be.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I'm just saying, I, the, we are entering a period
Speaker 4:  where people's personal relationships with the president will determine how
Speaker 4:  American tech regulation goes. And none of these guys can move.
Speaker 4:  Introducing a new face is,
Speaker 1:  And also Mark Zuckerberg is un killable. So he, he doesn't Oh,
Speaker 4:  He is by far the most stable. No,
Speaker 3:  He's, he's
Speaker 4:  In right. Founder, CEO. He's staying forever.
Speaker 1:  Okay. All right. Moving on. We're all saying Yes. End of
Speaker 1:  2025. Nvidia is the most valuable company in the world.
Speaker 4:  No.
Speaker 1:  Okay.
Speaker 3:  What is more valuable?
Speaker 4:  Right now it's, it's Apple on Microsoft every day. Go back and forth, right?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But NVIDIA's right there. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I just think that my prediction on the last episode was the AI bubble's gonna
Speaker 4:  pop.
Speaker 3:  Right?
Speaker 4:  And so if that necessarily means demand for chips will drop,
Speaker 1:  Okay. I'm saying yes, say yes because
Speaker 1:  Nvidia seems to be so far ahead of this game right now. And
Speaker 1:  even if what you're saying is true, there's gonna be some
Speaker 1:  lag to that. Like I think if the AI bubble does burst, I don't think it's
Speaker 1:  gonna happen in 2025. And I think we're gonna get one more
Speaker 1:  year of wild frothiness and then something is gonna
Speaker 1:  happen and it's
Speaker 3:  All gonna fall apart. Yeah. People are gonna keep buying these Blackwell
Speaker 3:  chips. That's gonna just keep happening. Yeah. Maybe it,
Speaker 4:  But all of that forward investment has to turn into revenue,
Speaker 3:  Not for Nvidia.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And NVIDIA's good.
Speaker 3:  NVIDIA's, they're selling 'em. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right. But then at some point when the companys stop booking, sure.
Speaker 3:  At some point, but maybe it doesn't happen in 2026.
Speaker 4:  Lemme say again. At some point when the companies don't have business models
Speaker 4:  to run on their Nvidia chips, Nvidia will stop selling as many
Speaker 4:  chips. But that might not happen until the end. And it's coming faster.
Speaker 3:  You think it's gonna happen in 2025?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But these companies
Speaker 3:  Are promising their AI agents and they're all, they're all on in, they're
Speaker 3:  all in in next year.
Speaker 4:  Right. And then they have to ship them.
Speaker 3:  Sure. And then,
Speaker 4:  I mean, there are companies right now like cloud computing companies that
Speaker 4:  are taking out loans to buy Nvidia chips. And the collateral they're putting
Speaker 4:  up for their loans is the Nvidia chips.
Speaker 3:  I just,
Speaker 4:  That's bananas. That is the
Speaker 1:  Bubbliest bubble you could possibly describe.
Speaker 3:  We might have time.
Speaker 4:  Oh, serious. Okay. I, but yeah, but I think if the straight
Speaker 3:  Prediction like it's gonna keep going
Speaker 4:  Up, is the stock, right? That's how I'm measuring it's
Speaker 3:  Market cap happen. Yes.
Speaker 4:  I'm out. Okay. I don't think so.
Speaker 1:  Are you in I'll be in, I'm too
Speaker 1:  End of 2025, somebody has acquired Snap.
Speaker 3:  Mm. That's a
Speaker 4:  Good one.
Speaker 3:  Who?
Speaker 1:  Somebody, I can't tell you. I forgot. I have a lot to remember. Coming back
Speaker 1:  from December, 2025.
Speaker 3:  Is it Apple? No, it's not Apple.
Speaker 1:  I don't think it would be Apple.
Speaker 3:  Apple doesn't want, no, apple doesn't want it, but they, I think it's,
Speaker 1:  Maybe it's Walmart again. Walmart.
Speaker 3:  Walmart.
Speaker 4:  Just TikTok and Snap. Yeah. No, no.
Speaker 4:  Just 'cause it's a public company.
Speaker 1:  It's just hard to do. It.
Speaker 4:  Just, it is gotta fail on its own. Activist investor shows up and tries
Speaker 4:  to push out Evan Spiegel. Mm sure. Okay. A straightforward
Speaker 4:  GE is here by Snapchat. I don't know. I don't think so.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I think Eileen the same way. Just because I don't know where it goes.
Speaker 3:  I don't know where it goes.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Because I think Snap's problem Yep. Continues to be
Speaker 1:  that it is a phenomenally successful product that is essentially impossible
Speaker 1:  to turn into a business. And I don't think anybody else has ways to solve
Speaker 1:  that.
Speaker 3:  And I don't know who would want it. Like
Speaker 1:  Maybe it's one of the big adver, like maybe Amazon buys it just because it's
Speaker 1:  like we're better at selling ads. We, we can do that, but I don't, I don't
Speaker 1:  totally see it, so, all right. I'm out on that one. We're all out on that
Speaker 1:  one. Yep. Okay. Number four.
Speaker 1:  OpenAI is a officially a for-profit company and it's making money.
Speaker 3:  Those should be two separate things.
Speaker 4:  Making money or making a profit.
Speaker 3:  Well, yeah, that's
Speaker 1:  All right. You're right. Let's, let's split them. OpenAI is officially a
Speaker 1:  for-profit company.
Speaker 3:  I would say yes.
Speaker 3:  Making a profit, I would say, no,
Speaker 1:  This one's hard for Neli.
Speaker 4:  I think that, I think that's a harder, longer fight than
Speaker 4:  anybody thinks. But
Speaker 4:  can they pull it off in a year?
Speaker 1:  A year is both a long time and not a long time. I mean, in like
Speaker 1:  this, this lawsuit with Elon Musk is gonna keep getting messier.
Speaker 1:  He just, he's going to paperwork everybody into oblivion.
Speaker 1:  It appears for however long it takes.
Speaker 1:  I think OpenAI gets it done just because there is so much money
Speaker 1:  at stake that they're just gonna have to figure out how to do it.
Speaker 1:  And again, If you believe that the AI bubble is going to burst, it is in
Speaker 1:  everyone's best interest to get that done as quickly as humanly possible.
Speaker 1:  Because then a bunch of people are gonna get liquid
Speaker 1:  and take that money out. And that's how they win. I think everyone has an
Speaker 1:  incentive
Speaker 4:  To do this really fast. So I'm with you that they will get it done. I'm out
Speaker 4:  that they will turn $1 of profit.
Speaker 1:  Okay. All right. So we're, we're all in on, OpenAI is officially a for-profit
Speaker 1:  company. Yeah. OpenAI is a profitable company. No way. No. Yeah. Easy. No,
Speaker 1:  it's like, okay.
Speaker 1:  I think I would honestly have a harder time with the, like,
Speaker 1:  open AI is on an obvious path to being a profitable company
Speaker 1:  than this one. Right? Right. Can is this company going to be
Speaker 1:  around for a while? Probably. Are they ever gonna make a dime?
Speaker 1:  I have absolutely no idea. Alright, last one.
Speaker 4:  What? Oh, sorry.
Speaker 1:  All right, last one for this section then we're gonna take a quick break.
Speaker 1:  The government is breaking up one of the big tech companies. Lot of possible
Speaker 1:  candidates on this one. Google seems like probably the most likely Yeah.
Speaker 1:  In our current timeline.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Let's talk about the verb there. Breaking up has
Speaker 3:  broken up.
Speaker 1:  Ha. I would say I would allow anything from has broken up to,
Speaker 1:  has officially decided and won required court cases in order to break
Speaker 1:  up. It has to be, it has to be done and
Speaker 1:  official that it is happening, but it doesn't have to have happened yet.
Speaker 4:  Oh, I think Google and yes, Google is in for it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I agree. What do
Speaker 1:  You think it looks like the
Speaker 4:  One with Chrome and search,
Speaker 4:  it's kind of on the exact same timeline as the Microsoft
Speaker 4:  case where like the Clinton administration won that suit and then the Bush
Speaker 4:  administration like settled that suit. So like you can see how
Speaker 4:  maybe you're just gonna get a bunch of weird compliance stuff happening.
Speaker 4:  The other one though, the ad tech won,
Speaker 4:  like someone in the Trump administration has to understand what's going on
Speaker 4:  in order to stop it.
Speaker 1:  True. But that one would also be the cleanest If you wanted like the, the
Speaker 1:  answer to what to do about that one is just split the two things apart. Right?
Speaker 1:  Right. That's the whole argument is these two things should not be together.
Speaker 1:  We are going to take them apart and then everything will be better. And so
Speaker 1:  if you're the government and you win that case, we don't have to do all this
Speaker 1:  other, like, what are the right remedy? You just split the two things apart.
Speaker 4:  And the reason I say someone in the Trump administration has to understand
Speaker 4:  what's going on is who knows. But the people
Speaker 4:  around the Trump administration hate Google. I guess JD Vance is in the Trump
Speaker 4:  administration, but like he's the vice president. Like what's he gonna do?
Speaker 4:  It's like the nature,
Speaker 1:  He's gonna be busy. Like getting kids to be more active.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Right. The nature of the vice president is not like you get to break
Speaker 4:  up Google. Right. But Mark Andreessen hates Google. Peter Thiel
Speaker 4:  hates Google. There's a lot of antipathy towards Google. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  JD Vance, by the way, also hates Google. He has been on stage at events being
Speaker 4:  like, Google is a problem. So I, that one seems
Speaker 4:  assured to me whether or not the search case is the
Speaker 4:  mechanism
Speaker 4:  that's like too fancy. Yeah. Like the Trump administration made
Speaker 4:  Google sell Chrome with all whatever
Speaker 4:  DOJ shakeup is happening. Maybe that's too much.
Speaker 4:  Trump administration forces Google to divest ad tech.
Speaker 4:  Who cares? Like, right. Try try to get that story
Speaker 4:  across the Fox News channel. Like we'll see.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I, I tend to agree and I also think like, as we've talked about
Speaker 1:  on the show, that Google search stuff seems more likely to end with a bunch
Speaker 1:  of like behavioral remedies, right? Like Google's gonna have to do the weird
Speaker 1:  data sharing stuff, it's gonna have to stop making the default deals. That's
Speaker 1:  not the same thing as
Speaker 4:  Breaking it
Speaker 1:  Off. I don't even think they end up selling Chrome. Right. Like would be
Speaker 1:  my prediction. That's
Speaker 3:  What I was wondering. Like do some of these concessions happen and would
Speaker 3:  that happen? Oh,
Speaker 4:  And all of those concessions are like First Amendment nightmares. I just
Speaker 4:  wanna be very clear about this. Oh, for sure. Right. Google is not allowed
Speaker 4:  to have Google search be the default in Chrome. But, but like
Speaker 4:  right wing search.com has to be, the default search in Chrome is a real outcome
Speaker 4:  here. Covid is cool. Dot com is the new default homepage
Speaker 4:  of every Chrome browser is like a real outcome we could get to.
Speaker 3:  But does that ha, could that happen sooner than
Speaker 3:  they break off the ad tech business?
Speaker 4:  Well that case is already decided.
Speaker 3:  But they
Speaker 4:  Have, right. So Google is like ruled a monopolist. They're guilty of it.
Speaker 4:  We're onto the what are we gonna do about it phase, right? Right. The Trump
Speaker 4:  administration is gonna, well that, yeah, that'll all go back and forth.
Speaker 4:  But somewhere in here, the Trump administration now has the ability to settle
Speaker 4:  that case. Right. And like who knows what will happen and
Speaker 4:  whether or not those settlements are a bunch of weird First Amendment ideas
Speaker 4:  that Trump already has about Google. Right. I get such bad results in Google
Speaker 4:  as a thing Trump says out loud it, that's all messy. Yeah. And the ad tech
Speaker 4:  one is like not messy. This
Speaker 3:  All comes back to me about time. Like how much can they really do in a year?
Speaker 3:  That
Speaker 1:  Is fair. I think that's the,
Speaker 3:  That's what I guess I'm trying to,
Speaker 1:  The most compelling reason to bet against would be that this stuff all just
Speaker 1:  takes a long time to get done.
Speaker 4:  Right. Hai calls Donald Trump and says, Hey, I will
Speaker 4:  make you the number one result for every query in Google search.
Speaker 4:  If you settle this case with us, is a thing that could happen. Yep.
Speaker 1:  But you're still saying yes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Okay. Something will happen with Google like the, I think,
Speaker 3:  But something will happen and they break off their business or something
Speaker 3:  will happen and there will be
Speaker 3:  clear concessions made,
Speaker 4:  I guess. Clear
Speaker 3:  Concessions.
Speaker 4:  Clear concessions.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Okay.
Speaker 1:  I'm in too. What do you think? Yeah, we're all in. I
Speaker 3:  Don't know, I'm, my whole thing is This time, like a year is
Speaker 3:  long. I mean, but it's also not betting
Speaker 1:  On the legal system, taking a really long time Right. Is a pretty safe bet
Speaker 1:  most of the time. Right. So I think it's not, it's not crazy. But now you
Speaker 1:  have to decide, you know, you're out. I'm
Speaker 3:  Out. Then I'm just right
Speaker 1:  To the other side. All right. But
Speaker 4:  By the way, I have no idea what's gonna happen with the Apple cases.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right. Yeah. They might not even arrive. Right?
Speaker 1:  And there's Amazon stuff floating around and there's Microsoft stuff floating.
Speaker 1:  Like I think all that stuff definitely takes too long.
Speaker 3:  Amazon stuff is such an, I mean whatever. Yeah. Alright. Okay.
Speaker 1:  One more for this section then we're gonna take a break. We have had a huge
Speaker 1:  society shaking AI scandal that made everybody think
Speaker 1:  differently about AI end of 2025.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. I think they're already happening. I just think we don't know how
Speaker 4:  to talk about them. I think that the sort of like deep fake bullying in
Speaker 4:  schools will reach a crisis point like so much faster than we
Speaker 4:  think. And none of the big platforms have any real plans to stop it.
Speaker 4:  Like it's, it's, it's already here.
Speaker 1:  But do you think, I would argue that would have to get bigger than some of
Speaker 1:  this stuff. Like, that would have to be an order of magnitude bigger than
Speaker 1:  like the stuff that has been happening on Instagram already. And like cyber
Speaker 1:  bullying stuff and the, the mental health crisis on Instagram. That stuff
Speaker 1:  didn't, it never hit the level of like,
Speaker 1:  the most important thing to everybody. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I think it's probably gonna happen in some sort of like,
Speaker 3:  institutional way to make people care. 'cause like, I'm not
Speaker 3:  sure people keep caring about these one-off issues about kids, but if there's
Speaker 3:  some big hospital or some big company
Speaker 3:  that has some AI flaw and they're put it all on, you know, they
Speaker 3:  lose a lot of money or at worse they lose some lives and they put it on ai,
Speaker 3:  then that's probably a likely thing. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  America is very much in the Let's touch the stove Yeah. Moment. Yep. Right?
Speaker 4:  Like, let's just see is it hot? Right. Let's just super, it's touch it as
Speaker 4:  hard as we can and I think that's where we are with AI. And I, I just think
Speaker 4:  that we're also in a moment where a bunch of parents are
Speaker 4:  really rethinking the value of the phones for their kids. Yes. Just across
Speaker 4:  the board and one or two more of these
Speaker 4:  stories where a bunch of kids circulate
Speaker 4:  non-consensual deep fake nudes of each other.
Speaker 4:  You can just, right. It's like we're also in a political environment where
Speaker 4:  we have a bunch of politicians, we're like, I'm I'm gonna do stuff. Right.
Speaker 4:  And this is, you can just point a lot of that energy at this 'cause no one
Speaker 4:  can argue about it.
Speaker 2:  Yep.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I think I'm, I'm, I'm a yes on this one. I have no idea what it'll
Speaker 1:  look like, but I think the idea that I, I just think about like Cambridge
Speaker 1:  Analytica, which was one of those things that Right. For,
Speaker 3:  For, I think that's what we we're gonna, we're definitely going to get one
Speaker 3:  of those at some point.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. For whatever Cambridge Analytica was. Right. And wasn't, it was like,
Speaker 1:  it was a thing everyone Yes. Knew about and could reference and talked
Speaker 1:  about. And I think we haven't had any of those with AI specifically yet.
Speaker 1:  And I think we're gonna get one actually.
Speaker 3:  And that's why I think it's gonna be like, something institutional, like
Speaker 3:  it's gonna touch
Speaker 1:  A hospital is a really interesting one. Honestly. Like you could see a bunch
Speaker 1:  of ways that could get, I think
Speaker 3:  It's gonna touch some part of life and I hear what ne is saying about the
Speaker 3:  kids, but I just don't think there's enough outrage. Like there's outrage
Speaker 3:  about it, but like Yeah. Everyone agrees. Like, you know, kids have too much
Speaker 3:  tech
Speaker 1:  Kids don't have the juice. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like there's already all, everyone like it. Every side
Speaker 3:  agrees.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And yet here we are. Yeah. Alright. Bye. So
Speaker 1:  we're, we're all in on this one. Alright, let's
Speaker 1:  All right. Right. We're back. I have a bunch of streaming ones that we're
Speaker 1:  gonna do, streaming entertainment, et cetera. I'm gonna get you outta here
Speaker 1:  on time. I promise. I see you looking at your watch.
Speaker 1:  One or more of Max Paramount Plus and Peacock no longer exists.
Speaker 4:  Max, I feel like I have to disclose already. 'cause
Speaker 4:  Peacock is owned by Comcast, a Comcast investor on Rocks Media. I made a
Speaker 4:  Netflix show.
Speaker 3:  Do you really have to disclose these
Speaker 4:  Things? We do it every time. Really? And when we don't do it, the people
Speaker 4:  yell at us. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Disclosure is our brand. Joanna? Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 4:  One time in our disclosure Start Joanna.
Speaker 1:  Want an Emmy? Can we disclose that? And we should
Speaker 4:  Dis
Speaker 3:  Disclosed?
Speaker 1:  'cause it done disclose Disclosure
Speaker 3:  Happened. Done.
Speaker 4:  One time I reviewed starlink and I said this is kind of spotty If you shine
Speaker 4:  it through trees and most people have trees in the backyard. And then I was
Speaker 4:  like, what's the disclosure? My wired internet connection is superior
Speaker 4:  to this. And I was accused of being a Comcast show because I said wireless
Speaker 4:  wired connections are better than wireless ones. And I was like, if that's
Speaker 4:  where we're at,
Speaker 3:  Was Peacock an option there?
Speaker 1:  Peacock Paramount plus Max One or more of those three services
Speaker 1:  in particular. Paramount Plus is Gone. Does not exist at the end of 2025.
Speaker 4:  Although I will say they're like all in on letting Taylor Sheridan do whatever
Speaker 4:  he wants, which is like a reasonable strategy
Speaker 4:  actually. Like I watched Landman, it does
Speaker 1:  Kind of work. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  The Billy Bob Thornton one, I was like, oh, you should just let Teo Sheridan
Speaker 4:  do whatever he wants. It's pretty good. He's kind of like redneck
Speaker 4:  Aaron Sorkin. Like, it's just like a, a lot of nothing happens in these
Speaker 4:  shows. And then there's an explosion.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But like the dialogue is crisp right through
Speaker 4:  Out and like everyone's walking and talking and they're like, man, that's
Speaker 4:  been about an hour. Something should blow up
Speaker 4:  every one of these episodes. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  He's Aaron Sorkin, not Coastal Elite.
Speaker 1:  I love it. It's good. Okay. But
Speaker 4:  I but they're done. That deal will go away. That's not him. Drive enough
Speaker 4:  steps for them.
Speaker 3:  I really love Max. That's my, that's my contribution here. Oh, I
Speaker 4:  Should have picked Max
Speaker 1:  To Die. To die. Yeah. I think I love Max. One of Max on. Max. Max
Speaker 1:  in Paramount Plus is gonna be gone. I don't which one. It's Max forever.
Speaker 1:  There's gonna be some, max
Speaker 3:  Has to be doing pretty good
Speaker 4:  Because they're being run so well by Warner Brothers. Discovery. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  That's, that's going great.
Speaker 3:  They have decent programming on there.
Speaker 4:  What do you watch on Max?
Speaker 3:  I just watched all of industry.
Speaker 4:  Sure. Okay. Industry solid people like that show. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Gen Z succession. They call it
Speaker 4:  One One. Show
Speaker 3:  Hacks.
Speaker 1:  Hacks is good. Hacks.
Speaker 3:  I think we watch Paw Patrol through Max.
Speaker 3:  Maybe not.
Speaker 4:  It sucks that my kid is named Max. Yeah, it
Speaker 1:  Does. It does. Joanna just calls Max and says, describe
Speaker 1:  Paw Patrol to me.
Speaker 3:  We also watched Jurassic Park on there.
Speaker 4:  Did your kids have a crush on Chase The dog. Max had a,
Speaker 4:  like a baby crush the dog. Like Chase was her favorite dog on Paw Patrol.
Speaker 4:  And I was like, why'd you pick the cop? Like why, why not? There's a water
Speaker 4:  dog.
Speaker 3:  Alex does. Alex does like, no, I think he, he really likes rubble. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Rubble's great. Rubble's great. You know, he like, he fixes stuff.
Speaker 3:  Do we watch it through Max
Speaker 4:  Cop dog?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. See, I would argue this, this might not be the great case
Speaker 1:  for Max that you think it's,
Speaker 3:  But watch that on Max. Okay. I'll be honest. Like we had Peacock for the
Speaker 3:  Olympics. Don't have it anymore. Paramount. Don't have it anymore. Oh.
Speaker 4:  This is my other prediction. They will all solve this problem by not letting
Speaker 4:  you churn as hard as you can churn right now.
Speaker 3:  That I believe that I will a good one. Put
Speaker 1:  A lot on a good, that's a really good one.
Speaker 3:  But yeah, there was just that legisl like there's, was it, what's the
Speaker 3:  legislation that just happened that makes it, you have to make it. That's
Speaker 3:  click a cancel.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So how are they gonna get around that?
Speaker 4:  That's going away in the Trump administration. Yeah. Wow. Wow. A federal
Speaker 4:  agency doing stuff. Yeah. That's, that's all over now. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Especially 'cause Lena Conn did it.
Speaker 1:  All right. We're all saying yes to that one. Right. We're all,
Speaker 4:  We're all one of the three. You don't have to
Speaker 1:  Pick one, one or more of the three is is gone. Yeah. Again, my my time
Speaker 1:  travel is, you lose some stuff. It's hard to remember everything in the time
Speaker 1:  travel. Netflix is killing it in
Speaker 1:  live TV and is already the biggest thing in life.
Speaker 4:  No,
Speaker 3:  No
Speaker 4:  Disclosure. You already know this.
Speaker 1:  We did that already. Disclosure,
Speaker 3:  How long ago did that show? How long do you have? Many years. You have to
Speaker 3:  say that
Speaker 1:  Forever since
Speaker 3:  It's on there, it's gonna be on there
Speaker 1:  Forever. Video on demand. That's
Speaker 4:  Happens. Yeah. I didn't even paid for it. This is like the funniest part
Speaker 4:  of this. It's like, not even a conflict of interest. I just did the thing.
Speaker 3:  Do I have to have a disclosure that I talked to you when you were doing,
Speaker 3:  working on that
Speaker 4:  Show? If you wanna Sure. If you, if everyone like to remind everyone else
Speaker 4:  that I made an Netflix show, that's great for me personally.
Speaker 1:  Disclosure,
Speaker 3:  I spoke to Eli when he was working on Netflix, his Netflix show. And I also
Speaker 3:  talked to him when he had Comcast.
Speaker 1:  Well, you're clearly in somebody's pocket. Yeah. I don't know who
Speaker 4:  It's if I had Comcast, you mean the service in Chicago? You
Speaker 3:  Still have Comcast?
Speaker 4:  No, I, we, there's no Comcast out here.
Speaker 3:  What do you have? Xfinity. Isn't Xfinity
Speaker 4:  Content? Do I have to disclosure? I Fios and it rules. I dis
Speaker 4:  wired. Internet is better than wireless internet. My friend
Speaker 3:  Disclosure. I also have Fios.
Speaker 1:  Well, I have Ting. Let's go.
Speaker 4:  We're conflicted out.
Speaker 1:  Ting maybe. All right, next one. We're all saying no on that one. Yeah, we're
Speaker 1:  good. Okay. They
Speaker 4:  They have a long way to go. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Jake Paul needs to fight somebody else and then they
Speaker 4:  Have a big test Christmas this Christmas. Yeah. I I I reserve the right to
Speaker 4:  revise this after the NFL on Christmas on Netflix.
Speaker 4:  But I, yeah, I
Speaker 1:  Don't think they're right. Netflix certainly has the money to do it, but
Speaker 1:  it's, it's harder work than anybody thinks. Grand Theft auto launched
Speaker 1:  Grand Theft Auto six rather. Grand Theft Auto six launched. And it is the
Speaker 1:  single most successful game in history and has basically changed the video
Speaker 1:  game industry all by itself.
Speaker 4:  That's a, that's too many ideas. So I I say yes
Speaker 4:  to launch
Speaker 1:  Grand Theft Auto six is the Prince that was promised. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's too many ideas.
Speaker 3:  It launches.
Speaker 4:  It launches, it makes a bunch of money. Agreed. Okay. Everyone else has
Speaker 4:  already tried to do the big game as a service
Speaker 4:  thing. What was the Sony one that just failed Concord. Yeah. Everyone
Speaker 4:  just wanted to do Fortnite and it like didn't work. You need to have the
Speaker 4:  big property that can support it. Grand Theft Auto is one of those properties.
Speaker 4:  Yep. Changes the, I think everyone's gonna be like, man, I wish we'd invented
Speaker 4:  Grand Theft Auto. And they will continue not investing money into these things
Speaker 4:  that fail.
Speaker 1:  But you think Grand Theft Auto on its own big hit's gonna
Speaker 1:  work. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I mean, assuming it's not a disaster, but I think a lot of people are gonna
Speaker 4:  die. Well,
Speaker 1:  No, this is, this is the prediction we have to make here. It's, I mean the,
Speaker 1:  the reason I put this in is that we have had a long run of huge
Speaker 1:  expensive games that haven't worked for one reason or another.
Speaker 1:  And if that happens to GTA six, it's gonna be a disaster. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Like this, this is the most hyped game in forever
Speaker 1:  and it has been around for forever there. It has like loomed over the gaming
Speaker 1:  industry for years and if it doesn't hit and it's not as
Speaker 1:  good and big and exciting and cool and groundbreaking, like GTA
Speaker 1:  five is still a wildly successful game. If GTA six flops,
Speaker 4:  Chris Grant, who's our publisher and the founder of Polygon is always showing
Speaker 4:  me this chart that's like the highest grossing games in the world. And they're
Speaker 4:  all over like seven years old. Yeah. They're all very old. 'cause they've
Speaker 4:  all just turned into these places where people hang out. So GT six has a
Speaker 4:  long road.
Speaker 1:  It does
Speaker 4:  Like cyberpunk 27 7 came out and it like didn't work and then now it works
Speaker 4:  and like everyone loves it,
Speaker 1:  But a lot of, a lot of heads rolled in the meantime. Yeah. All right. I'm
Speaker 1:  in on this one. Sounds like you are too.
Speaker 3:  I have no idea what you're talking about.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Joanna's, just a big question mark. Okay,
Speaker 1:  few more. It's the end of 2025. And folding phones are
Speaker 1:  completely mainstream now
Speaker 3:  Unless Apple's releasing one and they're not. So no,
Speaker 4:  You don't think they are.
Speaker 1:  One of the other ones I was gonna put is
Speaker 3:  In 2025. I don't think So.
Speaker 4:  I think it's actually very funny that Apple thought I could drive a supercycle
Speaker 4:  with AI and really it just needs to make the phone fold over and that would
Speaker 4:  be the thing.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Well a hundred percent drive a supercycle.
Speaker 1:  What if I changed it to Apple released a foldable iPhone or iPad.
Speaker 1:  Apple released a foldable something in 2025.
Speaker 4:  The displays aren't gonna have
Speaker 3:  It. They released a foldable MacBook, which is just a MacBook as it's a laptop,
Speaker 1:  But it's a MacBook. You can, you can, it just folds scrunch up into your
Speaker 1:  pocket.
Speaker 3:  It's just like that. But it has a better chip that's, they're foldable for
Speaker 3:  the year.
Speaker 1:  Alright, so you're out on foldable phones going mainstream.
Speaker 3:  I think they will go mainstream once Apple has one.
Speaker 1:  But you don't think it's next year? No.
Speaker 3:  Okay.
Speaker 1:  Neli?
Speaker 4:  No, not next year.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I'm out too. I think it's coming. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Think I continue to
Speaker 3:  Use 26 is was
Speaker 1:  Fold foldable phones and flip phones, which I all Yeah. Collapse into
Speaker 1:  folding phones. It will be a thing are going to happen. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. They're getting better. Not next year. I see 'em, I see 'em a lot now.
Speaker 1:  Okay. The Pixel 10 is by far the best and
Speaker 1:  most successful Android phone.
Speaker 3:  What is success? How is Best Measured?
Speaker 1:  I'll, let's just land on best. It is by far the best Android phone.
Speaker 3:  How is Best Measured?
Speaker 4:  You are a product
Speaker 1:  Reviewer. Yeah. Right. You
Speaker 4:  Are the lead product reviewer of the Wall Street Journal.
Speaker 3:  How is it
Speaker 4:  Measured? How are you having this like, existential debate about what's a
Speaker 4:  good phone? How do you, what do you think a good phone is?
Speaker 3:  Best? Fine. I think we've all agreed that it's been the best Android phone
Speaker 3:  for a long time. Wait,
Speaker 4:  Are we agreed on that? I
Speaker 3:  Mean,
Speaker 4:  Go on.
Speaker 3:  I will say I do not think Samsung has, other
Speaker 3:  than some hardware improvements, I do not think they've had substantial
Speaker 3:  improvements to their phones.
Speaker 3:  And I think they lean very heavily on their relationship with Google to do
Speaker 3:  all the work. And Yeah. Like at this point, like
Speaker 3:  nobody,
Speaker 4:  You don't think the Galaxy fold is better than the pixel fold?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I guess Foldables, I would say they've done a better job on the
Speaker 3:  hardware and they're fine. But I guess I'm talking about like
Speaker 3:  flagship phones that continue to be the most popular. Yeah. That is
Speaker 3:  always gonna be Samsung. They're going to, sorry. And I say this by
Speaker 3:  sales, Samsung will continue to sell more phones whether they
Speaker 3:  have the best one or they don't. And that's just been the story of Android
Speaker 3:  for how many years?
Speaker 1:  All of them. Pretty
Speaker 3:  Much. Is that going to change in 20 20, 20 25? Well,
Speaker 4:  You think right now the pixel's a better phone than whatever Galaxy?
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 3:  I prefer, I will always prefer the software experience of the Pixel.
Speaker 3:  I just do.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I I I don't disagree with you. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So I mean, like, you know, I I don't know the, like
Speaker 3:  can it, the Galaxy take slightly better photos in
Speaker 3:  my last testing like two years ago. I don't know, like did that change?
Speaker 3:  You guys tell me. Not at all. I haven't done camera testing of the Pixel
Speaker 3:  in the Samsung in probably two years.
Speaker 4:  They, at this point, they're all on top of each other. It's
Speaker 3:  Like, yeah. Right. So I come down to on, okay, there's a great
Speaker 3:  software experience on the Pixel and people, they,
Speaker 3:  they gained one point of market share I believe
Speaker 3:  this
Speaker 4:  Year. Well they also, according
Speaker 3:  To IDC,
Speaker 4:  Google can't try very hard. This is a real,
Speaker 4:  they'll break them up. This is a real problem for them. Right. Because they
Speaker 4:  can't piss off Samsung. Right.
Speaker 3:  So I guess that's where I was like success and best. Like sure
Speaker 3:  it's the best. But you first said success, which you
Speaker 3:  changed. Wait,
Speaker 4:  Read, read your thing again. If we
Speaker 1:  Wanna just, I originally said best and most successful,
Speaker 1:  but if we wanna split hairs, we can do one and the
Speaker 3:  Other. I think those are very different things. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Well, yeah, they are different things, but I'm telling you both happened
Speaker 1:  hairs in 2025.
Speaker 4:  Oh, then that's a hard no. If it's both absolutely not.
Speaker 3:  That's what I'm saying. Okay. Okay.
Speaker 1:  All
Speaker 4:  Right. But I will it remain the best one. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  How do I write that in my notes about what you guys said? All right. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I think we're all, we're all No on that one. I
Speaker 3:  Mean, but like, what is the most exciting thing that's gonna happen in smartphones
Speaker 3:  in the next year?
Speaker 3:  What are we all gonna be excited about when Samsung comes out with the gala?
Speaker 1:  Ossibly, it's ai.
Speaker 3:  And is that something we're gonna get excited about?
Speaker 1:  No.
Speaker 4:  Bluetooth six
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth is ai. I've come full circle.
Speaker 1:  All right, let's do a couple more. Joanna, you have to leave here in a minute.
Speaker 1:  Let's do a couple more. Apple is actually making a television. It's
Speaker 1:  official.
Speaker 4:  There's, there's been rumored again recently. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  They've been making television.
Speaker 1:  It's real. This time Apple is going to sell you a television
Speaker 3:  It thousand and eight,
Speaker 4:  Not in 2025. But they, I think that the rumors on this will heat up. Apple
Speaker 4:  is out of markets. This is a real problem. They don't make enough stuff.
Speaker 4:  It's weird that they don't make enough stuff. The
Speaker 1:  The longer I, I wrote this one down originally, like as kind of a joke. And
Speaker 1:  the longer I think about it, the more I wanna say yes. Right. But
Speaker 3:  This year,
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I think it's
Speaker 4:  Possible. It's, I mean, it's not like hard to do
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  TV's right? Like at the end of the day, they gotta buy an OLA panel from
Speaker 4:  Samsung. They gotta glue an Apple TV to the back of it and they're gonna
Speaker 4:  be like $6,000
Speaker 3:  And they gotta make some nice frames Yeah. To put around it.
Speaker 4:  It's weird. 'cause the thing you're saying about cable television dying and
Speaker 4:  all this other stuff like runs against Apple doing a tv.
Speaker 1:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  It's a real problem. I I think they might have missed the window on doing
Speaker 4:  this. I think
Speaker 1:  Unless Apple thinks there's a giant ads business in being
Speaker 4:  A, or or an extension of their services business. Sure. But they were chasing
Speaker 4:  other huge iPhone sized markets and the only ones that could identify were
Speaker 4:  healthcare and cars. And they got run outta cars. Yeah. It's too hard. I
Speaker 4:  know what they're gonna do in healthcare over time,
Speaker 3:  But if the home, which seems to be this big place, they're gonna focus some
Speaker 3:  of the effort this year. And they do this home tablet sometime this
Speaker 3:  spring. Seems like something between an iPad and a
Speaker 3:  Apple TV type of thing. Yeah. In terms of like
Speaker 3:  software. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right. Yeah. They gotta put another screen in your house and they gotta find
Speaker 4:  a way to charge you
Speaker 3:  Money garage. So let's say they put another screen in your house that's home-based.
Speaker 3:  Is it a TV this year or is it this like
Speaker 4:  Tablet? No, they're gonna do this little thing first.
Speaker 3:  Right. So I don't know if, I think this TV thing is to your point, like they've
Speaker 3:  gotta go to other markets. This makes sense. They can finally say, Hey, we've
Speaker 3:  got it all integrated. It's just one cord into the wall. Like, great. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But then does that happen this year?
Speaker 1:  I'm
Speaker 3:  Saying that, I don't think it happens this year. No,
Speaker 1:  I'm in on it.
Speaker 4:  I think, I think we're gonna hear a lot about it this year. They're gonna
Speaker 4:  feel that just a ma like Apple making a TV like
Speaker 3:  Reports.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We're gonna hear a lot of noise.
Speaker 3:  This Mark Urman is gonna be very busy talking about this this year.
Speaker 4:  Does an Apple TV have HTM I ports?
Speaker 3:  No.
Speaker 4:  Well then what are all the people Psi gonna do?
Speaker 3:  They're not, they're
Speaker 4:  Not. So you're gonna make it a TV that just excludes No.
Speaker 1:  It'll it'll have ht MI
Speaker 3:  Ports. You think so? This
Speaker 4:  Is complicated. It immediately makes it complicated.
Speaker 3:  See, I think that's what they've wanted to do, is to like one port.
Speaker 3:  Like it just plugs in.
Speaker 1:  But again, if, if you're doing, if you're doing the home stuff you're talking
Speaker 1:  about, you could sell me a bunch of new screens or you could take advantage
Speaker 1:  of the big screen that sits in the middle of everyone's house and is like
Speaker 1:  this Gen tui on our team keeps railing on this. Like, the TV
Speaker 1:  is the center of the smart home. It is. I love that. It's ridiculous. Love
Speaker 1:  that. That no one has solved this yet.
Speaker 3:  I love when my garage door opens and I see a little alert on my TV
Speaker 3:  that says Garage door open
Speaker 1:  And it's two o'clock in the morning. And you didn't do that on purpose. And
Speaker 1:  here we are. All right. Last one. And then Joanna, you're gonna go,
Speaker 1:  what do I wanna do? Last Waymo's self-driving cars are now everywhere in
Speaker 1:  New York City.
Speaker 3:  No, I just interviewed the CEO. No, but I, but they will
Speaker 3:  be like in a lot of other cities.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I I picked New York specifically. Yeah, because it is, it is probably
Speaker 1:  the highest
Speaker 3:  Bar. I think New York is like New York. They are working on, but it's,
Speaker 3:  it's not, not yet. You don't
Speaker 4:  Think so New York also has the weather issue that they are, the last time
Speaker 4:  I talked to to Cadra, she was, I was like, can you get this thing in
Speaker 4:  Aspen, Colorado? And she's like, no. Right. She's like, no. Like
Speaker 4:  we can't solve that problem yet. Like, weather is too hard. And New York
Speaker 4:  has enough weather where I think it's too, that's
Speaker 3:  True. Do you think they'll, they're testing here. Apparently
Speaker 4:  They are. And there's aspects of New York that are Make it simpler.
Speaker 4:  Totally. It's a big grid. Yeah. You can just like solve that problem. But
Speaker 4:  there's two feet of snow on the ground gets rolled icy.
Speaker 3:  There's not bike lanes. I think New York's really challenging.
Speaker 4:  No, I'm saying there are aspects of New York that make it simpler. Yes. Than
Speaker 4:  LA or whatever. Right? Like, So
Speaker 3:  I think like Brooklyn makes a lot of sense.
Speaker 4:  Just like no laws in Brooklyn, no laws in
Speaker 1:  Brooklyn,
Speaker 3:  But like, you go down Manhattan. Manhattan is gonna be tough for them. But
Speaker 3:  whether there's a lot of reasons, I think. No, but I think we are gonna,
Speaker 3:  I I think that 2025 is the year that
Speaker 3:  me, I don't wanna say most people,
Speaker 3:  A lot of people will go in Waymo's for their first time. Mm. Okay. And you'll
Speaker 3:  see tons of it on social media.
Speaker 1:  It's it's gonna have its moment.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's gonna have its moment. Okay. Because like, I was in LA last week
Speaker 3:  and everyone who was in LA was trying it. It was like a total viral thing.
Speaker 3:  So it's coming to Austin. Phoenix. They're already
Speaker 3:  in San Francisco. They're working on getting on highways. It's already in
Speaker 3:  la. They expanded. It's gonna, people are gonna talk about it when they go
Speaker 3:  to these cities. Okay.
Speaker 1:  I like this one. I'm changing this to Waymo is going to have its moment.
Speaker 4:  Waymo has a real problem though because their platform is the Jaguar I pace.
Speaker 4:  Oh. And Jaguar has decided to just Yeah. Be an
Speaker 4:  influencer company now or whatever it is. Like they need a new
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Okay. I have a couple here that rhyme
Speaker 1:  slightly with some of the stuff we were talking about last week. The first
Speaker 1:  one I have here is the new Alexa is sick and everybody likes it.
Speaker 3:  I like sick.
Speaker 1:  It's sick. It's not just like, it
Speaker 3:  Actually physically
Speaker 1:  Gets sick. Sick.
Speaker 4:  It's literal
Speaker 1:  Cold's. Like my Alexa has been throwing up on me.
Speaker 3:  It's so sentient. It's like, ugh,
Speaker 4:  Wait, wait, I'm in. If we are like, it has an illness,
Speaker 3:  I cannot send it timer
Speaker 4:  If we're, if if it's sick, it's so cool. It's sick. I'm out.
Speaker 1:  It's, it's so cool. It's sick.
Speaker 4:  Has it appears to have an illness I'm in.
Speaker 3:  It appears to have an illness and it's, so it's, it has such a strong
Speaker 3:  personality that it develops sicknesses and
Speaker 3:  colds and has Stomach Pro. It's like, oh, you ordered. I would say If you
Speaker 3:  ordered too much Whole
Speaker 1:  Foods, If you could set the character as just like your ill relative who
Speaker 1:  lives with you, that would be incredible.
Speaker 1:  And anytime you ask it for anything, it's like, ugh.
Speaker 3:  Anyway, I'm totally in on Alexa having an illness. Okay.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well, I think we're both, we're both picking illness.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I'm, I'm writing illness. I'm in on
Speaker 1:  this one. My, I I think Amazon
Speaker 1:  is, that
Speaker 3:  Is actually a best case scenario for the launch is they, they put these in
Speaker 3:  homes and it's so sentient and it's, and it, and it believes
Speaker 3:  it's alive that it's like, sorry, I can't, I can't order the Whole Foods
Speaker 3:  today.
Speaker 3:  Sorry, I can't tell you if the package was delivered. Do you like my
Speaker 3:  Oh, sick Alexa voice.
Speaker 1:  That's pretty good. I
Speaker 4:  Don't worry that if I react to it too much, it's racist.
Speaker 4:  Like it's like a little too neurotic. You know what I mean? Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. That's fair. All right. Well
Speaker 4:  I could do anxious Indian mom. Yeah. Do it. Like, do you think that's gonna
Speaker 4:  work?
Speaker 3:  I think you need more of a stronger accent there, but I get You're not wanting
Speaker 3:  to go racist. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Should I go to med school? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  See what I
Speaker 1:  Mean? All right. Next up. Blue Sky is every bit as big
Speaker 1:  as threads.
Speaker 3:  I think it already kind of is. I don't know. Is it,
Speaker 4:  You're having a real, what? Is everything existential crisis over there?
Speaker 4:  No, absolutely not. They're gonna keep juicing the threads, numbers with
Speaker 4:  Instagram forever. Is Blue Sky more relevant on threads?
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  Relevant? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Because of the
Speaker 3:  People that are there.
Speaker 4:  Because of the people that are there. Is that where the conversation is?
Speaker 4:  Okay.
Speaker 1:  I'll, I'll allow both of these. So Blue Sky is more relevant than
Speaker 1:  Threads, you're saying? Yeah. But
Speaker 4:  Threads will be huge and Threads is just gonna be, it's already hundreds
Speaker 4:  of millions of people, right? Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It's, it's probably given what we've heard from earnings and since they're
Speaker 1:  probably like knocking on the door of 300 million users.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's, and they're gonna keep juicing it with Instagram and it's a
Speaker 4:  creator platform and it will, that will be a thing. I think
Speaker 4:  Blue Sky, who knows how big it will get. I'm very high on
Speaker 4:  interop and Fed verse and all this stuff, but the, the ceiling
Speaker 4:  that we know of is Twitter, which at its heyday was 325 million
Speaker 4:  people. And So I think Threads can get bigger than that because they can
Speaker 4:  just keep juicing it with Instagram.
Speaker 1:  Hmm. That seems right to me. I think the threads is going to be so big and
Speaker 1:  so integrated into Instagram that it's actually going to be more
Speaker 1:  powerful than it would've been on its own. But I think the cool kids
Speaker 1:  will be on Blue Sky and that matters like the what are, what are people on
Speaker 1:  cable news going to read and put on the screen as they talk about it?
Speaker 1:  I would bet on Blue Sky. Yeah. Over Threads. If it's those two
Speaker 1:  against each other, I would bet on Blue Sky.
Speaker 3:  Well, this goes back to your cable dying thing from last week.
Speaker 3:  But I think those people continue to stay on X.
Speaker 1:  Interesting. Okay. So the answer is kind of neither one.
Speaker 3:  I I think it depends, but like, I hear what Neil is saying on the relevant,
Speaker 3:  like, if, if it continues at this pace, and it can bring over people
Speaker 3:  that are breaking news there, and it is more of the conversation, but they've
Speaker 3:  got to keep, I mean, this is where the Reds has done a slightly better job,
Speaker 3:  is getting politicians and celebrities and they've had those people, but
Speaker 3:  they're not actively posting there. Right. So if they can build the
Speaker 3:  relevancy on Blue Sky and get those people coming over and actually consistently
Speaker 3:  posting, I'm in.
Speaker 1:  Okay. It is,
Speaker 4:  I don't think they're gonna say an X though. X has gonna have the same algorithmic
Speaker 4:  brain rot as threads.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right.
Speaker 1:  It's just a different kind of gas leak social network. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's just like threads. Like I keep making this distinction and I probably
Speaker 4:  need to like explain it better, but I think you have
Speaker 4:  creator platforms now and you have social media platforms and like most
Speaker 4:  things have become creator platforms where they're walled gardens. They're
Speaker 4:  focused on keeping your engaged time on those sites high. They're algorithmic
Speaker 4:  for you recommendations. They're entirely built around
Speaker 4:  incentivizing creators to run content businesses on the terms of the platforms.
Speaker 4:  That's threads. Got you. Like that's the shape of threads.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But you're talking old school social media. You go, you share your
Speaker 3:  thing. You don't care if people leave. You're, you've got links. Yeah. You're,
Speaker 3:  it's, it's a portal to the web. Right.
Speaker 4:  Well, I mean that part is interesting, but the part where it's like, I'm
Speaker 4:  going here to follow a bunch of people and see what they're talking about.
Speaker 4:  And those people are not professional content creators
Speaker 3:  And they're not totally like after the algorithm and juicing the
Speaker 4:  Algorithm. Right. And so Blue Sky just is much more of that. And Twitter
Speaker 4:  used to be that to whatever extent. Yeah. And I think that that
Speaker 4:  is gonna be where that class of people wants to gather because the
Speaker 4:  economics and the in incentives of creator platform algorithms
Speaker 4:  just
Speaker 3:  Make it that way.
Speaker 4:  They just make it that way. And X is headed that way. Yep. In a, in like
Speaker 4:  a meaningful,
Speaker 3:  Explicit way. It's also like all they know how to do. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So I, and that's what Ellan wants, like Elon's, like just don't do lazy links,
Speaker 4:  just like put your content on the X
Speaker 1:  Platform. I was just gonna say, I keep being really struck by how meaningful
Speaker 1:  a thing it is that Blue Sky is the only one that's like, we love when you
Speaker 1:  link to stuff. Yeah. It's like there's a whole group of people on the internet
Speaker 1:  who are very important who just link to stuff. Yeah. And, and if all of those
Speaker 1:  people go to Blue Sky like that, that's a pretty meaningful thing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But I don't know if that, that ceiling is bigger than 325 million people.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Maybe not. Hmm.
Speaker 4:  Like that was as big as Twitter ever got.
Speaker 3:  Comes back to my prediction from last week. We're all going to be just posting
Speaker 3:  everywhere.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I'm with you. But
Speaker 3:  Hopefully there's a system where it's
Speaker 1:  Easy. Yeah. All right. Two more and then we're outta here. Apple launched
Speaker 1:  the search engine. Call it, it, it doesn't have to look exactly like Google,
Speaker 1:  but it is recognizably a web search engine.
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Apple's gonna start to hedge and the AI will give them the cover to Hedge.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I
Speaker 3:  Was gonna say, I think yes, but it's under the guise of AI
Speaker 3:  and it might link into, you might be able to search chat GBT or
Speaker 3:  Gemini or I don't know, Claude, whatever businesses they actually partner
Speaker 3:  with. I think we're gonna see those partnerships happen this year. And so
Speaker 3:  that's their answer to search.
Speaker 1:  Do you think they do it? I think
Speaker 3:  Apple will also knows people are using these apps, these AI apps as search.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Oh yeah. So they're getting ahead of that and they will, well, they'll
Speaker 3:  be a little bit behind that in some ways.
Speaker 4:  Apple also has a giant library of content that they
Speaker 4:  don't really expose to anyone. And Apple News, like if what you want is like
Speaker 4:  a bunch of recipes, they're in Apple News. Apple,
Speaker 3:  I think this is a year for Apple News. Like more happens
Speaker 3:  in Apple News or more hooks into Apple News to your
Speaker 3:  point. Yeah. I mean it's just because I think that, I think Apple News is
Speaker 3:  another place with that home display where they can really take advantage
Speaker 3:  of it.
Speaker 4:  Oh, for sure. Yeah. And, and if your thing is like the web is getting poisoned
Speaker 4:  and search is bad and that thing, you're like, well, I'll just point to people
Speaker 4:  Yeah. To high quality content to
Speaker 3:  The source.
Speaker 4:  I mean, If you go look at what's trending Apple News, you will Yeah. I'm,
Speaker 3:  I'm aware.
Speaker 4:  I'm aware. It's, it's like a lot of like old people yelling at stuff, you
Speaker 4:  know, like the number one story at Apple is always a Buzzfeed article
Speaker 4:  that's like, why are these kids stupid?
Speaker 3:  It's our like a Huffington Post thing that's like ripped off three times
Speaker 3:  from something else.
Speaker 4:  You can really get a sense of who a platforms users are. Yeah. By the most
Speaker 4:  popular post on the platform.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I, I'm out on this one just because I think
Speaker 1:  the $20 billion from Google really spends, and I think if you're Apple
Speaker 1:  trying to balance those two things, you're just gonna land
Speaker 1:  on the side of we're gonna keep taking the money as long as the money is
Speaker 1:  here.
Speaker 3:  And Yeah. I mean it doesn't necessarily mean they like change what happens
Speaker 3:  through Safari search. I just think they're going to, maybe they don't call
Speaker 3:  it search,
Speaker 1:  But it was part of, part of the stuff that came up during the search trial
Speaker 1:  was essentially Apple agreeing not to launch a search engine while they had
Speaker 1:  these deals. So I think that stuff is just, I think, gonna take a while to
Speaker 1:  unwind. I think If you gave me like three years instead of one year, I would
Speaker 1:  say yes, but I don't know. Doesn't seem
Speaker 1:  like it's gonna happen this fast. But you also may be right that like they're
Speaker 1:  one button away from the chat GPT integration. Yeah. Just being live web
Speaker 1:  search. Like it just could happen.
Speaker 3:  It's really slow and bothersome anyway.
Speaker 1:  Agreed. Okay, last one. The Nintendo Switch came out,
Speaker 1:  and I hate to break this to you, but it's kind of a bust.
Speaker 4:  Ooh, that's tough. It all, it all
Speaker 4:  depends on the packing game.
Speaker 4:  No, I'm out. There's no way They, they, they, they won't blow it. That's,
Speaker 4:  that's too outta character for
Speaker 1:  Nintendo. I don't know. The Weu exists. They did, they did do the Weu.
Speaker 4:  No, not still out. No.
Speaker 1:  All right. I I, I wanna believe I'm saying,
Speaker 1:  I'm saying no just because I am at this
Speaker 1:  moment avoiding buying a PS five because I want the new switch very badly.
Speaker 1:  And if it sucks, I'm going to have wasted six months of not buying a game
Speaker 1:  console. So I need the new
Speaker 3:  Switch. Is the switch supposed to come out
Speaker 1:  Sometime before the end of March was what Nintendo promised.
Speaker 1:  So like with, we're, we're, we're in the sort of any minute now phase
Speaker 3:  That changes some things for me.
Speaker 3:  Hmm. They couldn't get it out before holiday anyway. I, I have no, maybe
Speaker 3:  that's
Speaker 1:  'cause it sucks
Speaker 3:  This's the first time I'm hearing of this, So I I do not,
Speaker 4:  I don't dunno what video games are,
Speaker 3:  Whatever video games I'm gonna learn soon. 'cause I have a kid that finally
Speaker 3:  into video games.
Speaker 1:  You gonna buy him a switch?
Speaker 3:  Well, I was going to,
Speaker 1:  But maybe it sucks,
Speaker 3:  But now I'm waiting 'cause I don't know.
Speaker 4:  Hmm.
Speaker 1:  I will say I have,
Speaker 3:  So I should wait now.
Speaker 1:  The current switch and it is slow and I would very much like the new one
Speaker 1:  to be faster.
Speaker 3:  I'm sure they'll do that. You would hope So. I'm waiting then.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's successful because I have bought one.
Speaker 4:  You've already bought one. Perfect. No, there's no way that it's a bust.
Speaker 1:  Okay, great. I hope, I hope we're right. Yeah. I believe in all of us. All
Speaker 1:  right. I, this is too many things to go back over. I'm gonna put all the
Speaker 1:  results in the show notes, but thank you both. This is delightful.
Speaker 1:  We agreed more than I wanted to, but it's okay. We did all right.
Speaker 3:  You seem like you've had a great year. I've won. 2025 was good to you, David.
Speaker 1:  2025. Listen, it's been complicated. Yeah. I've forgotten some of the details,
Speaker 1:  but I'm killing it. Yeah, that's all I can tell you. Yeah, you, I'm on top
Speaker 1:  of the world.
Speaker 3:  You still fitting your clothes from 2024? I,
Speaker 1:  I have been wearing this sweater for 365 days and no one has noticed until
Speaker 1:  you just now
Speaker 3:  It's just, you own that many versions of that sweater. It's a good year for
Speaker 3:  you.
Speaker 1:  All right, thank you both.
Speaker 1:  Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today, and that's it for our two part
Speaker 1:  mini series about 2025. Thank you to Neli and Joanna for
Speaker 1:  doing this deeply silly thing with me. And thank you As always for listening.
Speaker 1:  I hope this was fun. I really enjoyed doing these two. We just got to
Speaker 1:  have some wild speculation time and that is rare in this
Speaker 1:  business. We had a good time. There is lots more on all of this at The Verge
Speaker 1:  dot com and there's going to be lots more on all of this for the next year.
Speaker 1:  I think inside of these two episodes, you can sort of see what we're thinking
Speaker 1:  about for the next year. A lot's gonna change. A lot's gonna happen.
Speaker 1:  We're probably not going to Mars in 2025, but a lot of things are gonna happen
Speaker 1:  and we're gonna be covering it all. So keep it locked on The Verge dot com.
Speaker 1:  It's a good website. I'm slightly biased, but I kinda like it. And As always,
Speaker 1:  If you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or other things that you definitely
Speaker 1:  for sure a hundred percent think are gonna happen in 2025, you can always
Speaker 1:  email us at Vergecast to The Verge dot com or call the hotline eight six six
Speaker 1:  VERGE one one. We truly, truly love hearing from you. We're gonna do a couple
Speaker 1:  more hotlines at the end of this year and then we have a big plan for all
Speaker 1:  of the stuff we're gonna get to do next year. So keep calling, keep emailing,
Speaker 1:  keep it locked on The Vergecast. This show is produced by Liam James Wil
Speaker 1:  Pour and Eric Gomez. The Vergecast is VERGE Production and part of the Vox
Speaker 1:  Media podcast network. We'll be back on Tuesday and Friday with your regularly
Speaker 1:  scheduled programming. We are nearing the end of the year and we're gonna
Speaker 1:  take a break at the end of the year, but we got a couple more fun things
Speaker 1:  for you before we do. We'll see you then. Rock and roll
Speaker 2:  Support for The Vergecast comes from Polestar Pole Star's. First, all
Speaker 2:  electric SUV Polestar three is now on the roads across the US
Speaker 2:  and it's ready to make an impression. It's got a sleek
Speaker 2:  aerodynamic exterior and a spacious, minimalist interior.
Speaker 2:  Its custom developed. Android Automotive OS is totally integrated
Speaker 2:  made to enhance your driving experience. That includes an intuitive
Speaker 2:  infotainment screen, smart voice controls, and over the air updates.
Speaker 2:  And you can have Google Turn on your favorite podcast whenever you want to
Speaker 2:  be immersed in 3D surround sound by Bowers and Wilkins. See what
Speaker 2:  else Polestar three has to offer when you test drive at your local Polestar
Speaker 2:  space. Book yours today@polestar.com.