# Transcript
ID: c0243cea-cc56-44e5-acd7-40022692089a
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4742942631772175572/-2803630046333972925/s93290-US-6023s-1726664208.mp3
Description: We've finally finished testing, scoring, and reviewing Apple's new gear for the fall. On this episode we talk through our reviews of the iPhone 16 and 16 Pro, the Apple Watch 10, and the AirPods 4, to see whether they're real upgrades and whether they're worth your money. And then, on the Vergecast Hotline (866-VERGE11), we make the case for the Pixel in 2024.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (33 ads detected)
Speaker 1:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of ugly
Speaker 1:  color tinted app icons that we love. Anyway, I'm your friend
Speaker 1:  David Pierce and I bought a new computer monitor. This is
Speaker 1:  not like exciting big news, but to me it is exciting and big news. I went
Speaker 1:  from 24 inches to 27 inches, which is
Speaker 1:  actually a bigger difference than I expected. I almost got a 32 inch monitor,
Speaker 1:  but the idea of being one of those people who has to like look from side
Speaker 1:  to side to see everything on my screen just felt
Speaker 1:  ridiculous. It's just a normal like 4K de monitor.
Speaker 1:  I don't think I'm good enough or sensitive
Speaker 1:  enough to need a studio display or one of those LG ones that
Speaker 1:  everybody likes that are, you know, thousands of dollars. I'm a simple man
Speaker 1:  with simple pixel needs and this one makes me happy. But there is
Speaker 1:  one feature about it that I deeply, deeply love already.
Speaker 1:  So, I spend all of my time staring into webcams, right?
Speaker 1:  I'm doing podcasts, we're making videos. I'm just in meetings.
Speaker 1:  I'm using webcams all day, every day. That is the life of of modern
Speaker 1:  person it seems, and I never know where
Speaker 1:  to look, right? You can do the thing where you like barrel the camera and
Speaker 1:  it kind of freaks everybody out 'cause they're making eye contact with you
Speaker 1:  over zoom. Or you can sort of look way down and
Speaker 1:  they're looking at the top of your head, but you're looking at them and so
Speaker 1:  there's no eye contact. It's weird. And what this monitor does
Speaker 1:  is it just lets me, it just lets me slide it up and down. So I can go, I
Speaker 1:  can go down so it's easier. It's like right at eye level. I can make
Speaker 1:  eye contact, I can move it up. So then it's up there and it's
Speaker 1:  nice and high and now it's not weird because I can look at
Speaker 1:  sort of a normal distance and I'm looking right into the screen and not into
Speaker 1:  the camera. I love it. Now I can just
Speaker 1:  make whatever level of eye contact I want to and I can wield eye contact
Speaker 1:  as a weapon instead of just awkwardly sort of staring down
Speaker 1:  all the time. I'm unstoppable now. My webcam game
Speaker 1:  is on point anyway. We're not here to talk about computer monitors or webcams
Speaker 1:  or my deep eye contact. We are here to talk about Apple
Speaker 1:  reviews. That's what we're gonna do on this whole show. All the new devices
Speaker 1:  came out, we've reviewed all of them. That's actually the reason the show
Speaker 1:  is a day late. Embargoes make everything complicated, but all
Speaker 1:  of our reviews are out. The new iPhones, the new Apple watches, the new AirPods,
Speaker 1:  everything. And we're gonna spend this whole show talking about those, whether
Speaker 1:  you should buy them, whether they're good upgrades, what all this means for
Speaker 1:  the future of everything in our lives. So much to get to. It's gonna be very
Speaker 1:  fun. All that is coming up in just a second, but I
Speaker 1:  have been sitting here staring into this camera for way too long now and
Speaker 1:  I gotta go take a break before we get into it. This is The Vergecast. We'll
Speaker 1:  be right back.
Speaker 1:  where saying the words iPhone or 16 all just sounds not
Speaker 1:  like words anymore. You know, that happens. It's not great, but
Speaker 1:  some spec bumps, some new buttons, some old buttons on new
Speaker 1:  phones. An interesting lineup this year. And I would say one of
Speaker 1:  the more complicated ones to suss out which phone
Speaker 1:  is actually the right one for most people. So we're gonna get into that.
Speaker 1:  Neil Patel and Allison Johnson have been reviewing these things ever since
Speaker 1:  we got them and heard about them last week and they have lots of thoughts.
Speaker 1:  Let's dive in. Neil Patel. Hello? Hello. Alison
Speaker 1:  Johnson. Hi. Hello. Okay, so just to like pull back the cover
Speaker 1:  slightly here we are doing this 24 hours before the
Speaker 1:  review embargo, not even 20 hours before the review embargo for the iPhones,
Speaker 1:  which is not a super fun time to do anything.
Speaker 1:  If, you are the person having to review the iPhone. So just thank you both
Speaker 1:  for doing this to me. And also If, you just sort of like disappear into
Speaker 1:  insanity in the middle of this. I will, I will understand.
Speaker 3:  Well actually, can I say one thing about that, which is I think very funny,
Speaker 3:  please. The review period is a day longer than usual,
Speaker 3:  even though there's a full days less worth of stuff to talk
Speaker 3:  about on these days,
Speaker 1:  Right? 'cause the event was a Monday and it's normally Tuesday to Tuesday.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And now it's Monday to Wednesday.
Speaker 1:  It's Monday to Wednesday. Yeah. Every new button we get an extra day
Speaker 1:  I think is how it works.
Speaker 3:  It's just fun. It's like for, for as little stuff as there is to say, we
Speaker 3:  have much more time to say it, which I think is fascinating.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So, but I,
Speaker 3:  But please keep it this way Apple, if you're listening. Oh yeah. More time
Speaker 3:  is better. Which I've been telling them for a full decade.
Speaker 1:  No takebacks. Yeah, yeah, agreed. This is the bare minimum forever.
Speaker 1:  Apple. Okay, so Allison, you're doing the
Speaker 1:  regular iPhones and Neli, you've, you've been reviewing the pro, is that
Speaker 1:  right? Yes. Okay, so let's just quickly dispense
Speaker 1:  with all the stuff that is not on these phones yet, which is any sign of
Speaker 1:  Apple intelligence. Have you noticed, like it's been a weird time. That was
Speaker 1:  the big thing. They talked about the, the iOS 18 came out,
Speaker 1:  there's a bunch of new stuff in there, but none of the really Apple intelligence
Speaker 1:  stuff, like do these phones feel incomplete in your lives
Speaker 1:  without Apple intelligence stuff? Like how much should people write off the
Speaker 1:  fact that none of that is here yet?
Speaker 4:  No, I'm, I'm finding it kind of easy to ignore. Like there's,
Speaker 4:  there's a ton of new stuff in iOS 18 actually without all the Apple
Speaker 4:  intelligence. So it just very much feels like the new
Speaker 4:  iPhone. Like there's two new buttons on the regular version. There's all
Speaker 4:  this stuff to dig into in iOS 18. So
Speaker 4:  that it's kind of outta my mind for the moment for sure.
Speaker 1:  Neela, what about you? We had a big argument about this last week. We
Speaker 3:  Did. I think these phones are incomplete in that
Speaker 3:  it's hard to make the case to buy one If. you have an
Speaker 3:  iPhone and the reason that you might buy particularly
Speaker 3:  the regular 16 is that it has the eight gigs of ram, which supports Apple
Speaker 3:  intelligence, which is not here. So If, you have a regular iPhone and you
Speaker 3:  upgrade to the new iPhone 16, you'll have a nice experience. I,
Speaker 3:  Allison has had a nice experience. It's a nice phone, it's seven ninety nine,
Speaker 3:  you get a bunch of stuff, but it will be
Speaker 3:  essentially the same experience as upgrading a regular phone to iOS 18.
Speaker 3:  And I think that's a real problem for Apple. I feel the same way on the pro
Speaker 3:  as well. Particularly if a 15 pro, there is zero reason
Speaker 3:  to get a 16 pro. Hmm. The 15 pro is getting Apple intelligence
Speaker 3:  when it arrives. It's just hard to make the case So I. I've
Speaker 3:  spent a week with these phones, I've come up with one reason to upgrade them
Speaker 3:  and that is so wonky and you have to
Speaker 3:  be such a photo nerd to even make the argument that I don't think
Speaker 3:  it's convincing.
Speaker 1:  Okay, well that is where we're going to spend most of our time. But I, I
Speaker 1:  am curious, big picture, Alison, has that been your, your takeaway too? Like
Speaker 1:  pretty good phone, nothing to sort of run out to the store
Speaker 1:  for here?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think, like, I agree with everything Neil says
Speaker 4:  except that there's no reason to upgrade to it. I think it is like
Speaker 4:  it's, it's the, we're on like a three or four year cadence of
Speaker 4:  like, you hold onto your iPhone and you're sort of doing this dance of
Speaker 4:  like, should I upgrade? Should I not upgrade? And this is excluding anybody
Speaker 4:  who's like super interested in a five x telephoto lens or like any of
Speaker 4:  the, the cool pro stuff that happens. So, I don't, I think for someone who's
Speaker 4:  doing that dance of like, is it now do I upgrade now? Like this
Speaker 4:  is a really good year to upgrade, but yeah, you, it's it's
Speaker 4:  gonna be an iPhone. It's gonna be a lot like the iPhone you had.
Speaker 1:  I do like that as a way of thinking about it actually. 'cause there is the
Speaker 1:  question of like, is this the phone you've been waiting for?
Speaker 1:  And I think the answer is no. But the question is if, if the
Speaker 1:  question is, should you wait for the next one, the answer's also kind of
Speaker 1:  no. Yeah. Which says something about like the, just the path that we're on
Speaker 1:  with the iPhone, but it's also a nice place to be. It's like, If, you need
Speaker 1:  a new phone, go buy this one. You'll like it. Yeah. And it will do the things
Speaker 1:  that are coming, you won't feel left out by the time we get
Speaker 1:  to the next one.
Speaker 3:  There's also just the reality of how most people are acquiring these phones
Speaker 3:  now, which is they're, they're on payment plans, they're carriers on a cycle.
Speaker 3:  Right? So will this phone just happen to you? It will, it
Speaker 3:  will just occur to you and you'll, you'll fi you'll wake up one day and you'll
Speaker 3:  have an iPhone 16 and that will just be the end of it. And I think that's
Speaker 3:  fine and weird, but it is true as Allison points out. But those upgrade cycles
Speaker 3:  can get much longer now. And that to me is why I keep saying the phone's
Speaker 3:  incomplete because you would ideally Apple
Speaker 3:  would get to push up the upgrade cycle by offering the suite of new
Speaker 3:  features that you can't get on any of the other iPhone. And that is just
Speaker 3:  not the case right now.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that, that's fair. So before we get into the camera stuff, which is
Speaker 1:  I assume where we are going to get very lost in the weeds of, of Eli's feelings,
Speaker 1:  is there anything else about these that you wanna like, spend some time talking
Speaker 1:  about? I think we've talked about the action button feels like it's good
Speaker 1:  that that's coming to the, the base level phones. Has anything else really
Speaker 1:  like jumped out at you and your experiences here? Alison, I'm particularly
Speaker 1:  curious for you with the, the entry level phone quote unquote
Speaker 1:  entry level phone.
Speaker 1:  Is there anything that you feel like has, has jumped out in your experience
Speaker 1:  so far that we should talk about?
Speaker 4:  No, it's sort of just been a feeling like, oh, this is nice
Speaker 4:  that this is here. You know, I spent some time with a 15 pro
Speaker 4:  before I moved over to the 16 that I'm reviewing
Speaker 4:  and just feeling like, oh, okay, I get this little action button and I program
Speaker 4:  it to open the daycare app. So when I'm signing my kid out, there isn't like
Speaker 4:  a line of people behind me while I'm fumbling around trying to find an app.
Speaker 4:  So it's like, just, just little nice, nice to have things here and there.
Speaker 4:  But yeah, the, the real actions in the, the camera stuff I think.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Let's, let's just get into this now and
Speaker 1:  Neli I would like you to explain, so what I would call
Speaker 1:  not quite an existential crisis, but like a deep philosophical
Speaker 1:  hole you have fallen into over the last week about
Speaker 1:  the iPhone sixteens camera. Yeah. What has your experience been?
Speaker 3:  There's just a lot going on with this camera. So I think the first thing
Speaker 3:  to say is that the pro camera is, is in fact
Speaker 3:  significantly better than the regular iPhone 16 camera. We've gotten a lot
Speaker 3:  of questions from folks that are asking whether the pro is worth it this
Speaker 3:  year because on paper the specs seem pretty much the same And, then
Speaker 3:  you actually look at the photos and the pro cameras just substantially better.
Speaker 3:  The main camera is substantially better. It can capture more light, it has
Speaker 3:  bigger pixels, all this stuff. But as you use them, and particularly as you
Speaker 3:  use the new photographic styles, Alison and I have been talking and the entire
Speaker 3:  vibe from Apple is like, you figure it out.
Speaker 3:  Like what does, what do you want? What do you want photos to look like? You
Speaker 3:  just, you just, you, whatever you want is fine. Whatever color you want the
Speaker 3:  people to be is fine. And that is just like,
Speaker 3:  it's not wrong, right? Like that is a pretty valid approach to
Speaker 3:  give the person taking the photo control over what the photos look
Speaker 3:  like. But Apple also ships the most popular camera
Speaker 3:  in the world and it, it is like they have just let go of having a
Speaker 3:  point of view, which is I think a big change.
Speaker 3:  And it's not a big change in the sense that like it's doing wild AI stuff.
Speaker 3:  It's just a big ch like once you let go of what
Speaker 3:  color people are like, it's, there's not much left
Speaker 3:  to hold onto. You know what I mean? Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Real quick, how do you actually use the styles? It's, it's a thing we saw
Speaker 1:  like bits and pieces of it in the announcement, but you guys have actually
Speaker 1:  used these, like how do they fit into the workflow of using the camera
Speaker 3:  In, in like 10 different ways?
Speaker 1:  Well this is why I ask because it's, it's not, my initial impression was
Speaker 1:  that it was kind of like an Instagram filter where like you take a picture
Speaker 1:  And then it's like these are the things it can look like it, it seems like
Speaker 1:  it is that and not that at the same time
Speaker 3:  It is, it is not though there it's much fancier than Instagram filters. But
Speaker 3:  at the end I think most people perceive them to be Instagram filters. Okay.
Speaker 3:  Do you know what I mean? Like they're an Instagram filter literally just
Speaker 3:  sits over the top of your photo, right? Apple controls the whole imaging
Speaker 3:  pipeline so it can just do a higher quality job of adding colors and
Speaker 3:  shadows and whatever. So yeah, apple is running the same,
Speaker 3:  you know, take up to nine photos, HDR imaging pipeline
Speaker 3:  that they always have been, they call it photo engine, which is very funny.
Speaker 3:  And all they've really done is reshuffle the steps so that you can edit the
Speaker 3:  styles after you've taken a photo. That's it. Like, it's the same
Speaker 3:  basic steps as the iPhone 15. And the thing that they've changed is
Speaker 3:  when you take your nine photos that expose everything in the
Speaker 3:  photo evenly, now you can do things like change which
Speaker 3:  parts of the photo expose at what rates, how many shadows there are.
Speaker 3:  They can semantically detect faces. So you can
Speaker 3:  adjust things like the undertones and skin tone, which is one set of filters.
Speaker 3:  Or you can go pretty wild into what they call the mood filters.
Speaker 3:  Then that's much more like the Fuji film recipes where you're like
Speaker 3:  simulating a film stock that has different colors and it, it's cool, all
Speaker 3:  of it is cool And. then the actual controls of it are, you can do it live
Speaker 3:  with a preview. You can switch the styles using the new camera control
Speaker 3:  and you like slide along And. then there's a really important control that
Speaker 3:  we'll get to called Tone, which you can also adjust while you're taking a
Speaker 3:  photo that is the HDR ness of a photo,
Speaker 3:  for lack of a better term. And you can just turn it down. Like
Speaker 3:  when I say there's one reason to buy this camera, it's that you can just
Speaker 3:  turn off apple's super intense HDR look and make
Speaker 3:  it look like a normal camera again. That's, and so you can control
Speaker 3:  that. Or once you've taken a photo you open the, the
Speaker 3:  photo picker and you can change the styles and it is a
Speaker 3:  dpad, which is a, just a totally fiddly
Speaker 3:  way of dealing with this. Yeah. But it's like you have a, a little two axis
Speaker 3:  dpad of what your photo looks like and you can mess around with it
Speaker 1:  Is, so this sounds like the kind of thing that is like extra
Speaker 1:  editing features as the way you're describing it, which seems like
Speaker 1:  fine, they're just like, here's some stuff you might do in Lightroom. We're
Speaker 1:  gonna let you do it in the photos app.
Speaker 1:  Allison, are you using this as, as much as Neli is? Like has this
Speaker 1:  caused you as much philosophical pain as this has caused Neli over the last
Speaker 1:  week?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I, I don't know if pain's the right, well no pain is the right word.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I am super into it. Like I, I am a person
Speaker 4:  who want, I want more shadows in my photos. I'm, I'm tired of,
Speaker 4:  you know, everything being smooshed into this gray middle ground. Yes.
Speaker 4:  And this feels like the answer to a lot of people
Speaker 4:  being like, skin tones look weird on my iPhone
Speaker 4:  or like, I don't like all this HDR processing and yeah, they're just going
Speaker 4:  like, okay, you do the work then.
Speaker 4:  But I like that 'cause I like getting in there and messing with
Speaker 4:  things. It's kind of wonky how you set it up.
Speaker 4:  Like I think with the previous photographic styles you would just kind of
Speaker 4:  swipe to one And then like you can make that your
Speaker 4:  default from the camera app. I think this time
Speaker 4:  around you kind of have to go through this like setup process
Speaker 4:  where it's like, pick four of your favorite photos that you've
Speaker 4:  taken with this camera. And there's like a whole philosophical thing of
Speaker 4:  like, you know, the, the thesis is like to get you
Speaker 4:  to dial in the skin tone, you kind of prefer like
Speaker 4:  a warmer or cooler cast. And so you're like, is this four
Speaker 4:  pictures of me? Is this four pictures of my kid? Like what, what does this
Speaker 4:  mean? So there's a weird kind of, I kind of had to work
Speaker 4:  through all that And then I settled on one. I think I like
Speaker 3:  Allison and I both have families with ranges of skin tones in them. So you're
Speaker 3:  like, I'm gonna pick these four photos And, then I'm gonna pick a style.
Speaker 3:  And it's like who? Yeah, I think we both landed on our kids. Yeah. Who
Speaker 3:  are like interesting in the middle.
Speaker 4:  Like, like I only, I only accidentally take a picture of my husband
Speaker 4:  sometimes like it's all pictures of my kid. But yeah,
Speaker 4:  he is sort of in the middle ground there. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And that picker is actually really interesting 'cause you open it and it
Speaker 3:  says pick four photos and you think you're gonna do something
Speaker 3:  algorithmic or mathematical, but it's just a preview. Hmm. It's
Speaker 3:  just preview. Like you can slide through the presets And, then pick one you
Speaker 3:  like And, then that is the default, which is I think a little odd. You can
Speaker 3:  also just change it after the fact. You can leave it, you can, you mess with
Speaker 3:  the camera controls. There's so many camera controls now you can leave it.
Speaker 3:  So it's sticky once you pick one. There's all the stuff you can do to
Speaker 3:  get the camera to consistently shoot the photos you want them to look, but
Speaker 3:  there's nothing bad at the sort of guides you to it
Speaker 3:  apart from pick four photos of someone and pick
Speaker 3:  an undertone that it becomes the preferred undertone.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's really interesting there there's, there's such a like power
Speaker 1:  of defaults thing in that that feels so unapply to me that
Speaker 1:  it's like app Apple is for better and for worse the
Speaker 1:  most aggressive company maybe in tech at being like, here is how this
Speaker 1:  should work. Yeah. And it has, it has sort of slowly rolled it back
Speaker 1:  in such a way that If you want to change things, you can, but it has
Speaker 1:  still always had really strong opinions about how things should be.
Speaker 3:  And so what's really interesting here is one, all of these features are on
Speaker 3:  both the pro phone and the regular phone. The camera control, the styles,
Speaker 3:  the sliders, the tone, all of it is there on both phones, which is
Speaker 3:  fascinating. And. then the default, the take it outta the box,
Speaker 3:  take a picture. It's even more HDR than it was before.
Speaker 1:  Oh really?
Speaker 3:  So Apple has heard all this feedback. They've got taken all this criticism,
Speaker 3:  you know, in the review video you'll see we just have a super cut of people
Speaker 3:  on TikTok saying the camera looks bad on the FN 15 Pro Alex
Speaker 3:  Earl to 7 million followers is like, why does the iPhone 15 camera suck?
Speaker 3:  I've been reviewing things a long time, I will never publish anything that
Speaker 3:  devastating. That's, that's bad, right? That's a bad place
Speaker 3:  for them to be. Yeah. And they, instead of walking it back, they've added
Speaker 3:  these controls, but then the photos one to one are
Speaker 3:  even brighter from the 15 Pro to the 16 pro. The photos from the 16
Speaker 3:  pro are even like massively brighter than the photos from the 16. So
Speaker 3:  Apple's really leaning into, we're gonna bring down all the bright parts
Speaker 3:  and bring up all the shadows and everything will be totally flat. So you
Speaker 3:  can see all the detail. But then they're adding this control, which is, you
Speaker 3:  know, tone is like a weird word to put in the top level
Speaker 3:  of a camera. Yeah. Right. And what they mean, what that means is
Speaker 3:  tone mapping, which is not a word that anyone knows. No.
Speaker 3:  Like it what most people when they see tone, I think they think of the old
Speaker 3:  control and like a CRT TV that would make everything green or like make
Speaker 3:  everything blue. Right.
Speaker 1:  It's it's a color slider. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Right. And this what this actually is a shadows. So they're, they're taking
Speaker 3:  that big stack of nine photos And, then they're, you know, by tone mapping
Speaker 3:  it, you're, you're saying, okay, I'm gonna find all the right exposures across
Speaker 3:  the whole image and add them all up. So you get one even image with detail
Speaker 3:  everywhere. So the blacks don't go to black and the brights don't go to white.
Speaker 3:  It's just gonna be stuff everywhere. And tone mapping by turning it down,
Speaker 3:  they're saying we're gonna do that less. And that's it. That's the whole
Speaker 3:  control. And it is confusing and weird and I think people are gonna think
Speaker 3:  it's just brightness, but it is actually controlling the HDR processing.
Speaker 1:  So it sounds like the possibility, like you're going to be
Speaker 1:  able to take better looking photos on the 16 maybe
Speaker 1:  than on any iPhone before. But If, you don't touch it, your photos might
Speaker 1:  be even worse.
Speaker 3:  And yeah, this, and to me yes, I agree.
Speaker 1:  Like lower floor and higher ceiling than a lot of iPhone photos
Speaker 1:  we've seen before. Yeah. Which is a really strange place to be. We're like
Speaker 1:  min maxing the, the phone set up here.
Speaker 3:  It's, we, I think Apple's default is getting away from them. I, I think they
Speaker 3:  have like some ideological rules about never wanting to lose any
Speaker 3:  detail, never letting things clip, never showing you noise. They're still
Speaker 3:  doing an awful lot of sharpening and noise introduction. Like
Speaker 3:  it's just all over the place in these phones. So if that's the thing that
Speaker 3:  bothers you, the tone control isn't gonna help you. But I think that
Speaker 3:  Apple has these rules that like If, you anyone pulls out a photo and takes
Speaker 3:  a photo, they should be able to generate a usable image no matter how hard
Speaker 3:  it is. Which is incredible, right? Like that has not been true
Speaker 3:  of most cameras in most situations. Right.
Speaker 1:  And that's a reasonable starting point.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like people love taking backlit photos. Like they, people are like
Speaker 3:  a window, let me stand in front of it. And then complain that the faces are
Speaker 3:  in shadow and the iPhone just doesn't have this problem anymore. Like
Speaker 3:  you can just do it and it can solve that problem, which is kind of incredible.
Speaker 3:  But it also means that other thing, like the trade-offs of that are, are
Speaker 3:  bad. Like people are complaining about those trade-offs now. But the weirdness
Speaker 3:  of it for me in, in sort of the upgrade conversation is If, you are the person
Speaker 3:  who didn't like the way the 15 photos looked. You're gonna not like the
Speaker 3:  16 photos even more unless you know to go into the
Speaker 3:  settings to mess with the tone control to set the, the undertones
Speaker 3:  to like, to really adjust the camera to your liking, which implies one,
Speaker 3:  you know why you don't like the 15 photos and two, you understand what those
Speaker 3:  controls mean so she can get them to a place where you do like them while
Speaker 3:  the default is getting worse. So you might be taking one step forward, but
Speaker 3:  actually like two steps back and the upgrade.
Speaker 1:  Well, and and to your point about this coming to all of the phones,
Speaker 1:  I think if you're Apple, you can get away with that
Speaker 1:  trade off to some extent on the pro and especially the pro max, right? Like
Speaker 1:  you're, you're selling these things to an audience of people who are willing
Speaker 1:  to pay more, to get more tools with which to
Speaker 1:  do stuff. And I think that's where you can say like, look, If, you want to
Speaker 1:  have this other stuff here it is, but it's, it's gonna be more complicated.
Speaker 1:  But here it is, I think on the $799 iPhone 16,
Speaker 1:  the default thing out of the box becomes much, much, much more
Speaker 1:  important. Yeah. And that's where I start to worry that you're gonna get
Speaker 1:  a lot of people who are disappointed with this camera because they don't
Speaker 1:  know and maybe shouldn't have to know all this other
Speaker 1:  stuff that they can do with it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I honestly think Apple should have labeled these presets in a much
Speaker 3:  stupider way. Like point and shoot camera, camera
Speaker 3:  with big lens, you know, like Yeah. Like
Speaker 3:  just some instead of right wing tone. Which again,
Speaker 3:  once you understand it, it's very powerful and it, to me it is the reason
Speaker 3:  to buy this phone. I am a very unique individual
Speaker 3:  in that sense. Like I just want shadows in my photo. I'm gonna spend money
Speaker 3:  on a new phone. Like weird, I own 50 cameras, I can just get
Speaker 3:  shadows at any time. Right. But I think for most
Speaker 3:  people these presets are just, they're a bunch of words. And then Alison,
Speaker 3:  I don't know If, you've had this experience, the camera control is pretty
Speaker 3:  sensitive and it's kind of easy to get yourself sideways.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. By adjusting stuff you had no intention of adjusting.
Speaker 1:  Oh, interesting. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I, I have had some struggles with the camera control and
Speaker 4:  boy was I primed to like it,
Speaker 4:  but I'm just generally finding it like really stiff
Speaker 4:  to like, you do the full press and you do the actual button press
Speaker 4:  to take a photo And, then there's all the other stuff that you can
Speaker 4:  accidentally mess with. It's, it's that like hap kind of light press
Speaker 4:  And, then you slide your finger to change one of
Speaker 4:  those settings or like do a double press and you'll pick another setting.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I found myself like I'm trying so hard not to shake
Speaker 4:  the phone and I'm pushing down on the shutter button but not hard
Speaker 4:  enough and I keep pushing and like my finger will move a little bit and
Speaker 4:  I'll change the exposure come up and I'm like, this is bad. Like
Speaker 4:  I was just trying to take a photo now. Yeah. Like I am paying way
Speaker 4:  more attention to like the camera settings than I am the thing I'm taking
Speaker 4:  a picture of.
Speaker 3:  Mostly I just want the controls to go away. Yeah, right. Once you adjust
Speaker 3:  like on any other camera you like adjust the control, your finger
Speaker 3:  doesn't stay on the control. Yeah. And this is because it's a
Speaker 3:  capacitive slider and a button you like adjust it with a capacitive part
Speaker 3:  And, then your finger's still on it to push a photo and the control is still
Speaker 3:  there. So you're still adjusting the control while you're pushing the shutter
Speaker 3:  button and it's all just a little bit too much. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  You're supposed to tap on the screen to get the controls
Speaker 4:  to go away. And I'm like, well then I'm tapping back, tapping under
Speaker 3:  It. I'm so
Speaker 4:  Close going back and Yeah, no, don't make me do that. You
Speaker 1:  Know what that makes me think of is like, you know when you're using a, a
Speaker 1:  game controller and you're supposed to click with the joystick and how long
Speaker 1:  it takes to learn to click the joystick without moving the joystick so that
Speaker 1:  you're suddenly slightly in the wrong place when you're clicking.
Speaker 1:  and we talked about this on the show last week that like the, the upside
Speaker 1:  of this would be forget all the funky stuff in the middle.
Speaker 1:  Mostly what you want to do is just mash the button and take a picture and
Speaker 1:  If you mash the button, it will take a picture. It sounds like it's actually
Speaker 1:  maybe not even quite nailing that, that sometimes you
Speaker 1:  wanna mash the button and you can't mash the button and so you're accidentally
Speaker 1:  doing the stuff in the middle while you're trying to just mash the button.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, no,
Speaker 3:  You can just mash the button. It's just If you change anything
Speaker 3:  using the button, then you can't mash the button anymore.
Speaker 1:  Oh okay. I see. Right. It's
Speaker 3:  Like you just can't get outta that unless you tap the screen and once you've
Speaker 3:  tapped the screen, you might as well just be tapping the screen.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Right. Yeah. At that point, what, what are we accomplishing here? Okay,
Speaker 1:  interesting. Ha. Have you guys liked the camera control? Like has it become
Speaker 1:  part of the sort of muscle memory of using your phone
Speaker 1:  in the time you've been testing it? I
Speaker 4:  Will say I'm using it to launch the camera and that I am,
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna stick with that. You know, like
Speaker 1:  So you're using it as an action button?
Speaker 4:  It's Yeah, but
Speaker 1:  I want my action button action.
Speaker 4:  I want two action buttons. I want the other action button to do whatever
Speaker 4:  I want And then this one, yeah. I'm using to launch the camera and I have
Speaker 4:  it set on exposure comp because if you've ever tried to
Speaker 4:  change the brightness of a photo while you're taking a picture on the iPhone,
Speaker 4:  it's like the most infuriating thing. So I think I'm
Speaker 4:  gonna like that in the long term. But yeah, I've just gone back to like launch
Speaker 4:  it with the camera control And, then push the onscreen shutter button.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Exposure conversation is a good one. 'cause that one you can't change
Speaker 3:  after the fact, but tone you can. Interesting. So you, you just,
Speaker 3:  again, you're just kind of like making all these like calculations while
Speaker 3:  you take an iPhone photo. Now
Speaker 3:  the other thing that I'll say is there are so many ways to launch camera
Speaker 3:  apps in iOS 18 on one of these new phones because you can set
Speaker 3:  the shutter button, the camera control button to open whatever So, I have
Speaker 3:  a preview version of Allied that you can just open there. There's, you can
Speaker 3:  change the button on the lock screen, you can set the action button to whatever
Speaker 3:  you want, And. then you can still from the lock screen, just slide over to
Speaker 3:  the right and open the stock camera. So by the end of this you'll be able
Speaker 3:  to open four different cameras from the logs, cameras
Speaker 4:  Everywhere.
Speaker 1:  A million ways in control center. You can, yeah. Anything the world is your
Speaker 1:  oyster so you can tap on the back to open it like this. Yeah. Open.
Speaker 3:  And I'll say we, we are, we, you know, as everyone knows, our rule is you
Speaker 3:  have to review what's in the box and you, you can't really talk about potential
Speaker 3:  or future products. That's our longstanding rule. It is
Speaker 3:  very obvious that one of the reasons you put a camera button like this on
Speaker 3:  the phone is so that when you do launch Apple intelligence and you have visual
Speaker 3:  intelligence and the phone can look at stuff, right? You can just get to
Speaker 3:  the camera as fast as possible or set one of these many ways to open the
Speaker 3:  camera to a regular camera and another one to an AI camera or whatever you
Speaker 3:  wanna do. None of that stuff is shipping it. But you can see how Apple's
Speaker 3:  creating a lot of options for what the camera is doing, only one of which
Speaker 3:  necessarily is taking a picture.
Speaker 1:  Right. Okay. Does all the stuff you guys have been talking about
Speaker 1:  apply to video as well? The, the styles, the defaults, some of the
Speaker 1:  same stuff. Like, I, I just thinking about this, 'cause I know with iOS 18,
Speaker 1:  a lot of people get really excited about the thing where you can pause a
Speaker 1:  video recording as you're going, which is such a small thing, but it's like,
Speaker 1:  it's a useful reminder that like, oh, these are as much video cameras for
Speaker 1:  people as they are. Anything else? What have you guys had with
Speaker 1:  video so far? Any feelings?
Speaker 4:  I, there is a new feature in the video
Speaker 4:  recording with a, I think it's called Audio mix,
Speaker 4:  where after you record your clip you can go in and it's, it's one
Speaker 4:  of those things that like 99% of people are not gonna find.
Speaker 4:  But you go in and edit your video and you can mess with the
Speaker 4:  like audio channels and I can't, I can't keep them straight
Speaker 4:  in my head. There's like in frame in studio
Speaker 4:  and they just change how much of the like subject you hear and how
Speaker 4:  much of the like background noise it tunes out. Or if I'm talking and
Speaker 4:  like saying dumb stuff to my kid while he's playing, like I can just
Speaker 4:  like erase that now and just hear him, which is ideal.
Speaker 1:  That's cool.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. So I've been playing with that a little bit and I, I always
Speaker 4:  forget how nice like the cinematic video is on the
Speaker 4:  iPhone, like even the regular iPhone. It's like kind of wild
Speaker 4:  that you get that from this seven nine nine phone. So
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So I've been shooting the review video with our video team with
Speaker 3:  Veen, our supervising producer. We tested audio mix on
Speaker 3:  a, in a street festival in New York City and it held up really, it
Speaker 3:  wasn't perfect. You can watch the video but it holds up, which is remarkable.
Speaker 3:  And that's 'cause they've added four studio quality mike's to
Speaker 3:  the iPhone, which is interesting. They record
Speaker 3:  spatial audio as well. But if they're really there for this
Speaker 3:  audio mix feature. And so If, you If you play the video
Speaker 3:  back on an Apple tv, it plays in 5.1 surround sound for some reason,
Speaker 3:  like not at now.
Speaker 1:  Your kid can sneak up on you.
Speaker 3:  It's just like, what is going on here? Your videos If, you airplay it, it's
Speaker 3:  only in stereo, but If, you somehow get the file to an Apple TV airplay through
Speaker 3:  photos or whatever. You get five phone surround, which is like a crazy thing
Speaker 3:  for a phone to be able to do. But it's all,
Speaker 1:  I live a surround sound video that I'm going to watch vertically on my phone.
Speaker 1:  Like yeah,
Speaker 3:  Perfect. It's, it took a long time. Port
Speaker 3:  the people at Apple, like I have a number of surround sign questions and
Speaker 3:  they're like, okay, like this is gonna take us a long time to get through.
Speaker 3:  So that's cool And. then, you know, the pro, the big feature is 4K one 20
Speaker 3:  and shooting 4K one 20 in log and you can attach all these extra external
Speaker 3:  drives. And Veen had the time of his life doing this and he came
Speaker 3:  away being like, this is fun. But one of the weirdest
Speaker 3:  pieces of this puzzle is that it's still an iPhone. It's like an
Speaker 3:  incredibly personal device tied to an iCloud
Speaker 3:  account that wants you to upgrade storage all the, like all the stuff.
Speaker 3:  And using it as a professional video camera is starting to run right up
Speaker 3:  against the fact that it's a phone, it's a phone meant for a person. Right?
Speaker 3:  It's, this isn't like a utility. Like at our office we have a
Speaker 3:  gear room where video producers from across the company, like check out cameras.
Speaker 3:  They're not like tied to their iCloud accounts. And so like you're just in
Speaker 3:  this place where this phone is getting in Incre becoming an incredibly powerful
Speaker 3:  video camera, but the way the software thinks about it is
Speaker 3:  still as one person's phone. And you're just kind of like running into that
Speaker 3:  reality. I think, I think Apple will find some way to solve it. It's obvious
Speaker 3:  they want people to use this as video cameras, but it that one context,
Speaker 3:  it's like, do you want install game center? And it's like, why, why do
Speaker 3:  I don't actually
Speaker 4:  You're shooting the weekend, there's, you know, a music video and
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And it, it's like you're getting an Rrc s message now it's like, I
Speaker 3:  don't wanna do any of this.
Speaker 1:  Right. Fair enough. Okay. So the,
Speaker 1:  the last thing I'm curious about is whether this has brought up any,
Speaker 1:  what is a photo apocalypse feelings from both of you? It doesn't seem
Speaker 1:  like Apple has done much of the, like, here's some wacky
Speaker 1:  editing stuff you can do that is either very cool or the end of truth in
Speaker 1:  humanity in the world. What has been your experience so far? Have
Speaker 1:  you had any of these feelings run across any of this stuff?
Speaker 4:  I, in my experience is a weird one because I more or less
Speaker 4:  came over from the Pixel nine. I was doing all those reviews and picking
Speaker 4:  up this,
Speaker 1:  Which is a full on what is a photo
Speaker 4:  Apocalypse? Yeah. It's just so beyond what is a photo
Speaker 4:  And then picking this up. I'm like, oh, I'm playing with sliders. Like I
Speaker 4:  am, I'm dialing in like saturation and contrast. It's like just such
Speaker 4:  a wildly different experience and I,
Speaker 4:  yeah, I, I'm digging it, but I haven't had anything, you know,
Speaker 4:  throw me into a, a whirlwind of what is reality
Speaker 4:  for sure.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I will say I've been using a pixel line and as part of this review
Speaker 3:  and also an S 24 Ultra and both of those phones are like ai, do you wanna
Speaker 3:  do some ai? Like you pick up a, a pixel line, you open the camera and it's
Speaker 3:  like, are you ready to make some weird stuff with me?
Speaker 3:  And there's like very And then this, this phone is not that. Apple is releasing
Speaker 3:  one feature with Apple intelligence, a feature called cleanup, which is basically
Speaker 3:  magic eraser that lets you take stuff out. So we'll see how that works and
Speaker 3:  we'll see if that causes any particular, what is a, a photo
Speaker 3:  apocalypse thoughts. But I think Apple is gonna play it pretty
Speaker 3:  safe. I I spent some time with John McCormick who is the
Speaker 3:  VP of camera software engineering at Apple every year. He and
Speaker 3:  I have like an existential dilemma about photography together
Speaker 3:  and I basically asked him to respond to the pixel team at Google
Speaker 3:  saying they now make memories instead of photos. Right. Which they said in
Speaker 3:  a wired piece and So I, like what's a photo? And so here's what he told me,
Speaker 3:  he answered, I've got John McCormack from Apple
Speaker 3:  answering the question, what is a photo in Apple's mind? So here's the quote,
Speaker 3:  it's long, I apologize. Here's our view of what a
Speaker 3:  photograph is. The way we like to think of it is it's a personal celebration
Speaker 3:  of something that really actually happened. Whether that's a simple thing,
Speaker 3:  like a fancy cup of coffee that I had that's got some cool design on it all
Speaker 3:  the way through to my kids' first steps or my parents' last breath. It is
Speaker 3:  something that really happened and it's something that is a marker in my
Speaker 3:  life and it's something that deserves to be celebrated. That's the
Speaker 3:  answer. It happened
Speaker 1:  Deserves to be celebrated is a really weird
Speaker 1:  place to end that thought. But I think the, like,
Speaker 1:  it, it is a, a personal celebration of something that really actually happened.
Speaker 1:  Something that really actually happened is like a, a, a thing I wholeheartedly
Speaker 1:  agree with. So I'm just gonna focus on that. That feels good.
Speaker 3:  I think this is tied to why they, why they are so intent
Speaker 3:  on bringing up the shadows and dropping the highlights and
Speaker 3:  capturing all of the detail and solving the backlit photo.
Speaker 3:  Hmm. Right. They're like, we are gonna get a photo of this,
Speaker 3:  whatever it's Right. And that I I think Celebr I agree with
Speaker 3:  you, celebration's an odd word, but I, I think what they mean of it is like
Speaker 3:  they need to honor the the moment
Speaker 1:  I see,
Speaker 3:  Right. Like that I've been, I've been puzzling over this quote since you
Speaker 3:  said it to me. And I, that's what I've gotten to is like, I
Speaker 3:  think that's why this camera is so aggressive at so many of the
Speaker 3:  things it does because Apple is, they do not want to be in the hook for,
Speaker 3:  it was the birthday party and you all stood in front of the window and everyone's
Speaker 3:  face was in shadows. Right. And the window is bright white, right. Like that
Speaker 3:  is a photo lots of people have taken by accident and Apple is not gonna let
Speaker 3:  that happen. Yeah. And I, you know, none of the phone manufacturers are gonna
Speaker 3:  let that happen anymore. They're all chasing that same idea, which is we
Speaker 3:  are gonna get this, we are gonna make this photo happen.
Speaker 1:  Right.
Speaker 3:  Like, and it's just, it it's gotten to like a set of aesthetic trade offs
Speaker 3:  that I personally think is weird. It sounds like Allison, you, you might
Speaker 3:  think shadows are good too,
Speaker 3:  but I Yeah, when I, I've been thinking about the word
Speaker 3:  celebration here for a minute. I I think that's what that means, right? Like
Speaker 3:  the, the taking of the photo as a real moment that we were not gonna screw
Speaker 3:  up and it actually happened. I'm curious, right, whether
Speaker 3:  over time the competitors who are less
Speaker 3:  idealistic push Apple off this position, you can already see it with some
Speaker 3:  of the aggressive processing they've done in response to Samsung in other
Speaker 3:  markets,
Speaker 3:  beautification filters and things like that are much more prevalent and much
Speaker 3:  more accepted in markets like China. Apple hasn't gotten all the way that
Speaker 3:  far, but they're starting to let people do it right in in different ways.
Speaker 3:  They're, they're starting to let go because that is the competitive pressure.
Speaker 3:  If Google starts selling a lot of pixel phones, 'cause you can just add weed
Speaker 3:  to every photo by, by literally writing ad weed to photo. Like who
Speaker 3:  knows what's gonna happen. Yeah. But that's where they're starting today.
Speaker 3:  And I think cleanup is like a little bit off of that. But his other point
Speaker 3:  to me was they only do things that are rooted in photographic tradition and
Speaker 3:  taking stuff outta the background at this point is pretty much a part of
Speaker 3:  photo photographic tradition.
Speaker 1:  I mean that's fair. I I think I buy that thesis. It does seem like a pretty
Speaker 1:  slippery slope from that sort of honorable
Speaker 1:  starting point. I think that is like we are, we are going to get the thing
Speaker 1:  you wanted to get damn the shadows and the aesthetics, right? Like
Speaker 1:  you're, you're gonna see all the faces in that backlit photo, even if it
Speaker 1:  makes everything else look like trash because the thing you wanted was the
Speaker 1:  faces. I actually think that's like a reasonable place to be,
Speaker 1:  but then it, it does cause lots of trade-offs and I think to your
Speaker 1:  point about like face filters and all this stuff, like Apple has seemed
Speaker 1:  to start coming to this place where they're like, we're gonna let you do
Speaker 1:  it. We're not gonna make it super easy. But If you want to do it If you want
Speaker 1:  to just nasty up your home screen.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 1:  You can now. Exactly. You can now. We don't want you to, but you super
Speaker 1:  can now and, and there is definitely a thing that Apple is like, look, If
Speaker 1:  you If you wanna ruin it, you can. That's on you dog.
Speaker 1:  Like, and I think to some extent I think that's actually the right approach.
Speaker 1:  But it's, it's interesting to see how far Apple will go
Speaker 1:  with that approach and just basically be like, we didn't do it. We just let
Speaker 1:  you do it. Which is very unapply and very
Speaker 1:  interesting to watch as it tries to figure all of this out.
Speaker 3:  I do think one of the reasons Apple hasn't gone into full, what is a photo
Speaker 3:  apocalypse territory is that there's no like meaningful at
Speaker 3:  scale photo verification standard that works, right?
Speaker 3:  There's C two PA, which literally the day we're recording Google said it's
Speaker 3:  gonna support in search and ads but not put in Android.
Speaker 3:  So this idea that you can like take a photo and have it verify
Speaker 3:  that this was a real photo that happened and you know, track the chain of
Speaker 3:  edits and know whether it was AI generated or not. And that's like
Speaker 3:  cryptographically in the metadata. That's a big idea. There's a
Speaker 3:  lot of companies signed up to make that idea work. Apple is not one of those
Speaker 3:  companies yet. And I, I think their point of view is we, we don't wanna adopt
Speaker 3:  this until we know it's gonna work and it's worth it. And it's actually the
Speaker 3:  thing that we wanna tie ourselves to because it is the most popular camera
Speaker 3:  in the world. So, I think if they can solve that problem or the industry
Speaker 3:  can solve that problem, which who knows big open question.
Speaker 3:  I think that gives all these companies more freedom to, to let you do all
Speaker 3:  kinds of wacky AI stuff. But I think you have to solve that problem first.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that makes sense to me. All right, last thing And, then we gotta take
Speaker 1:  a break. Battery life
Speaker 1:  full last week of feces about best battery
Speaker 1:  life ever. That didn't mean anything and didn't even have graphs that didn't
Speaker 1:  mean anything. Just a lot of open-ended statements about battery life.
Speaker 1:  Have either of you noticed any new changes in the
Speaker 1:  battery life of your iPhone in your testing so far?
Speaker 4:  I, I mean I'll say it's good but it's not like it's,
Speaker 4:  you can't get two days out of an iPhone battery all of a sudden.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's just sort of like, yeah, I think this is it. It keeps
Speaker 4:  up with me all day. I can do a whole bunch of stuff and stream the
Speaker 4:  radio station and do GPS and, and it's
Speaker 4:  okay. It's, I think the question in on
Speaker 4:  our minds is like, how is this gonna perform in the long run? Like
Speaker 4:  the 15 pro has been kind of notorious for running
Speaker 4:  down the battery health, like Yep. Alarmingly fast. So
Speaker 4:  yeah, it's, it's like TBD it's fine now on the 16 and
Speaker 4:  the 16 plus you can just like add 30% to
Speaker 4:  like, it'll go that much more 'cause it's just massive.
Speaker 4:  But that's been my experience.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I I have the same general experience, the 16 Pro Max,
Speaker 3:  which is a huge phone by the way. Yeah. It has bigger battery in it
Speaker 3:  and it runs longer. I mean, I've had the camera open and the screen on shooting
Speaker 3:  this video, the, the whole week basically. It's fine. It's, it's doing its
Speaker 3:  job but my 15 pro doesn't make it through the day anymore. And so
Speaker 3:  does a brand new phone make it through the day? Yes. I think that is the
Speaker 3:  case for every brand new phone, right. Six months from now or a year from
Speaker 3:  now when you're still looking at your $1,400 investment. Is it gonna,
Speaker 3:  is it gonna survive? And I I we have to find out, I think Apple is actually
Speaker 3:  on a bad run of this. I think the 14 pro was bad and the 15 pro was
Speaker 3:  bad and I'm hoping the 16 pro is better.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I agree. And e even in the best case scenario, it feels like we're
Speaker 1:  still very much at, you can use your phone all day, but you should probably
Speaker 1:  charge it every night. And until we're past that,
Speaker 1:  don't, don't give me big speeches about battery life.
Speaker 3:  Oh no, I'm in a, I'm in a different spot entirely.
Speaker 1:  Are you?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I'm at until I don't have to leave my house with
Speaker 3:  a little MagSafe battery, don't talk to me.
Speaker 1:  Oh wow. Right.
Speaker 3:  That's where I'm at with the 15 pro. I leave the house with a battery pack
Speaker 3:  or I put it into low power mode. Right. And that battery's only at 93%
Speaker 3:  according to iOS. That's
Speaker 1:  Pretty bad. I
Speaker 3:  Know people who are down in the eighties or after a year.
Speaker 1:  I'm at, I'm at 89. Last I checked a few days ago. Yeah, it's pretty bad.
Speaker 1:  And
Speaker 3:  You know this all this depends, it's impossible to measure like If, you stay
Speaker 3:  at home on wifi, okay these batteries are great, right? The second you leave
Speaker 3:  the house, you go into like three or four challenging cell environments.
Speaker 3:  If, you take the subway, you phone's, hunting between stations for signal,
Speaker 3:  like you're gonna run the battery on faster. So the idea that it is just
Speaker 3:  better is probably true in the beginning. You're gonna have a radically different
Speaker 3:  experience and I think Apple's challenge now is maintaining battery health
Speaker 3:  over time. Especially because the battery replacements on these phones are
Speaker 3:  more expensive than they're, than they were before. Right.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. All right, well we'll see, I think this is going to be a particularly
Speaker 1:  fun generation of iPhones to come back to in six months because
Speaker 1:  like you're saying, 'cause all the
Speaker 3:  Software will
Speaker 1:  Change, all the software will change. Literally. It's possible that the whole
Speaker 1:  like value prop of an iPhone will change if Apple is right about what
Speaker 1:  all of this stuff can do. Particularly
Speaker 3:  For the 16.
Speaker 1:  That's what I mean. Yeah, because
Speaker 3:  Then it, then it becomes the one that you're supposed to upgrade to. And
Speaker 3:  I, I just dunno. By the way, speaking of battery life, we have no idea what
Speaker 3:  the effect of Apple intelligence and battery life will be. Right. Here's
Speaker 3:  a bunch of stuff that might just be running in the background summarizing
Speaker 3:  everything on your phone at all times. and we don't know the Apple intelligence
Speaker 3:  goes to the cloud, right? The private cloud compute for a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 3:  Yep. It's gonna run your radios and a bunch of moments and we don't know
Speaker 3:  when or how like we're gonna find out.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, fair enough. Alright, we gotta take a break. Allison, you're gonna
Speaker 1:  come back in a little while 'cause we have one more thing to do on the show,
Speaker 1:  but thank you both Godspeed, finishing your reviews.
Speaker 3:  Thank you.
Speaker 1:  Thanks guys. Later.
Speaker 3:  Alright,
Speaker 1:  We gotta take a break And then we're gonna come back and we're gonna talk
Speaker 1:  Apple watch and we're gonna talk AirPods. We'll be right back.
Speaker 7:  material? Is that new? Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But So I think for the most part here, we should probably talk about the
Speaker 1:  series 10 because I think that is, that is the one with actual sort of new
Speaker 1:  stuff going on.
Speaker 7:  Some newness is is happening.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So let's start with the outside of it because there, I just
Speaker 1:  can't get over this video that like, it's still seared into my brain all
Speaker 1:  week of just this like very long pan shot down the watch
Speaker 1:  band and it's like, okay, sure we, this is a thing. But anyway,
Speaker 1:  how is it? It's, it's thinner, it's bigger. What's the verdict?
Speaker 7:  It's thinner and bigger and lighter, which you know that that is a thing.
Speaker 1:  Those are good things. I like all those things. Right? Those
Speaker 7:  Are good things. Those are good design choices. It's just
Speaker 7:  If, you know what an Apple watch looks like. No
Speaker 7:  amount of adjectives is going to really, you know,
Speaker 7:  change the fact that it looks like an Apple watch. It looks like, okay, all
Speaker 7:  the Apple Watch, like, you know, when we were in the theater and he's like
Speaker 7:  a design that you've never seen before. It's like, I Gretchen form you.
Speaker 7:  I have seen this design before. It is just been tweaked. Okay.
Speaker 7:  They're very nice tweaks. I'm not trying to disparage the tweaks. It
Speaker 7:  is, I will say there has been, even though there is like a,
Speaker 7:  a, a thinning of the watch, like it is a lot thinner, you know, take
Speaker 7:  a lot with a grain of salt. It's 9.7 millimeters that is quite thin for smart
Speaker 7:  watches. Generally we see them in the 11 to 13 millimeter
Speaker 7:  range, sometimes 14, 15 if they're chunkers. So that is
Speaker 7:  quite thin. I'm not, I'm not trying to say that that's not a a thing, but
Speaker 7:  I'm just saying it's, it's the, there has also been an in
Speaker 7:  beginning of it, because you know, when the first Apple Watch came
Speaker 7:  out back in 20 14, 20 15, it was 38
Speaker 7:  millimeters and 42 millimeters. Now we are at 42 millimeters and
Speaker 7:  46 millimeters. So the small watch has become what
Speaker 7:  was the biggest watch back in the day. It's
Speaker 1:  The, I mean this is, this is what happens, right? This is like the iPhone
Speaker 1:  intonating of Yes. The whole thing. This is, this is how it goes.
Speaker 7:  There is like a, a real sense that it's, you know, we're 10
Speaker 7:  years into the Apple Watch there is like an iPhone ification of it. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And, and that they're facing similar problems now where the updates
Speaker 7:  every year are iterative and like sometimes they feel very
Speaker 7:  iterative. Like, Ooh, I think I saw someone online say this
Speaker 7:  about both the phone and the watches. But it really feels like an S year
Speaker 7:  and yeah, it does, it does feel like an S year in some ways. And I think
Speaker 7:  people were hoping for more of like a big jump of a year. Okay.
Speaker 1:  But I will say, and this is, this is the thing about the little hardware
Speaker 1:  changes that I'm most curious about is the sort of
Speaker 1:  ideal watch. Screen size seems to be
Speaker 1:  bigger, while the ideal watch size seems to be smaller,
Speaker 1:  at least for me
Speaker 7:  There's a lot of min maxing happening.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And so what I wonder is with this one, does it feel like Apple
Speaker 1:  has gotten closer? I know you have kind of a tortured relationship with the
Speaker 1:  sizes of smart watches over the years.
Speaker 7:  I really do.
Speaker 1:  But I'm very curious if it feels like this one If, you can make it
Speaker 1:  a little bigger but a little thinner and a little lighter, maybe it'll still
Speaker 1:  feel smaller despite being bigger. And maybe that's the right
Speaker 1:  combination of things.
Speaker 7:  I think they're onto something. Okay. I, whether people appreciate that
Speaker 7:  is gonna be a different thing. But you know, I am wearing the 42
Speaker 7:  millimeter 'cause they sent me the smaller size. 'cause I am the smaller
Speaker 7:  person. So I have the 42 millimeter series 10.
Speaker 7:  Which do
Speaker 1:  You think is like the default size by the way? Like I feel like when it was
Speaker 1:  38 and 42, I think most people bought 42. But now that it's 42 and 46
Speaker 1:  If, you just pure off the top of your head, guess which would you think is
Speaker 1:  like the main one people have?
Speaker 7:  I would think the 42 to be quite honest because I think that's
Speaker 1:  Where I'm at too.
Speaker 7:  It's quite impressive. So actually the 46
Speaker 7:  millimeter series 10 has the largest display area of any
Speaker 7:  Apple Watch. And that is including the Ultra,
Speaker 1:  Which is nuts. Which
Speaker 7:  Is nuts when you think about it. Like truly the min maxing has happened here
Speaker 7:  with with the four four, the 46 millimeter. And that's quite impressive
Speaker 7:  and actually quite compelling to a lot of people who have ultras who don't
Speaker 7:  love the weight, me being one of them when I run.
Speaker 7:  And you know like I love our Blurple band but the problem with the
Speaker 7:  Ral band is that my wrist is a little too small. So I have to wear it a little
Speaker 7:  looser. So I really feel that drag when I'm running. That is
Speaker 7:  not the case when you have a series 10, it is thinner and lighter. It
Speaker 7:  feels like you're not really wearing quite as much when you go on a run.
Speaker 7:  So I think for some people that will be quite compelling. Especially since
Speaker 7:  I do have the 42 millimeter and I right, right on the same wrist
Speaker 7:  right next to the, to the Ultra. I'm not really
Speaker 7:  looking at that much smaller of a screen. So the 42 is slightly smaller
Speaker 7:  I believe, than the Ultra, but not by much.
Speaker 7:  Not by much.
Speaker 1:  And I remember when the first ultra came out, we were talking about it and
Speaker 1:  I think it was Neli who got really excited about it and he was like, let,
Speaker 1:  I'm just gonna love it with you. I'm not gonna use any of these features.
Speaker 1:  I don't care about any of the outdoorsy nonsense. I'm going to sit on my
Speaker 1:  couch and look at this huge screen and Apple Watch Ultra. And I think that's
Speaker 1:  a lot of people. Right. And I think especially as we get to
Speaker 1:  this thing where Apple is big on Glanceable information and it's an AI input
Speaker 1:  output system, like I kind of get the appeal of like, how much screen can
Speaker 1:  we put on your wrist before it feels bad? And it sounds like they've got
Speaker 1:  that balance kind of right? Like does that forever change
Speaker 1:  the appeal of an Apple watch? To most people it feels like, probably not.
Speaker 7:  Probably not. But within the balance, like as far as wearability goes,
Speaker 7:  like I, they did make some like meaningful, significant tweaks in
Speaker 7:  terms of wearability especially, you know, part of the impetus to make these
Speaker 7:  lighter and more comfortable and more wearable is, you know, sleep tracking.
Speaker 7:  Sleep tracking has historically not been the Apple Watch like
Speaker 7:  biggest strength. Just because one Battery life is not as impressive
Speaker 7:  as other wearables in this category. Which, you know, they're addressing
Speaker 7:  with faster charging but also comfort. Like I, I've been sleeping with
Speaker 7:  the ultra too for the past year. It's not fun. It's, it's not what I would
Speaker 7:  call the most comfortable smart watch to sleep with.
Speaker 7:  It's, it's just not agreed. So you know, in that respect I've been
Speaker 7:  wearing the series 10 to sleep and it's a lot more
Speaker 7:  comfortable than the ultra two. So, you know, sleep tracking is a thing that's
Speaker 7:  important to you. That is a thing. It, there is a blurring of the lines now.
Speaker 7:  'cause something that I've been thinking a lot about in the last couple of
Speaker 7:  days is the electrification of the series 10. Hmm. Because it does
Speaker 7:  feel like they were like hmm, there are certain things about the ultra that
Speaker 7:  have really gotten people excited. Let's port that over
Speaker 7:  to the series 10. So now you have people online just really confused
Speaker 7:  as to like, should I ditch the ultra? Because
Speaker 7:  as you said, some of these people are not athletes or not very like
Speaker 7:  into the training aspect or like the outdoorsiness of of the
Speaker 7:  ultra. So they don't need dual dual band GPS, they don't need
Speaker 7:  an 80 decibel siren that's like, you know, like these things that were made
Speaker 7:  for it to be extreme and raw outdoorsy. They just really want
Speaker 7:  that big beautiful screen and the lightness of it. So like for them
Speaker 7:  you're starting to look at the titanium version, which I must say it's very
Speaker 7:  fancy. Yeah I feel very special and fancy while wearing it. I'm like, ooh,
Speaker 7:  I feel expensive. And it is expensive. It starts at 6 99.
Speaker 7:  The, the ultra is I think just a hundred dollars
Speaker 7:  more. So you're starting to get to the point where it's like, well well why
Speaker 7:  am I buying an ultra then So I think like the real question is like who is
Speaker 7:  supposed to get what because the prices, especially If, you get the nicer
Speaker 7:  materials, they're starting to look the same. So like
Speaker 7:  the watches themselves also is just like, okay, so really what we're getting
Speaker 7:  down to is battery. Like battery is a big thing
Speaker 7:  and dual band GPS for like if you're like me I I am just like
Speaker 7:  ooh how do I feel about giving up dual band GPS because I
Speaker 7:  really want to know down to the hundredth of a mile like what my run was
Speaker 7:  this morning For sure. And then you just like battery life
Speaker 7:  I think for the ultra is kind of gonna be a distinguishing
Speaker 7:  factor because yeah,
Speaker 1:  So I, I'm glad you brought that up 'cause I, it, it does seem to me that
Speaker 1:  for like an everyday user the
Speaker 1:  question of skews is kind of more complicated than ever.
Speaker 1:  I think like, and this is such classic Apple right now, right? There was
Speaker 1:  a time when it was like okay I can pretty quickly explain
Speaker 1:  to you which thing in the line is which and now it's like there's the cheapest
Speaker 1:  one And, then everything up from there is confusing. Yes. And where you land
Speaker 1:  on that line is very hard. But I think my instinct is the same as
Speaker 1:  yours that there's going to be a lot of people who would've wanted an ultra
Speaker 1:  who are now going to be perfectly happy with the series 10, which does all
Speaker 1:  the same stuff in terms of like day-to-day use has an even
Speaker 1:  bigger screen is lighter. Like that all seems like a victory except for the
Speaker 1:  battery life. Like I, the, the ultra, this is the thing that has gotten me
Speaker 1:  for the last couple of revs of this thing is the battery life. It's, it's
Speaker 1:  like an order of magnitude better. It's not like slightly better. It is like
Speaker 1:  twice as good and that is a huge
Speaker 7:  Difference. It is, you can go two days without charging If. you have an ultra.
Speaker 7:  Whereas I, I am still charging daily if I have the series 10
Speaker 7:  and you know, I had I think a, I had a 25 minute
Speaker 7:  shower this morning and it went from
Speaker 7:  67% ish to a hundred within that time.
Speaker 7:  That's, that's great.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Right. 'cause fast charging was one of the upgrades here, right?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So like fast charging
Speaker 1:  That's pretty good. Yeah, mine is currently charging much slower than that.
Speaker 7:  I, I will say that fast charging can be tricky with the Apple Watch because
Speaker 7:  one you have to make sure that the charger supports fast charging And. then
Speaker 7:  two, you have to make sure like all of your accessories are are like gonna
Speaker 7:  do the fast charging for you. 'cause otherwise, like even with the Ultra
Speaker 7:  which supports fast charging like my, my spouse is just like it
Speaker 7:  didn't charge what happened. So like they, I find that to be like a,
Speaker 7:  a thing that people have trouble with in general with knowing
Speaker 7:  whether the charger they're using is actually gonna support that.
Speaker 7:  So especially since it's even less clear If you buy a dock, the docks
Speaker 7:  don't all support the fast charging for the Apple Watch. So that can be very
Speaker 7:  confusing. So yeah, battery life, you know,
Speaker 7:  I the ultra just is a lot more reliable when you
Speaker 7:  stick it into battery saver mode. It does last quite a
Speaker 7:  while in that mode. So I really think like battery life
Speaker 7:  is kind of the distinguishing factor here. 'cause you're going from daily
Speaker 7:  to multi-day and Right. For a lot of people that
Speaker 7:  is really difficult to give up and I understand why it's a big difference.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I understand why because as soon as you take the smartwatch off there's
Speaker 7:  a good chance you're not gonna put it back on. So that is the thing like,
Speaker 7:  I mean Garmin fans, I love you but y'all are insufferable about like
Speaker 7:  comparing the battery life and it's like yes, yes, yes we know, we
Speaker 7:  know that the Garmin has the better battery life. It you also don't do quite
Speaker 7:  as much so that that there's like that trade off there.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. The big other thing about the series 10, I'm curious about And then.
Speaker 1:  I'm curious if there's anything else that has jumped out to you in testing.
Speaker 1:  Is the speaker both. Both the, like I,
Speaker 1:  I was thinking about this after the event, like a
Speaker 1:  God help us if we get to the point where people are like playing music and
Speaker 1:  podcasts and yelling into their like awful
Speaker 1:  dystopian disaster stuff. Like sounds awful.
Speaker 1:  Also I'd probably do it like would I occasionally
Speaker 1:  like to be able to listen something through the speaker of my watch? Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Do I hate that? Yeah. But like, so this is what I wonder, have you
Speaker 1:  been, have you been testing this at all? Are you running around listening
Speaker 1:  to just like bumping Taylor Swift out of your smartwatch? How's this going?
Speaker 7:  I will not be bumping Taylor Swift out of my smartwatch. I'm not a, I'm not
Speaker 7:  a Swifty, I'm, I'm a K-pop head. So I have
Speaker 7:  been bumping k-pop out of my smartwatch. Okay.
Speaker 7:  But there is like a question of etiquette there because if I
Speaker 7:  am on a subway that just makes me a jerk doing that.
Speaker 7:  And I think Apple itself is very aware that people are
Speaker 7:  primarily going to be using headphones when they listen to stuff through
Speaker 7:  the watch. That is the natural way of doing things. I'm
Speaker 7:  a little baffled by this feature as to like why,
Speaker 7:  and I think it just comes to a topic you and I have talked about is just
Speaker 7:  open ear transparency, like needing that
Speaker 7:  situational awareness. So like where I find it most natural to use is when
Speaker 7:  I'm at home and I have to kind of cook
Speaker 7:  and you know, I find that it's better if I don't have headphones in when
Speaker 7:  I'm cooking because you should know what appliances are beeping and
Speaker 7:  beeping at you. I have a menace of a cat who
Speaker 7:  thinks he's Catie and wants to help and I gotta make sure he's not gonna
Speaker 7:  burn himself while licking a pan or you know, that kind of stuff. Sure.
Speaker 7:  Or the spouse comes in, they have a question and like then you have to take
Speaker 7:  out your headphones and you're like what? So in those instances, yeah
Speaker 7:  like it's actually kind of nice to have it playing
Speaker 7:  on the watch 'cause it's closer to you. I leave my phone, I have a recipe
Speaker 7:  up there, I'm trying to do different things. So in that instance, sure
Speaker 7:  it doesn't get that loud. It's loud enough but like If
Speaker 7:  you were to actually whip it out and just try and play your music like a
Speaker 7:  jerk on the subway, no one would hear it
Speaker 7:  because it's, it's just really loud. The ambient noise is super loud anyway
Speaker 7:  and it doesn't get that loud like If, you're in a quiet room, you're definitely
Speaker 7:  gonna be able to hear it. But yeah. Does it have the best sound quality
Speaker 7:  also? No. Like If you care about like hearing the
Speaker 7:  high hat in the distance like in a mix, like let's
Speaker 7:  be real. That's, that's, that's not happening here. But yeah,
Speaker 1:  I mean to me that actually feels like the right outcome. The only
Speaker 1:  occasions I ever would use this really is for like
Speaker 1:  phone calls occasionally out of the watch when like my phone is
Speaker 1:  somewhere else or I'm walking or whatever. Or the
Speaker 1:  situation like the one you described where I'm in the kitchen cooking
Speaker 1:  or even like you see the people on a, on a bike ride Yeah. With the
Speaker 1:  Bluetooth speaker or whatever. Like little things like that there, there
Speaker 1:  are moments in time I can see this being sort of okay. And the fact that
Speaker 1:  it's not good enough to be annoying on the subway actually feels like a huge
Speaker 1:  victory. Yeah. So I will take that. Yeah. That is good for the world that
Speaker 1:  the speaker is not good enough to do that.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it it, like I was with the podcast guys yesterday and
Speaker 7:  they're like, oh show us the speaker. And I like, I put it on and they're
Speaker 7:  like eh, it doesn't get that loud. And I'm like, yeah it, it doesn't like
Speaker 7:  I don't want it
Speaker 1:  To get that
Speaker 7:  Loud. No you don't want it to. Yeah. So it's like it's appropriate for like
Speaker 7:  your headphones die and you wanna listen to the last two minutes of your
Speaker 7:  podcast or something like that. Yeah it's appropriate for that. It's not
Speaker 7:  really, we're not replacing phones as playing something,
Speaker 7:  we're not replacing speakers. It's just, it's there If, you need
Speaker 7:  it in a pinch. That sort of situation.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's totally fair. Has anything else jumped out to you about this
Speaker 1:  one as you've been reviewing it?
Speaker 7:  It's just lighter and thinner and bigger. It's like really all about the
Speaker 7:  screen and what's really kind of jumping out to me, like I said is
Speaker 1:  There's a whole extra line of text. I still, I I'll never not hear
Speaker 1:  them saying that during the event you can read an extra line of text. There's
Speaker 7:  A whole extra whoa line of text. Oh actually because
Speaker 7:  the screen is bigger actually like the buttons are also slightly bigger,
Speaker 7:  which is great.
Speaker 1:  Oh see that's actually nice.
Speaker 7:  Which is great. If, you have nails like me right now during review season
Speaker 7:  and like touchscreens and nails are not friends. Tough times.
Speaker 7:  They're not friends. So this actually does help me a little bit when I'm
Speaker 7:  putting in the passcode. That's kind of nice. The thing that I
Speaker 7:  have been thinking about though is whether we've reached the end of min
Speaker 7:  maxing size of screen versus comfort because
Speaker 7:  I really do not think we can get the case size much bigger.
Speaker 7:  Like once you get to the 43, 44 millimeter as like the
Speaker 7:  smallest size you are leaving out quite a large swath of people.
Speaker 7:  'cause I have small wrist but I don't have the smallest risks. I know
Speaker 7:  lots of like mostly women out here with very, very tiny bird
Speaker 7:  wrist and the 42 millimeter with this giant honky screen
Speaker 7:  is kind of gonna be the biggest that I think is gonna be
Speaker 7:  usable for them. After that we start getting into a
Speaker 7:  territory that's not great and So I do think that means
Speaker 7:  like we gotta solve this battery issue because you know right, we
Speaker 7:  saw this on the pixel watch three, two, like the 45 millimeter,
Speaker 7:  that's about the biggest eye could go comfortably
Speaker 7:  and So I don't know where companies are gonna go from
Speaker 7:  here as far as like these big screens,
Speaker 7:  small, smaller wrist. I feel like we've reached the limit.
Speaker 7:  So Nice, nice that you pulled out the, the tricks and the stops.
Speaker 7:  But what's next year? Are we gonna go like the bezel is
Speaker 7:  8.76% thinner? Like are we just gonna go that
Speaker 7:  route? Because you know, I did see some people online and I think y'all need
Speaker 7:  to calm down about how like just visually the, the changes
Speaker 7:  from the nine to the 10 make the bezels look slightly larger on the
Speaker 7:  10 that is like optically speaking. True
Speaker 7:  also as someone who uses all manner of smart watches is not that serious.
Speaker 7:  It's really not that serious. A lot of the Apple Watch screens, like the
Speaker 7:  pixel watch ones make use of the darker background and the bezels. So it's
Speaker 7:  functionally depending on what watch face you use, it's functionally you're
Speaker 7:  not, you are really not gonna see it there but oh, oh oh
Speaker 7:  wide oled so you can view more angles. That is surprisingly
Speaker 7:  like it's one of those things that you're like, okay, yeah, whatever.
Speaker 7:  But like when you're just like very discreetly trying to read a, a funny
Speaker 7:  text message in a meeting and you're going like, oh yeah, that
Speaker 7:  that actually is kind of kind of fun.
Speaker 1:  I agree with that and it does my, my strident belief since
Speaker 1:  the first days of the Apple Watch has been that If, you have a smart watch
Speaker 1:  that doesn't tell you the time. Every time you look at it you have failed.
Speaker 1:  And this is another step in the right direction of when I
Speaker 1:  look at my watch it will tell me the time. Yes. So I'll take it. Yeah this
Speaker 1:  is, this is a victory. Okay. So it seems to me that if
Speaker 1:  you're in the position of like I
Speaker 1:  need to upgrade my watch, you have an old one, it broke batteries, terrible
Speaker 1:  whatever, this is probably the one to get right. Like yes or
Speaker 1:  the last couple of years it's been like you could maybe go back a year and
Speaker 1:  it would be fine but it feels like this one is probably worth the upgrade.
Speaker 7:  It's pro, I think it is worth the upgrading to this. Like there are a few
Speaker 7:  exceptions I guess like If you really like the color pink and you're gonna
Speaker 7:  go with the aluminum last year's pink is more
Speaker 7:  pink than this year's rose gold. There are like a very small number of people
Speaker 7:  I'm talking to at the moment here who care about that particular
Speaker 7:  color. The one thing I would ask people to consider is blood
Speaker 7:  oxygen, If, you live in the US if that matters to you in
Speaker 7:  any capacity at all, If, you do upgrade to the
Speaker 7:  10, you will be losing that feature.
Speaker 1:  Right. If you upgrade at all.
Speaker 7:  Well like If you upgrade and you are in the us If you're outside of the US
Speaker 7:  you still get blood oxygen. Love that for you. But
Speaker 7:  my, my thought though as a caveat is do you really
Speaker 7:  need it on the Apple Watch? My my my my read is no
Speaker 7:  I have not missed it using the series 10. So
Speaker 7:  there's that. It's not that serious. Like I, I'm gonna
Speaker 7:  be real, I don't think most people use the blood oxygen app.
Speaker 1:  So, I tend to agree. Yeah. Okay. But then the other question
Speaker 1:  is like if I have an eight or a nine, my watch is
Speaker 1:  fine. I'll get some trade in money if I get the 10, is it worth like
Speaker 1:  going out of my way to go get the 10
Speaker 7:  Calm down. No. Okay. Like calm down. No.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean this is kind of what it feels like this whole year of Apple
Speaker 1:  products is right. It's like these are good ones. If, you need a new
Speaker 1:  one. These are probably the ones to get But If, you don't need a new one.
Speaker 1:  There's nothing here that is going to give you like incredible gadget. fomo.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I would, I would say that
Speaker 1:  Except maybe the titanium a li like a tiny bit. A little bit. The titanium.
Speaker 7:  The titanium a little bit. Because I will say, you know, just in my experience
Speaker 7:  in the past using stainless steel, it's lighter. It is significantly lighter
Speaker 7:  to have the titanium and it looks just like the stainless steel and it's
Speaker 7:  very pretty and it has a little coating over it to
Speaker 7:  prevent scratches. We'll see that. That's not something I can know over like
Speaker 7:  a really short term period like that has to be tested over a
Speaker 7:  few months. Right. Scrapes, cats trying to eat the watch. Like that sort
Speaker 7:  of thing. But I gotta say it really looks nice. I, I was just looking,
Speaker 7:  I was like, wow, I look fancy. Like my outfit
Speaker 7:  has been upgraded by like several points just because it looks
Speaker 7:  much nicer. I I tend to have like very sporty accessories. So I don't look
Speaker 7:  polished. But I was like, ooh, ooh I could go to a wedding and this and look
Speaker 7:  cool.
Speaker 1:  It's a little like super pish. It
Speaker 7:  Is. It is. It is. It is quite nice. It's quite nice Colors.
Speaker 7:  Colors are nice this year.
Speaker 1:  All right, well that's not helping my FOMO as somebody with a perfectly usable
Speaker 1:  series eight, but that is probably the right
Speaker 7:  Answer. Yeah, no, no, you're, you're in the chill out zone. I think
Speaker 7:  the only, only
Speaker 1:  That's where I live.
Speaker 7:  The only people who I think have a debate on their hands are people with
Speaker 7:  series sixes. Like those are the only ones who I think series
Speaker 7:  five older time to upgrade. Yeah. Series six. You could make
Speaker 7:  a very good case for it. Series seven,
Speaker 7:  series eight, series nine. I think you could just chill.
Speaker 1:  Fair enough. All right v thank you so much as always.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, thanks for having me.
Speaker 1:  One quick note before we move on, V and I did talk very briefly
Speaker 1:  about the sleep apnea testing stuff that's in the Apple Watch now,
Speaker 1:  but when we talked it hadn't come out yet and there were
Speaker 1:  questions about FDA approval anyway. It did get approved by the
Speaker 1:  FDA and it will be in the Apple Watch and that is a thing we're gonna have
Speaker 1:  to follow up on. That's also a hard thing to do in a review cycle. The
Speaker 1:  health stuff is complicated and it takes time. So we're gonna let V do some
Speaker 1:  real proper testing on that and we'll get back to you on all things sleep
Speaker 1:  apnea. Anyway, let's move on. Let's do AirPods.
Speaker 1:  AirPods, I confess are the ones I am most personally fascinated
Speaker 1:  by. I'm forever looking at this perfect middle
Speaker 1:  ground of comfy good sounding, not terribly
Speaker 1:  expensive and noise canceling headphones and the perfect
Speaker 1:  middle ground of that does not exist. At least it has not existed
Speaker 1:  so far. But it seems like Apple might be inching ever
Speaker 1:  closer with the AirPods four. I know this is a hard thing to get
Speaker 1:  right so I'm not getting my hopes up, but I'm very, very, very, very curious.
Speaker 1:  Chris Welch has reviewed all of these for us over the years. He has the new
Speaker 1:  pairs. Let's get into it. Chris Welch. Hello.
Speaker 8:  Hello David. It's a pleasure to be back.
Speaker 1:  Just headphones. This is, I feel like there are other things we should talk
Speaker 1:  about
Speaker 8:  On the
Speaker 1:  Show from time to time. You do all these things that are very interesting
Speaker 1:  and yet we just talk about it. Headphones here on the show.
Speaker 8:  Fine by me.
Speaker 1:  So. I. I've realized that unusually this year
Speaker 1:  with Apple devices. The first question I have to ask is what
Speaker 1:  are you actually testing? There are things Apple announced that haven't shipped
Speaker 1:  yet. There are things Apple announced that aren't shipping for a very long
Speaker 1:  time. You got, you got some devices. What have you been testing
Speaker 1:  that you actually have access to right now?
Speaker 8:  So I've got the AirPods for both pairs, the standard pair and also the new
Speaker 8:  pair that has noise cancellation for the first time. That's really all I've
Speaker 8:  been testing this whole time is really like how well does noise cancellation
Speaker 8:  work in this open style of earbud. Thankfully like all the features are there
Speaker 8:  on day one with this product on, unlike the rest of apple's lineup this
Speaker 8:  year. So it all works out of the box, which you know, always very nice.
Speaker 8:  So yeah, just been kinda going back and forth. They sound the same so there's
Speaker 8:  not much there between them that's all good. They sound really good. Like
Speaker 8:  honestly like I've never been like a standard AirPods person 'cause like
Speaker 8:  for years they just didn't fit my ears right at all. Like you'd like twist
Speaker 8:  them in just a certain way to get them to stay. These ones do a better job
Speaker 8:  staying in my ears. So, so far so good I think. Okay.
Speaker 1:  How different is the design this time? It's always hard to tell in the photos
Speaker 1:  and renders
Speaker 8:  Very slight tweaks. Like the contours and the shape. Yeah, they didn't change
Speaker 8:  much.
Speaker 1:  I'm somebody for whom the open ear AirPods have always worked really well.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I really like the way that they fit. So every time they're like,
Speaker 1:  we've changed the design, I'm like no don't change the design.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, yeah. They changed it ever so slightly using 50 million scans or data
Speaker 8:  points of like ear shapes. So you know the usual but okay not
Speaker 8:  that different compared to the last ones. I compared them directly and yeah,
Speaker 8:  they're still pretty similar. Okay.
Speaker 1:  So the idea is there, there are some people for whom they should fit now
Speaker 1:  but they shouldn't not work for anybody that they did work for before.
Speaker 8:  Hopefully. Hopefully there's always someone who's gonna complain.
Speaker 1:  I know. Yeah. It, it will be me. I mean I, I say they work for me but also
Speaker 1:  like the number of times they've just fallen out of my head. I,
Speaker 1:  I don't know what work for me really counts as in a lot of cases. Right.
Speaker 1:  But it does seem like the big question with the AirPods for
Speaker 1:  is just as simple as is a NC worth $50,
Speaker 1:  right? Like that's the price difference. That is the only feature change
Speaker 1:  as far as I can tell is that kind of the frame. So there
Speaker 8:  Are some other differences. So with a NC Molly you get the wireless charging
Speaker 8:  which might be enough for a lot of people to spend 50 bucks for. There's
Speaker 8:  that. Yep. The case has the speaker for fine mine, which I've never used
Speaker 8:  but it's there. If you need it. And that's really the main three features
Speaker 8:  that it has over the standard one. But the battery life, they're both
Speaker 8:  IP 54 I think water resistant and so yeah, that's all the
Speaker 8:  same between the both.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I am slightly bummed I have to say that we didn't get like one
Speaker 1:  of the rumors right before was that there might be a more interesting capacitive
Speaker 1:  case with like some music controls on it. Mm. Like we've seen from some of
Speaker 1:  these other companies. I am slightly disappointed we didn't get that. I have
Speaker 1:  to say
Speaker 8:  No still the white GLO of case it is small, it's like so tiny now it's almost
Speaker 8:  like a square shape that it's gotten like so small. Oh it's
Speaker 1:  Small. Okay.
Speaker 8:  So sorry for people listening to this.
Speaker 1:  It's like imagine a a piece of orbit gum stretched a little bit.
Speaker 1:  That's basically what that case looks like now.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  So all right, so what's, first of all, let, let's just science
Speaker 1:  this a little bit for a second. The idea of a NC
Speaker 1:  on a pair of open ear headphones like the
Speaker 1:  AirPods four I, I know you were skeptical going
Speaker 1:  in that this is even a thing that is possible to do or do well
Speaker 1:  how does Apple do a NC on something like this? Like
Speaker 1:  how does it even sort of in theory work as opposed to a pair of headphones
Speaker 1:  you can shove interior ears that actually physically block out a lot of things.
Speaker 8:  So it's been done before like Samsung just put out the buds three that have
Speaker 8:  the same kind of concept doesn't work quite as well, but the technology's
Speaker 8:  the same between these and the AirPods Pro like so that there are mics in
Speaker 8:  the earbuds, they scan for noise and they play like the inverse of whatever
Speaker 8:  you're hearing to kind of cancel it out. And so Apple says they like kind
Speaker 8:  of changed the driver so they like tilt towards your ears more with these
Speaker 8:  and I guess that helps out when it comes to the A NC. And so like I've been
Speaker 8:  impressed, you have to like set your expectations. Like it's nowhere near
Speaker 8:  the pros, it's nowhere near tips. So you can't like put these into your ears
Speaker 8:  and have everything just like fade away. I'd say it cuts
Speaker 8:  things down by like 30%, maybe
Speaker 8:  40%, probably 30 ish. So like If you like what
Speaker 8:  I found is like you can't just put them in and have quiet but If you play
Speaker 8:  music. That's really where you notice that you don't have to like turn up
Speaker 8:  the volume as loud as you would would have otherwise. Like that's really
Speaker 8:  part of this whole appeal I think. And also kind of ties into like apple's
Speaker 8:  like hearing health stuff lately. So you just don't have to crank the volume.
Speaker 8:  That's been the main benefit. But if you're like you're on a plane and you're
Speaker 8:  like just turn 'em on without music, you're gonna hear everything around
Speaker 8:  you still. So it's not gonna like be some miracle but
Speaker 8:  Right. But it's nice. Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 1:  So is maybe the right analogy just in terms of what this feels like in
Speaker 1:  practice, like a pair of over ear headphones
Speaker 1:  without the noise cancellation turned on. Like it's, you put them on and
Speaker 1:  everything gets quieter and a little more isolated
Speaker 1:  but it's not like when you flip it on and like the noise from the plane
Speaker 1:  disappears.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. No, not at all. Okay. Yeah, it takes off like you hear what kinda
Speaker 8:  like a, I'd say it's like a white noise machine. Like you would still hear
Speaker 8:  like a fair amount of noise in the background and it's like I was at a bar
Speaker 8:  last night super loud. I just put 'em in for the sake of trying it and I
Speaker 8:  could still hear a conversation nearby and people talking. So it's not gonna
Speaker 8:  like change that kind of environment. But it did cut it down. So
Speaker 8:  I was playing music at like 70% volume and I could still hear my music just
Speaker 8:  fine. And so, you know, like it does make a difference, which I think think
Speaker 8:  is gonna be enough for a lot of people to just kind of say 50 bucks, why
Speaker 8:  not? You know, plus the wireless charging and whatnot so. Right.
Speaker 1:  Well yeah, it's to your point about the hearing health stuff, that
Speaker 1:  way of thinking about reducing the noise is actually really interesting
Speaker 1:  'cause you can see that as a negative, right? Like Right. What that sounds
Speaker 1:  to me like is when I get on a plane it's still going
Speaker 1:  to be very loud. So these are not going to replace like the, the Bose
Speaker 1:  headphones that I like to get on a plane with because it's quiet and helps
Speaker 1:  me sleep while I watch a movie. Right. But on the other hand, the thing you
Speaker 1:  just described, like I can listen to music at the bar without it being impossibly
Speaker 1:  loud and still sort of hear the people around me's actually that's a, that's
Speaker 1:  a use case, right? Like that's a real Yeah, that's a real thing And it's,
Speaker 1:  it's kind of a hack on transparency mode in a certain way
Speaker 1:  where you have headphones that let you hear the world but
Speaker 1:  also your music and if, if Apple can get that balance right. That's both,
Speaker 1:  it's a pro and a con of the level of a NC in a strange way.
Speaker 1:  Right?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So it's been good. I mean these actually have, so there's noise canceling
Speaker 8:  mode, there is transparency mode on these as well and you would think like,
Speaker 8:  why is that necessary in open, open style earbuds? But so it boosts like
Speaker 8:  certain frequencies like voices, you can hear people easier. Okay. When you
Speaker 8:  turn on the transparency mode and it's got all the like AirPods Pro software
Speaker 8:  stuff, like the conversation awareness, so when you start speaking the volume
Speaker 8:  goes down yada yada. So that's all there, which is nice. Sound quality
Speaker 8:  is actually like, surprisingly like the base response is like way better
Speaker 8:  than like most of the past models they put out. So that's been my main like
Speaker 8:  thing I've noticed. The base response is really good. Yeah, they just sound
Speaker 8:  really clear. They're still not like my type of earbuds but they're just
Speaker 8:  really well made AirPods so. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Do you think we're at a point now where the biggest difference between
Speaker 1:  the AirPods and the pros just in sort of
Speaker 1:  day-to-day use. Obviously there's the, the hearing health stuff and all that,
Speaker 1:  but do you think the main difference between the two is just going to be
Speaker 1:  how they fit and feel in your ears? Like it, it feels like the, the
Speaker 1:  base AirPods are getting closer to the pros in such a way that the pros
Speaker 1:  are gonna be better. Yeah. And if, if the main thing you want is sound quality,
Speaker 1:  yeah fine. But it does seem like the gap between the two in terms
Speaker 1:  of sort of everyday sound quality is much, much smaller than it once was.
Speaker 1:  Yeah,
Speaker 8:  For sure.
Speaker 1:  That's really exciting. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  It is. Are the pros like still sound better obviously. And the A NC is obviously
Speaker 8:  like that much better than these are. So like If you want the best thing,
Speaker 8:  there's that so it's like good, better, best like good is the AirPods four
Speaker 8:  and they sound really nice for the price
Speaker 8:  1 29, 1 79 or the AirPods four with a NC
Speaker 8:  And, then you go up to the pros and so it's a pretty good straightforward
Speaker 8:  product lineup. I, you know, I can't say that but like the iPads or whatever,
Speaker 8:  but this is pretty straightforward as as far as like what you should buy
Speaker 8:  and like here's what you get buying that thing. So yeah,
Speaker 1:  Compared to the iPads, everything is straightforward. Yes. So, I don't know,
Speaker 1:  that's a totally fair part
Speaker 8:  But valid point. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Does it make sense to you that the AirPods four and the
Speaker 1:  AirPods four with a NC are two separate things like it, it seems like the
Speaker 1:  normal Apple move in a lot of ways would've been to just scrap the bottom
Speaker 1:  one and say $179 is still a pretty competitive price
Speaker 1:  for this kind of headphone. Yeah. Is it surprising to you that
Speaker 1:  the sort of very base model exists at all?
Speaker 8:  Not really. I think they still want something like in that price point. 'cause
Speaker 8:  there's so many lower cost options from like so many brands like JBL and
Speaker 8:  whoever else that yeah that cost like $70, $50. So you've gotta have something
Speaker 8:  that's like not too far off from that and that's what the AirPods four are
Speaker 8:  and you get most of the same sound qual, well same sound quality and like
Speaker 8:  much of the same features. The call quality is nice. They've got this new
Speaker 8:  voice isolation feature from the AirPod pros as well. So I uses AI
Speaker 8:  of course to make you clear on phone calls. So that's on both
Speaker 8:  models too. So you get a lot for 1 29 honestly. But If you want a NC and
Speaker 8:  wireless charging 50 bucks more so.
Speaker 1:  Got it. Okay. And one question we got on the hotline from actually a couple
Speaker 1:  of people was how big a deal is the H two chip? And I think
Speaker 1:  to some extent it's just better, right? Like new
Speaker 1:  chips do more things. Yeah. And I think if I'm not mistaken, apple mentioned
Speaker 1:  voice isolation as like one of the things that's gonna get better with extra
Speaker 1:  processing. Yeah. But I'm also assuming based on the way you're describing
Speaker 1:  A and C working that that is like, that's a huge amount of processing
Speaker 1:  this thing has to do. Yeah. So that makes me think that there are gonna
Speaker 1:  be a lot of people who are like, do I buy the H one AirPods because
Speaker 1:  they're gonna be cheaper or is the H two chip worth it? And it sounds like
Speaker 1:  maybe the H two chip is gonna be worth it. Yeah, for sure. For sure. Okay.
Speaker 8:  I would say So I mean it's not that much more expensive. I'm sure you can
Speaker 8:  find deals on the past models, but these sound better first of all. So like
Speaker 8:  that's why I would buy them. Most of all they sound significantly better
Speaker 8:  than the AirPods three did to my ears at least. Always subjective. But yeah,
Speaker 8:  like you get a lot and like the H two chip is key for a lot of the, those
Speaker 8:  features plus the A NC. Like this is why these have a lot of these features
Speaker 8:  and the AirPods max still don't because the AirPods max do not have the H
Speaker 8:  two chip. Yeah. So, but yes, I would myself, I would
Speaker 8:  go with the A NC model. I think it is worth just having those few extra features
Speaker 8:  for not a ton more money. But yeah, I mean there are some
Speaker 8:  downsides. Like there's still no multi-point, which I would love. Apple just
Speaker 8:  loves it's like multi-device like auto switching, which has gotten better
Speaker 8:  over the last couple years I think. But it, it can still like always like
Speaker 8:  pair to the wrong thing at the wrong time when it's like most inconvenient
Speaker 8:  for you. So,
Speaker 1:  I Apple is, I would say guilty. A lot of
Speaker 1:  being too clever by half. And I think, yeah, the clever multi switching is
Speaker 1:  the most too clever by half thing that Apple does. Yeah. I just want a button
Speaker 1:  that says, I never ever, ever, ever want to connect my
Speaker 1:  AirPods to my MAC mini ever. I have never once wanted to, I am never going
Speaker 1:  to want to stop asking me every single time I sit down in a
Speaker 1:  chair if I want to connect my AirPods to my Mac mini. Like it just drives
Speaker 1:  me crazy.
Speaker 1:  But that is neither here nor there. So you haven't gotten a chance to test
Speaker 1:  the AirPods Pro two yet with the hearing health stuff,
Speaker 1:  otherwise they're basically the same. The hearing health stuff is coming.
Speaker 1:  We'll try that when it comes. Yep. You have I would say
Speaker 1:  for all intents and purposes, tried the AirPods max because they're the AirPods
Speaker 1:  max with A-U-S-B-C port and some new colors.
Speaker 8:  New colors. Yeah. At
Speaker 1:  Some point I think we'll we'll end up doing a full review of those because
Speaker 1:  we should, they're gonna be on sale. But my biggest question for you is
Speaker 1:  coming into this event, there was like a little bit of talk about what
Speaker 1:  the maxes might be, if there were gonna be maxes on a,
Speaker 1:  you know, scale of one to 10, how surprised were you that Apple decided to
Speaker 1:  essentially do nothing with the AirPods Max?
Speaker 8:  Pretty bummed, honestly. 'cause I like the max, you know, I'm not sure like
Speaker 8:  why they're like so unworthy of like actual hardware upgrades after all these
Speaker 8:  years. And like I see them everywhere. It's like people clearly buy them,
Speaker 8:  people like buy like cases for their like ear cups. Have you seen these?
Speaker 8:  Like on the street? It's wild. So there's a whole like aftermarket for accessories
Speaker 8:  for the AirPods Max and they're really good headphones. But I assume Apple
Speaker 8:  just has must have some kinda like customer data that says like, people just
Speaker 8:  don't need like some of the AirPods Pro features or care, like they just
Speaker 8:  wanna get on a plane, put these on and zone out and like that's all they
Speaker 8:  really want them for.
Speaker 1:  That's interesting that like maybe there's less to do in that
Speaker 1:  space. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  But like you would think they would want like some of the hearing health
Speaker 8:  stuff there too, like in the over ear Yeah. Format too. So, I'm not
Speaker 8:  sure like what the thinking is there, but you would hope like there's
Speaker 8:  the true AirPods max too. Not, not too far off.
Speaker 8:  Who knows? Maybe once the AirPods Pro three come out, they'll
Speaker 8:  like do both at the same time. But, but yeah, it's a bummer. I mean they're
Speaker 8:  so heavy and that case hasn't changed the case. The
Speaker 8:  case is still as it was.
Speaker 1:  That is the thing that kills me is there are just a couple of really obvious
Speaker 1:  upgrades. Yeah, I think the, the basic look of it, I've really come around
Speaker 1:  to over the years. Yeah. I was not wild about it at the beginning, but I
Speaker 1:  think it, it looks better on people's heads than it does kind of on its own.
Speaker 1:  So like I, I'm, I'm in favor. Sounds good. Works great. But there are,
Speaker 1:  there are enough sort of little upgrades both in the hardware and the case
Speaker 1:  and now even in the, the processing and the software, it's like you could
Speaker 1:  make these better without trying very hard. Yeah. And that, that is the thing
Speaker 1:  that kind of bums me out about the max. So. Okay, last question And then,
Speaker 1:  then I'll, I'll let you get outta here. The, the, again, the big question
Speaker 1:  I think a lot of people are gonna ask is do I get the four or is it worth
Speaker 1:  $50 to get the a NC for most people? Obviously
Speaker 1:  if price is your main question, get the cheaper one, but do you think
Speaker 1:  most people, the right best option is gonna be to spend the 50 bucks?
Speaker 1:  Is it worth the upgrade? Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Okay. I think So I mean it's there. If, you need it and it's pretty easy
Speaker 8:  to just like turn off If. you don't like it. Like you can actually feel so
Speaker 8:  like some of the pressure that you would get, like when you on a NC from
Speaker 8:  the AirPods Pro Mm. You still get like some of that sensation. Some people
Speaker 8:  don't like that, but you can just turn it off If, you don't want that. But
Speaker 8:  it's nice to have, you know, like if you're out somewhere on the street and
Speaker 8:  it's like loud, it'll cut it down by like, you know, like a third or so,
Speaker 8:  like, but, and that's like enough to just play your music and not
Speaker 8:  go crazy from like outside whatever. So yeah, it's worth it.
Speaker 1:  All right, fair enough. All right, well one of these days you have to come
Speaker 1:  back and we're gonna do Pixel Buds, we're gonna do Galaxy Buds and we're
Speaker 1:  gonna do AirPods and we are going to put a bunch of bad sounding audio on
Speaker 1:  the Bcast and I cannot wait. So many good reviews. Yeah. Good. Alright
Speaker 1:  Chris, thank you as always. Thank you sir. Cheers. Alright, we gotta take
Speaker 1:  one more break. And, then we are gonna take a question from the Vergecast
Speaker 1:  Hotline. We'll be right back.
Speaker 13:  think they really showed me why I should get a new iPhone,
Speaker 4:  this and I couldn't do that before, like
Speaker 4:  the nine pro fold is like the poster
Speaker 4:  child for that. Like you can, the way you can use
Speaker 4:  the, the inner screen,
Speaker 4:  there's just like, there's really nothing else. Like it is kind
Speaker 4:  of how I would put it and,
Speaker 4:  you know, RCS on iOS 18 might alleviate
Speaker 4:  a little bit of the, the messaging woes. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  There's still, you know, really not a substitute for like
Speaker 4:  FaceTime or any of that, but yeah, two times the phone. That's what I
Speaker 1:  Got's pretty good. I have been amazed
Speaker 1:  by how much I like the fold. We're gonna come back, you and I are at some
Speaker 1:  point in the next couple of weeks gonna have to come back and re-litigate
Speaker 1:  our flip versus fold debate. Mm. Yeah because I have,
Speaker 1:  I have new feelings that are making me sad about my old feelings and we're,
Speaker 1:  we're gonna talk about that. I love this phone and I think that's so nice
Speaker 1:  to, to Keith's point about the Google ecosystem, every time I really
Speaker 1:  reinvest in Android, which I've been doing because of this phone, I am reminded
Speaker 1:  of how much better it is to be a Google user on an Android phone.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Just in part because Gemini is so built into everything
Speaker 1:  and you can access all of your information in all the different Google
Speaker 1:  services. It's so much better. Yeah. As a Google Home controller than the
Speaker 1:  iPhone is. You get like top level access to all that stuff
Speaker 1:  in a way that if you're on an iPhone, you always have to launch an app before
Speaker 1:  you can do Google stuff. You can just do it all from the home screen of your
Speaker 1:  phone. Yeah. And that's very powerful. But literally it is such a nice phone.
Speaker 1:  It's such a nice phone. It's, I cannot get over how much I like this phone.
Speaker 1:  It's thin, it's the right size. Even If, you like don't open the inner screen
Speaker 1:  all that often, which I don't, it's still a great phone And. then you're
Speaker 1:  like, oh my God, there's an inner screen. Yeah. It's, I I love this phone
Speaker 1:  and I think the switching costs have gone way down,
Speaker 1:  which is very exciting. Like the, the idea that leaving an iPhone and going
Speaker 1:  to an Android phone is going to sort of break your brain is just not true
Speaker 1:  anymore. Yeah. Weirdly, the thing that is always the
Speaker 1:  hardest for me switching is that you swipe down on an
Speaker 1:  iPhone to get to Spotlight and be able to start searching for stuff and you
Speaker 1:  swipe up on Android. Oh yeah. That is the thing that takes me the longest
Speaker 1:  to switch every single time. Yeah. Everything else, they've just become so
Speaker 1:  similar over time. They have most of the same features. They do most things
Speaker 1:  the same way. Apple has adopted a lot of Android's customization.
Speaker 1:  Android has started to sort of organize the phone in the way that Apple
Speaker 1:  did for a long time. They're just not that far apart. Yeah. Like weirdly,
Speaker 1:  I agree with you that FaceTime is the single stickiest thing left the RCS
Speaker 1:  thing. It won't solve everything, but it makes some things easier. You can
Speaker 1:  deregister from iMessage much more easily than you used to. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Liam, our producer did this. He bought a fold and he turned off
Speaker 1:  iMessage and it used to be somewhere between like 24
Speaker 1:  and 72 hours you were in like weird iMessage limbo it, it was like
Speaker 1:  minutes with him. Yeah. This time it was very exciting. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I, I live that, that dangerous life like several times
Speaker 4:  a year when I switch from an iPhone to
Speaker 4:  Yeah. One of the Android phones and it, it is easier. I think there's
Speaker 4:  kind of an outdated notion of like how difficult it is to switch
Speaker 4:  between these systems and I am living
Speaker 4:  proof that you can do it multiple times a year and it, there's
Speaker 4:  no like major social cost to it. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  You will still be a green bubble, but I think yeah, like
Speaker 1:  it, it's fine. Yeah. Just own being a green bubble. Lean in. Yeah. Your
Speaker 1:  phone has two screens that's cooler than iPhone.
Speaker 4:  So just open up the phone anytime, you know, you need to prove something.
Speaker 4:  You know someone like, well, do you have two phones attached to your phone?
Speaker 1:  Right. Oh, you can't see those words on that screen? Watch this. I have a
Speaker 1:  whole nother screen. Yeah, no
Speaker 4:  Big deal. Yeah. Look at this. Yeah, something else. I think
Speaker 4:  particularly this year with the Pixel series, I haven't tried out
Speaker 4:  the Pixel Watch three yet, but I'm dying to. But it seems like that
Speaker 4:  the ecosystem of hardware around it has also gotten
Speaker 4:  is just elevated this year. Like the Pixel nine hardware,
Speaker 4:  the Pixel Watch three by all accounts is very nice and finally
Speaker 4:  just feels like this is a great smartwatch. Like you, you
Speaker 4:  just buy this one when you have a pixel phone and everything is nice.
Speaker 4:  So, I think that that's always been part of the, the
Speaker 4:  math in the Apple ecosystems is like, well you have this phone,
Speaker 4:  you just buy these earbuds, you buy this watch and you're done and it all
Speaker 4:  works and yeah. Yeah. Pixel maybe getting there a little bit.
Speaker 1:  A a hundred percent. And the other thing is that as Google has made
Speaker 1:  all that stuff work really well with like Fast Pair and nearby share and
Speaker 1:  all this stuff that is sort of knitting its own ecosystem together, it's
Speaker 1:  giving that to other companies too. So like we're at a point now where
Speaker 1:  Apple's ecosystem is probably still a little cleaner
Speaker 1:  and simpler and better connected, but only If you only buy Apple products
Speaker 1:  and Google and Android have gotten 90% of the way there with
Speaker 1:  like the rest of the industry. And I think your just pure
Speaker 1:  sort of number of choices you have of things that you can attach to your
Speaker 1:  devices
Speaker 1:  way better on Android and like, it, it won't be quite
Speaker 1:  as perfect as just buying an Apple watch and scanning the thing and poof
Speaker 1:  it's set up. Yeah. But it's a lot closer and you have a lot more choices.
Speaker 1:  And I think, I think like the, the whole better together
Speaker 1:  thing that Apple has had for so long is not nearly the advantage it once
Speaker 1:  was.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I am also just sitting here convincing myself to switch to Android. Like
Speaker 1:  I'm, I'm using the full but I haven't moved my eim yet and I'm sitting here
Speaker 1:  being like, I it's time to, it's time to do
Speaker 4:  Eim. Oh, that's a commitment. Yeah. Yeah. I don't know. Maybe it's time.
Speaker 1:  It's just time to do it. It's time. I'm just, it's just time. But okay. So
Speaker 1:  now last question. W would you recommend doing
Speaker 1:  this? Like is this, if you've been debating leaving the
Speaker 1:  ecosystem, switching Apple to Android,
Speaker 1:  is this the year to do it?
Speaker 4:  I think it is. I think that the hardware has been
Speaker 4:  on the Pixel side particularly kind of inching towards this.
Speaker 4:  Like is it really a flagship, eh, it's kind of this like upper
Speaker 4:  mid-range thing and this, I, I hold a Pixel nine up
Speaker 4:  next to the iPhone 16
Speaker 4:  Galaxy S 24 and like they're all just really nice phones and
Speaker 4:  it sort of feels like the first time that I've, I've been like, yeah,
Speaker 4:  these, these deserve to all be in the same conversation.
Speaker 4:  I think it's a really good year to do it and I think we're gonna,
Speaker 4:  yeah, to your point on the, the Gemini stuff, I think we're going
Speaker 4:  to get funneled into these AI subscription
Speaker 4:  nightmares. Yes. Where If, you are in the Google ecosystem and
Speaker 4:  like I am very much, you know, in Gmail and
Speaker 4:  Google Docs and all of those services, it's gonna get
Speaker 4:  weird If you are, you know, trying to use the AI
Speaker 4:  features and they're behind some kind of like Google one paywall.
Speaker 4:  You know, I don't know, this is speculation. I don't wanna like
Speaker 4:  get too far ahead of myself,
Speaker 4:  but that is something to consider. I think there is
Speaker 4:  potential for like, value of being all
Speaker 4:  in on one system, like they're quite wasn't before.
Speaker 4:  I don't know. There, it, it feels like a, a stick that they're getting ready
Speaker 4:  to just like smack us with.
Speaker 1:  I I totally agree. And I think the system thing is the one thing
Speaker 1:  that weirdly keeps me sort of tied to
Speaker 1:  iPhone. Like you can use most Google things,
Speaker 1:  most of the Google universe on an iPhone it's not
Speaker 1:  as good, but it's there not true in reverse. Right? Yeah. Like if,
Speaker 1:  if there are any Apple only apps that you like or you like
Speaker 1:  Siri or there are certain Apple E experiences that you want
Speaker 1:  to have, they just don't exist on Android and So I. Think the
Speaker 1:  question of like, do I want to use a little of both
Speaker 1:  kind of leads you to an iPhone in a strange way where I think If, you
Speaker 1:  just want to pick one. The clear answer at this moment is Gemini. I think
Speaker 1:  I, I'm so happy if I'm wrong about this in six months,
Speaker 1:  but I have incredibly low expectations for what Apple intelligence is gonna
Speaker 1:  look like for the foreseeable future. And Gemini
Speaker 1:  has many flaws but is doing a lot of stuff already.
Speaker 1:  And so If you If you want to just buy in, that's probably the one to start
Speaker 1:  with as opposed to like crossing your fingers for Siri to get really good
Speaker 1:  next year. Yeah. But you can a little bit have your cake and eat it
Speaker 1:  too on the iPhone. Yeah. Because there is both Siri and there is the
Speaker 1:  Google app and you can, you can have both and So, I think in,
Speaker 1:  in a weird way. Android forces you to both it, it gives you a bigger ecosystem,
Speaker 1:  but also forces you to make a choice in a way that the iPhone a little bit
Speaker 1:  doesn't yet.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. I think that's fair.
Speaker 1:  But the fold is so nice.
Speaker 4:  The fold is so NICE's so nice. Just 10 out of 10 on like
Speaker 4:  niceness.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. If this thing wasn't $1,800, I would be like screaming from rooftops
Speaker 1:  that this is the phone everybody should buy. Yeah, absolutely. Its $1,800.
Speaker 1:  I know. So Keith, do it. Do it. That what you will.
Speaker 1:  I don't know if we helped at all, but that's where we're
Speaker 4:  Probably not.
Speaker 1:  All right Allison, thank you as always.
Speaker 4:  Thank you.
Speaker 1:  Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everybody who came
Speaker 1:  on the show, and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on
Speaker 1:  everything we talked about, all the reviews, all of our coverage, all of
Speaker 1:  the hearing health stuff in the AirPods, all of the
Speaker 1:  sleep apnea stuff in the Apple Watch. Lots of interesting things going
Speaker 1:  on, lots of stuff coming in the coming months. Lots of coverage
Speaker 1:  of camera buttons, all of it on The Verge dot com. I'll put a lot of links
Speaker 1:  in the show notes, but as always, just go read the site, find our bylines.
Speaker 1:  It's good stuff. And