# Transcript
ID: eb452a88-5e03-4261-917f-20c891629185
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/28739089557670192/2452147059233137698/s93290-US-4107s-1709026546.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of the economic theory of Dave and Busters:
02:50 - The Verge’s Mia Sato shares her experience on a new shopping app called Flip, which is filled with only videos that earn affiliate revenue.
Where everyone’s an influencer and everything’s for sale
35:34 - The Verge’s Vjeran Pavic and Becca Farsace chat with David Piece about the new Fuji X100VI, and why this line of cameras was a sensation on social media.
Fujifilm announces the X100VI, its follow-up to a TikTok sensation
The internet's NEW favorite camera? (Fuji X100VI)
Fujifilm X100T review
57:44 - Verge producer Will Poor answers a follow-up question about the right to repair legislation in this week’s Vergecast Hotline.
The Vergecast and Decoder are live at SXSW this weekend, March 8th and 9th. SXSW attendees can see both shows live on the official Vox Media Podcast Stage at the JW Marriott, presented by Atlassian. Learn more at voxmedia.com/live.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (8 ads detected)
Speaker 1:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the economic theory of
Speaker 1:  Dave and Busters. I'm my friend David Pierce and I am currently on my
Speaker 1:  way to a new bagel shop, which in my life at this point in my
Speaker 1:  life, counts as a huge life event. See, when I move somewhere new, I
Speaker 1:  immediately go on a grand quest for three things, a really
Speaker 1:  great cup of coffee, a really great deli sandwich, and a really great bagel
Speaker 1:  in New York. I found all three of those things, new York's good like that
Speaker 1:  in San Francisco. I found the first two, but never really found a
Speaker 1:  bagel that I loved. And now that I'm in the DC area, coffee
Speaker 1:  was easy to find, found a good deli sandwich, but it's been like four years
Speaker 1:  and I still haven't found the bagel. But this new place
Speaker 1:  just opened like a week ago in my neighborhood. Everybody says it's great.
Speaker 1:  I've been burned before, but I'm gonna go try it because that is my job.
Speaker 1:  This is my quest. I will find a great bagel. Anyway,
Speaker 1:  we have an awesome show coming up for you today. We're gonna do two things.
Speaker 1:  First, we're gonna talk about this app flip, which is like If, you took the
Speaker 1:  TikTok shop and the shopping stuff in Instagram and the shopping stuff in
Speaker 1:  Pinterest and just sort of smooshed it all together into a social
Speaker 1:  media app that is nothing but shopping and it's kind of working.
Speaker 1:  We're gonna get to the bottom of what's going on and why this thing is so
Speaker 1:  successful. Then we're gonna talk about the Fujifilm X 106,
Speaker 1:  which is the successor to the camera that The internet has spent the last
Speaker 1:  like three years totally obsessed with. It's beautiful,
Speaker 1:  it's cool, it takes neat photos. People are very excited about
Speaker 1:  it. We're gonna figure out if this is really worth the upgrade. All that's
Speaker 1:  coming up in just a sec, but first I have to go spend what I can only assume
Speaker 1:  is going to be an alarming amount of money on a bacon, egg and cheese. This
Speaker 1:  is The Vergecast. We'll see you in a sec.
Speaker 1:  Welcome back. All right, I'm home. I'm in the studio. I have eaten
Speaker 1:  the bacon, egg and cheese. It was good, but I think the hunt for the really
Speaker 1:  great one still continues. This one did have a little honey on it though,
Speaker 1:  which I liked a lot. That was a good tip. Anyway, let's get to the show.
Speaker 1:  Over the last few weeks the Verges, Mia Sato has been moonlighting
Speaker 1:  as a shopping influencer on an app called Flip. She hasn't told
Speaker 1:  me much about how it's going or what she's been up to in her time
Speaker 1:  as a shopping influencer, but this app is weird and
Speaker 1:  strange and she's going to tell us about all of her adventures.
Speaker 1:  Mia Sato, Welcome To, The Vergecast.
Speaker 4:  Thank you.
Speaker 1:  So I'm told the First thing you wanna do is share with me a video
Speaker 1:  that you made that the people need to hear.
Speaker 4:  Yes, the people need to hear this. It's very important.
Speaker 1:  Let's, let's just play this and then we'll see where we go.
Speaker 5:  Wow. I absolutely love this pure sonic facial
Speaker 5:  steamer because it feels so good on my face.
Speaker 5:  As you can see, it's really steaming
Speaker 4:  My face.
Speaker 1:  What, what is happening here? I need you to explain yourself. Okay,
Speaker 4:  So David, what if I told you that I had a TikTok for you where it was
Speaker 4:  only ads? Would you be interested?
Speaker 1:  I mean I would, I would make the slight argument that that might just be
Speaker 1:  called TikTok, but yes.
Speaker 4:  And you would use my referral code to sign up so that we could both get like
Speaker 4:  30 to $50.
Speaker 1:  Listen, if there is one thing, I believe it's that The internet is made for
Speaker 1:  scamming your way into 50 to a hundred dollars worth of free
Speaker 1:  stuff on The internet, most of which will be garbage, but some of which will
Speaker 1:  be great.
Speaker 4:  Okay. That's the, I love that we're on the same page because that's exactly
Speaker 4:  what I did, but more like $400 worth of stuff and I used my friends to do
Speaker 4:  it. Oh wow. And I'm here to tell my story and maybe get you on So.
Speaker 4:  I can get more stuff.
Speaker 1:  What, what is this app? It's not TikTok. It sure sounds
Speaker 1:  like TikTok. What app are we talking about here?
Speaker 4:  It's this app called Flip If. you are on TikTok and you use
Speaker 4:  Flip. You'll know exactly what to do because it, the user experience is very
Speaker 4:  similar. It's a vertical video feed where you swipe up and
Speaker 4:  you get new stuff except on Flip there is like a dislike button and a
Speaker 4:  like button and every video is about a product
Speaker 4:  that you can buy directly from that video. And there's also
Speaker 4:  like a shopping page similar to TikTok Shop where it's just loaded
Speaker 4:  with a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 1:  So it's shopping all the way down. Like it's, it's videos about
Speaker 1:  products you buy the products, you make a video about the product you bought,
Speaker 1:  other people buy the product and it's, it's just this endless cycle of
Speaker 1:  content about products that you can buy to make content about.
Speaker 4:  Exactly. It is completely circular, which is actually brilliant. Like you
Speaker 4:  can only make videos about stuff you've purchased there. It's like kind of
Speaker 4:  like TikTok and social media gamified to the extreme. So
Speaker 4:  as you're scrolling this feed there is a little counter in the top right
Speaker 4:  hand corner with a dollar amount and every time you watch a video you earn
Speaker 4:  a couple pennies. You just keep going and then you have sort of
Speaker 4:  a fake amount of money that you can then use as like
Speaker 4:  basically a 30% off coupon for anything you buy inside the money can
Speaker 4:  be, can cover up to 30% of your purchases. So it encourages
Speaker 4:  you to keep watching videos, you comment on them, you like them, sometimes
Speaker 4:  you buy stuff, you're racking up Little little points as you go
Speaker 4:  along.
Speaker 1:  Where did this app come from?
Speaker 4:  So. I heard about it through friends who had also been doing what I
Speaker 4:  did invite a bunch of friends so that you have kind of like an endless stream
Speaker 4:  of of fake money to buy stuff with and it's a
Speaker 4:  startup. It raised I think maybe around a hundred million dollars in the
Speaker 4:  last round and it has been kind of bubbling
Speaker 4:  under the surface for a bit. There have been a few articles about it's launch
Speaker 4:  last year, but mainly it seems like
Speaker 4:  a place where people jump on it with like a
Speaker 4:  lucrative referral program that they're doing right now. Buy one thing, make
Speaker 4:  a weird video and then maybe never come back. But then there are people like
Speaker 4:  me who spend ungodly amounts of time on it because it's like,
Speaker 4:  it feels like an upside down wacky world of like
Speaker 4:  things we already know and are very familiar with.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I do think there, there is a fascinating sort of statement about
Speaker 1:  the world inside of this app that I'm not sure this app wants to be making,
Speaker 1:  but tell me about like these videos I'm imagining I would say
Speaker 1:  like Mia I love you but your video is not particularly
Speaker 1:  enticing. I don't feel like I got to the end of that and I'm like, you know
Speaker 1:  what I need now as a facial steamer. Are you like worse
Speaker 1:  than average on Flip among the influencers? Are you better
Speaker 1:  than average? Like what kind of stuff do you see scrolling in this feed?
Speaker 1:  The
Speaker 4:  Feed is so chaotic. It is truly
Speaker 4:  like I was hooked from like the first five minutes because you get on the
Speaker 4:  feed and it is like nothing you've seen before. It's like the collection
Speaker 4:  of the worst videos you've ever seen and then some really like kind
Speaker 4:  of cringey like really tough watches one after another and
Speaker 4:  I'm obsessed with that. So there's several buckets of people on flip.
Speaker 4:  There are people who, like I said, buy one thing are
Speaker 4:  told that hey, if someone buys stuff off of your video that you made,
Speaker 4:  you can make money to. It's like an affiliate marketing scheme. They make
Speaker 4:  one video and then that's all that's on their profile.
Speaker 6:  So this is the clips, the clip,
Speaker 6:  a very nice clip.
Speaker 4:  There are the people who maybe have like something of a following on other
Speaker 4:  platforms and they've just jumped to this platform to see if this can become
Speaker 4:  a revenue stream for them. So they're making slightly more polished videos.
Speaker 4:  This
Speaker 7:  Is the men's sponge gel super buffer and smells so, so good.
Speaker 7:  I'm not going to open this because I got this as part of a birthday gift
Speaker 7:  for my boyfriend, but I've got this.
Speaker 4:  There are children, like literal children in school making videos
Speaker 4:  about phone cases. Those are extremely hilarious. Oh
Speaker 8:  God my phone died. I hate it.
Speaker 9:  Oh yo. I got portable charges.
Speaker 8:  Oh my God, thank you.
Speaker 4:  There are people doing like mimicking the
Speaker 4:  videos of legitimate and established influencers. What's
Speaker 10:  Up Flip fan. First time reviewer here just got my first
Speaker 10:  purchase. Mommy and Sonos Polar fleece,
Speaker 10:  olive Green, super comfy.
Speaker 4:  There are the honest reviewers just you
Speaker 4:  know your friend saying like, oh I don't really know if I liked this product.
Speaker 11:  Hmm, extremely disappointed. This course set
Speaker 11:  it's over a hundred dollars. I got it because I saw this
Speaker 11:  outfit from Sophia Regatta and I was like Ooh, lemme try that.
Speaker 11:  Look at this. This is the center one cup. It's higher than the
Speaker 11:  other one. Which
Speaker 4:  Is kind of like, I think the ideal that Flip Wants, it's all about this like
Speaker 4:  authenticity, honest reviews. They very much
Speaker 4:  lean into like it's good that these people are not practiced influencers.
Speaker 1:  Does that make sense to you as an approach when the whole point
Speaker 1:  of every single video is to sell you a product?
Speaker 4:  No, I mean obviously there's a tension there that nobody wants to
Speaker 4:  acknowledge, which is that you can make honest videos and you still
Speaker 4:  make money when people watch those videos. Right? You still make money even
Speaker 4:  if nobody buys it. Also there is tremendous financial incentive
Speaker 4:  to get people to buy it from your video. Like that is kind of the whole point.
Speaker 4:  And I think that you know the, the company can push this
Speaker 4:  sort of, this is authentic, this is real line as much as they
Speaker 4:  want. But that does not remove the central tension, which is
Speaker 4:  you are paying people really, really bad influencer rates
Speaker 4:  to make content for stuff that you otherwise would be outsourcing to people
Speaker 4:  who are charging like thousands of dollars a post.
Speaker 1:  Okay so part of this makes sense to me and part of it doesn't, we've seen
Speaker 1:  this with a lot of shopping apps, whether it's it was Wish a bunch of years
Speaker 1:  ago or she and and Timo and what the TikTok shop is doing where they
Speaker 1:  pour a bunch of money into subsidizing this for everybody. So you get cheap
Speaker 1:  stuff, you get referral codes. That part of this makes sense to me. There's
Speaker 1:  a bunch of money coming in, it's not sustainable but somebody can afford
Speaker 1:  to pump this up for a while. For you as a user, it sounds like,
Speaker 1:  if I'm understanding correctly, you make money just by watching
Speaker 1:  videos. Yes. And you also make money when people buy
Speaker 1:  products after they click on videos that you make?
Speaker 4:  Yes. It's like money on both sides. Money being sort of
Speaker 4:  like imprecise term because some of these are just like points basically.
Speaker 4:  Sure. Just with the dollar a sign in front of it. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  It all sounds a little like Dave and Busters where you just like spend a
Speaker 1:  bunch of money to buy your way into this sort of teeny tiny fake economy
Speaker 1:  that has no bearing on anything and no one actually understands how any
Speaker 1:  of it works but they get money and you don't at the end
Speaker 4:  1000% I am making videos for Chuck E Cheese tokens. Like that's what's
Speaker 4:  happening
Speaker 1:  And yet you decided to let this completely take over your life because
Speaker 4:  It's kind of fun. It's kind of, it's kind of fun
Speaker 4:  and it's, that is like the weird part of this. I think I have like
Speaker 4:  $80 right now in watch points I'll call them. Okay,
Speaker 4:  that's how much I've scrolled this feed and mind you I'm making like two
Speaker 4:  to 6 cents of you. Something like that. So I've been watching a lot of
Speaker 4:  videos.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So take me through kind of the the the Mia economy on Flip. You've
Speaker 1:  been in this for a while, you referred a bunch of people. What has your
Speaker 1:  voyage through this app been like over the last month or so?
Speaker 4:  So first I invited a bunch of friends and I think by
Speaker 4:  the end I had like almost $400 worth of credit.
Speaker 4:  And this is also kind of a little sneaky but the credit can be used to cover
Speaker 4:  up to 95% of the price of an item. So
Speaker 4:  if I had like a $100 jacket or something, I would pay 95
Speaker 4:  bucks and I would pull it out of my flip referral money,
Speaker 4:  So I invite a bunch of friends. I rack up all this money and then I just
Speaker 4:  started buying random stuff.
Speaker 5:  I think this is a hat and this is interesting. There is a
Speaker 5:  packing slip in the package and it's shipped to me
Speaker 5:  but it's billed to the flip shop and it's like
Speaker 5:  their address. I'm pretty confident that this is all being drop
Speaker 5:  shipped and they're just fronting the money for the purchase
Speaker 5:  and then you are paying them, you know, five bucks or however, whatever the
Speaker 5:  difference is after your 95% off coupon.
Speaker 4:  I bought clothes, I bought eye masks like skincare
Speaker 4:  eye masks. I bought the facial steamer of course that I
Speaker 4:  absolutely love how it steams my face. I bought mushroom
Speaker 4:  chocolates, I bought like a 35 millimeter film scanner. I
Speaker 4:  bought the protein powder of course I
Speaker 4:  tried to buy a variety of stuff just to see what would show up to my house.
Speaker 5:  These two are from a clothing brand
Speaker 5:  that was sort of suspiciously cheap about two shirts and they were each
Speaker 5:  12 to $15 So I'm not expecting much.
Speaker 5:  And the other I think are socks
Speaker 1:  That So I did this one time with Wish for a story. I actually
Speaker 1:  never ended up writing. I bought like a few hundred dollars worth of
Speaker 1:  obvious knockoffs of gadgets. There was like a thing that was clearly
Speaker 1:  a GoPro but wasn't a GoPro. I was kind of amazed at the spectrum
Speaker 1:  of quality. It was kind of a total grab
Speaker 1:  bag of whether any of this stuff was gonna be any good or even what it looked
Speaker 1:  like on the listing page. Was that your flip experience too?
Speaker 4:  I think it's yeah a hit or miss thing because there are some brands on flip.
Speaker 4:  I should also also mention that brands have to like apply to be on it and
Speaker 4:  for every purchase that is made on flip, flip takes a cut. Okay.
Speaker 4:  So it's like affiliate marketing on affiliate marketing. It's really,
Speaker 4:  there's a lot of layers here. So there are legit brands, several makeup
Speaker 4:  brands that people always post normal tiktoks of, right? Like
Speaker 4:  they're very popular brands. The film scanner was I think maybe a Kodak
Speaker 4:  one. It really runs the gamut.
Speaker 1:  Okay. But then again if I'm understanding the, the flip economy correctly,
Speaker 1:  buying and receiving the products is only the first part of
Speaker 1:  the process. You then are immediately supposed to turn around
Speaker 1:  and make content and this is where I think you, you hit your true star
Speaker 1:  turn at least as far as I can tell, which is Mia Sato
Speaker 1:  weird product reviewer on The internet. Tell me about protein
Speaker 1:  powder Hawking Mia, what's her deal?
Speaker 4:  Okay, so that was the first video I made. Mm. My first instinct was to
Speaker 4:  be kind of an asshole about it. I haven't opened
Speaker 4:  this and I haven't eaten it but I think I
Speaker 4:  recommend it. In fact I do recommend it. Okay. That video
Speaker 4:  has 860 views. Okay. And I've
Speaker 4:  made a dollar and 92 cents, which actually is really good
Speaker 4:  for views. Nobody has bought it from my video but it's pretty good.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's a pretty good conversion. And then the next day I decided to actually
Speaker 4:  use the protein powder in a protein shake and I made another video
Speaker 4:  of course. Okay. Another update. I made a protein shake
Speaker 4:  with the protein powder and it is absolutely horrendous.
Speaker 4:  It is horrifyingly bad. It is so fucking bad. Do not buy this.
Speaker 1:  So a, I appreciate the journalistic integrity here. This is good.
Speaker 1:  But also this is the thing that people are watching in deciding maybe
Speaker 1:  I'll buy this product. Like you're, you're making money off of telling people
Speaker 1:  how terrible these protein shakes are.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's hysterical also multiple people put it in their cart from my video.
Speaker 4:  Good
Speaker 1:  Lord
Speaker 4:  So I have to say that. Like if I tried a little bit harder, imagine what
Speaker 4:  I could do. Imagine how much, how much flip money I would have.
Speaker 1:  So the like the neg as a product review strategy is kind of
Speaker 1:  amazing. Yeah. This this is a thing we need to explore like The Verge just
Speaker 1:  nagging products is is maybe a thing we should start doing more of. I love
Speaker 1:  this. Did you do the mushroom chocolates? This is the other one I'm fascinated
Speaker 1:  by. 'cause I feel like the the facial steamer is like look it's steaming
Speaker 1:  my face. Like I get that trying to explain to people whether they should
Speaker 1:  buy mushroom chocolates based on a recommendation from a stranger
Speaker 1:  on The internet seems like an interesting content challenge.
Speaker 4:  Well it's actually really easy because the mushroom chocolates look kind
Speaker 4:  of cute. Mm. One thing about a lot of the reviews that I saw
Speaker 4:  was that the people will say stuff about the
Speaker 4:  product that has nothing to do with the product, right? They will say
Speaker 4:  here it is, I just got this. Check it out. Right. Like they
Speaker 4:  don't use it.
Speaker 12:  Yo what else? Flippers just got this bucket hat from dumb club on
Speaker 12:  flip, it's got sick,
Speaker 12:  sick, I can't even explain the word for it. Characters. It's
Speaker 12:  got all the characters from their website on here. Sick quality,
Speaker 12:  sick hat,
Speaker 4:  So I was like let me try that where I'm not doing anything with the item.
Speaker 4:  So a maim mushroom chocolate video.
Speaker 5:  We don't love that these mushroom chocolates came, the
Speaker 5:  tin came open. But yeah,
Speaker 5:  they also be warned they will not get you high. Not
Speaker 5:  fun mushrooms just focus on energy mushrooms.
Speaker 4:  That has gotten me $3 and 45 cents
Speaker 1:  Killing it. Did anybody buy it?
Speaker 4:  No of course. No nobody. Nobody has purchased anything from me. So
Speaker 1:  You've sold nothing. Nothing to anyone. Nothing. But you're still making
Speaker 1:  money. Yeah, that's The future right there. I
Speaker 4:  Think that means I'm doing well but also
Speaker 1:  Perfectly low stakes 'cause nobody actually bought anything so nobody can
Speaker 1:  blame you for anything. Yeah
Speaker 4:  Totally. Another thing is like there's no way to add music. So
Speaker 4:  all of these are like silent, it's very like unsettling kind of. Oh
Speaker 1:  That's true.
Speaker 4:  Yeah it's really weird. Some people sometimes sneak music in like maybe they
Speaker 4:  recorded it in TikTok and then re-uploaded it but for the most part these
Speaker 4:  are like very like you can hear people breathing
Speaker 1:  Well. Yeah. So this is one of the things I keep wondering as you're talking
Speaker 1:  about this, which is I think about these kinds of videos as compared to
Speaker 1:  product placement stuff you see on Instagram or TikTok. And so for me, like
Speaker 1:  if I'm a brand, if I'm Kodak trying to sell a printer, why on earth
Speaker 1:  would I want to be on Flip?
Speaker 4:  That is such a good question because the brands get no control
Speaker 4:  over these videos. There's no review process that happens like with other
Speaker 4:  influencer content where brands are looking at it, editing it,
Speaker 4:  sending it back, accepting it like I am just some
Speaker 4:  rando making videos about your product. And that is where it
Speaker 4:  kind of gets into stickier, weirder
Speaker 4:  places. There's videos on Flip that if I were the brand I
Speaker 4:  probably would not want to exist.
Speaker 1:  Like gimme an example,
Speaker 4:  The funniest one that kind of came up really soon after I indicated that
Speaker 4:  I wanted to see men's fashion content. There was a video
Speaker 4:  with a man in shorts and
Speaker 4:  he and his friends are laughing and cackling about
Speaker 4:  the video that he is making and I think we should just roll the clip 'cause
Speaker 4:  I'm not going to try to repeat it.
Speaker 13:  Reveal these shorts all around comfort.
Speaker 13:  Incredible. Especially on the ball sack. Great
Speaker 13:  flexibility. I really like the way you can see just the outline of my
Speaker 13:  fucking balls just, just right there
Speaker 1:  Somewhere. Everyone who works in brand safety is just sobbing
Speaker 1:  into their phone right now. That's
Speaker 4:  Not even the worst one.
Speaker 4:  There was another one where the review is for socks
Speaker 4:  and the guys' feet are up on a coffee table.
Speaker 14:  Yo, what is up you guys? It's me with
Speaker 14:  my first flip review. I'm reviewing these
Speaker 14:  socks that I just got. First impressions, pretty
Speaker 14:  comfortable, nice soft touch to him.
Speaker 4:  If, you listen to it, it's fine. But what you do not see unless you're watching
Speaker 4:  the video is that around, first of all in front of his socks, his feet
Speaker 4:  is a bong that is like two feet tall and then
Speaker 4:  surrounding the bong and on the coffee table are dozens of Whippet canisters.
Speaker 4:  Which yeah, if I'm the company that makes a socks a company which I did
Speaker 4:  reach out to and they didn't get back to me, I would be like please don't
Speaker 4:  do this. Yeah, I'm paying money, I'm paying money Every time someone makes
Speaker 4:  a purchase off this video, the brand safety is non-existent.
Speaker 4:  Well
Speaker 1:  And and that brings up I would say even like the slightly higher stakes version
Speaker 1:  of like content moderation stuff, right? Because if you're trying
Speaker 1:  to sell me something there's going to be an element of like life
Speaker 1:  recommendation that you have to do. But if you're doing it surrounded by
Speaker 1:  cans of whippets you have a real like genuine content
Speaker 1:  moderation problem that is more than just making the advertisers happy. Like
Speaker 1:  obviously TikTok has been through this, Instagram has been through this.
Speaker 1:  Everybody at any scale doing social stuff, shopping or otherwise goes
Speaker 1:  through content moderation stuff. Is flip doing content
Speaker 1:  moderation or are they as blase about everything as they seem to be about
Speaker 1:  these videos?
Speaker 4:  So I asked the flip CEO about this and his
Speaker 4:  response was they have a team of seven or eight content moderators
Speaker 4:  or working at least on that side and their main thing that they're
Speaker 4:  looking for is like abusive content, hateful stuff.
Speaker 15:  When something is escalated, when a report is escalating is is checked by
Speaker 15:  a human being but 70% of it is managed with machine learning.
Speaker 4:  But other than that they like the unvarnished sort of
Speaker 4:  average people doing stuff vibe. They don't
Speaker 4:  seem too concerned with like this idea of brand safety. They
Speaker 4:  also, you know like kind of like the trolley videos.
Speaker 15:  I generally believe the influencer ecosystem of selling you
Speaker 15:  stuff is not something that's going on the way up.
Speaker 15:  I think there is a real ache for any realness
Speaker 15:  online, like anything that is real and not scripted
Speaker 15:  and not like filtered a thousand times.
Speaker 4:  They say that most people if they're going to troll do it in their first
Speaker 4:  video and then don't go on to like make that their entire account. I would
Speaker 4:  like disagree. I've definitely seen people who their entire thing is sort
Speaker 4:  of wink, wink, nudge, nudge. Like this is so stupid that we're doing this
Speaker 4:  but we're gonna do it anyway. It's something of the wild wild west where
Speaker 4:  people are just making money, you know,
Speaker 4:  producing the stuff that is like so low effort and and very unserious.
Speaker 1:  Do you buy the idea that that authenticity can scale
Speaker 1:  in this way? I mean I think we've seen over and over that once you introduce
Speaker 1:  not you know, pennies and nickels and dollars but like real make a
Speaker 1:  living kind of money to any kind of platform like this,
Speaker 1:  it changes you and I have both covered a million apps that come out and
Speaker 1:  are like we're the one that's real and then they get popular and they stop
Speaker 1:  being real and then another one comes out and it's like well we're the one
Speaker 1:  that's real and I wonder if it's possible. Do you think
Speaker 1:  Flip can grow the way it wants to and still feel like this?
Speaker 4:  I think right now it's in this sort of era of Gold Rush where it has all
Speaker 4:  this investor money just funding people joining
Speaker 4:  but Flip does not exist unless people are actually making purchases. So
Speaker 4:  let's say like everything is trash and nobody buys anything on Flip,
Speaker 4:  eventually that will collapse because the company is not
Speaker 4:  bringing anything in. Why would people make videos for stuff if
Speaker 4:  they're not buying anything, right? Like you can't So I think that this
Speaker 4:  idea of authenticity is, it's a pretty limited view
Speaker 4:  of what that looks like. I don't really need to go on
Speaker 4:  an app to see what my friends think about products, right? I can just text
Speaker 4:  them, I can just ask them if they like something, even if I saw them
Speaker 4:  make a video about a product, who's to say that I would buy it from them.
Speaker 4:  I might just like go to the site and see if there's a discount or buy it
Speaker 4:  somewhere else. So I think this idea that they can corral all of your shopping
Speaker 4:  habits and sort of review culture
Speaker 4:  into one place is I would say it's a pipe dream.
Speaker 1:  I agree with all of that in theory and yet there is part of me that says
Speaker 1:  maybe what Flip is doing, and this is this is kind of where my like
Speaker 1:  Galaxy Brain feelings you take on all of this goes is that maybe what Flip
Speaker 1:  is doing is just short cutting and end running
Speaker 1:  this process that Instagram and TikTok and all the other platforms are already
Speaker 1:  on. I mean we've talked about on this show and you've been, you've been writing
Speaker 1:  about the overwhelming influx of the TikTok shop
Speaker 1:  onto TikTok and now If you want to be popular on TikTok. The single
Speaker 1:  quickest way to get there is to be selling something and now it feels like
Speaker 1:  everything you see on TikTok, somebody is selling you something and that's
Speaker 1:  where the business is going. That's where a lot of this stuff is going and
Speaker 1:  it's also just becoming sort of accepted. I think like
Speaker 1:  years ago it would've felt gross for people to be nakedly
Speaker 1:  selling you stuff like this online and now it's just kind of what it is.
Speaker 1:  So maybe flip is just skipping to the last step
Speaker 1:  and it's gonna be right because shopping is the end stage of all of this
Speaker 1:  anyway. Like is there a version of this where Flip is just gonna like win
Speaker 1:  because it threw out all the other pretend stuff and just did the thing that
Speaker 1:  actually makes the money? Well
Speaker 4:  I think one of the reasons I find Flip very compelling and why I've spent
Speaker 4:  again hours on the app is that it does feel like
Speaker 4:  sort of the evolution of short form video that
Speaker 4:  we are already seeing hints of like that this is the direction even apps
Speaker 4:  like TikTok are going where I don't know that Flip will be the one that wins
Speaker 4:  in the end, but it is capturing and
Speaker 4:  sort of trying to monetize what TikTok also is
Speaker 4:  trying to do. If you have maybe been, you know on TikTok in
Speaker 4:  the recent, in the last like week or so you've probably seen like at the
Speaker 4:  end of videos there will be a popup that says Shop
Speaker 4:  more shoes or Shop more men's
Speaker 4:  coats on TikTok shop and it takes you to TikTok shop and gives
Speaker 4:  you a list of products that in my experience I wrote about
Speaker 4:  this as well in my experience have nothing to do with the product that it
Speaker 4:  says it wants you to shop for but the goal is to get you
Speaker 4:  on to shop on the shop platform and the videos that these prompts
Speaker 4:  are being added to are not even nakedly
Speaker 4:  promotional. They're talking about something and TikTok
Speaker 4:  picks up what is in that video and tries to convert that into a purchase.
Speaker 4:  And so the flip platform is like that if it
Speaker 4:  drops a pretext
Speaker 1:  Right? It's almost more honest in a way.
Speaker 4:  It is completely. And we already know that this is really the direction
Speaker 4:  that TikTok wants to go in and that it is seriously trying to ramp up its
Speaker 4:  shopping business in the United States this year. So it was giving
Speaker 4:  all these crazy promotional deals to merchants to try to get them onto TikTok
Speaker 4:  shop. It was doing sort of the Ali Express
Speaker 4:  Shian Temu thing of you know, 99% off
Speaker 4:  or free item just pay shipping, like whatever these kind of crazy
Speaker 4:  good, too good to be true deals to get people to buy things on
Speaker 4:  TikTok shop. The parallels with Flip are very obvious. It feels like
Speaker 4:  Flip is just that but more focused where
Speaker 4:  they just stop pretending that it's about anything other than actually making,
Speaker 4:  making sales and getting that affiliate money. Getting merchants on onto
Speaker 4:  the platform. I've observed this, I don't know David if you've seen this
Speaker 4:  too with like your favorite creators who start out educational, you know,
Speaker 4:  start out making educational content, start out vlogging or not
Speaker 4:  monetizing their content in any way in particular, but then very quickly
Speaker 4:  when the opportunity presents itself they jump to doing the sponsored content.
Speaker 4:  Yep. Or the, the ads and that bridge
Speaker 4:  is like a stone's throw, you know, it is so easy to
Speaker 4:  switch into that mode If you want and there are a lot of people who
Speaker 4:  hold down normal jobs and then also are making, you know, getting brand deals
Speaker 4:  and making tiktoks and making sponsored content. So this idea of
Speaker 4:  like influencer being a separate category
Speaker 4:  is I think increasingly becoming less true. And the whole thing about Flip
Speaker 4:  is that you see non influencers make this content
Speaker 4:  and potentially benefit and profit from it and they want you to do that.
Speaker 4:  They want you to create this new side hustle that maybe might
Speaker 4:  amount to, you know, 20 bucks in a in a couple weeks, which is,
Speaker 4:  I haven't even hit that point and I've been trying so hard on flip and I
Speaker 4:  still have only made like $14 and I can't even cash it out. I cannot even
Speaker 4:  cash out my money because I need to get to 20. So yeah, it's very sad and
Speaker 4:  feels like stolen labor on my part but
Speaker 4:  this vision that it presents is that all of your activities
Speaker 4:  online, all of your purchases, maybe you can monetize them. What if, what
Speaker 4:  If you could.
Speaker 1:  Right. And it makes me wonder if Flip looks more
Speaker 1:  like The future of Amazon or The future of
Speaker 1:  social networking because I think to me the idea that TikTok and
Speaker 1:  Instagram and sort of the places we used to go to like connect and find stuff
Speaker 1:  we liked online are just rapidly becoming shopping malls
Speaker 1:  is true and also like deeply bleak and kind of
Speaker 1:  dystopian in a way. But the idea that the way I shop on Amazon
Speaker 1:  is essentially going to be sort of overrun by middlemen
Speaker 1:  who are like real people, quote unquote real people who are talking
Speaker 1:  about the products. That doesn't strike me as like more or less
Speaker 1:  bad in the world. It just seems like kind of a future of
Speaker 1:  shopping that is already really real in places like China where like live
Speaker 1:  streaming shopping has been a huge business for a really long time. And So
Speaker 1:  I wonder, like as you talk to folks that flip and use the platform, like
Speaker 1:  does it feel more like social or more like shopping over time?
Speaker 4:  That's a good question because so much of short form video like TikTok was
Speaker 4:  already about finding things to buy. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Totally.
Speaker 4:  I have been like beating this drum for a long time, especially with
Speaker 4:  people in my age group women Gen Z, right? Like
Speaker 4:  they go to TikTok for recommendations. They do and they jump off the app
Speaker 4:  then buy the thing. Often it sells out. Sometimes it's like in the
Speaker 4:  New York Times style section or whatever, gets all these writeups of the,
Speaker 4:  about this viral product and TikTok is making no money from that. So
Speaker 4:  obviously they want in on this. And Flip is sort of just like
Speaker 4:  systematizing this and automating that in a way that TikTok I think is really
Speaker 4:  trying to flip's footprint is obviously way smaller than TikTok,
Speaker 4:  but you know, the point stands and in terms of like, I don't know, does
Speaker 4:  it feel better or worse? I think it's
Speaker 4:  interesting that we are in an era of hyper
Speaker 4:  recommendations and we still need someone to tell us what to do. That we
Speaker 4:  still need someone to tell us what is good and what is bad and what we should
Speaker 4:  buy. I saw like the explosion of gift guides on TikTok this year more than
Speaker 4:  other years, which I find fascinating when presumably our
Speaker 4:  for you algorithm should be like an endless stream of
Speaker 4:  gifts or things that we might be interested in. Things that, you know, the
Speaker 4:  data shows that we might, we might purchase or we might watch or we might
Speaker 4:  like or save. And so this idea that like we still want
Speaker 4:  newsletters with recommendations, we still want friends telling us things.
Speaker 4:  It tells me that there's, there's something that is not
Speaker 4:  quite there with like the algorithmic recommendations. And
Speaker 4:  is it good that all of us become salespeople?
Speaker 4:  Like, no, is that brave of me to say, I don't know. That feels
Speaker 4:  bad. That feels bad. And but I also get the other point of
Speaker 4:  like If, you are posting something on TikTok and it's going to be catapulting
Speaker 4:  the viewer to TikTok shop anyway. Why not try to get
Speaker 4:  a cut of it? Because right now as it stands, the people who have that TikTok
Speaker 4:  shop, you know, shop more shoes button, as far as I
Speaker 4:  know, they're not getting a cut of that. So it makes me think like, why would
Speaker 4:  I make any content if it's just going to be a sort of portal
Speaker 4:  for TikTok to make more money? Totally.
Speaker 1:  No, I I think that's right and I think in, in a funny way, you just sort
Speaker 1:  of encapsulated like a central tension of The internet right now that we
Speaker 1:  are gonna have to spend a lot more time talking about. But for now, before
Speaker 1:  I let you go, give me the, the state of the Mia flip business.
Speaker 1:  You said you've made like 14 bucks. Tell me, I want, I wanna know the money,
Speaker 1:  I wanna know the views, I wanna know how quickly you are becoming a
Speaker 1:  mogul on flip.
Speaker 4:  I have to say that it's, it's not going as successfully as I
Speaker 4:  would've hoped. Also, the videos that I spent the most time on have done
Speaker 4:  the worst, which is fascinating. There's
Speaker 1:  A life lesson there.
Speaker 4:  It's a life lesson. It's sad too because a lot of the products that I bought,
Speaker 4:  like I probably won't end up doing much with, I, I tried
Speaker 4:  to buy some perishable things. So like I bought coffee beans, which I will
Speaker 4:  drink coffee eventually. I bought candles that I actually am obsessed
Speaker 4:  with that I purchased before I was on Flip and I was like, oh, they're on
Speaker 4:  Flip too. So I bought like four of those candles. Nice. So I'm
Speaker 4:  stocked but I will not quit my job at The
Speaker 4:  Verge dot com anytime soon. Unless something crazy happens to my
Speaker 4:  flip content, then I then I'm out. Once
Speaker 1:  You hit 20 bucks and you can cash out, it's all over.
Speaker 4:  I'm taking my money and running. Exactly. Love
Speaker 1:  It. Mia. Thank you. Appreciate it as always.
Speaker 4:  Thanks David. This was so fun.
Speaker 1:  All right, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna talk cameras. We'll
Speaker 1:  be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Last week Fujifilm announced the X 106,
Speaker 1:  which is its newest camera. Normally in 2024. A new camera
Speaker 1:  doesn't qualify as a culture shaking event, but this one
Speaker 1:  kind of did the X 105. The last model of this camera
Speaker 1:  became kind of a viral sensation over the last few years to the point where
Speaker 1:  you basically couldn't get your hands on one, even If you wanted to even
Speaker 1:  If you wanted to spend the well over a thousand dollars that it would cost
Speaker 1:  you. This new model is apparently going to be easier to get your hands on
Speaker 1:  and also comes with some upgrades. But fundamentally it's still an X 100
Speaker 1:  oh and it's a little more expensive to help me figure out why this camera
Speaker 1:  matters so much and whether the new one is a worthy upgrades. The
Speaker 1:  Internet's favorite camera, I grabbed two members of the verges video team
Speaker 1:  and two of our most dedicated camera nerds. Verin Pavich
Speaker 1:  and Becca Farsace Verin, welcome to the show. Oh
Speaker 18:  My God. Hello
Speaker 1:  Becca. Hello. Hello my camera people. This is very exciting.
Speaker 1:  I'm glad to have you here. We never get to talk about dedicated cameras
Speaker 1:  on The Vergecast because who cares? But now we get to because people care.
Speaker 1:  This is very exciting. Boy do they care? They super care. Yeah, right.
Speaker 1:  So I wanna get it? That's like mostly what I wanna talk about is like the,
Speaker 1:  the cultural phenomenon of this camera. But I feel like we should
Speaker 1:  educate people on a little bit of, of Fujifilm
Speaker 1:  history here to start. So Verin, maybe let's start with you 'cause
Speaker 1:  I think you've been using the X 100 line of cameras for
Speaker 1:  a very long time. So like take me back to the, the beginning of the X
Speaker 1:  100. What is this camera like? What's its deal? Even from the very
Speaker 1:  beginning,
Speaker 18:  So I, someone actually asked me yesterday, they used Fuji and I went back
Speaker 18:  to like see when I started and it was exactly a 10 years ago. Oh nice.
Speaker 18:  When I bought the X 100 T, which is the
Speaker 18:  third one, now it's six and people are opinionated. It is a
Speaker 18:  point and shoot fixed lens 23 millimeter F two
Speaker 18:  on, which is an equivalent to 35 millimeter camera that just
Speaker 18:  does a lot of things, right? Like people love it is the fact that it
Speaker 18:  has like film simulations that make your JPEG look amazing
Speaker 18:  for a lot of people and myself included, it's been like the the perfect
Speaker 18:  beat camera. Like I want a digital camera that is a small footprint that
Speaker 18:  I can bring everywhere and get good results with. And that's kind of it.
Speaker 18:  And it was my entry into Fuji and at that point, like I saw this camera,
Speaker 18:  I played around with it and I was like, oh wow, this is what a modern camera
Speaker 18:  looks like and a retro body. I got really excited by like the, the
Speaker 18:  viewfinder and the built-in nds and all these little things
Speaker 18:  that make it like very useful.
Speaker 19:  But I, I don't think it's just that it produces good results. I think
Speaker 19:  what's actually more important is that you look cool doing it because
Speaker 19:  there's many point and shoot cameras like this, like Ricoh makes one
Speaker 19:  and I mean If you have a lot of money like, but like the whole idea is that
Speaker 19:  like, this looks really cool. It's a, it's a price point that some people
Speaker 19:  can digest easily without knowing too much about cameras. And then you also
Speaker 19:  have the added bonus of sometimes it can produce good results if you know
Speaker 19:  what you're doing.
Speaker 1:  Balance those two sides of it for me. 'cause I think there is something to
Speaker 1:  the fact that this is just a great looking camera and has been for a long
Speaker 1:  time and it started to be everywhere. you know people are doing like street
Speaker 1:  photography and like the blogging era and everybody was excited about those
Speaker 1:  cameras for that. But there is also something to what you're saying, ve
Speaker 1:  and I, somebody described it to me at one point as like it is the perfect
Speaker 1:  middle between A-D-S-L-R and a smartphone where it's, you get
Speaker 1:  some controls but fundamentally you can just turn the thing on, point it
Speaker 1:  at something, shoot and trust that it will do something spectacular
Speaker 1:  for you. So like for you guys as people who do this like professionally,
Speaker 1:  do you buy this because it's cool over another sort of
Speaker 1:  equivalently spect equivalently priced camera or is there something
Speaker 1:  about the X 100 that is special as a camera?
Speaker 19:  I can't wait to hear Vern's answer.
Speaker 18:  I will say there is something very special about this camera.
Speaker 19:  There it is.
Speaker 18:  I will say that much. There it is. You won the bed if that was your bed.
Speaker 19:  Bingo. But I would buy this camera as a hobby camera.
Speaker 19:  Like this is what I take with me because it's fun to use.
Speaker 19:  It has like all, I have it right here. It has like all of these dials and
Speaker 19:  it feels good in your hand. Although this front grip could be hella thicker,
Speaker 19:  which is why a lot of people buy a thumb grip for the back. It's just fun
Speaker 19:  to use and you get results that are better than a smartphone.
Speaker 19:  But I wouldn't do professional work on this
Speaker 19:  because on a professional camera I want more control over my lenses
Speaker 19:  and I do want a full frame sensor.
Speaker 18:  Yeah it is not like a camera that can do a lot.
Speaker 18:  It has that perfect focal length for a lot of people. It has very good
Speaker 18:  video capabilities. But does it really need, I mean like
Speaker 18:  yeah it's nice to have and I guess in a world of like TikTok and Instagram
Speaker 18:  like reels like yeah it's good to have like good video as well. But
Speaker 18:  even like video capabilities, I always like never really cared about those
Speaker 18:  on this camera. So it is like, it is very limiting in what it can
Speaker 18:  do actually as a camera. but it really exploded
Speaker 18:  in popularity in the last couple of years.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, no Vern, hold on. I'm not letting you off the hook for this though.
Speaker 1:  You love this thing. Thank you. Yeah, there this thing has like mythical
Speaker 1:  properties for you and I want you to explain why
Speaker 18:  I do love this camera. I do have a confession that I actually like sold
Speaker 18:  mine. What? Yes I did. 'cause I just knew that maybe
Speaker 18:  I will get whatever is coming and the pricing for it was still like, oh
Speaker 18:  yeah, you know what? I can, I can sell it for a decent amount of money.
Speaker 19:  Not only does Verin wanna get what's coming, but he saw the limited
Speaker 19:  edition. It was like I, I don't really want this camera, I want the one
Speaker 19:  that's only 1,900 and I don't know, 36 of 'em remain. I want that
Speaker 19:  one. Love it.
Speaker 18:  Yes. Well I did spend my entire morning trying to get Eldon Ring collector's
Speaker 18:  edition and that failed. So you know, I have to like redeem myself with
Speaker 18:  the Fuji X 106 limited edition.
Speaker 18:  No, I mean I do love what Fuji is doing with like the film
Speaker 18:  simulations and everything. I make a lot of my own. I go through the,
Speaker 18:  the websites that like give you recipes that you can use for the camera.
Speaker 18:  I just love bringing it around. Like I'm an am the person who like wants
Speaker 18:  to bring a camera everywhere I go for the longest time that it used to be
Speaker 18:  like a five D for me, which is massive and really not like
Speaker 18:  a thing that you would wanna like carry around. So this was always like,
Speaker 18:  oh I can bring this, it's a digital camera. I mainly film
Speaker 18:  still shooting digital. So there was a lot
Speaker 18:  about it that just like, it does very well. But once I got my
Speaker 18:  first one, like the, the idea of like all the modern specs that it
Speaker 18:  actually had in it made me realize about like, oh
Speaker 18:  these cameras are just like super fun to just like use
Speaker 18:  and have a bunch in it that I like wasn't expecting.
Speaker 19:  Yeah. So it's like the joining of this is fun to use and I can also get
Speaker 19:  pretty good results with it.
Speaker 1:  And there is something too, having a camera this size that is
Speaker 1:  not scary to bring to parties. Like I have been places where Veen has
Speaker 1:  busted out big giant cameras with you know, 18 to 200 lenses and they
Speaker 1:  freak people out. Whereas the X 100 is like that perfect size where
Speaker 1:  it sort of blends in in a way that other better cameras don't. And
Speaker 1:  it is like, it's a middle point that I think is very powerful.
Speaker 19:  I saw on threads somebody was saying like this is the greatest camera to
Speaker 19:  bring to concerts 'cause I know it won't get confiscated, it doesn't look
Speaker 19:  professional enough for that. But I can get great results and like genius.
Speaker 19:  Yep.
Speaker 1:  Perfect explanation. I love that. So, but for like a decade this thing just
Speaker 1:  trundles along. It's a good camera, people like it, but it then in 2020
Speaker 1:  becomes like a cultural phenomenon. And I, I missed the
Speaker 1:  origins of this. Like all of a sudden I feel like I turned around and everyone
Speaker 1:  was talking about it. But this is a TikTok thing, right? Like
Speaker 1:  Becca, how did this become such a thing on The internet
Speaker 19:  TikTok is a visual platform and folks saw this camera,
Speaker 19:  they saw the results that some folks were getting and they're like, I want
Speaker 19:  that too. And like I was saying before, it has a price that
Speaker 19:  is friendly to some folks. Not all, this is not a cheap camera
Speaker 19:  by any means, but it's much cheaper than most muralist cameras
Speaker 19:  or most cameras that produce similar results that are in, you know, into
Speaker 19:  the two thousands. And that's just for the body alone. This you get the
Speaker 19:  camera and the lens. And at the time I think it
Speaker 19:  was going for like, well before it blew up on TikTok, it was going for like
Speaker 19:  $1,400 and then it blew up and so did the prices.
Speaker 18:  Honestly it took me by surprise how many people would come to me asking
Speaker 18:  me about this camera and I had no idea that it was blowing up on TikTok.
Speaker 18:  Hmm. Like I, I truly had no idea that it was like becoming so popular.
Speaker 18:  And soon after that, like my algorithm changed
Speaker 18:  entirely and the only thing I can see is just like X 100 V photos and
Speaker 18:  samples and not even like samples. Like my, my algorithms are like
Speaker 18:  very much like photo video creators. Like I see a lot of samples
Speaker 18:  with everything but the X 100 V was kind of like
Speaker 18:  just chilling there. It was like part of the set as well. And it was not
Speaker 18:  only about what it can do, but it was also very cool to have this camera.
Speaker 18:  Like I do think that a lot of people now like do love the film
Speaker 18:  look in general, but some people don't want to make film photos.
Speaker 18:  And this was kind of like, oh I can, I can have the best of both worlds.
Speaker 19:  Yeah. If you'll allow me to talk about that for a second. The whole, the
Speaker 19:  whole idea of having film photos without having to shoot film.
Speaker 19:  Like I think a lot of folks swung to film because you can naturally get
Speaker 19:  a really great baked in look but there's a lot of friction there with having
Speaker 19:  to drop it off at a lab and like kind of having to know what aperture
Speaker 19:  is.
Speaker 1:  Plus then you have it on film and what the hell are you gonna do with film?
Speaker 19:  You're gonna put it in a binder and you're never gonna look at it again.
Speaker 18:  Yeah. You have to scan it. How are you gonna scan it? Are you taking photos
Speaker 18:  or a scanner? Like there's a whole culture of like,
Speaker 18:  you know, subculture people like doing it and it's fantastic. And I think
Speaker 18:  in like, especially when we're like in the AI role of just like
Speaker 18:  generative images and now videos, like there is something about
Speaker 18:  the tangibility of film that people are like really going after again.
Speaker 18:  Oh
Speaker 19:  Yeah, I love it. but it is filled with friction. I'll say it film is a
Speaker 19:  pain in the ass and that's what I love about it. But this can give you
Speaker 19:  film like it's, it's the closest digital camera that can naturally give
Speaker 19:  you film-like results without having to do anything with film.
Speaker 1:  Becca, dig into that a little bit for me. 'cause people do talk a lot about
Speaker 1:  the film simulation stuff and I think I have
Speaker 1:  been conditioned over the years to not trust any built-in
Speaker 1:  setting inside of a camera because they'll just screw up your photos and
Speaker 1:  everybody's like, just do it in post, fix it on your computer. You can make
Speaker 1:  it look like anything you want. There's tons of good software. You, you should
Speaker 1:  shoot the rawest cleanest thing outta the camera that you should.
Speaker 1:  But on the X 100 people buy into these film
Speaker 1:  simulation things, right? Like what is, what is Fuji doing here that is different?
Speaker 19:  So David ML made an incredible video for the studio about
Speaker 19:  why and how Fujifilm is perfectly poised to make this camera.
Speaker 19:  And the guts of that video is that they have been creating film
Speaker 19:  for, I mean most of their history. And so they have
Speaker 19:  a lot of great color scientists who know how to make great
Speaker 19:  colors and they just baked that into this camera. And that's something that,
Speaker 19:  I mean if Kodak was still around, maybe they could do it, but nobody else
Speaker 19:  has that background knowledge on color science. And so there's a level of
Speaker 19:  trust that folks have in this camera and the colors that it produces that
Speaker 19:  they don't have in other companies cameras. And again, go watch David's
Speaker 19:  video. It is excellent. And he also speaks about shooting
Speaker 19:  raw versus jpeg and makes a great analogy to
Speaker 19:  clay and you gotta go watch that video. But the long short of it is that
Speaker 19:  the colors that this camera produces are actually really good and more
Speaker 19:  importantly they're unique to this system, whereas in most manufacturers
Speaker 19:  are just creating color profiles that are pleasing to the most amount of
Speaker 19:  people.
Speaker 1:  Got it. Okay. So let's talk about the, the X 106 itself.
Speaker 1:  This thing has been, I would say more hotly awaited than just
Speaker 1:  about any camera I can think of. I admittedly am not in like the
Speaker 1:  professional camera world, So, I, don't know if they're like weird Sony
Speaker 1:  lenses that are getting just as much press, but like people have been talking
Speaker 1:  about it waiting for this camera for a very long time. Like there, there
Speaker 1:  were leaks about every piece of it, which I don't remember happening for
Speaker 1:  a camera in a really long time. What is different from a hardware
Speaker 1:  perspective about the camera this time? Becca, you have one. What are kind
Speaker 1:  of the big upgrades for this generation?
Speaker 19:  You do have 40 megapixels as opposed to 26
Speaker 19:  megapixels on the V. The LCD allows 15 degrees more
Speaker 19:  tilt, but otherwise it's pretty much the same
Speaker 19:  camera. There's one more thing that's very important. you know, how have
Speaker 19:  InBody image stabilization so you can basically shoot at
Speaker 19:  lower shutter speeds and still get crisp photos.
Speaker 1:  That feels fine. Were people clamoring for anything new and
Speaker 1:  huge in the hardware? It doesn't sound like they were,
Speaker 19:  I think what's a bigger deal about this camera though is there was a lot
Speaker 19:  of scarcity in the v hmm. And now they're producing this
Speaker 19:  camera in China as opposed to Japan, which some folks aren't stoked about,
Speaker 19:  but Fujifilm is promising that they will have more available to folks
Speaker 19:  and that's just good news for a lot of people who couldn't get their hands
Speaker 19:  on an X 100 V.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. How scarce was it? E everything got kind of weird during the pandemic
Speaker 1:  trying to buy stuff, but like how rare did the X 100
Speaker 1:  V actually become?
Speaker 18:  Yeah, I think like after the pandemic it was just like extremely hard to
Speaker 18:  get and like I wanted to get one and it just like never made
Speaker 18:  sense. Like the prices were just like insane. And
Speaker 18:  I think this was like one of the last few Fuji cameras
Speaker 18:  before they switched their factories. So I think like it was
Speaker 18:  the X 100 V and then like X PRO three. I think the X PRO
Speaker 18:  three was like the last one made in Japan and then they switched to China.
Speaker 18:  Probably did not help with just like trying to get those orders out. And
Speaker 18:  at one point Fuji was just like we, we we're not accept
Speaker 18:  accepting any more orders. So there's the other side of the argument that
Speaker 18:  just like a lot of people are like maybe not entirely happy with like the,
Speaker 18:  the improvements between the two models and are just kind of saying that
Speaker 18:  like, oh, Fuji is capitalizing on the popularity of this camera. They're
Speaker 18:  gonna do an iterative update for it and also raise the price
Speaker 18:  for it as well. Instead of making more of the X 100
Speaker 18:  vs. They're just gonna make more of the X 106 now.
Speaker 1:  Got it. Okay.
Speaker 18:  Which I think that's fair.
Speaker 19:  I don't think there's anything wrong with having small
Speaker 19:  updates to systems. It's funny, I was sent a review
Speaker 19:  of the X 100 T done nine years ago,
Speaker 19:  changed some names around and that review could be used for the X
Speaker 19:  106, but don don't think there's anything wrong with that. It's a good system.
Speaker 19:  It has a good, like what we would, you know, quote unquote call a retro
Speaker 19:  feel and that's a good thing. Don't fix it if it ain't broke. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  So, I. I do wonder though if part of the appeal of the X 100
Speaker 1:  V was that it became so rare and hard to
Speaker 1:  get and was such a cool kind of status symbol to be able to shoot
Speaker 1:  with and have in the background of your shots and whatever. Is this thing
Speaker 1:  if it floods the market and everybody who wants one can get one, is it gonna
Speaker 1:  be as cool and viral as the V was?
Speaker 19:  No.
Speaker 18:  Yeah, the answer is like, no, it's been a very
Speaker 18:  polarizing camera since, I don't know, like for like last
Speaker 18:  week. All I can see on threads and everywhere else is just like,
Speaker 18:  people have a lot of opinions about this camera and I think like its popularity
Speaker 18:  is making some quote unquote like real photographers kind of mad
Speaker 18:  'cause they feel like they're, the other ones are like, they don't know
Speaker 18:  what to do with the camera. What they have it, they, the whole idea behind
Speaker 18:  the X 100 is that it's like a very much like a proper
Speaker 18:  photographer's camera. It's the poor manica so to speak.
Speaker 18:  It's the one that's like, you know, you, you're kind of limited to these
Speaker 18:  like form factor of it. I think the general
Speaker 18:  kind of consensus and conversation around it is kind of switching a
Speaker 18:  little bit too, like a negative in a way.
Speaker 19:  Yeah. V sent me this, this great thread and it just says
Speaker 19:  you're gonna take the same shitty photos with the X 106 that you were taking
Speaker 19:  before you spent that $1,500 stay broke. King. Oof.
Speaker 19:  That's perfect.
Speaker 18:  I know it was pretty funny, but yeah, I feel like a lot of people have like
Speaker 18:  a lot of opinions about it, about like how to properly use this camera.
Speaker 18:  It, it's weird, it used to be like kind of like a, like a little bit of
Speaker 18:  a secret. Like it wasn't never as popular and it was just like, oh you can
Speaker 18:  get a lot of great stuff with this tiny camera and now it feels like, it's
Speaker 18:  like switches, like pendulum just kind of like swung in
Speaker 18:  the other direction and some people are kind of getting mad about it or
Speaker 18:  trying to justify their own purchases and I don't know, it's weird. It's
Speaker 18:  like, it's like cons Wars, but cameras
Speaker 1:  And if I've learned one thing about the photography community over the year,
Speaker 1:  it's that everybody is super chill about new ideas and new things
Speaker 1:  and everybody, nobody has like really strong entrenched opinions about the
Speaker 1:  right ways to do things and everybody's just very relaxed.
Speaker 18:  Yeah. It is fundamentally like a, a very objective
Speaker 18:  art form and yeah,
Speaker 19:  But okay, what there's like so many other products that are sold with like
Speaker 19:  the promise of greatness, right? Like I I, my mind goes to the Apple Watch
Speaker 19:  ultra. It's like people are gonna buy this and then they're gonna go hike
Speaker 19:  mountains and get lost and get saved and it's like no. So it's kind
Speaker 19:  of, you know, similar to that, which there's nothing wrong with that. We
Speaker 19:  all have ideas of who we wanna be and think that buying something
Speaker 19:  to make us that thing will, you know, I dunno make us feel better.
Speaker 18:  Are you calling it an aspirational product
Speaker 19:  For some? I, yeah, I am. So
Speaker 1:  Becca you've been, you've been shooting with it a little bit. You're gonna,
Speaker 1:  you're gonna make a, a video and do some stuff for us, but what's the, what's
Speaker 1:  the early returns on your time with it so far?
Speaker 19:  Yeah, I mean it's, it's beautiful to hold, it's very fun to use.
Speaker 19:  I love that about it. I don't think it's as turnkey
Speaker 19:  as everybody claims. The idea that anybody could
Speaker 19:  pick this up and just have great photos is, I mean simply not the
Speaker 19:  truth. Even knowing like what each film stock looks like and like
Speaker 19:  kind of honing in the look that you want to get from this camera
Speaker 19:  is not a walk in the park. So I've been thinking about it like I don't know
Speaker 19:  if I've just been watching too much HGTV, but I've been like tons of curb
Speaker 19:  appeal in this camera but it is not turnkey. That's
Speaker 1:  Very good. HGTV would be very proud of you. I thought you were gonna make
Speaker 1:  a whole like house flipping analogy but I like that even better. It's very
Speaker 19:  Good. Don't gimme, don't gimme props for that. I, it's, I am workshopping
Speaker 19:  it.
Speaker 1:  Vern, are you gonna buy one you you sold, did you have a five that you sold?
Speaker 18:  No, I only had the the third, the tea. Oh
Speaker 1:  Right, okay. So you had the tea, you sold it. Hoping for this one, is it
Speaker 1:  everything you hoped it would be?
Speaker 18:  Honestly like what Becca said earlier, like you can look at the old review
Speaker 18:  and it'll like a lot of things will just like transfer over. I think it
Speaker 18:  like it is very much like the form factor of it is fantastic. The
Speaker 18:  fact that it has this like new sensor, which I haven't used yet. It's been
Speaker 18:  in the XD five, it's been the Xh two wood
Speaker 18:  ibis and the 40 megapixel count. Very intrigued by
Speaker 18:  that. I've heard great things about just like how well it
Speaker 18:  maximizes the smaller sensors. Some people wanted it to be a full frame
Speaker 18:  camera and I completely understand that. I do think there's like,
Speaker 18:  you know Fuji's kind of like putting the eggs in the crop sensor and
Speaker 18:  the median format and they're skipping full frame entirely and with a
Speaker 18:  fixed lens there's like maybe one day they will make this thing a full
Speaker 18:  frame. I can see that happening because I don't know, I feel like you can
Speaker 18:  only get that much out of a smaller sensor but it looks like they are able
Speaker 18:  to get a lot out of it. People are raving about like how good the sensor
Speaker 18:  is. So I sold the tea. I was like you know, maybe I'll
Speaker 18:  buy this one. I have a confession. I did pre-order it
Speaker 18:  late last night. Oh like all day. I know I was waiting
Speaker 18:  to tell you Becca, but here we are. I'm doing it publicly in front of you
Speaker 18:  and everyone else. No I was, I had it in my basket for a while
Speaker 18:  and I was like, can I get it? And then I read a couple of reviews late
Speaker 18:  last night 'cause I was only able to like go through all the X 100 coverage
Speaker 18:  yesterday and I'm like, I just miss having that camera.
Speaker 18:  Like I just miss having an X 100 in my arsenal. Just
Speaker 18:  like a thing that I can bring everywhere and feel good about. Just like,
Speaker 18:  yeah I'm like, I don't know, not bringing like a massive camera but have
Speaker 18:  something that's like fundamentally like super fun to use.
Speaker 18:  So the pre-order is in, I've caved.
Speaker 1:  We always knew you were going to veen if it makes you feel any better. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I know there was never a question.
Speaker 19:  I mean truly I, I almost pre-ordered one as well, but
Speaker 19:  then I remembered that I can just put a pancake lens on my A seven C
Speaker 19:  and I know Lightroom well enough I could pop things into there. So,
Speaker 1:  But hey, if the answer is it looks kick ass and takes kick ass pictures and
Speaker 1:  it will make people follow me on TikTok and that's the reason people buy
Speaker 1:  cameras. I'll take it. I'll take anything we need. I'm into it. People
Speaker 19:  Pay a lot of money for clothing accessories and this is, this is one of
Speaker 19:  them at for some folks not for ruin.
Speaker 1:  Exactly. All right, thank you both so much for being here.
Speaker 1:  It's super fun as always.
Speaker 19:  Thank you.
Speaker 18:  Thank you.
Speaker 1:  Alright we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna do a question from
Speaker 1:  The Vergecast Hotline. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Let's get to The. Vergecast Hotline as always. The
Speaker 1:  number is 8 6 6 Verge one one or you can email Vergecast at The Verge dot
Speaker 1:  com. We love all your questions. We try to do at least one on the show every
Speaker 1:  week. This week we have a question about our right to repair segment from
Speaker 1:  last week, which will pour is here to help me answer Hi Will. Hello. We got
Speaker 1:  a bunch of good feedback on that episode. People liked it. People are super
Speaker 1:  interested in Right to repair. Love it. Everybody wants to break their own
Speaker 1:  batteries by themselves, don't
Speaker 25:  I? I don't wanna be responsible for that but but that's great.
Speaker 1:  But we got one question from a bunch of people I would say
Speaker 1:  as people are want to do, some people were very nice about it, some people
Speaker 1:  were very rude about it. Oh God. But we got this question over and over so
Speaker 1:  I'm gonna read an email from Mike that I would say is representative of a
Speaker 1:  bunch of the feedback we got. Mike says, one big thing you left outta the
Speaker 1:  parts pairing section of your right to repair discussion was the rise of
Speaker 1:  phone chop shops because things like activation lock and stolen device
Speaker 1:  protection prevent thieves from using or reselling iPhones whole. There's
Speaker 1:  now a burgeoning market of phone chop shops where much like their automotive
Speaker 1:  counterparts stolen phones are being disassembled and sold on as parts
Speaker 1:  serialization and parts pairing deters this since thieves can no longer use
Speaker 1:  or sell parts from stolen phones. I know this is something you also talked
Speaker 1:  to a bunch of people about, so I'm curious what your thoughts on that
Speaker 1:  piece of the parts pair argument are.
Speaker 25:  Yeah, so that listener mentioned activation locks,
Speaker 25:  which we didn't talk about because it is a completely different system from
Speaker 25:  Apple, but that is sort of the primary way that Apple prevents
Speaker 25:  stolen working phones from being wiped and resold.
Speaker 25:  So that's the system where your phone is tied to your iCloud
Speaker 25:  account and if someone steals it, that
Speaker 25:  motherboard is sort of forever locked to your account and without you,
Speaker 25:  there's nothing they can do to resell that working phone. So that is
Speaker 25:  a very important anti-fat mechanism for Apple that's different
Speaker 25:  from parts pairing and there's nothing to my
Speaker 25:  knowledge that prevents someone from stealing a phone
Speaker 25:  and chopping it up and selling all of the parts individually. you know,
Speaker 25:  one thing we didn't talk about a ton is that not all of the parts in an
Speaker 25:  iPhone are paired to the motherboard. Lots of them aren't.
Speaker 25:  So any of those parts would be super easy to take apart and sell and
Speaker 25:  activation locking doesn't prevent that in any way.
Speaker 25:  And even the paired parts are resellable, it's
Speaker 25:  annoying to reuse the paired parts from a stolen phone just like it's
Speaker 25:  annoying to reuse the paired parts from a non-ST stolen, a broken phone.
Speaker 25:  So that's, you know, that doesn't help or hurt the
Speaker 25:  anti-fat cause one way or the other.
Speaker 1:  Have you heard Apple try to make the security argument at all? you know,
Speaker 1:  you mentioned it's put out statements kind of both in favor of these
Speaker 1:  laws for right to repair, but also making what I would say are relatively
Speaker 1:  consistent arguments that not having parts pairing and allowing right to
Speaker 1:  repair is a security risk for lots of different reasons. I mean
Speaker 1:  like we talked about on the show, there's issues with the biometric stuff
Speaker 1:  and all that. Has Apple made the theft argument
Speaker 1:  at all that you've seen?
Speaker 25:  Not really, no. And they, you know, offered a kind of a rare public
Speaker 25:  testimony in Oregon that we talked about on last week's show. They ran down
Speaker 25:  all of the reasons why they're very attached to part pairing and like you
Speaker 25:  say, it's, it's safety, it's security around
Speaker 25:  keeping people from hacking your, your biometric sensors.
Speaker 25:  They didn't bring up theft one way or the other. When it comes to part
Speaker 25:  pairing, is it possible that Apple sees parts
Speaker 25:  pairing as part of their anti-fat strategy
Speaker 25:  broadly just because again, it, it makes parts more
Speaker 25:  annoying to work with outside of Apple's own repair ecosystem.
Speaker 25:  Sure. Maybe they see that as a knock on benefit but it's not something that
Speaker 25:  they talk about actively around parts pairing.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Yeah, it seems like one of those things where there might be something
Speaker 1:  to the idea that having these parts be digitally signed might help
Speaker 1:  you sort of trace things as they go wrong. Like it would help in an investigation
Speaker 1:  of stolen parts maybe more so than it would actually
Speaker 1:  deter people from selling the parts.
Speaker 25:  Yeah, again, it doesn't, you know, it doesn't really hamper the existence
Speaker 25:  of chop shops any more so than, again, prepared parts are
Speaker 25:  annoying to work with So I. you know, the one thing I will mention is
Speaker 25:  that that activation lock system is something that
Speaker 25:  repair shop owners are not super wild about and right to repair advocates
Speaker 25:  are not super wild about.
Speaker 1:  Oh, interesting. Why? Because
Speaker 25:  It means that, you know, abandoned phones or just
Speaker 25:  any, any kind of phone that is not stolen but you know has
Speaker 25:  doesn't have an owner anymore, it's sort of lost forever. The activation
Speaker 25:  locking is pretty bulletproof. So if someone brings a phone
Speaker 25:  into a repair shop and never comes back for it, there's not much that the
Speaker 25:  repair shop owner can do with that. Even if they've done all of their due
Speaker 25:  diligence to try to return that to the owner, that phone basically has to
Speaker 25:  be scrapped for parts or tossed. That
Speaker 1:  Always makes me think of like at The Verge obviously we get tons of review
Speaker 1:  units of gadgets and every once in a while somebody will, you know, put
Speaker 1:  their data on a phone or a tablet or a laptop or whatever, lock it with a
Speaker 1:  passcode and then leave The Verge. And so we have this
Speaker 1:  closet full of devices that literally no one can access. We can't access
Speaker 1:  them, we can't send them back to the company. To have some way in like this
Speaker 1:  stuff is permanently tied to someone's pin code that they
Speaker 1:  set up. you know, in a moment of just sort of randomly setting up a device
Speaker 1:  and you forget how, especially do you remember on old Android funds, you
Speaker 1:  had to draw the shape. Yeah, yeah, totally of the unlock If. you didn't have
Speaker 1:  one of those, that was the one you always did. I guarantee you
Speaker 1:  50% of the time you would forget what you did because you're constantly setting
Speaker 1:  up new funds, right? Which on the one hand huge security win on the other
Speaker 1:  hand, total disaster and So I can imagine that
Speaker 1:  being a problem for basically anyone. Like I have a drawer full of
Speaker 1:  smartphones because of what my life is and there's probably at least a handful
Speaker 1:  of them that neither I nor anyone else will ever get into ever again.
Speaker 25:  Well, clearly what we need is an a, a Verge chop shop. Like we,
Speaker 25:  we just need to start selling parts from all of the random gadgets that
Speaker 25:  we've accumulated.
Speaker 1:  Listen there, you just saved the media business right there at will. Poor,
Speaker 25:  Always happy to help.
Speaker 1:  All right, If, you wanna reach Will on all the right to repair stuff. You're
Speaker 1:  covering this basically for the rest of the year. I think this is like a
Speaker 1:  thing you're gonna be interested in and presumably forever, but definitely
Speaker 1:  for the rest of this year. 'cause we both feel like this is a big year.
Speaker 25:  This is why I don't, I never wanted to have a beat 'cause I wanted to just
Speaker 25:  do a story and move on with my life. But yes. Yeah, I'm the right to repair
Speaker 25:  guy forever.
Speaker 1:  I love this for you. How can the people reach you if they have other questions?
Speaker 25:  Will dot pour at The Verge dot com. POOR
Speaker 1:  Will thank you as always. Yeah,
Speaker 25:  Later.
Speaker 1:  All right, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everybody who
Speaker 1:  was on the show and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more
Speaker 1:  on everything we talked about the Fuji camera, Mia's flip story, all this
Speaker 1:  stuff about right to repair all of it at The Verge dot com. We'll put some
Speaker 1:  links in the show notes, which we're putting into full posts. Leave us comments,
Speaker 1:  tell us everything you wanna see. Read The Verge dot com. As always, If
Speaker 1:  you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or things you wanna see in
Speaker 1:  the X 107. You can always email us at Vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 1:  dot com or keep calling the Hotline 8 6 6 VERGE one one. Like I said, we
Speaker 1:  try to do at least one Hotline question every week and we're gonna probably
Speaker 1:  do a Hotline episode coming up in the very near future. So keep all your
Speaker 1:  questions coming. we love hearing from you. This show is produced by Angel
Speaker 1:  Marino, Liam James, and Wil Poor The. Vergecast is Verge production and part
Speaker 1:  of the Vox Media podcast network. NELI, Alex and I will be back on Friday
Speaker 1:  to talk about AI more Google naming weirdness,
Speaker 1:  MWC and a whole bunch more. We'll see you then. Rock and
Speaker 2:  Roll.
Speaker 2:  Hi. We're visible ringing in 2024 with a two years resolution to help you
Speaker 2:  save on wireless Get. one line with unlimited 5G data on Verizon's network.
Speaker 2:  Just $20 a month for 24 whole months with no annual contracts. That's 20
Speaker 2:  for 24 in 2024. Yep. We're pretty proud of that. Your gym
Speaker 2:  goals, you're on your own A, two years resolution To save on wireless. We've
Speaker 2:  got you. Switch and save at Visible dot com. Use code Visible 24 Hurry ends
Speaker 2:  January 31st. New members only promotional rate with service on the Visible.
Speaker 2:  Plan For additional terms and network management practices. See visible.com.