# Transcript
ID: 846b885a-8a60-40ba-b5a0-810909a56a29
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-3352600858404378115/-3896029659919305335/s93290-US-3751s-1731240289.mp3
Description: For the second episode in our three-part miniseries about the future of music, Charlie Harding, a music journalist and co-host of the Switched on Pop podcast, joins the show to tell the story of Auto-Tune. He walks us through how a simple plugin became such a recognizable sound in music, why both artists and fans gravitated to the Auto-Tune sound, and why Auto-Tune has continued to grow even through backlash in the music business. Then we look ahead to AI, and try to figure out what — if any — lessons we might be able to learn about the sound and culture of the AI era to come.
Speaker 1:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the Difference Between
Speaker 1:  Reverb and De Verb. I'm your friend David Pierce, and I have decided that
Speaker 1:  I am going to relearn how to play the guitar. So I have this guitar that
Speaker 1:  sits behind me on all of my meetings and all of my podcast recordings. And
Speaker 1:  so people are often like, oh, that's cool. Do you play guitar? What's your
Speaker 1:  favorite song? Do you know Time of Your Life by Green Day? Like all this
Speaker 1:  stuff? And the answer is, I don't really play. I used to, I played a lot
Speaker 1:  when I was a kid for a long time. I was actually pretty good at it. But then
Speaker 1:  I got to that point that you get to with a lot of things where my guitar
Speaker 1:  teacher was like, you either need to try harder and care about this more,
Speaker 1:  or just quit. And So I just quit. Bad choice in
Speaker 1:  retrospect, but like I was 12, whatcha gonna do. But now I have this
Speaker 1:  guitar and I've decided I'm gonna remember how to play it. So I got this
Speaker 1:  app musician that people really recommend, and I really like so far.
Speaker 1:  It just sits here on the iPad and it tells me what to play and it actually
Speaker 1:  uses the microphone to see if I'm playing it correctly and gives you
Speaker 1:  this sort of dynamic feedback as you go. It's not as good as having like
Speaker 1:  a person to teach me, but I can do it in my basement. So I'm calling it a
Speaker 1:  victory. So far I have learned basically that this is
Speaker 1:  a C chord
Speaker 1:  and not much else, but you know, it's progress. We're we're, we're doing
Speaker 1:  it one day at a time. Anyway, that is not what we're here to talk about.
Speaker 1:  This is the second episode in our miniseries all about the future of
Speaker 1:  music. Last week we talked to Jack Coy about Track Star and basically
Speaker 1:  music content and how we as fans discover new music and how
Speaker 1:  musicians discover new fans and be in the world.
Speaker 1:  This week we're talking about a technology that I think you could argue is
Speaker 1:  the single most important thing that has happened to music in the last two
Speaker 1:  decades. And that thing is autotune. We're talking to Charlie Harding,
Speaker 1:  who is a longtime Vergecast contributor and a friend of the show and also
Speaker 1:  the co-host of the excellent podcast, Switched on Pop. I'll link it in the
Speaker 1:  show notes. If, you don't listen to it. You should. It's excellent. He's
Speaker 1:  gonna tell us all about the history of autotune, how it changed music,
Speaker 1:  and maybe try to figure out with us if there's a way to take
Speaker 1:  what happened to Autotune over the last two decades and think ahead as we
Speaker 1:  get to AI and TikTok and all the other changes that are
Speaker 1:  happening to the music industry. What can we learn from what has happened
Speaker 1:  with Autotune that might give us a hint about where we're going
Speaker 1:  the next 25 years? All that is coming up in just a sec. We have a lot of
Speaker 1:  very fun songs to play. They are going to stick in your brain for months
Speaker 1:  and I'm very, very sorry about that, but it's gonna be worth it. It's gonna
Speaker 1:  be awesome. All that is coming up, but I just remembered how to play a de
Speaker 1:  chord and So. I'm gonna go do that a bunch of times and feel very good about
Speaker 1:  myself. I know two chords now. I'm basically a guitar player. This is The
Speaker 1:  Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  Welcome back. Alright, let's just get into it. So Charlie Harding, like I
Speaker 1:  said, is a music journalist. He's a professor of music. He's also the
Speaker 1:  co-host of Switched on Pop, one of my absolute favorite
Speaker 1:  deep wonky music podcasts. I really cannot recommend it enough.
Speaker 1:  He's been on this show with us before talking mostly about AI music.
Speaker 1:  We did a great episode with him last fall where we tried to make a song with
Speaker 1:  AI and it got weird and very fun. He was around for the whole laser
Speaker 1:  bong craziness. We talked a lot about ai, Drake with him. We've talked
Speaker 1:  a lot about AI with Charlie. Today we're gonna talk about something different
Speaker 1:  and that is autotune. But one of the reasons I wanted to have Charlie here
Speaker 1:  to do this is that I think there might be some similarities between the
Speaker 1:  story of Autotune and the story of ai. So in order to do that,
Speaker 1:  Charlie is going to show up here and he's going to tell us the story of
Speaker 1:  autotune, how it changed music, how it changed the world, and then we're
Speaker 1:  gonna try to figure out if there's anything we can learn about what comes
Speaker 1:  next. So here we go. Let's just get into it. Here's my conversation with
Speaker 1:  Charlie Harding. Charlie Harding, welcome back to the show.
Speaker 4:  Pleasure to be here.
Speaker 1:  It's been a minute. I, this is, this is very fun. I always like having a
Speaker 1:  reason to talk to you, and this time it's not about like weird AI videos
Speaker 1:  on YouTube. This is very exciting for us.
Speaker 4:  I imagine we will get to AI because that is the topic we
Speaker 1:  Will almost, that's every topic. Get to AI videos on YouTube. I just realized
Speaker 1:  that is where we are headed here at some point, but we're gonna take a minute
Speaker 1:  to get there. Yeah. So I. I wanna start like this, this
Speaker 1:  is sort of a, a like needlessly pedantic way to start this conversation,
Speaker 1:  but I, I've realized in prepping for this that when we talk
Speaker 1:  about autotune, we're kind of talking about a bunch of things,
Speaker 1:  but also one very specific thing. So before we get into
Speaker 1:  the whole story of autotune, like yeah, what, what is autotune, what do
Speaker 1:  people mean when they refer to autotune today in 2024?
Speaker 4:  I think there's two different definitions of autotune. The sort of formal
Speaker 4:  definition is that there's a company called ANS that made
Speaker 4:  a audio software tool called Autotune
Speaker 4:  that is used to help people adjust the pitch of their vocal
Speaker 4:  after they have recorded it. Or actually you can even record it live into
Speaker 4:  autotune today. That is also an effect. People use it, it's an audio processing
Speaker 4:  effect and it is also, second definition
Speaker 4:  basically becomes synonymous with any kind of pitch correction.
Speaker 4:  There are many companies that help us do pitch correction and so
Speaker 4:  when you say autotune, you could either mean this audio plugin or you could
Speaker 4:  mean any form of pitch manipulation and correction.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So autotune is like the, the Kleenex of the space. It is, it is both
Speaker 1:  a thing, but it's also the name everybody uses to refer to everything. Kind
Speaker 1:  of like it.
Speaker 4:  Yes, exactly.
Speaker 1:  Okay, got it. So let's go all the way back to the beginning here. You, you
Speaker 1:  mentioned Autotune, the product. Yes. Where did it come from?
Speaker 4:  There are so many things in audio that have come from the military industrial
Speaker 4:  complex aerospace, and in this case the oil
Speaker 4:  industry because Autotune was invented by
Speaker 4:  a guy named Andy Hildebrand, who was a geologist who worked
Speaker 4:  in oil and gas. And he used techniques like the
Speaker 4:  foyer transform analysis, which is used both in
Speaker 4:  geophysics and in audio processing. And he, he
Speaker 4:  helped find oil deposits using
Speaker 4:  wave seismology tools. I, I don't quite know the science of this stuff.
Speaker 4:  I'm a music journalist and he had this idea that
Speaker 4:  he wanted to pursue his passion in music. He was a flutist
Speaker 4:  and that is one who plays the flute, just to be clear. And, and
Speaker 4:  so he, he launched this software company in the nineties and built
Speaker 4:  a tool that used some of the math and science that he had used in
Speaker 4:  oil and gas to create a pitch correction tool. Somehow the
Speaker 4:  wave technology he used to identify oil fields also applied to
Speaker 4:  how we can better Tune our vocals. So thank you Oil and gas
Speaker 4:  for pitch correction. If there's any reason you didn't like autotune, I just
Speaker 4:  gave you another one.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, right. It's for, for better or for worse, I have to say no single part
Speaker 1:  of that answer was remotely close to what I expected. I love it. This is
Speaker 1:  great. So how, how does it go from
Speaker 1:  like Guy Makes Science Project to actually
Speaker 1:  being used? I think brief spoiler alert, we're gonna get
Speaker 1:  to share here very quickly, but yeah, of course. Is Cher the very, very beginning
Speaker 1:  of that story or was Autotune kind of around in the industry before
Speaker 1:  Share
Speaker 4:  Happened? It's very close to share the tool
Speaker 4:  Autotune launches in 1997
Speaker 4:  shares Believe,
Speaker 4:  Which is really the song where people start to recognize the effect
Speaker 4:  isn't until the fall of 1998. The idea
Speaker 4:  of autotune was that it would be a sort of subtle effect to
Speaker 4:  help slightly enhance a out of Tune vocal, not completely
Speaker 4:  out of Tune. Like you still had to sing pretty well in Tune, but it could
Speaker 4:  help sort of nudge the, the bad moments back into Tune. Hmm. And so there
Speaker 4:  certainly were some producers that were using it before Cher.
Speaker 4:  What Cher did is that she and her team took this
Speaker 4:  tool and kind of abused it. They set the settings so that
Speaker 4:  it pitch corrected as fast as it possibly could in such a way that
Speaker 4:  it created this, this very strange vocal effect
Speaker 4:  that they started calling the share effect. I do have to note though,
Speaker 4:  there is an important recording that came out before Cher's
Speaker 4:  belief that also had this over the top autotune
Speaker 4:  effect. And it's very unfortunate that it is
Speaker 4:  Kid Rock's only God knows why. Released a few months before Cher's
Speaker 4:  belief
Speaker 6:  Say Every man
Speaker 6:  like me.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's tough. We'll give it a Cher I think, I think it's right. The
Speaker 1:  Cher absolutely gets the credit
Speaker 4:  For that one. So, and, and, and, and the thing is, that song was released
Speaker 4:  as an album cut, not as a single, but after Cher is believed. They were like,
Speaker 4:  oh, that's stuff that's a cool sound and we already did it. So they later
Speaker 4:  released only God knows why as a single. And so it's often heard as
Speaker 4:  having occurred after shares belief. It was technically released beforehand.
Speaker 4:  So that's fair enough. We've got oil and gas, we've got Kid Rock.
Speaker 4:  We're, we're just, we're hitting all the marks right now.
Speaker 1:  Some tough bedfellows on The Vergecast today. Yeah, So
Speaker 1:  I. It's super interesting to me that it very, at the very beginning, like
Speaker 1:  months after this thing was launched for this ostensibly pretty
Speaker 1:  straightforward purpose.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Odine totally. It's
Speaker 1:  Already being used in these wild out there
Speaker 1:  surprising ways. Did it happen like that from the very beginning? Like was
Speaker 1:  it, it, it seems like it got crazy before it got
Speaker 1:  quiet in, in such a really interesting way with Autotune.
Speaker 4:  Well, the share effect was almost a one-off. Like some people
Speaker 4:  started to do similar-ish things. You can think of. Like
Speaker 4:  Madonna's music in 2000 has a sort of pitch
Speaker 4:  correction. He sound
Speaker 4:  DAF Punk's one more time in 2001 actually uses a
Speaker 4:  different pitch correction tool, but people start to mimic this effect
Speaker 4:  for sure. It's much more common that people are using
Speaker 4:  autotune the proper tool, this, this effect as like
Speaker 4:  really gentle pitch correction. And,
Speaker 4:  and so the share effect was kind of like, I think at first kind of a one-off
Speaker 4:  novelty.
Speaker 4:  People were using Autotune though. Like you can hear it very
Speaker 4:  audibly on a song like Maroon
Speaker 4:  Five's. She will be loved from 2002
Speaker 4:  where it was supposed to be subtly used, but there's something just like
Speaker 4:  a little bit wrong with the recording and people picked up on the fact that
Speaker 4:  like, I don't know, there's something about that vocal, which is slightly
Speaker 4:  inhuman. I can't identify it. 'cause it's not that like hard tuning
Speaker 4:  share effect. It's, it's the Auto-Tune tool, but kind
Speaker 4:  of overused. And people started to complain, oh, this is the
Speaker 4:  sign of the end of music. People aren't really singing. They're, they're
Speaker 4:  doing something after the fact too, you know, make it glossy and shey.
Speaker 1:  Fascinating. Was that the reaction to Cher even because she
Speaker 1:  was not trying to hide what was going on there? No,
Speaker 4:  No. Well, when you listen to the song, believe it
Speaker 4:  uses both a mix of tuning and
Speaker 4:  no tuning in the verse. She begins with
Speaker 4:  autotune on and she's sort of singing about, you know, trying to find love
Speaker 4:  after a broken heart. And there's this sort of feeling of
Speaker 4:  like this, you know, this robotic
Speaker 4:  just going through the motions kind of person and the, the vocal tuning
Speaker 4:  almost matches the, the presentation of, of
Speaker 4:  the lyric.
Speaker 4:  Then as she goes into the chorus, she sings, I believe in
Speaker 4:  Life After Love, she actually drops the auto Tune.
Speaker 4:  So it's actually this creative effect in which she's saying like,
Speaker 4:  I can feel robotic and like soulless and then I can sort of break through
Speaker 4:  and shares of course an amazing vocalist. And so she turns that effect on
Speaker 4:  and off to match the lyric of the song. When
Speaker 4:  it came out though, everyone's like, whoa, what is she doing? Not like, oh,
Speaker 4:  she's not singing, but that is a very strange and cool
Speaker 4:  effect. I wanna do that too. And Shera and her producers actually misled
Speaker 4:  people and didn't tell them what they did really because they wanted to have
Speaker 4:  this kind of cool proprietary sound that nobody else could mimic.
Speaker 1:  That's so interesting. And at that point, autotune, I guess was new enough
Speaker 1:  that we hadn't already sort of explored the edges of it in that
Speaker 1:  same way? Oh
Speaker 4:  Yeah, absolutely not. This was, this was, this was totally novel to people.
Speaker 4:  They'd never heard a thing quite like it, but there is a whole history of
Speaker 4:  other vocal processing techniques, tools like the Vocoder
Speaker 4:  or the Talk Box, and people probably assumed, and actually the producers
Speaker 4:  misled interviewers and said, oh yeah, it's just like a voc coating tool,
Speaker 4:  which is a, a a a tool that actually goes back to World War ii. It was
Speaker 4:  invented as a, a way of encoding and decoding
Speaker 4:  messages to be sent under sea so they wouldn't be caught by German u-boats.
Speaker 4:  I'm telling you. Wow. Audio is like all military industrial stuff.
Speaker 4:  We wouldn't have recorded music if it weren't for, you know, early sort of
Speaker 4:  military audio tools, but in any, in any case, they said that it was this
Speaker 4:  tool that had been around for, for decades and decades and decades so that
Speaker 4:  they could have their, you know, secret sauce.
Speaker 1:  That's so interesting. So real quick, just give me like the, the
Speaker 1:  technical explanation of how autotune actually works. Like you
Speaker 1:  mentioned it's, it's job ostensibly is to take
Speaker 1:  a pitch that you sing incorrectly and make it the correct
Speaker 1:  pitch. Yes, I understand that much. Yeah. How,
Speaker 1:  what else is useful to understand about how Autotune actually works
Speaker 1:  in order to understand how people use it?
Speaker 4:  Basically it's a tool that is trying to identify what pitch are
Speaker 4:  you attempting to sing, and then it does what you would call pitch
Speaker 4:  quantization, basically pushing the pitch that you are singing to the pitch
Speaker 4:  that you're trying to sing. And you can do this at different
Speaker 4:  speeds. So if I'm singing here, but I'm
Speaker 4:  trying to sing here,
Speaker 4:  it would go, it would sort of glide you to your pitch.
Speaker 4:  And when we think of the share effect or the autotune effect that
Speaker 4:  is turning that pitch speed all the way down to zero, meaning it
Speaker 4:  automatically, immediately jumps your voice from one pitch to another. And
Speaker 4:  when it does that, it creates this sort of digital artifacting that is
Speaker 4:  unnatural. It is strange, and it is now
Speaker 4:  very desirable. People like this sound and
Speaker 4:  intentionally bake it into how they sing because it is a fun,
Speaker 4:  creative effect.
Speaker 1:  Got it. Okay. But in, in theory, it really is just that simple of
Speaker 1:  like, you, you have a pitch and you have a pitch that you want and
Speaker 1:  Autotune makes those the same thing.
Speaker 4:  Yes. Okay. And you can say how, how fast does it do it? You can maybe add
Speaker 4:  some vibrato, there's all these little, you know, fine Tune parameters, but
Speaker 4:  basically fix my pitch. Okay. And you do this by sort of saying, I'm trying
Speaker 4:  to sing in this scale, and you set your scale
Speaker 4:  and then it just knows that, hey, you're singing way off your scale. Let,
Speaker 4:  let me, lemme fix that for you.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So in sort of that basic definition of it, I can actually
Speaker 1:  understand why Autotune, if it worked
Speaker 1:  at the beginning, and it sounds like it did, would be an immediate gigantic
Speaker 1:  hit. Right. And like it, from the way you describe it, it sounds like it
Speaker 1:  was like, you, you talk about Madonna, you talk about Maroon five, you talk
Speaker 1:  about like these are Yeah. A plus list artists who are using
Speaker 1:  autotune basically immediately did this thing just like come out and
Speaker 1:  take over the music industry.
Speaker 4:  I mean it definitely today is used on the majority of recordings. And I said,
Speaker 4:  when I say majority, I mean like over 90% of recordings. The only
Speaker 4:  recordings that won't use autotune are probably going to be, and I should
Speaker 4:  say use some kind of pitch correction. The only recordings that don't use
Speaker 4:  pitch correction would be like a very naturalistic rock song, maybe an
Speaker 4:  indie song. You certainly certain rappers who are not singing use it, but
Speaker 4:  the majority of, of any song vocals using autotune when it came out
Speaker 4:  the gate. Sure. I mean, anytime that somebody needed to post process fix
Speaker 4:  something that was outta Tune autotune was the tool to use. There have been
Speaker 4:  tools for Quantizing rhythm that had existed before
Speaker 4:  Autotune so that you could say, Hey, you meant to hit the snare here, but
Speaker 4:  you actually hit it a little bit late. Let's nudge it back over. And so producers
Speaker 4:  have always wanted to find ways to fix pi pitch
Speaker 4:  problems and, and they actually had really challenging slow ways
Speaker 4:  of fixing pitch all the way back into the seventies where you would go into
Speaker 4:  a piece of tape, there were digital processors you would send it to and you
Speaker 4:  could like nudge one little note a little bit. Oh wow. North or south of
Speaker 4:  where it's supposed to land. It was very slow and laborious. So
Speaker 4:  people have been always trying to perfect recordings that are slightly
Speaker 4:  imperfect to, to make them, you know, more Exactly. In key
Speaker 1:  So I. I just, I keep coming back to the share thing. Yeah. Because it's like,
Speaker 1:  I'm so fascinated by the idea of like a lot of what you just described are
Speaker 1:  sort of tools in a producer's toolkit, right? Yes. Like things
Speaker 1:  that in theory aren't sort of front and center in the
Speaker 1:  recording. They're just designed to like solve a set of problems that you
Speaker 1:  have. And I, I think there was clearly a lot
Speaker 1:  of that in how autotune is used and still is. And I think like to your point,
Speaker 1:  it not every song sounds like believe, but if every song has autotune, like
Speaker 1:  that's, it's being used in the way it's supposed to. Yeah. But also it
Speaker 1:  became an instrument in a very real way. Oh yeah. In a way
Speaker 1:  that most of these technological things don't.
Speaker 4:  Right. And that's thanks to T-Pain, right? So like it goes from being the
Speaker 4:  Cher Effect to becoming the T-Pain Effect T-Pain who like Cher
Speaker 4:  Great singer,
Speaker 1:  Which no one knew forever, by the way. My favorite thing about T-Pain, like
Speaker 1:  everybody knew Cher could sing before she did believe, but we spent like
Speaker 1:  a decade being like, oh, T-Pain can't sing and it's all because of auto T.
Speaker 4:  Right? Right. So Cher puts up believe in 1998, fast forward
Speaker 4:  to 2005 T Payne's I'm Sprung is one of the first time that people
Speaker 4:  hear this effect in the world of r and b.
Speaker 4:  And it goes from being the share effect to being the T-Pain effect. And pretty
Speaker 4:  quickly it becomes the sort of way that
Speaker 4:  people sing in particular, it gives rappers the capacity of sing.
Speaker 4:  And there are a number of early recordings, but the one
Speaker 4:  that really sort of lands it for folks is Kanye's eight oh Eights in
Speaker 4:  Heartbreak, the song Heartless in 2008.
Speaker 4:  All of a sudden Kanye who, you know, he's not a particularly strong singer,
Speaker 4:  has the capacity to hit a pitch and sing melodies.
Speaker 4:  Once that track is out the gate, every rapper
Speaker 4:  realizes that they have the opportunity to start embedding hooks
Speaker 4:  into their music. And you know, oftentimes it is the chorus hook that people
Speaker 4:  sing. And so I I I would say from
Speaker 4:  to T-Pain to Kanye and then everybody,
Speaker 4:  it, that's really, it's really in the sort of late
Speaker 4:  aughts that the Auto-Tune effect becomes
Speaker 4:  ubiquitous. It takes more than a decade from shares belief
Speaker 4:  before people start using it as in the same way they might use
Speaker 4:  distortion or reverb. It just becomes another tool in the
Speaker 4:  toolbox that people are using as this overblown effect,
Speaker 4:  not the gentle version of it.
Speaker 1:  Right. But I guess one key difference is that
Speaker 1:  at least to my knowledge, yeah, and you're, you're much more in this than
Speaker 1:  I am, but I don't remember there being a huge cultural backlash against
Speaker 1:  reverb. And yet there, there have been at least
Speaker 1:  a co, at least a couple that I can remember of sort of big
Speaker 1:  loud angry moments where the music industry or someone big in the
Speaker 1:  music industry said, you know, we have to get rid of autotune. It's
Speaker 1:  ruining everything. It is destroying this thing. We believe in. What, just
Speaker 1:  before we get into all it, make the case against autotune, like If, you were
Speaker 1:  put yourself in the position, you Charlie Harding, hate
Speaker 4:  Autotune and think it should be excised from the earth. Tell me why.
Speaker 4:  I guess
Speaker 4:  you could say that autotune
Speaker 4:  homogenizes the voice. I'm having trouble saying this 'cause I actually don't
Speaker 4:  believe it, but like, we're just gonna clip that part and just, just play
Speaker 4:  it. That's okay. Perfect. Yeah, like someone's unique
Speaker 4:  vocal identity is the way that they hit a pitch.
Speaker 4:  Not, not nobody sings perfectly in pitch. We all scoop into our notes.
Speaker 4:  We use vibrato differently and autotune sort of, you know,
Speaker 4:  carves out all of those imperfections. Part of what makes
Speaker 4:  us sound like ourselves makes us sound human. And so
Speaker 4:  you could say that, yeah, it's a homogenizing tool. You could also say that,
Speaker 4:  you know, prince Stars who don't have
Speaker 4:  proper vocal training and technique, but you know, that's
Speaker 4:  like the history of rock and roll are people who were not trained singers,
Speaker 4:  right. Who sing properly with all their air and you know, oh, but
Speaker 4:  like rather have personality to their voice and maybe intentionally don't
Speaker 4:  sing. Like Henry Rollins is a great example. Like the entire word of like
Speaker 4:  punk music is not about singing properly. So I think both of this, these
Speaker 4:  arguments of it homogenizes the voice and it allows people who don't sing
Speaker 4:  well to be stars are probably the, the primary
Speaker 4:  criticisms in the aughts after Kanye's record
Speaker 4:  as more and more people start to copy the sound. There were plenty of critics
Speaker 4:  who are just like, everyone's starting to sound the same. That's the age
Speaker 4:  old criticism of all popular music. Yeah. You know, everyone sounds the same.
Speaker 4:  There are still plenty of, you know, boomer YouTubers who like to talk about
Speaker 4:  how autotune is still ruining music. And the reality is that
Speaker 4:  autotune only becomes more popular after that era. Listeners want
Speaker 4:  more of it. It's not some cabal of music executives being like,
Speaker 4:  ha ha ha ha, we are going to give autotune to the people. But rather it's
Speaker 4:  like, clearly people are listening to this music and they want more of it.
Speaker 4:  The counter argument to autotune, homogenizing
Speaker 4:  voices is that like If, you listen to Drake's passion,
Speaker 4:  fruit
Speaker 9:  Passion
Speaker 9:  passive, you said
Speaker 4:  It does not sound like Charlie XC X is 360. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  360. When you're in, you see when you're mirror,
Speaker 10:  you're just looking at me everywhere. I'm so,
Speaker 4:  It does not sound like Travis Scott's sicko mode
Speaker 11:  Made this ice in Booth at the gate outside
Speaker 11:  when
Speaker 4:  Like, you can still identify who people are. And I I love that about
Speaker 4:  Autotune is that actually it's what you do with it that makes it your
Speaker 4:  own way of recording. I think about it kind of like, you know, when you,
Speaker 4:  when you pick up an old style phone, there's all kinds of ways that
Speaker 4:  the voice is being processed. All the low end information and the high end
Speaker 4:  information is being cut off and all of the dynamic
Speaker 4:  volume changes are also being squashed and compressed. And they're doing
Speaker 4:  that to save data on their, on networks. And yet, like, I
Speaker 4:  mean, If, you call me on the phone, I would immediately know it's your voice
Speaker 4:  and not Eli's voice. Right? Right. Like the ear
Speaker 4:  is so meltable to whatever effects that we use to change it.
Speaker 4:  I think that's awesome. So I think where Autotune goes from here
Speaker 4:  is that people learn to use this effect to
Speaker 4:  enhance their own creativity, their own artistry.
Speaker 4:  Artists like Drake start embedding really
Speaker 4:  great hooks in his raps because
Speaker 4:  he can now sing in ways that he couldn't otherwise. He's not a, you know,
Speaker 4:  he, he's not a great vocalist. He's a great rapper and he's a greatist.
Speaker 4:  But like, again, he is not trained to be a great vocalist. Right. Singer.
Speaker 4:  You know, we don't get Travis Scott without autotune. I you don't get Charlie
Speaker 4:  xx without Autotune. People end up using this Tune this this sound very creatively
Speaker 4:  and it explodes.
Speaker 1:  Okay. And do you think of it in, in your own
Speaker 1:  world and work as sort of spiritually different from any
Speaker 1:  other tool that in, in a, in a toolkit that a producer
Speaker 1:  or an artist has? Like is it, does it belong on the same level as reverb
Speaker 1:  and distortion or is it something else entirely?
Speaker 4:  I think about it as a producer and as an educator in music as just
Speaker 4:  another tool in the toolbox for sure. I think that a lot of
Speaker 4:  the backlash has to do with this question of like, what is human and what
Speaker 4:  is inhuman? The synthesizer had the same kind of backlash in its
Speaker 4:  development that, oh, it's not a real person playing a real instrument.
Speaker 4:  This is mechanical. It doesn't sound as expressive. I mean, clearly those
Speaker 4:  critics also lost the plot because the synthesizer is one of the predominant
Speaker 4:  sounds of popular music. I think about it as just a normal effect
Speaker 4:  that anybody can use and one that should be used
Speaker 4:  creatively to enhance the feeling of a song.
Speaker 1:  Okay. How has Autotune changed? It's what, 27 years old
Speaker 1:  now? Yeah. Is it, is it functionally still the same piece of software it
Speaker 1:  was in the nineties or has it? Sure,
Speaker 4:  Sure. There, there are many. Autotune is a
Speaker 4:  software developer, thus they need to constantly new things.
Speaker 4:  They gotta
Speaker 1:  Show quarterly growth, man. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You gotta keep buying the next version. So I think, I don't know, we're well
Speaker 4:  past Autotune XI can't remember what version we're on
Speaker 1:  Right now. Yeah. Their engagement metrics are off the charts. There's like
Speaker 1:  a social network in there somewhere.
Speaker 4:  Oh, they have, they have a subscription service. They've got everything.
Speaker 4:  The reality is that actually a lot of people still like the autotune effect
Speaker 4:  of yesteryear. And so If, you use autotune today
Speaker 4:  and you buy the latest version of it. You can turn on classic mode so you
Speaker 4:  can actually go back to how it used to sound. That's amazing. Autotune today
Speaker 4:  is much more naturalistic. It does a better job of tuning your vocal in
Speaker 4:  ways that are less obvious, but the effect, the autotune effect that people
Speaker 4:  love, whether it's with T-Pain or Cher or Kanye, whoever, what you like is
Speaker 4:  that hard tuning the thing which is inhuman and you like to, to
Speaker 4:  play with it. And so most people actually will just go back to the classic
Speaker 4:  mode.
Speaker 1:  Alright, I wanna talk about more about where we are right now with
Speaker 1:  Autotune But. first we gotta take a quick break. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Charlie Harding still here. Hi Charlie. Hello So.
Speaker 1:  I. Wanna talk about Autotune kind of right now, because I
Speaker 1:  think you, you've mentioned this a little bit a couple of times, but I think
Speaker 1:  the idea that the existence of Autotune has a changed
Speaker 1:  the kinds of music that people are like able to make who didn't
Speaker 1:  have certain kinds of skills or whatever before, but also the kinds of people
Speaker 1:  who might be coming into the music industry has changed. So, I. I'm
Speaker 1:  curious, If, you look at sort of the the sweep of like who is making music
Speaker 1:  and the music that they're making. Can you look at it as like autotune
Speaker 1:  changed all of this, the fact that autotune is everywhere and can make anyone
Speaker 1:  singing sound pretty good? Like has that changed
Speaker 1:  the entire music universe?
Speaker 4:  I kind of think about it more like the development of the electric guitar.
Speaker 4:  It was like a new instrument that people could pick up and it created this
Speaker 4:  new sound. And So I think produ young
Speaker 4:  producers today want to sound like autotune
Speaker 4:  just as in the sixties. They want it to sound like Hendrix. Right? Like
Speaker 4:  it's the sound that is attractive. And so yeah,
Speaker 4:  it does let anybody sing, but it only lets people sing if they can't sing
Speaker 4:  with the autotune effect. And that's probably the thing that they're going
Speaker 4:  for anyway.
Speaker 1:  It's slightly surprising by the way that that that sound has
Speaker 1:  been popular for this long, right? Like we're, we're, yeah, we're a long
Speaker 1:  way into this world and decades. Again, you go all the way
Speaker 1:  back to, to T-Pain in the early OTTs and share even before that
Speaker 1:  and like, yeah. The idea that people like the sound of autotune has lasted
Speaker 1:  a really long time.
Speaker 4:  That's why it's more like a guitar or a distortion effect.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's a feeling that it gives people, it's not about vocal tuning,
Speaker 4:  like this is, this is what gets people angry. They're like, ah, it makes
Speaker 4:  you inhuman. But no, no, no, no, no. It's like the electric guitar is also
Speaker 4:  unreal, right? Like it's generating electrical signals that has to be amplified
Speaker 4:  by an amplifier. It doesn't have all the acoustic properties of a beautiful
Speaker 4:  acoustic guitar, but it also sings and speaks in its own unique way. And
Speaker 4:  so that's how I think about it. And I think that young people wanting to
Speaker 4:  produce music want to sound like autotune. I mean,
Speaker 4:  truly when you record with autotune today, it's not a post-processing
Speaker 4:  technique. I mentioned it earlier, people put autotune on their vocal
Speaker 4:  from the get go, and they're trying to play with the effect to get it
Speaker 4:  to do this weird artifacting thing. This, they, they
Speaker 4:  like all the things that it does imprecisely. That's why
Speaker 4:  they use the classic mode. They want it to sound like this thing from 1998.
Speaker 4:  They don't want it to sound like a, a pristine, pure tool that allows
Speaker 4:  'em to sing better. It's not about that.
Speaker 1:  Interesting. So explain that to me a little bit because I think one, one
Speaker 1:  thing I've read a bunch is that one big shift was when
Speaker 1:  autotune went from a thing you did in post after you laid down
Speaker 1:  a vocal track, like a, it it was a, it was a post-processing tool to
Speaker 1:  now something that you do live in the beginning. Yes. And
Speaker 1:  there was a, there was a line in the, there's a really good pitchfork story
Speaker 1:  that you sent me about the history of autotune
Speaker 4:  Oh, by Simon Reynolds. Yeah. It's spectacular.
Speaker 1:  There's a line in there that's basically like, there are a lot of singers
Speaker 1:  who have never heard their takes without autotune. Oh yeah. That is like
Speaker 1:  just my, my brain exploded thinking about that. And so Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But you, you mentioned like thinking differently about the way that they're
Speaker 1:  actually making this stuff in real time because of autotune. Yeah. What does
Speaker 1:  that look like? Like what, what would it be like in the studio to record
Speaker 1:  in a, in a sort of immediately post autotune universe?
Speaker 4:  I mean, people do this not just in studios, but in home bedrooms. I mean,
Speaker 4:  the biggest stars in the world where intentionally travel to Hawaii to record
Speaker 4:  and record in an Airbnb, they bring a microphone, they bring a
Speaker 4:  portable, small recording interface. Oftentimes they'll use one
Speaker 4:  called the Universal Audio Apollo that allows you to
Speaker 4:  run autotune on this little interface live without any
Speaker 4:  sort of latency so that when you're speaking into your microphone, you just
Speaker 4:  hear yourself through autotune. And then they
Speaker 4:  are singing, trying to get it to do things that make weird
Speaker 4:  auto Tune sounds. I am bad at singing with autotune. Here's the thing, like
Speaker 4:  you actually have to be good at using the effect to make it sound right?
Speaker 4:  Mm. You have to intentionally sing slightly out of Tune to get it to sort
Speaker 4:  of bend back into Tune. You have to
Speaker 1:  So If you sing. Well, it actually, it doesn't get to do anything. So it doesn't
Speaker 1:  work.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's not gonna be interesting. Yeah. I, I don't, I don sing well, by
Speaker 4:  the way, I'm not a vocalist, but like, I am not good at using autotune to
Speaker 4:  make it sound fun and creative. You actually have to be talented at using
Speaker 4:  autotune and practice with it. So yeah, it's something you like, bake into
Speaker 4:  the sound before it even goes into your software. Like you can't turn
Speaker 4:  it off after the fact. Now, I mean, you, some people still do, but like,
Speaker 4:  a lot of people don't want to hear what their voice sounds like without it
Speaker 4:  on This is what I'm saying, where it's like, I think of it more like the
Speaker 4:  electric guitar because to play electric guitar with a lot of
Speaker 4:  distortion is fundamentally different than playing classical guitar.
Speaker 4:  And If, you ask a classical guitarist to play a super distorted electric
Speaker 4:  guitar, they might not be able to control all the feedback that it creates.
Speaker 4:  They might not be aware of how to get it to sing properly and vice
Speaker 4:  versa. You know, a like a fast lead guitarist, an electric guitar might
Speaker 4:  sound absolutely terrible on an acoustic guitar. It's a skill that you have
Speaker 4:  to learn to sing into autotune.
Speaker 1:  So you ac you actually think of singing into autotune and singing
Speaker 1:  without autotune as two just utterly different skills.
Speaker 4:  I think that they are related skills. Sure. But to make autotune sound
Speaker 4:  good, I think you gotta be good at it. Again, it doesn't necessarily mean
Speaker 4:  you have to, I'm not, I'm, I'm not arguing that you have to go to music school
Speaker 4:  to learn how to do this, but you have to practice at it. Like it takes time.
Speaker 4:  It's a skill that you have to develop as a musician. And when I do it, I
Speaker 4:  don't sound good. It is common that people will use autotune to
Speaker 4:  practice melodies and, you know, use it as a way of
Speaker 4:  dealing with the fact that they aren't good vocalists. But I, I, again, I
Speaker 4:  think that If, you wanna sound like T-Pain. You have to practice
Speaker 4:  singing like T-Pain. Yeah. Yeah. And again, T-Pain is a great vocalist. Cher
Speaker 4:  is a great vocalist.
Speaker 1:  They're just not doing the same thing as, you know, Frank Sinatra was decades
Speaker 1:  ago.
Speaker 4:  It's just, yeah. It's just a different way of singing. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I feel like there are gonna be some people who hate that, but I find that
Speaker 1:  kind of fascinating. I love
Speaker 4:  That. I think there are a lot of people that are not gonna like what I just
Speaker 4:  said, but I really believe it.
Speaker 1:  We'll put Charlie's email in the show notes. You could tell it yourself.
Speaker 4:  Thank you. I just, I mean, I just know this through practice of working
Speaker 4:  with musicians in studios and some people are really good
Speaker 4:  at using autotune and other people aren't.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. What, how does that pertain to live music? Is
Speaker 1:  it the same, is it the same sort of thing? Like as, as Autotune has gotten
Speaker 1:  more powerful, it's just present, live the same way it is in recordings and
Speaker 1:  it's fine. Once
Speaker 4:  Again, there are both ways of using Autotune live. Some
Speaker 4:  people need to have that effect on when they sing because like if you're
Speaker 4:  Travis Scott and you're performing live in concert, that is your sound. So
Speaker 4:  they developed, Ontario's developed an autotune live tool that
Speaker 4:  you can run, you know, through your microphone on a live stage. It's not
Speaker 4:  baked into the microphone. It's an effect down the, you know, audio chain
Speaker 4:  at some point. Sure. There is also Autotune Live used for
Speaker 4:  that subtle vocal tuning to help people, you know, when you're running around
Speaker 4:  on stage, it's exhausting. You might be outta breath, you're not hitting
Speaker 4:  your pitches as effectively. There's all kinds of ways that vocals are enhanced
Speaker 4:  to sound more like the original recording. You know, subtle auto tuning
Speaker 4:  is one version of that. Also, playing backing tracks of like a thousand
Speaker 4:  chorus vocals that are perfectly already in Tune is another way that things
Speaker 4:  sound more in Tune when you're at a live recording. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  So you, you sing the one, but there's 50 other yous singing it correctly
Speaker 1:  around you. Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Exactly.
Speaker 1:  I want that every time I sing. That sounds great.
Speaker 4:  I know, totally. It's like I always want my backing tracks. Yeah, that's
Speaker 4:  because people expect the recordings that they hear and when you listen to
Speaker 4:  your favorite artists, they're usually in the chorus singing at least
Speaker 4:  nine versions of the track to add depth with
Speaker 4:  Coing. Like the thing that just makes it sound big and awesome and, you
Speaker 4:  know, bringing eight extra backup singers on tour is expensive. So we might
Speaker 4:  just play the backing track and add a little tuning to your vocal 'cause
Speaker 4:  you're outta breath. Yeah. So those are all different ways that people use
Speaker 4:  autotune Live. Either the autotune effect or the sort of more subtle pitch
Speaker 4:  correction version of it.
Speaker 1:  What's the like simplest, most mainstream version of that
Speaker 1:  at this point? I think about the, the, maybe video is a good
Speaker 1:  metaphor, right? Where at the very high end you have super high end
Speaker 1:  video editing software, but we've boiled it all the way down to like, you
Speaker 1:  can edit pretty successfully inside of TikTok and it has made it available
Speaker 1:  to tons of people who are doing tons of different things. Do we have that
Speaker 1:  equivalent for autotune? Like is that just available to regular people
Speaker 1:  in the way that like Instagram filters are?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean there are iPhone apps that are like the autotune effect that
Speaker 4:  have been developed by the Gregory Brothers who famously made
Speaker 4:  autotune the news years ago.
Speaker 12:  We Looking, you, we, you, we find you
Speaker 4:  If, you buy Apple's Logic, which is their like audio
Speaker 4:  recording software. It comes with their own free version of pitch correction.
Speaker 4:  Every software developer that makes audio tools has tried to
Speaker 4:  make their own autotune effect and they are cheaper than the on
Speaker 4:  Tara's version. So there's all kinds of way of getting into autotune If.
Speaker 4:  you wanna try to autotune your vocals. It's very accessible.
Speaker 1:  Okay. And is that, is that a good thing? I feel like you, you would argue
Speaker 1:  that's a good thing. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I don't know. It's like, are you trying to argue that there should be like
Speaker 4:  fewer paint brushes and paints in the world so that we can have more Monets?
Speaker 4:  I don't like, I think more creative tools for more people is great.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I, I I support it. So I, there is one sort
Speaker 1:  of new backlash to Yeah. This that I, I'm, I've been thinking about
Speaker 1:  a lot and I'm, I'm curious to get your feedback on. So one thing I see on,
Speaker 1:  on TikTok and Instagram and everywhere else these days is like
Speaker 1:  these videos of singers in their kitchen
Speaker 1:  or in like a garage or just wandering down the street singing
Speaker 1:  these, these beautiful soulful melodies. Do you, do you know the ones
Speaker 1:  I'm talking about? There's this one that's like a guy with a salt and pepper
Speaker 1:  beard and he's just pouring coffee and his girlfriend is standing behind
Speaker 1:  him and he just starts singing into an AirPod. And it sounds incredible.
Speaker 1:  And I'm like, first of all, the, the way I know this isn't real is because
Speaker 1:  AirPods don't sound like that. Yeah. And you're lying. But like, all
Speaker 1:  that aside, there's been this really fascinating thing where a bunch of
Speaker 1:  singers have come up and gotten a lot of, a lot of fans
Speaker 1:  and a lot of fame and like record deals and some stuff out of these social
Speaker 1:  videos. It's, it's a very like, natural, you know, musician creator
Speaker 1:  way to come up. But then in every single one of their
Speaker 1:  videos there is this giant comment section saying,
Speaker 1:  oh, they're using autotune. I'd love to hear what it sounds like without
Speaker 1:  autotune. Ugh, it's autotune. And it's like, on the one hand,
Speaker 1:  maybe the argument is who cares? But on the other hand, it's like we're in
Speaker 1:  this moment where authenticity is everything. Yeah, totally. And totally.
Speaker 1:  Also you're standing in your kitchen singing. So the idea that I'm supposed
Speaker 1:  to process this like a professional recording Yeah. It, it, there's
Speaker 1:  a disconnect there that I have always struggled to wrap my head around how
Speaker 1:  I'm supposed to feel about this. And I, I'm curious, like if if they were
Speaker 1:  playing an electric guitar, I'd be able to see the electric guitar, right?
Speaker 1:  Sure. So, I'm, I'm curious how you think about How Auto Tune is supposed
Speaker 1:  to fit in that version of music that we're in right now.
Speaker 1:  Well,
Speaker 4:  I think autotune has become a sort of like catchall for any sound that is
Speaker 4:  post-processing that makes things sound more perfect than they are. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So for example, like if I'm singing in my kitchen, there's gonna be a bunch
Speaker 4:  of reverb and it's gonna sound really bad, but there's all kinds of tools
Speaker 4:  you can use to get rid of reverb after the fact. There are
Speaker 4:  ways that you can use just EQ and compression and other very common tools
Speaker 4:  and post-processing to make your, your voice sound better. So even if
Speaker 4:  I record with an iPhone, I can get my iPhone to sound
Speaker 4:  pretty close to a professional recording by having
Speaker 4:  good post-processing tools. I So I, think autotune has just been Yeah. As
Speaker 4:  the catchall enemy for anyone who doesn't like music, which
Speaker 4:  is slightly un naturalistic. I I just wanna say If, you
Speaker 4:  don't like the sound of autotune. That's fine. Like,
Speaker 4:  I think it's totally fine to have your taste If, you prefer House Sinatra
Speaker 4:  sings. That's cool. Like If, you prefer how
Speaker 4:  punk rockers sing. That's also fine. There are different aesthetics
Speaker 4:  and auto Tune is just one of them. It is the one that's really popular at
Speaker 4:  the moment.
Speaker 4:  If, you feel that? It's like, it sounds unnatural. I don't like unnatural.
Speaker 4:  That's fine. But it just, it's just is another way of, of singing.
Speaker 4:  And I think that this, this criticism is fair, is a bit
Speaker 4:  overblown.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I guess I agree to a large extent, but I do think there
Speaker 1:  is something that I've, I just can't sort out inside of me
Speaker 1:  that there's something about autotune that feels like hiding that, that it's
Speaker 1:  like if you're, if you're if, because I actually, I buy
Speaker 1:  the thesis that there are things that sound like autotune, but I, I
Speaker 1:  do think, and and maybe I'm wrong about this, that there
Speaker 1:  is still a, a real use of autotune that is not designed to be seen.
Speaker 1:  Right? Yes. Like if, if, if you're right, that 90 plus percentage of
Speaker 1:  music is using autotune in some way, like,
Speaker 1:  I don't know, Taylor Swift is, is not somebody people like, she sounds like
Speaker 1:  autotune, but she's using it and there are people who get really pissed about
Speaker 1:  that and Yeah. And because they're like, oh, it's dishonest in some way,
Speaker 1:  that this isn't actually what you sound like this is, this is you, this
Speaker 1:  is the equivalent of like putting a, a face filter on yourself before you
Speaker 1:  post a picture. Sure. Which is now another thing, people have sort of visceral
Speaker 1:  reactions to online Yeah. In this moment of like fake authenticity. And
Speaker 1:  I don't know, like do we need, is there like, is there like an Auto-Tune
Speaker 1:  watermark that should exist on every song that uses it? I don't know. Well,
Speaker 1:  okay, so,
Speaker 4:  So you're, you're getting at this question of like, authenticity just with
Speaker 4:  the pop star. Like we want something about us wants our pop star to be
Speaker 4:  sitting right next to us, our best friend telling their personal stories,
Speaker 4:  and yet we know that they're recording it in a professional studio working
Speaker 4:  with producers and songwriters to make this presentation, which is
Speaker 4:  exciting and, you know, enhances all of our emotions. So there's always this
Speaker 4:  conflict about what is real and unreal in recorded music. And I think especially
Speaker 4:  in pop music than other forms, we don't expect our actors to be themselves
Speaker 4:  in a film, and yet pop stars are putting on a performance,
Speaker 4:  and yet we have this expectation of they are who they say they are. You brought
Speaker 4:  up Taylor Swift, for example, and Taylor Swift uses all kinds of vocal processing
Speaker 4:  in her music on the song Delicate, she uses a vocoder
Speaker 4:  on the song Midnight Reign. She uses a tool called Formin Shifting where
Speaker 4:  she sort of shifts the voice to sound more masculine.
Speaker 4:  I don't like the moments in a Taylor Swift vocal where I can hear
Speaker 4:  Audible pitch correction done poorly. And I've heard it done
Speaker 4:  one or two times. Sometimes when you're producing a song and you need to
Speaker 4:  get it out fast for whatever reason. Getting these pitch tuning
Speaker 4:  tools to sound natural actually is, is a skill you can get paid
Speaker 4:  a good amount of money just to do the really slow version of
Speaker 4:  hand drawn autotune. Thi this is a big part of the craft
Speaker 4:  and what you're trying to do is make something which was a beautiful
Speaker 4:  emotional performance, be a little bit more in Tune
Speaker 4:  and If. you do it wrong. You hear this
Speaker 4:  like this weird artifact that's unpleasant. I, I
Speaker 4:  don't like when I hear that because it's the attempt of a naturalistic performance
Speaker 4:  clearly being manipulated. You have to hide the tools
Speaker 4:  you're using to clean things up in order for it to sound good. In the same
Speaker 4:  way that a photoshopped photo that is poorly done and you can see some kind
Speaker 4:  of weird, like the anatomy of the person isn't right. We don't like
Speaker 4:  that. Even though we completely accept that every single magazine photo is
Speaker 4:  photoshopped.
Speaker 1:  Interesting. So there's a, there's a real, as long as you don't make
Speaker 1:  me think about it, I can rock with it kind of thing. Yeah. But it's like,
Speaker 1:  as soon as you put this, you know, cognitive dissonance in front of my face,
Speaker 1:  it's gonna feel bad. Yeah. But otherwise I can sort of internalize that it's
Speaker 1:  happening. I just won't have to think about
Speaker 4:  It. It's the same thing with CGI, right? Yeah. So I just watched Alien Romulus
Speaker 4:  recently. Nice. And this CGI of the, of the
Speaker 4:  Android character is trying to recreate a deceased actor
Speaker 4:  and it doesn't work. It's, it's so obviously inhuman
Speaker 4:  and even though they're an Android, it's just like, it doesn't look right.
Speaker 4:  But the rest of Alien Romulus is like full of CGI and
Speaker 4:  at no point am I like, not alien just doesn't like, feel alien enough
Speaker 4:  to me. So I. It's, it's all about the context in, in this
Speaker 4:  presentation, anything which is supposed to be completely authentic ent
Speaker 4:  entirely natural that is processed, we will perceive as that doesn't feel
Speaker 4:  right. Yeah. Things that are presented as I am a pop star on a
Speaker 4:  stage and everything about me is like perfectly composed. We accept that
Speaker 4:  there is go, we, we, we not only accept, we expect that things are
Speaker 4:  going to have been enhanced. So I just wanna give everyone, everyone
Speaker 4:  permission to be mad at autotune at certain moments. But
Speaker 4:  when it's intentional, let go of it. Whatever. Like if someone's trying to
Speaker 4:  do it, let them do it. If someone's doing it poorly, fine criticize them.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I like it. Alright, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna come
Speaker 1:  back and talk about where we go from here. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Hello Charlie. We've gone long enough without talking
Speaker 1:  about AI videos on YouTube or some of the AI videos on YouTube.
Speaker 1:  So, I wanna I actually wanna talk about basically two different pieces of
Speaker 1:  where I think things might be headed from here. One is
Speaker 1:  AI and one is back to the kind of authenticity thing.
Speaker 1:  Let's talk about AI first. Yeah. And I, I bring this up because I think there
Speaker 1:  is a, a possible future for AI that looks
Speaker 1:  a lot like the arc of autotune that you just
Speaker 1:  described, where tool becomes available. Some people
Speaker 1:  use it like a tool and it's rendered mostly invisible. And it does, it
Speaker 1:  helps in the process and it becomes a tool in the toolkit. Other people will
Speaker 1:  use it incredibly aggressively and showy and it will allow new people
Speaker 1:  to do new kinds of things.
Speaker 1:  Ultimately, some people will be pissed off about it, but eventually it will
Speaker 1:  just be rolled into how the music industry works and may even
Speaker 1:  become like the dominant aesthetic in the way that autotune is.
Speaker 1:  Could be totally wrong, but I i, there there's something about that rhymes
Speaker 1:  to me with where AI might be headed. What do you make of that
Speaker 1:  comparison?
Speaker 4:  Well, we'd have to break AI down into all the various ways that it's being
Speaker 4:  used for music, because AI is just sort of like a process that can be used
Speaker 4:  in lots of different ways from writing lyrics to separating
Speaker 4:  stem recording. So you can separate the bass and drums and vocals and instruments
Speaker 4:  from a recording to generating whole songs for you from a prompt.
Speaker 4:  There's so many different ways that AI is being used, some of which are maybe
Speaker 4:  more invisible. For example, like If, you use chat GPT to help you find a
Speaker 4:  rhyme. There's no way that I can identify that you did that. Sure. Except
Speaker 4:  for this, sometimes chat GPT makes really bad rhymes. It's getting better
Speaker 4:  and better. It
Speaker 1:  Really likes to rhyme like do and two, and it's like, great job chat.
Speaker 4:  Thanks for that. Yeah. That's the thing. AI songs and poorly written songs
Speaker 4:  use too many perfect rhymes. They're kinda just overly sweet, really bad
Speaker 4:  single syllable, perfect rhymes. That's, that's the tell.
Speaker 4:  But I, I don't think we've seen a tool yet that
Speaker 4:  is marketed as an AI tool that has become a
Speaker 4:  predominant sound in, in popular music. There's all kinds of AI tools that
Speaker 4:  I use in my music production, but I don't think of them as ai. So like
Speaker 4:  I use a de verb plugin if there's too much reverberation in a recording and
Speaker 4:  like technically it's using a neural net, but it doesn't really have a sonic
Speaker 4:  fingerprint in the way that that autotune does. So I
Speaker 4:  imagine there will be some kind of effect that will use some
Speaker 4:  kind of ai neural net in its thing that will become a
Speaker 4:  sound. But the AI as a, as a
Speaker 4:  methodology is, is sort of too broad to say that, well, we're gonna hear
Speaker 4:  AI in the future. Does that make sense?
Speaker 1:  It does. And I think, I hadn't really thought about it like that until you
Speaker 1:  put it like that, but it is, it, maybe the strength and weakness of AI is
Speaker 1:  that it doesn't have a mark in its way. Like you can make Yeah.
Speaker 1:  An AI song that sounds like anything,
Speaker 1:  but it's never really gonna sound like itself in a, in a way that is,
Speaker 1:  I think by design, right? Like the, all these tools are meant not to
Speaker 1:  sound like themselves. They're all trying to mimic something else and they're
Speaker 1:  all generally doing a bad job of it. And that maybe it would be more interesting
Speaker 1:  if they had like If, you went and made a song with Suno that it sounded
Speaker 1:  like something and, and that maybe, maybe there is something to that that
Speaker 1:  is actually missing from these tools. So,
Speaker 4:  So you know how like If, you try to currently make an image
Speaker 4:  of a person in Dolly three or Midjourney, like,
Speaker 4:  it kind of has, there's a style, there's a default style and obviously there's
Speaker 4:  all kinds of way you can get around that style, but it's this weird
Speaker 4:  somewhat cartoony magazine. Glossy very thin.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like very white.
Speaker 1:  Well, and they're the things, right? Like you look at the fingers and you
Speaker 1:  look at the lapels and like they, they have their tells in that
Speaker 4:  Kind of way. They have tells. Yeah, exactly. And so, so right now If you
Speaker 4:  use tools like Suno or uio, they do have their tells and
Speaker 4:  perhaps, you know, in 20 years in the future, people are like, I wanna use
Speaker 4:  classic suno because I like the things that it does wrong. Wait,
Speaker 1:  What are those tells? Like how would you describe those?
Speaker 4:  Okay, so first of all, a lot of it's trained on actually really low
Speaker 4:  sample rate and bit rate MP threes just to like reduce
Speaker 4:  the size of the, of the data. And so there is this like
Speaker 4:  grainy hissy sound. Mm. Like it sounds, it sounds like a bad
Speaker 4:  MP three from 1997 being played in winamp. Awesome. Or
Speaker 4:  maybe, maybe like more relatable for folks would be like, If, you turn on
Speaker 4:  AM radio, AM radio has a sound where it's just like not quite high fidelity.
Speaker 4:  There's a low fidelity sound.
Speaker 4:  The, the, the sounds of instruments are
Speaker 4:  strange. Like, okay, take for example a horn section If, you try to make
Speaker 4:  a like a, a funk song with horns. The great thing about a
Speaker 4:  horn section is nobody hits the note at exactly the same
Speaker 4:  time at exactly the right pitch. The excitement is the subtle
Speaker 4:  differences of, you know, eight horns all trying to do
Speaker 4:  their thing at almost the exact same time. And that actually cr that inhuman
Speaker 4:  imperfection is what makes it sound really good. AI oftentimes
Speaker 4:  just like makes it all too perfect. Mm. Same with vocals. The vocals
Speaker 4:  sound actually pret tuned. And so you can identify
Speaker 4:  these things and in addition to the vocals are the, the lyrics are have way
Speaker 4:  too many perfect rhymes, et cetera, et cetera. I actually assigned my students
Speaker 4:  to NYU one of their assignments was go to suno,
Speaker 4:  prompt it to write a song. Grade that song based off of everything that you've
Speaker 4:  learned in class now write your own song from the same prompt. And all of
Speaker 4:  my freshman students wrote significantly better songs than,
Speaker 4:  oh, that's a great one than the UD and Suno song. And most of them threw
Speaker 4:  them out entirely. I asked them to try to incorporate elements of them into
Speaker 4:  their track and they're like, it's too hard, it's too bad. So, but
Speaker 4:  maybe this badness could be something that we, we like in the future.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And that comes back to the other thing I wanna talk about with this
Speaker 1:  authenticity thing. I think a, a theory that
Speaker 1:  I'm starting to hear more and more from people is that the next
Speaker 1:  phase of culture in so many ways is going to be a
Speaker 1:  spin all the way back to, again, whatever you want to think of as like, quote
Speaker 1:  unquote authentic stuff.
Speaker 4:  It's called punk rock.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's right. Like it. And, and we're going to, people are going to
Speaker 1:  deliberately start releasing vocals that sound
Speaker 1:  worse because they are more honest somehow. And yeah, we're gonna go back
Speaker 1:  to, you know, not using the internet in the ways that we've been using,
Speaker 1:  like this idea of just sort of ask, skewing all of this stuff because it
Speaker 1:  has made us not ourselves anymore. And going back to like,
Speaker 1:  I don't know, I'm gonna, I'm gonna just put a bunch of instruments in a room
Speaker 1:  and record like the Beatles 60 years ago. And that, that is the next
Speaker 1:  thing.
Speaker 4:  Who famously used the music studio for all of its wild creative tools and
Speaker 4:  use all kinds of post-processing vocal tools like Vera Speed and
Speaker 4:  et cetera. So I'm just saying we've always been doing this, but yes, I hear
Speaker 4:  where you're going
Speaker 1:  Again. Yeah. Again, the question of like, how far back do you have to go
Speaker 1:  to find something, quote unquote authentic is a good one.
Speaker 4:  We're all gonna play the mandolin guitar and, and
Speaker 4:  banjo and violin and, you know, sing in, in old timey bands, is what
Speaker 4:  you're saying.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And like if, if, if I sang flat on the take, it's gonna be flat
Speaker 1:  on the record. And I would say, historically speaking, there have been
Speaker 1:  a lot of people who want us to go that way. and we have never ever, ever
Speaker 1:  gone that way. But I do think there's a reasonable argument that
Speaker 1:  AI is like the end of a certain road of
Speaker 1:  inauthenticity that maybe we are due for a pushback the other
Speaker 4:  Way. I think that that's a completely acceptable expectation. Like we've
Speaker 4:  seen that trend many times in the history of popular music, in the rise
Speaker 4:  of electronic recording and the, the electric guitar,
Speaker 4:  louder sounds and rock and roll. You had the folk
Speaker 4:  resurgence after the super highly produced era of the
Speaker 4:  1980s. You had grunge as a pushback to that
Speaker 4:  So I think it's completely likely that we're gonna see new sounds and styles
Speaker 4:  emerging that do try to harken to our most human sound
Speaker 4:  as a pushback to anything that is, is ai. At the same
Speaker 4:  time, I wonder if we've already reached peak
Speaker 4:  authentic, because If, you go on TikTok today.
Speaker 4:  I feel like every other thing on TikTok is the TikTok shop
Speaker 4:  Yes. Is some sort of advertisement. And it's all filmed the exact same way.
Speaker 4:  It doesn't matter if it's a creator with 10 likes or if it's progressive
Speaker 4:  insurance, it's all like, Hey, I'm holding my phone, I'm back lit.
Speaker 4:  I'm just like talking naturally, just shooting the breeze, whatever. Oh,
Speaker 4:  and by the way, this is progressive insurance. And so it's already been co
Speaker 4:  that like the authentic human thing in video has
Speaker 4:  already been co-opted by advertisers. So where people go next, I
Speaker 4:  think it might be weird, it might be something like autotune that
Speaker 4:  is, is the effect of the, of, of the, of the next, you know, generation of
Speaker 4:  music.
Speaker 1:  Do you have any theory about what that might be in, in this world? Like
Speaker 1:  what are the, what are the teens doing that is gonna seem crazy to, to the
Speaker 1:  old folks in a couple of years?
Speaker 4:  They're still using a lot of autotune there. It's not going anywhere
Speaker 4:  right now. It seems like we have like a, i I
Speaker 4:  joked about everybody playing the mandolin and there does seem to be like
Speaker 4:  a lumineer style resurgence in the, the music of like, Noah Kahn
Speaker 4:  is a great example.
Speaker 15:  Sticks and
Speaker 15:  Mom, she forgot that I exist.
Speaker 1:  I was gonna say thank you. Stick season. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Ex exactly. So I. I don't, I don't think there is the
Speaker 4:  emergent thing yet. People are still having a lot of fun making
Speaker 4:  music on their computers because it's the easiest way to record
Speaker 4:  So I think we're seeing more a, like branching of many different kinds of
Speaker 4:  expression than a solidification around one sound. Mm.
Speaker 1:  Can I tell you my theory and I'm, I'm very curious. I wanna hear it If you
Speaker 1:  think of this, my theory is that the like voice
Speaker 1:  memo demo is going to become an actual
Speaker 1:  honest to god like genre of music.
Speaker 4:  Oh, interesting. Yeah. I think
Speaker 1:  That you see this all the time, right? Where like the, a song will come out
Speaker 1:  and then, like Charlie Po does this all the time. Yeah. Where he'll, he'll
Speaker 1:  go on TikTok or or whatever at some late night show and
Speaker 1:  play his demo of the song where he's just like
Speaker 1:  sort of inventing the melody in his head and trying to get it down into his
Speaker 1:  phone. Yeah. And that part of me is starting to wonder like, maybe we're
Speaker 1:  gonna get to the point where the, the polished thing in the unpolished thing
Speaker 1:  actually get to live next to each other. If, if instead of there just being
Speaker 1:  sort of one canonical finished version of the thing,
Speaker 1:  what we actually want is lots of different experiences of this same kind
Speaker 1:  of thing. Yeah. All the way down to just like the artist riffing
Speaker 1:  into their phone for a minute. And that that, like, we want to experience
Speaker 1:  all of that as fans.
Speaker 4:  The new Halsey record has multiple tracks that are exactly that Oh shit.
Speaker 4:  That are basically like voice memos and demos and things that are interspersed
Speaker 4:  and you know, that, that has a long history of like interlude tracks on hip
Speaker 4:  hop tracks that are kind of like, oh, this is a phone call. But
Speaker 4:  IIII like that. I mean, I wanna just point out one other trend that has popped
Speaker 4:  up as well as like the return to 1920s,
Speaker 4:  thirties jazz. Yeah. Or, or like what you might call classical pop
Speaker 4:  with the artists like ve who are making things that are things
Speaker 4:  a false nostalgia for music, which is a hundred years old and that young
Speaker 4:  people are into, so yeah, there's all kinds of routes.
Speaker 4:  I don't know if I really wanna hear a lot of people's voice memos though,
Speaker 1:  But
Speaker 1:  as we look at, you know, we're, we're 27 years into autotune,
Speaker 1:  which is a long time in Yeah. Music genre and in
Speaker 1:  pop music. Do you think If, you fast forward a while,
Speaker 1:  we will look back at this as kind of an autotune
Speaker 1:  era in the way that we've had sort of distinct eras in music and it'll,
Speaker 1:  it'll linger, but like the idea of autotune being kind of the dominant sound
Speaker 1:  of music will go away ly and we will be replaced by something else and this
Speaker 1:  will be the autotune moment. Or is this just gonna
Speaker 1:  be how music is forever?
Speaker 4:  What's amazing about all listeners, whether they're a trained musician or
Speaker 4:  not, is they can turn on a recording and often tell you, oh, that's like
Speaker 4:  an eighties thing and I don't like the eighties. Mm. And the reason why they
Speaker 4:  can do that is because snare drums were produced in a very specific way from
Speaker 4:  the 1980s. There's lots of other production techniques that sound 1980s.
Speaker 4:  And every era has these, these sonic artifacts of,
Speaker 4:  of their moment. And you can, and they place them in time in the same way
Speaker 4:  that a, you know, point and shoot Kodak photograph from the early two thousands
Speaker 4:  screams early two thousands. Yeah. You can even have AI generate things that
Speaker 4:  look like 0.0 shoot Kodak photographs, which are actually having a comeback.
Speaker 4:  I've been at birthday parties recently where people are handing these things
Speaker 4:  around to get that aesthetic. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  People are out here buying like cool pics. Cameras from 2003 again. Yep.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 4:  And So I think that, you know, 20 years in the future, it may
Speaker 4:  be that autotune is no longer the predominant sound. I think that's probably
Speaker 4:  likely. But when someone's like, but I wanna sound like, you know, 2008,
Speaker 4:  they're gonna use that again as a, you know, and as an act of sort of creative
Speaker 4:  nostalgia, So I think that we have been in the autotune decades,
Speaker 4:  we'll probably move beyond it, but in the same way that like the
Speaker 4:  electric guitar is not the most popular instrument today, but it's still
Speaker 4:  ubiquitous in recording. Right. I think that autotune will be around in
Speaker 4:  some kind of form and it might just sort of fade into the background and
Speaker 4:  pop forward later on. Who knows?
Speaker 1:  Okay. But right now we're still very much in the autotune era.
Speaker 4:  I mean, I think the coolest record of the year was Brat by Charlie
Speaker 4:  XCX and she admits that she has no
Speaker 4:  longer has the ability to sing without autotune because it's just
Speaker 4:  so part of her sound. She's like, I don't sound good to autotune anymore.
Speaker 4:  And that record is, is amazing. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. If, if, if Autotune is what it took for us to get brat, I'll take it.
Speaker 1:  We'll, we'll be all right.
Speaker 4:  Amen.
Speaker 1:  All right, Charlie, thank you so much as always. This was really fun.
Speaker 4:  Thanks.
Speaker 1:  All right, that's it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to Charlie again
Speaker 1:  for being here. And thank you as always for listening. There's more on everything
Speaker 1:  we talked about in the show notes. I highly recommend the
Speaker 1:  Pitchfork story on the history of autotune. There's a ton of good stuff in
Speaker 1:  there. I'll also link to Switched on Pop, so many great episodes of that
Speaker 1:  show that you should listen to. Truly cannot recommend it highly enough.
Speaker 1:  As always, If you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or other autotune
Speaker 1:  songs that belong in the cannon of autotune over the years.
Speaker 1:  Please tell me, you can always email us at vergecast at The Verge dot com
Speaker 1:  or call the hotline eight six six VERGE one one. we love hearing from you.
Speaker 1:  We have a bunch of fun hotline stuff coming up between now and the end of
Speaker 1:  the year. So get your questions in. This show is produced by Liam James
Speaker 1:  Wil Pour and Eric Gomez. The Vergecast is VERGE production and part of the
Speaker 1:  Vox Media Podcast network. We'll be back with your regularly scheduled programming
Speaker 1:  on Tuesday and Friday. Lots of news, lots of stuff going on,
Speaker 1:  lots of fun things to talk about. We'll see you then rock and roll
Speaker 1:  Off the top of your head. Yes. Give me a a, a intro to
Speaker 1:  autotune playlist. What are like for, for somebody who is like, I want to
Speaker 1:  experience autotune, what are some songs you would just recommend off the
Speaker 1:  top of your head?
Speaker 4:  Okay, well, I would first go to other vocal processing
Speaker 4:  techniques and you'd have to listen to like Kraft Fors, trans Europe
Speaker 4:  Express, using the Vocoder, you have to put harder, better, faster, stronger
Speaker 4:  from DAF Punk, not autotune technically you have to listen to some talk box,
Speaker 4:  like show me the Way by Peter Frampton Living on a Prayer by
Speaker 4:  Bon Jovi, California. Love by Tupac and Dre. And then,
Speaker 4:  you know, obviously you need to have Lollipop on there because
Speaker 4:  I mean, what, what, what is auto do without Lollipop?
Speaker 4:  You need what else has to go on there? Certainly
Speaker 4:  Travis Scott HIAs in the room, the entire album of Brat. But if
Speaker 4:  any one song, I'm more of a 3 6 5 than a 360.
Speaker 4:  So I'm gonna say 3, 6, 5. Okay. Drake's in my feelings
Speaker 4:  shares believe TPAs, I'm sprung and I'm not
Speaker 4:  gonna recommend Maroon five's. She'll be left.
Speaker 1:  You also left out blue by Eiffel 65, which I find personally outrageous.
Speaker 1:  But
Speaker 4:  No, that, that's because I mean that that is, I would have to have like a
Speaker 4:  consumer warning on that playlist. If, you put blue on there because it is,
Speaker 4:  it is a devilish earworm. But I did say little Wayne's lollipop So I.
Speaker 4:  You know
Speaker 1:  That's true.
Speaker 4:  Proceed with caution.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.