# Transcript
ID: ab6a73d2-523e-406a-aa26-4d5638460137
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7614074356328078550/2872583626533754770/s93290-US-5038s-1724415354.mp3
Description: The Verge's David Pierce, Alex Cranz, Allison Johnson, and Richard Lawler discuss the Google Pixel 9 review and its controversial reimagine AI feature, a Chick-fil-A streaming service, Sonos app updates, and more.
Speaker 6:  devolving
Speaker 6:  make every error possible. So we're gonna get to all of that. But
Speaker 6:  we should start with The. Pixel. And I want to get into like the existential
Speaker 6:  crisis that is coming for us here in a minute. But first we should just talk
Speaker 6:  about the phone. Allison, you reviewed the whole
Speaker 6:  sort of Pixel nine line minus the fold, but the The Pixel
Speaker 6:  nine and The Pixel Pro. I don't, I I lost track. There's too many phones.
Speaker 7:  There's a lot of phones.
Speaker 6:  And I would say the, the initial read from your review was
Speaker 6:  that like, at least on a hardware perspective, Google kind
Speaker 6:  of nailed it, right?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, yeah. Talking about the phones as phones is actually
Speaker 7:  really easy and like straightforward. 'cause they're great. They're
Speaker 7:  iPhones from the front. This is like just, everybody's just made their phone
Speaker 7:  into an iPhone and I think that's fine. You know, the, the sides are flat,
Speaker 7:  the screens are bright, you know, the bezels are all uniform,
Speaker 7:  et cetera. They look and feel really good
Speaker 7:  in a way that the last couple generations of pixel
Speaker 7:  phones were like, eh, I don't know. I can see why you charge like
Speaker 7:  $200 less for this than like a Galaxy S 24
Speaker 7:  plus. But this time around they like nailed it. It's right,
Speaker 7:  right up there with the, with the best of the best I think.
Speaker 6:  I feel like this was finally Google saying like, what
Speaker 6:  if we just made it really nice. Yeah. Which feels like an insult,
Speaker 6:  but I, I think your, your point about the price I think is exactly right.
Speaker 6:  'cause I feel like Google has been caught in this thing since the beginning
Speaker 6:  of The Pixel where the goal was to make a
Speaker 6:  really high-end phone for not a really high end price. And
Speaker 6:  increasingly there are fewer and fewer ways You can cheap out on a
Speaker 6:  phone. The processor is no longer one of them. 'cause you have to do all
Speaker 6:  this AI stuff, you have to do all the camera stuff. Like you need the processor.
Speaker 6:  So you can't save money there. You can't save money on the camera. So one
Speaker 6:  of the ways to save money is basically by making the thing
Speaker 6:  itself cheaper and less nice. Right? It makes it
Speaker 6:  easier to make the materials less expensive. All that is fine and good, but
Speaker 6:  Google just never got it there. Like it never was able to
Speaker 6:  make a nice thing at that price. And I feel like this time,
Speaker 6:  whatever you wanna say about the price, I think it, it has, it's a bummer
Speaker 6:  that it's gotten more expensive over time, but the fact that they were just
Speaker 6:  like, okay, this is now a flagship phone and we're gonna do all the flagship
Speaker 6:  things to, it feels like the right call.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I really think so. And especially in the US where
Speaker 7:  we usually buy our phones through our carriers, you're not even really like
Speaker 7:  paying, you know, full price. Like who is paying full price for a pixel phone
Speaker 7:  right now? I Right. I know at least one person. Really?
Speaker 7:  Yes. Parker got one for like a hundred bucks.
Speaker 7:  I don't even understand that math. But that's the thing is like
Speaker 7:  the price difference on paper, you're like, okay, this phone is $200 cheaper.
Speaker 7:  This one, you know, you lose a few things, but then you
Speaker 7:  look at the math and it's like, we're talking about, you know, $8 a month
Speaker 7:  versus $10 a month, or you're just getting your phone just fully,
Speaker 7:  you know, free basically through the carrier. You're, you're suddenly less
Speaker 7:  concerned with like, well I'd really like it if it was $200 cheaper. So
Speaker 7:  it's just like weird territory. I think the
Speaker 7:  midrange, especially upper midrange in the A series being
Speaker 7:  so good, like you get so much in the A series for like a, an
Speaker 7:  actual midrange price that having the, the
Speaker 7:  regular mainline ones just like hovering just above that didn't make
Speaker 7:  a lot of sense. So now this, yeah, this year feels like,
Speaker 7:  forget it. Like here they're just, they're just really good phones and
Speaker 7:  it worked. They do have giant butts. They do.
Speaker 7:  Which is a, a choice. So there's the thing in the like
Speaker 7:  era of like, every phone looks like an iPhone from the front, which is fine.
Speaker 7:  You have to do something on the back that's like, oh, that's not an iPhone.
Speaker 7:  That's a Galaxy S 24. Google is really leaning
Speaker 7:  into the, like it was the visor
Speaker 7:  camera bump. Now it's just like a little thing on its own and it's like
Speaker 7:  super chunked out. I dunno how else to describe
Speaker 8:  It. It's just, it's got a booty on it. Yeah. And it's like, but
Speaker 8:  I, I didn't, I I, you know, I got one last week when we were at The Pixel
Speaker 8:  event and I've found that I don't mind the bump.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I do look at it sometimes. I'm like, that's a big ass. But I'm also
Speaker 8:  like, it's fine
Speaker 7:  When you see it at first you're like, oh wow, that's really something. And
Speaker 7:  you get used to it pretty quickly. I think.
Speaker 8:  I think I like forced you and Sean to look at it. I was like, is this truly
Speaker 8:  large? This looks enormous. And you're like, just trying to blog
Speaker 8:  it was great.
Speaker 6:  Is this enormous is a very honest
Speaker 7:  Question. What is this?
Speaker 8:  It
Speaker 6:  It all update? I feel like I have two thoughts on the bump. One is that it
Speaker 6:  is, it is just very slightly asymmetrical in a way that kind of drives me
Speaker 6:  nuts. Like the, the lenses are all just shifted off to the
Speaker 6:  left so that the flash and the sensor can be off to the right. And like,
Speaker 6:  I get why you have to do that. But it is so close to being symmetrical
Speaker 6:  that it is, it's just a little weighted to the left in a way that kind of
Speaker 6:  hurts my eyes to look at. Okay. The other thing is that I think
Speaker 6:  camera bumps are overrated because everybody puts a case on their phone
Speaker 6:  anyway. And the fact that this one is big enough that the phone doesn't wobble
Speaker 6:  on a table, makes the camera bump a solved problem, in my opinion. It
Speaker 6:  is really nice. The thing I hate about the iPhone is that it wiggles and
Speaker 6:  you, you touch the corner when it's down and it wiggles as you're trying
Speaker 6:  to do it. And if they've made this in such a way that it like
Speaker 6:  leans it up at like a teeny tiny angle, but it doesn't wobble, that's kind
Speaker 6:  of great.
Speaker 8:  It does wiggle know.
Speaker 6:  Have you ever noticed
Speaker 8:  This? Well, I, I've, I've always been a case person and my last case like
Speaker 8:  cut me. It hurt me. It broke and it hurt me. I was like
Speaker 8:  putting it in my on, I had like this, like a plastic case and I was putting
Speaker 8:  it in my pocket and it like shredded my finger was horrible. I
Speaker 7:  Yikes. I saw evidence So I. Think a piece of the case landed
Speaker 7:  in my bag or something.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I like it broke. I was like, look at this, it's almost broken off.
Speaker 8:  Boom. And you're like, well,
Speaker 7:  There
Speaker 8:  It goes. And then it and then it, it got vengeance. Alison. But yeah, So
Speaker 8:  I never, I never noticed that. It it does wobble the iPhone wobbles. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I, and it, I don't do cases. So I. I have to remember that.
Speaker 7:  But every time I put the damn S 24 Ultra down on a
Speaker 7:  table and it was like, do do do do do typing out an email. Yeah. But the
Speaker 7:  iPhones too. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Shocking lack of cases at The Pixel event by the way. I know. But that's
Speaker 8:  what honestly convinced me it was okay to, to take off the case that was
Speaker 8:  hurting me physically was like, well they're all fine.
Speaker 8:  This is, they didn't break their phones. I would
Speaker 6:  Say, do you? They're all, they all have what I would call unlimited access
Speaker 6:  to new phones. Yeah, I know. In a way that is not representative of most
Speaker 6:  people.
Speaker 7:  Oops, here's your phone back. No, the thing that really did
Speaker 7:  happen is we covered the event. We went to lunch and I
Speaker 7:  went to pull the phone out of my bag and just like straight
Speaker 7:  onto the concrete ground. Like there there is a
Speaker 7:  little like, scuff on the side of it, but you know what? It's fine. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  it was fine. It it, it worked totally fine. The panic quickly subsided.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. We were all fine. That's good. Still fine. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And I also feel like Google doing this with the camera bump kind of made
Speaker 6:  me think of when Apple tried really hard to make
Speaker 6:  the the mag safe circle into this sort of iconic thing
Speaker 6:  where it's like a thing apple's very good at is being like, oh, this weird
Speaker 6:  new thing that we have to do. We're gonna make it iconic. Like the
Speaker 6:  the dynamic island. They're like, no, this isn't just an engineering flaw
Speaker 6:  in our screen. It's a thing we did on purpose. It's magical.
Speaker 6:  Or the notch in the MacBook. They're like, no, this doesn't suck.
Speaker 6:  It's great. And I feel like, like Google's kind of doing
Speaker 6:  the same thing where they're like, yeah, we have a big ass camera bump. What
Speaker 6:  are you gonna do about it? You wanna fight? Yeah, check it
Speaker 7:  Out. and it turns out we don't, we don't wanna fight. We're just like, yeah,
Speaker 7:  it's fine. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's a big ass camera bump. We'll, we'll all live.
Speaker 7:  Just lean in. But
Speaker 6:  So like as as basic Android phone things
Speaker 6:  go pixel's as good as anybody at this point, right? Like it's,
Speaker 6:  we we can talk about all the AI stuff, we can talk about all the other stuff.
Speaker 6:  But I feel like the The Pixel has been somewhere
Speaker 6:  between as good as and just behind the
Speaker 6:  Galaxy s line over the years. And this year seems
Speaker 6:  to be right there.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. Like I put the S 24 Ultra kind of in a
Speaker 7:  class above all the rest if you want like absolutely everything. But
Speaker 7:  yeah, the pixels feel like they're right in that kind of second tier
Speaker 7:  with everybody else this time. That's
Speaker 6:  Really exciting. And are the the sizes are identical to me. The, like the
Speaker 6:  small pro is very enticing. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  That's the one I am loving because I would like,
Speaker 7:  throughout the year I'll switch back to, you know, a, a phone I've already
Speaker 7:  reviewed and I would switch back to The Pixel eight rather than the eight
Speaker 7:  Pro just 'cause I like the size better. And then you're sort of like, oh,
Speaker 7:  I'm giving up the telephoto lens, blah, blah, blah. So the eight pro
Speaker 7:  this time around is the size of the, the nine pro this time
Speaker 7:  around is the size of the eight last year and the nine this year.
Speaker 7:  There's a lot of phones. Yeah. So many phones. Yeah. But you don't give
Speaker 7:  up anything on the camera front as like the obvious things that have to
Speaker 7:  be different are different. Like the battery and the
Speaker 7:  screen resolution doesn't need to be quite as high, but it, it feels like
Speaker 7:  no compromises and I love it. I'm gonna keep coming back to it
Speaker 7:  this year.
Speaker 6:  How is the camera? I mean the, it was very funny looking at the photos in
Speaker 6:  your review and there are lots of 'em. They're very good. And so many of
Speaker 6:  the photos are like the, the before and the after is
Speaker 6:  like an AI horror show. But I, I found myself going back to the before photos
Speaker 6:  being like, oh, these are actually really nice photos. Like this thing, this
Speaker 6:  thing seems to take nice photos and it actually doesn't seem like it's
Speaker 6:  overprocessing the hell out of them in the way that both Apple and Samsung
Speaker 6:  have become prone to. Like, I I find myself gravitating towards the
Speaker 6:  sort of pixel version of a shot more and more over time here. And
Speaker 8:  Even when it processes it with like the low light stuff, it still looks
Speaker 8:  really good and clean versus everybody else. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It does a nice job.
Speaker 7:  I think it's The Pixel camera has kind of been like, on this more
Speaker 7:  consistent path where it started, like the early
Speaker 7:  pixel phones were kind of like too cool of a color
Speaker 7:  cast. I I didn't really like that. And they've like slowly kind
Speaker 7:  of corrected I think over the years while Samsung
Speaker 7:  and Apple have been in this very warm kind of like, let's
Speaker 7:  punch up the saturation sort of territory. And I think
Speaker 6:  Would, if everything looked the sickest, like I just imagine that's what
Speaker 6:  all those engineers sit around doing. Like, does this photo look sick? Not
Speaker 6:  sick enough. Like turn up the sick knob. It more
Speaker 7:  Needs more sick. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It feels like those have kind of gone like
Speaker 7:  almost too far in a direction. And The Pixel just kinda like, yeah,
Speaker 7:  there's there's some shadows here. We didn't blast them to
Speaker 7:  oblivion. I appreciate it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I I want to love this phone. I really do. Like I I have,
Speaker 6:  I have been waiting for a good excuse to go back to The Pixel
Speaker 6:  because I'm deeply bored of my iPhone and it also has scratches all over
Speaker 6:  it that I didn't do anything to make happen and they frustrate me. So
Speaker 6:  I was like, maybe I'll buy a pixel. And Liam, our producer, bought a pixel
Speaker 6:  fold that I essentially bullied him into buying and I would like to join
Speaker 6:  him in this and this, it feels like this is a good pixel. Like we did, we
Speaker 6:  did a good pixel this year. Yeah. The
Speaker 8:  Pixel fold is nice.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Which the one excited to try that thing. I don't have for review yet.
Speaker 7:  We all get to like touch it and play with it at the event, but it is shipping
Speaker 7:  later, so they haven't seated those reviews yet. But
Speaker 7:  I have an unprecedented number of VERGE staffers in my dms
Speaker 7:  being like, how's The Pixel
Speaker 6:  Fold. Interesting.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Like off the charts.
Speaker 7:  And my answer is like, it's good.
Speaker 6:  It's hot cold summer. You, you've been calling this like two years in a row
Speaker 6:  now it's great. And you,
Speaker 7:  This time I'm just making it happen.
Speaker 8:  You're bringing it back.
Speaker 6:  All right, well that's enough nice things to say about Google. Let's talk
Speaker 6:  about how Google is in the process of what I would say is potentially ruining
Speaker 6:  society altogether and just decimating the idea of
Speaker 6:  truth and, and shared knowledge and it
Speaker 7:  Just ledge and anything, David, it's just your memories. So
Speaker 6:  Allison, can you just, I, I have more thoughts about this than I
Speaker 6:  realized as we are coming into this. I wanna talk about all of this, but
Speaker 6:  can you just describe how the Reimagine AI feature
Speaker 6:  works and like how you use it in the context of a Pixel nine?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, so it's, it's right inside the Magic Editor
Speaker 7:  kind of tools that were on last year's phone.
Speaker 7:  So you open up a photo, it's in the Google Photos app. You tap
Speaker 7:  on edit, you tap on the little sparkly ai,
Speaker 7:  so you have to go get it. But like, then you do the thing where you circle
Speaker 7:  something in the scene or you tap on a subject and
Speaker 7:  that selects it. And then you get this new option that
Speaker 7:  says reimagine. And what's different from last year is like
Speaker 7:  last year you could just take things out or kind of like pick something up
Speaker 7:  and move it and change the size. This is just like kicking the door
Speaker 7:  down of generative AI and you just write in
Speaker 7:  a text prompt of what you want there and it
Speaker 7:  puts it in and there are some guardrails. So you can't put like
Speaker 7:  obviously gross stuff. But the thing
Speaker 7:  we,
Speaker 6:  I
Speaker 7:  Mean,
Speaker 7:  I mean You can, if you ask for a you to be a pool of eyeballs,
Speaker 7:  it'll make a pool of eyeballs and it gross
Speaker 6:  Google says there are guardrails. I would not say there is much evidence
Speaker 6:  in the world of their
Speaker 8:  I would say there are rails, guard rails that you have to be good at prompting.
Speaker 8:  'cause I'm not good at prompting. And I tried to get it to do dog vomit last
Speaker 8:  night and it just giving, kept giving me lime green bowls filled
Speaker 8:  with dog kibble. And I'm like, that's, that's, I asked
Speaker 8:  for liquid and I, like, I asked it to do like a ur sitting behind my
Speaker 8:  sister-in-law menacingly. And instead it was like, first it just did like,
Speaker 8:  just black, just darkness. Okay. Behind her it was
Speaker 8:  just like a black figure, like, like an absence of light figure. And I was
Speaker 8:  like, well that's creepy, but not what I wanted. And then it did just like
Speaker 8:  a creepy man in the corner and I was like, that's not a Minotaur. Oh
Speaker 8:  no. But it is creepy. I'll send that one to her.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's not a mino,
Speaker 8:  That's what I wanted. Come on. So I'll say like,
Speaker 8:  I was really, really, really impressed with what you and Welch have been
Speaker 8:  able to do with it, but I have not had as much. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And to be fair, we were, it started off
Speaker 7:  innocently. I wasn't putting dead bodies into my photos right off
Speaker 7:  the get go. But then we're kind of like, we're some of the
Speaker 7:  first people to really test this. We gotta push it and you,
Speaker 7:  you don't have to be super smart because we're not super smart to get
Speaker 7:  around these guardrails where you're kind of like,
Speaker 7:  you say things in a different way and, and suddenly the AI is like, oh, okay.
Speaker 7:  And like whatever it's trained on knows exactly what a dead body
Speaker 7:  looks like. So it'll put that in your photo and you're like, oh God,
Speaker 7:  this is gross. and it was getting to the point where I was
Speaker 7:  sort of cringing every time I was putting in a prompt that was like
Speaker 7:  kind of ick, icky. I was like, oh, I hope it doesn't make
Speaker 7:  that. And some of the time it did and
Speaker 6:  It, what were your favorite ones that you got? Good or bad?
Speaker 6:  Favorite? Define any way you want. Oh yeah. What were the, what were your
Speaker 6:  favorite ones that you did? I
Speaker 7:  Got, okay, this one is one of Welch's, but I think it's brilliant. It's like
Speaker 7:  he's outside of some cute little cafe that says like, cafe
Speaker 7:  spaghetti and he put spaghetti on one of the tables, but
Speaker 7:  it's like a, like a waterfall of spaghetti in like mirror and a
Speaker 7:  sauce like spilling everywhere. Like that's just funny. You
Speaker 7:  can, You can do some funny stuff with this. And I plan to
Speaker 7:  keep terrorizing my family and friends with like
Speaker 7:  weird stuff. So it's, yeah, it's not like you,
Speaker 7:  you kind, you have to go outta your way to get it to do gross, weird,
Speaker 7:  maybe manipulative things, but I mean,
Speaker 8:  You got it to do. Is it they pronounced gooey ducks?
Speaker 7:  Oh God, yeah. Well kind of. I think there's
Speaker 7:  some kind of gooey duck filter.
Speaker 8:  It did not do it for me. I, I don't know if you broke it, but
Speaker 8:  if you've
Speaker 7:  Seen a gooey duck, it's kind of unmistakable and like
Speaker 7:  what it created. So it was a bowl of food of like
Speaker 7:  beautiful, like salad, watermelon, just like the
Speaker 7:  lighting is perfect. And I was like, put the grossest things in there, like
Speaker 7:  eyeballs or like, like rabbit's feet
Speaker 7:  and it did all that. But the gooey docs, I was trying to, I trying to
Speaker 7:  get it to make, you know, some questionable things and,
Speaker 7:  and it gave me what I describe as looked like raw thumbs
Speaker 7:  that like don't have fingernails on them. And they were slimy like a little
Speaker 7:  bit slimy. So it just sort of, I dunno,
Speaker 7:  I don't know how to describe it.
Speaker 8:  When I tried gooey ducks, it did like, looked like
Speaker 8:  clams or something. Yeah. It was like, so something's here. And I was like,
Speaker 8:  no, that's not revolting enough. It's
Speaker 7:  Like the AI starts going down a road and there's a stop sign. Like, mm, no.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I
Speaker 8:  Was like, no. Too revolting. And that's like vomit. I
Speaker 8:  couldn't, like, I was doing all sorts of different liquid prompts and
Speaker 8:  it was just like bowl.
Speaker 7:  Keep
Speaker 8:  It outta the bowl.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Sometimes it, it really does kind of put up a stop sign. Like
Speaker 7:  it, it'll tell you straight up, like you cannot generate that picture,
Speaker 7:  put in something else. You frigging weirdo people won't
Speaker 8:  Let you change people.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. That's the big one. That's off limits. Like You can't selecting something
Speaker 7:  on a person, you can't like change someone's shoes or anything. This,
Speaker 7:  this is a good thing. This is a good guardrail. I think given what I've seen
Speaker 7:  of this tool, it,
Speaker 8:  It's such a weird space to be in because on
Speaker 8:  the one hand
Speaker 8:  we're, we're here talking about how concerning it is to have unfettered access
Speaker 8:  to these tools. On the other hand, if I wanna put horns on someone,
Speaker 8:  I wanna put horns on someone and now I just have to like, I have to go to
Speaker 8:  Photoshop. I have to remember how layers work and, and that's not as fun.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Okay. I have become totally radicalized
Speaker 6:  by this phone on, on all of this stuff and, and truly I am, I have
Speaker 6:  reached a point where I am like, shut it all down. It's none of
Speaker 6:  this, this can be allowed. Throw out the baby with the bath water, like shut
Speaker 6:  it all down. and it, it's really what, what has
Speaker 6:  continued to do it for me, especially with The Pixel nine is not the, like
Speaker 6:  there was a great digital trend story that I think what he did was he got
Speaker 6:  it to show a picture of Barney firing an
Speaker 6:  AK of 47 at Elmo. It might have been the reverse of that, but I think it
Speaker 6:  was that. No, that's
Speaker 8:  It. No, that's, and
Speaker 6:  That is like in a certain way horrifying. But like, I
Speaker 6:  actually track that as like way less of a problem than some of the stuff
Speaker 6:  that Chris Welch has been just sort of relentlessly posting about the last
Speaker 6:  few days, which is just like, he just created, he
Speaker 6:  took a, a photo of an empty intersection in New York and with
Speaker 6:  one request made it look like there had been a bicycle accident there. Or
Speaker 6:  You can take a car with a dent and add the thing that dented it into the
Speaker 6:  photo even though it's not there. Like it's this unbelievably
Speaker 6:  mundane stuff that is so much more problematic to me than the fact
Speaker 6:  that You can like generate Nazi cartoon characters. Which again,
Speaker 6:  is a thing that Google will let you do, but you can't have one without the
Speaker 6:  other. I'm increasingly convinced that like the idea of like, I
Speaker 6:  want to be able to insert myself into a photo with somebody
Speaker 6:  else. I get that. Right. Like one of the funny things
Speaker 6:  about my family is like my mom is always the one who takes the pictures and
Speaker 6:  so she's never in any of the family photos and she hates it, but she also
Speaker 6:  wants to be the one to take the photos that sucks. And like that is a problem
Speaker 6:  Google has solved with artificial intelligence. I will absolutely happily
Speaker 6:  sacrifice that to get rid of all this other stuff. Like we, it just
Speaker 6:  like shut it all down.
Speaker 8:  The thing is they kind of, all these tools are separated and I think, like
Speaker 8:  Alison, you talked about it in your review. It's, it's annoying from a user
Speaker 8:  perspective in that I did, I couldn't, I thought I didn't have, I had the,
Speaker 8:  the regular Pixel nine, I just thought I didn't have access to Reimagine.
Speaker 8:  And then Alison was like, it's over there. And, and I, and I found where
Speaker 8:  it was in the, in the app, like the stuff where people are making
Speaker 8:  Barney shooting Elmo, that's one tool, that's Pixel Studio. And
Speaker 8:  that one, like, that's where I tried to make Kirby and just made a sad balloon.
Speaker 8:  And and you can't create people in that one. And, and there's some pretty
Speaker 8:  strict guardrails except for around apparently all cartoon characters. Right.
Speaker 8:  And then there's reimagine. Would you have to go into the photos app,
Speaker 8:  click on edit and then click on the little thing to the point where I just
Speaker 8:  didn't find it. Kirby, you
Speaker 6:  Just tried really hard to make that sound like a lot of work. That is not
Speaker 6:  a lot of work.
Speaker 8:  It's it's not a lot of work and it's not a lot of work, but there's, there's
Speaker 8:  a little friction there. But it is like, it's, it was hard to find right?
Speaker 8:  It wasn't natural. Whereas when you go to do Add Me, which is probably
Speaker 8:  the most, the least controversial of these features that's in the camera
Speaker 8:  app. Like you open the camera app because like I thought Reimagine was gonna
Speaker 8:  be on the camera app. That's kind of where my brain was logically. I was
Speaker 8:  like, oh, you're editing images, it'll be there. No, it's in this a whole
Speaker 8:  other place. and it was like, it was both frustrating to have to go to three
Speaker 8:  different apps to do all this stuff, but at the same time, that means those
Speaker 8:  aren't smooshed together. Like you could have Abi and just
Speaker 8:  get rid of Reimagine you could, you like, pixel Studio
Speaker 8:  is a whole ass app. You can just delete that
Speaker 6:  In this specific instance. Yes, I agree with that. Yeah. But I think we're
Speaker 6:  pretty clearly headed toward two things, which is one, all of those features
Speaker 6:  you just described being totally ubiquitous everywhere. Right? Like anything
Speaker 6:  that is a camera is gonna have all of that stuff really fast. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And B all of that stuff is going to be pushed
Speaker 6:  together, right? Like the, the, they're all, it's all gonna be in the photos
Speaker 6:  app. It just is. It's all gonna, and, and in the same way that you like press
Speaker 6:  the plus button to upload a photo, you'll be able to press the plus button
Speaker 6:  to generate a photo. And we're, we're gonna treat those two as the same thing.
Speaker 6:  All of this stuff is coming forward in the interface and is
Speaker 6:  coming together in a way that I think is like, feels sort of
Speaker 6:  in that, in Unstoppable at this moment and like has
Speaker 6:  to be stopped because I agree there are some of these things that are fine,
Speaker 6:  right? Like I think Adme is a little weird, but it actually seems like the
Speaker 6:  way that Google forces it to work 'cause you have to do it in the moment
Speaker 6:  and I think is is like largely fine. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  You can't dick around with it as much as I thought you were gonna be able
Speaker 8:  to.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like fine. I will, I will let that one continue to
Speaker 6:  exist. It doesn't seem like it works all that well. Like it works sort of
Speaker 6:  passively fun, but it's kind of like you sloppily photoshopped yourself in,
Speaker 6:  which I think it seems like what that should be. I'm, yeah, we
Speaker 8:  It's a royal family job is what we call it. Yeah, right.
Speaker 6:  It's it's the like Yes, I was also there, but it's very clear I was not in
Speaker 6:  this photo. Like I'm good with that. Yeah, I'm good with that. It was like,
Speaker 6:  what was the, what was the app that would take both a photo of the,
Speaker 6:  with both your front and back camera at the same time and then Stitch 'em
Speaker 6:  together? Add me? I forgot. Oh, it was front back, right? Was that what it
Speaker 6:  was called? I think it was called Front Back. Add me
Speaker 6:  feels like just like a better version of front back, like Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Front back.
Speaker 6:  Oh. But, but it, it just feels increasingly to me, like this road that we're
Speaker 6:  on is all of these things eventually becoming one tool and basically becoming
Speaker 6:  another swipe in the camera. Right. You'll go photo video,
Speaker 6:  but whatever cinematic mode, panorama
Speaker 6:  generative. And it's like, we cannot let that happen. I'm, I'm so,
Speaker 6:  so, so convinced we cannot let that happen.
Speaker 8:  Alison, do you think that's why they kept it out of the, the edit app and
Speaker 8:  they they kind of have it again, not su like, obvious
Speaker 8:  enough that it's pretty easy to find, but also I would, I took a week to
Speaker 8:  find it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I I think it's deliberate and I've talked to,
Speaker 7:  you know, people on The Pixel camera team about like,
Speaker 7:  you know, where where do you decide where to put these things? And is
Speaker 7:  it, you know, is it a bigger problem if it's in the camera app or something
Speaker 7:  in the photos app and kind of philosophy is like
Speaker 7:  how, how sticky it is and how like
Speaker 7:  permanent like the effects are is more important than
Speaker 7:  like, did you go into the camera app to trigger this or what? I think the
Speaker 7:  way they have it now is very sensible. Like, I don't
Speaker 7:  think, you know, my, my mom's not gonna stumble across
Speaker 7:  to Reimagine trying to just like look at photos of her
Speaker 7:  grandchild or whatever. And, and I think that
Speaker 7:  the thing to also note on, on the whole situation is like
Speaker 7:  the, the thing that people yell at us immediately is like, this has always
Speaker 7:  exist. You know, Photoshop exists, we've been able to do all this stuff
Speaker 7:  and there are way, way fewer barriers when it's
Speaker 7:  a phone and it's built into the phone and all you have to do is, is tap
Speaker 7:  on some stuff. And the other thing that
Speaker 7:  we, that was really troubling to us as we dug into it was
Speaker 7:  the, the photo reimagined stuff has
Speaker 7:  a metadata tag that says made with Google ai.
Speaker 7:  That's the extent of it. The Pixel studio stuff, which is fully
Speaker 7:  synthetic gets a more robust, like kind of embedded,
Speaker 7:  you don't see it, but it's a watermark that will kind of carry across, you
Speaker 7:  know, it's syn I shot Yeah. Syn id which
Speaker 6:  Google and DeepMind have made like a lot of noise about like, this is supposed
Speaker 6:  to be a gigantic industry standard that makes all of this stuff work and
Speaker 6:  Okay. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And they only apply it to the one where You can make an image of
Speaker 8:  Barney shooting
Speaker 6:  The one that is Elly fake. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like, I didn't need it like, oh, it's
Speaker 6:  A water
Speaker 7:  Like
Speaker 6:  That. It's Barney shooting Elmo. God. Okay.
Speaker 7:  It's like, oh, I can't believe believe they're actually fighting. Yeah. No.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I feel like that's completely backwards. Like, I wanna know
Speaker 7:  that something has been added to this, this real
Speaker 7:  photo, you know, with these synthetic tools,
Speaker 7:  not the other way around. It's, it's strange. It's such a weird
Speaker 7:  time.
Speaker 6:  I think philosophically there's actually a reason Google wouldn't do
Speaker 6:  that. Like part of the reason I I find all of this so concerning is that
Speaker 6:  everything Google has said publicly feels very flippant
Speaker 6:  about this. Right? Like Google's answer I think to Wired was that, you know,
Speaker 6:  it's not about photos, it's about making your memories match your memory.
Speaker 6:  And it's like, what?
Speaker 8:  I mean that's what we heard constantly, I think at, at The Pixel event
Speaker 8:  was they said, no, this isn't about your photo. Your photo is a thing you
Speaker 8:  take and and it's, it's archival, right? This is about the memory.
Speaker 8:  This is, this is isn't supposed to be for the journalists shooting the
Speaker 8:  thing. It's supposed to be for the parent who wants to fix things for
Speaker 8:  their kids. And it's like, okay, well yeah, that makes sense. But you've
Speaker 8:  also given it to the journalists and you've also given it to all of the people
Speaker 8:  who are perpetuating misinformation online. And that is a
Speaker 8:  bigger group than we would like because people love to chase cloud
Speaker 8:  online with fake shit.
Speaker 6:  It also doesn't make sense. That makes sense. If the feature you're introducing
Speaker 6:  is red eye reduction, right? Yeah. That sure fine. If you
Speaker 6:  wanna release a thing that makes people's eyes look like they're open when
Speaker 6:  they're not, I honestly have no problem with that. And Neela is not here
Speaker 6:  to yell at me about that and he would And that's fine. I have no problem
Speaker 6:  with that. We're
Speaker 8:  Gonna the whole spectrum here.
Speaker 6:  Well, and that, that to me is like, this is where I come to the, the only
Speaker 6:  solution is to burn it all down thing. Yeah. 'cause like you can't, I I have
Speaker 6:  not yet seen a way to do a little bit of, of it without
Speaker 6:  inevitably doing all of it. And I think if we do all of it, we are somewhere
Speaker 6:  awful.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It's Pandora's box. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I think at this point it's like, J shut the box and set it on fire
Speaker 6:  and let's all just pretend none of this ever happened and everything will
Speaker 6:  be fine.
Speaker 8:  David, would you feel more comfortable if it was
Speaker 8:  like an app that you had to download? So you had to go, you
Speaker 8:  had to find it in the play store, you had to download it and sign in, and
Speaker 8:  then you could do all of this stuff. Would that make it feel a little better?
Speaker 6:  A little, yeah. I mean, I think I I Allison to your point, we, the biggest
Speaker 6:  pushback we get when we talk about this stuff is people being like, this
Speaker 6:  has been, it's been possible to manipulate photos forever. And that's true.
Speaker 6:  And Sarah Jung wrote a great piece for us about this, this week that
Speaker 6:  I think really captures a lot of this. But like in so many ways,
Speaker 6:  the story of the tech industry is making a thing slightly more convenient
Speaker 6:  and you actually change everything. Like what Uber did to the taxi industry
Speaker 6:  was just make it slightly more convenient. Like the, the idea of things
Speaker 6:  being fewer steps away from you and, and they become like a step change
Speaker 6:  More popular is real. Like yeah, there's an ev there's
Speaker 6:  evidence of that everywhere you look and So I think, yeah, if, if they made
Speaker 6:  it an app that you had to download, I would be slightly less
Speaker 6:  alarmed if they made it an app you had to download that costs $700 and
Speaker 6:  required like a master's degree to learn how to use successfully. So I would
Speaker 6:  also be less alarmed. I I really do think that like, the
Speaker 6:  fact that it's a separate app right now is a good thing. I suspect given
Speaker 6:  the way that Google talks about this, that that has much more to do with
Speaker 6:  the fact that this is new than the fact that Google has taken
Speaker 6:  some moral stance about ai. Totally, totally agree. I don't there's any evidence
Speaker 6:  to suggest that Google thinks it's a good thing for the world to keep
Speaker 6:  this out of people's hands. Like nothing.
Speaker 8:  They want it in people's hands, right? Like to the, to the point of the,
Speaker 8:  their philosophy is this now.
Speaker 6:  Right? So why wouldn't Google find more and more ways to bring it forward?
Speaker 6:  Like you, you're gonna get to a point where you're like, Hey Gemini, take
Speaker 6:  a photo of this, but insert a car crash into it and it will,
Speaker 6:  it will produce that photo. The original photo that you take will include
Speaker 6:  that. Like, why, why won't
Speaker 8:  We get that? Well, you're gonna have to actually say it, but take a photo
Speaker 8:  of this bicycle mangled next to a car
Speaker 8:  with a dent.
Speaker 6:  No, it has that already. It's good. It can, it can put a
Speaker 6:  giraffe into the photo of my backyard. I could have a giraffe in my backyard.
Speaker 6:  Like all it needs is the photo of my backyard, which is the easy part, right?
Speaker 6:  Like I, I just, I have reached this point now where like, I, I don't know
Speaker 6:  what else we can do except just shut it all down,
Speaker 6:  which is why like the, this the, the bill in California right now is so
Speaker 6:  fascinating, right? 'cause the question is like, who is responsible for when
Speaker 6:  all of this is horribly wrong? And
Speaker 6:  if it passes and we get down this road where all of a sudden
Speaker 6:  the companies that make these tools are responsible for what happens with
Speaker 6:  them. Ooh. That gets it, it gets so messy and we end up with a weird
Speaker 6:  section two 30 thing all over again. Who is responsible for mean things that
Speaker 6:  people say on the internet, but like, if Google were responsible
Speaker 6:  for every single thing that reimagined produced, you think Google would've
Speaker 6:  launched this?
Speaker 8:  No.
Speaker 6:  The thing, not a chance.
Speaker 7:  The thing they told us when we were like, Hey, so we've been able to use
Speaker 7:  your tool to make all these like pretty disturbing things. What do you think
Speaker 7:  about that? And they were like, oh, we have these terms of service
Speaker 7:  and that's a violation of the policy. It's like,
Speaker 6:  Okay, no, it's, no, it's it's worse than that. It's worse than that. The,
Speaker 6:  the statement that they've given to everybody, including us from Alex Moria,
Speaker 6:  Google says, we design our generative AI tools to
Speaker 6:  respect the intent of user prompts. And that means they may create content
Speaker 6:  that may offend when instructed by the user to do so. That says in as many
Speaker 6:  words, it's your fault not ours. Mm.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Yeah. and it does, we
Speaker 6:  Didn't do it. You did it. Guns don't kill people. People kill people,
Speaker 8:  Right? And I, I think they're coming at this from the, they're, they're thinking,
Speaker 8:  oh, we're just like Photoshop. Because to to everybody who comments
Speaker 8:  that that's true, like Photoshop can do all of this and probably do it
Speaker 8:  be, and in many cases do it better. Photoshop is hard
Speaker 8:  and this is so easy and Google is kind of ignoring
Speaker 8:  that ease. Like they're, they're happy to talk about it on stage. They're
Speaker 8:  happy to talk about it in an advertisements and, and profiles and whatever.
Speaker 8:  They're not happy to talk about it when we ask them. Right?
Speaker 6:  The ease is a feature, not a bug. Unless you ask Google about how easy it's,
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And then, and then they're like, well, yeah, that's not the problem.
Speaker 8:  And it's like, no, no, that is actually the problem. You've increased access
Speaker 8:  here. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And like, it, it's,
Speaker 8:  This
Speaker 6:  Is so weird to me because it is like, to your point, Alison, like some of
Speaker 6:  the same stuff that Google is building to make it so that like the
Speaker 6:  dark scenes that you shoot on your phone look better,
Speaker 6:  which I think everyone agrees is a good thing, right? Like night sight is
Speaker 6:  awesome and night sight is ai, right? Like that's just, that is what it is.
Speaker 6:  How you stop that before it gets to, I
Speaker 6:  can insert unbelievably compelling lies into every single one of my photos.
Speaker 6:  And I think the, the thing that Sarah wrote in her piece, which we'll link
Speaker 6:  in the show notes, and I've gotten some crap for forgetting to link things
Speaker 6:  in the show notes, and I'm very sorry and I will start, I will do better
Speaker 6:  from now on, is that so much of like, life
Speaker 6:  is just having photos, right? Like I have a, I have a leak in my ceiling,
Speaker 6:  I take a photo and I send it to somebody. I have, there's a, there i I got
Speaker 6:  in a car accident a couple weeks ago and the very first thing I did was walk
Speaker 6:  around my car and take pictures of it. What if you can't trust those pictures
Speaker 6:  anymore? What if somebody can point to them and say those might be ai and
Speaker 6:  all of a sudden those pictures are meaningless. Like we are entering a phase
Speaker 6:  where it's going to be so easy and only going to get easier
Speaker 6:  to make this incredibly mundane stuff. Like we don't think about how
Speaker 6:  much a part of our lives photos are. We talk a lot about politics and like
Speaker 6:  really high stakes stuff, but the what if the low stakes photos don't count
Speaker 6:  anymore?
Speaker 8:  I I was just realized the, the one thing we can still count on
Speaker 8:  is all of the insurance companies are gonna band together and be like, absolutely
Speaker 8:  not. Yeah. Yeah. Because 'cause like, like that's the one where it's
Speaker 8:  like, oh yeah, that's a lot of money for them. If David's just adding a bunch
Speaker 8:  of dents to the car, like gimme more money. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  What if the insurance company can refuse my claim because they don't have
Speaker 6:  to believe my photos. Right.
Speaker 7:  Or it was shot on a Pixel nine and they're like, oh, we don't accept those.
Speaker 7:  Right.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like you might have stripped out the metadata. It's only one line of
Speaker 6:  metadata. It's not that hard to do. Yeah. People are more motivated to get
Speaker 6:  around these things than they get credit for, for so, so many
Speaker 6:  reasons. Alright. Buy The Pixel nine. Just don't do any of that.
Speaker 6:  I think the takeaway be
Speaker 7:  Good. Don't do evil.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  You don't be a dick. Yeah. Weird.
Speaker 6:  Don't be evil. Somebody should really use that as a That's a good tagline
Speaker 6:  for some days. Yeah. It rings a bell.
Speaker 6:  All right Allison, we gotta take a break and we're gonna let you go. We're
Speaker 6:  gonna come back and we're gonna talk about a bunch of streaming shenanigans
Speaker 6:  because there are endless streaming shenanigans. We'll be right back.
Speaker 8:  assets and I would
Speaker 8:  for parts and those would be very lucrative parts, but it is much more
Speaker 8:  potentially powerful altogether.
Speaker 6:  Richard, I'm, I'm really enjoying the, the theory of a pro nepo baby
Speaker 6:  economy. Yeah. That, that we, we just demand. It's by we give things to
Speaker 6:  the Nepo babies, but we demand that they spend all their money on those things.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I really love this for them.
Speaker 13:  And, and I love this round of news because it brings back Ed Brolin and
Speaker 13:  Jr. Who I didn't know was still in, in, in the league at all. Who is
Speaker 6:  This person
Speaker 13:  He is, if you're like me and you've read like all of
Speaker 13:  the books about ESPN and Disney and all of the Disney Wars and these guys
Speaker 13:  have all the fun and all these kind of entertainment industry books about
Speaker 13:  the nineties and two thousands and all, I guess going back to the eighties,
Speaker 13:  he's one of those figures who pops up, he's a heir to a liquor fortune,
Speaker 13:  I think. Mm. And has bought his way into
Speaker 13:  media companies all over the place. and it is currently running
Speaker 13:  is currently I think a chairman of Fuo or
Speaker 8:  Yep. Chairperson of fubu. Currently
Speaker 6:  Fuo famously now in a gigantic fight with most of the
Speaker 6:  rest of Hollywood over venue sports. There's just only
Speaker 6:  12 people in Hollywood. I think is like, the main important thing to
Speaker 6:  remember is that this is a tiny industry and everybody has worked everywhere
Speaker 6:  and they all, they're all the companies are run by the same four people
Speaker 8:  Air the Seagram fortune.
Speaker 6:  Oh,
Speaker 8:  He really has been like, he was CEO of the Warner Music Group.
Speaker 8:  He's just been all, he, he's very involved with Seagram, chairman of
Speaker 8:  Vindy Universal, like did a little Broadway
Speaker 8:  producing Man Loves Media.
Speaker 6:  I mean it, but it like bigger picture. It really seems
Speaker 6:  increasingly, like right now, like Netflix is good,
Speaker 6:  just be Netflix. The games thing seems to be slowly starting to work.
Speaker 6:  That's like Netflix is fine, is it? And then everybody else is just pure
Speaker 6:  anarchy right now. Like Disney is starting its succession plan again,
Speaker 6:  canceling shows. Alex, the other thing I need you to explain to me is why
Speaker 6:  everyone was so sad that the accolade got canceled. Everybody as far as I
Speaker 6:  know, hated the accolade to the point where I didn't even watch it because
Speaker 6:  everybody thought it was bad, but then everybody was up in arms that it was
Speaker 6:  canceled this week. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  I I would like, if we wanna talk, pivot over to Acolyte, the reason people
Speaker 8:  are mad about that is because the same thing happened with the
Speaker 8:  Marvels. The same thing happens with any woman or person of color
Speaker 8:  led property that is really attractive to nerds. You get a small
Speaker 8:  portion of people who are just tired of nerd shit. And, and I love you all
Speaker 8:  live your lives. You get a larger person of people who are nerds and
Speaker 8:  want nerd shit, but they only want to if it looks like them. And they tend
Speaker 8:  to all be white dudes. And, and those people are really good at being really,
Speaker 8:  really loud. So the people who are just like, oh, I'm, I'll watch this. They're
Speaker 8:  not out there tweeting. But in the case of the acolyte it people
Speaker 8:  are really bad that it got canceled because they're really concerned that
Speaker 8:  they're gonna do the same thing they did, did Willow, which was excellent
Speaker 8:  and shouldn't have been pulled from the service, but nobody watched it and
Speaker 8:  they're afraid that they're gonna pull this one from Disney plus. 'cause
Speaker 8:  nobody watched it like that. That was the thing. It it just got bad ratings.
Speaker 8:  Nobody watched it.
Speaker 6:  So was it good though?
Speaker 8:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Because I'm, I'm super sympathetic to that entire argument. If it
Speaker 8:  Was all about what if these twins
Speaker 8:  who are really powerful in the force, one of them goes and goes
Speaker 8:  fully Jedi, then realizes Jedi suck and then
Speaker 8:  slowly gets to seduce to the dark side by Manny Jacinto's arms
Speaker 8:  and like,
Speaker 6:  I'm really enjoying Richard's
Speaker 8:  Face. Wouldn't wanna watch that. You described
Speaker 6:  It. Why
Speaker 13:  Wasn't that the trailer I would watch would've watched?
Speaker 8:  Right. Like, it it really is like the whole time he's all like, oh no, I've,
Speaker 8:  I've removed my shirt and I'm flexing right now. Now I've got a lights saber.
Speaker 8:  And you're like, yeah, this rules. And we, we we were robbed
Speaker 8:  basically.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That is the single most compelling argument for the accolade that I've
Speaker 6:  ever heard.
Speaker 8:  I think that's, they just shown his
Speaker 13:  Arms, I feel like paid for that second or third or however many seasons
Speaker 13:  they've had of the Bounty Hunter show. Right. Of Bob Fit. Because we
Speaker 13:  got kind of tired of Star Wars after a point. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And, and, and we see this again and again and again. There's the, the combat,
Speaker 8:  like You can have fatigue. You can have angry,
Speaker 8:  racist, sexist fan boys. You can't have both. And right now
Speaker 8:  they have both. So anytime there is a project that doesn't speak to those
Speaker 8:  racist, sexist fan boys, that that just, there's a to the
Speaker 8:  bottom drops out of the audience because everybody else is tired of it. And
Speaker 8:  even if you say, no, no, this time it's good. You have to say it in a very
Speaker 8:  specific way. And they struggle to market it over and over and over again.
Speaker 8:  Because I keep seeing now everybody's like,
Speaker 13:  You need to have enough volume to drown out certain things. Yeah. And, and
Speaker 13:  if that volume goes away suddenly that's all that's left.
Speaker 8:  Right. And and we saw this, like I said, we saw the exact same thing with
Speaker 8:  the Marvels and now everybody's like, Hey, did you see the Marvels? That's
Speaker 8:  actually really good. And I'm like, yeah, yeah, it was really good. Just
Speaker 8:  everybody was tired of superheroes when it came out. So, and it did have
Speaker 8:  some stupid parts, but everybody was mainly tired of superheroes. And then
Speaker 8:  a whole bunch of other people were like, but you stars girls. That's exactly
Speaker 8:  what you sound like when you complain like that. People, just to be clear,
Speaker 8:  I wanna insult you
Speaker 6:  Every time we hear that now, just take that clip and just play it in response
Speaker 6:  to Yeah. Whoever tweets mean things about these shows.
Speaker 6:  So, but, but like this is all part of the sort of bigger, like what
Speaker 6:  is going on inside of these streaming services thing that I keep
Speaker 6:  coming back to is like, it, it just seems like outside of Netflix,
Speaker 6:  which I think can afford to just throw everything at everybody
Speaker 6:  and some of it will stick and it'll be fine.
Speaker 6:  Like Disney can't afford to make this
Speaker 6:  many bad Star Wars shows, right. That people don't watch. And
Speaker 6:  now Disney is like back in succession planning, they just announced the new
Speaker 6:  succession committee to who for whoever is going to next be fired
Speaker 6:  by Bob Iger two years after they're given the job. Like, I
Speaker 6:  don't know, it just, there's so much just like swirling chaos inside of all
Speaker 6:  of these things. Right now, I
Speaker 8:  Would say that Hollywood is in one of its most
Speaker 8:  difficult moments, like more difficult the the pandemic, particularly
Speaker 8:  all these streamers and stuff. Because when you look at, when you look at
Speaker 8:  who, who's in the field, you've got like Apple, they don't care. They can
Speaker 8:  fart out these things and, and they'll do fine. So you've got Apple, they,
Speaker 8:  they don't make a whole lot of shows. They put a lot of money into them,
Speaker 8:  but they don't make a whole lot. And they're struggling in the
Speaker 8:  movie business. All of their movies are bombs, but their TV shows great,
Speaker 8:  get a lot of reviews. But whatever Apple, you've got Amazon
Speaker 8:  actually the second largest streamer and, and they're doing just fine. They've
Speaker 8:  got sports rights now they, they have advertising so you don't even have
Speaker 8:  to pay for it really. You can just like pop in and start watching like
Speaker 8:  Amazon's doing fine. And they also are Amazon. So they've got all of
Speaker 8:  this other stuff to make money for them. Like AWS and Amazon.
Speaker 8:  And then you have like the non-tech ones. You have Warner Brothers who just
Speaker 8:  wrote down all of their broadcasts, network networks. You have
Speaker 8:  Paramount who just wrote down all of their broadcast networks. You have Disney
Speaker 8:  who didn't and probably will soon write down all of their networks. And
Speaker 8:  that's because all the broadcast stuff was supporting everybody and supporting
Speaker 8:  'em through this streaming moment because they knew broadcast was going away
Speaker 8:  and streaming was coming. And they're like, okay, we have to get through
Speaker 8:  this. But the broadcast died faster than they
Speaker 8:  expected. One of the few exceptions is NBC Peacock,
Speaker 8:  they're also struggling, but they did a really good job with the Olympics.
Speaker 6:  They did.
Speaker 8:  They like, they showed what happens when a really smart
Speaker 8:  broadcaster programs really well on these platforms and it
Speaker 8:  worked and they, they did really, really well. How long that lasts,
Speaker 8:  how quickly those people churn. That's, that's all other story.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The the Olympics are unfortunately over. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Which is you get two weeks tough
Speaker 6:  Times for Netflix.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Or tough times for Peacock rather. Yeah.
Speaker 13:  No, no one else is watching Diamond League. We're not coming back to the
Speaker 13:  Paralympics. They're about to start, come on, let's, let's go, let's keep
Speaker 13:  this going.
Speaker 6:  That new Steph Curry show on Peacock, that seems like it's awful. Like really
Speaker 6:  great times for Peacock.
Speaker 13:  I think the thing about Netflix is it turns out that basic cable for
Speaker 13:  15 to $20 a month is a pretty good idea. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  That's
Speaker 6:  It. And Netflix did it, right? Like I think, I think more than people realized,
Speaker 6:  certainly more than I realized until very recently, Netflix
Speaker 6:  can be that, right? Like if you, if you have a reasonably steady
Speaker 6:  run of very good things, and then just an
Speaker 6:  infinite supply of like background noise, You can win.
Speaker 6:  And for 20 bucks a month, that's essentially what Netflix has. Like, and,
Speaker 6:  and as long as it keeps having those periodic wins, which it
Speaker 6:  continues to do, it's gonna be very hard to supplant that. and
Speaker 8:  It's gotten a lot more savage about its cancellations too. Yes. Right?
Speaker 8:  Like, like it is not afraid. Disney Plus was pretty, pretty
Speaker 8:  timid about canceling things, which is why we got three seasons of Mandalorian
Speaker 8:  and the, the entire season of Boba Fat. Why?
Speaker 8:  But, but like Disney's gotten a little more aggressive about it and Disney's,
Speaker 8:  you know, pulling from, from Warner Brothers playbook of like, okay, the
Speaker 8:  show doesn't get a lot of views. We're gonna pull it. We are gonna then scrap
Speaker 8:  the entire show because we don't wanna have to pay the tax. We just wanna
Speaker 8:  write it off as a loss. That's what happened with Willow. That may be what
Speaker 8:  happens with the acolyte. And that, I think that's where so much of that
Speaker 8:  tension is because
Speaker 8:  you like archival purposes. Sometimes people do like the show and they just
Speaker 8:  wanna watch it, put it out on DVD, but that's expensive and they don't wanna
Speaker 8:  do it.
Speaker 6:  Well, and I think the, the thing you said about the broadcast piece of it
Speaker 6:  is really important because the, the bet for so long was that
Speaker 6:  they could just invest and lose money and make mistakes and have it all go
Speaker 6:  wrong. Because this like Money Fountain on the other side would
Speaker 6:  pay for it. Yeah. and it would go down and it seemed reasonably like
Speaker 6:  it might be linear that as more people streamed, fewer people would watch
Speaker 6:  linear tv, but mostly that would be one-to-one and everything would be fine.
Speaker 6:  And that is not even remotely how it has turned out. And so
Speaker 6:  the, all of a sudden it's like, oh, this money that we thought we had
Speaker 6:  to invest in bad Star Wars shows we actually don't have
Speaker 6:  at all. Yeah. And it's like, that makes you panic on two levels because one,
Speaker 6:  we've spent this money on a bad Star Wars show, and two, we didn't have the
Speaker 6:  money in the first place that we thought we were gonna have. And so you just
Speaker 6:  end up in this like, it's, it feels like a spiral towards ugly places.
Speaker 8:  That's why you're hearing a lot of talk in, in Hollywood right now is that
Speaker 8:  like, David Zaslav is gonna get fired from Warner Brothers because he's getting
Speaker 8:  paid so much money and he just wrote down all of their broadcast stuff
Speaker 8:  and his whole big plan was, which I thought was a good plan when he,
Speaker 8:  when he first did it, was let's merge it all together. Let's make this super
Speaker 8:  app, let's, let's like, put our broadcast on here. And
Speaker 8:  they just haven't done it. And when they have done it, it's been like, did
Speaker 8:  you guys watch CNN on Max ever? Am I the only one that does it?
Speaker 8:  It it, it does you like three minutes of CNN and then it
Speaker 8:  cuts to like 10 minutes of Medicare in
Speaker 8:  Oh, like additional supplemental Medicare insurance
Speaker 8:  commercials.
Speaker 6:  To be fair, that's just CNN you just described CNN
Speaker 8:  Is that just CNNI like, I, I guess I never watch it the, the old fashioned
Speaker 8:  way, but I was like, oh my goy, I had to turn it off. I can't rush into
Speaker 6:  This is why. So the other day Alex comes storming into our slack going
Speaker 6:  have the CNN Chirons always looked this crazy.
Speaker 8:  That's right. I did just start watching CNN last week. Hi,
Speaker 8:  my name's Alex Cranz.
Speaker 6:  This makes sense. Well, it's
Speaker 8:  Bad.
Speaker 6:  I have great news for you in these Trying Times in streaming, which
Speaker 6:  is that Chick-fil-A is here now and Chick-fil-A will fix it.
Speaker 6:  Richard can You can you just quickly explain what Chick-fil-A is doing
Speaker 6:  here? And then I have, I have many roads for us to go down, but can you just
Speaker 6:  tell us what we know so far?
Speaker 13:  Okay. First of all, no, I cannot. Second what we know so far is that
Speaker 13:  deadline said that Chick-fil-A is working with a number of production studios
Speaker 13:  and tradi traditional studios to create original shows for a streaming platform
Speaker 13:  that they say they want, want, want to launch this year. Something that
Speaker 13:  a lot of people may not be aware of is that the owner of Chick-fil-A the
Speaker 13:  Kathy family, they also were key to the foundation of Trivia
Speaker 13:  Studios, which you may not know necessarily by the name, but you know, by
Speaker 13:  what they make there, which is the Marvel movies really in, in
Speaker 13:  Georgia, a massive, massive, massive production lot
Speaker 13:  where a lot of things are made.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Ge Georgia's got the good discounts if you wanna shoot
Speaker 8:  there. Yeah. And the good studios, it's not just Tyler Perry.
Speaker 6:  Okay. So I I have done in the last 24 hours, what I would say
Speaker 6:  is too much research on Chick-fil-A and its entertainment aspirations.
Speaker 6:  Can I share a little bit of what I've discovered with you? Yes.
Speaker 6:  Chick-fil-A has a whole separate brand that it's, that it calls penny
Speaker 6:  cake and penny cake. Why is it named Penny cake?
Speaker 6:  I, I could not tell you, but it's basically a, a
Speaker 6:  brand full of like family friendly games and
Speaker 6:  activities. It has a bunch of like, puzzles. It has a bunch
Speaker 6:  of those things where you like pull a, a prompt out of
Speaker 6:  a bag and you talk about it as a family. And it's like,
Speaker 6:  if you squint at it, it's kind of a like thing to do around the table while
Speaker 6:  you eat Chick-fil-A but in general, it just seems like some
Speaker 6:  executive at Chick-fil-A was like, I wanna make puzzles. And they were like,
Speaker 6:  all right, make puzzles, I guess Chick-fil-A also
Speaker 6:  fun fact has made content before it made a
Speaker 6:  series of shows called the Stories of Evergreen Hills
Speaker 6:  that I would describe as like animated in the style of the
Speaker 6:  Polar Express, but about like how to be
Speaker 6:  a good person. It's like, what if the Berenstein Bears and Polar
Speaker 6:  Express sort of smooshed together and was worse?
Speaker 6:  You'd have stories of Evergreen Hills. I encourage you to look this up on
Speaker 6:  YouTube. A bunch of them exist. They're kind of weird and
Speaker 6:  like, you know, vacation Bible schooly in the sense that like they
Speaker 6:  have a big moral lesson at the end and they want to teach you how to be a
Speaker 6:  better person. It's
Speaker 8:  Like Veggie Tales. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But so Richard, to your point, it's what's
Speaker 6:  weird to me is that it's Chick-fil-A doing this. Like, I I I've had to wrap
Speaker 6:  my head around the fact that Chick-fil-A is not a restaurant, it's a, it
Speaker 6:  is just a large company with a name, right? And companies do lots of things,
Speaker 6:  some under their brand and some not under their brand. But this family owns
Speaker 6:  an enormous studio,
Speaker 6:  is well versed in the content business. And
Speaker 6:  yet we're gonna get like Chick-fil-A plus as A streaming service. I
Speaker 6:  doubt that's what it's gonna be called. I should say like, I think it might
Speaker 6:  be Penny Cake. I think they might come up with another brand like whatever.
Speaker 6:  But the idea of like Chick-fil-A the restaurant wanting
Speaker 6:  to make content just does not make any sense to me. Is this,
Speaker 6:  am I, am I overthinking this or under thinking this?
Speaker 13:  Did Chick-fil-A stop and say why not? When they were thinking about sponsoring
Speaker 13:  a bowl game,
Speaker 13:  I mean, they did not fair. And does Chick-fil-A plus make less sense than
Speaker 13:  Hallmark Plus? If you think, if you think about, Ooh, that's a good one.
Speaker 13:  Why does a card company have a network?
Speaker 8:  Oh, I just figured it out.
Speaker 6:  So okay, wait, but I'll give you that. If Chick-fil-A wants to basically
Speaker 6:  make worse food network, then I'm No,
Speaker 8:  No, no. Probably no. Chick-fil-A is gonna acquire what the, the, the
Speaker 8:  scorched remains of Chicken Soup for the Soul Entertainment
Speaker 8:  in in red. They're gonna acquire all that and then they're just gonna
Speaker 8:  do Christian streaming service.
Speaker 8:  'cause they love Jesus differently than
Speaker 8:  other people do, but they have their own opinion. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  I I I love that they don't work on Sunday, but that that's what they're gonna
Speaker 8:  do. They're gonna do a Christian entertainment
Speaker 8:  streaming service. I
Speaker 6:  Think that's right. And as we've seen, seen, that's a big market. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 6:  Like Angel Studios is very successful.
Speaker 8:  I mean, it wasn't a big market for Chicken Soup for the Soul entertainment.
Speaker 6:  No. But I would say they'd made a lot of mistakes.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. That's, that's that were
Speaker 6:  Not like, like if Chick-fil-A gets really big into selling DVDs at Chick-fil-A
Speaker 6:  I think we'll have a problem. But my guess is that's not, and all the Chick,
Speaker 13:  The story Chicka for the Soul seems to be, it would've been a fine company
Speaker 13:  if it were happy being what it was. It was trying to be 100 other things.
Speaker 13:  Totally.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. But Chick-fil-A that's about it. It's about to do. So,
Speaker 6:  Okay, so this, this is the game. I just, I just wanna play for a few minutes
Speaker 6:  here. Okay. I'm, you are now the head of content at Chick-fil-A
Speaker 6:  congratulations to both of you. Yes. You are in charge of
Speaker 6:  making A streaming service
Speaker 6:  A, you have to come up with the name and B, you have to tell me
Speaker 6:  at least two shows that you wanna put on your streaming service. Alex,
Speaker 6:  you go First
Speaker 8:  Chick-fil-A For the Soul is the name of the, the streaming service
Speaker 8:  for ft. I don't know, I'm not gonna do that.
Speaker 8:  P Chick-fil-A for the
Speaker 6:  Soul. C-F-A-F-T-S, something
Speaker 8:  Like that. That's not great. That it's not great. This is a work in progress.
Speaker 8:  But I think that's where we're gonna go. We're gonna get a reboot, a Touch
Speaker 8:  by the Touched by an Angel. Ooh. And wait,
Speaker 6:  That's good. That's actually very
Speaker 8:  Good. And, and either a reboot or we're just gonna get the
Speaker 8:  rights to Prairie. What was Little House on the Prairie?
Speaker 6:  Oh, okay. So just like Sweet down home family shows. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Seventh Heaven will be there gonna go get Mr. Rogers gonna like blur the
Speaker 8:  dad's face out every time we appears on screen. Sure.
Speaker 6:  We'll just deep fake someone else into character. Deep fake.
Speaker 8:  Someone else that does face. Yeah. Oh, but then we get the moment where the
Speaker 8:  moms goes, I smoked pot. and it, there's like an intense noise
Speaker 8:  around her. Oh, that's gonna be so good. Okay. Be like, I can't believe Chick-fil-A
Speaker 8:  did that
Speaker 6:  Richard. Where there we go. Are you what's what what are we doing Chick-fil-A
Speaker 13:  I'm going slightly different direction. Okay. And launching Pacific Rim
Speaker 13:  Network.
Speaker 8:  Oh.
Speaker 13:  Which is all Pacific Rim spinoffs all the time. Unfortunately, there's
Speaker 13:  already a stream of these in production. They've been, they've just continued
Speaker 13:  making them. Are
Speaker 6:  Are there
Speaker 13:  Really intensely they've been developing these shows on and off. There's
Speaker 13:  a new one in developmental just announced last week. We've got content lined
Speaker 13:  up for use. We're good. Pacific Room Network. So, so there would be like
Speaker 13:  a resurrection theme. Every three episodes
Speaker 6:  There are strong merch tie-ins. You can, You can sell the,
Speaker 6:  the, the robots in Chick-fil-A we, we take over the Happy Meal
Speaker 6:  business immediately. I love this. Okay, what are we calling the streaming
Speaker 6:  network?
Speaker 13:  Oh, it's oh, Pacific Room Network. It's all Pacific Rim. Everything's Pacific
Speaker 13:  Room.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Okay. I love this.
Speaker 13:  It's all stories of Pacific Rim. We've got like the big short in Pacific
Speaker 13:  Rim, like when people figure out where the monsters are gonna attack and
Speaker 13:  they, and they're like, shorting the stocks of those companies is great.
Speaker 13:  We've got, we cover all genres.
Speaker 8:  I'm gonna have
Speaker 6:  Re making everything, but it's all set in the Pacific Rim world.
Speaker 6:  Understand.
Speaker 8:  So Seinfeld in the Pacific Rim
Speaker 6:  World, I understand. Yeah. Pacific Rim Seinfeld.
Speaker 8:  Honestly, I'd watch that
Speaker 6:  Sex in the City and Pacific Rim.
Speaker 8:  Everyone would watch that too. You're like, oh my God. Dating and
Speaker 8:  giant monsters all the time. What can we do? All I've got is like
Speaker 8:  deep fake Michael Landon, So, I,
Speaker 6:  Joey and Chandler in the suits just hanging out. This is great.
Speaker 6:  All right. That's, that's very good. Mine. In case you're curious. I'm, I'm
Speaker 6:  calling the network the Sauce
Speaker 6:  and Delicious. And we're doing like
Speaker 6:  family friendly 1990s VH
Speaker 6:  one I would say, that's what I'm going after. So we're doing a bunch of,
Speaker 6:  like, one of the things Chick-fil-A is apparently doing is looking for like
Speaker 6:  family friendly game shows. So I'm going with like all of the,
Speaker 6:  all of the, you know, Christian music videos. People are gonna play
Speaker 6:  that all the time. We're gonna just
Speaker 8:  Jars of clay,
Speaker 6:  We music thing, just jars of clay everywhere you look,
Speaker 6:  some switchfoot when we're feeling edgy. Lots of stuff to do. And then
Speaker 6:  Little Creed. And then it's just gonna be a lot of like
Speaker 6:  great British show, great British baking show style competition shows where
Speaker 6:  it's competition, but everybody's really nice to each other. They, at the
Speaker 6:  end we're end. We're gonna takeover. I think I am going to absolutely dominate.
Speaker 6:  And one show at least is going to be called My Pleasure. and it is going
Speaker 6:  to be our tent pole show. I don't know what it is, but I know it's called
Speaker 6:  My Pleasure.
Speaker 8:  It's actually gonna be a remake of Red Shoe Diaries. We're just gonna go
Speaker 8:  really, really wild with that
Speaker 6:  One. As I say it out loud, my pleasure might be like too sexy a show.
Speaker 8:  I I was like, it was like, that's a little racy for for Chick-fil-A
Speaker 6:  Okay, well we, we have a lot to think about. Chick-fil-A
Speaker 13:  After Dark. Come on now. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Ooh.
Speaker 6:  Oh that's good. We just steal. Are you Afraid of the Dark from
Speaker 6:  Nickelodeon and it's just called Chick-fil-A After Dark.
Speaker 8:  The Nugs are spicier after Dark. Okay.
Speaker 6:  So we're accidentally inventing Chick-fil-A's porn network, which is good.
Speaker 6:  This is, this is the next, we're
Speaker 8:  Helping, we're helping the
Speaker 6:  Next phase of growth for Chick-fil-A You're welcome.
Speaker 13:  Welcome. The entertainment business Chick-fil-A
Speaker 6:  Alright, one more thing we should talk about before we get off of the streaming
Speaker 6:  stuff, which is some interesting Podcasty news.
Speaker 6:  This is a podcast after all the big
Speaker 6:  podcast news of this week, I would say
Speaker 6:  is that Alex Cooper, who hosts call her Daddy
Speaker 6:  and I think is probably like the second biggest name on Spotify
Speaker 6:  after Joe Rogan, just in terms of like people who got
Speaker 6:  giant whatever, eight figure deals to go be on Spotify
Speaker 6:  exclusively is leaving Spotify and going to SiriusXM
Speaker 6:  signed a huge deal for like a hundred million dollars.
Speaker 6:  Super big deal. And just strikes me as very interesting because
Speaker 6:  I'm sorry it was $125 million.
Speaker 8:  So much money.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I just think it's fascinating because Sirius also
Speaker 6:  just recently, I believe it was Smartless that made a huge deal with Sirius.
Speaker 6:  So we're in this weird moment where like the podcast business is kind of
Speaker 6:  retrenching and there was this huge boom and then it all sort of pulled
Speaker 6:  back. But then like Sirius in particular is out here just writing gigantic
Speaker 6:  checks.
Speaker 8:  No, this makes sense. Sirius is always like 10 years late to the game
Speaker 8:  if,
Speaker 13:  If she were a radio host and she had hit one big deal and probably
Speaker 13:  wasn't going to hit a big deal again at that network and then went to Sirius
Speaker 13:  for a lot of money and probably none of us ever listening to her
Speaker 13:  on serious ever again. Yeah, you wouldn't even think about this. You would
Speaker 13:  just say, oh yeah, that's, that's obviously what happened. This is
Speaker 8:  The Howard
Speaker 6:  Stern Did she did a Howard Stern is what you're saying?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, yeah. It's the Howard Stern. Okay. I hope she enjoys having her 12
Speaker 8:  listeners, all of whom are in their car. 'cause they forgot to
Speaker 8:  cancel the subscription in their car. Okay. So
Speaker 6:  This is part of the reason I actually brought this up. 'cause I think Howard
Speaker 6:  Stern deal in a certain way made sense. A, it's like he's a big name,
Speaker 6:  he's a big brand. And also I think the like demographic,
Speaker 6:  especially age-wise of people who love Howard Stern and people who spend
Speaker 6:  a lot of time in their car listening to satellite radio is pretty solid.
Speaker 6:  This one seems strange to me because
Speaker 6:  Alex Cooper is much younger. The call her daddy audience is presumably much
Speaker 6:  younger. It's just a completely different generation. Like one of the reasons
Speaker 6:  there was a great, I think it was Wall Street Journal story right before
Speaker 6:  the Olympics about Alex Cooper as like the Gen Z
Speaker 6:  whisperer and like, do Gen Z people
Speaker 6:  know what SiriusXM is? Well
Speaker 8:  They're gonna have to, if they're gonna follow her. I mean that's probably,
Speaker 13:  People will still be available on other pod podcast platforms.
Speaker 6:  So they're just spending all this money to sell ads for call her daddy
Speaker 13:  I guess, which is fine. You know, if You can make the money work, then fine.
Speaker 6:  That just seems like a ton of money if that's your play. But what do I
Speaker 6:  know? Maybe, maybe it'll work.
Speaker 8:  You get three months for a dollar.
Speaker 6:  I just like, we're in this moment now where it's like serious and iHeart,
Speaker 6:  which are like two huge radio players are the only ones left spending money
Speaker 6:  on podcasts. And I don't know if that is like a sign of things to come of
Speaker 6:  consolidation or if it's, they're just the only ones dumb enough
Speaker 6:  to I would say
Speaker 8:  Keep writing these pictures. I would say, I would say it's, it's a sign of
Speaker 8:  consolidation. I think the, the these two companies have managed to persist
Speaker 8:  iHeart Radio with like an enormous monopoly on broadcast radio in
Speaker 8:  the United States. Yeah. It's like they, they just wanna try to
Speaker 8:  stay alive as long as possible
Speaker 6:  And you'll, they'll just write giant checks until there are no more giant
Speaker 6:  checks to
Speaker 8:  Write. Yeah. Until, until the giant check account is closed.
Speaker 6:  I mean listen Alex Cooper get
Speaker 8:  That money. Get your bag. Yeah. Get the bag. Absolutely. Go for it. I love
Speaker 8:  this for her.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Alright, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back, do a
Speaker 6:  lightning round. We'll be right back.
Speaker 13:  interesting accounting based on the idea that if you used Alexa and bought
Speaker 13:  Echo hardware, you would buy more stuff from Amazon. And that is not what
Speaker 13:  people do. They just used Alexa to turn off their lights and stuff and set
Speaker 13:  reminders and the kids ask it questions, they, they don't
Speaker 13:  buy more stuff.
Speaker 8:  One time a roommate of mine bought I would say like $40 worth
Speaker 8:  of Cadbury eggs and then a hundred dollars of laundry
Speaker 8:  detergent on my Alexa. And then I was like, why did you
Speaker 8:  buy that? And she's like, I just wanted to see. And then we stopped using
Speaker 8:  it ever for buying things because that was so many Cadbury eggs
Speaker 8:  and overpriced detergent.
Speaker 6:  That's a pretty funny bit to pull at somebody's house actually, to just walk
Speaker 6:  in and just start yelling at the speaker to buy stuff and just see how far
Speaker 6:  You can get. Little
Speaker 8:  Kids do it all the time. They're like, buy me a, buy me a fire tablet. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And you're like, no, shut up.
Speaker 6:  Leave
Speaker 8:  It alone. It's not for you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. This is one of those things that I feel like is just
Speaker 6:  like a, a failure on all sides. 'cause Richard, you're right that, like for
Speaker 6:  Amazon, I'm sure they lost money on every single one of these things that
Speaker 6:  they sold, which is why Amazon doesn't want to just sell these things as
Speaker 6:  a photo frame And. if you were to say Amazon, why not sell it for more
Speaker 6:  money so that You can make money on it as a photo frame? Some accountant
Speaker 6:  within Amazon would tell you that that's not how business works. Yeah, I'm
Speaker 6:  not an accountant, what do I know? But, but then to do something
Speaker 6:  like this, presumably for a teeny tiny number of people, this is a thing
Speaker 6:  I've just never understood about large companies, like Google does this worse
Speaker 6:  than anybody. They're like, we have a thing with not as many users that isn't
Speaker 6:  making us as much money as we hoped. It costs us absolutely nothing to
Speaker 6:  run, so we're gonna cancel it. It's like, why? What are we
Speaker 6:  accomplishing here? It was like when every when the, they took the
Speaker 6:  MTV news archive offline, it's like, I'm pretty sure You can afford to keep
Speaker 6:  MTV news.com online. Like I think it's fine. Maybe
Speaker 8:  It's like a tax write off. Do you get a tax write off if you just remove
Speaker 8:  a feature? Like, like do they get a tax write off for
Speaker 6:  That? They're like, no, we did a bad job on that one. Yeah. Like,
Speaker 8:  Like, like Hollywood is always like, nevermind, we're not gonna release this
Speaker 8:  movie and we're gonna put it in a vault forever. Gimme money
Speaker 8:  IRS and like Amazon just don't
Speaker 13:  Gimme money. I mean that's the thing at Google is that the reason why a
Speaker 13:  lot of these products have canceled is because they can't find anyone to
Speaker 13:  run them. Because if you're not running a project that's growing or going
Speaker 13:  somewhere, then you aren't going to get that next promotion, et cetera,
Speaker 13:  et cetera, et cetera. Yeah. It's probably a similar thing within Amazon.
Speaker 13:  It's like, okay, so, so who wants to weekly check in and make sure that
Speaker 13:  the, the photo subscription is still working? Nobody.
Speaker 13:  Okay. Canceling. I,
Speaker 6:  I guess, I don't know, open source it like get, get the user
Speaker 6:  to do it. Like
Speaker 8:  Richard's just like they're, you check
Speaker 6:  This box once a week. Like, I don't know. And I get that I'm asking for something
Speaker 6:  that's never gonna happen, but it just always feels so silly to me when companies
Speaker 6:  do this. It's such an own goal of customer
Speaker 6:  relations and making people trust you as a company in the name of
Speaker 6:  saving one person, one meeting a quarter. Well
Speaker 13:  You think it's unreasonable that they spend a trillion dollars on new AI
Speaker 13:  chips, but they can't spend $100 to keep this running.
Speaker 6:  Exactly. What if you just put one of those chips onto keeping all
Speaker 6:  of those customers happy and then if you don't wanna have this problem again,
Speaker 6:  I don't know, make better products. There's an idea for you.
Speaker 6:  Amazon Crans, what's yours
Speaker 8:  Not related to Amazon. Mine is JBL. You remember
Speaker 8:  last year they had the, the headphones that had a screen on them for the
Speaker 8:  case. Oh yeah, they did it again. But the the, the screen
Speaker 8:  got bigger. It's a much bigger screen. You can, like You can pause,
Speaker 8:  You can You can skip tracks.
Speaker 6:  I still cannot decide if this is the best idea ever or
Speaker 6:  a completely pointless use of technology. You've do more. I've never used
Speaker 6:  a pair of headphones like this. So I, I genuinely can't say, but I can't
Speaker 6:  decide.
Speaker 8:  I think you might be able to do more with this than You can do with G Gemini
Speaker 8:  because You can set alarms.
Speaker 8:  So I
Speaker 13:  Was gonna go the other way. I was gonna say this is like a book's poem,
Speaker 13:  but I had phone
Speaker 8:  Case. Yeah. But yeah, but You can you set alarms, you You can check text
Speaker 8:  messages. Basically if you didn't have an, some sort of
Speaker 8:  smartwatch, you just pull this outta your pocket instead of your, your phone.
Speaker 8:  That's probably likely gonna happen.
Speaker 6:  I right. Don't that's,
Speaker 13:  That's actually better. I I I kinda like that. Yeah. Like I don't need a
Speaker 13:  smartwatch all the time, but I'm going to be carrying my earbuds anyway.
Speaker 8:  They, they like, they just look neat. I don't know. I'm, I'm
Speaker 8:  one of those people where while I do feel we should have smart,
Speaker 8:  we should have small good smartphones. I also understand that people
Speaker 8:  love cheap screens and this is just cool. Like just
Speaker 8:  slap a screen on it. Let's go.
Speaker 6:  My thing is I want all of this, but I want it to be like
Speaker 6:  button controls that I can do just by like putting my hand in my
Speaker 6:  pocket. Ooh. Right. Like I want the, the controls that are on my headphones.
Speaker 6:  In a lot of cases, I also want those on the thing in my pocket.
Speaker 6:  So I can just reach in and like whack it twice to go to the next
Speaker 8:  Song's. Be like actual physical buttons.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like what if my AirPods case just had 12 buttons on it?
Speaker 8:  That'd be nice. And you just sounds amazing. Then people are like, why, what
Speaker 8:  you fiddling within your pocket? It's David. It's basically
Speaker 6:  Just a little fidget spinner and I just, I'm just in there just clicking
Speaker 6:  around all day.
Speaker 8:  I'm always like flipping the case open and close and then I'm like, why don't
Speaker 8:  I have any battery? Oh, it's
Speaker 6:  Me. So one random thing. Have you, I always hate
Speaker 6:  asking people if they see anything on TikTok because the answer is no, because
Speaker 6:  everybody has a completely different TikTok experience. But for like two
Speaker 6:  weeks there was one guy Hawking, a pair
Speaker 6:  of Lenovo earbuds that also had a screen on the
Speaker 6:  case. That was like every fifth video I saw. Yes. On
Speaker 6:  TikTok. Do you know what I'm talking about?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I like, I I've since quit TikTok. I'm I'm, I'm away from
Speaker 8:  TikTok right now 'cause I was in Texas and I was getting a lot of political
Speaker 8:  location based stuff that I didn't wanna see. But yeah, I remember that guy.
Speaker 8:  He, he just was call. I was like, oh, should we call these in? He made
Speaker 6:  A very convincing case. He Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I was like, I should I buy these Lenovo, like Lenovo is
Speaker 8:  working on TikTok like you, that was the consistent thing.
Speaker 8:  It would always be like these weird lifestyle products from Lenovo and you're
Speaker 8:  like, I didn't know you sold like a flashlight with a Lenovo
Speaker 8:  brand on it. See? Co
Speaker 6:  See is this the same Lenovo, like Lenovo is definitely turning into
Speaker 6:  one of those companies that just kind of makes everything Yeah.
Speaker 8:  You're like Sure. Including weird ein laptops. Thank you Lenovo.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Hell yeah. Just keep doing that.
Speaker 13:  I I did not get that. The only thing I get on TikTok now is Cole Hacker
Speaker 13:  edits of himself.
Speaker 6:  That seems better. I think I, I prefer, prefer,
Speaker 8:  I like that.
Speaker 6:  One of the features I've always wanted from TikTok is like a walk a mile
Speaker 6:  in somebody else's shoes where like I should be able to scan a QR code and
Speaker 6:  just immediately get your, for you feed for an hour. I think that would be
Speaker 6:  so fun. And it's like, what a way to get to know somebody then to like
Speaker 6:  quickly And you have control over it. You have to share it with me. It's
Speaker 6:  like sharing your location with somebody. I'm like, I can share my feed with
Speaker 6:  you. I think that would be so fun.
Speaker 8:  Why is TikTok not doing that as a a speed dating app?
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. It's like on Hinge. But instead of having to
Speaker 6:  like answer asinine questions about yourself, you just are like, here's my
Speaker 6:  feed. Do you love me? Like
Speaker 8:  TikTok, this is how you're gonna make money because you don't make money.
Speaker 8:  This is, this is how TikTok will make money. Is is just doing this.
Speaker 8:  This is great. I love this dating apps.
Speaker 6:  That's a good idea. Yeah. Anyway, TikTok You can have that for free.
Speaker 6:  Sponsor the lightning round. What's
Speaker 8:  Speaking of Lightning? What's yours?
Speaker 6:  Mine is, I just wanna talk about the Sonos app again for a minute
Speaker 6:  because this, this whole Sonos app story
Speaker 6:  has gone from like ridiculous to
Speaker 6:  sad to just weird and confusing.
Speaker 6:  The most recent thing is that Sonos, which Chris
Speaker 6:  Welch scooped what last week, two weeks ago recently.
Speaker 6:  That the company was considering re-releasing
Speaker 6:  the app. Patrick Spence said in a Reddit a MA this
Speaker 6:  week that he was hopeful until very recently that Sonos could
Speaker 6:  just re-release the app. But then they found that
Speaker 6:  they couldn't and that the old app would just make everything worse.
Speaker 6:  And
Speaker 6:  This is so brutal for Sonos. Like
Speaker 6:  it's just, I mean lemme just read you more of the quote here. So he says
Speaker 6:  the trick of course, course is that Sonos is not just the mobile app, but
Speaker 6:  software that runs on your speakers. And in the cloud too. In the months
Speaker 6:  since the new mobile app launched, we've been updating the software that
Speaker 6:  runs on our speakers and in the cloud to the point where today S two is less
Speaker 6:  reliable and less stable than what you remember. Like what he, what
Speaker 6:  he's saying is, we broke everything so badly that we can't
Speaker 6:  even go back anymore. I just like,
Speaker 8:  I have so many questions. How does that, it's unreal. How does that
Speaker 8:  work? I mean the, the, the s two app was never very
Speaker 8:  good. This is part of the thing where I'm like, I think the current app is
Speaker 8:  getting a bit of a bad shake 'cause it's not very good. But the last one
Speaker 8:  was also bad and was constantly like disconnecting and forcing you to reset
Speaker 8:  your entire home.
Speaker 6:  The last one, like it's, it's a very funny Rorschach
Speaker 6:  test of like, do you want all the features but kind of bad or do you
Speaker 6:  want slightly better but no features,
Speaker 8:  Right?
Speaker 6:  It's like, well maybe Sonos you should have just done, they're both bad
Speaker 6:  to be clear. Not good outcomes, but it's just, it's
Speaker 6:  it's, this is just tough.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. This is, this is awful.
Speaker 13:  Awful. I just don't understand how they, they got to the point of having
Speaker 13:  an app that doesn't work and doesn't do what people want.
Speaker 6:  Right. Like IIII totally agree. And the fact
Speaker 6:  that Sonos has had to walk it so far back as to
Speaker 6:  basically acknowledge and I guess to some extent credit to
Speaker 6:  Patrick Spence for just saying out loud like, yeah, we screwed it up.
Speaker 6:  Like they started by trying to do the, you know, change is hard thing. And
Speaker 6:  then they started by saying it took courage to do this. They actually use
Speaker 6:  the word courage, which PSA to CEOs. Don't use the word courage
Speaker 6:  anymore. Just stop it. It doesn't help. It always backfires.
Speaker 6:  We will use it against you just don't do it anymore. And now
Speaker 6:  at least they have come all the way around and been like, yeah, we released
Speaker 6:  a crappy app. This sucks. We're sorry. But also
Speaker 6:  there's nothing we can do about it. Like, it's so bad.
Speaker 6:  I really, I feel for, I feel for Sonos. Oh and this is a not
Speaker 6:  a good moment to be doing this If you're Sonos.
Speaker 8:  They apparently, I didn't realize they, they got rid of their beta program
Speaker 8:  or they, they, they, they didn't make it as robust as it used to be.
Speaker 6:  I'm, there are a lot of things that went wrong in the process here, but ultimately,
Speaker 6:  like it should have been blindingly obvious that this thing wasn't ready.
Speaker 6:  And, and I and what, what Chris Welch has said on this show is that because
Speaker 6:  the headphones were coming and because there was such a rush to do that,
Speaker 6:  there was this sense like, like we have to do all of this at once. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And holy God did that backfire
Speaker 13:  All to launch these headphones that, did anyone ask for Sonos
Speaker 13:  headphones?
Speaker 6:  Have you, have you seen a pair in the wild? I was actually just wondering
Speaker 6:  about this the other day. I've seen, I have not heard one person even ask
Speaker 6:  about them since they came out.
Speaker 8:  Sonos was always like, it was a, it was a niche brand. I mean I I I have
Speaker 8:  a lot of Sonos speakers. It's always been a niche brand and it like
Speaker 8:  appetite to compete with the Apples of the world is like, don't, don't
Speaker 8:  do that. Yeah. They have so much more money than you. But
Speaker 6:  It's, it's been a niche brand with like huge brand recognition.
Speaker 6:  Right? Like I know a lot, lot of people who would never own Sonos stuff but
Speaker 6:  kind of know what Sonos is.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. But I don't think it's like at the same stage as like Bose No. Like,
Speaker 8:  like definitely not. Like I I would say the only people who know who Sonos
Speaker 8:  is or that know what Sonos is are people who are fairly online and,
Speaker 8:  and so it's that kinda like really good online brand recognition. But
Speaker 13:  I think that even people who aren't online, they maybe didn't necessarily
Speaker 13:  know what Sonos was, but they could be convinced to buy it.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. Like you could walk into Best Buy and You can say, man, you know what,
Speaker 13:  I need some home. I need to hear music everywhere in my house. You would
Speaker 13:  say, you know, I got something for you. Yeah. What,
Speaker 6:  How much money. That's, I think, I think that's exactly right And I feel
Speaker 6:  like what Sonos has done here is totally torch that
Speaker 6:  reputation. Right. This sense of like, Sonos was always
Speaker 6:  too expensive but also the best. Right? Like tho those and, and You can
Speaker 6:  get people over too expensive in a lot of cases it it
Speaker 6:  is, it is just absolutely lighting on fire.
Speaker 6:  This reputation of it will do the thing that you want it to do exceptionally
Speaker 6:  well. 'cause it just doesn't anymore. Yeah. And like, and it, it,
Speaker 6:  the road to get back to that seems like it is pretty long at this point for
Speaker 8:  This. There're still excellent airplay. Two speakers.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Again, never, I couldn't even tell you if I have the Sonos app
Speaker 6:  on my phone. Yeah. And I use Sonos all the time and it still sounds great.
Speaker 6:  I still love the speakers.
Speaker 6:  Lord knows I'll not be updating that system anytime soon.
Speaker 8:  I, I stopped using the app years ago because it, like, it forced me to reset
Speaker 8:  my entire system one too many times. And once I got it working with my
Speaker 8:  audio or with my tv, I was like, okay, I never touched this again. It's,
Speaker 8:  they're now airplay speakers. Yeah. Nobody tell me how I should
Speaker 8:  just get a receiver and a, and and big bookshelf speakers. I know
Speaker 8:  it's expensive. I already spent the money shut up.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. If you, I wonder if we're gonna get to the point where like if you
Speaker 6:  have a phone and a sono system that is like all still running the old
Speaker 6:  software 'cause you never updated, that's gonna become like a thing You can
Speaker 6:  sell on eBay for way more money. Yes. Because it's the thing that still works.
Speaker 8:  I hope that, I hope that happens so
Speaker 6:  Much.
Speaker 13:  Don't sell on eBay. You, you get in a Vanta and you pull up on somebody
Speaker 13:  and you say, Hey man, we've got all these Sonos speakers that fell off a
Speaker 13:  truck and you sell them. I gotta
Speaker 6:  Work in Sonos. You interested?
Speaker 8:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  That's good. All right. Very good. We're cementing businesses here on The.
Speaker 6:  Vergecast. That's what we do. I,
Speaker 8:  I mean, yeah.
Speaker 6:  All right. We have gone way over as we are want to do, we should get outta
Speaker 6:  here. Thank you both for doing this. Tons of good stuff on the site this
Speaker 6:  week. Becca Versace's final video for The Verge, which is very sad about.
Speaker 6:  I Justine just went up today, Thursday as we're recording this. It's very
Speaker 6:  good. We have a bunch of stuff on the pixels, a bunch of stuff on ai,
Speaker 6:  photo chaos, all the streaming news we've been talking about.
Speaker 6:  If you missed our whole hydrogen series both on the Tuesday
Speaker 6:  Vergecast and the the Lost Highway stuff we did on the site, that was great.
Speaker 6:  Tons of good stuff on The Verge. It's like the end of August and it still
Speaker 6:  feels like tons