# Transcript
ID: 03bfc60b-0101-445c-8e44-363ea1443cde
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/2914124582103806465/-7065658135529835/s93290-US-6292s-1728650709.mp3
Description: Nilay and David make some predictions about Thursday evening’s Tesla event — which you’ve already seen, but we haven’t! Then they talk about the week’s gadget news, from Nintendo’s new Alarmo alarm clock to Apple’s upcoming iPads and Macs. Then Lauren Feiner joins to talk about the latest on all fronts in Google’s antitrust fight, and how the government might be planning to break up the company altogether. Then it’s time for a lightning round about Google Docs tabs, FEMA misinformation, and Zoom AI avatars.
Speaker 2:  in the studio. This is my second studio. Time in the studio. But the first
Speaker 2:  time that you've been here when I've been in the studio. Well, the other
Speaker 2:  thing, you typically run away from me when I arrive in New York. You flee
Speaker 2:  upstate somewhere. Yeah, that's, that's my entire goal in life is to flee.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Flee to the woods. Later on the show, Lauren Finder's gonna join us.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna talk about Google, which has attracted the attention
Speaker 2:  of our nation's regulators. The, the white hot
Speaker 2:  attention, the nations court system, potentially like historic way. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And it's like going, it's, I would say it's not making a blip.
Speaker 2:  No. Like what if we break up Google and everyone's like, huh.
Speaker 2:  So Lauren's gonna explain why it's much more than a blip because there's
Speaker 2:  two different cases that are gonna result in major changes to how Google
Speaker 2:  works. And then we're gonna have lightning round and boy do we have a lot
Speaker 2:  of stuff in the lightning round, which remains, I would say. Unsponsored.
Speaker 2:  Also, there's at least one thing here is titled Microsoft Word. Final. Final
Speaker 2:  Google Remedy Framework.
Speaker 2:  Listen, that's how justice gets done in this country. You, I Final,
Speaker 2:  final two. Yeah. Alright, let's start with the news.
Speaker 2:  There's one piece of news that I really want to talk about the most important
Speaker 2:  news of the week, which is Nintendo be a a hundred dollars alarm clock. Yes.
Speaker 2:  We'll get to that. Then there's the news that has not happened yet
Speaker 2:  as we are recording, but by the time you listen to this
Speaker 2:  will have occurred. And by occurred, I mean
Speaker 2:  people will make you promises that will not come true. And
Speaker 2:  specifically what I mean is Tesla's gonna have its robax event. It's long
Speaker 2:  awaited once delayed, twice delayed,
Speaker 2:  I mean delayed since 2016. Fair. Yeah. Delayed
Speaker 2:  several times at this point. But yeah, they've been promising this
Speaker 2:  Elon Musk, not they fair. Elon in particular has been promising
Speaker 2:  this for like a long, long, long time. and it
Speaker 2:  was supposed to happen what in August and then that got
Speaker 2:  delayed and now it it between when we record and when you hear
Speaker 2:  this, it is supposedly going to happen. Yeah. I think it's like 10:00 PM
Speaker 2:  at night on the east coast for us. It's happening on a movie studio lot in
Speaker 2:  California and they're gonna unveil what looks like a
Speaker 2:  two-seater car with like Lambo doors. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I mean it seems, it seems like it's going to be a Tesla.
Speaker 2:  I don't know what I was expecting. Part of me was like, you know, if the
Speaker 2:  robot taxi is gonna be the thing, maybe they're gonna take this huge swing.
Speaker 2:  And we've seen all these concepts that are like, what if we completely reinvent
Speaker 2:  the whole idea of what it means to be in a car? And instead of everybody
Speaker 2:  facing forward, it's just gonna be like lounges inside that everybody hangs
Speaker 2:  out in. And I, it looks an awful lot. Like they're just gonna be like, here's
Speaker 2:  a car. Well, it's a weird looking car. It's like, there was a picture of
Speaker 2:  it in the Elon Musk biography by Walter Isaacson. It's just,
Speaker 2:  it looks like a, like a tricycle car, like a backwards, like a three wheel
Speaker 2:  car, two wheels in front, one wheel in the back, two seats, and then doors
Speaker 2:  that kind of open up into the side.
Speaker 2:  Sure. Yeah. I think the car is the least important part of this.
Speaker 2:  I think in classic Tesla fashion, we're all
Speaker 2:  gonna look at the weird car idea and no one will look at the
Speaker 2:  underlying does it work idea? Right. Well, and this has
Speaker 2:  kind of been Tesla's thing for a long time. Like I think, I don't remember
Speaker 2:  if this was the last time we talked about Tesla, but not that long ago. We
Speaker 2:  talked about Tesla and I got very upset about the door handles on a Tesla.
Speaker 2:  A lot of people got very angry at me for thinking the door handles on a Tesla
Speaker 2:  are stupid. They are stupid. And I was right. And
Speaker 2:  I think one of the strange things that Tesla has been doing for
Speaker 2:  a long time now is trying to like reinvent all the things about cars
Speaker 2:  that we mostly figured out a while ago. Like the cyber truck is just a lot
Speaker 2:  of new ideas about things that we've already solved. And
Speaker 2:  to your point so far, not doing, ultimately the only thing that matters
Speaker 2:  both to Tesla and ostensibly to Elon Musk, which is solving
Speaker 2:  self-driving like that has been the thing for so long
Speaker 2:  that you could kind of argue everything else has been just a diversion along
Speaker 2:  the way towards making self-driving actually work. Yeah. Like that
Speaker 2:  is the thing. So Andy Hawkins wrote us, I would say
Speaker 2:  somewhere between a timeline and a primal scream. Yeah, that's about
Speaker 2:  right. Like If, you can organize a primal scream in
Speaker 2:  chronological order that is Andy's piece,
Speaker 2:  which by the way, was immediately brigade by people who started their commenting
Speaker 2:  accounts that day to tell us, If, you were hand at Yohan. What's a tell guys?
Speaker 2:  You gotta start the bot accounts and lie 'em and wait. Yeah. Play a long
Speaker 2:  game here people. And what you should do in the meantime is be a thoughtful
Speaker 2:  and constructive VERGE commenter so that when it's time to strike,
Speaker 2:  we're not expecting, you don't start your account that day and be like, I'm
Speaker 2:  never reading The Verge again. We, we just, we're gonna Yeah. That's like
Speaker 2:  a 2016 strategy. Like we've come a long way. Yeah. You gotta again, thoughtful,
Speaker 2:  constructive commenter for years and then you strike.
Speaker 2:  Think about that. Yeah. All right. So Andy wrote a timeline, and
Speaker 2:  I'm just gonna read you the first paragraph. In 2016, Elon Musk had Tesla
Speaker 2:  self-driving cars were two years away in 27. In 2017 it was quote
Speaker 2:  six months. Definitely. And customers were able to sleep in their
Speaker 2:  Teslas while driving in two years. In 2018, Elon Musk said it was
Speaker 2:  quote a year away and would be 200% safer than human driving in
Speaker 2:  2019. He said there would be feature complete full self-driving
Speaker 2:  this year. That's 2019. He still
Speaker 2:  talked about it. He's renamed full self-driving to full self-driving
Speaker 2:  parentheses supervised, which is so funny. Full self-driving
Speaker 2:  narrator voice, not full self-driving. and it, it, it doesn't
Speaker 2:  work like If, you use full self-driving in a model three today, say you
Speaker 2:  are the chances that you will have to grab the wheel in anything but a highway
Speaker 2:  environment are, are basically guaranteed. Yeah. That's just how it goes.
Speaker 2:  And the accidents that it gets into or the mistakes that that system makes
Speaker 2:  are funny if you're watching them on a YouTube video and I think not so funny
Speaker 2:  if you're in the car. Yeah. Agreed. Meanwhile, and to be clear, a lot of
Speaker 2:  these things that are happening with self-driving cars are not limited to
Speaker 2:  Tesla. Like, it's just that Tesla gets so much more
Speaker 2:  crap for it because Tesla is the one most confidently saying it has solved
Speaker 2:  the problem. Like Waymo is not out here being like, we did it. We're
Speaker 2:  finished. The job is done. Yeah. years ago, I would say
Speaker 2:  10 years ago, Waymo was just as ambitious as Tesla was and then
Speaker 2:  pretty quickly started to rewind and be like, actually we've realized this
Speaker 2:  is a much longer like asymptotic problem than we realized
Speaker 2:  where we're gonna get really good. And then the last 1% of this is going
Speaker 2:  to go from like a two year problem to maybe like a two decade problem. And
Speaker 2:  to your point, Waymo had no aspirations of reinventing the car.
Speaker 2:  Right. They're like, their early ones are like, you know what, it's a Chrysler
Speaker 2:  Pacifica. Yeah. A car, like car What? When you
Speaker 2:  imagine a car that can hold six people Chrysler, Pacifica. And then I
Speaker 2:  think later on they're like, okay, it's some Jaguar F type. Yes. And now
Speaker 2:  they only operate in San Francisco, Phoenix, Los Angeles, and Austin, notably
Speaker 2:  cities with good weather and except for San Francisco pretty flat.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And so pretty easy terrain for the most, they, they have just like
Speaker 2:  radically constricted their effort, right? Can we make a
Speaker 2:  Chrysler Pacifica turn left? And that took them I think three years can,
Speaker 2:  can this thing make a left turn at a busy intersection? and it, the answer
Speaker 2:  for a long time was maybe, and they just diligently solved that
Speaker 2:  problem. Now you can get Waymo in all those cities and it's fine. People
Speaker 2:  really like them. People actually prefer them. They're paying a premium to
Speaker 2:  ride our own in way modes. Well, and again, like I, I think I, I keep
Speaker 2:  coming back to like, everybody drags us for dragging Tesla.
Speaker 2:  And I think at this particular moment, the thing that has changed is If,
Speaker 2:  you rewind back to 2016 when, when Elon and everybody else was saying
Speaker 2:  that stuff, everybody was saying that stuff, right? Like there was this industry
Speaker 2:  wide belief that by 2020 we were all gonna be riding around in rot taxis.
Speaker 2:  Uber was making that bet. Lyft was making that bet. Car companies were making
Speaker 2:  that bet. And then pretty quickly over the next
Speaker 2:  couple of years, a as the money for
Speaker 2:  saying that started to dry up and b, as the
Speaker 2:  realities of like the world and the regulatory state and people being
Speaker 2:  dumb at driving started to appear, everybody else
Speaker 2:  started to slow down. and it was like, okay, this is the thing we have to
Speaker 2:  do thoughtfully and methodically. and it, it caused them
Speaker 2:  trouble. Like there are people out there who are like, Google needs to shut
Speaker 2:  down Waymo, it's a waste of money. Why on earth are they still at this?
Speaker 2:  But they've all started to push more
Speaker 2:  carefully with some exceptions. I think like Cruz got out over at skis in
Speaker 2:  some ways and like there have been issues, but in huge ways. Yeah. But like
Speaker 2:  for the most part, a lot of these companies were at least starting to recognize
Speaker 2:  like, okay, this is a bigger problem than we thought. Let's try to be more
Speaker 2:  thoughtful. Elon Musk is the only one who has continued to come out and tell
Speaker 2:  us that it's going to be any minute now and calling things full
Speaker 2:  self-driving and like, and it's, we've just gotten to the point where it's
Speaker 2:  like he's just been either wrong or lying
Speaker 2:  so many times in a row now that on this particular thing he has
Speaker 2:  just lost all benefit of the doubt Yeah. To talk about any of this stuff.
Speaker 2:  And the really interesting dynamic in what you're describing is all these
Speaker 2:  companies are promising that they will do robotaxis. Well that was
Speaker 2:  2016 ish. The height of zero interest rate
Speaker 2:  Exactly. VC funding into everything. And the whole plan was, we'll
Speaker 2:  flood these markets with VC dollars, we will take them over, we
Speaker 2:  will just predatorily price everybody else out. Right. We'll kill public
Speaker 2:  transportation. We'll get all the taxis off the road and we'll make it stupid
Speaker 2:  for you to buy a car and then you'll have no choice but to use. And then,
Speaker 2:  then we'll raise the price on Uber. And by then we'll get, and Travis Kanick
Speaker 2:  said this on stage of code. He said, my problem is the other guy in the car,
Speaker 2:  I gotta get rid of the other guy in the car. Right. The driver and then the
Speaker 2:  robot can drive the car and then I will make more money. And
Speaker 2:  he said this with, I was in the room and he said this with such pride on
Speaker 2:  his face to Kara Swisher. And everyone else was like, what about
Speaker 2:  the guys? Right? Like the guys in the car and it was like huge
Speaker 2:  protests, you know, like walk it back. But what they were all chasing is
Speaker 2:  software style margins in hardware. Right. So we, we have
Speaker 2:  this one car, we're just gonna run it 24 7, it's gonna produce money while
Speaker 2:  it lasts and then we'll throw it away and we'll we'll make a new car. And
Speaker 2:  they, no one has gotten there. No. Like Waymo's are still very expensive,
Speaker 2:  except if you're listening to this maybe Tesla, maybe they didn't. Right.
Speaker 2:  And, and then along the way there's been these like enabling technology fights,
Speaker 2:  right? Should we have lidar? Can we do it all with vision? Can we do it with
Speaker 2:  just a handful of like half a megapixel video cameras on the sides of Teslas?
Speaker 2:  No, we should probably upgrade those cameras. Like all of these little fights
Speaker 2:  along the way. And really what you have is Waymo with the full lidar sensor
Speaker 2:  suite. You have a handful of other companies that are also
Speaker 2:  trying lidar stuff but haven't shipped anything. And then
Speaker 2:  whatever happened between the time we are talking and the time you're listening,
Speaker 2:  and I am just guessing that it's nothing.
Speaker 2:  Wait, okay. Let's, this is fun. Let's do this. So this is the rare time when
Speaker 2:  we don't know the answers to something, but everyone listening to this is
Speaker 2:  going to know like you're, you're at the part of the murder mystery where
Speaker 2:  the audience has seen the murderer, but the people have not. It's a good
Speaker 2:  time. So let's do this. Let's, let's just make predictions about what's gonna
Speaker 2:  happen at this Tesla event. Yeah. And everyone who listens can tell us how
Speaker 2:  right or wrong we were, this is our only move, right. I feel
Speaker 2:  like we have to do this. All right. You, what's your first prediction? Okay.
Speaker 2:  My my first prediction is that there will
Speaker 2:  be a live demo and it won't work in some
Speaker 2:  meaningful way. It will not work. I'm thinking
Speaker 2:  about the person in the optimist robot costume
Speaker 2:  that counts as a demo. That didn't work. Throwing the ball at the cyber truck
Speaker 2:  window. That's a thing that didn't work. I think there is going to be
Speaker 2:  some way in which this thing tries to move itself. And it's not,
Speaker 2:  it's not gonna work in, in some defensible but
Speaker 2:  fairly problematic way. Can, can I make a sub prediction
Speaker 2:  please? I think there will be a live demo and it will work and it will be
Speaker 2:  later revealed that the car was just being remote controlled off stage.
Speaker 2:  The, the, the Nicola truck rolling down the hill. Yeah. Yeah. Kind of vibes.
Speaker 2:  Okay. That's, that's my, that's my sub prediction. There literally was a
Speaker 2:  person in the trunk. Yeah. There's a guy with an RC controller, you know,
Speaker 2:  just doing it. I would be shocked. And we, we'll see it is true that Tesla
Speaker 2:  cars can do summon in a parking lot. They can operate.
Speaker 2:  But I think, but so this is the thing, right? This is the reason I think
Speaker 2:  this, because if you're going to show off what it can do, you have to do
Speaker 2:  something more than that. Because that basic stuff, they're, they're good
Speaker 2:  at and they've been good at for a long time. So if you're gonna show we made
Speaker 2:  a robo taxii, then I think they're gonna show a robo taxii
Speaker 2:  and they're gonna show it driving around a parking lot and then let everybody,
Speaker 2:  let all the fanboy imaginations go wild.
Speaker 2:  See what I'm saying? Yeah. I don't think So I think it like hits a cone
Speaker 2:  in the parking lot. Alright, that's your prediction's. Like, oh, it's just
Speaker 2:  a cone. My prediction, no matter what,
Speaker 2:  he will not announce an arrival date before 2027. That's
Speaker 2:  two years. That's essentially two years. Okay. First of all, wild that that's
Speaker 2:  only two years. Second of all sub question,
Speaker 2:  if I'm giving you the over under on July 1st, 2027 for when this
Speaker 2:  actually ships, are you taking the over the under over way, way over. Okay.
Speaker 2:  And that, and that's what I'm, what I'm pinning that to is it took
Speaker 2:  how long to ship the cyber truck, he's gotta make a whole new car. Right?
Speaker 2:  He's gotta make this little taxi that's gonna distract everybody from whether
Speaker 2:  or not it can actually drive itself. And they're not great at that
Speaker 2:  right now. Okay. All right. So 2027 is your, is your prediction?
Speaker 2:  That's my prediction. Are we, are we saying after 27 or are you just calling
Speaker 2:  your shot? It's 2027 is the, I'm saying the announced date. Yeah, not the
Speaker 2:  act I'm not taking any No, but I mean the one he's gonna say he's gonna say
Speaker 2:  2027. Okay. All right. I love it. My second
Speaker 2:  one, and this is, this is only half formed because I haven't all the way
Speaker 2:  figured it out. I think the optimist robot is going to be featured in this
Speaker 2:  product somehow. I don't, I don't. That's the guy in the trunk. It's the
Speaker 2:  guy.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The back of open it up. It's, it's, it's full self-driving.
Speaker 2:  But then if, if it all goes wrong, something just springs out of the truck
Speaker 2:  in through the sunroof and starts driving, there is a debate slash rumor
Speaker 2:  that they have to certify level five
Speaker 2:  self-driving without a steering wheel to pull this off. And
Speaker 2:  that is really hard. So the, the rumor slash debate
Speaker 2:  is, will there be like a steering wheel that pops up when you need intervention?
Speaker 2:  So it's still a level three or level four because you can't,
Speaker 2:  you can't not have a steering wheel. You pull a brick record in the steering
Speaker 2:  wheel at the others. Yeah, that's, I'm just saying that's like, I've heard
Speaker 2:  this debate like, will it have a steering wheel? 'cause a picture we've seen
Speaker 2:  from the Isaacson book has no steering wheel. Right. But if you're gonna
Speaker 2:  have no steering wheel, that means you have now launched level five autonomy,
Speaker 2:  which means a bunch of people get to decide if that thing is safe.
Speaker 2:  Or you can have something less than that. And like a steering
Speaker 2:  wheel appears, or optimist is in the back being like
Speaker 2:  something I, I honestly would believe
Speaker 2:  Elon Musk being like, and the beauty of this is because there's an optimist
Speaker 2:  robot in the driver's seat. You always get to be in HOV lanes so you can
Speaker 2:  go even faster. Oh, that's good. Like I could, it's just sitting right there.
Speaker 2:  I could see it. So, I think, I think If, you get one of these,
Speaker 2:  you will get, there will be an optimist robot involved somehow. I haven't
Speaker 2:  figured it all the way out, but it's just, that is a, that is a prediction.
Speaker 2:  It's just in there somewhere. It's just somewhere in there is hand wavy optimist.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. What's yours? Is it a guy in a suit optimist or an actual optimist?
Speaker 2:  No, it's an actual optimist. Okay. That's pushes way out past 27 in
Speaker 2:  my mind. I'm not saying any of this is gonna ship. To be clear,
Speaker 2:  none of this is predicated on actually shipping. Okay. My third prediction,
Speaker 2:  I think is the one that will cause the most consternation.
Speaker 2:  So for years, Tesla's evaluation in the stock market and with a bunch of
Speaker 2:  Tesla fans has been predicated on the idea
Speaker 2:  that the model threes and Ys sitting in driveways around the world and
Speaker 2:  country will suddenly turn into the robotaxis fleet.
Speaker 2:  This is the promise. Yeah. People have bought these cars expecting that
Speaker 2:  they'll go to bed and their model threes will wander the streets
Speaker 2:  being taxis making them money. Right. And that is, that is
Speaker 2:  the multiplier of the stock price.
Speaker 2:  I am saying they're gonna have this launch event and they will say existing
Speaker 2:  Teslas will not be robotaxis. No. No way. No
Speaker 2:  way. Why That would immediate, that is the worst possible,
Speaker 2:  like investor move Elon Musk could make. Oh, oh, I know. But it's the,
Speaker 2:  I think they, they're gonna have to come clean and be like, here's the cyber
Speaker 2:  taxi, here's our other weird triangle car that we've made.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's the future of the Roboto Taxii program. And a model three
Speaker 2:  from 2018 that we promised would turn into a taxi 2020.
Speaker 2:  I think this the, the, the height of this was around 2020. I only know this
Speaker 2:  because it was one of those like pandemic feelings that I had. Sure. Like
Speaker 2:  I've, I've been drunk for four days and Elna sing. All the cars are
Speaker 2:  taxis. Like whatever that swirl of feeling is
Speaker 2:  2020. Let's say people bought these cars in 2020, assuming they would turn
Speaker 2:  into taxis that run on Bitcoin or whatever they were doing in the middle
Speaker 2:  of the pandemic, obviously. And he's gonna have to show up and
Speaker 2:  say, and the robo taxii is only works
Speaker 2:  on our cyber triangle or whatever he is gonna call it.
Speaker 2:  Ah, I just don't buy it. I'm gonna make my prediction the opposite. Okay.
Speaker 2:  I think, I think he might be slightly hand wavy about it.
Speaker 2:  Like I I could imagine being like, this is the one, this is the future
Speaker 2:  also random sub prediction. Do you think this is gonna be a thing that regular
Speaker 2:  people can buy? No. No, no, no, no. Absolutely not.
Speaker 2:  Okay. The idea that you would buy a two seater cyber taxi
Speaker 2:  that you are like the landlord of, have you seen the cyber truck on the road?
Speaker 2:  Dude? Like yeah. People will buy that. But that's a status symbol. This is
Speaker 2:  a taxi cab,
Speaker 2:  but it's your personal taxi cab that you let other people. Are you telling
Speaker 2:  if I was like, Nila, do you wanna buy my yellow cab from me? You wouldn't
Speaker 2:  buy it.
Speaker 2:  I'm just saying the cyber truck is a status symbol. Sure. The
Speaker 2:  ridiculous status symbol. Yeah. What status it confers. We can debate Sure.
Speaker 2:  But Yeah. But this is literally meant to be a taxi. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So the idea is that you, a regular person would buy a taxi
Speaker 2:  and let it loose in the streets of your suburb at night. Oh. I don't know.
Speaker 2:  The, the frame of that is like, it's,
Speaker 2:  it's your own personal robot driver. Right. And then when it's not working
Speaker 2:  for you, it can go work for somebody else. That's, I don't see that pitch
Speaker 2:  as being all that different from what they've been saying about Teslas for
Speaker 2:  four years. But I I would be so shocked if he gets up and
Speaker 2:  he's like, oh, I bait and switched all you clowns the last four years. You
Speaker 2:  would be shocked if Elon Musk, would I be shocked if he did it? No. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Would I be shocked if he said that? Yeah. And I think my
Speaker 2:  guess would be there will be a lot of focus on this and some like
Speaker 2:  vague gesture toward it's coming
Speaker 2:  for all the Teslas exist today. Yeah. I, but I cannot imagine a world in
Speaker 2:  which they just cut bait because people would go nuts. Maybe not cut
Speaker 2:  bait, but they will hand wavy. But I I, my prediction
Speaker 2:  is that whatever robax program they announced today will not work on the
Speaker 2:  Teslas that exist on the road today. All right. I'm going with it. Will,
Speaker 2:  this is good. We're now, we're we're directing. That's it. And you let us
Speaker 2:  know, but maybe they won't address it directly, but it will be, I think it
Speaker 2:  will just, it'll be one of those things like becomes obvious. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You know, like you're, you're just like brushing away. They're like, oh,
Speaker 2:  this dinosaur sucks. Yeah. I think it's by the end of this event it'll be
Speaker 2:  obvious. I am just really looking forward to this being like 90 minutes of
Speaker 2:  optimist, robots driving around and my victory lap is going to be incredible.
Speaker 2:  I will say that in the lead up to the event, there's been some reporting
Speaker 2:  that basically all the Tesla executives are leaving.
Speaker 2:  So four Tesla executives, this is reported in Business Insider. Four Tesla
Speaker 2:  executives announced In the past week they were leaving or had already left.
Speaker 2:  Oh boy. Some had been there for nearly a decade. How high executive are we
Speaker 2:  talking company's chief information officers leaving after 12
Speaker 2:  years.
Speaker 2:  Director of public policy and business development announced on October one
Speaker 2:  that he was leaving on Sunday. The global vehicle automation and
Speaker 2:  safety policy lead also announced that he'd left Tesla.
Speaker 2:  Those are people who would be quite important to the idea
Speaker 2:  of like a global rollout of robo taxis. Yeah. You would think that public
Speaker 2:  policy guy who's running self-driving and, you know, information systems
Speaker 2:  and automation would, he would stuff matters. He would, this should be your
Speaker 2:  time to shine. Interesting. And then the former model S and model X program
Speaker 2:  manager also left, which is fine. Whatever the model.
Speaker 2:  He's like, you know, we're not making another model XI un I understand what's
Speaker 2:  happening here. We're we're just doing triangles now just doing cyber things.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. These are all people who are leaving right before
Speaker 2:  presumably a giant increase in the stock price because you're gonna
Speaker 2:  unveil the robot taxi program, which is the valuation of the company. And
Speaker 2:  I really mean this. I we don't often talk about stock prices on The Vergecast,
Speaker 2:  but the entire story of Tesla right now is it's just another
Speaker 2:  car maker that is struggling to move cars. They just had a pretty good
Speaker 2:  quarter, but they are struggl they've been struggling to move cars. There's
Speaker 2:  a lot of competition coming for them. Hyundai will just be like, it's a hundred
Speaker 2:  dollars a month here, take an ionic five, get it outta my face. So there's
Speaker 2:  just competition coming from all corners. And the stock price
Speaker 2:  has just been based on the idea that it's a tech company
Speaker 2:  and a tech company valuation is we're gonna run a robo
Speaker 2:  taxii program. Right. There isn't another one. And this is in
Speaker 2:  a, in a pretty real way, like the tech company launch of
Speaker 2:  Tesla. Yeah. We should probably stop talking about this. 'cause now everything
Speaker 2:  we've said is now woefully out of date already. I see. We should move on.
Speaker 2:  But I'm just saying that it the That's the stakes. Those are the stakes.
Speaker 2:  I totally, and we, we'll pick it up again next Friday. We'll have Andy come
Speaker 2:  on. Yeah. And tell us what actually happened. But those are our predictions.
Speaker 2:  Let us know. If, you got 'em right or wrong. Optimist. Robots in the trunk.
Speaker 2:  All right. Now onto something that is extremely real. Like the
Speaker 2:  most real. We already, Chris Welch already went out and bought one reel.
Speaker 2:  Nintendo made it a hundred dollars alarm clock called Alarm O It's fantastic.
Speaker 2:  First of all, all alarm clocks should have names from now on If. you make
Speaker 2:  a, like Cassio made one this week that's like a blown up
Speaker 2:  version of one of its watches. Looks very cool. Only available in Japan.
Speaker 2:  Its name is like 16 Hexa decimal things.
Speaker 2:  No, I'm done with that. If your product doesn't have a cool name anymore,
Speaker 2:  get outta my face alarm mow or nothing. I
Speaker 2:  I love this thing and I do not for one second, understand why it exists.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's right. It's, it's just,
Speaker 2:  it's just an alarm clock. Like it's not even well has some sleep tracking
Speaker 2:  in it. You can download some detection, sleep tracking, which like an app
Speaker 2:  on your phone that you can do. Like, that's not that it's fine, but it's
Speaker 2:  not anything particularly exciting. But it, it's a, it's adorable as all
Speaker 2:  hell. It's got a screen. It does the like Nintendo fonts. It'll like
Speaker 2:  yell at you in very cute ways when you need to get outta bed. It has some
Speaker 2:  fun sounds that'll make, like, this thing is very charming and I want one
Speaker 2:  and I I will get one I'm sure. But like, what,
Speaker 2:  what was it like a week ago that there was a, it came through the FCC that
Speaker 2:  Nintendo Nintendo was doing some new hardware device and everybody got all
Speaker 2:  excited and they were like, is this the next switch? What's Nintendo doing?
Speaker 2:  It could be anything. and it,
Speaker 2:  I will say the the, there's a thing on the top that
Speaker 2:  looks like a bell and it's a dial that lights up so revolutionary and it
Speaker 2:  device,
Speaker 2:  the fact that that is not the snooze button is a huge miss. Wait, is it not?
Speaker 2:  I literally assumes news button. It's SNOO button. What is it? The SNOO is
Speaker 2:  automatic to you. It ha because it has motion detection in
Speaker 2:  it. You can snooze it by just like waving your hand at it. Oh, I do
Speaker 2:  like that. And Then it when you get out of bed, it stops the alarm clock.
Speaker 2:  So like the motion you do when you're trying to like find your phone to shut
Speaker 2:  it up. Yeah. That will shut it up. So again, I like that So I have plugged
Speaker 2:  this app on the show so many times. The alarm clock I use,
Speaker 2:  it's called Sleep cycle and the snooze button is a motion detector on the
Speaker 2:  phone. So you can just smack the table and make the phone bounce and it'll
Speaker 2:  snooze. That's cool. Oh, or If, you are particularly lazy. You can
Speaker 2:  grab the USB BBC cord that is charging your iPhone and just give that
Speaker 2:  a wave and just go B boop that snooze it. All right. And this all works.
Speaker 2:  But the idea that the alarm o that the dial on top of the LAO is not a
Speaker 2:  classic bash it snooze button, but is instead a dial that lights up.
Speaker 2:  I think this product is doomed because of it. That's my hot What it,
Speaker 2:  what it should be is like one of the, the money bricks from a
Speaker 2:  Mario game. That's And you should, that's good. You should be able to hit
Speaker 2:  it. You, you bounce on it and stuff comes out. Yeah. That's, that's what
Speaker 2:  I want from this. Why the only rea the only reason I really wanted to talk
Speaker 2:  about this is because I came up as a gadget
Speaker 2:  writer in the time of a device called the Chumby.
Speaker 2:  Oh. Some of our listen don't do that to Alarm o some of our people will remember
Speaker 2:  the Chumby. This is just a weird closed source proprietary chumby. I'm telling
Speaker 2:  you right now. That's what it, what it is. It's alarm clock with a screen
Speaker 2:  has a weird little app story download stuff that you can put on it.
Speaker 2:  It has high-minded ideas about motion controls. The Chumby was a alarm clock
Speaker 2:  that ran Linux. It was endless story as successful
Speaker 2:  as you could imagine that sense to be. Some people still have Humes, they're
Speaker 2:  still running them out in the world. But the idea that you would have a connected
Speaker 2:  device in your kitchen or by your bedside in 2006
Speaker 2:  revolutionary. Yeah. And that was, I was like, I grew up being
Speaker 2:  like, I have to write about this every day. Chumby also were in
Speaker 2:  a certain way very charming in a way that then like died with the
Speaker 2:  Alexa generation of Yeah. You know, cans of tennis
Speaker 2:  balls. So like kudos to bring it back. One other thing
Speaker 2:  that this has in common with Chumby is that the screen is way worse than
Speaker 2:  you think. Yep. and it looks like it, it, it's a round little
Speaker 2:  face, but it's a square screen inside of said round little face. And
Speaker 2:  it's just a lie. Like the screen, the screen's a lie and that's fine.
Speaker 2:  And I'm okay with it. It's $99.
Speaker 2:  I still don't understand why it exists. Why does this exist? Like if you're,
Speaker 2:  if you're running Nintendo, why do you make
Speaker 2:  this Just 'cause you can and you're a Nintendo. Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 2:  I think fundamentally Nintendo does cute stuff and they're like, we can
Speaker 2:  put Mario by your bedside and people will pay us $100
Speaker 2:  for that service. I mean that's Yeah. When you put it like that. But
Speaker 2:  Nintendo is so weird because it's like if If, you take
Speaker 2:  the cynical, not even cynical, but the sort of ruthless read of that that
Speaker 2:  is like, we want to be everywhere that you are and be like
Speaker 2:  a lifestyle business. Ambient Nintendo.
Speaker 2:  There's a million things they would've done by now, right? Like yeah.
Speaker 2:  Nintendo could have made smart everything for your whole house for the
Speaker 2:  last decade and people would've eaten. No, that would require technological
Speaker 2:  innovation. This is much more like we have a box of motion sensors
Speaker 2:  and we're gonna put them in alarm clock. Like what is it? What
Speaker 2:  can we do? Switch outcast with a 12-year-old arm chip. And it's like,
Speaker 2:  well we can make a switch alarm clock. That's about the only other thing
Speaker 2:  you can do. They just took apart a bunch of DSS and then put them back together
Speaker 2:  into alarm clocks. As Kranz was saying on the show last week, the switch
Speaker 2:  two, it feels like the switch emulators can already run switch
Speaker 2:  two games. Right. Because Nintendo's cracking down on switch emulators. It
Speaker 2:  does not feel like Nintendo wants to be the bleeding edge of the curve. So
Speaker 2:  what can you do with a bunch of old hardware? It's an alarm clock. Fair enough.
Speaker 2:  They just, they found a bunch of chums. Right? Here you go.
Speaker 2:  Here's some chumby. Yeah. I do think Nintendo is more ruthless
Speaker 2:  about selling its IP in various, like you can buy Mario anything.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Nintendo collects its money. Yeah. If. you wanna do total doo and gloom.
Speaker 2:  One thing this might signal is they don't have a switch to for the holidays
Speaker 2:  so they have an alarm clock instead. Oh. Because you gotta sell
Speaker 2:  something. It's a pretty good little stocking stuffer. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  As these things go, it has Mario in the box. That actually makes
Speaker 2:  quite a lot of sense to me. I mean, I I hope they have a switch too.
Speaker 2:  I hope so too. I'm ready to buy one. But If, you wanna If you wanna play
Speaker 2:  be the most negative. That's what you would say. But even like there, there
Speaker 2:  are a lot of people with switches who don't wanna upgrade and like the, the
Speaker 2:  timing Sure. Suggests that they intend this as like a big holiday victory.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And it's mar big ass Mario on the bag that
Speaker 2:  Chris Welch bought. Like I could see it. Yeah. And again, I find
Speaker 2:  this thing so charming. I just think Nintendo is like the least
Speaker 2:  like every other company, company that we cover in ways that are mostly
Speaker 2:  really fun and occasionally just completely inscrutable. And this is one
Speaker 2:  of those moments for me. Yeah. What are you doing? But I'm, I wish more companies
Speaker 2:  were weird. Oh, for sure. In this specific way. We got like eight stories
Speaker 2:  about alarm OI would love to cover things like, we're gonna have a full review
Speaker 2:  of this alarm clock. Absolutely. It's gonna be amazing. Some Apple rumors
Speaker 2:  we should talk about. Oh yeah. That kind of lead into, I wanna talk about
Speaker 2:  the Met Raybans for one second, but the Apple rumors are that sometime
Speaker 2:  this month or early November, I'm guessing it'll be early November,
Speaker 2:  we'll get New Mac minis that are in the form factor of like an Apple TV or
Speaker 2:  on that size and a new iPad mini for all the pilots out there who listen
Speaker 2:  to the show and email. David, please stop.
Speaker 2:  I've started getting creep shot photos from people who take
Speaker 2:  pictures of the iPads that they see their pilots having and send it
Speaker 2:  to me. That's good. So I just have, that's how you get arrested by the air
Speaker 2:  marshal. Yeah. Civil, whole library of pilots now. It's not good.
Speaker 2:  I don't want that. But yeah. The, the rumor or from
Speaker 2:  Mark Gerberman, the, the reporting that he has had is that I think they're
Speaker 2:  launching on November 1st. At least the Mac Mini will be.
Speaker 2:  I'm very excited about this Mac Mini. I have an M1 Mac mini that I love very
Speaker 2:  much and I'm very excited to upgrade to an M four Mac mini.
Speaker 2:  I don't understand the compulsion to make the box smaller.
Speaker 2:  Like, yeah. No one is mad about the size of their Mac. Mini Liam
Speaker 2:  in the control room. Liam just started at me waving. Liam is the only person
Speaker 2:  that's more activity in the control room than we seen in, was angry about
Speaker 2:  the size of his Mac Mini. That was a lot. I take it all back.
Speaker 2:  Everyone is so upset about the size of their Mac mini. It's,
Speaker 2:  it's way too big. Make it smaller or else
Speaker 1:  To be clear, I was agreeing with you. Oh, okay. I I'm a
Speaker 1:  longtime lover of the Mac Mini. I've had many over the years as Plex servers
Speaker 1:  and I just don't understand why it needs to be smaller. Okay. There you go.
Speaker 1:  There's absolutely no reason for it. Sure. Let's, let's make it less versatile.
Speaker 1:  Let's take away ports that people use for weird.
Speaker 2:  You're gonna get one USBC port and the highest performance M four processor
Speaker 2:  available and you're gonna like it lean and I'm gonna plug in my like
Speaker 2:  8-year-old USBC hub that threatens to catch on fire every time I use it.
Speaker 2:  And I'm gonna compute the hell out of it. It's gonna be great. I think this
Speaker 2:  is gonna be great. I think the Mac mini is like a sneaky hit for
Speaker 2:  Apple in a way that it never really talks about but like, just sort of
Speaker 2:  anecdotally. Yeah. People love the Mack Mini in a way that the iPad
Speaker 2:  mini has. Its like devoted really loud followers but
Speaker 2:  not that many of them. I think the M mini is like just sort of around.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's the, it's everybody who needs I You bought your M1 because I,
Speaker 2:  I basically was like shut up and buy an M1 M mini You literally I was, I
Speaker 2:  was getting off a plane in DC from somewhere and you
Speaker 2:  sent me a link because it was on sale on Amazon and I had bought it before
Speaker 2:  I got off the plane. I was literally, I'm sitting there on the tarmac and
Speaker 2:  you're like, the Mac mini's on sale. Buy this shut up. I bought it. I was
Speaker 2:  like, stop complaining about your computer. Buy this Mac mini and it worked.
Speaker 2:  I'm excited for it. I, you know, we run the decoder studio in a Mac mini.
Speaker 2:  What is wrong with your M1 that you want an M four? Nothing It's,
Speaker 2:  it's fine. Like, okay. Just checking. Really what it is is I have set
Speaker 2:  up a beautiful thing where I get to get new things and then
Speaker 2:  gift all of my gently used things to family members. And so really
Speaker 2:  what it is is my 2011 iMac.
Speaker 2:  No, 2013 maybe somewhere in there. iMac is finally starting to
Speaker 2:  die on my sister So. I have to start the whole process again by buying
Speaker 2:  an M four Mac mini and and passing things down such that she gets a workable
Speaker 2:  computer. I'm doing this for them. Yeah, I see what you're doing. I'm a very
Speaker 2:  good Are you gonna do their project where you turn the iMac into a
Speaker 2:  standalone display? Oh that's actually a good idea. So I have
Speaker 2:  looked into this. It's a 27 inch screen. I really should. I have a bunch
Speaker 2:  of parts sitting around my house. You have to figure out exactly what model
Speaker 2:  of display is in the iMac. Okay. And then you can literally just buy
Speaker 2:  adapters that you can use it as a display. You have to take it all apart.
Speaker 2:  Right. But I'm like excited to apart It's fine if I break it, it's broken.
Speaker 2:  Like whatever. Yeah. Oh no. This 2013 iMac is broken. So I have all the
Speaker 2:  parts of my house. I just have not done the thing. That's where
Speaker 2:  I like take a heat gun and suction cups to an iMac to take it all apart.
Speaker 2:  We should maybe like bring that into the studio and both do it. Both. Both
Speaker 2:  of Neli and David both break their iMac today.
Speaker 2:  But yeah, my 2015 iMac is just sitting waiting for this to happen to
Speaker 2:  it. Yeah. One day it's pretty good. But yeah. But then there's also,
Speaker 2:  we're supposed to get an M four MacBook Pro I think in both sizes
Speaker 2:  supposedly and weirdly it's already leaked. People think, oh, So I like Russian
Speaker 2:  YouTuber has a 14 inch M four, oh I missed this. But
Speaker 2:  then there's a controversy 'cause the box has the old,
Speaker 2:  the old wallpaper on it. Okay. So people think the whole thing is fake. Huh.
Speaker 2:  And people are like, this is the biggest leaks in HUN for And I'm like, I
Speaker 2:  don't even if it's real, like it's not. No, I feel like it
Speaker 2:  also tells you a lot about what to expect that no one can really tell
Speaker 2:  like fast computer now faster.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Here you go. I mean I'm kind of ready. There's no reason to upgrade
Speaker 2:  this. Which one is that? This is an M1 PRO 16. Okay. I have an
Speaker 2:  M1 error sitting here that I'm like Yeah, that's a 16 inch MacBook Pro with
Speaker 2:  an M1 Pro in it. Okay. Not the M1 max. Oh. So that thing is still, but it's
Speaker 2:  still, that's a pretty beefy computer. It's It's killing it. Yeah. So this
Speaker 2:  is the best laptop I've ever had. I'm like, what if I got rid of you? What
Speaker 2:  if I got an M four for no reason? For me it's colors. Every time I look at
Speaker 2:  the really like dark MacBooks, I'm like, ah, I want one
Speaker 2:  silver stupid. Who wants silver? I want more fingerprints in my computer.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, exactly. So we'll see. That is the rumor for the next couple weeks.
Speaker 2:  It's all coming out now. It does feel like we are ready for an Apple upgrade
Speaker 2:  cycle. So keep an eye on that. Yeah. Lastly, there's some other little
Speaker 2:  Apple news that I want to try to connect to Meta
Speaker 2:  and what it's doing. Okay. So it was announced this week Dan Riccio who used
Speaker 2:  to be SVP of all hardware engineering at Apple and is now in charge of vision.
Speaker 2:  Bro, he's retiring and it's like retirement season for a lot of Apple executives.
Speaker 2:  They've all been there a long time. Being at Apple for 20 years is like,
Speaker 2:  oh you're just a baby. Truly. Like there are people stick around. Yeah. So
Speaker 2:  it makes sense that he is retiring. The Vision Pro is announced. It is released,
Speaker 2:  it's out in the world. And he took over
Speaker 2:  engineering that project in 2021. So the thing is out in the world, it's
Speaker 2:  gonna go do its thing. He's been there a long time. Goodbye everybody. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Presumably numbers two, three and four are deep in the works. Like Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And he had been at Apple for 26 years. Yeah. He ran iPad. There are a lot
Speaker 2:  of ways that as not problematic, but what I would say
Speaker 2:  is the Vision Pro itself in a weird spot.
Speaker 2:  The Apple just announced a new movie for it submerged like
Speaker 2:  its first immersive movie. Yeah. At the same time it announced that Apple
Speaker 2:  TV Plus will not be available on Amazon channels, which is a pretty huge
Speaker 2:  indictment at Apple TV plus. Yep. As a thing that is selling any Apple products.
Speaker 2:  Do you remember all the controversy a while back? I think it was Lucas shot
Speaker 2:  Bloomberg, just like Offhandedly tweeted something about like nobody
Speaker 2:  watches Apple TV plus and people just like ran him down over
Speaker 2:  it. I would say every available piece of evidence suggests
Speaker 2:  that Lucas Sha was right. And yeah, no one really watches Apple TV plus,
Speaker 2:  especially now that they're gonna sell it on Amazon to get more reach. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  But so all that, there's just a swirl of stuff at Apple and
Speaker 2:  one of the things in the swirl I think is a Vision Pro and this big decision
Speaker 2:  over whether Apple wants to keep selling what is essentially VR headsets.
Speaker 2:  Especially now that Meta not Orion. Orion is
Speaker 2:  vaporware no matter what Alex seats says, it's fully vaporware. Yes. It is
Speaker 2:  a thing that doesn't exist no matter how proud of it meta appears to be,
Speaker 2:  but it's like here's some vision of the future that is in this headset. Sure.
Speaker 2:  Meta's pushing in front. And much more importantly, the Ray
Speaker 2:  bands appear to be a success. Hard to tell if they're
Speaker 2:  really a success, but that form factor is much more successful than here's
Speaker 2:  a giant headset that has an external battery pack. And so it just feels
Speaker 2:  like we're gonna see some reset on Vision Pro. That's just very much, and
Speaker 2:  Gerin has reported this, apple has to make some decisions. It hasn't figured
Speaker 2:  out what it wants to do. And now the guy in charge of it is leaving. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I, I forget who it was that I was reading a while back, but basically what
Speaker 2:  they said was, I can't remember the last time
Speaker 2:  Apple was ahead, but completely on the wrong
Speaker 2:  path. And I've been thinking about that ever since. Like it it is, it's still
Speaker 2:  so true that the Vision Pro was like an incredible technical achievement
Speaker 2:  and increasingly it seems like who cares that
Speaker 2:  like maybe the technical achievement was the wrong thing to do and that,
Speaker 2:  like, I keep going back to the, the early days of the iPhone where it was
Speaker 2:  like, do we do a, a more impressive iPod with the click wheel and
Speaker 2:  everything? Or do we like build this brand new
Speaker 2:  epic thing that no one has ever tried before? And they picked that path and
Speaker 2:  it worked super well and I think it taught Apple that the only swings you
Speaker 2:  should make are the biggest ones possible. and it really seems like the lesson
Speaker 2:  of this generation of hardware is like build the iPod with the click wheel.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like that bring people along with you
Speaker 2:  in a way that is get people used to wearing computer on their face all the
Speaker 2:  time. Right. And the other thing is like when the iPhone came out, people
Speaker 2:  had been using cell phones for a long time. Yeah. Right. Like we don't have
Speaker 2:  that history yet. And so you have to do the first cell phones before you
Speaker 2:  can do the iPhone and Apple just tried to skip all the way there. And so
Speaker 2:  it feels like If, you wanted to If, you were to tell me
Speaker 2:  somebody is two generations away from getting it right. It it seems like
Speaker 2:  it's pretty clearly the meta ray bands, right? Like
Speaker 2:  in terms of like mainstream success two generations from now,
Speaker 2:  that one feels like the easy betting favorite. Okay. Except
Speaker 2:  I bought the clear ones and I'm sending them back. No, everybody
Speaker 2:  loves them. Sean Holster's sending his back too. They're, they're
Speaker 2:  fine. They're fine. They're a fine product and I know people who love them.
Speaker 2:  Janist Stern loves hers. Do they look cooler in pictures than they do in
Speaker 2:  reality? They super look cooler in pictures than they do in reality because
Speaker 2:  they look so cool in pictures. They like
Speaker 2:  Wayfairs are very classic shape. And I think they're
Speaker 2:  meant to be classic and black and then you make them clear and they're, at
Speaker 2:  least in my face, they're, they're too curvy. Mm.
Speaker 2:  Like the, when they are, when I have worn a lot of wafers in my life and
Speaker 2:  when they're expressed in black, they're like, they're this very cool shape.
Speaker 2:  And then you make them clear and it's just like, huh, I'm wearing C eye glasses.
Speaker 2:  That's one thing. Did you see all the Yeah, all the movements. I guess that
Speaker 2:  makes sense. So it's, there's one thing. Yeah, maybe clear, maybe I should
Speaker 2:  buy these again in black. But then they only ship the
Speaker 2:  clear ones with transition lenses because they want you to wear them all
Speaker 2:  the time. But they supposed to inside supposed to good transitions. Now they
Speaker 2:  don't get dark enough outside and they also only turn blue, which is weird.
Speaker 2:  And then you're like, why am I wearing these glasses all the time? And then
Speaker 2:  as I have said many times, I have a huge head and the,
Speaker 2:  they're just like not, they're just like uncomfortable on my face. And I
Speaker 2:  think even though I got the bigger ones, it would still be uncomfortable
Speaker 2:  on my face. And this was Sean's complaint. He's like, I've tried them in
Speaker 2:  both sizes and the big ones are loose and still uncomfortable.
Speaker 2:  And the other ones are, and this is the other which you tied and this is
Speaker 2:  the fundamental problem with all of this stuff. Yeah. Is our bodies are not
Speaker 2:  really designed to mount hardware on. And
Speaker 2:  particularly face is a very challenging Yeah. Mounting environment.
Speaker 2:  And so I'm sending back and I think I'm just coming back to my graph,
Speaker 2:  my matrix of wearable bullshit, that face penalty is just huge. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  No matter how useful it's, oh also the camera's not so whatever. I've, I've
Speaker 2:  got a camera in my pocket all the time and like kudos to meta for having
Speaker 2:  better options. But it is very true that you're still not solving it with
Speaker 2:  two styles. Yeah. And then the last piece, which I think Alex
Speaker 2:  brought up when he was on the show last time, it is also true
Speaker 2:  that iOS and Apple keep these glasses
Speaker 2:  from being actually integrated with your phone. Oh, a hundred percent. Like
Speaker 2:  the weird Bluetooth to wifi pairing switch you have to do
Speaker 2:  on Android, it just syns with your phone because the operating
Speaker 2:  system allows it to apple's. Like you're, you will never get close to this.
Speaker 2:  You have to switch your phone to the glasses wifi network to it's garbage.
Speaker 2:  I'm actually super annoyed at Heath because he brought
Speaker 2:  I was waiting patiently. I talk about Google. We'll be right back with her.
Speaker 2:  We're back. David still here. Still here. I didn't
Speaker 2:  kick him. The auction robots haven't gotten me yet. Lauren fines here. Hey
Speaker 2:  Lauren. Hi. Welcome back. Every time we talk to you on the
Speaker 2:  show, it feels like some legal catastrophe has befall
Speaker 2:  Google.
Speaker 2:  Wow. That's true. We have to break this pattern. We like talking to you.
Speaker 2:  But right now you're a bit of an omen. Lauren, what
Speaker 2:  do you think about Nintendo alarm box? Yeah. Did you buy the Nintendo alarm
Speaker 2:  box?
Speaker 6:  I did not. I unfortunately have to talk about Google.
Speaker 2:  No. Well, at least this time we didn't make you sit in a courthouse all week,
Speaker 2:  which is, we have been doing this time a little more
Speaker 2:  procedural. So there was the big Google search antitrust case, which
Speaker 2:  the government won. Google lost. We didn't know what the remedies would be.
Speaker 2:  The government has put forth, its not the actual
Speaker 2:  proposal, but it's like framework of a proposal. It's concepts of a plan,
Speaker 2:  quote Donald Trump. It's very much con, it's 11 pages of concepts of a plan.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And the plan I want, Lauren, I I want you to go into it in
Speaker 2:  detail, but the plan right now is like everything, every idea is on the table
Speaker 2:  for us. So we'll we, let's talk about that and what those ideas are.
Speaker 2:  Then Google also lost the antitrust case that Epic
Speaker 2:  filed against it around the Play store and the court has a plan
Speaker 2:  for some remedies in that case. Which amount to
Speaker 2:  just like having to open things up and share apps with other app stores and
Speaker 2:  all that. And then next to it is the big ad take case, which where
Speaker 2:  you were just in the courtroom for weeks and I dunno what's gonna happen
Speaker 2:  there. That's a lot. and we were joking at the top of the show
Speaker 2:  and Lauren, I'm very curious for your perspective on this. That's a lot of
Speaker 2:  stuff happening to Google that doesn't appear to be like
Speaker 2:  having an impact. Like people, I, I can't tell if everyone knows that
Speaker 2:  whatever we think of as Google today is going
Speaker 2:  away. Like it's going to change in some way over the next X years
Speaker 2:  because of all this activity. Is that what you see as well?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I, I agree. I think the key is maybe that it is
Speaker 6:  in X years, which could be a very large number
Speaker 6:  because you know, now that these things are in the
Speaker 6:  remedies phase, at least in the case of Epic and
Speaker 6:  the search case, you know, Google can then appeal
Speaker 6:  and then we have a whole other process there. So it's still gonna take quite
Speaker 6:  a bit of time to see any real change here.
Speaker 6:  I think in the Epic case, it depends on if they get a
Speaker 6:  stay on remedies while they appeal, but you
Speaker 6:  know, it's still, you know, it's not something that consumers are necessarily
Speaker 6:  gonna see a change on super quickly.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, I think it hasn't really settled in for a lot of
Speaker 6:  people that, you know, Google is definitely going to change. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Or at least it, it seems like it will based on how these cases have turned
Speaker 6:  out so far.
Speaker 2:  And to be fair, Google has said it will appeal all of the cases and it has
Speaker 2:  asked for a stay, which means a delay on the remedies in the Epic
Speaker 2:  case being applied while it goes off and appeals and the blog posts are appropriately
Speaker 2:  outraged. If, you read Google's blog posts,
Speaker 2:  but, so it's like something's gonna happen, right? Like
Speaker 2:  all of this stuff is happening at once and maybe Google can delay some of
Speaker 2:  it and maybe Google can appeal its way out of some of it, but it can't do
Speaker 2:  it to all of it. Yeah, it seems very hard to imagine at this moment
Speaker 2:  that Google is able to just play it all
Speaker 2:  the way out and just litigate its way out of trouble.
Speaker 2:  And the sense I get just from talking to people at Google is that part
Speaker 2:  of what is confusing for Google right now is that it's not
Speaker 2:  clear what is gonna stick and what isn't that there's like, and Lauren, I
Speaker 2:  don't know if this is the sense you're getting from folks involved in this
Speaker 2:  too, but it, there's something going on where there's, there's, there is
Speaker 2:  so much all happening at once that it's almost like you kind of
Speaker 2:  can't pick where to focus your energy and so you are, you're just like, well
Speaker 2:  we're just gonna kind of let all this wash over us and then something will
Speaker 2:  stick and we'll deal with that when it comes. But everybody I talk to even
Speaker 2:  like sort of in and around all of this is just like
Speaker 2:  yeah. Thrown by the volume of it all. Like, is is that what you're hearing
Speaker 2:  too, Lauren?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, no I think that seems right. I think you know it,
Speaker 6:  a lot of all of these different cases are in different parts of Google's
Speaker 6:  business. So you know, I guess Google could say, alright, we're gonna
Speaker 6:  make some proactive changes in some of these businesses. But you
Speaker 6:  know, even if they think, even if they think they won't win everything, they
Speaker 6:  don't know which things will stick necessarily. So it's sort
Speaker 6:  of difficult to get in front of right now.
Speaker 2:  Well, and I feel like that's actually a really good segue to the search remedies,
Speaker 2:  which I, I want to talk about Lauren now. Yeah. I want, I want you to help
Speaker 2:  us go through, because I think what, what I get from that is
Speaker 2:  the DOJ in particular is like, no Google, you
Speaker 2:  can't just make teeny tiny changes and sort of wiggle your way out of this.
Speaker 2:  Like we, we are coming for you and we are coming for all of it. Yeah. It's
Speaker 2:  like I, I could not believe reading this filing how big
Speaker 2:  a window the DOJ is giving itself or would like to give itself
Speaker 2:  to mess with Google. And I think it's because of what you just said, Lauren,
Speaker 2:  that Google is like, this touches lots of pieces of our business, we'll sort
Speaker 2:  of noodle around the edges and we'll we'll build a firewall back between
Speaker 2:  things and we'll let Congress yell at somebody three times a year and then
Speaker 2:  everything will be fine. And the DOJ seems very clearly to be like,
Speaker 2:  absolutely not like we are, we are going to burn you down. And like
Speaker 2:  that's what James and out of the Epic judge has essentially said. Yeah. He's
Speaker 2:  like, I'm going to tear this company open. And that is like the, the vibe
Speaker 2:  is so aggressive on that front from the government side of this. It's wild.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So let's talk about the search remedies. It, it is a 32 page
Speaker 2:  filing only 11 pages of which are actually substantive. 20
Speaker 2:  pages are just state attorney general signing it, which I think is great.
Speaker 2:  Everyone just like joined the club at That's what I aspire to. Yeah. Just
Speaker 2:  to be like helped the 11th signatory of everything I cut down,
Speaker 2:  I helped. But it is, it starts with, we should break up
Speaker 2:  Google. It's on our minds all the way down to, I don't know, you should appoint
Speaker 2:  a compliance officer for us to yell at Lauren. Take us through it. What are,
Speaker 2:  what are the approaches in here?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so basically there's four high level,
Speaker 6:  high level categories that the DOJ lays out that they're looking for
Speaker 6:  in terms of remedies here. So, you know, the first one is
Speaker 6:  about the search distribution and revenue sharing
Speaker 6:  deals. I think these are kind of like the most closely
Speaker 6:  tied to like the surface level of what this case was about, which was like
Speaker 6:  contracts with phone makers and browser makers
Speaker 6:  to make Google the default on their products. And
Speaker 6:  basically the DOJ says like, we'd wanna put some limits on
Speaker 6:  the kinds of contracts that Google can make. So, you know,
Speaker 6:  that seems like probably the lowest hanging fruit here
Speaker 6:  and, but it's also something that doesn't really
Speaker 6:  like fundamentally change Google's business.
Speaker 6:  But another part of that section they talk about,
Speaker 6:  you know, making change structural changes, which means a breakup
Speaker 6:  involving Google's, Google's ownership of
Speaker 6:  Chrome, Android and the Play store. And so it's basically saying like
Speaker 6:  there are these other channels where
Speaker 6:  Google distributes its search engine that Google
Speaker 6:  has an advantage in that its rivals don't, and you know,
Speaker 6:  that's fundamentally a problem. So that's kind of where,
Speaker 6:  you know, we get from this more surface level
Speaker 6:  remedy of contracts to something that really would like go
Speaker 6:  into Google's business and change it up.
Speaker 2:  Just to pause on that one, I there, I wanna get to the other ones, but I
Speaker 2:  think the, the, the move from the first
Speaker 2:  part of that to the second I think is what's so interesting about this whole
Speaker 2:  filing because it's like If, you take the argument to be that
Speaker 2:  Google made illegal amounts of money from its
Speaker 2:  search engine, which is like not exactly the argument but is like
Speaker 2:  it's, it's, you can get there pretty easily, right? Like you have to, you
Speaker 2:  have to make some things up and not be right, but you can get there. No,
Speaker 2:  but it's like that that is what they're, what part of what they're saying
Speaker 2:  is it's not an illegal amount of money, it's they illegally protected their
Speaker 2:  monopoly and thus made a ton of money. Right. Like's but
Speaker 2:  they're not so worried about the money. No, but they are. But the but the
Speaker 2:  point is the what they're doing and they, there's all
Speaker 2:  this setup at the top of the document that is like, not only do we have to
Speaker 2:  stop Google from doing what it's doing, we have to undo it and fix it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And, and pull the market back. And you, there's like, they have a quote from
Speaker 2:  somebody that's like, you know, we can't go back in history, but we have
Speaker 2:  to, we have to do our best to fix it. And so it's like that's how you arrive
Speaker 2:  at, we have to split off Android because Lauren, I think you're exactly right
Speaker 2:  that like the, the obvious thing to come out of this or one
Speaker 2:  obvious outcome would be no more search deals, right? You can't pay it to
Speaker 2:  be the default anymore. That seems like a very straightforward answer to
Speaker 2:  what Judge Meta clearly had issues with. But then
Speaker 2:  it's, it's a surprisingly small number of steps from that to
Speaker 2:  even If. you let Google be the default search engine in the thing that it
Speaker 2:  already owns. It's still too powerful. And so it's like that,
Speaker 2:  that leap feels wild, but I was surprised at how quickly
Speaker 2:  the government got there. Yeah. I would say. So it's not, to me it's not
Speaker 2:  money, it's data. The money is like related to data. Well that's
Speaker 2:  make a good that, that's one of the four things too, right? You can't make
Speaker 2:  a good search engine without all the data that Google collects and if they
Speaker 2:  continue to own Chrome, you're hooped. Right?
Speaker 2:  Like, but I agree with you there. It's a small jump from these search
Speaker 2:  deals are illegally being made to,
Speaker 2:  we should tear Google the shreds, right? Because Chrome makes you too powerful
Speaker 2:  because Chrome makes you too powerful. Yeah, I, I agree with that. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Lauren, what are the other two remedies proposed or concepts of a
Speaker 2:  plan of remedy?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so the next one kind of what we were just talking about was the
Speaker 6:  accumulation and use of data. So, you know, during the trial the
Speaker 6:  government kind of described this like self-reinforcing cycle where
Speaker 6:  you know, users go to Google because
Speaker 6:  it's the default and it's what they're used to using and they enter
Speaker 6:  their search queries and then Google gets a lot of information from what
Speaker 6:  you click on about what's actually a useful
Speaker 6:  answer. And that's, and because it, you know, kind of
Speaker 6:  has this basically has all of these distribution
Speaker 6:  channels pretty much set to itself as
Speaker 6:  the default. You know, most people are going to
Speaker 6:  Google and then other search rivals are kind of being
Speaker 6:  deprived of that query click information and then,
Speaker 6:  you know, aren't able to improve their services as much and then, you know,
Speaker 6:  they're not, they don't feel as good to users and then they go back to Google.
Speaker 6:  So that's kind of the cycle that was described at trial,
Speaker 2:  Including by Satya Nadella. Yeah. Yeah. That was very,
Speaker 2:  he was not messing around.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. So basically go the government
Speaker 6:  wants to offset that a advantage by
Speaker 6:  making it so, you know, Google has to kind of share
Speaker 6:  certain information. You know, they might have to,
Speaker 6:  you know, license some information or make APIs to
Speaker 6:  share some of the information on how it trains
Speaker 6:  its search engine with that query data
Speaker 6:  essentially. And you know, the DOJ says like they know that
Speaker 6:  there are privacy concerns here with sharing that kind of
Speaker 6:  information, but they also say, you know, we need to kind
Speaker 6:  of parse out what is really a privacy concern and what is just like
Speaker 6:  a big tech defense.
Speaker 2:  Yep. That comes up a few times where the, the government is like, yeah, we
Speaker 2:  know there are privacy issues, eh, we'll figure it out. It comes up a lot.
Speaker 2:  You know, Jonathan Canter, the assistant attorney general for antitrust has
Speaker 2:  been on decoder twice now and he's very careful. He's very,
Speaker 2:  he's a government lawyer. He's very good at this. Yeah. Politician. But you
Speaker 2:  can hear his frustration with privacy as a defense to
Speaker 2:  every problem. Just it's blindingly clear. He's like, we
Speaker 2:  know Apple wants to protect your data. That doesn't mean they can do illegal
Speaker 2:  things. We can figure it out. And I think that's kind of what they're saying
Speaker 2:  to Google here too. Like, yes, other companies
Speaker 2:  need this data to compete. They need to know what's going on the internet
Speaker 2:  too. You can't say only we can protect you. Like we're just
Speaker 2:  not, that's not a rational defense right. To the government. Right. I have
Speaker 2:  no idea how that's gonna play out, but I will say that I've, I've interviewed
Speaker 2:  Cantor twice and he is very frustrated about that
Speaker 2:  particular wall going up. Yeah, yeah. And they do, like
Speaker 2:  Lauren was saying, there are a few times where it's like, and before you
Speaker 2:  say privacy,
Speaker 2:  don't say privacy. All right. What's the fourth one? There's two more.
Speaker 2:  There's two more? Yeah, two more. Yeah, she's only said two. Oh
Speaker 6:  The first was like a parter.
Speaker 2:  I gotcha.
Speaker 6:  So the third is about generation and display of search
Speaker 6:  results. So this one is pretty much about AI
Speaker 6:  and you know, the government kind of says, you know, Google, Google
Speaker 6:  is creating these like new
Speaker 6:  AI products that are, you know, integrated in search and a feature in
Speaker 6:  search that basically come from scraping data from
Speaker 6:  sites that they say have quote little to no bargaining
Speaker 6:  power against Google's monopoly. So they're basically wanting to make sure
Speaker 6:  that, you know, sites can maybe opt
Speaker 6:  out of having their information being trained on
Speaker 6:  AI data and things like that.
Speaker 2:  This one feels to me like the government being like not
Speaker 2:  entirely sure what problem it's trying to solve here because I think the
Speaker 2:  thing we heard in both these trials, both in the search trial and in the
Speaker 2:  ad tech trial was there's this whole group of round
Speaker 2:  Google on the internet that just feels powerless, right? And there's, there's
Speaker 2:  a sense that one of the things that is monopolistic about Google is that
Speaker 2:  you just have to play Google's games all the time. And so you can feel this
Speaker 2:  energy from the government saying we wanna level the playing field and
Speaker 2:  give people more tools and more stuff to do. And like
Speaker 2:  you've actually been able to opt out of Google for a pretty long time. It's
Speaker 2:  just that no one wanted to Yeah. Because it wasn't a good trade for the
Speaker 2:  most part. And now that trade is different and it's worse, but like
Speaker 2:  the tools are still kind of there. So I. I feel like to me this was the least
Speaker 2:  compelling part of this document. The government basically just trying to
Speaker 2:  be like, we want everyone else to feel
Speaker 2:  big.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. This was the shortest section in the remedies and
Speaker 6:  it does feel like the one that like maybe they're gonna have to figure out
Speaker 6:  how to flush out a little bit more. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. This one one and it, it's hard. I mean like it's, it's easier in
Speaker 2:  this instance to sort of bring Google down a peg than it is to
Speaker 2:  bring everybody else up, right? And I think they're, they're trying to do
Speaker 2:  both and I think that that makes sense in this moment. I think they're trying
Speaker 2:  to push Apple into making a search engine. If I had to, interesting. If I
Speaker 2:  had to describe the shape of the outcome that everyone wants
Speaker 2:  the most, it's we knock Google down a peg, we make
Speaker 2:  it illegal for you to, to just pay the money and Apple looks around and says,
Speaker 2:  well we should just do a search engine of our own and we'll use some of this
Speaker 2:  innovative new i AI technology to do it well. Wait, can I, can I read you
Speaker 2:  a thing that might actually point at that? So one
Speaker 2:  of the things in the generation display of search results
Speaker 2:  section says that they're considering remedies that
Speaker 2:  would require Google to make available in whole or through an API the indexes
Speaker 2:  data feeds and models used for Google search, including those used in AI
Speaker 2:  assisted search features and Google search results, features and ads including
Speaker 2:  the underlying ranking signals, especially on mobile. So that's like a,
Speaker 2:  that is bananas. That's, that's, that's it. Give Google away for
Speaker 2:  free. You open source Google. Alright. But
Speaker 2:  like that that, what that clearly says is we wanna spin up a
Speaker 2:  whole bunch of Google competitors right away because anyone with 10 minutes
Speaker 2:  of coding experience is now going to be able to build a Google level search
Speaker 2:  engine like on the back of Google. Right. Like wild.
Speaker 2:  But it does, it does suggest that one of the things they want to do is very
Speaker 2:  quickly create a lot of competitors in the search industry. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  to
Speaker 6:  The point of Apple at trial, the government
Speaker 6:  did kind of suggest that Google had
Speaker 6:  made it in its contract so that it would make sure Apple would not compete
Speaker 6:  with it directly in search. So, I. I could definitely see that being something
Speaker 6:  that the government would like to see, you know, opening up the opportunity
Speaker 6:  for even, you know, a very well positioned competitor to just like
Speaker 6:  get going here and crack open the ecosystem.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That was when they were talking about Spotlight, right. And there were
Speaker 2:  all these internal emails where Apple was trying to decide whether the stuff
Speaker 2:  they were doing in Spotlight was like too close to Google and people at Google
Speaker 2:  were worried that Spotlight was becoming too googly and like there these
Speaker 2:  two things were actively trying to not run into each other
Speaker 2:  and, and you could, you could tell the whole time this came up in trial,
Speaker 2:  the government's just sitting there being like, yeah we got,
Speaker 2:  I can't tell you the number of times I've walked out of a WW C, which is
Speaker 2:  where Apple does its operating system updates. And I've gotten texts from
Speaker 2:  Google employees that are like, they're coming in for searching. And my response
Speaker 2:  is always like, why are you talking to me? Right? Right. Like
Speaker 2:  you're Google and it's because Apple has the click data, right? They have
Speaker 2:  the captive audience, particularly in the iPhone that is just searching in
Speaker 2:  Safari and right now that goes to Google and the second that's diverted,
Speaker 2:  Google knows it's in trouble. So it pays the money. And I,
Speaker 2:  I think generally I've heard both Jonathan
Speaker 2:  Cantor and Lena Kahn at the FTC say all these like
Speaker 2:  programs where we install a babysitter to tell a company they're doing
Speaker 2:  something bad and they fix it like don't work, like these compliance
Speaker 2:  regimes don't work. We want structural remedies, which means we're gonna
Speaker 2:  break up your dumb company and now you're two companies. And what we want
Speaker 2:  is actual competition in the market. And the reason I'm saying I think they
Speaker 2:  want Apple to launch a competitor to Google is like, that is the easiest
Speaker 2:  fix to this problem. Yeah. Like without question it's Google should
Speaker 2:  have a competitor where can I just drag one into existence? It is on
Speaker 2:  the iPhone with Apple intelligence and you're talking to Siri and you've
Speaker 2:  got new search results and new things to query all that stuff.
Speaker 2:  Just do it Well and it's also the exact same logic that
Speaker 2:  doesn't make it make sense for Apple to have not launched a
Speaker 2:  search engine. Yeah. There were a lot of negatives in that sentence. But
Speaker 2:  basically the, the point is like, given all of that evidence,
Speaker 2:  the only obvious reason Apple wouldn't have launched the search engine is
Speaker 2:  because Google pays it lots of money. And that was like Lauren, I think you
Speaker 2:  and I both heard that was the implication at trial that like they have successfully
Speaker 2:  with $20 billion a year kept a huge and
Speaker 2:  well-funded and immediately at scale competitor from
Speaker 2:  existing and now we're just gonna give them all of Google's other data.
Speaker 2:  We're just gonna fix it. Yeah. All right. I think that's three. One more.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, one more. One more. All right.
Speaker 6:  So the last one is about kind of a different part of
Speaker 6:  this case, which was Google's monopoly
Speaker 6:  in general search text ads. So
Speaker 6:  this is like a super specific part of the
Speaker 2:  Case. We love a market definition podcast,
Speaker 6:  But basically in this area, you know, this is
Speaker 6:  like the the sponsored blue links that you see when you enter a search
Speaker 6:  query.
Speaker 6:  And you know, the government here is thinking
Speaker 6:  about maybe
Speaker 6:  making Google license or syndicate its ad feed even like
Speaker 6:  separately from its search results to allow for more
Speaker 6:  competition in that really particular part of the market.
Speaker 2:  You should see if, if you're not watching this, you should see the squinting
Speaker 2:  Neli is doing listening to explanation. Yeah. I mean
Speaker 2:  I've been spending a lot of time talking to ad people lately. You have, it's
Speaker 2:  changed you because I see them, you're wearing a tie. God I'm wearing a tie
Speaker 2:  because of a secret VERGE project that will soon be revealed. And I decided
Speaker 2:  to just keep wearing a tie today.
Speaker 2:  But I've been just sort of like watching like the influencer advertising
Speaker 2:  market. So I've been talking to a lot of people like where's this money going?
Speaker 2:  Like what is happening on these platforms? I promise I'll write a story about
Speaker 2:  this. But the thing that they're all saying is search ads on Google
Speaker 2:  are not so valuable to us anymore. Hmm. That this all
Speaker 2:  the action, all the young people, the money is in like TikTok shop or whatever
Speaker 2:  and so the money's moving. So it's just like this last piece of the puzzle
Speaker 2:  where you're googling running shoes and Google is
Speaker 2:  gonna show you search results for running shoes with a sponsored link at
Speaker 2:  the top. Like it's still very valuable, it's very lucrative, it hasn't moved
Speaker 2:  in any meaningful way, but it's the thing that is changing all on
Speaker 2:  its own without any intervention. Right? Right. Because the dollars are,
Speaker 2:  are just going somewhere else. And so this one just seems
Speaker 2:  like do what is what I want to feed of Google Ads.
Speaker 2:  That's my, that's the plan. Like we're fine, it's good. But it goes back
Speaker 2:  to kind of the this same idea of like how do we undo
Speaker 2:  the thing that has made Google unstoppable, which is that it just has this
Speaker 2:  gigantic lead on everybody. It has so much scale, it has so much
Speaker 2:  click data, it has so much query data, it has so much user data and it
Speaker 2:  really seems like the only thing the government has figured out to do here
Speaker 2:  is just give all that data to everybody else in order to level the playing
Speaker 2:  field. I'm not a lawyer, but that doesn't seem like a real plausible.
Speaker 2:  So there's this idea Sarah, John and I've been talking this lot.
Speaker 2:  There's this idea that you can't force a company to do something,
Speaker 2:  you can't force someone to do anything. It's called specific
Speaker 2:  performance. It's very nerdy, but it's like it's the thing you, it's
Speaker 2:  like the hardest thing to get. Like I,
Speaker 2:  you're, I'm mad at you because your tree is hanging on my
Speaker 2:  property and like I need you to cut down the tree and it's much more likely
Speaker 2:  that the judge will move our property lines than to force you
Speaker 2:  to cut down the tree. Interesting. Right? Like that's a, if you're a first
Speaker 2:  year lawyer, I know there's a million problems with that example, but that's
Speaker 2:  the shape of it, right? Like it is very hard to force a force someone
Speaker 2:  to do anything in an ongoing way. It's just the last thing you
Speaker 2:  can ask for. And I think in this context, and Lauren, I'm curious what
Speaker 2:  your reporting has revealed. It feels like the government's like, yeah, we're
Speaker 2:  gonna break it up along the way. We're gonna ask for a bunch of like duty
Speaker 2:  to deal. You have to do these deals. We're gonna force your business to do
Speaker 2:  business with that business. We're gonna force you to do these things, which
Speaker 2:  are the other choice. Either Judge,
Speaker 2:  you can break up Google, you can take YouTube and Chrome and
Speaker 2:  Android, just break 'em up. Now you got three companies clean. If we can
Speaker 2:  all go to dinner or we can force these companies
Speaker 2:  in a slap in the face, you're gonna slap George Washington in the face. The
Speaker 2:  most anti-American thing you do. And so you have to do deals with your competitors,
Speaker 2:  right? It and it just feels like that's the setup. And I don't, I
Speaker 2:  don't know what's gonna happen but like you have to license all of your data
Speaker 2:  and your search results generations and your ad stack so that Apple can build
Speaker 2:  a thing and you have to keep that going. And where the American economy depends
Speaker 2:  on your doing this deal because we forced you to
Speaker 2:  That's tough. That's a tough one. Yeah. And Lord knows, and it might be easier,
Speaker 2:  there's no way around getting that deal done correctly in the spirit of the
Speaker 2:  law and it just might be easier to be like cut it in three. And I, I
Speaker 2:  kind of think that this whole concept of a plan thing is like just setting
Speaker 2:  up the, oh that seems hard. We should just break up a little,
Speaker 6:  Well the government does say they think that there needs to be like
Speaker 6:  pretty, the judge needs to consider remedies from like
Speaker 6:  Mo at least most of these buckets. Like it can't just be like
Speaker 6:  one thing and obviously you know, this is early days, they're
Speaker 6:  asking for as much as they think they might be able to get and they
Speaker 6:  haven't even gotten into specifics yet. But you know, I think
Speaker 6:  they feel like they need to attack this from multiple angles and
Speaker 6:  also attack the network effects. Which I think is what our licensing aspects
Speaker 6:  of this get to is like, yeah, okay, once Google
Speaker 6:  has all this query information, no one else is really able to get
Speaker 6:  it and get in there unless they're able to access that in some way.
Speaker 2:  Do these things typically get filed as like a negotiating
Speaker 2:  tactic? I'm, I'm realizing as you're talking that the way I read this is
Speaker 2:  the government sort of vastly overshooting what it thinks it can do just
Speaker 2:  as kind of a, a first overbid in, in the game
Speaker 2:  to try and land somewhere in the middle. Is that actually how this works?
Speaker 2:  I I, I don't know to whatever extent, although I think that DOJ
Speaker 2:  does not want to settle this one. I think they want, okay, they want it.
Speaker 2:  They've won. They won, right? They won a trial, they, they want to see what
Speaker 2:  remedies they will win whatever. I think the weirdness here is
Speaker 2:  this was a two part trial. So they had the first trial
Speaker 2:  that's just like, are you bad? And the answer is yes. Yes. Did you do it?
Speaker 2:  Oh you super did. And the second part is what should the remedies be? And
Speaker 2:  a lot of this filing
Speaker 2:  is here's what we think the remedy should be. Now we're gonna have another
Speaker 2:  trial and we're gonna get more information about how bad they are to support
Speaker 2:  these. I
Speaker 6:  There's also gonna be a whole other discovery process for this phase. So
Speaker 6:  the government's gonna get even more information about what's possible, what
Speaker 6:  Google thinks actually gives it the power that it does
Speaker 6:  and you know how it could get at that So I think that will be refined
Speaker 6:  as they get that information.
Speaker 2:  So that's the reason you go super broad in this first one is to essentially
Speaker 2:  give yourself leeway to go every possible direction
Speaker 2:  in this remedies trial. Yeah. Okay. That makes sense. And the the and
Speaker 2:  then the thing, and people are probably listening to me, I'm like, you're,
Speaker 2:  you just wanna break up Google, you hate Google. The thing that is right
Speaker 2:  next to it is Google is generally terrified of all of this and has gotten
Speaker 2:  itself into trouble throughout all of these antitrust cases for constantly
Speaker 2:  deleting emails and like saying things like
Speaker 2:  antitrust take this chat to private, which is weird. Or the
Speaker 2:  putting attorney-client privilege at the top of every email even when it's
Speaker 2:  obviously not attorney-client privileged. Yeah. Like there like If, you can't
Speaker 2:  talk about your own business without having to say we shouldn't talk about
Speaker 2:  this. Like something is going wrong
Speaker 2:  all the way up, all the way up to Shai who is like, we should take this offline.
Speaker 2:  Like so there's just this overwhelming sense inside of
Speaker 2:  this case in particular that like the government's gonna just
Speaker 2:  run it to the end. Yeah. I don't know if that's the sense in the Epic case.
Speaker 2:  So that's this case. Well again there's another poor Lauren and David are
Speaker 2:  both gonna have to sit in DC courtrooms some more. They see that coming.
Speaker 2:  That's just one of the cases. The ad tech case we
Speaker 2:  can set aside. 'cause nothing has really happened in the past couple weeks.
Speaker 2:  We think November right for next moves on that one though.
Speaker 6:  November 25th is when closing arguments are happening.
Speaker 6:  Ah,
Speaker 2:  Sick Thanksgiving present for everybody. Yeah. That's gonna be so fun. You
Speaker 2:  can just be like, you know the judge is like, I, I cannot hear about CPMs
Speaker 2:  anymore. We're all taking a break and then you can come back and do your
Speaker 2:  closing arguments.
Speaker 2:  So that's, that other case is happening over there. That's Google's money.
Speaker 2:  So that's a big deal. And then there's the Epic case,
Speaker 2:  which is the weird one. It's like the weird outlier 'cause it wasn't brought
Speaker 2:  by the government, it was brought by Tim Sweeney epic. They lost against
Speaker 2:  Apple and basically the same theory, but they super won against
Speaker 2:  Google because in order to keep the Android ecosystem in line, Google had
Speaker 2:  to go make contracts. And there's just a huge paper trail
Speaker 2:  of what those contracts are and what they restrict companies from doing and
Speaker 2:  how they work. And now we're at the same part where the judge is like, how
Speaker 2:  do I fix it? And Lauren, it feels like the remedies in this case are their
Speaker 2:  own kind of extremely complicated multi-port system.
Speaker 6:  Yes, that is true. And but I guess basically the high level
Speaker 6:  is that the judge is allowing for other app stores on Android
Speaker 6:  to have you know, kind of more equal footing with the Play store.
Speaker 2:  And I think Google has to give the entire catalog of play store apps to other
Speaker 2:  app stores for three years. Which is just back to that, how
Speaker 2:  do I make it fair? I'm gonna force this to be fair. Yeah, Google has to
Speaker 2:  give third party developers access to all the apps
Speaker 2:  in Google Play and list those third party app
Speaker 2:  stores in Google Play. So it's this, it turns the app
Speaker 2:  store into this crazy like, or boros of apps that
Speaker 2:  you're like, oh you wanna download Instagram? You can do it from 900
Speaker 2:  places now knock yourself out. But
Speaker 2:  yeah, I mean there's a lot of like little things also that, that the judge
Speaker 2:  ruled here. Like there's some of the, the steering or the anti
Speaker 2:  steering stuff where it's, it's now easier to link to billing outside of
Speaker 2:  Android with these remedies. There's a lot of,
Speaker 2:  I guess I would call it like weird contract ness that that's trying to
Speaker 2:  be undone in terms of like how app revenue gets shared
Speaker 2:  and what developers get from Google to do things or in some
Speaker 2:  cases not to do things. But yeah, it seems like basically
Speaker 2:  what the judge is trying to do here is just say there are a
Speaker 2:  lot of apps on Android and everyone should have all of them
Speaker 2:  and they should all be able to peacefully coexist. And that is like
Speaker 2:  I think a really fascinating UI experiment we're
Speaker 2:  about to have. Because like I just, I think most people are
Speaker 2:  going to have trouble figuring out how any of that is actually supposed to
Speaker 2:  work. But it also does mean If, you run a competitive
Speaker 2:  app store, you have a lot of new advantages going
Speaker 2:  for you. Well it's, let me, I mean this case is Epic's case.
Speaker 2:  They, they're the ones who want all these outcomes. So Epic gets to start
Speaker 2:  the Epic app store, epic game store on Android. Tim Sweeney has already,
Speaker 2:  they're gonna do this. Yep. That's gonna have Fortnite in it. Yep. The
Speaker 2:  argument as far as I can tell, and Lauren correct me if I'm wrong, is the
Speaker 2:  Epic game store is at a huge disadvantage if the only app and it is Fortnite.
Speaker 2:  So you need some other apps. Okay Google, you have to give the entire catalog.
Speaker 2:  Well and If, you can't download the Epic game store through the app store
Speaker 2:  that comes built into your right without the warning screens. Right. Okay.
Speaker 2:  So to get the Epic game store, you gotta go through the Play Store. And so
Speaker 2:  now it feels like it's on par everybody else now you got the Epic game store,
Speaker 2:  you go in there to get Fortnite and if the only thing in there is Fortnite,
Speaker 2:  you're never gonna use it again. And Google retains its advantage, they've
Speaker 2:  just made it harder to get Fortnite. So instead we're gonna demand that Google
Speaker 2:  give the entire catalog of the Play Store to Epic. So when you open the Epic
Speaker 2:  game store, you can see all the apps that are available on Android
Speaker 2:  and Fortnite and Fortnite, but the Play store doesn't get Fortnite.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it actually disadvantages the Play store Right. In a lot
Speaker 2:  of ways because now If, you have an app that is so compelling that you can
Speaker 2:  pull people into your ecosystem.
Speaker 2:  It's still gonna be a lot of work and maintenance to build an app store of
Speaker 2:  your own. But like you now have pretty strong incentives to do it because
Speaker 2:  there aren't a lot of downsides.
Speaker 6:  But going back to the search case, you know the Play Store
Speaker 6:  is preloaded on a lot of Android phones, so
Speaker 6:  there's still that advantage for the Play store.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It just seems like what we're gonna get is Epic gets to launch the
Speaker 2:  Epic game store and maybe Microsoft will launch a Microsoft
Speaker 2:  store and maybe Amazon will try again. Maybe
Speaker 2:  Amazon will notice that it runs the Amazon app store, I dunno the Silk
Speaker 2:  browser. Yeah. Like and those will become more viable.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Because just by default Instagram will be in them as well
Speaker 2:  in a way that right now
Speaker 2:  whatever, like they're not gonna go make those deals and they, no one has
Speaker 2:  any incentive to chase that down. Right. Does that,
Speaker 2:  does that, does this matter for anybody? But Epic,
Speaker 6:  I think it matters for any developers that want to make a
Speaker 6:  app store. But you know, I don't know how
Speaker 6:  many developers are out there who want that. And I guess it also
Speaker 6:  matters for developers who want options
Speaker 6:  to be in other app stores that don't have
Speaker 6:  the same rules as the Play store.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So on on the iOS side, this has been expressed pretty directly, right?
Speaker 2:  So there's Alt store because the EU mandated alternative app stores
Speaker 2:  in iOS immediately Alt store came out, the bunch of emulators
Speaker 2:  showed up and then Apple changed the rules in its app store because of some
Speaker 2:  competition that has sort of been already like
Speaker 2:  available on Android. Like you could side load all the stuff in Android.
Speaker 2:  It hasn't changed the rules of the Play store. So is it that
Speaker 2:  we'll have another app store with more permissive rules about
Speaker 2:  what's allowed or better payment splits? I don't know,
Speaker 2:  like this one because Android was already openish, it's like a weird
Speaker 2:  paradox of this case. Yeah. Like because Google doesn't control the
Speaker 2:  ecosystem, the evidence of it trying to control the ecosystem is much more
Speaker 2:  available. 'cause it's just like sending emails to Samsung being like, we
Speaker 2:  control your phone. Well, and there were a couple of things that Epic
Speaker 2:  was asking for that it didn't get, that I think might have potentially been
Speaker 2:  bigger deals. Like one of their things, I forget exactly how they expressed
Speaker 2:  it, but the idea was basically you should be able to side load an app as
Speaker 2:  easily as you can download an app from the play store. And they didn't get
Speaker 2:  that. And if they've gotten that, that becomes a big deal because now,
Speaker 2:  and it just becomes trivially easy to distribute an Android app
Speaker 2:  outside of any app store. Yeah. And that becomes very powerful for lots of
Speaker 2:  good and bad reasons. And then there was the one where they wanted
Speaker 2:  to decouple a lot of the Android APIs from Google Play so
Speaker 2:  that in theory you could buy a device that has the full Android experience
Speaker 2:  except it doesn't have Google play at all. And so then if you're Epic,
Speaker 2:  you sell a gaming handheld that is full Android but only the Epic game store
Speaker 2:  or something like it, right? Like you can see how you get down the road from
Speaker 2:  that. I think the world in which we're
Speaker 2:  gonna live, which is that the Play store is still very powerful and still
Speaker 2:  exists. You just have more control inside of it.
Speaker 2:  That one feels a little, a little less obvious to me. And I think
Speaker 2:  one weird possible outcome of all of this is that you get some of the big
Speaker 2:  companies you're talking about, like in theory Microsoft and Meta
Speaker 2:  and a handful of other companies are powerful enough to say
Speaker 2:  we are doing our own app store. We're not, we're not gonna play the rest
Speaker 2:  of your games and we're gonna offer you better terms If, you come buy apps
Speaker 2:  from our store instead of the play store or whatever. And then you start
Speaker 2:  to have real weird tiers of competition inside of
Speaker 2:  Android where like, I'm gonna get to the point as a user where I have to
Speaker 2:  download five app stores just to have my side. And that sucks. Like that's
Speaker 2:  a bad consumer outcome and that is what Google has been railing against
Speaker 2:  this whole time. And I think that is a reasonable part of its defense. But
Speaker 2:  the truth is, I, I just think Epic got what it wanted. Yeah. Which is we
Speaker 2:  can do Fortnite on our own terms and there's gonna be a lot of fallout,
Speaker 2:  but I don't think there are that many epics out there.
Speaker 2:  You know what I mean? What we'll see, even the way that there are a million
Speaker 2:  search engines that would like to be powerful. I don't know that there are
Speaker 2:  a million other Epic, well there's a Sony, there's a Microsoft, there's a
Speaker 2:  bunch of game companies that really watch, there are a bunch of game companies.
Speaker 2:  I'm just saying that the little with a weird paradox here is because it was
Speaker 2:  already open
Speaker 2:  to control it, Google had to do a bunch of aggressive stuff that created
Speaker 2:  the evidence that is like, now you have to be more open. Which is weird.
Speaker 2:  And I can tell you because I had this exact reaction, a bunch of our listeners
Speaker 2:  are screaming in their cars right now that it is already somewhat trivial
Speaker 2:  to download an a PK an Android phone outside of an app store. Sure. Right.
Speaker 2:  And that it's weird 'cause that openness exists. When Sonos was broken,
Speaker 2:  I just got the AP PK of the old version of the Sonos app and my Sonos was
Speaker 2:  fine for a week. It's easier, but you can't go to a website tap install this
Speaker 2:  app on my phone and it installs the app on your phone. You can, but you also
Speaker 2:  have to accidentally run like a Bitcoin mining scam. That's fine.
Speaker 2:  Actually you brought up Google's responses to this, Lauren, I'm looking at
Speaker 2:  a blog post that from Google that says do j's radical and sweeping proposals,
Speaker 2:  risk hurting consumers, businesses and developers. That seems like it's sums
Speaker 2:  up the response, but you've been doing some reporting, you've read this more
Speaker 2:  closely than I have. What is Google's response to all this?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's their response to the, the search remedies
Speaker 6:  I believe. And yeah, they, they basically think,
Speaker 6:  you know, this is a big overreach. You know, this case is about,
Speaker 6:  you know, a a set of search distribution contracts and
Speaker 6:  you know, here's the government going and like reaching out into all these
Speaker 6:  different businesses that it has. And you know, this is, you know, really
Speaker 6:  going beyond what this case is about. So I
Speaker 6:  think, you know, we're gonna be seeing a lot more from them. I
Speaker 6:  believe they have to file something about
Speaker 6:  their response at some point. So, you know, I think we're not gonna
Speaker 6:  really see them backing down from this and they have to go through this remedies
Speaker 6:  phase before they can appeal. But I think we're gonna
Speaker 6:  see a big fight from them down the road.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Am I being too hard on Google to just read this blog post as Google
Speaker 2:  yelling, but privacy over and over and over? They do kind of yell,
Speaker 2:  but China once in here, but mostly it seems to me that they're
Speaker 2:  just like, it's all the stuff that we've been saying, the the judges
Speaker 2:  in these cases are not finding compelling.
Speaker 6:  I think it, it's privacy, it's, you know, we're gonna hold
Speaker 6:  back American innovation and also just this is a
Speaker 6:  big overreach, So I think those are kind of some of their key
Speaker 6:  arguments here. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  They also say that if Android and Chrome were their own companies,
Speaker 2:  there would be no incentive to keep them open source, which is a, a
Speaker 2:  big deal. And I feel like we could make a hard left turn in talking
Speaker 2:  about WordPress right now, but we should not do that. We should not do that.
Speaker 2:  But there's a lot there that, that Google's response to this will, we'll
Speaker 2:  link the blog
Speaker 2:  Hey, we gotta take a break, Lauren, stick around. We want you on the lightning
Speaker 2:  round with us. Sounds good. All right, we'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Unsponsored lightning round.
Speaker 2:  It's never gonna happen. We've gotten some very nice emails, but I'm not
Speaker 2:  allowed to make the deals.
Speaker 2:  I just walk into rooms of Vox Media demanding and no one, no one takes
Speaker 2:  me seriously for
Speaker 1:  All you guys know, this is a sponsored lightning round. I, I won't tell you
Speaker 2:  That's true. That's true. Sponsored by Liam. Alright,
Speaker 2:  David, you're gonna start with the first one. It's, it's another Google story,
Speaker 2:  but I will tell you one, it's a pallet cleanser and two shockingly
Speaker 2:  popular story. Okay. Not shocking because it's the greatest
Speaker 2:  news in, in years
Speaker 2:  If, you are a person who cares about your documents and, and don't we all
Speaker 2:  care about our documents. So Google announced this feature
Speaker 2:  in April and I completely miss it, but is now rolling out a thing
Speaker 2:  that basically it's the docs equivalent of the thing
Speaker 2:  in Sheets or Excel where you can have sort of multiple tabs open
Speaker 2:  that, that kind of interact with each other. It's, it's just a pain
Speaker 2:  on the side that you can open tabs and sub tabs,
Speaker 2:  but it's essentially like having multiple documents inside of one document.
Speaker 2:  Does that sound like a big deal to you? That will completely change your
Speaker 2:  life? You're wrong. 'cause it is and it will, this is as
Speaker 2:  a, as a person who creates infinite Google Docs.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. For my job, this is the greatest thing that has ever happened to me.
Speaker 2:  I knew it was a big deal when I saw Wired staffers who I know and love
Speaker 2:  like freaking out on threads about our story about it. Yeah. Because they
Speaker 2:  like immediately needed to share it. So the thing that's great about this
Speaker 2:  is a thing that is more and more popular all
Speaker 2:  the time it seems is the like public Google document. Yes. More and more
Speaker 2:  you're, you're seeing like there's a great newsletter that I subscribe to
Speaker 2:  that the newsletter every month is just a link to a Google doc and you go
Speaker 2:  read the Google Doc and it's kind of a great experience. This is, it's great
Speaker 2:  for navigation, it's great for putting lots of docs together. There has been
Speaker 2:  that table of contents thing you can do on the side where it'll let you just
Speaker 2:  jump from header to header. This is just that, but like better
Speaker 2:  and more navigable and less awful on big
Speaker 2:  documents. But I think it, it's Google Docs is like
Speaker 2:  used for a lot of really interesting things. Public docs are everywhere.
Speaker 2:  It's a super collaborative thing. I see things where like groups of hundreds
Speaker 2:  of people are like planning things together in a single Google doc and like
Speaker 2:  this is a, a kind of structure that Docs has just never had and is going
Speaker 2:  to make a lot of type A people very, very happy and they are very happy,
Speaker 2:  they're so happy. They are just reading and sharing the story. We, if we
Speaker 2:  did nothing but write about tabs and Google Docs the rest of the year, we'd
Speaker 2:  be set. It's real. And that's what we're doing. It's Google antitrust and
Speaker 2:  tabs and Google docs. You could make com you can make them emojis.
Speaker 2:  When I was a a just a pup, there was this piece of software that came with
Speaker 2:  almost every mat called HyperCard and it was, I don't
Speaker 2:  even know how to describe it. It was the internet, but local and expressed
Speaker 2:  as like virtual index cards. And you could like program hyper, they were
Speaker 2:  called stacks. You could program hyper card stacks. Some of our audience
Speaker 2:  is freaking out 'cause know what we're talking about when I tell you other
Speaker 2:  people think I sound like an ancient wizard. This involves hyper cards in
Speaker 2:  a surprisingly me meaningful way. This is just HyperCard. Oh, a hundred percent.
Speaker 2:  Google's making HyperCard. Yeah, they're turning Google Docs into HyperCard.
Speaker 2:  Or if another less successful comparison Google
Speaker 2:  wave. Ooh, they're doing just the modular. That's good. I mean, Google has
Speaker 2:  been trying to do Google wave in various forms for an extremely, we gotta
Speaker 2:  just Google, it's an impossible thing to Google, to Google the word Google
Speaker 2:  and the word wave. It's hard. We'll, we'll find a link to some ancient
Speaker 2:  coverage or this thing Google made. Yeah. years ago it was like, what if
Speaker 2:  we blew up all, all email and docs and it was all the same thing and no one
Speaker 2:  could figure it out. And now we're, we're just back. Lauren, are you as excited
Speaker 2:  about tabs as I am? Be honest,
Speaker 6:  I can't say I am the person who has like a million
Speaker 6:  chrome tabs open at the same time.
Speaker 2:  You guys are the problem.
Speaker 1:  As someone who's somehow missed a story, I'm like freaking out in the
Speaker 1:  control. I'm so excited. There are
Speaker 2:  Workflows in my head right now that are now possible.
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna just share. Was that a threat? William just threatened us.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, he did. All right. We're toast. It's lightning around. We gotta move
Speaker 2:  on. Yeah. All right. Lauren, what do you got? Next tab? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Next tab. Yeah, I mean we sure everyone
Speaker 6:  heard there was a major hurricane in Florida this week
Speaker 6:  and FEMA is out there cleaning up, fighting
Speaker 6:  the storm and also now fighting disinformation about the
Speaker 6:  storm as well, including some false claims spread by
Speaker 6:  former President Trump. And you know, I think
Speaker 6:  FEMA kind of always knew this was gonna be a problem, but the FEMA
Speaker 6:  administrator said, this is absolutely the worst I've ever seen
Speaker 6:  about misinformation around the storms recently.
Speaker 6:  So, you know, it's just kind of wild that they've had to do all this
Speaker 6:  fact checking while just trying to literally
Speaker 6:  clean up a major disaster.
Speaker 2:  I think we did a, a link to a Rolling Stone story on the homepage today,
Speaker 2:  just about meteorologists who are getting death threats because people believe
Speaker 2:  they can control the weather. Marjorie Taylor Greene out there saying that
Speaker 2:  they can control the weather. Oh great. Which is an incredible
Speaker 2:  like retcon of climate change. Like do you
Speaker 2:  Yes, it's true. We can control the weather just not the way that you think.
Speaker 2:  It just takes 40 years of burning fossil fuels. It's true.
Speaker 2:  We did in fact control the weather in one very specific way.
Speaker 2:  I, I don't know, If, you, we've run a bunch of stories about just moderation,
Speaker 2:  failures lately, like threads moderation is way too heavy handed. Yep.
Speaker 2:  It appears to be partially AI driven in a way that no one can control
Speaker 2:  at least of all the people at Meta X obviously not moderating any of
Speaker 2:  this misinformation. It is weird to be in a social media
Speaker 2:  environment where I'm like, they did kind of a good job during covid
Speaker 2:  because they, they didn't like that was a nightmare.
Speaker 2:  And this is so much worse and it feels like people are going
Speaker 2:  even one step farther away from reality into
Speaker 2:  they're controlling the weather in Florida to influence the election.
Speaker 2:  I I, I mean all of, like, I I don't think we were doing a great
Speaker 2:  job when we were bringing Jack Dorsey
Speaker 2:  in front of Congress so that people could yell at him and then bad
Speaker 2:  tweets and then people were yelling at Mark Zuckerberg about Twitter. Like
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That accomplished broadly nothing. I think Lauren,
Speaker 2:  you covered all that. Not nothing, nothing was accomplished and some
Speaker 2:  weird first Amendment problems there, but it taught these companies that
Speaker 2:  what if doing nothing was a more viable strategy and now it feels like we're
Speaker 2:  just reaping the dividend of doing nothing.
Speaker 6:  Well it feels like these companies are just very reactionary
Speaker 6:  and it's like being like yelled at as a kid and
Speaker 6:  at first you're like, oh, I need to do better. I need
Speaker 6:  to like do what I'm being asked. And then they're like become
Speaker 6:  adolescents and are like, wait a minute, why am I just following what you
Speaker 6:  save? It seems like it gets me in more trouble. And then they decide to back
Speaker 6:  off.
Speaker 2:  By the way, that is a perfect description of Mark Zuckerberg and his T-shirts
Speaker 2:  and chains and seriously flowy, like flowing
Speaker 2:  logs. Like he's in his adolescent phase of like, eh, screw you.
Speaker 2:  Well, and I remember yeah, we, we were talking a couple of years ago about
Speaker 2:  like all of these companies, a few of them in
Speaker 2:  particular made a real show of doing their
Speaker 2:  best and trying their hardest and decided that it accomplished nothing Yeah.
Speaker 2:  For them, for their image. And, and, and we
Speaker 2:  were even wondering, we were like, okay, what's it gonna look like when they
Speaker 2:  decide that actually the, the penalty for not caring and
Speaker 2:  the penalty for caring are basically the same and they're just gonna decide
Speaker 2:  to not care. No, I'm saying it's worse right now.
Speaker 2:  It is worse. The penalty for caring was worse
Speaker 2:  than the penalty for not caring in the world, but they are
Speaker 2:  paying less of a penalty. They are in their bunkers. That's what I mean.
Speaker 2:  And on their mega yachts. Right. And they are not paying any price for like
Speaker 2:  fake AI generated photos of like children with puppies
Speaker 2:  that don't exist. They're like, oh, this is fine. Right. Whereas
Speaker 2:  when they tried, they got yelled at. Exactly. That's exactly. And the incentive
Speaker 2:  structure is like totally backwards. Yes, a hundred percent. And they're
Speaker 2:  like, we, we have now reached a point where the all of their incentives
Speaker 2:  are to not try and, and now we know what it looks like. Right. It turns out
Speaker 2:  trying and failing. And I think we all pretty much agree that content moderation
Speaker 2:  is a completely unwinnable game and all you can do is try and fail as
Speaker 2:  well as possible that trying and failing
Speaker 2:  gained them nothing and they might as well just give up and not care and
Speaker 2:  wear t-shirts and here we are and it's awful. It is.
Speaker 2:  It's, I would say the hurricane misinformation story is, it might be a
Speaker 2:  defining story in, in like the history of media. Like it was just
Speaker 2:  fully outta control. I mean the the other aspect of that that I, I don't
Speaker 2:  know If, you guys have seen this, but like all of my feeds everywhere are
Speaker 2:  just creators in Florida who stayed and, and are like
Speaker 2:  making a show out of not going. Some of them are like outside trying
Speaker 2:  to sort of journalism the hurricane. But then there's one guy I keep finding
Speaker 2:  who just wears a headlamp and is just like walking around his house being
Speaker 2:  like, seems bad. I'm in the eye. I don't care.
Speaker 2:  And he just has a headlamp and that's, that's like I've seen like 50 of his
Speaker 2:  baby. We don't have the time to do David and Neil Eli talk about
Speaker 2:  journalism and really never do we have the time and nor
Speaker 2:  should we on the show, but drawing the difference between that and Anderson
Speaker 2:  Cooper being like, it's pretty bad. Yeah. Actually pretty hard to do. That's
Speaker 2:  what I mean. You can journalism the hurricane just by going outside the hurricane.
Speaker 2:  Can I get it? It's like they're like, I'm staying here to do, to get eyeballs
Speaker 2:  and Anderson Cooper's like I'm going there to get eyeballs. And it's a
Speaker 2:  very fine line between those two things. A hundred percent. I do think
Speaker 2:  these, the platforms are, they've dropped the ball and I, I don't know,
Speaker 2:  I, I've, all of every vir house listener knows how I feel about the first
Speaker 2:  amendment, which is everyone else seems to be sick of it. And I think that's
Speaker 2:  a worrying trend. Like we're banning books and
Speaker 2:  everyone has bad, everyone's screaming fire in a crowd at theater. Tim Walls
Speaker 2:  of the debate just randomly blurted it out for no reason. And our entire
Speaker 2:  newsroom, you saw our entire slack. Everybody's like, no.
Speaker 2:  Like, I don't know what's going on. It's, it's all bad. But the idea that
Speaker 2:  our social networks are actually, they actually have an important social
Speaker 2:  function in our society to try to get accurate information out and not
Speaker 2:  amplify lies.
Speaker 2:  They just let go. Not going great. Super let go. Yeah. Alright. I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  try to clean this up. Yeah. I'm gonna try to end us on a high note. That's
Speaker 2:  my goal. Okay. Here's the high note. Several months ago, the CEO E of Zoom
Speaker 2:  came on coder and he said, here's my dream.
Speaker 2:  All of your Zoom meetings will have AI clones in them. Digital twins.
Speaker 2:  You're gonna clone yourself and then that clone will go to
Speaker 2:  the zoom meeting for you while you sit on a beach and drink a daiquiri. And
Speaker 2:  I was like, how many clones do I have? Could I have 10,000? And he was like,
Speaker 2:  as many as you want. Unclear how any of this will work. Unclear if he was
Speaker 2:  building, unclear how, if he had the technology to do it.
Speaker 2:  I dunno, there were some great YouTube videos made about that specific
Speaker 2:  interview. Sure. We'll link it.
Speaker 2:  Zoom has announced AI avatars can talk to your
Speaker 2:  team on your behalf. The first step towards our goal of
Speaker 2:  1000 digital neli going to meetings across Fox Media,
Speaker 2:  demanding to have the lightning round sponsored, but now it's one
Speaker 2:  digital neli. Yep. I feel like one's too many
Speaker 2:  Zoom announced. It will soon let you create an AI avatar of yourself that
Speaker 2:  you can use to send brief messages to your team. And the only message
Speaker 2:  I wanna send is, when is the lightning round getting sponsored? And I would
Speaker 2:  like my AI avatar to attend every single meeting at this company.
Speaker 2:  Ugh. This is nothing you need to, you need to record an initial video of
Speaker 2:  yourself that Zoom's AI will use to make an avatar that looks even sounds
Speaker 2:  like you. From there you can write the message you want your avatar to say
Speaker 2:  and then have it go to meetings and say it. It's voicemail.
Speaker 2:  It's the same amount of work. It's the same amount
Speaker 6:  Of work is doing it. Feel like this could have been an email,
Speaker 2:  Liz. Seriously. And I'm gonna have my AI avatar go to every meeting and
Speaker 2:  say, this could have been an email.
Speaker 2:  Okay. A, that's a pretty good idea. B, I have come around to the idea
Speaker 2:  that actually the solution to our AI problem
Speaker 2:  is to just ban meetings. Everybody is like, we're gonna make a
Speaker 2:  thing so that you don't have to go to a meeting, just don't have the meeting.
Speaker 2:  This is uncomplicated. No 1000 digital AI avatars all having meetings
Speaker 2:  with each other while we sip daries in the beach. This is the future of the
Speaker 2:  information economy. Or don't have meetings just daiquiris,
Speaker 2:  just the daiquiri parts and no meetings. But
Speaker 6:  Then you have to have a meeting with your AI avatar to learn what happened,
Speaker 6:  which feels
Speaker 2:  Worse. It he I would say Eric did not. Yeah. I go from having
Speaker 2:  don't. I'm gonna make, I'm gonna train one of these on you.
Speaker 2:  Send David to meetings. That's fine.
Speaker 2:  It's coming. I'm just telling you these ideas are coming. This is the dream.
Speaker 2:  This is the last first cast where it will be real me ever again.
Speaker 2:  Just an AI avatar of David for some reason demanding that the
Speaker 2:  lightning round could sponsor.
Speaker 2:  I do think if you're a CEO If, you make an AI of yourself that goes to every
Speaker 2:  Zoom meeting your company and just says, this meeting should have been an
Speaker 2:  email. You will have done the greatest service to your company that any
Speaker 2:  CEO has ever done. A hundred percent. Just be like, why is the CEO here?
Speaker 2:  and it said, and then like theatrically leaves before they even realize it
Speaker 2:  was ai. That's pretty good. That's pretty good. There it is. That's your
Speaker 2:  idea. All right. That's it. We gotta wrap this thing up. We are way over
Speaker 2:  like crazy over. Lauren, thank you so much for joining us. Thanks for having
Speaker 2:  me. We have lots and lots to come, including this ROBAX event, which is happening
Speaker 2:  Yep. Tonight. And then we'll cover it next week on the Vergecast, but we'll
Speaker 2:  have full coverage on the site in the meantime. So go check that out. Let
Speaker 2:  us know how we did on our predictions. Optums Robots. That's it.
Speaker 2:  That's The. Vergecast. Rock and roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one. One The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Liam James Will Pour