# Transcript
ID: 503a8340-e6de-4eb0-9891-f09d645db0e7
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5318134746026451263/3348870878991066999/s93290-US-23395s-1735036189.mp3
Description: Happy Holidays! The Vergecast is off this week, but we also know you might be doing a lot of traveling and / or avoiding of your family this time of year, so we figured we'd do something a little different. We compiled a bunch of our favorite Vergecast segments and moments from this year — a full six hours of them! — in case you need something to listen to. You may have heard them all before! They might all be new! Maybe it'll be a mix! This one's an easy skip if you're looking for one, but if you need some Verge in your ears this holiday season, we've got you covered. We'll be back for real in January, starting at CES. If you'll be in Vegas, come see us live on Wednesday, January 8th! https://voxmediaevents.com/vergecast And in the meantime, have a great holiday, and rock and roll.
Here are the segments we picked, in order, with timestamps (because we can't do chapters, we know, we hate it too):
The wild world of undersea cables — 00:04:32
Meet Tony Delivers — 00:42:19
The story of the Delta emulator — 00:56:29
Phones are the ultimate AI gadget — 01:37:12
The history and future of notebooks – 02:04:34
What is a photo? — 02:41:07
An existential gaming console crisis — 03:17:46
Inside the AI music lawsuits — 03:52:12
The history of podcasts — 04:40:59
Our Vision Pro score debate — 05:03:15
A road trip on the hydrogen highway — 05:35:13
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (18 ads detected)
Speaker 5:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of really, really,
Speaker 5:  really long podcasts. I'm your friend David Pierce and
Speaker 5:  I am on vacation. We are leasing this episode on Christmas Eve,
Speaker 5:  December 24th, and So I hope you are also on vacation. I hope
Speaker 5:  everybody gets to have a restful, relaxing
Speaker 5:  end of the year. It has been a bonkers year in just so, so,
Speaker 5:  so many ways and I hope everybody gets a chance to wind down a little
Speaker 5:  because 2025 also seems like it's gonna be pretty full curse, but we'll get
Speaker 5:  back to that for this episode. We wanna do something we've never done
Speaker 5:  before. This might be a horrible idea. Everybody might hate this. We might
Speaker 5:  never do it again, but I just wanted to do it just in case. So
Speaker 5:  we've published a lot of stuff over the course of this year and we're also
Speaker 5:  not publishing anything for the next couple of weeks because we're off. Everybody's
Speaker 5:  off. Things are, you know, pretty slow in the news world anyway, so this
Speaker 5:  is usually a time we just take a couple of weeks off. But we've also heard
Speaker 5:  from a lot of folks who travel a lot during this time of year and would
Speaker 5:  like to have something on in the background maybe so you don't have to talk
Speaker 5:  to your family or an excuse to wear headphones so that you don't have to
Speaker 5:  talk to your family. Lots of things going on. So what we did was
Speaker 5:  we went back through this whole year of vergecast and we found
Speaker 5:  a whole bunch of things that frankly we just really liked. We've published
Speaker 5:  a lot of stuff this year. Some of it I think is really good, some of it less
Speaker 5:  so, but some of it I think is really good and some of it is
Speaker 5:  also pretty timely and newsy and makes less sense now than it did you
Speaker 5:  know, three or six or nine months ago. But some of the stuff I think
Speaker 5:  we've done kind of holds up and is still interesting and evergreen and and
Speaker 5:  worthwhile. So we compiled a lot of it. I think it's like six
Speaker 5:  hours of it into just a bit of a clip
Speaker 5:  episode of some of our favorite stuff that we've made this year. To be clear,
Speaker 5:  if you've been listening to The Vergecast all year, there is nothing, not
Speaker 5:  one second of new stuff in this episode.
Speaker 5:  Absolute no hard feelings. If you don't listen, you won't miss anything.
Speaker 5:  Totally fine. This is just If you want more vergecast,
Speaker 5:  more background noise or just frankly something to listen to. 'cause
Speaker 5:  sometimes we all need something to listen to and I guess I think of this
Speaker 5:  as like, you know, I've seen every episode of the office 50 times
Speaker 5:  and I still like it. So maybe you'll like hearing some cool Vergecast stuff
Speaker 5:  again. I don't know. Again, this is just an experiment. I would love to know
Speaker 5:  what you think I, I think there's something to this like clip showy thing
Speaker 5:  because we make a lot of this stuff. I've seen podcasts do like
Speaker 5:  reruns of their best ofs and I've always really enjoyed that. If you have
Speaker 5:  ideas on how we can do this better next year, please let me know. Vergecast
Speaker 5:  at The Verge dot com. I'm also David at The Verge dot com. Hit me up,
Speaker 5:  we'd love to hear from you. But for the next six hours we're
Speaker 5:  just gonna play you some of our favorite Vergecast stuff. Some of this now
Speaker 5:  is going to be wildly out of date. We tried to pick things that are pretty
Speaker 5:  evergreen and still pretty interesting and relevant, but you'll hear some
Speaker 5:  details, some numbers, some facts and figures. I mean we talk about
Speaker 5:  the Vision Pro when we did the review that was 11 months ago. Like
Speaker 5:  lots has changed, but it was still a fun conversation and I think a lot of
Speaker 5:  it still holds up and is still interesting. So we're gonna play that for
Speaker 5:  you at some point here too. Two more notes and then we're gonna get into
Speaker 5:  it. One, there are no chapters in this podcast and
Speaker 5:  please understand that this is both the perfect, perfect
Speaker 5:  episode to have chapters for. And because our platform does not allow it,
Speaker 5:  we don't have it. There are timestamps in the show description. I think a
Speaker 5:  lot of platforms will let you click on those timestamps to jump. That's the
Speaker 5:  best thing we can do. We'll also put kind of the table of contents of all
Speaker 5:  the stuff that's gonna be in here so you can jump around if you'd like to.
Speaker 5:  I promise we are working on chapters. It is the thing we want the most. I
Speaker 5:  know it's the thing you want the most. We're gonna keep working on it.
Speaker 5:  Thing number two, like I said, we are off for the rest of the year
Speaker 5:  and we will be back at CES. And If you are going to be at
Speaker 5:  CES in January, you should come see us January 8th, which is
Speaker 5:  Wednesday at CES, at the Brooklyn Bowl on the link Promenade.
Speaker 5:  It's like right in the middle of the strip. The Vergecast is free. We'll
Speaker 5:  put a link in the show notes. You can come hang out, eat, drink, make dumb
Speaker 5:  jokes about technology with us. We would absolutely love to see you very
Speaker 5:  much looking forward to that and looking forward to seeing all of you. So
Speaker 5:  that's enough preamble. Let's get into it. Here are, I think
Speaker 5:  it's 11, 10 or 11, many, many hours of our
Speaker 5:  favorite VERGE cast things that we've done this year. I hope you have a
Speaker 5:  wonderful holiday season and we'll see you in a couple of weeks. Here we
Speaker 5:  go.
Speaker 5:  Welcome back. Over the last few years, one of those ongoing news stories
Speaker 5:  that always makes me stop and think is whenever a company
Speaker 5:  usually Google or Meta recently announces that they're starting a
Speaker 5:  project to build a cable between countries or continents or across the
Speaker 5:  ocean, like in 2022, both those companies announced these
Speaker 5:  big plans to build cables pretty much all the way around the African
Speaker 5:  continent. The diagrams of them alone are mind blowing. Just imagine
Speaker 5:  you were sort of loosely tracing your way around Africa three or four
Speaker 5:  times all the way around. That's what it looks like. Thousands of miles of
Speaker 5:  cable underneath the ocean hitting land at these various points all
Speaker 5:  around Africa. And increasingly, this is what the whole world looks like.
Speaker 5:  The whole internet is just right there underneath the ocean all over the
Speaker 5:  world. The VIRs, Josh Za has been reporting on these cables for months
Speaker 5:  and he's found himself inside a whole huge industry that really
Speaker 5:  nobody ever knows or talks about, which is the folks tasked with
Speaker 5:  laying and just as important, maintaining and fixing these undersea
Speaker 5:  cables. If you're hearing this on Tuesday as this podcast goes live,
Speaker 5:  his story just also went up. We might have actually beaten him by a couple
Speaker 5:  of hours, so keep an eye on The Verge dot com. So we figured we'd have him
Speaker 5:  on the show to talk about it and explain this whole under the sea
Speaker 5:  world to us. Josh Za, welcome back to The Vergecast.
Speaker 6:  Thank you.
Speaker 5:  You have spent however many months at sea
Speaker 5:  learning about the weird machinations of the internet.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Unfortunately in in port, but I guess it's still
Speaker 6:  technically the sea. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's good enough. So I want to like talk through
Speaker 5:  this big story that you've been working on and just publish for us. But I
Speaker 5:  also want to kind of explain the infrastructure of the internet in
Speaker 5:  a way that I think you're now sort of uniquely set up to do. And
Speaker 5:  my sense is what you've discovered, if we're just gonna start from the very
Speaker 5:  beginning, is that like yes, in fact the internet is just a series
Speaker 5:  of tubes?
Speaker 6:  Absolutely. It is a series of tubes. I was surprised at actually how
Speaker 6:  tube-like they are. Like you imagine, at least I imagine, I
Speaker 6:  feel like a lot of people imagine kind of big pipes at the bottom of the
Speaker 6:  ocean, but it's actually just little garden hose with
Speaker 6:  tubes running between continents. They have some fiber optic cables in the
Speaker 6:  middle, basically just strands of glass that
Speaker 6:  lasers pulsing through, encode data and that is how data
Speaker 6:  travels around the world.
Speaker 5:  So give me kind of the big picture way to think about this
Speaker 5:  infrastructure. Like I know it's lots of very long
Speaker 5:  cables, but like how, how sort of big and sprawling is the
Speaker 5:  undersea cable universe?
Speaker 6:  It's huge. It's, there are 500 or
Speaker 6:  so cables around the world, around 800,000 miles of
Speaker 6:  cabling. Often going through between sort of big
Speaker 6:  population centers. So you have a lot going from uk, Western Europe
Speaker 6:  to New York, New Jersey. On the other side you have various parts
Speaker 6:  of California going to Japan or other location in
Speaker 6:  Asia. And that is how, you know, you think about these
Speaker 6:  big global networks. You are, even if you're not
Speaker 6:  always, like, if two people in America in the US are emailing,
Speaker 6:  they're probably just on terrestrial cables, but the second year
Speaker 6:  accessing data that's overseas in some capacity. If you are
Speaker 6:  watching YouTube videos that were posted from somewhere overseas, it's
Speaker 6:  cached locally at a data center, but it got there using an undersea cable
Speaker 6:  from some other data center somewhere. And If you, of course zoom or email
Speaker 6:  or whatever with someone overseas, it's going through one of these cables.
Speaker 6:  Right.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. How would you think about in the sort of day-to-day life of a normal
Speaker 5:  person, how important are these cables, do you think?
Speaker 6:  I would say they're very important, but they might not be
Speaker 6:  directly accessing them every day. If you're in a big continent like North
Speaker 6:  America, you're largely traveling over terrestrial network, but
Speaker 6:  services you interact with are dependent on these
Speaker 6:  cables. So you have like big global platforms like YouTube and TikTok. That
Speaker 6:  content is reaching you. Like the last mile
Speaker 6:  is gonna be terrestrial, but it got to North America
Speaker 6:  using a subsea cable. A lot of financial data,
Speaker 6:  any kind of international transfer is happening on a subsea cable.
Speaker 6:  Anytime you call customer service and you're talking to someone
Speaker 6:  overseas that's on a subsea cable and then you have kind of the
Speaker 6:  bits of the internet, you have, you might little website,
Speaker 6:  it might seem like it's local, but you have, you know,
Speaker 6:  software libraries and various things that could be stored somewhere else
Speaker 6:  that it's calling on and you don't necessarily know where
Speaker 6:  it's coming from. So I would say every day you're doing
Speaker 6:  something that maybe on a secondary tertiary level relies on
Speaker 6:  these cables.
Speaker 5:  Got it. Okay. And undersea cables, if, if I understand correctly, are
Speaker 5:  not like a new internety idea, right? The idea of
Speaker 5:  having a cable that connects the United States to Europe and Europe
Speaker 5:  to Africa and Africa to Asia or whatever, we know how to do this
Speaker 5:  at this point, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. One of the surprising things to me in doing this story
Speaker 6:  is how little this has changed over the years. And I'm not just
Speaker 6:  talking like the decades of the internet, but like a lot of these companies
Speaker 6:  trace their lineages back to the telegraph era. And a lot of the practices
Speaker 6:  are, are date from the Telegraph era. Like you lay cables, you repair cables
Speaker 6:  pretty much how you did in the 19th century.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We're talking like mid 18 hundreds, right when the telegraph was starting
Speaker 5:  to kind of move around the world.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You read these accounts of the early telegraph people and, and it's
Speaker 6:  quite a lot of, it's trial by air. It's quite exciting as people, they don't
Speaker 6:  really know how electricity works, they don't really know what the bottom
Speaker 6:  of the ocean looks like. And they're just sort of setting out, being like,
Speaker 6:  well, we strung a cable over through the English channel, like
Speaker 6:  why not do the ocean? And it's just
Speaker 5:  More water.
Speaker 6:  It goes terribly for, for several decades before they eventually figure out
Speaker 6:  how to do it.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So today, what does it take to keep all these important garden
Speaker 5:  hoses safe and working?
Speaker 6:  So they're breaking all the time. They break 200 times a year.
Speaker 6:  It's like every other day a cable breaks. So
Speaker 5:  We have 500 cables and 200 of them break every year. Right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Wow. They get 200 breaks. Sometimes they're on the same cable. It's
Speaker 6:  complicated. But yeah, basically a good chunk of them are breaking, there's
Speaker 6:  enough redundancy in the system that data can be routed around on
Speaker 6:  alternate paths. So you don't really notice, but you know, if they,
Speaker 6:  if 200 cables were to stay broken, you would notice things very bad things
Speaker 6:  would happen happen. So yeah, these brakes happen all the time, 200 times
Speaker 6:  a year. And when one breaks traffic is rerouted
Speaker 6:  along alternate paths and while that's happening, one of this
Speaker 6:  small band of ships will sail out with some spare cable and
Speaker 6:  fix the brake. You know, as the internet has become more important there,
Speaker 6:  there's a report that was interesting a couple years ago that talks about
Speaker 6:  how cables have not become more vulnerable in recent years.
Speaker 6:  It's just that our dependence on them has grown exponentially.
Speaker 6:  Hmm. So say in the nineties there's an a massive break. Some things
Speaker 6:  break, it's not bad. You might not notice in your day-to-day life. Now
Speaker 6:  everything breaks, you know, banks stop working, companies can't
Speaker 6:  function, supply chains, break websites don't load. We rely on it for
Speaker 6:  everything. But the industry that repairs it keeps things running
Speaker 6:  is basically the same. It's just sort of handled by private companies
Speaker 6:  that have a bunch of contracts with cable owners
Speaker 6:  and they have this arrangement that is sort of, you know,
Speaker 6:  days back half a century maybe, where everyone kind of pays
Speaker 6:  into a organizing body that has a couple ships
Speaker 6:  that stand by and repair any cables that break in a big zone.
Speaker 6:  And like the zone is the Atlantic ocean.
Speaker 5:  It's a big, big zone. Yeah. So how do these cables break?
Speaker 6:  Overwhelmingly, it's people break them, specifically
Speaker 6:  fishing vessels break a lot of cables. You have these
Speaker 6:  dredging nets, troll fishing, they
Speaker 6:  scrape these big hooks across the bottom of the sea with a
Speaker 6:  net and they snap cables all the time.
Speaker 5:  So it's not like a targeted attack on the cable, it's just sort of this gets
Speaker 5:  caught up in the phishing net and snaps kind of thing.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. One of the interest there, there's been hardly any proven
Speaker 6:  hostile attacks on a cable. Okay. It's almost all just sort of accidental
Speaker 6:  damage. You have a fishing, fishing vessel, you have like a
Speaker 6:  ship drags its anchor in the wrong place, things like that. And then you
Speaker 6:  have natural disasters, you have like landslides under the ocean basically
Speaker 6:  earthquakes, volcanoes, weird currents, things like that. And then,
Speaker 6:  you know, if there have been cable breaks that people suspect could maybe
Speaker 6:  be from a malicious actor, but it's never really been proven. The
Speaker 6:  one case I've seen cited was like during World War I when
Speaker 6:  various the UK and and Germany sort of sent people
Speaker 6:  Aho to cut telegraph cables with axes. Other than that, there hasn't
Speaker 6:  really been any documented cases of a, of attack on a cable
Speaker 5:  World war i a lot of fights over TikTok and World War I. Right, right. From,
Speaker 5:  from what I remember. So you, you mentioned the, the maintenance industry
Speaker 5:  here. What does this industry look like? This feels like
Speaker 5:  this incredibly important gigantic job. Like
Speaker 5:  is this, is this a huge teaming industry of huge teaming
Speaker 5:  multinational corporations fixing the internet?
Speaker 6:  It's really not. It's actually quite a small industry like
Speaker 6:  ballpark, maybe a thousand or so people in the direct sort of
Speaker 6:  maritime side of maintenance. Do you have for
Speaker 5:  All 800,000 miles of undersea cables?
Speaker 6:  That's right. Wow. So you have, there's about 70 cable ships in the world,
Speaker 6:  but most of them mostly do installations, which pays better. You have like
Speaker 6:  22 or so dedicated maintenance
Speaker 6:  vessels and they are stationed around the world, you know,
Speaker 6:  a handful per ocean basically. And their
Speaker 6:  job is to, you know, like firefighters stand ready
Speaker 6:  24 hours a day to sail out within 24 hours of being
Speaker 6:  notified of a cable fault. So they belong to these consortiums.
Speaker 6:  They, you know, maybe a couple different maintenance providers have a ship
Speaker 6:  in a given ocean and they cover the whole area. And if you're a cable owner,
Speaker 6:  you call the maintenance provider and say, Hey, I have a cable broken. Send
Speaker 6:  a ship out. And they send a ship app to fix the cable. It's basically
Speaker 6:  how, how it works.
Speaker 5:  Wow. It's like, it's like an adventure story every time they're like, we
Speaker 5:  have to, we have to go explore the depths of the ocean to find a
Speaker 5:  broken garden hose and figure out what to do with it.
Speaker 6:  It really is like drop everything. We go to a random
Speaker 6:  place in the middle of the ocean often. Wow.
Speaker 5:  22 ships strikes me as not a lot of ships
Speaker 5:  to cover a all of the problems you've described and b just the
Speaker 5:  sheer size and scope of all of this. Can they do it with
Speaker 5:  22 ships?
Speaker 6:  So they have done it with 22 ships.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Fair. I guess. Yeah, the internet still works. We're still here. Okay.
Speaker 6:  I think the, the, the concern is that a lot of these ships are getting pretty
Speaker 6:  old. They're like several decades old. There's not a lot of money coming
Speaker 6:  into the industry. And if there were to be a big event
Speaker 6:  like a big earthquake or a deliberate attack on a cable
Speaker 6:  choke point or something like that, then you could have a real disruption.
Speaker 6:  So the ships are really this critical component of the
Speaker 6:  internet that so far have been able to
Speaker 6:  keep things running, but it's pretty lean. If there were a major event, it
Speaker 6:  would be challenging, I think in some cases for them to, to do the job.
Speaker 5:  Okay. And who are these people? Is this like a, is this a sort of
Speaker 5:  manual labor kind of job on a ship? Is this like a
Speaker 5:  incredibly technically complicated job on a ship? Like who,
Speaker 5:  who are these folks doing this work on these ships?
Speaker 6:  It's both manual labor and very technically complicated.
Speaker 6:  You have a mix of, you have crew who are sort of seafarers and run the ship
Speaker 6:  and then you have cable engineers who kind of come from all the
Speaker 6:  kinds of different backgrounds. But the job requires,
Speaker 6:  you have to be quite good at geometry and, and
Speaker 6:  angles and forces and sort of ocean engineering stuff to
Speaker 6:  know how to, you know, pull up a cable from several miles to the
Speaker 6:  bottom of the ocean without things snapping. You're dealing with these big
Speaker 6:  metal hooks that are used to catch the cables, high tensions. It's like quite
Speaker 6:  physically demanding work. And then at its heart
Speaker 6:  it's these various technical tasks that involved with
Speaker 6:  figuring out where the fault is splicing the fibers, which is
Speaker 6:  just ultra precise work that's done. You know, you're
Speaker 6:  fusing two strands of glass end to end with as perfect as you can get
Speaker 6:  a connection. And that stuff is, it's, you know, it's like
Speaker 6:  neurosurgery. It's, it's extremely delicate
Speaker 5:  And you have to do it on a ship in the middle of the ocean,
Speaker 6:  Right? Yeah. On a, on a rocking ship that is in the middle of the ocean.
Speaker 6:  This
Speaker 5:  Is like everything possible on incredibly hard mode at all times.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. It's pretty, as you see the, the workshops zone, it's just like
Speaker 6:  in the belly of a ship sort of surrounded by tarps. It's really not,
Speaker 6:  you know, it's not this fa precision factory that you would wanna be doing
Speaker 6:  this work in.
Speaker 5:  So now I can't help imagining the, the like montage
Speaker 5:  action scene of everybody snapping into action. One of these things happening.
Speaker 5:  So like, walk me through the process a little bit. I'm in port in some
Speaker 5:  centrally located city somewhere waiting for a call. I get a
Speaker 5:  call from, I'm assuming it's like Google and Meta who seem to be the companies
Speaker 5:  that own more and more of these cables over time. They
Speaker 6:  Own a lot of the cables. They've, a lot of the newly built cables are coming
Speaker 6:  from the big, big tech companies, Google and Meta primarily.
Speaker 6:  And then you have cables that are owned by, you know, dozen, sometimes
Speaker 6:  ISPs and telecom companies and things. Got it. Okay. And so
Speaker 6:  each cable will have someone who's in charge of maintenance
Speaker 6:  and you know, they'll get a message from their network
Speaker 6:  operation center saying, Hey, we've got a cable down, here's what we know
Speaker 6:  about it. That person will then call someone at the repair
Speaker 6:  organization. They could be public or private, but it's one of these consortiums
Speaker 6:  usually.
Speaker 5:  I was really hoping there would be like a big red button on somebody's desk
Speaker 5:  that's like cable down and the alarms start going off in the ship somewhere.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It, there are alarms and big red warnings, but then it's a lot of
Speaker 6:  people calling people around the world at weird hours. So they call someone
Speaker 6:  at the, on the maintenance side, that person then calls the ship and says,
Speaker 6:  you know, get ready, we're gonna need X miles of spare
Speaker 6:  cable for this cable system. We think it's here, we think this, cut it,
Speaker 6:  whatever information they have. And then they, and then they kind of plan
Speaker 6:  out what the repairs gonna look like.
Speaker 5:  Okay. And what, what does a repair normally look like? Like walk me through
Speaker 5:  a little bit of what it would look like actually on the boat trying to do
Speaker 5:  the repair.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so the first thing you do is you need to locate where the fault is
Speaker 6:  approximately. And that's done on either end of the cable.
Speaker 6:  Basically you have people in the landing station on
Speaker 6:  either end of the cable, so you, on opposite sides of the ocean, shoot
Speaker 6:  a laser down there, end it hits the brake, reflects
Speaker 6:  back, and the time it takes to come back will tell you pretty much where
Speaker 6:  along the cable the, the brake is.
Speaker 5:  So like wherever the signal dies, that's, that's the point you send them
Speaker 5:  to?
Speaker 6:  Exactly. Okay. And so you sail out to there with a certain
Speaker 6:  amount of spare cable in your ship and a bunch of these big hooks that
Speaker 6:  are called grab mills,
Speaker 5:  Which I Googled by the way. And they just straight up look like Batman's
Speaker 5:  grappling hooks. Like that's just, that's just what they are.
Speaker 6:  That's exactly what they are. And there's a bunch of different kinds. You
Speaker 6:  have like multi gral things. You have ones with giant
Speaker 6:  arms and blades, depending on what the ocean bottom looks like, whether it's
Speaker 6:  muddy or rocky or what cables are laid with such little
Speaker 6:  slack on the seabed that you can't just, you know, hook it and pull it to
Speaker 6:  the surface. Ah, it's too hot. So the first thing you need to do is you
Speaker 6:  need to cut the cable somewhere near where it's broken using one of
Speaker 6:  these ols, but one with a big blade in the middle. So you drag this blade
Speaker 6:  across where you think the cable path is, and then you
Speaker 6:  turn around with one of these gr metals and catch one end of the cable,
Speaker 6:  pull it to the surface, attach it to a buoy, go back to the other
Speaker 6:  side, catch the other side of the cable, bring it to the surface, and then
Speaker 6:  you do the slicing. So you splice like a piece of spare cable to that end,
Speaker 6:  go back to the other side that's attached to the buoy, splice it to that
Speaker 6:  end, and then test it. And you should have a working cable that then you
Speaker 6:  have to lower back down to the ocean floor.
Speaker 5:  So it's basically like you're fishing for cables on the ocean
Speaker 5:  floor, right? Like how do they know if they've caught one?
Speaker 6:  That's exactly right. Like fishing based on just the, the
Speaker 6:  tug on the line. In this case, you have this enormous
Speaker 6:  metal hook that you're dragging along the ocean floor. And as that's
Speaker 6:  happening, someone is in the bridge watching This
Speaker 6:  one dial called the tension meter and watching it waver back
Speaker 6:  and forth. And one of the interesting things about it is it's an analog dial.
Speaker 6:  It's not an ultra precise digital readout because
Speaker 6:  you want that kind of fuzziness to, to, to
Speaker 6:  be able to judge intuitively what's happening. Is tension rising or falling?
Speaker 6:  Is it rising and falling fast or slow that you can't get from a bunch of
Speaker 6:  numbers jumping around? And so you're watching this dial and if it's moving
Speaker 6:  up slowly kind of wavering, maybe you're going through some
Speaker 6:  mud, if it jerks up quickly, maybe you hit a rock.
Speaker 6:  And what you want is this slow increase, slow steady increase in
Speaker 6:  intention that shows you've hooked this cable and you're dragging it along
Speaker 6:  the ocean floor. And that's when you know it's time to reel it in. Interesting
Speaker 5:  Man, that's such a inexact science, but that's like you just
Speaker 5:  described, like an art form more than a piece of sort of data analysis.
Speaker 6:  It really is one of the, one of the engineers I was talking to in Japan.
Speaker 6:  It's, it really is this act of kind of reading what's happening on the ocean
Speaker 6:  floor imagining based on this dial, you know, oh, I'm, I'm going,
Speaker 6:  I am going over a trench. I'm, I've hit a rock. That's
Speaker 5:  Wild. And how long does that process take?
Speaker 6:  Like days to weeks to to months, even if it's hard to find the
Speaker 6:  cable? Everything here is at just a massive scale. So like
Speaker 6:  if you're in deep water, the garden hose is several miles
Speaker 6:  down and just the act of like lowering it down to the ocean floor and hauling
Speaker 6:  it up can take, you know, nearly a day because it's so deep. And then
Speaker 6:  so each step of this process takes several days. Splicing
Speaker 6:  the cable takes about a day. It's just incredibly time consuming. And then
Speaker 6:  so it's like If you don't catch the cable on first try, then, you know, several
Speaker 6:  more days to try again and it adds up pretty soon. You're looking, you're
Speaker 6:  outta sea for weeks. It
Speaker 5:  Just keeps reminding me of one of those movies where there's like, there's
Speaker 5:  the one shark that they're trying to catch and they're like, we think we
Speaker 5:  found it, it's over here. And then they go and they don't get it and it's
Speaker 5:  like, oh, okay, well we think we know where it'll be next. And it is this
Speaker 5:  like sort of perpetual cat and mouse game that you're playing with this thing,
Speaker 5:  trying to get it into your arms and then you can do something with it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's remarkable how little visibility, you know, they have onto
Speaker 6:  the ocean floor and what's happening down there. Yeah. You know, there are
Speaker 6:  times when people are doing, you know, a dozen passes back and forth
Speaker 6:  Wow. Being like, well that wasn't there. Maybe it's a mile that way and let's
Speaker 6:  try over here. And
Speaker 5:  That's, that's nuts. Why don't we know better? This is one of the things
Speaker 5:  I, I found myself wondering, reading your story is I feel like I
Speaker 5:  could make a solid argument that the location of these
Speaker 5:  cables should be like, closely held state secrets that no one
Speaker 5:  knows that because they're so important to the way that the world works that
Speaker 5:  they should be, you know, it should be like the, the bunkers where the president
Speaker 5:  goes. Like you just, it just should be all classified information on the
Speaker 5:  other side. I can imagine a world in which we should do much more work to
Speaker 5:  have much better knowledge of how these things work and where they are and
Speaker 5:  what's going on with them because they're so important and because laying
Speaker 5:  them and fixing them needs to happen so quickly. But it, it seems like we're
Speaker 5:  in sort of a weird middle between those two things. We're like, we kind of
Speaker 5:  know, but not really.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's a trade off. So you can go and you can see tele
Speaker 6:  geography tracks, cables. You can see kind of broadly where they are in the
Speaker 6:  ocean. If you're like a sea captain, you
Speaker 6:  get charts that have cable areas marks, you know, with some degree of
Speaker 6:  precision. And that makes a lot of sense because the biggest
Speaker 6:  actual threat to cables is someone accidentally dropping an anchor on them.
Speaker 6:  And so If you are worried about an attack and you make the most secret, you're
Speaker 6:  probably gonna increase the number of accidental cable breaks. On the other
Speaker 6:  hand, they are vulnerable. It would be fairly,
Speaker 6:  you know, you don't need a low tech attack, you can just drag an anchor across
Speaker 6:  the ocean floor. In practice the network is redundant enough, you're still
Speaker 6:  talking about like a really small thing in a big ocean. So it's not quite
Speaker 6:  that easy to attack. It would take a pretty sophisticated antagonist
Speaker 6:  to actually cause a catastrophic cable outage.
Speaker 6:  So, so far it's been fine, but it is a topic of active debate,
Speaker 6:  I think in, in, in governments, what should we do? How should we protect
Speaker 6:  these cables that are, are so important and
Speaker 5:  For the people whose job it is to actually maintain them
Speaker 5:  over time, what is life like? You talk to a bunch of people who are sort
Speaker 5:  of in this industry and in some cases have been for a very long time. Right.
Speaker 5:  What's it like to be a sort of superhero keeping the internet running?
Speaker 6:  It's a very strange job. People, you know, when they join they
Speaker 6:  tend to kind of stumble into it. It's not a very well known industry.
Speaker 6:  And so you have people who are working as cable engineers in some other
Speaker 6:  area or you know, in Merchant Marines or, or something like that.
Speaker 6:  Geologists in optics. And they sort of stumble into it
Speaker 6:  and you know, if they, if they stay for a bit, they tend to stay for a long
Speaker 6:  time, like decades, a lot of the work is earned on, learned on the job.
Speaker 6:  And so people tend to sort of move around between different roles. But it's
Speaker 6:  not an easy job. It's a weird lifestyle. You rotate
Speaker 6:  in and off ships, you're often far from home out of contact.
Speaker 6:  You know, this is changing now a bit with starlink, but like when you're
Speaker 6:  on board one of these ships historically you're pretty much cut off. You
Speaker 6:  don't have great internet connections. You can't stream things
Speaker 6:  or, or FaceTime or anything like that.
Speaker 5:  You have the fast internet literally in your hands. You just can't do anything
Speaker 5:  with it.
Speaker 6:  Right, exactly. It's a difficult job. Just the lifestyle's hard, but
Speaker 6:  people come to love it because it takes you to very
Speaker 6:  unusual places. It's exciting and a lot of them have like
Speaker 6:  a real sense of purpose. They're maintaining this infrastructure that the
Speaker 6:  modern world runs on, even if no one actually knows about it or what they
Speaker 6:  do. Knowing
Speaker 5:  You as I do, I'm, I'm confident that at some point in reporting this story,
Speaker 5:  you tried to live the cable maintenance life yourself
Speaker 5:  and you were like, yes, I will live the ship life. How close did you get?
Speaker 6:  Not that close. I did try, you know, when I first heard about this
Speaker 6:  industry, I was like, well, I should go on board for repair and was basically
Speaker 6:  laughed out the room several times, you know, for various reasons. The big
Speaker 6:  one was security. It's a, it's a secretive industry. They just
Speaker 6:  can't have a journalist hanging out on a cable ship in most cases. And then
Speaker 6:  the other very compelling reason was that they don't know how long they'll
Speaker 6:  be gone. So like, yeah, you can come along, but maybe we'll be gone for a
Speaker 6:  week or two and maybe we'll get called off to another repair and you'll be
Speaker 6:  at sea for months. Which is just, you know, hard to really plan around.
Speaker 6:  That's
Speaker 5:  Fair. So were you, were you able to get any kind of firsthand glimpse into
Speaker 5:  this life?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, So I ended up going to Japan to
Speaker 6:  talk to people who work at KCS and going aboard the
Speaker 6:  ocean link, which was the ship that repaired a lot of the cables
Speaker 6:  in Japan after the 2011 earthquake and tsunami.
Speaker 6:  And so it was in port for a period of time and I was able to go there and,
Speaker 6:  and visit the crew and, and get a tour of the ship.
Speaker 5:  What was the ship like?
Speaker 6:  It was fairly big, like 400 foot long sort of
Speaker 6:  tall working ship. It's from the nineties, it's kind of old
Speaker 6:  at this point, but well maintained. I'm
Speaker 5:  Imagining sort of a big fishing vessel, but instead of
Speaker 5:  like nets and containers, it just has a massive spool of cable
Speaker 6:  That's basically right. It essentially is a massive spool of cable. Like
Speaker 6:  the middle of it are these, I think three big empty
Speaker 6:  tanks that are just kind of spindles of wound spare cable. The interior
Speaker 6:  is really empty. It's kind of like a, it's built kind of like an aircraft
Speaker 6:  carrier or something where there's no sort of beams or, or struts or anything
Speaker 6:  because it's all just, you have to string cable outta these tanks to
Speaker 6:  the workstation and then out to the front where there's kind of a rolling
Speaker 6:  pulley kind of thing where it goes over and into the ocean.
Speaker 5:  Got it. So it pulls it up and then you sort of spool from the middle boy.
Speaker 5:  It's what a complicated system.
Speaker 6:  It's counterintuitive how the, how the ship is put together and how it all
Speaker 6:  works. But it makes sense when it's you're working with a material that is
Speaker 6:  thousands of miles long and it just creates all these weird logistical problems.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So you mentioned the, the Fukushima incident in 2011 in Japan,
Speaker 5:  which was a big part of the story that you wrote, kind of how they
Speaker 5:  repaired and the reaction to all of this. What was it about those
Speaker 5:  repairs that was sort of different? I feel like you, you found one of the
Speaker 5:  hardest cases you could have to tell this story about what happened in that
Speaker 5:  case.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so there are a few, there have been a few major, major cable
Speaker 6:  events. This was one of them. They tend to be earthquakes that caused the
Speaker 6:  most damage. So, so in this case there was this very, very large
Speaker 6:  earthquake off the coast of Japan that sent a large tsunami that caused
Speaker 6:  immense devastation. And part of that, that tsunami
Speaker 6:  knocked out the Fukushima nuclear reactor causing a nuclear meltdown. So
Speaker 6:  you have this disaster on top of a disaster and then you have the other disaster,
Speaker 6:  which is not really well known but happened at the same time,
Speaker 6:  which is that the earthquake caused all of these submarine avalanches
Speaker 6:  that wrecked the majority of the cables Japan uses to
Speaker 6:  connect to North America. Oh wow. And the rest of the world. And so while
Speaker 6:  the earthquake tsunami recovery was happening, while Fukushima was,
Speaker 6:  you know, people were trying to bring Fukushima under control, the ship
Speaker 6:  had to set out and try to fix these cables as fast as possible
Speaker 6:  while contending with the fact that there may or may not be a cloud of radiation
Speaker 6:  over them. So
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean again, it just feels like so much of this process is just unknowns
Speaker 5:  on top of unknowns on top of unknowns. It's just going out and trying to
Speaker 5:  figure out, okay, something happened to these cables, we don't know what
Speaker 5:  or where or what it's gonna take or how we're gonna fix it.
Speaker 5:  And just bit by bit they just solve it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's really just, it's very methodical. Like you, like you've just
Speaker 6:  gotta kind of follow the steps. And so they ki they, they looked at the cable
Speaker 6:  map, they figured out, okay, based on the timing of these faults, you know,
Speaker 6:  interestingly a lot of them happened hours after the tsunami. Like, like
Speaker 6:  that night basically you have these big debris flows that
Speaker 6:  sort of barrel down these canyons and, and end up wrecking the cables. And
Speaker 6:  from the timing of the breaks, they figure out that's probably what happens.
Speaker 6:  The seabed is probably very transformed. They're gonna need a lot of spare
Speaker 6:  cable and typically you figure out, you know, it's not
Speaker 6:  usually up to the maintenance provider which cables they fix first. It's
Speaker 6:  usually kind of first come first served from the cable owners, whoever calls
Speaker 6:  in their fault first. But in this case the cable owners are like, you guys
Speaker 6:  figure it out. Like whatever, whatever cable you can fix,
Speaker 6:  fix it. And so they settled on, you know, the one farthest from Fukushima.
Speaker 6:  'cause the other thing is that normally in a big event like this, other ships
Speaker 6:  arrived to help, but there was so little known about what was
Speaker 6:  happening with Fukushima and no one felt comfortable sending their crews
Speaker 6:  into that. And so they were sort of the only ones doing it for the first,
Speaker 6:  the first period of time.
Speaker 5:  So, and then there was a moment in the Fukushima
Speaker 5:  response where they had pulled the cable up and then couldn't figure
Speaker 5:  out what to do with it. Right. Am I what, what happens here? You get the
Speaker 5:  cable up above the ocean and then you have to figure out what to do. What
Speaker 5:  did they do?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so this was the first repair. They hooked this cable and they
Speaker 6:  start reeling it in and it's under an unusual amount of tension. And
Speaker 6:  basically what happens, you know, they, they start reeling in very, very
Speaker 6:  slowly because every cable has a certain amount of tension. You don't wanna
Speaker 6:  exceed it 'cause the cable could snap. And so they're just moving very, very
Speaker 6:  slowly and it takes them nearly a day to get it to the surface. Wow. And
Speaker 6:  what they learn when it gets there is that it's in just been
Speaker 6:  completely mangled. And, and what they think happened is some
Speaker 6:  enormous landslide happened. It dragged the cable, it buried it
Speaker 6:  under a bunch of debris. And now they've been slowly pulling it tighter and
Speaker 6:  tighter and tighter until it reaches the surface. Now they can see
Speaker 6:  it, it's on the front of the ship, it's on the, the four deck and it is
Speaker 6:  hooked around one bar with the grapnel and totally stripped and mangled
Speaker 6:  and under a huge amount of tension. And so you
Speaker 5:  Basically at this point have like a thousands of miles long bungee cord like
Speaker 5:  sitting on your boat.
Speaker 6:  Exactly, yes. Exactly. Attached to a heavy metal hook that if
Speaker 6:  the bungee cord snaps, which it's being strained, it's sort of each wave
Speaker 6:  and, and, and swell, it will fly across the ship, kill anyone, it
Speaker 6:  hits smash into the cable control room, just do immense damage.
Speaker 6:  And so the priority becomes, you know, you can't repair a cable under this
Speaker 6:  kind of tension that's this damaged. They need to get it off the ship. And
Speaker 6:  so they do this sort of complicated precarious procedure
Speaker 6:  where they, they hook chains around each side of the cable,
Speaker 6:  swap the grapnel out for a blade of grapnel, lower it back over the
Speaker 6:  bow of the ship while they've evacuated the area. And then once it's under
Speaker 6:  the water, they release the chains, the cable is cut and goes back to the
Speaker 6:  bottom and, and they start over.
Speaker 5:  That feels like a really interesting test case. 'cause you know, like you
Speaker 5:  said, these cables go back a century, but 2011 is very much
Speaker 5:  like the internet. And as we've learned, you know, catastrophes
Speaker 5:  happen, things like this happen all the time in lots of places. That was
Speaker 5:  a particularly bad one. But like earthquakes happen, we just had one in New York.
Speaker 5:  Like, these are things that happen. Did that, were there any sort of lessons
Speaker 5:  learned from that? Like do you, do you feel like whatever, 13 years after
Speaker 5:  that we're in a different era of how we think about undersea
Speaker 5:  cables?
Speaker 6:  Yes and no. I mean, it's interesting to look back on the coverage of 2011.
Speaker 6:  Like a lot of the, when the internet was mentioned, it was usually that,
Speaker 6:  you know, this is remarkable. The internet fared remarkably well. It stayed
Speaker 6:  up.
Speaker 5:  Oh really? So for all the, for all the issues, the internet stayed up in
Speaker 5:  Japan.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And, and so you have these reports and, and people were basically
Speaker 6:  just, you could only use the internet to communicate in the immediate aftermath.
Speaker 6:  People were sending emails, they were tweeting, people were posting videos,
Speaker 6:  other telecommunications were cut out. Like the, the terrestrial cables were
Speaker 6:  cut, the cell towers were wrecked. And so they were really reliant on the
Speaker 6:  internet. But you talk to the people who were at the operation centers and
Speaker 6:  on the ships and it was so much more precarious than
Speaker 6:  people knew. Basically they had succeeded in rerouting all
Speaker 6:  the traffic over the remaining cables. But if one of those cables had gone
Speaker 6:  down, you would've started to see a real degradation in service. You would've,
Speaker 6:  you know, things would've started to drop. It would've been difficult to
Speaker 6:  communicate. And so it was sort of right on the cusp of being a
Speaker 6:  communications disaster. And the lesson that the industry learned from that
Speaker 6:  is, is largely around redundancy. Hmm. There's not like a real
Speaker 6:  geographic reason unlike the Red Sea or the Luon
Speaker 6:  Strait or something. There's not a geographic reason why all the cables
Speaker 6:  were in one place there. It was just sort of haven't, like we'd
Speaker 6:  always put cables there. Sure. And they always kind of landed at the spot.
Speaker 6:  And so that makes sense. And so you had this, these sort of choke points
Speaker 6:  that then when a landslide comes through, it wrecks a bunch of them
Speaker 6:  and there's more of an awareness that you need multiple landing points.
Speaker 6:  But in practice that doesn't always happen because it's, you know,
Speaker 6:  cheaper to follow known routes or, or whatever.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So where, where does it feel like this industry is right now? Obviously
Speaker 5:  it's as critical as ever, if not more so. Like the world relies on this
Speaker 5:  stuff more than we ever have. And I feel like it purely anecdotally,
Speaker 5:  I've heard more about undersea cable projects just
Speaker 5:  in the last couple of years I feel like than I ever have. And
Speaker 5:  that might just be because I pay attention to companies like Google and Meta
Speaker 5:  and they're doing a lot of this stuff. But is there, is there energy in
Speaker 5:  this space to increase from, you know, 500 cables and
Speaker 5:  800,000 miles to, are we gonna have more than that or multiples of that
Speaker 5:  over time, do you think?
Speaker 6:  There we are in a cable boom right now. There's a lot of new cables going
Speaker 6:  in. Whether that means the net number of cables goes up is a
Speaker 6:  debate debated topic because the cables are also
Speaker 6:  higher and higher capacity. So some think maybe there'll be
Speaker 6:  fewer of cables, they'll just be really, really, really high bandwidth. But,
Speaker 6:  but there are a lot of new cables going in that's driven by the tech
Speaker 6:  companies primi primarily, which starting a couple years ago decided,
Speaker 6:  you know, rather than purchase bandwidth on these cables, let's have
Speaker 6:  our own cables. And so they started laying their own systems
Speaker 6:  largely between their data centers. And the reason for that is that they
Speaker 6:  need a ton of capacity to kind of sync all of their data centers around
Speaker 6:  the world to keep these like huge content libraries up to keep their cloud
Speaker 6:  services running. And so they wanted to kind of that all under their own
Speaker 6:  umbrella. But that hasn't really spilled over into the
Speaker 6:  maintenance side yet. It's mostly kind of the installation side.
Speaker 5:  I was gonna say, are we still at, we're still at 22 ships.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Still not a lot of new ships there. And, and you know, while the new
Speaker 6:  cables do provide a lot of redundancy, you also don't want, you know,
Speaker 6:  your handful of super high capacity cables to go down. 'cause it, it's
Speaker 6:  difficult to, to sort of move that track traffic over onto other routes.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Did as you were talking to people, did you get a sense that there are
Speaker 5:  new kinds of threats to these cables too? Whether it's some of the ones that
Speaker 5:  have been there a long time getting old and not getting replaced quickly
Speaker 5:  enough or climate change or like the geopolitics of the
Speaker 5:  internet, which are becoming a bigger and bigger deal all the time. I, is
Speaker 5:  there a sense that this could get worse rather than better
Speaker 5:  as we fight about undersea cables?
Speaker 6:  Geopolitics are the big thing. Climate change will make certain things harder.
Speaker 6:  All these cables all land on coastline, which is eroding
Speaker 6:  and and sinking and that will be a problem. But part of the reason you're
Speaker 6:  also hearing more about cables is the geopolitics around them have become
Speaker 6:  really sensitive. Largely that has been China
Speaker 6:  US conflicts. You have the US saying we don't want Chinese
Speaker 6:  owned cables landing in the US and
Speaker 6:  China also denying repair permits for the South China Sea
Speaker 6:  or, or sort of slowing them down and
Speaker 6:  concerns about routing cables through China's waters
Speaker 6:  or into Hong Kong has caused this kind of reconfiguration of
Speaker 6:  the, the network. You have alternate routes going through the
Speaker 6:  Philippines or a lot of cables landing in Singapore or
Speaker 6:  China trying to build up its own cable maritime industry
Speaker 6:  so that it doesn't have to rely on, on, on the west. And these changes
Speaker 6:  are making it, it's not necessarily harder but very
Speaker 6:  different. It's just a period of change in the industry and, and kind of
Speaker 6:  one that is increasing, getting, increasing attention from,
Speaker 6:  from various governments that more governments are saying we need to control
Speaker 6:  this infrastructure in some way.
Speaker 5:  So, and as you talk to people in this small kind of under
Speaker 5:  talked about and under-resourced industry, is the sense that given all
Speaker 5:  of that it is just change and this is stable and this is how we're gonna
Speaker 5:  keep doing things? Or did you, do you run into people who are like, screw
Speaker 5:  all of this, the answer is satellites and we have to get there as quickly
Speaker 5:  as we possibly can or like, is this just what it is and we have to figure
Speaker 5:  out how to do it better?
Speaker 6:  There's a fair amount of concern I think about the long-term
Speaker 6:  sustainability of the industry. It can't all be satellites. That was the,
Speaker 6:  the other thing that everyone reminded me of. Satellites can
Speaker 6:  carry like half a percent of the global traffic. It's, it's gonna be
Speaker 6:  cables. They're, they're just way more efficient and cheaper to
Speaker 6:  transmit data. There's a sense that they will have to navigate this. I think
Speaker 6:  the industry has been pretty stable for
Speaker 6:  decades and there's some anxiety about these changes. The big
Speaker 6:  tech companies coming in, governments taking a greater interest.
Speaker 6:  The sort of geopolitical jockeying around cable,
Speaker 6:  cable routes that are just gonna be tricky. I think
Speaker 6:  a lot of the anxiety comes from kind of the market
Speaker 6:  forces involved. Like the big tech companies, they have so
Speaker 6:  much buying power, they can drive down prices and so they can negotiate lower
Speaker 6:  rates. And so while that means maintenance companies can operate
Speaker 6:  year to year, it Maybe it means they don't have enough to invest in a new
Speaker 6:  vessel. And so you have this kind of slow degradation, which also means that
Speaker 6:  they have trouble recruiting 'cause no one wants to join this sort of aging
Speaker 6:  fleet. Sure,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Having done this whole process of, of reporting and
Speaker 5:  sort of understanding how this world works, has it changed the way you think
Speaker 5:  about the internet? Like I feel like the more I learn about the actual
Speaker 5:  infrastructure of the internet, the more remarkable it seems that any of
Speaker 5:  this ever actually works. And, and I feel like I got some of that
Speaker 5:  sense from your story that on the one hand this is this incredibly robust,
Speaker 5:  incredibly impressive group of people working on this thing that we
Speaker 5:  understand and have worked on for a long time. On the other hand, the internet
Speaker 5:  is forever like one wayward anchor away from falling apart.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's really, it's one of these cases I feel like you hear about everybody
Speaker 6:  so often. Like the ways in which the internet is just sort of
Speaker 6:  this cobbled together apparatus is way
Speaker 6:  less stable than, than it seems. This is just sort of an ordinary user.
Speaker 6:  It does depend on, on just sort of these, these random people. Whether
Speaker 6:  it's like a software engineer who's keeping things running or
Speaker 6:  these people who are really good at, you know, catching internet cables
Speaker 6:  with hooks in the ocean that, you know, if it weren't for their
Speaker 6:  sort of largely invisible work, the the system would fall apart.
Speaker 5:  Welcome back for years now I've been conflicted
Speaker 5:  about these delivery apps like DoorDash and Uber Eats. They are super
Speaker 5:  convenient and they're helpful and sometimes I don't want to cook or go out
Speaker 5:  and most of us don't live within walking distance of a million good restaurants.
Speaker 5:  Like, I get it, I get why they're helpful and good, but I also
Speaker 5:  can't shake this idea that actually these services are bad and they're
Speaker 5:  bad for everyone involved. They make your meals more expensive, often
Speaker 5:  more than you know, through sneaky price increases. Like the
Speaker 5:  menu on Uber Eats is sometimes just more expensive than the menu
Speaker 5:  at the restaurant. They also don't pay delivery people enough or
Speaker 5:  offer them the protections or benefits that the people who work there should
Speaker 5:  get. And for the most part, historically speaking, they're not even a very
Speaker 5:  good business for the companies running them. It's hard to make money
Speaker 5:  for anybody, including the restaurants, the drivers, everybody.
Speaker 5:  It just seems bad. So what are we doing here? Anyway, A couple of
Speaker 5:  weeks ago there was this guy who went viral online because of some posters
Speaker 5:  he had put up around Seattle saying basically skip the apps, call me
Speaker 5:  instead I'll deliver your food. He became kind of a folk hero
Speaker 5:  online. So we sent our producer will pour to go see what's going on.
Speaker 7:  This is one of those stories that exists because of a perfect storm type
Speaker 7:  situation. Here's what happened for years gig workers
Speaker 7:  here in Seattle, notably delivery drivers have been pissed at the lousy
Speaker 7:  pay they've been earning in this very expensive city. So in
Speaker 7:  2022, the city council stepped in and mandated a higher pay
Speaker 7:  rate for app-based delivery workers.
Speaker 8:  It's a good day for gig workers. As the city of Seattle's new ordinance takes
Speaker 8:  effect.
Speaker 7:  The new pay scale went into effect this past January and the apps
Speaker 7:  didn't take the change graciously
Speaker 9:  In reaction apps like Uber Eats and DoorDash began charging
Speaker 9:  customers $5 in what they're calling a local operating fee.
Speaker 7:  That's on top of the service fees and delivery fees that apps
Speaker 7:  routinely charged to say nothing of. Tips and customers are
Speaker 7:  finding their limits. Fewer people are ordering from the apps, gig
Speaker 7:  workers are feeling even more squeezed and everyone is pointing fingers at
Speaker 7:  everyone else.
Speaker 10:  Food delivery orders plummeting. Since Seattle implemented new minimum
Speaker 10:  wage requirements for delivery workers a month ago,
Speaker 7:  This kind of battle is playing out in other markets too. New York City enacted
Speaker 7:  similar rules last year, which the apps have also been fighting tooth and
Speaker 7:  nail. But there's one thing Seattle has that no one else does.
Speaker 7:  A guy named Tony Isles, who I am trying to literally chase down
Speaker 7:  right now,
Speaker 11:  I always carry like a tennis ball in my pocket for like the round fluidity
Speaker 11:  of a ball. I just like the idea of like, when I was in San Francisco, I
Speaker 11:  had a conversation with my buddy and I was like, do you think shapes have
Speaker 11:  thoughts? And I think I do. I think they do. I think that they influence
Speaker 11:  the way that you think. Yeah. And I, I always carry that tennis ball, So
Speaker 11:  I always feel like I have like a fluid mind.
Speaker 7:  Tony is telling me this while flying across downtown Seattle on a rented
Speaker 7:  e-bike in the pouring rain, I'm on my own rental trying to
Speaker 7:  listen and keep up at the same time. We're weaving in and out of bike
Speaker 7:  lanes, dodging construction and crashing through puddles that could be
Speaker 7:  potholes.
Speaker 7:  It's chaos, which is partly the setting and partly
Speaker 7:  Tony's fluid mind. In the first 30 minutes or so of pedaling we have
Speaker 7:  talked about Maslow's hierarchy of needs, China's social credit
Speaker 7:  score and the Stanford Prison experiment. And I haven't asked any of the
Speaker 7:  questions I came to ask.
Speaker 11:  There's this idea called the method of Lokey. I don't don't know If you
Speaker 11:  know what that is. I
Speaker 7:  Don't. It's
Speaker 11:  Like this way of remembering things verbatim historically
Speaker 11:  in like these ancient societies. It was asked this, this book that I read,
Speaker 11:  it was called Moonwalking with Einstein, take a left.
Speaker 7:  Hey, if we get separated for any reason, just go finish your delivery
Speaker 7:  and text me when you're done. I'll, I'll find you again. All right.
Speaker 11:  Okay. Oh, 'cause I'm hustling.
Speaker 7:  Well, I just realized that I signed up to do a story about a delivery guy.
Speaker 11:  You're all right
Speaker 7:  Man. And I don't know how I expected this to go, but it's
Speaker 11:  A pleasure meeting you. I
Speaker 7:  Got, I gotta up my game here.
Speaker 7:  Tony's backstory is pretty simple. He was driving for Uber
Speaker 7:  Eats when those new fees suddenly killed demand. So at the beginning
Speaker 7:  of February, he decided to go it alone. He put up some very
Speaker 7:  DIY flyers downtown with an offer, text him a food order
Speaker 7:  from any restaurant within a couple square miles and he'll get it to you
Speaker 7:  for five bucks. No taking a cut from restaurants, no service
Speaker 7:  fee, no delivery fee, no local operating fee.
Speaker 7:  Just a tip if you're feeling generous. He went viral pretty much instantly.
Speaker 12:  Right now on Kro seven tonight, growing frustrations for Seattle's new food
Speaker 12:  delivery rules.
Speaker 11:  One
Speaker 10:  Driver, it becomes his boss's competitor.
Speaker 11:  I
Speaker 7:  Think I now, just a few weeks later, Tony is a full on local
Speaker 7:  celebrity. He's all over the news, Reddit, Twitter slash
Speaker 7:  x, and he says the orders have followed. The biggest challenge is cadence.
Speaker 7:  He might get five texts all at once and then nothing for a while. So he's
Speaker 7:  trying to figure that out along with the fame. Has this amount of attention
Speaker 7:  been weird? Oh,
Speaker 11:  It's crazy. I mean, it's just like all of a sudden my opinion matters.
Speaker 11:  And a lot of people are asking me, they're just like, how much money are
Speaker 11:  you making? And I'm like,
Speaker 7:  Right,
Speaker 11:  Right. I'm like, well, I'm not a monetary guy, I'm not a business
Speaker 11:  oriented person. But what's interesting is, is like I feel like I've
Speaker 11:  introduced a solution for like a social thing.
Speaker 7:  Tony's social solution goes something like this because of apps
Speaker 7:  like Uber Eats and DoorDash. Yes, delivery has gotten expensive,
Speaker 7:  but more than that it's gotten rushed and sloppy and impersonal.
Speaker 7:  It's just bad vibes all the way down. And it's ruining takeout for
Speaker 7:  everyone.
Speaker 11:  It's such a hard position to be in.
Speaker 7:  For who?
Speaker 11:  For, for everybody. Every party that's involved, the restaurants, the city,
Speaker 11:  the people that are working as a deliverer, they're in this terrible
Speaker 11:  toxic relationship with somebody.
Speaker 7:  Like the restaurant owners and the apps and the apps and the drivers and
Speaker 7:  just like that whole, that whole thing.
Speaker 11:  Well just like think about it, last time you went into a restaurant and
Speaker 11:  some driver goes in and is like cuts in front of you and you're just like,
Speaker 11:  what in the world? Like, hey man, I've been standing here for five minutes.
Speaker 11:  What do you, what do you, what's your problem? You know that that person
Speaker 11:  is, they're like, they're hustling, right? So they're going in and they're
Speaker 11:  not thinking about that at all because that's not their psychology.
Speaker 7:  No. They gotta keep moving.
Speaker 11:  Right?
Speaker 7:  And from where Tony's standing, the apps are moving in precisely the wrong
Speaker 7:  direction.
Speaker 11:  I think that they, the apps have this kind of misaligned misdirection
Speaker 11:  of where they think the market is and what, what they're planning for. I
Speaker 11:  think that their whole goal is to like send robots to the buildings and
Speaker 11:  you know, send automated cars. And it's like, okay, well if
Speaker 11:  that's your solution then you might bleed for a while, right? Like, and
Speaker 11:  so it's like, yeah, I'm not a monetary guy, but I, I could tell you how
Speaker 11:  to make it work a little bit better.
Speaker 7:  Tony's whole thing is to strip all the tech and anonymity outta the process
Speaker 7:  and be your friendly neighborhood delivery guy. And he thinks people will
Speaker 7:  actively prefer a more social alternative even if that care and attention
Speaker 7:  limits him. I'm
Speaker 11:  Almost like kind of certain, once I get to a certain number of people that
Speaker 11:  order from me, I almost kind of want to cap it to kind of ensure
Speaker 11:  the law of of Dunbar
Speaker 7:  Dunbar's number is another favorite Tony topic. It's a theoretical limit
Speaker 7:  to the number of social relationships any one person can maintain.
Speaker 7:  You wanna cap the number of people that order from you so that you can
Speaker 7:  stop and chat for a couple of minutes so you can get to know repeat
Speaker 7:  customers
Speaker 11:  Wouldn't even call 'em customers. I would just, I would just call them my
Speaker 11:  friends, the homies, you know? There you go. Yeah, they're, they're literally
Speaker 11:  like, yo, Tony, can you get this for me? And I think that's kind of the
Speaker 11:  thing is, is like when you try to turn it into a business to customer relationship
Speaker 11:  versus a person to person relationship, they're not gonna be as understanding.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. If I, if I forget your drink right now, someone will be like, Tony,
Speaker 11:  it's fine. Yeah. You don't have to go back to Chipotle. Totally. But if
Speaker 11:  I forget on Uber Eats, they're gonna be like, yo man, what's going on here?
Speaker 7:  In short, Tony thinks that there is a whole lot more to delivery than speed
Speaker 7:  and cost. But yes, he is cheaper than the competition
Speaker 7:  and often faster too.
Speaker 11:  I've never seen anybody run through a target. I picked up somebody's target
Speaker 11:  stuff and I was running through the target.
Speaker 11:  I'm gonna run here real quick. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I follow Tony as he makes two, maybe three deliveries back to back
Speaker 7:  some chicken and a shake from Dave's hot chicken. Hey, is
Speaker 11:  It, does it come with a drink or anything? Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Lemme get a salad from a Healthy Bowl place called Evergreens.
Speaker 7:  I'm honestly not a hundred percent sure it was such a blur, but at each
Speaker 7:  pickup and drop off, Tony lives up to his own pitch. He's
Speaker 7:  courteous, warm, casual and chatty.
Speaker 11:  So man, how you doing? Today
Speaker 7:  We pull up to our next destination, a big apartment building and while we
Speaker 7:  wait in the lobby for Tony's customer, sorry, his homie to come down,
Speaker 7:  he's recognized by a stranger.
Speaker 11:  You're the guy. Thank. Yeah, I am. Nice. Nice to meet you. Sweet.
Speaker 7:  I stop and chat with Tony's homie for a few minutes. How far away? He says
Speaker 7:  that he and his roommates have ordered from Tony maybe 10 times in the past
Speaker 7:  month.
Speaker 13:  I was just scrolling through Reddit one day and then I saw someone posting
Speaker 13:  a, they posted a picture of one of his flyers that were posted like in
Speaker 13:  the city and I was like, oh that's pretty interesting. It's cheaper than
Speaker 13:  DoorDash. So I was like, let me give it a try. And then ever since it's
Speaker 13:  like been me and my roommates I go to.
Speaker 7:  Oh nice. So you guys are like serious regulars at this point.
Speaker 13:  Like I'm saying like between the three of us type thing.
Speaker 7:  And were you Uber eats DoorDash people before that?
Speaker 13:  Yeah, exactly. DoorDash mainly. And then it was just like got expensive
Speaker 13:  so we're like, let's see what else? There's,
Speaker 7:  What's the like the Tony experience like and how is it different from
Speaker 7:  the, the apps?
Speaker 13:  I think it's a lot nicer because first of all, all you have to do is just
Speaker 13:  like text him. So that's already a lot easier. He's much faster.
Speaker 13:  And then it's always nice like having like a quick conversation with him
Speaker 13:  and like the lobby, he always waits. He's fun to talk to. He is a, he's
Speaker 13:  a very chill guy. Like we've had some nice conversations. It's cool.
Speaker 7:  At the end of the lunch rush, Tony and I sat down at a cafe to talk some
Speaker 7:  more. I went into the story wanting to know whether a guy like Tony
Speaker 7:  can make it, Seattle's minimum wage is almost $20 an hour.
Speaker 7:  So to match that he'd need four deliveries an hour, not accounting for tips,
Speaker 7:  which after seeing him in action definitely feels doable. But it
Speaker 7:  is a hustle. In other words, it's still gig work and
Speaker 7:  Tony's only working the lunch and dinner rushes right now. So after this
Speaker 7:  whole adventure, my question remains can he make it?
Speaker 7:  It turns out that is Tony's least favorite question.
Speaker 11:  I'm looking at it as like I just understand people, you know people, they
Speaker 11:  all have their perspectives and all I'm trying to be is the glue that glues
Speaker 11:  you in that connective tissue so that that way you can get off Reddit and
Speaker 11:  stop arguing about how much money I'm making, get off Reddit
Speaker 11:  and stop arguing whether it's gonna be financially responsible. I can figure
Speaker 11:  that out on my own.
Speaker 7:  I get the sense that Tony has become a kind of avatar.
Speaker 7:  Everyone's putting all their thoughts and feelings about the gig economy
Speaker 7:  onto him. I think that's why his story blew up online. If
Speaker 7:  you're frustrated by big powerful companies making life more annoying,
Speaker 7:  he is the folk hero to root for, which is just way too
Speaker 7:  much for Tony to take on.
Speaker 11:  All of a sudden, like people are texting me and they're like, you got a
Speaker 11:  great business mind. And I'm like, what are you talking about? And I think
Speaker 11:  that what people are trying to do, they're trying to box me. They're trying
Speaker 11:  to say Tony fits here. And I think what they're, they're lacking of
Speaker 11:  understanding is, is like, I actually don't fit anywhere.
Speaker 11:  I'm this like round ball that's just rolling down the street. Like
Speaker 7:  The one in your pocket.
Speaker 11:  That's exactly, exactly.
Speaker 7:  Tony has no idea whether Tony delivers will make it or
Speaker 7:  what will happen to food delivery more broadly. He just knows that something
Speaker 7:  needs to change.
Speaker 11:  Like what they tried to do is they tried to put food on a conveyor belt
Speaker 11:  and deliver it like an Amazon package and it's not gonna work. They're winning
Speaker 11:  right now, but at the end of the day it's not gonna work. It's too
Speaker 11:  expensive. They're like waiting for things to be solved and
Speaker 11:  they're hoping, they're hoping that somebody down the line is like
Speaker 11:  intelligence is gonna hit that S-curve. They're gonna be able to plug in
Speaker 11:  the robots and they're going to, they're gonna be able to do it. And I'm
Speaker 11:  here to tell you it's not gonna work.
Speaker 7:  As kg as Tony is about his own future, he will say that he's
Speaker 7:  been fielding calls from all over the country, people who have heard his
Speaker 7:  story and wanna do what he does.
Speaker 11:  So it's like, all right, well how can I then be the energizer bunny
Speaker 11:  for some things that we do like and that we do think about and maybe that
Speaker 11:  I can kind of more positively impact in a different sense.
Speaker 11:  Just giving people the right direction, energizing their buddy,
Speaker 11:  you know, so to speak. Giving them the battery to to to kind of the right
Speaker 11:  mindset.
Speaker 7:  So what does this all reveal about the gig economy? Well, Tony
Speaker 7:  has clearly tapped into something and in spite of his grander
Speaker 7:  pronouncements, what he's saying is pretty straightforward.
Speaker 11:  I think that what it represents I think personally is like
Speaker 11:  this idea that we don't need the apps.
Speaker 7:  We're so used to apps mediating all of our activities that
Speaker 7:  at this point, what if not apps actually feels
Speaker 7:  revelatory, but it's telling that Tony's customers are
Speaker 7:  more than happy to ditch Uber Eats and DoorDash at the drop of a hat
Speaker 7:  or the drop of a new fee. And if big tech companies really do
Speaker 7:  double down on automation and robots, more people might
Speaker 7:  actively seek out more humanity, more idiosyncrasy,
Speaker 7:  more Tony. Tony himself wants to
Speaker 7:  experiment and meet people and hopefully pay the bills.
Speaker 7:  And if he accidentally starts a revolution along the way, all the better.
Speaker 11:  It would be nice to be known as the guy that was trying to connect us back
Speaker 11:  together. That'd be kind of cool. But not in like the sense of like this
Speaker 11:  was the guy, it was just more like, oh, like this. Tony Isles mentioned
Speaker 11:  this and we thought it was like a good idea and it worked. And then like
Speaker 11:  eventually, like we reconnected.
Speaker 5:  Welcome back. For all of the last two weeks, the most
Speaker 5:  popular app in the Apple app store has been a game emulator called Delta.
Speaker 5:  We've been talking a lot about Delta on this show over the last few weeks,
Speaker 5:  both because it's a huge hit and because it seems like
Speaker 5:  maybe the start of a new era for the app store, like in the
Speaker 5:  history books of smartphone apps, there might be a
Speaker 5:  before Delta and an after Delta for lots of reasons. But there's
Speaker 5:  actually nothing even remotely new about Delta. The story of
Speaker 5:  this app is actually a full decade long and it starts with this guy,
Speaker 16:  I'm ri Testa and I'm the founder of alt store developer of Delta
Speaker 5:  RI has had, as you might expect, a pretty wild few weeks
Speaker 5:  in the middle of it all. I asked him to come on the show and just tell me
Speaker 5:  the whole Delta story, why he wanted to build an emulator in the first place,
Speaker 5:  how the regulatory and technological world changed around him and
Speaker 5:  in general how Delta went from a big hack to a big
Speaker 5:  hit. It starts with RI in high school, just kind of looking for something
Speaker 5:  to do.
Speaker 16:  I was just back in high school, I think it was my junior year and I just
Speaker 16:  one day came across just like the open source repo
Speaker 16:  for a jailbreak game boy advanced simulator GPS phone. And
Speaker 16:  I was like, oh this is cool. This is all the code. I can probably just download
Speaker 16:  this and tweak it and then put it on my own phone without having to jailbreak
Speaker 16:  because yeah, I've never been a fan of jailbreaking, it's just never really
Speaker 16:  appealed to me. So I found this code base, I hacked out
Speaker 16:  away for a couple months, put it on my phone, I
Speaker 16:  put it on a few of my friends' phones, they liked it and then I uploaded
Speaker 16:  it to GitHub and called it GBA Fry West and then
Speaker 16:  kind of left it there for a bit and then people found
Speaker 16:  it on GitHub and started talking about it. And So I was like, oh,
Speaker 16:  there's interest in this kind of thing.
Speaker 5:  So you just made it as, as sort of a, it sounds like a mix of like a thing
Speaker 5:  that you thought would be useful and just kind of a thing to do.
Speaker 16:  Yeah, I just wanted Pokemon on my phone. That was literally just, I found
Speaker 16:  this, I was like, oh cool, I can Pokemon on my phone now and that's awesome.
Speaker 16:  And that's really all I was thinking at the time. And then I put on my friends'
Speaker 16:  phones and then we were playing just Pokemon ourselves. And then just completely
Speaker 16:  coincidentally, there was this service that came out around the same time
Speaker 16:  that let you connect like GI open source GitHub projects and
Speaker 16:  sign it with Apple's enterprise certificate. Basically there was a company
Speaker 16:  that had enterprise certificate and you could just connect your GitHub account
Speaker 16:  and then resign your apps like that. And So I was like, oh cool,
Speaker 16:  I'll connect this to GBA for iOS and then people can install it outside
Speaker 16:  the app store. Maybe a few people will download it. And that's basically
Speaker 16:  when I learned, oh wait, there's a huge demand for this thing.
Speaker 16:  Oh interesting. I did that and then within like a week people
Speaker 16:  were like posting videos about how to install it. There were lots of Reddit
Speaker 16:  posts and I was like honestly caught off guard. 'cause at this point it
Speaker 16:  was still just a project I made for me and my friends like in high school.
Speaker 16:  And so right then I was like, okay, there's demand for this thing. Let's
Speaker 16:  take this seriously. Let's like build like a real version of this app that's
Speaker 16:  not like throwing together not hacky. And so that's when I got my friend
Speaker 16:  Paul Thorson on board, my also still in high school. And we were
Speaker 16:  like, we're gonna do a brand new version of GBA, fry Wests, GBA, fry Wests
Speaker 16:  2.0. We're gonna redesign it from the ground up, just build it and make
Speaker 16:  a really polished experience. And so we basically spent all of senior
Speaker 16:  year working on that and in like halfway through senior year
Speaker 16:  we released GBA for iOS 2.0 and that's the version that most people
Speaker 16:  know. That was the version that you installed from my website. You set your
Speaker 16:  date back like 24 hours and you can install it because of the weird bug
Speaker 16:  that allowed enterprise certificates to work that way, even if they're expired.
Speaker 16:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Wait, so real quick, just pause for a second and explain the enterprise
Speaker 5:  certificate thing to be, because I feel like part of the story here is like
Speaker 5:  Riley's adventures in figuring out how to install apps on phones.
Speaker 16:  Yes. Yeah. Slowly getting more and more complicated. Yeah. Yeah. So this
Speaker 16:  was the easiest hack is just, yeah, as long as I found an enterprise certificate,
Speaker 16:  I could just sign GBA fors with it and literally anyone
Speaker 16:  could just download it from a website on the phone. Super simple.
Speaker 5:  And the idea is basically it's like that's the certificate you would use
Speaker 5:  if I'm like a company wanting my employees and no one else to have that app,
Speaker 16:  Right? Yeah. The exact same flow. And so it's just, you're not supposed
Speaker 16:  to do it for this reason. And so what Apple normally would do is
Speaker 16:  they would just like revoke the certificate, they'd make it, this is no
Speaker 16:  longer valid and all apps that are signed with it can no longer be installed.
Speaker 16:  And so the bug that I took advantage of was apparently at this time, like
Speaker 16:  an I seven, If you just set your date back on your phone by
Speaker 16:  more than an hour, the checks for whether a certificate is valid or not
Speaker 16:  just don't work. They just don't do it. Sure. You did try to
Speaker 16:  install GBA and Apple would've revoked the certificate, but because you
Speaker 16:  set your date back, iOS was fine installing it. And so it was just like
Speaker 16:  a really weird bug that I could take advantage of because there Apple
Speaker 16:  couldn't do anything easily about it. They had to actually fix iOS to address
Speaker 16:  it. They couldn't just be like, okay, nope. Turn out certificate. It was
Speaker 16:  about nine months later that they finally addressed it. And then that was
Speaker 16:  when I moved on basically from GBA for iOS is when they, it was like iOS
Speaker 16:  8.1, they killed the date trick. It was literally on my birthday
Speaker 16:  when it actually happened and I was like, oh that's funny. But honestly
Speaker 16:  at that point I had just gone to college and So I was like, you know what,
Speaker 16:  I'm gonna move on from this whole thing. GBA fires is really cool. I wanted
Speaker 16:  to go on to the next thing.
Speaker 5:  Do you know how many people were using GBA for iOS? Like at that sort of
Speaker 5:  peak moment before it got shut down?
Speaker 16:  A lot of people like more than 10 million for sure.
Speaker 5:  Wow. Whoa. Yeah. That's like a zero or two bigger than I thought
Speaker 5:  you were gonna say.
Speaker 16:  Yeah. There was a stupid amount of people using GBA FarWest, which
Speaker 16:  is why I was so motivated to do this for this whole time was I just knew
Speaker 16:  that there was a market for this kind of thing that everyone just kind of
Speaker 16:  assumed there wasn't. But I'm like, no GVA got 10 million downloads outside
Speaker 16:  the app store. Like it's just people just really wanna do this, like play
Speaker 16:  old games.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Okay. So you kind of, you're sort of forced to shut down that
Speaker 5:  project a little bit. Yeah. Was there a moment where you're like, okay, I'm
Speaker 5:  ready to go to war with Apple, let's fight this to the death and figure
Speaker 5:  out how to get GBA for iOS back? Or when it, when the sort of exploit gets
Speaker 5:  shut down, do you just kind of say, you know what, like you said, I'm going
Speaker 5:  to college anyway, this is just a moment, let me focus on other things.
Speaker 16:  It is basically that. Yeah. I was like, you know what, this is just a sign
Speaker 16:  that I should move on to something else. So this was really cool. I'm glad
Speaker 16:  I got to do this, got a lot of experience but may I'll try to make an app
Speaker 16:  in the app store next time. That was what I was thinking. I'm like, this
Speaker 16:  is a lot of work to have an app outside the app store. Yeah. So then that
Speaker 16:  whole thought process lasted like a few months and then I got bored and
Speaker 16:  I needed a new app to work on. And so yeah, swift had also just been announced
Speaker 16:  like the previous year and So I was like, oh you know what, lemme just make
Speaker 16:  another toy app for myself to learn Swift just for me. And you know
Speaker 16:  what? I'll make another emulator, it'll have more systems, but it's just
Speaker 16:  for me, like I'm again like it's just like a fun thing I wanted to work
Speaker 16:  on to learn Swift. That was like my entire motivation. So you're
Speaker 5:  Just run the exact same playbook again. Yeah. Without even realizing
Speaker 16:  It. Exactly. I was like, you know, I'm just gonna make for fun. Yeah, I
Speaker 16:  know. You'd think I'd learn at some point.
Speaker 5:  Okay, so and that's where Delta starts.
Speaker 16:  Yes. And so that's the beginning of Delta was like, okay, I'll call it Delta
Speaker 16:  and just build it for fun and that is what I thought I was gonna be working
Speaker 16:  on. And then I went to WDC that year. It was my
Speaker 16:  first time ever at WWDC.
Speaker 5:  What year is this at this
Speaker 16:  Point? 2015. Okay. So I go to WC and I talk to the
Speaker 16:  app review team like, 'cause they have like a lab there and I basically
Speaker 16:  just say, Hey, I'm working on this EM other app, is there
Speaker 16:  any world that it could be approved in the app store? And then they were
Speaker 16:  like, actually yeah, we'll allow that. You just gotta like comply with some
Speaker 16:  weird things. Basically they said I had to like submit a list of approved
Speaker 16:  games to them whenever I submitted a version of Delta so that could, they
Speaker 16:  could just make sure all the games at Delta supports were safe. Like they
Speaker 16:  just didn't wanna have like an open pipeline of like games and everything.
Speaker 16:  And So I like, okay fine that works for me. I'll submit a version of Delta
Speaker 16:  to you and I'll have like a a list of games that you can play and then every
Speaker 16:  app update I'll expand it to include more games. And
Speaker 16:  it seemed like that would be something I could do. And So I was really motivated.
Speaker 16:  I'm like cool, I'm gonna get Delta in the app store. And so then I spent
Speaker 16:  the next year like actually building it for real. I was like okay, this
Speaker 16:  is now a real app no longer just for me. I like really want it to be
Speaker 16:  polished, I want it to be good. I took a lot of my time, I got on my college
Speaker 16:  schedule to be working on it and then I went to the WWE C next year
Speaker 16:  and I talked to the same person and I said, Hey, I'm ready to submit,
Speaker 16:  can I submit it now? And he was just like,
Speaker 16:  So I talked to some people we can't allow
Speaker 16:  Ambulator and that was just all I got. I didn't get a
Speaker 16:  why. It was just like a, we can't allow that.
Speaker 16:  And then I was just pissed off.
Speaker 5:  Do you think this person was wrong the first time they told you it
Speaker 5:  would happen or do you think something happened in that year and they changed
Speaker 5:  their mind?
Speaker 16:  Honestly, I don't know. It's either one's possible. My guess is though that
Speaker 16:  they thought it was okay and then they talked to someone in the year and
Speaker 16:  then maybe they just had discussions about it and then they came away basically
Speaker 16:  like it's not worth the risk because I think that's what it's been this
Speaker 16:  whole time. Apple is like, it's not worth the risk to allow these emulates,
Speaker 16:  there's so much stuff that could open up. So I think they're just like,
Speaker 16:  eh, it's one kid, whatever, we don't need to allow his app in the app store
Speaker 16:  and it'll be fine.
Speaker 5:  And at that point, I mean I I, I confess I was late to the
Speaker 5:  iOS emulation universe, but it, it seemed, it's a weird thing
Speaker 5:  like GBA for iOS was huge and then it kind of went away. And So I
Speaker 5:  would assume we're back to like lots of pent up demand. People are very excited
Speaker 5:  about it. So it's not like you're the first person in history to ask Apple
Speaker 5:  this question, I'm sure. But at that point emulation was just kind of, it
Speaker 5:  was sort of nowhere on the iPhone. So I guess for them to say no, we're going
Speaker 5:  to continue to not allow it is not totally out of character.
Speaker 16:  Exactly. Like yeah, I wasn't surprised. I was just pissed off. Like I
Speaker 16:  was just like, I wasted a year of my life working on this and
Speaker 16:  'cause you told me I could release it. That was really just all I was feeling.
Speaker 16:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's fair. That's fair. So what do you, at that moment you're faced again
Speaker 5:  with this same decision of like, okay, do I just call this a
Speaker 5:  successful project, I learned how to use Swift, let me just move on with
Speaker 5:  my life or do I go the other way? I know the answer. Yeah. Historically
Speaker 5:  speaking but what, what is that? What do you, what is that moment like?
Speaker 16:  Yeah and this time I was just so pissed off. I was just like, you know,
Speaker 16:  this is not okay. I am gonna get this out there somehow. It's just like
Speaker 16:  really what I came to and I didn't, at that point I really didn't know what
Speaker 16:  it would be, but I was just like, I just wanted to show Apple that they
Speaker 16:  can't treat developers kinda like this. It was really just like, I was like,
Speaker 16:  you can't treat us like this. You can't tell us one thing and then change
Speaker 16:  your mind the next year 'cause real people are spending real time doing
Speaker 16:  this kind of thing. So I, yeah, I just motivated to just, I dunno, prove
Speaker 16:  them wrong. This is the best I could say. And so yeah, I was like, I'll
Speaker 16:  figure out a way.
Speaker 5:  So then next project is figure out a way like how
Speaker 5:  do you, how do you even start?
Speaker 16:  I just got lucky honestly, apple had also just around that time made
Speaker 16:  it so that you can install apps from Xcode for free
Speaker 16:  with a free Apple ID that like they just changed that rule of right around
Speaker 16:  now so that students could start developing. And So I saw that and I was
Speaker 16:  like, wait, you can install apps for free If you just have an Apple
Speaker 16:  id. There's something there. Like I was like that's all the technical
Speaker 16:  thing I needed to, I could make something from that. And so that was just
Speaker 16:  like the beginning of Alt store. I was like okay, I gotta do something with
Speaker 16:  this free Apple ID side loading from Xcode thing
Speaker 16:  that Apple has just announced. And then I was basically just like
Speaker 16:  took a few years to research that, build it up, find out
Speaker 16:  what would be the most convenient flow 'cause yeah, there are a lot of obstacles
Speaker 16:  with that. It was apps installed this way only could last seven days. You
Speaker 16:  could only have three apps installed at a time this method. So it was just
Speaker 16:  like kind of trying to come up with creative ways to make a lot of these
Speaker 16:  restrictions not as annoying. Like the fact that Alt Server's a thing was
Speaker 16:  the number one that alt server could just refresh your apps every week in
Speaker 16:  the background. And when I thought of that, that's when I was like, okay,
Speaker 16:  I think there's something here we can at least work with that's good enough.
Speaker 5:  So when did the first version of alt store like work,
Speaker 5:  what was sort of the first version of it that you had that you were like,
Speaker 5:  okay I this, this does the thing that I need it to do?
Speaker 16:  I think that was 2019 is when I finally like had put
Speaker 16:  together all the pieces into One Flow, whereas in like I had a program on
Speaker 16:  a computer that could install Alt store onto my phone and then Alt Store
Speaker 16:  could send apps to that device or to my computer and then reinstall it.
Speaker 16:  And then it was early 2019 I was like, okay, this
Speaker 16:  can work. Okay. Like just seeing it actually work in practice, it was totally
Speaker 16:  janky. Like the UI was horrible, but just like the fact I could press a
Speaker 16:  button on my phone and it would do everything, send it to Alt Server and
Speaker 16:  install it was just honestly kind of magical.
Speaker 5:  So explain to me why that worked okay in in the sort of infrastructure of
Speaker 5:  Apple's Universe. Like why did that system work?
Speaker 16:  Because, so the way Apple allows students to test out their apps
Speaker 16:  is they have to have a Mac and they have to be using Xcode and they have
Speaker 16:  to plug their phone into Xcode and then they have to install an app
Speaker 16:  from Xcode onto the phone. Like you can't just download a file and do it.
Speaker 16:  It's all through Xcode and all through a computer. And so Alt
Speaker 16:  Server is basically replicating everything Xcode does.
Speaker 16:  You can have an app file, but iOS can't install an app file on itself. You
Speaker 16:  have to send it to a computer. And then Alt Server does the same stuff
Speaker 16:  Xcode does behind the scenes to install it back onto the phone as if you're
Speaker 16:  a developer testing out yourself.
Speaker 5:  Got it. Okay. And you were able to basically build a thing that lets anyone
Speaker 5:  kind of mimic that system for themselves? Yes. When I set it up it was,
Speaker 5:  I wouldn't say it was a lot of work, but it wasn't no work.
Speaker 16:  It's, yeah, it's a lot. It's a bit, yeah. Especially on the Mac, there's
Speaker 16:  the mail plugin for a long time that was just, oh yeah, really it was,
Speaker 16:  yeah, it was confusing to everyone and I was like, oh this is too nerdy
Speaker 16:  to try to explain even to people why it matters but just, yeah. Yeah, people
Speaker 16:  got through it.
Speaker 5:  Well so, and this is, this is, I feel like the, the sort of ongoing story
Speaker 5:  here is you're, you're finding these increasingly complicated ways to do
Speaker 5:  this and continuing discover that there is so much demand for something like
Speaker 5:  Delta that people will jump through basically any hoops that you ask them
Speaker 5:  to jump through in order to do this.
Speaker 16:  Yeah, the biggest thing I was surprised about with Al stores, we need to
Speaker 16:  get your Apple ID and password to like log in with your account.
Speaker 16:  And I was like, wow, we really are just asking people to trust us and give
Speaker 16:  us your Apple ID and password. And I mean we're, we do everything we can
Speaker 16:  with it. We literally don't touch ourselves, we send it straight to Apple.
Speaker 16:  But I was like, ooh, that's a big scary thing that you really
Speaker 16:  just aren't supposed to give your password to random people. And then nope,
Speaker 16:  people are still giving us their password as if they don't care. And I'm
Speaker 16:  like, this is cool, but also makes you nervous for security as a whole
Speaker 16:  that people are just doing, just not thinking about it. Oh,
Speaker 5:  For sure. And it puts you in a really interesting position I would think
Speaker 5:  as the, as the developer this to say, okay, what is this
Speaker 5:  thing? Like am I just building this as sort of a fun side project
Speaker 5:  for people who wanna play Pokemon on their phones? Which comes with I think
Speaker 5:  one set of like security and privacy implications. Like
Speaker 5:  to some extent, honestly, If you send your Apple ID and password to
Speaker 5:  just a dude, I don't think you have any reasonable expectation of privacy.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Like I think it's a good thing Exactly that you were taking care
Speaker 5:  of people's privacy as best you could. But I think for me as the user,
Speaker 5:  I deserve what I'm getting at that point, right? Yeah, yeah. But then if
Speaker 5:  you're, if you're like a company that is, that has a terms of service and
Speaker 5:  is set up to make money and you're like, we're in this for the long haul
Speaker 5:  and we're serious about it, I think that changes both the way you have to
Speaker 5:  treat stuff and the way that I can expect you to treat stuff. Yes. And it
Speaker 5:  seems like as you were going through this, you were also trying to decide
Speaker 5:  like how professionalized do I want this thing to be?
Speaker 5:  Is that, is that fair?
Speaker 16:  That's pretty fair because when the first version of Al Store that launched
Speaker 16:  was literally just like a Delta installer. The only app in it was Delta.
Speaker 16:  It could install Delta. And I just knew that was important. But
Speaker 16:  even at that point I knew I wanted alt store to be a bigger platform. That
Speaker 16:  was like kind of what motivated it was like I didn't wanna build a whole
Speaker 16:  nother workaround just to install Delta. The fact that I could do it for
Speaker 16:  alt store and for other apps too made it more appealing to me. I was like
Speaker 16:  fine, I can do the work and then lots of other apps can take advantage of
Speaker 16:  it. And so it was always the plan to expand beyond Delta,
Speaker 16:  but I just didn't know really what that would look like until probably like
Speaker 16:  a year or so after we launched and I started, we started actually having
Speaker 16:  some third party apps wanting to be on the store. And then I got a sense
Speaker 16:  of, okay, this is the type of apps people wanted install, this is what I
Speaker 16:  gotta be dealing with. And yeah, that's helped a lot.
Speaker 5:  See so what, what was that like? We're gonna get into the kind of
Speaker 5:  history moved towards you a little bit aspect of this in just a
Speaker 5:  sec, but I am curious in that moment the idea of like, I'm gonna get my third
Speaker 5:  party app store to be sort of, you know, legitimate in
Speaker 5:  Apple's eyes Yeah. Was completely off the table like 20 19, 20 20. There
Speaker 5:  was just no world in which that was gonna happen. But you're like, you're
Speaker 5:  talking about, you know, other apps that want to do this kind of stuff. What
Speaker 5:  were you starting to see? What was kind of the, the like unifying thesis
Speaker 5:  behind apps that wanted to be part of this thing you were doing?
Speaker 16:  I, I mean at first it was just any app that wasn't allowed in the app store.
Speaker 16:  Okay. And honestly it is still a big appeal date. It's like for whatever
Speaker 16:  reason that was rejected for whatever type of rule, they just could be the
Speaker 16:  app store and so then they'd see alt store and then they'd be like, oh an
Speaker 16:  alternative. There are a lot of emulators like obviously. Sure. So there
Speaker 16:  are plenty of those. There's stuff you can expect. Like I Torrent had like
Speaker 16:  an app and you can be like, yeah, I can see why Apple wouldn't approve it.
Speaker 16:  But stuff like that. UTM, the virtual machine app, just
Speaker 16:  running Windows on your iPad, really cool. Not loud in the app store. So
Speaker 16:  it was just like a bunch of different random project or another
Speaker 16:  one I liked what that I think is really cool. Old os, If you've heard of
Speaker 16:  that one. No it's so, it's like a high schooler just recreated iOS
Speaker 16:  four in Swift ui and so it's just like the whole exp If you
Speaker 16:  open the app and it's the home screen from iOS four, you can open all the
Speaker 16:  apps and it looks exactly like it did back in the day. Oh that's awesome.
Speaker 16:  And it's really cool. And so it's just like, oh a fun little idea that not
Speaker 16:  allowed an app store. So yeah, a bunch of stuff like that. So I launched
Speaker 16:  alt store and the first year was really great but the first year was also
Speaker 16:  a lot and it was just me working on at the time. And then I honestly was
Speaker 16:  like, what am I doing here? Am I gonna keep with alt store?
Speaker 16:  Is this ever gonna be a real thing? Should I just like move on to something
Speaker 16:  else Now I was really going, trying to figure out what I wanna do and then
Speaker 16:  it was really that point I realized what I wanted was I saw basically that
Speaker 16:  the US was investigating Apple and that the EU was investigating Apple
Speaker 16:  around this time. And I was like, you know what? I feel like there is gonna
Speaker 16:  be something that happens in the next few years. I wanna be ready for that
Speaker 16:  but I need help. And that's when I basically brought on my partner Shane
Speaker 16:  Gill, who's my best friend and I've lived with for like 10 years. And I
Speaker 16:  was like, Hey, I need you with this with me. I need just do it together.
Speaker 16:  I need you to do all the business stuff. And So I can just focus on the
Speaker 16:  programming and then we can make that happen. And at that point we started
Speaker 16:  like making the plans for what alt store is today or at least an alt store
Speaker 16:  in the EU alt store pal.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So you, you actually really were betting on the theory that eventually
Speaker 5:  this was gonna be a real thing that you could do and not just
Speaker 5:  sort of a series of ever more elaborate hack.
Speaker 16:  Yes. Yeah. By that time I was convinced it would happen. Just I didn't
Speaker 16:  know when but just at some point in the future.
Speaker 5:  That's fair. Okay. So, and this was like peak
Speaker 5:  COVD if I'm, if I'm doing my timing math here correctly, everything's weird
Speaker 5:  at this time and you're like, well let's, let's just go
Speaker 16:  For it. Everything's weird. I'm, yeah, everyone's reevaluating their lives.
Speaker 16:  My original plan was, I was like, Hey Shane, let's move to New Zealand together.
Speaker 16:  Let's just escape everything. Let's build this in New Zealand. 'cause I'm
Speaker 16:  a New Zealand citizen so it'd be cool to go home for me. But that didn't
Speaker 16:  work out. It was too hard to get New Zealand during Covid. Yeah, understandably
Speaker 16:  So. We're in Dallas now, which is the same thing. It's
Speaker 5:  Like this close Yeah.
Speaker 16:  Space. It's
Speaker 5:  Okay. So you start building this thing and was the idea
Speaker 5:  we want to build sort of a full app store? Like was
Speaker 5:  that is is it as simple as that? That was the pitch.
Speaker 16:  Yeah. When Shane Karen board, that was the full pitch. Like we're gonna
Speaker 16:  build a real app store and show people what life could be like if there
Speaker 16:  were other apps. Just like just be the example and then whenever it was
Speaker 16:  official be the official like be an official store.
Speaker 5:  And what was, what were developers saying? Were you like reaching out to
Speaker 5:  folks being like, do you wanna be part of this and what were they telling
Speaker 5:  you?
Speaker 16:  Honestly, we didn't need to be reaching out to anyone. People were just
Speaker 16:  reaching out to us. Like there are a lot of people who just have app ideas
Speaker 16:  that just aren't getting in the app store and just, and even I'm like, wow,
Speaker 16:  there are just so many apps that like were getting like reaching out to
Speaker 16:  us. I'm like Oh wow, that was rejected. That was rejected. So we just,
Speaker 16:  yeah, people just reaching out for us.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And were you having any contact with Apple at this point? Obvi,
Speaker 5:  other than you know, those two conversations at WBDC, was there any inclination
Speaker 5:  that Apple was even sort of aware of your existence throughout this process?
Speaker 16:  We did. At one point when the EU started investigating stuff,
Speaker 16:  me and Shane sent an email to the executives of Apple basically saying,
Speaker 16:  Hey y'all, I think the EU may be going too much and do you
Speaker 16:  like we just reach out, Hey like we're here and we don't want like a crazy
Speaker 16:  world of side loading. Do you wanna like be on the same page here? And they
Speaker 16:  didn't respond at all. But we were at the time just thinking we don't want
Speaker 16:  a crazy free for all. And that's what it seemed like maybe the EU was gonna
Speaker 16:  be, we wanted a more restricted siloing world where the app store
Speaker 16:  was still the main app store. Why? I really think that's what makes
Speaker 16:  iOS so good for like the disaster people. Like it is just so simple that
Speaker 16:  you can get any app that you trust through one store. I think that's
Speaker 16:  really valuable. It's why like so many people I know personally use an
Speaker 16:  iPhone that aren't techies. And So I just always knew that there needed
Speaker 16:  to be a way for siloing to exist without taking over the app store or taking
Speaker 16:  like so many apps away from it.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So you then are watching the regulation stuff happening. Are you like
Speaker 5:  barreling through all the, you know, DMA white papers and trying
Speaker 5:  to get the deep sense of what's going? Like how into this were you as that
Speaker 5:  regulation was happening
Speaker 16:  Once the DMA was like an actual thing and they were talking about it? Oh
Speaker 16:  yeah, we were very much deep in it and then we were just like, we gotta
Speaker 16:  be ready for anything li because literally until Apple announced what they
Speaker 16:  were doing, we just were like, are we gonna be a siloing tool? Are we
Speaker 16:  gonna be a full app store? Are we gonna exist at all? Like we just had no
Speaker 16:  idea what was gonna come next. We just knew that there would be some way
Speaker 16:  of installing apps.
Speaker 5:  Okay. And So I guess with that idea you can kind of keep
Speaker 5:  building Delta and Alt store the way you had been without making
Speaker 5:  too many kind of unchangeable decisions
Speaker 5:  at that point?
Speaker 16:  Yes. We basically were working on like stuff that we knew would be true
Speaker 16:  no matter what. Like we were building up like the UI for browsing apps and
Speaker 16:  like we were expanding like, or building the Patreon flow so that people
Speaker 16:  could connect their Patreons and and install that. 'cause we just knew no
Speaker 16:  matter what, that would be good for this world. We just didn't go
Speaker 16:  into like the really technical stuff about like the actual installing process.
Speaker 16:  Right. It was just basically making the app look as much like a store as
Speaker 16:  it could be.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that makes sense. And at that point, how are you thinking about like
Speaker 5:  the business of Delta? You've been working on this thing for an awfully long
Speaker 5:  time without making any money on it. I'm assuming there were conversations
Speaker 5:  about like how do we, how do we all get rich from this thing that clearly
Speaker 5:  lots of people want?
Speaker 16:  I, people do keep asking me but the thing that I've believed
Speaker 16:  in and what Shane, like Shane, before he even joined Alt store, he was the
Speaker 16:  one that convinced me to make a Patreon for all this in the first place.
Speaker 16:  He was like, Hey, when you're working on Delta and Alt store, just have
Speaker 16:  a Patreon the side to support yourself. Because honestly I thought my original
Speaker 16:  plan was to release Alt store and Delta and then move on to something else.
Speaker 16:  Like, like just let it exist and let people install it. Let, Shane was the
Speaker 16:  one telling me, no people wanna support creators right now.
Speaker 16:  You should just have a Patreon that people wanna subscribe to and just support
Speaker 16:  future development. And So I start, I launched alt store at that and
Speaker 16:  it did really well. Like it has paid for everything ever since I launched,
Speaker 16:  started Alt store. We really believe that's a really important thing that
Speaker 16:  should exist. 'cause developers right now you can't sell apps through
Speaker 16:  Patreon in the app store. And it's just such a really good way I think for
Speaker 16:  creators to build a, like a relationship with their audience and just, people
Speaker 16:  also don't mind spending a few bucks to a person but they do
Speaker 16:  mind spending a few bucks on an app. Yep. So it's just like very different
Speaker 16:  relationship. And so we are basically just trying to really promote the
Speaker 16:  Patreon idea. Our own income basically is just through the Patreon.
Speaker 16:  We're still selling or having access to our betas for our patrons
Speaker 16:  and that's worked out pretty well as a way of monetizing Delta honestly.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Yeah, I mean even just the idea of thinking of an app developer as
Speaker 5:  a creator in the same way that you think about like a content creator as
Speaker 5:  a creator is really interesting and is totally not
Speaker 5:  how most people perceive it. Right, exactly. And and I think, I think it's
Speaker 5:  coming around a little bit like personally at least I've seen a lot more
Speaker 5:  of the sort of bootstrapped one person app become
Speaker 5:  a thing that people like in a way that I didn't and they like associate the
Speaker 5:  app with the person who makes it. Yes. Yeah. But I think for most people
Speaker 5:  it's all so faceless, right? Yes. Like you just, it's just an app that exists.
Speaker 5:  I don't know if it's made by one person or 10,000 and I don't care. I'm just
Speaker 5:  mad that they're charging me money and, and it's interesting to think that
Speaker 5:  like maybe the business model is part of the problem there that because it
Speaker 5:  all just sits in the app store and it is so divorced from
Speaker 5:  personality and people that maybe that's the problem. So actually connecting
Speaker 5:  Patreon to that is, is a really interesting way of just changing the way
Speaker 5:  people think about what like an app is and how it gets made.
Speaker 16:  Yeah, exactly. And I'm so, yeah, I'm really excited for that. And I'll,
Speaker 16:  another nice benefit is we can just have our apps be
Speaker 16:  free and then people just get the betas and, but so it means there's no
Speaker 16:  features that are locked behind paywalls like forever. It's just a, you
Speaker 16:  can wait forever and get it for free. Or If you just want early access
Speaker 16:  you can donate. And I think that's more appealing to people to like when
Speaker 16:  they're trying to support an app versus, oh you've locked away a feature
Speaker 16:  and now I can never use it unless I pay. It's like, yeah, that difference
Speaker 16:  I think makes a huge deal. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  No, I, I totally agree. So, okay, so right before the
Speaker 5:  DMA drops in, I guess, what was it like March of this year
Speaker 5:  when Apple put out its third party app store plans?
Speaker 16:  It was end of January. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So this year, yeah, this year.
Speaker 16:  Apple
Speaker 5:  Right before that, what was kind of the status of Delta and
Speaker 5:  all store? It sounds like it's, it's growing. People are using it. Like
Speaker 5:  how, how were things?
Speaker 16:  Things were good. We had like at that point, like 4 million users on
Speaker 16:  alt store, like just existing. I was like, oh wow, this is going great.
Speaker 16:  Things are going great. At Delta, we had been prioritizing basically a new
Speaker 16:  version of Delta 1.5 to release
Speaker 16:  alongside whatever Apple announced. And so we just like,
Speaker 16:  were working on that, but then basically by January we're just like, okay,
Speaker 16:  everything's in a good spot. We're ready to go. We just
Speaker 16:  need to know what the hell is happening. And so we were just basically just
Speaker 16:  waiting around to see like, okay, we can do
Speaker 16:  this. We have like the store had been finished by then, like all the UI
Speaker 16:  was done, Delta was ready, clip was ready. So, so
Speaker 5:  You, you have this thing and you're like, this exists, we made it, it's good.
Speaker 5:  We have absolutely no idea what we're about to do with it.
Speaker 16:  Exactly. That is exactly where we were. What
Speaker 5:  A strange place to
Speaker 16:  Be. It was very strange. It was, yeah. Just 'cause we're just, every day
Speaker 16:  we're like, what do we do? Like we can't move forward in a lot of things
Speaker 16:  but, so it was just a lot of planning and strategizing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that makes sense. So then end of January, apple drops
Speaker 5:  like a million press releases and technical documents about how all this
Speaker 5:  is gonna work. What, what happens to you on that day? What do you do?
Speaker 16:  Wow. What? That was a overwhelming day like for sure.
Speaker 16:  And the first thing that we try to do is figure out, okay,
Speaker 16:  can we exist at all in this new world? Because yeah, there's all these like
Speaker 16:  restrictions and we're trying to figure out what the hell like an alternative
Speaker 16:  marketplace is and we're like, and so yes we're, we spend that whole day
Speaker 16:  basically trying just to parse We Apple's announced and then we
Speaker 16:  basically are like, okay, we think we can do this. We think we
Speaker 16:  can meet the criteria if we get very creative. 'cause yeah, the criteria
Speaker 16:  was like a lot of things like you needed to have like the
Speaker 16:  standby letter, we need to have a subsidiary in the eu. Right.
Speaker 16:  And just like a bunch of things that we just sat down like, okay,
Speaker 16:  we gotta make all this happen in a month basically. 'cause we're like, okay,
Speaker 16:  we have until March 7th was like the DMA compliance day. We're like, okay,
Speaker 16:  let's set up a subsidiary. Let's get the standby figured out. Let's build
Speaker 16:  everything. 'cause also they announced all the stuff we had to build and
Speaker 16:  it's like, okay, let's build everything we need to do. And then for the
Speaker 16:  next month was like extreme crunch time, just like getting
Speaker 16:  everything done. Shane honestly was incredible. He was calling
Speaker 16:  so many countries to figure out where we could incorporate he Oh wow. We
Speaker 16:  finally incorporated in Ireland. So we have a nice subsidiary in Ireland,
Speaker 16:  which is great. He was the one talking to banks to get
Speaker 16:  someone to believe in two people who are trying to do something crazy
Speaker 16:  and they need this step. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  How hard was that process? You're like, so we build a game emulator and also
Speaker 5:  other app stores. I'm imagining a bunch of banks are just like, this is a
Speaker 5:  prank call and hang up on you
Speaker 16:  A lot did. Yeah. It so many people just like wouldn't listen to us. It was
Speaker 16:  true pure luck that we found one person, lo, his name's Logan,
Speaker 16:  he just like Morgan Stanley and he was just understood what we
Speaker 16:  were doing and really wanted to go out of his way to help us.
Speaker 16:  And I honestly, if we had not met Logan, I don't know if we would've got
Speaker 16:  this all figured out, but he was like, okay, let's do this. I believe in
Speaker 16:  y'all. I can work with my bosses. We can make it happen. That that was a
Speaker 16:  big win getting that one for sure.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean I remember when the news came out thinking that there were,
Speaker 5:  like, you described a bunch of technical challenges, but there were always
Speaker 5:  gonna be a bunch of technical challenges, right? Yeah. I feel like that you,
Speaker 5:  you sort of know going in, there's gonna be a bunch of weird work you have
Speaker 5:  to do to get this thing to comply with what Apple wants. But the business
Speaker 5:  challenges of just like the, the hoops you had to jump through as an
Speaker 5:  organization seemed like they were designed to keep almost everybody
Speaker 5:  out except for the, the truest of
Speaker 5:  true believers and maybe just the most stubborn people
Speaker 5:  building this thing. Yes,
Speaker 16:  Exactly.
Speaker 5:  And, and part of me wonders if, if going back a few months, apple just deeply
Speaker 5:  underestimated your willing to, your willingness to pick this fight after
Speaker 5:  so many years of picking this fight. You're like, I've been through your
Speaker 5:  nonsense before Apple.
Speaker 16:  Oh, I I, yeah, I know they were caught off guard. They, they told us that
Speaker 16:  they, like when we, when we ended up going to the lab and everything, they
Speaker 16:  just said straight up, oh we did not expect anyone to be
Speaker 16:  this prepared, especially as a two person team. They just did not expect
Speaker 16:  us to be as prepared as we were. Which I think
Speaker 5:  That had to feel good.
Speaker 16:  It, oh, it did feel good. I was like, cool. But at the same time I was like,
Speaker 16:  well then let us launch. It was like, cool. Okay, that's amazing. Let us
Speaker 16:  launch, we're ready. Was
Speaker 5:  There any question for a team of two whether to invest all this
Speaker 5:  time on something that at least for now and potentially forever, is only
Speaker 5:  going to exist in the eu? Like there's a lot of people in the eu, but there's
Speaker 5:  a lot of people not in the EU also.
Speaker 16:  Yeah, I mean, so two parts I like One, I do think this is gonna come outside
Speaker 16:  the EU at some point. I think it's a just question of time. So
Speaker 16:  I, yeah, I expected to see within a few years it'll expand out to like,
Speaker 16:  I don't know, Japan, United States eventually. So, so we viewed this as
Speaker 16:  like the beginning of a much longer process was to
Speaker 16:  expand, but then the other thing was like, we had nothing to lose. This
Speaker 16:  is literally all we're doing. All our income is working on alt store of
Speaker 16:  Delta. We're like, well we might as well just go all the way with it. Like
Speaker 16:  what else? Like why not?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean I think the long bet I think is probably a safe one.
Speaker 5:  Again, it's a question of how long it takes. Yeah. But it, I do think you're
Speaker 5:  probably right. It also seems like you were in a position where even
Speaker 5:  if it didn't sort of immediately reach a ton of people, you were gonna get
Speaker 5:  so much notice just because this is such a big thing and such a big change
Speaker 5:  that like I all of a sudden alt sort just appeared in so many
Speaker 5:  headlines in like February and March of this year, which is like,
Speaker 16:  Yes. That was very, very surreal seeing that all of a sudden. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean it's so funny 'cause like explaining alt sort to people, it's
Speaker 5:  like, okay, it is this bizarre sort of convoluted
Speaker 5:  experience where you have to set up a server and I'm seeing this in like
Speaker 5:  mainstream news articles. I know.
Speaker 16:  I'm like, oh my God.
Speaker 5:  It's like, oh my God, if my mom asked me what alt story is, I'm not gonna
Speaker 5:  know how to answer that question for her.
Speaker 16:  Same, I, yeah, I explained to my friends, I'm like, eh, don't worry. It's
Speaker 16:  just a tool to install apps. That's it.
Speaker 5:  So, okay, so then we're almost to the present time, but I feel like we still
Speaker 5:  have not gotten to the single wildest part of this whole timeline. Oh
Speaker 16:  Yeah, that's been accurate.
Speaker 5:  So you're, you're building the store, things are going well, you launch,
Speaker 5:  I think on launch day, right? March 7th, was it ready to go?
Speaker 16:  No, we, we were ready. We were all
Speaker 16:  ready to go and that was the beginning of like this frustration. So
Speaker 16:  we were, yeah, we were invited to a lab in Cork for the Apple
Speaker 16:  to like help us implement our backend and everything. So like a week long
Speaker 16:  lab for us just to work with Apple Engineers to get everything working.
Speaker 16:  So then we flew out to Cork, it was like the week before March 5th. So the
Speaker 16:  end of it, the end of February, we flew out day one, I showed up, I
Speaker 16:  said, okay, here's everything. We're ready to go. Can we launch? And
Speaker 16:  then they were like, oh hold on.
Speaker 5:  They expected you to show up and be like, I'd like to build an app store.
Speaker 5:  And instead you show up and you're like, I have built an app store. They
Speaker 16:  Literally, I really think they expected everyone to show up with like no
Speaker 16:  code base, like to just start from scratch on how to do this. And yeah,
Speaker 16:  so we show up and we're like, here's the entire product. It has store pages,
Speaker 16:  everything you could possibly need downloading works. And then they were
Speaker 16:  just like, oh wow. Yeah, just very clearly. Yeah, they were not expecting
Speaker 16:  that. And so it basically was then, okay, so Monday I was like trying to
Speaker 16:  pressure them, can we launch tomorrow? Can we launch tomorrow? I watch 17.4
Speaker 16:  is coming out tomorrow, can we be there? And then it just
Speaker 16:  became clear that this whole process was gonna be much longer than
Speaker 16:  we expected for a lot of boring reasons. Like basically just
Speaker 16:  legal, like giving them documents, having them review documents,
Speaker 16:  stuff like that. So I 74 came out and
Speaker 16:  me and Shane were very bummed because we were like, we were ready to
Speaker 16:  launch on launch day. We were all ready to go and then, ugh. So
Speaker 16:  that was frustrating.
Speaker 5:  So how long did it take before you actually got the thing up and running
Speaker 16:  Then? I think it was two months later. Like it was, yeah, it was
Speaker 16:  April 17th. Like yeah, so yeah, from May, from
Speaker 16:  March 5th to April 17th was just waiting. It's a month and a half.
Speaker 16:  And so we did that. And then, yeah, the reception was immediately just
Speaker 16:  phenomenal. People just so excited and, but then we also immediately saw,
Speaker 16:  which we expected that Delta was the main story. Sure that Delta
Speaker 16:  in the app store was the big deal. But we had to figure out what to do and
Speaker 16:  we knew that would be the outcome if we released Delta in the app store,
Speaker 16:  that Delta would get like its big moments to be everywhere. And we just
Speaker 16:  were like, you know what, that's fine. It's free marketing for alt store
Speaker 16:  if everyone just knows about Delta and then they talk about it and then
Speaker 16:  they get it through alt store in the eu. So you
Speaker 5:  Just, you just glossed past part of it though. Like the, the whole Apple
Speaker 5:  suddenly allows emulators in the app store. Yeah. You say
Speaker 5:  that as If you expected that to happen. I don't think anybody expected that
Speaker 5:  to happen. Not
Speaker 16:  At all it the most, yeah. Unexpected thing that could have happened. And
Speaker 16:  me and Shane had different reactions at first. Shane was more like,
Speaker 16:  what, this changes everything now we gotta think through. And my just reaction
Speaker 16:  was, wow, what validation that Apple had to
Speaker 16:  change the rules to allow emulators because they were threatened by us about
Speaker 16:  to launch with an EM letter. Like that to me was like invigorating. I was
Speaker 16:  like, this is, yes, it means we're doing something right. That Apple is
Speaker 16:  literally like doing something I never thought they'd do because it was
Speaker 16:  the only way they could try to make the story. Not the EU
Speaker 16:  now has the best apps outside the EU has, doesn't have the coolest apps.
Speaker 16:  And I just knew Apple like yeah, they just couldn't have that story. Which
Speaker 16:  is also why emulators are allowed worldwide is my guess is the story just
Speaker 16:  could not have been, the EU has better apps than the rest of the world.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no I, I think that's exactly right. And it is very hard to argue that
Speaker 5:  this wasn't specifically about Delta. Like I just can't, the timing,
Speaker 5:  it's too,
Speaker 16:  It is all about Delta it because we haven't had a direct
Speaker 16:  confirmation Apple, but our app Delta was being notarized for like five
Speaker 16:  weeks. They changed this rule, it's approved the next day. Oh wow.
Speaker 16:  Like, oh wow. It's almost like they were holding it to figure out what they
Speaker 16:  could do about it.
Speaker 5:  Did you get any heads up that they were gonna make this change? Nope.
Speaker 16:  Nothing at all.
Speaker 5:  Well, and I would guess after that happened you would've
Speaker 5:  expected it to be big. It sounds like you did expect it to be big, but I
Speaker 5:  feel like it's been, it's certainly been bigger than I expected. Like
Speaker 16:  It is bigger than I expected. I
Speaker 5:  Can, it's been nuts man.
Speaker 16:  It's so validating. Like I really can't like, because yeah, we're doing
Speaker 16:  this because we just really believe that people just wanna play
Speaker 16:  old Nintendo games or old, old games. We just, I think it's just a
Speaker 16:  thing people wanna do and for so long everyone just says no, that's only
Speaker 16:  for the nerds. It's only for like the people who know what they're doing.
Speaker 16:  And I've just been like, you just have to make it accessible. That's all
Speaker 16:  it, like all you gotta do, if it's accessible, people will know how to
Speaker 16:  do it and they will love it. We we're seeing that that is exactly the case.
Speaker 16:  And yes. So even more people than I thought are enjoying it. It is the most
Speaker 16:  surreal thing, seeing it not only in the app store but being the top
Speaker 16:  app in the app store for
Speaker 5:  Like a long time. Are you still the number one app in the app store?
Speaker 16:  I mean, I think last time I checked, but yeah, since we've launched we've
Speaker 16:  been number one and yeah, so surreal. Like
Speaker 16:  the most, like anytime in my life I've never felt more like
Speaker 16:  I actually am dreaming right now. Like I need like pinching myself like,
Speaker 16:  'cause it was just too perfect. Like work on this app for 10 years and
Speaker 16:  then day one in the app store, it's the top. It was just incredible.
Speaker 5:  Has it changed what you think about how to do all of this? I mean, If you
Speaker 5:  had charged 2 99 for Delta, you would've made a crap ton of money by now.
Speaker 5:  Like have you, are, are you thinking about the business of all of this differently
Speaker 5:  after it's blown up the way that it has?
Speaker 16:  I think we want this to be bigger than just like Delta.
Speaker 16:  And we want this to cause like actual change in
Speaker 16:  like the emulation scene or in the gaming sphere. Just like we want to make
Speaker 16:  this more accessible for everyone and we want people to start talking about
Speaker 16:  it and to have real conversations about it without just being like, piracy,
Speaker 16:  piracy. And so a lot of what we're doing is we thought Delta
Speaker 16:  to make that change happen, we had to like, it had to be free, had to be,
Speaker 16:  everyone had to have it. And that's, I think just what we're focused on
Speaker 16:  really is like as long as we're, we're making, we're making enough to support
Speaker 16:  ourselves and so we're not in need of more money. But I just think for
Speaker 16:  Delta to have the biggest impact is just make it as fully free and
Speaker 16:  accessible to as many people as possible and let them just start reliving
Speaker 16:  games.
Speaker 5:  Are you worried at all about legal ramifications? I mean there was
Speaker 5:  obviously the, the yuzu thing that happened kind of right before this. It's
Speaker 5:  been a, it's been a weird moment in the emulation community. Have has, have
Speaker 5:  you heard from any Nintendo lawyers?
Speaker 16:  Yeah. That came out as we're also like in Europe trying to launch this.
Speaker 16:  I'm like, oh, interesting. Very, very relevant to us. But
Speaker 16:  I'm not gonna say I'm not nervous about things,
Speaker 16:  but I am confident in what we're doing. I've learned a lot of
Speaker 16:  what not to do over the past 10 years. And I think that we are
Speaker 16:  really trying to show how you can do something like this legal. Like we're
Speaker 16:  not yuzu, we're not emulating a current generation console.
Speaker 16:  We're not doing a lot of things that other emulators get in trouble. Like
Speaker 16:  we're, there's no DRM we have to deal with to like for the the game. So
Speaker 16:  just the game files ripped from cartridges so we don't have to do anything
Speaker 16:  like, like that. We're doing everything we can to do it right. And there
Speaker 16:  was no world that I wouldn't have done this. I guess that's a better way.
Speaker 16:  Like I wouldn't have got this far and not released Delta. I just had to
Speaker 16:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  No, I, I think that Well and I think that's part of why this moment of your
Speaker 5:  story is so interesting because we're at the beginning of
Speaker 5:  this weird new era of apps in the app store and
Speaker 5:  I think a lot of stuff is changing and a lot is gonna continue to change.
Speaker 5:  But we're also, in a funny way kind of at the end of your 10 year
Speaker 5:  journey, like the this you, you finally finished the thing
Speaker 16:  That that is what it feels like. It's really weird, but I'm like, wow,
Speaker 16:  it actually happened like it got in the app store and yes,
Speaker 16:  it does feel like the culmination of that whole journey, which is very
Speaker 16:  weird. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Does that make it feel like I finally got to do it and it worked
Speaker 5:  and it was huge and it was awesome and now I can go do something else?
Speaker 16:  I honestly, the, the fact that Delta's doing so well has just motivated
Speaker 16:  me to just wanna work on it so much for right now because I've just been
Speaker 16:  working on it in isolation. Assuming one day it could like be a big
Speaker 16:  deal That I don't know, actually seeing everyone playing it right now has
Speaker 16:  made me really motivated to like really focus on it again. And also
Speaker 16:  because so much of the past two years has been like a lot priority working
Speaker 16:  on alt store and now that we launched Alt store, we can just like have some
Speaker 16:  fun with Delta again. Like there's just so many fun features I want to add.
Speaker 16:  But I haven't had time to, 'cause we had to get alt store up and running
Speaker 16:  for this deadline. But, so I'm looking forward to a lot of that. But I don't
Speaker 16:  know if this is a 10 year thing. I don't know if this is the beginning of
Speaker 16:  like another 10 year adventure To me, I think it's, I'll work on Delta for
Speaker 16:  a bit and I think I gotta finish up what alt store is like. We still have
Speaker 16:  some to do to prove it out. Like we gotta get the third party apps on there.
Speaker 16:  We gotta build up the platform. And I think that's, to me the next
Speaker 16:  step is just making sure that alt store is a real app store that people
Speaker 16:  are using and happy with. And then maybe I'll be done
Speaker 5:  And then, then you will have resoundingly defeated Apple, which very few
Speaker 5:  people can say.
Speaker 16:  That's lot. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Welcome back. For the last few weeks I've been immersing myself in
Speaker 5:  AI gadgets, the humane AI pin, the rabbit R one, the Meta Smartt
Speaker 5:  glasses, this voice recorder I have called plot, a bunch of
Speaker 5:  apps, everything I can get my hands on that is like a way to use
Speaker 5:  ai. And the number one question in front of all of these
Speaker 5:  devices in particular I think is the same thing. Why isn't this
Speaker 5:  just an app on your phone? Actually that might be the number two question.
Speaker 5:  Number one is just, is this thing any good? And a lot of them aren't, but
Speaker 5:  let's focus on the phone thing for right now. The verges, Allison Johnson
Speaker 5:  wrote a piece last week arguing essentially that a smartphone is the perfect
Speaker 5:  AI gadget that we don't need dedicated devices, we have the dedicated devices.
Speaker 5:  And she ran an experiment to prove it. So of course I had to ask her to come
Speaker 5:  on and tell us how it went. Allison, welcome back.
Speaker 17:  Thank you.
Speaker 5:  We usually talk about phones when you come on the show and this time
Speaker 5:  we're gonna talk about phones, but maybe in the weirdest way that we've ever
Speaker 5:  talked about phones, which I'm very excited about.
Speaker 17:  I'm here for it.
Speaker 5:  So let's just start at the beginning here. Tell me about this wearable
Speaker 5:  phone experiment that you devised for yourself.
Speaker 17:  Oh my gosh. I have never been so glad that I just work in my own house
Speaker 17:  alone. I was just sort of ranting about how, you know,
Speaker 17:  the humane pin reviews came out and I was like, this thing is just an
Speaker 17:  Android phone, like a mid-range Android phone. And I was like, I have
Speaker 17:  so many mid-range Android phones. So I just kind of set out to like recreate
Speaker 17:  the capabilities with what I had. And
Speaker 17:  it was surprisingly hard. I tried a flip phone, I had the Motorola Razor
Speaker 17:  Plus and I had it like kind of clamped over the collar of my shirt,
Speaker 17:  you know, like you do. And I got like so far with that
Speaker 17:  like I could kind of talk to Google assistant. So
Speaker 5:  Wait, so you, you dangle it over with like what The front screen facing out?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And you just, and then you just sort of like, hey gee it from
Speaker 5:  Yeah there.
Speaker 17:  And I figure, 'cause then you have cameras facing forward. You could do
Speaker 17:  Google lens. That was the, the thought. It's not very easy
Speaker 17:  to do any of that kind of out of the box. Like the flip phones
Speaker 17:  won't let you download the Gemini assistant, which is strange. So you
Speaker 17:  kind of have to, that's weird. Like side load it, If you try and, and trigger
Speaker 17:  the Google assistant with the phone closed in the
Speaker 17:  cover, just using the cover screen, it tells you to open up the phone. So
Speaker 17:  it kind of like, I was already not off to a great start.
Speaker 5:  So did you ever find an actual solution
Speaker 5:  with the phone itself? We're gonna get to headphones in a minute. Yeah. Foreshadowing.
Speaker 5:  But did you ever find a version of like a wearable phone that actually kind
Speaker 5:  of worked?
Speaker 17:  I did not really. Okay. I had, I just ran chat GPT
Speaker 17:  in the kind of like talking mode where the conversation mode
Speaker 17:  and I had that on my shirt and just, but it's just always listening and
Speaker 17:  like waiting for you to say something so you can't just like go about your
Speaker 17:  day. And we had a very pleasant conversation about like the
Speaker 17:  weather, whatever. But yeah, nothing, nothing really worked the
Speaker 17:  way I thought it would.
Speaker 5:  Well this is why I wanted to talk about this because I think you and I have
Speaker 5:  been talking about this for months now and the question everybody brings
Speaker 5:  up about every single AI gadget is like, why isn't this just an app
Speaker 5:  on my phone? And my thoughts on the subject and
Speaker 5:  why it shouldn't just be an app on your phone are actually becoming increasingly
Speaker 5:  strong and intense. And I feel like I'm more right than I was before. But
Speaker 5:  I am curious, like at a, at a broad level, do you buy that
Speaker 5:  argument? Like are you also one of the people who is just like, this is all
Speaker 5:  ridiculous, this should just be an app on my phone.
Speaker 17:  I think I'm, I'm like 20% rooting for like a
Speaker 17:  gadget that does these things and 80% just, it just feels like
Speaker 17:  realism. Like phones have already solved
Speaker 17:  so many of these problems. Like these little gadgets get
Speaker 17:  hot, they have to connect to the internet, they
Speaker 17:  need cameras like check mark on all of those
Speaker 17:  for phones, right? Like they did it battery life, you know,
Speaker 17:  regular software updates. They got it. And I'm just like, I'm having
Speaker 17:  flashbacks of covering compact digital cameras
Speaker 17:  for years where it was like, you know, oh these are
Speaker 17:  so much better than your phone. And which is like not even true
Speaker 17:  anymore. But it was like, no, the phone is good enough for most
Speaker 17:  people and people do not wanna carry around two things. That is,
Speaker 17:  that is what we learned from that experiment is If you can carry
Speaker 17:  one thing instead of two things, you will carry one thing.
Speaker 5:  I do agree with that. And that that is a, I think maybe the most
Speaker 5:  convincing argument against the AI gadget is just,
Speaker 5:  it's, it's the good enough hypothesis, right? That it's like I don't need
Speaker 5:  it to be as good. I just don't wanna carry and charge and worry about
Speaker 5:  two things. But I think my most strident opinion on this subject
Speaker 5:  is that I think we all have forgotten how annoying it is to
Speaker 5:  use your phone. Hmm. Like we've just been doing it for so long that
Speaker 5:  I think it's why I believe in flip phones for the same reason. It's like
Speaker 5:  our phones are these big chunky things that you balance on
Speaker 5:  top of your pinky to the point where most of us have like divots in our fingers
Speaker 5:  now. Now from trying to hold these things, you have to sort of like worm
Speaker 5:  your thumb around this gigantic screen in order to touch anything.
Speaker 5:  Like from a pure, in a vacuum user experience,
Speaker 5:  it's not good. And if your hands are full, you can't do anything. And
Speaker 5:  I spend like an alarming amount of my time with like dog and
Speaker 5:  stroller in one arm and phone in the other. Like it's just bad.
Speaker 5:  And I this idea that, okay, every time I wanna do anything, the right user
Speaker 5:  experience is for me to dig into my purse, pull out my phone,
Speaker 5:  unlock it, swipe, swipe pipe, open an app, tap on the app,
Speaker 5:  log in, do a thing. Like that's bad. And the idea that you can
Speaker 5:  shortcut all of this by just yelling a thing is good. I believe in
Speaker 5:  that. Yeah. And this is why I like your experiment so much because it's like,
Speaker 5:  okay, can I make my phone that thing? Which I think is where we get to
Speaker 5:  earbuds. Yeah. The longer we do this, the more I'm coming to the answer of
Speaker 5:  like, maybe headphones are the problem solver in all of this.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. And this is something I, our colleague V song has
Speaker 17:  written about is like with wearable tech, it's
Speaker 17:  so important that it's just like something you want to put
Speaker 17:  on your body and is comfortable and is kind of like socially accepted.
Speaker 17:  And I just come back to earbuds. Like we're just, people just walk
Speaker 17:  around with them. I feel like such an old person being like these kids,
Speaker 17:  they just walk around with their earbuds all the time. But like you have
Speaker 17:  a good transparency mode, you know? And those things could get smarter
Speaker 17:  about the sound they let in and the sounds they keep out.
Speaker 17:  And then you have this connection to your phone that you can just like summon
Speaker 17:  it when you want it and keep it in your pocket and not have to do the whole
Speaker 17:  dance of like tapping on things. 'cause I think we've come, we're sort
Speaker 17:  of blind to that. Like we are just so conditioned to like, this is how you
Speaker 17:  get things done on a phone. You take it out, you do all this, you get distracted.
Speaker 17:  And yeah. Once you start kind of like conceptualizing
Speaker 17:  not having to do that, it's like, oh yeah, I, I buy
Speaker 17:  into that vision and I, but I think we're just gonna be able
Speaker 17:  to do it without touching our phone. Right. But it's still gonna be phone.
Speaker 5:  Yes. And well, and that turned out to be sort of the second half of your
Speaker 5:  experience with, with this phone AI gadget thing, right?
Speaker 5:  You you basically went like full pixel.
Speaker 17:  Yeah, I did. Like I downloaded the Gemini assistant
Speaker 17:  and switched into it and there's still like weird workarounds you have to
Speaker 17:  do because you can have Gemini assistant running on the phone. The
Speaker 17:  earbuds are not going to trigger Gemini 'cause they're,
Speaker 17:  they don't talk yet.
Speaker 5:  This is the most Google thing you've ever said. Yeah.
Speaker 17:  Seriously. Well like the pixel watch you, you can't have Gemini on it
Speaker 17:  yet. So you're like talking to one assistant here, you're talking to a different
Speaker 17:  assistant on the phone. The Google home in my kitchen is constantly being
Speaker 17:  like, what? So I had to like unplug that
Speaker 17:  and I kept Gemini like open and running on the phone, which is not
Speaker 17:  an ideal user experience, but had the earbuds in and my
Speaker 17:  like light bulb moment was, I took a picture of this recipe
Speaker 17:  I was making and I was like, look at this and remember it.
Speaker 17:  And I just walked around my kitchen doing things and I would ask it questions
Speaker 17:  like, how long do I put the fish in? How do I chop the vegetables? Just
Speaker 17:  kind of out of order. And like as I was doing things and it,
Speaker 17:  it got it right all the time and it was like, oh this is super helpful.
Speaker 17:  I would be running back to this recipe with like
Speaker 17:  stuff on my fingers trying to figure it out. And it's like, man, those
Speaker 17:  earbuds,
Speaker 5:  That is maybe the single coolest use of AI I've ever heard
Speaker 5:  by the way, to take a picture of a recipe and then just pepper
Speaker 5:  the assistant with questions Yeah. About that recipe as you go. That's very
Speaker 5:  cool.
Speaker 17:  I was super into it and it's that kind of thing of like I run outta things
Speaker 17:  to talk about with chat JBT I'm like, there's only so many like business
Speaker 17:  proposals you can brainstorm. But I'm like, If you give it a little data
Speaker 17:  set of like I'm doing this thing, help me out. Like
Speaker 17:  it makes so much more sense to me that way.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Are you a voice assistant person in your day to day?
Speaker 17:  Not at all. I set timers and I asked the weather and like trying
Speaker 17:  to get myself, I'm starting to like realize I can use
Speaker 17:  it a little more. Especially if I am using a phone with
Speaker 17:  Gemini on it. Hmm. Like I ask but you just, man you gotta
Speaker 17:  keep an eye on it 'cause it'll make up a word. Or like I was asking
Speaker 17:  it if the bridge they were working on in my neighborhood had reopened
Speaker 17:  and, and it like got the days backwards. It was like, yes
Speaker 17:  it's open but it's opening tomorrow so
Speaker 17:  you just have to keep an eye on it. But it's, it's like converting me a
Speaker 17:  little bit to more of a voice assistant person I think.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Yeah. I think one of the big questions I have about this space
Speaker 5:  right now is did voice assistant work because they were a bad idea?
Speaker 5:  Or rather did voice assistant not work because they were a bad idea? Or did
Speaker 5:  they not work because they weren't very good? And I think they definitely
Speaker 5:  aren't very good. Right. And I think that that Siri experience sort of
Speaker 5:  proves that for a lot of people. And I think a lot of people's first experience
Speaker 5:  with these things was Siri. And you ask it to do something and it just fails
Speaker 5:  or it's like, here's what I found on the web. And you're like, well this
Speaker 5:  is useless and then you never really try again. And so the first
Speaker 5:  attempt, we all had to build that habit, it failed
Speaker 5:  spectacularly. And there are a lot of like kids
Speaker 5:  who grew up asking Alexa silly questions and getting silly responses and
Speaker 5:  that was the thing that worked. So I think the attach rate there has actually
Speaker 5:  been better as a result. But then I come around to, okay,
Speaker 5:  we all bet on this a decade ago. Like the tech industry
Speaker 5:  was like, this is the thing, conversational interfaces, they're gonna change
Speaker 5:  everything and they super didn't. Yeah. And now to some extent we're back
Speaker 5:  in that exact same thing and the promise is no, it
Speaker 5:  was the right idea with the wrong underlying technology. And
Speaker 5:  at least my experience so far has been, I still see the theory
Speaker 5:  of it, but even as I use all these things, I'm not, I'm using
Speaker 5:  it more. Yeah. I, I agree with you. I've definitely found more reasons
Speaker 5:  to do this stuff. Particularly with like, I really like to use an
Speaker 5:  AI voice notes app to like say my to-do list out loud. And they're actually
Speaker 5:  getting pretty good at turning that into just a structured list of stuff
Speaker 5:  I have to do today. I feel like a doctor who's like saying all of my charts
Speaker 5:  into my voice recorder and then like something magical happens, it's great,
Speaker 5:  but I still don't feel like I have hit the thing where it just
Speaker 5:  sort of, that becomes the main way I use my phone and what people say
Speaker 5:  when I say that to them is, oh, it's just an interface question. It's because
Speaker 5:  once you have your phone out, why not just use your phone the way that you're
Speaker 5:  used to? Which is why they're all excited about these new gadgets. And So
Speaker 5:  I just, I don't know, I spin in circles about like what is the actual sort
Speaker 5:  of roadblock here to this actually becoming real? 'cause it seems like there
Speaker 5:  are a lot of them.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. There's just sort of like a pain versus reward,
Speaker 17:  you know, ratio of like, it, I feel like it's starting to even
Speaker 17:  out a little bit with the voice assistants, but you still get burned where
Speaker 17:  you're like Yeah. And there's nothing worse than like being at the grocery
Speaker 17:  store and being like, I'm gonna use the voice assistant. And then it's,
Speaker 17:  it just fails and you have to like either keep talking to it or
Speaker 17:  like take your phone out. I think once you had that experience you're like,
Speaker 17:  oh, just use my phone for this. Yeah. But yeah, I think, I think it's something
Speaker 17:  we can adjust to and it, it really has to like
Speaker 17:  that threshold of public embarrassment or just like
Speaker 17:  frustration has to change and there's like signals that
Speaker 17:  that will happen I think. But yeah, it's, it's not proven. I
Speaker 17:  wouldn't say.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. One of my developing theories is that
Speaker 5:  headphones are gonna be where a lot of this goes for that reason. It's
Speaker 5:  like, it's a thing you can wear one of in the grocery store and
Speaker 5:  no one will look twice at you. Like we have solved the public weirdness
Speaker 5:  problem of headphones. Sony did that for us 45 years ago. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  thank you Sony.
Speaker 5:  But what I wonder now is like, should you have the
Speaker 5:  AI system that is just purely baked into your headphones? Like one of, one
Speaker 5:  of the conspiracy theories that I have no evidence for but believe to my
Speaker 5:  soul is that the next AirPods maxes are going to be local
Speaker 5:  AI devices because they're big and they're heavy and they have a big battery
Speaker 5:  and they can do stuff. But like If you try to run some of that stuff on
Speaker 5:  AirPods or the Pixel buds or it's just the battery's gonna die
Speaker 5:  in one minute and there's just, there's literally no place to put the
Speaker 5:  AI stuff. Yeah. But maybe it's, maybe that's okay. Maybe Bluetooth
Speaker 5:  headphones and your phone in your pocket or purse is enough interface. And
Speaker 5:  it does seem like in your experiment, that's kind of where you landed.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. That, that kind of proved out and that didn't solve the
Speaker 17:  camera thing, which is also like an intriguing related,
Speaker 17:  you know, like feature which the humane pin has the camera
Speaker 17:  and you we're both like, wanna look at something and ask a
Speaker 17:  question about it. Or If you want a hands-free way to take pictures, which
Speaker 17:  both are kind of intriguing to me. So I mean everybody keeps bringing up
Speaker 17:  the meta ray bands and man that kind of solves a
Speaker 17:  couple of his problems and doesn't look stupid.
Speaker 5:  True. Do you wear glasses normally?
Speaker 17:  I wear contacts. Okay. So I'm, I'm so close to buying
Speaker 17:  these things. I don't know really. Yeah. I, it would be so good for
Speaker 17:  just like taking pictures of a kid running around and I don't
Speaker 17:  know, but another gadget, do I want another gadget?
Speaker 5:  I dunno. I I hear you. I've been, I've been debating this with some of the
Speaker 5:  folks on our team for a while. 'cause I think they're definitely a huge
Speaker 5:  leap better than like having a headset on your face to have
Speaker 5:  the, the metas smartt glasses and meta is leaning into the fact that we've
Speaker 5:  also solved, having glasses on your face is not weird. And I don't know what
Speaker 5:  your experience has been, but when I wear the meta glasses, no one ever looks
Speaker 5:  at me sideways. Yeah. Like I got more public
Speaker 5:  notice, more sort of weird double takes wearing the humane
Speaker 5:  pin than I ever have wearing the meta glasses by a mile. Yeah. So that's,
Speaker 5:  that's a huge victory. But I also don't wear glasses normally and I
Speaker 5:  don't wanna start wearing glasses. Like I wear sunglasses when I'm
Speaker 5:  outside and I have mostly replaced my sunglasses with the meta glasses, which
Speaker 5:  I like a lot. But in terms of a sort of always on assistant, like I'm not
Speaker 5:  gonna get to work and keep wearing glasses I don't need just
Speaker 5:  to use my assistant.
Speaker 17:  It's a different vibe. Yeah. You have to be ready for that shift.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like I are, if we can normalize sunglasses indoors just in
Speaker 5:  order to make AI happen Yeah. I'm here for it. This, this works.
Speaker 17:  We'll work on that. But
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I do think I have definitely come around to the idea in testing the
Speaker 5:  humane pin and now the rabbit and some of the other stuff that's out there
Speaker 5:  now that actually what we need to figure out how to put AI into other
Speaker 5:  socially acceptable things that already exist before we try and invent
Speaker 5:  some who new thing.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. Like the humane pin kind of tries to hide it, but
Speaker 17:  it's sort of like, look at this, this is kind of a cool gadget. I appreciate
Speaker 17:  that. The rabbit is just like, this is a thing. It is bright orange.
Speaker 17:  It like practically glows in the dark. I don't know If you had this
Speaker 17:  experience where I walk into a dark room and I'm like, there's the
Speaker 17:  rabbit art.
Speaker 5:  It really does it, it sort of screams at you from wherever it is. What do
Speaker 5:  you think about the rabbit, speaking of experiments you've been doing, you've
Speaker 5:  been, you've been testing rabbits, AI stuff with some of the other stuff
Speaker 5:  that's out there. How's that gone?
Speaker 17:  It is, boy,
Speaker 17:  that's a tough, that sounds right. It's a tough one. The, the battery
Speaker 17:  life is just god awful. Which, you know, as it turns out
Speaker 17:  is important. 'cause I don't, if I just have it in my bag and I go
Speaker 17:  somewhere, I'm like, I'm gonna leave it off because the minute I turn
Speaker 17:  it on it's gonna be like draining the battery. So like
Speaker 17:  a, if there's no battery, it doesn't help you do anything. It's just a cool
Speaker 17:  orange thing. I've seen a couple of moments when I'm
Speaker 17:  like, okay, this is maybe doing a little more than a Gemini. I
Speaker 17:  took a picture of my plant on my desk and it, it did the typical thing of
Speaker 17:  like, this is a pothos plant, blah, blah blah. And it, it kind of like
Speaker 17:  went into the care instructions and it was like, your plant looks happy
Speaker 17:  in its current pot. And I'm like, you know, great
Speaker 5:  Job.
Speaker 17:  I don't, I don't get that assessment from Gemini. It just sort of spits
Speaker 17:  out a bunch of stuff at you. Like, don't overwater it, don't underwater
Speaker 17:  it. So I don't know, there's, there's like something that is a little
Speaker 17:  more like could tune itself to like what you're actually
Speaker 17:  doing or looking at that feels like not just Googling something,
Speaker 17:  but I don't wanna give this thing too much credit. It is not
Speaker 17:  done that very often and it, it kind of feels that basic
Speaker 17:  stuff.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's bad. Like I think we're gonna have, we're gonna have more to say
Speaker 5:  about it both on the site and on this podcast, but the, the, the rabbit R
Speaker 5:  one is not good is is a pretty easy takeaway. But I'm curious, you've been
Speaker 5:  testing it against chat GPT in particular pretty
Speaker 5:  strenuously, right? Are they, my assumption would be that most of these things
Speaker 5:  should come out relatively the same because it's all kind of pulling from
Speaker 5:  the same backend infrastructure. Have you noticed anything interesting
Speaker 5:  poking at all this stuff?
Speaker 17:  Well, I think that something you mentioned I think is that it's running
Speaker 17:  perplexity so you get a little more like real
Speaker 17:  time info than a chat GBT that or the free
Speaker 17:  chat GBTI use that was trained whenever ago. Right.
Speaker 17:  So I can ask it like, is that bridge open that was closed
Speaker 17:  over the weekend and I get a real response. So
Speaker 17:  that's interesting. But it's, it's such a strange little
Speaker 17:  strange little creature. It's like very adorable. I think
Speaker 17:  there's an adorable factor. It perks up its little
Speaker 17:  ears when it's listening to you. But TBD on that,
Speaker 5:  Does that do anything for you actually? 'cause I think I, I have, I've definitely
Speaker 5:  had the same experience that I like that it, the little rabbit on the screen
Speaker 5:  sort of bounces waiting for you to talk and then you ask it a question and
Speaker 5:  it perks up its ears and stops bouncing. And when you're playing music, it,
Speaker 5:  it wears headphones and there's a lot of sort of charming little things about
Speaker 5:  it I think. And I can't decide if that's what I want
Speaker 5:  or is totally the opposite of what I want from a device like this because
Speaker 5:  you, you use Gemini or chat GPT or Siri or whatever
Speaker 5:  and it's all very matter of fact, right? Like they are, they are
Speaker 5:  tools to do a job. And actually every time we've seen these things exhibit
Speaker 5:  personality, it's been in really bad ugly problematic ways mostly.
Speaker 5:  And so they've all learned to just sort of shut all that down and just be
Speaker 5:  there to execute whatever they're required to execute and then move on. And
Speaker 5:  part of me is sort of endeared to rabbit for trying something else and part
Speaker 5:  of me is also like, well maybe if it worked but was less cute, I would like
Speaker 5:  it better. Yeah. And maybe that's what actually matters here.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. Like there's a cute little animation of the rabbit
Speaker 17:  in a hamster wheel or something when you, when you need to charge it.
Speaker 17:  I'm like, this is adorable, but I am annoyed that I need to charge
Speaker 17:  this thing again. Like, cute only gets you so far, I think.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Do you think there's gonna be ways to put more of this stuff onto
Speaker 5:  phones in interesting ways? Like is is the next round of flip phones and
Speaker 5:  foldable phones and smartphone gonna have some of the stuff we're seeing
Speaker 5:  in these gadgets? Or are we just gonna keep getting phones because like,
Speaker 5:  I I just keep thinking about the razor as you're talking about it and it's
Speaker 5:  like, what if the external screen of the razor could run an assistant and
Speaker 5:  could have that outward facing camera. Like it kind of has all the hardware
Speaker 5:  it needs to do that. Are we gonna get that do
Speaker 17:  You think? I I would like it. I mean it would be an ideal
Speaker 17:  world where you could kind of choose from your AI assistant and
Speaker 17:  you don't just have to use the one that you're operating system baked in.
Speaker 17:  Fair. But yeah. Then you get into like the tech
Speaker 17:  company's gonna let the app makers in, you know,
Speaker 17:  like get into the system the way it would have to where you don't
Speaker 17:  run into a wall like chat GPT can't change
Speaker 17:  settings on my phone. Right. Or like, put something on my calendar. You
Speaker 17:  know? So I feel like there is a pretty like firm wall on that right
Speaker 17:  now. And and that would be interesting. I think that's kind
Speaker 17:  of like rabbit's, you know, ethos is like how do we get around
Speaker 17:  that? And it, the answer is a weird system where you log
Speaker 17:  into stuff and Right on, I don't know, a virtual
Speaker 17:  computer.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The answer is largely you can't right now. It turns out that
Speaker 17:  That seems to be not working also. So,
Speaker 5:  But yeah, it's, it's an interesting question and, and my sense would be that's
Speaker 5:  only happening if regulators make it happen, right? It see it seems to
Speaker 5:  some extent like more powerful than setting your default browser,
Speaker 5:  which you can do even more powerful than setting your default search engine,
Speaker 5:  which has only become a thing because of regulatory pressure.
Speaker 5:  And essentially you, you could kind of argue it's like allowing you to install
Speaker 5:  another operating system on top of your operating system. Like If you were
Speaker 5:  allowed to let chat GPT run your phone. That's a pretty big thing for any
Speaker 5:  of these companies to be able to do. I kind of agree that's how it should
Speaker 5:  shake out. If this tech is gonna get better in the way that everybody says
Speaker 5:  it's gonna get better, it'll be cool to have options and not just be forced
Speaker 5:  to use better Siri or better Gemini or
Speaker 5:  better CHATT or whatever. I don't know that I would bet on that ever being
Speaker 5:  a possibility.
Speaker 17:  Yeah, that does seem like a big question mark. And then you
Speaker 17:  get back to just like, well what If you could just
Speaker 17:  talk to your operating system while you're walking around the kitchen and
Speaker 17:  it's like, not the ideal future that I want. I think I
Speaker 17:  want a future where there's weird gadgets or you can download a,
Speaker 17:  a, a virtual assistant that can actually do things for
Speaker 17:  you. Yeah. I think that's why I am, I'm on like team phones
Speaker 17:  'cause it's the realist in me is like, oh, they're not gonna let this
Speaker 17:  stuff happen.
Speaker 5:  I think that's probably right. But I do also remember somebody, I forget
Speaker 5:  who it was, somebody at one of the phone makers years ago was like, we're
Speaker 5:  gonna get to a point where the phone in your pocket is basically just a cellular
Speaker 5:  modem and all the accessories around are
Speaker 5:  going to be connected to that in some way. Your wearable is gonna use that
Speaker 5:  to connect to the internet. Your headphones, you can use that connect to
Speaker 5:  the internet. Your laptop is gonna use that to connect to the internet, but
Speaker 5:  it is, it's going to be less the device you use for everything and more
Speaker 5:  the device that just lets you use everything everywhere. Yeah. And I think
Speaker 5:  that's a really interesting version of the future and it's kind of what you
Speaker 5:  discovered with this is like, I can just use my phone as a go-between
Speaker 5:  to all these services that exist and with headphones that I already own.
Speaker 5:  I actually don't need to invent a completely new pipeline for that
Speaker 5:  stuff. I just need a new way to kind of get at that pipeline.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. And I've become just an addict for the smartwatch.
Speaker 17:  Like I, over the past couple years, like I never used one before
Speaker 17:  and now I cannot live without one. It's just like, it's
Speaker 17:  the right kind of light interface for when I need to do stuff. Like I'm
Speaker 17:  out on a walk and I need to pause music or just
Speaker 17:  check a quick notification or a text. And it's like you run into
Speaker 17:  the wall very quickly of like, you can't really respond to a text very
Speaker 17:  well or you can thumbs up emoji something. Right.
Speaker 17:  But boy has that been like, that is the point where I'm like,
Speaker 17:  I am so willing to charge this extra thing and it has
Speaker 17:  its own special charger that I have to bring along when I travel.
Speaker 17:  And like it crosses that threshold of like, yes,
Speaker 17:  I will do all of that because I find it so useful.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I think smartwatches probably land in the, the
Speaker 5:  earbuds category of that kind of light input system
Speaker 5:  that really works. Like when I wrote, when I wrote the humane pin review,
Speaker 5:  the overwhelming response was what you're describing is just a better Apple
Speaker 5:  watch. Yeah. And I think other than the camera stuff, which is
Speaker 5:  left to be solved, but right now is only kind of somewhat
Speaker 5:  useful anyway. That is true. Like my big
Speaker 5:  regret right now is that I didn't buy a cell connected Apple watch. Right.
Speaker 5:  I know. And I wish, I wish that I had because then I could do all that sort
Speaker 5:  of lightweight stuff you're talking about without needing my phone in my
Speaker 5:  pocket. Yeah,
Speaker 17:  That'd be awesome. You just leave the house. Can you imagine?
Speaker 5:  I mean, first of all no, no, but also it sounds wonderful.
Speaker 17:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The idea of your phone as a thing that lives in your pocket, that it lets
Speaker 5:  everything else connect to the internet strikes me as much more this sort
Speaker 5:  of AI gadget future than like these all encompassing
Speaker 5:  new ideas about gadgets.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. I know it's kind of depressing, but it's
Speaker 5:  Also I think true. It's
Speaker 17:  A little bit,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it means like all these other companies, humane Rabbit, everybody
Speaker 5:  else is like desperately trying to get around your phone, just like you said.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, oh, this maybe keeps the world the way that it is
Speaker 5:  if that's how we do it more than I would like. But it also just might
Speaker 5:  be inevitable.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. And it's an interesting moment at least. Yeah. Boy is
Speaker 17:  it not dull right now.
Speaker 5:  I know. And I'm I'm still thinking about the, the camera comparison and cameras
Speaker 5:  never came back. No. They just like mid-range. We found a lot
Speaker 5:  of interesting stuff to do at like the high end and I think about like the
Speaker 5:  Fuji series that people really love. Like I feel like If you want like a
Speaker 5:  good camera, your options have never been better. But If you
Speaker 5:  want a pretty good camera, they don't exist because you have a smartphone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 17:  You already
Speaker 5:  Have it. Yeah. And I wonder maybe that's where we're gonna go with AI stuff
Speaker 5:  and we're a ways away from the ai ai gadgets being any good.
Speaker 5:  So maybe we're, we're gonna be in a real sort of valley with that stuff for
Speaker 5:  a little while it feels like.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. We're gonna find out,
Speaker 5:  But luckily phones are getting better, so I'll speak to that.
Speaker 17:  Yeah, yeah. Phones are sticking around I think.
Speaker 5:  And you've given me yet another reason to buy a flip phone. Oh man. Which
Speaker 5:  is all I really needed from you was more reasons
Speaker 17:  I took that Motorola out of the closet. I was like, this is so nice.
Speaker 17:  Ugh. Just shutting it. Just shutting. It feels good.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I'm gonna start buying t-shirts with the pocket on the, on the breast.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, exactly. And I'm gonna, I'm gonna fold it out and just stick it right
Speaker 5:  there and chat with it all day. It's gonna be amazing. Yeah.
Speaker 17:  It looks super cool.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I I believe that, I bet you made a lot of friends and everybody thought
Speaker 5:  you were super normal and cool all the time. Yeah,
Speaker 17:  I was taking pictures of it for the article and my husband walked into the
Speaker 17:  kitchen and just slowly backed away. Like, I don't
Speaker 17:  understand what's happening here and I'm not gonna question it.
Speaker 5:  That's, that's the correct way to react to AI of all sorts.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. Probably just back away.
Speaker 5:  All right, Allison, thank you as always. Thank
Speaker 17:  You.
Speaker 5:  Welcome back. So a few weeks ago I started reading this book called The
Speaker 5:  Notebook, a history of Thinking on paper by a guy named Roland Allen.
Speaker 5:  And it traces like a thousand years of history
Speaker 5:  of how people write on paper. He makes
Speaker 5:  this big case, that paper is this incredibly
Speaker 5:  critical invention in the history of the world. And that actually
Speaker 5:  without paper, without notebooks, we wouldn't have modern capitalism.
Speaker 5:  We wouldn't know nearly as much about history as we do that actually
Speaker 5:  a lot of the world that we live in is defined by
Speaker 5:  the way that people wrote stuff down and what they wrote stuff down on. He
Speaker 5:  tells a whole history of notebooks all the way through the
Speaker 5:  Renaissance and all the way up to now. And even in the future,
Speaker 5:  If you listen to the show, you know that I love note taking apps. I love
Speaker 5:  thinking about how people write stuff down. I think the systems for all this
Speaker 5:  are fascinating. And this book was like catnip for me. So I asked Roland
Speaker 5:  to come on the show and talk through some of the big ideas in his book, and
Speaker 5:  also why notebooks continue to survive in this
Speaker 5:  increasingly digital world. It's a super fun conversation. I
Speaker 5:  really enjoyed talking to him. And yes, there is more
Speaker 5:  12 century history in this episode than most, but we're
Speaker 5:  gonna go with it. So to start with Roland, I asked him to quickly
Speaker 5:  recap the case that he makes that paper is
Speaker 5:  a hugely important invention in the history of the world. And that without
Speaker 5:  paper we might not have any of this. Here's what he said to that.
Speaker 18:  Yeah. Permanence is really why
Speaker 18:  for thousands of years we've had different ways of writing things down as
Speaker 18:  human beings. So you go back to, you can, you can carve on stone, you can
Speaker 18:  make little dents in clay tablets, which you then fire and dry out and they're
Speaker 18:  permanent, but they are clay tablets, so they're not super portable or practical
Speaker 18:  or robust. Then you have papyrus,
Speaker 18:  papyrus, the reed product, which grows in
Speaker 18:  Egypt. And you can write on that, you can draw on that. But
Speaker 18:  papyrus, it turns out, unless it's actually an in an Egyptian
Speaker 18:  tomb, completely dry with no movement and nothing to
Speaker 18:  disturb it, it will just automatically fall apart. It, it, it can't cope
Speaker 18:  with any kind of damp or it can't really cope with being handled. So
Speaker 18:  papyrus is handy, but it's not permanent.
Speaker 18:  And then you have wax tablets and these are beautiful things. They're amazing.
Speaker 18:  Completely died out in Europe. But for about 2000 years, this
Speaker 18:  is how Europeans pins retained information,
Speaker 18:  took notes, wrote poems, agreed
Speaker 18:  contracts, bills of sale, whatever, with a layer of wax on
Speaker 18:  wood, which you would then scrape into with a little stylus. Now
Speaker 18:  obviously that's not permanent, so it's very useful for being an
Speaker 18:  a poet's notebook, for instance, because you can wipe it over at the end
Speaker 18:  of the day when you're finished writing your poem. But for a business
Speaker 18:  record, it's no good at all because you know, you, you have to
Speaker 18:  know what you agreed, what you contracted. Then you
Speaker 18:  have parchment, and parchment comes along a little bit later during the
Speaker 18:  period of the Roman Empire probably. And that's a really good
Speaker 18:  writing material. It's very tough, it's completely indestructible and
Speaker 18:  you can write on it beautifully. And you can also paint on it If you like.
Speaker 18:  So the illuminated manuscripts, which we see the book of Kels and so on,
Speaker 18:  these are all on parchment and they're very beautiful. But the problem is
Speaker 18:  when you write on parchment with a pen, the ink
Speaker 18:  sits on the surface and dries, which means you can scrape it off.
Speaker 18:  Which means that, again, it's not permanent, you can change it, you can
Speaker 18:  affect the record. So it's no good for business. Paper turns up in Europe
Speaker 18:  around the year 12 40, 12 50. And very quickly
Speaker 18:  a few people realize it's a game changer because anything
Speaker 18:  which is written on paper, stay with ink stays there.
Speaker 18:  So you can have a contract, you can keep a business record, you
Speaker 18:  can do anything legal, you can have a deed, for instance, and you don't
Speaker 18:  have to worry about it being forged. Yeah. And that's
Speaker 18:  important. So paper is really important because it's permanent and that
Speaker 18:  leads to, its very, very rapid adoption
Speaker 18:  in the business community in particular.
Speaker 5:  Was that where it started? I was, was I was trying to match some of the timelines
Speaker 5:  and going back through, it seems like, if I
Speaker 5:  have the timeline correct, there were, there were two threads.
Speaker 5:  There was kind of the people who use it for business and people who use it
Speaker 5:  for recording things in their own personal lives. But it does seem like business
Speaker 5:  became a real use case for notebooks first.
Speaker 18:  Yeah, absolutely. A hundred percent. And the analogy, which you can very
Speaker 18:  easily draw is with the modern computer. Mm. You know, that comes
Speaker 18:  from IBM and its businesses and governments, which have it
Speaker 18:  to begin with for the first how long? 30 years, maybe 40 years.
Speaker 18:  And then you get people using it creatively, and then you get people like
Speaker 18:  jobs thinking, oh, you can have some fun with this thing. You know, you
Speaker 18:  can play games on it, but you can also be seriously creative. So now you
Speaker 18:  have Pixar, for instance, and I don't think anyone at IBM in the 1940s
Speaker 18:  was thinking that Pixar was gonna happen. Right. Looking back, it seems
Speaker 18:  inevitable that people would do something like that. And it's exactly
Speaker 18:  the same kind of relationship with notebooks. You have
Speaker 18:  businesses come to rely on notebooks, utterly, they use them for everything.
Speaker 18:  And therefore notebooks get into everyone's
Speaker 18:  hands, particularly in a culture like Italy, which at the time Italy's the
Speaker 18:  richest part of Europe. But it's also where they invent banking, where they
Speaker 18:  invent companies, where they invent accountancy, double entry, bookkeeping,
Speaker 18:  limited liability, partnerships, futures, markets, all of these things
Speaker 18:  which we know and love.
Speaker 5:  And, and a lot of that you talk about happens,
Speaker 5:  not sort of, it, it, that doesn't happen. And then they put it down in notebooks,
Speaker 5:  like the existence of those things and notebooks and this new
Speaker 5:  writing, permanent technology go hand in hand.
Speaker 18:  Absolutely. You can't do one without the other. But then of course, so they
Speaker 18:  have to have these notebooks, and once they have to have them in the evening,
Speaker 18:  they take 'em home and then, then they do the fun stuff with them. And that's
Speaker 18:  entirely accidental, I think. But, you know, thank God
Speaker 18:  from our point of view, it's given us all of this interesting literature
Speaker 18:  and art and poetry.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So I confess I'm particularly interested in the fun stuff. So let,
Speaker 5:  let's start there. I think the, the first thing I had written down in my
Speaker 5:  notes was like, let's go back to Florence and, and there's a
Speaker 5:  word that starts with a Z that I can't pronounce. And it was, it
Speaker 5:  was, it, my, my gut tells me it's pronounced zibo, but I could be
Speaker 5:  wrong.
Speaker 18:  I you are that right? Yeah. Yes. I I you just have to imagine yourself ordering
Speaker 18:  a ian an Italian restaurant and you'll be fine. Right.
Speaker 5:  A, a type of notebook and also a beautiful croissant like thing
Speaker 5:  that I will like very much. Tell me what those were. Talk a little bit about,
Speaker 5:  well, kind of how that spread.
Speaker 18:  Okay. Back to the restaurant, Zal seems to have been a word for salad
Speaker 18:  and that's exactly what it is. So it's a collection of lots
Speaker 18:  of different things jumbled together. Now, this is a time
Speaker 18:  before print, we're talking about about 1300 and it's Florence
Speaker 18:  and it's a time before print. So If you wanted to have any book or
Speaker 18:  literature or poetry in your house, you had to basically write
Speaker 18:  it down yourself. Yeah. And therefore,
Speaker 18:  Florence is a very business-like community. They're very entrepreneurial.
Speaker 18:  Everyone's got their own little business, therefore everyone's got their
Speaker 18:  business notebooks. They take 'em home in the evening and
Speaker 18:  if they hear a poem which they like, or if they hear is one of
Speaker 18:  ESOP's fables is very popular, or a bit of ovid or a prayer, which
Speaker 18:  is particularly resonant to them, or a recipe, very often they're writing
Speaker 18:  down medic medicinal cures. Anything you wanna keep written down in your
Speaker 18:  house, you just write it down in your zal. And it's a very personal notebook,
Speaker 18:  but it's completely unsorted. So it's like a salad in this jumbled up way.
Speaker 18:  And they're brilliant because they're these windows
Speaker 18:  into what Florentine people loved. Yeah. So we
Speaker 18:  know the poetry, they like to read, we know the prayers that they wanted
Speaker 18:  to remember. We know the stories that they like to tell and we know what
Speaker 18:  they liked to eat when they had a headache. You know, all of this kind of
Speaker 18:  information because everyone in Florence at this time who could read or
Speaker 18:  write, which was most of them unusually, they kept aze
Speaker 18:  baldoni. And it was a really strange local thing. But it was so fun.
Speaker 5:  I also get the sense that folks back then were reckoning with the same thing
Speaker 5:  people reckon with now, which is like, what do I do with any of this? And
Speaker 5:  this is sort of the eternal question of notebooks, right? Is you,
Speaker 5:  you write a bunch of stuff down, you collect all this stuff. And as a historical
Speaker 5:  artifact, especially in aggregate, it's very cool, right? You, you get a
Speaker 5:  sense of what people were doing in a, in a community. But if
Speaker 5:  I'm a person in Florence in the 13 hundreds keeping one of these,
Speaker 5:  what do, what am I doing with it day to day? What's gonna happen to these
Speaker 5:  notebooks? Are they thinking about like the grand sweep of history and their
Speaker 5:  responsibility to write this stuff down? Like what were the, what was the
Speaker 5:  point of these notebooks?
Speaker 18:  So the, well only the, the only point was fun. They weren't
Speaker 18:  thinking about the grand sweep of history, but they knew that they were
Speaker 18:  a bit precious because they would leave them in their wills. So this is
Speaker 18:  how we know, one of the ways we know how many people had them, because the
Speaker 18:  wills often survive. And also you see these little
Speaker 18:  dedications in the, someone will start their Z will, don't they? Then they'll
Speaker 18:  leave it to their son. And then the son will have an argument on the pages
Speaker 18:  of the ziel with his brother saying, oh no, he dad left it to me
Speaker 18:  actually. You know? So you have these little bickerings and you can see
Speaker 18:  that sometimes they pass down three generations and that people maintain
Speaker 18:  them 'cause the handwriting changes.
Speaker 18:  So that's one thing. So ziel donia, they're always for fun, but
Speaker 18:  people definitely keep know that they have a value.
Speaker 18:  The other thing that they also start doing is viewing their family as
Speaker 18:  a kind of business and then keeping it what they would call a libre de familia.
Speaker 18:  Oh, well, za is the other word for it. Where they keep a family
Speaker 18:  record, which is essentially births, deaths, marriages,
Speaker 18:  investments, you know, we bought this house, I invested in this company,
Speaker 18:  my daughter got married, my son died, my grandson was born, he was
Speaker 18:  baptized, et cetera. And they're very businesslike. You
Speaker 18:  wouldn't call them diaries because there's no emotion in there. There's
Speaker 18:  no happiness or sadness. But they just record the central
Speaker 18:  of most important events of a family's life. And then that would get passed
Speaker 18:  down through the generations as well. And that, but that's more viewing
Speaker 18:  your family in a kind of quite serious business-like way. If you
Speaker 18:  were a grammar school in the, say
Speaker 18:  15 hundreds, 16 hundreds in Europe, you were
Speaker 18:  expected to keep a commonplace book in a very rigorous way. And that was
Speaker 18:  a very formal kind of thing. But that was educational, you know, that wasn't,
Speaker 18:  no one ever really did that for fun. 'cause it's such hard work. Yeah. It's
Speaker 18:  a, it's a real effort and it's study. But I think that outside of
Speaker 18:  school you have people like Leonardo who would just draw all
Speaker 18:  over the place. You have people who doodle. You have people who write very
Speaker 18:  intimate personal diaries, people who write very formal ones, people who
Speaker 18:  write about their relationship with God. You know, there's no hard and
Speaker 18:  fast rules.
Speaker 5:  Okay. And that feels like the, the thing that
Speaker 5:  lingers most over time is that everybody is perpetually finding new ways
Speaker 5:  to fill up a notebook. Yeah. Kind of more chaotic over time
Speaker 5:  too. Everybody gets weirder and weirder about notebooks.
Speaker 5:  Da Vinci is an interesting one. You, you mentioned him and obviously I would
Speaker 5:  say you've obviously done more research on this than I have, but I
Speaker 5:  would say Leonardo da Vinci's notebooks probably history's most famous
Speaker 5:  notebooks, fair to say. Yeah,
Speaker 18:  I would say so. Yeah. Yeah. Those are the ones when I was telling people
Speaker 18:  that I was writing history of Notebook and they were looking baffled, I
Speaker 18:  would go, you know, Leonardo. Right.
Speaker 5:  Well, one thing I thought was really interesting in, in your telling of his
Speaker 5:  story was that he
Speaker 5:  did not seem to imagine that his notebooks would eventually become wildly
Speaker 5:  famous. And the idea that these were for public consumption
Speaker 5:  was kind of a thing that happened much later. The notebooks were very
Speaker 18:  Personal much
Speaker 5:  Later. Yeah. And very individual. How did that change come about? Like
Speaker 5:  at what point did people start writing notebooks, even in some of the
Speaker 5:  styles that you're talking about, thinking about other people?
Speaker 18:  Very, very late in the day. I would say, I think what's interesting,
Speaker 18:  Leonardo's notebooks are fascinating for two reasons, I think very
Speaker 18:  far apart in time. Firstly, because they're an amazing record of his thoughts,
Speaker 18:  his researches, his explorations and his personality up to a point
Speaker 18:  so that that period around the year 1500, wow. You know,
Speaker 18:  there was something really incredible going on there. And then basically
Speaker 18:  they just vanish into aristocrats libraries. Mm. You know, and
Speaker 18:  no one reads them, no one, they probably pull 'em off the shelf and just
Speaker 18:  look at them as a curiosity. No one studies them at all
Speaker 18:  until the 1890s when a German guy called
Speaker 18:  Richter goes around Europe. He looks at them all, he transcribes them,
Speaker 18:  he researches, he writes about them. And then for the first time,
Speaker 18:  400 years nearly after Leonardo dies, people
Speaker 18:  actually realize, oh, he wasn't just a good painter, he was also
Speaker 18:  all of these other kinds of genius as well, because he was just known as
Speaker 18:  a painter up to that point. And then, and I think it is
Speaker 18:  a direct result of the publication of Leonardo's
Speaker 18:  notebooks and people understanding that there's this process behind his
Speaker 18:  genius, then everyone else starts taking their notebooks much more
Speaker 18:  seriously. So Picasso, for instance, he starts painting in the 1890s at
Speaker 18:  exactly the same time or learns how to paint. He's a boy.
Speaker 18:  And he, for instance, took his sketchbooks incredibly seriously. He
Speaker 18:  never gave them away, he never lost them. He kept them filed away in boxes
Speaker 18:  in his house in the south of France, and they were numbered, cataloged,
Speaker 18:  ordered. He knew that his sketchbooks were really important,
Speaker 18:  whereas painters a hundred years before him,
Speaker 18:  it seems to have been a very casual relationship. You know, or rather they,
Speaker 18:  they themselves use their notebooks, but they had no sense that anyone else
Speaker 18:  would ever find them. Interesting. So
Speaker 18:  yeah, I think there's definitely a change. And I think that Leonardo sort
Speaker 18:  of accidentally 400 years after his death prompts it. Yeah.
Speaker 18:  And, and to the extent, you know, if any kind of well-known writer
Speaker 18:  now will sell their papers to the University of
Speaker 18:  the University of Austin, for instance. Right. You know, collects writer's
Speaker 18:  notebooks and it will pay good money for them a hundred, 150
Speaker 18:  years ago, you know, universities were not doing that, they would, wouldn't
Speaker 18:  have seen the value.
Speaker 5:  Do you think that changes the way we look at those notebooks now? I mean,
Speaker 5:  I, I think about even go back to Florence, like you, you, you think about
Speaker 5:  those as an important record of real life
Speaker 5:  in a way that as soon as people become self-conscious that someone else might
Speaker 5:  see their notebooks, it sort of ceases to be a record of
Speaker 5:  real life. It, it becomes an Instagram version of real life where
Speaker 5:  everything is maybe subtly self-consciously
Speaker 5:  changed to be for public consumption in a way
Speaker 5:  that, I don't know, like I, we, we think about notebooks as these intensely
Speaker 5:  private things, but as soon as you understand that someone else might see
Speaker 5:  it. I wonder if it changes what that thing is.
Speaker 18:  Oh, well, certainly when it comes to diary writing in particular, so the,
Speaker 18:  any number of published diaries you can tell were written with publication
Speaker 18:  in mind. Mm. I write a diary every day and I don't
Speaker 18:  expect that anyone else will ever read it.
Speaker 18:  And it's certainly never gonna be published. And it's, I think you're right.
Speaker 18:  It's more intimate and it's, you know, that it's pretty uncensored
Speaker 18:  unfiltered, but then you have the Tony Blairs of this world
Speaker 18:  whose diaries are published, I think. Sure. And that's a
Speaker 18:  completely different kettle of phish.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I guess that's okay. Both of those things can exist, but they are
Speaker 5:  very different things.
Speaker 18:  Yeah, yeah. Very, very definitely. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I am really curious about how you as a person in,
Speaker 5:  in a digital world came to think about notebooks.
Speaker 5:  Because again, there is such a, there's so much about
Speaker 5:  that history that a feels very modern. Like we're, we're talking about
Speaker 5:  the same kinds of things now and like you said, using computers for the same
Speaker 5:  kinds of things that people were using notebooks for 800 years
Speaker 5:  ago. But I wonder if you're going through and you have to spend time
Speaker 5:  thinking about the thing itself and, and like you said,
Speaker 5:  paper is this crucially important invention, and
Speaker 5:  if we had invented computers in 1200 instead of inventing paper,
Speaker 5:  would it have gone roughly the same way? Or is there something about
Speaker 5:  that thing and that time and that invention that
Speaker 5:  made it different from even everything that came after?
Speaker 18:  I think up to a point, the invention makes the time. You know,
Speaker 18:  you said to me very confidently that we live in a digital world, you know,
Speaker 18:  and, and of course you are, right? Yeah. We do definitely live in the digital
Speaker 18:  world. We're speaking to each other, you know, via a digital link
Speaker 18:  up and surrounded by amazing technology. I would
Speaker 18:  also, if I was being contrarian and say to you, you are living in a notebook
Speaker 18:  world. Hmm. Because capitalism, which gives us all of we,
Speaker 18:  what we see around us, that for 600
Speaker 18:  years was entirely based in notebooks.
Speaker 18:  We would call them ledgers or account books, but it was an entirely
Speaker 18:  notebook based system until the first IBM machines. So,
Speaker 18:  and that was invented at the same time as, or roughly speaking the same
Speaker 18:  time as the notebook arrives in, in Europe, in sort of in that place in
Speaker 18:  Italy around the year 1300. They invent all of the mechanisms of
Speaker 18:  capitalism. So really we are in that world as much as we're in
Speaker 18:  the digital world. But yeah, and I, there is definitely a
Speaker 18:  sense of you have an invention and then it shapes the
Speaker 18:  world that you live in. But in unexpected, surprising, fun,
Speaker 18:  hopefully ways no one saw that Twitter was coming
Speaker 18:  10 years before Twitter arrived. Sure. But, and then suddenly it's everywhere,
Speaker 18:  and then suddenly it's nowhere again. You know? So who knows?
Speaker 5:  So, okay, let's, let's fast forward a bunch in history to,
Speaker 5:  not now, but close to now. And I wanna talk about the bullet journal.
Speaker 5:  And the reason I wanted to start with the Z is that I feel like you can draw
Speaker 5:  a straight line from that thing in Florence
Speaker 5:  800 years ago to the bullet journal phenomenon of
Speaker 5:  today, like, like a dead straight line
Speaker 5:  through almost a millennium of time.
Speaker 5:  How, how is that possible? Like, why do you think this, this thing,
Speaker 5:  this idea of how we want to record our lives in a
Speaker 5:  physical notebook has been So, I
Speaker 5:  consistently persistent over so
Speaker 5:  many centuries.
Speaker 18:  It's a really great, simple, minimal tool. I think like
Speaker 18:  with, with any kind of technology, there's this a, there's a, or any kind
Speaker 18:  of invention, there's a real virtue to simplicity. You know, so your,
Speaker 18:  your knife and fork or your chopsticks, chopsticks are great because they're
Speaker 18:  minimal. Yeah. You can't, once you've pictured them, you've invented them
Speaker 18:  once. You cannot improve on them. And a notebook I think is a lot like that.
Speaker 18:  It came to a kind of, very quickly, it became
Speaker 18:  kind of perfect in terms of its how practical it was, how cheap it was,
Speaker 18:  how available it was to everyone. And you can't really
Speaker 18:  improve on that as a bit of technology, you know, because, and then people
Speaker 18:  will use it in different ways over history. And bullet journals are, I
Speaker 18:  think, a really good example of how you can take this really simple thing
Speaker 18:  and just use it in a slightly new way. And suddenly it opens possibilities
Speaker 18:  for people which they never appreciated before. Like, there are a lot of
Speaker 18:  people
Speaker 18:  whose genuinely, there are a surprising number of people whose lives have
Speaker 18:  really been improved by doing bullet points to
Speaker 18:  organize their life. And it kind of helps them to rationalize things and
Speaker 18:  make proper decisions and act more intentionally and therefore, thereby
Speaker 18:  live happier lives. I think I, I find it constantly
Speaker 18:  incredible how this really simple thing can be reinvented so
Speaker 18:  regularly, but you're right, there is a continuous line all the way through.
Speaker 18:  I think it's just 'cause it's incredibly simple and it doesn't require batteries,
Speaker 18:  it doesn't require system updates. It's, you know, If you drop it, it doesn't
Speaker 18:  break.
Speaker 5:  What was it that was interesting to you about the bullet journal and, and
Speaker 5:  its history? Like why, why did that jump out to you as a, as a thing worth
Speaker 5:  adding to this history?
Speaker 18:  It was important to me because,
Speaker 18:  firstly, because it was a, it was a real thing, it was a real trend, you
Speaker 18:  know, when I was starting to think about the book and it, it gave me sort
Speaker 18:  of confidence that there was gonna be an appetite of people who were interested
Speaker 18:  in this stuff, which is very key in terms of building my
Speaker 18:  confidence. And then what was interesting was, I never,
Speaker 18:  I've never bullet journaled myself. I've never done the writer Carroll method,
Speaker 18:  but I got his book and then I spoke to him, interviewed him, and
Speaker 18:  he's really thought about it quite deeply. And he's thought
Speaker 18:  about the implications of writing stuff down and of organizing your thoughts
Speaker 18:  on the page and having this notebook, which he carry everywhere, and which
Speaker 18:  you write everything down on. And that kind of encouraged me to
Speaker 18:  think deeply about it too. Hmm. You know, he's taken it very seriously for
Speaker 18:  a long time and he's thought about it in a particular way and I'm, I've
Speaker 18:  got a more historical angle and I think about it in different ways, but
Speaker 18:  they're completely compatible. But the, just the fact that he had taken
Speaker 18:  it seriously, I found really interesting. And, and
Speaker 18:  hence giving him a chapter, I think was, you know, kind of fair
Speaker 18:  because he was really about the only person who had written a book about
Speaker 18:  notebooking, you know? Yeah. Before I did so, and
Speaker 18:  he also has some really interesting things to say about notebooks, which
Speaker 18:  aren't bullet journals. He was really inspired, for instance, by kind of
Speaker 18:  artists scrapbooks and, and sort of
Speaker 18:  collages and sketchbooks, which were sort of more
Speaker 18:  than sketchbooks, which had elements of diary in them. So not pure bullet
Speaker 18:  journal stuff, but stuff, which is a really interesting expression of
Speaker 18:  your experience. And, and Ryder definitely put me onto those things.
Speaker 5:  Why do you think that way of thinking about notebooking
Speaker 5:  and journaling and keeping track of your life lagged
Speaker 5:  so much? The business side of things, which a as
Speaker 5:  you chart in the book got really systematized and really
Speaker 5:  specific. And like we, we built capitalism on top of these things, right?
Speaker 5:  Like double entry accounting became a worldwide phenomenon and people
Speaker 5:  understood how to do it. And there were kind of accepted
Speaker 5:  rules on how to keep these kinds of notebooks. But in
Speaker 5:  people doing it in their own lives, like you said, there have been bits and
Speaker 5:  pieces of this over time, but
Speaker 5:  somebody like Ryder Carroll comes along hundreds of years later and really
Speaker 5:  thinks like, okay, how can I break this thing down into sort of
Speaker 5:  understandable, repeatable pieces that just happened much later? Why do you
Speaker 5:  think that is?
Speaker 18:  Honestly, I have no idea. There, there are que there are
Speaker 18:  questions you can't answer. I mean, the, the another big question, which
Speaker 18:  I just have no idea, is why did people start writing diaries?
Speaker 18:  Hmm. Or, or rather, why did they start writing diaries in
Speaker 18:  England in around the year 1570 when
Speaker 18:  they'd never done them anywhere else in the world before? I've looked really
Speaker 18:  hard at trying to find out what was so special about England at that time,
Speaker 18:  which made people start to keep a diary like you, were you an emotional
Speaker 18:  diary of how they felt about the day's events. I, I, sorry,
Speaker 18:  not very good podcast material. I'm making a baffled expression.
Speaker 18:  Listen to picture that. Yeah, I have no idea. And I think your,
Speaker 18:  my answer to your question is, it's a good question. I have no idea.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's, I, I have, I have a theory and it's based on nothing,
Speaker 5:  but it's a theory and I'm gonna, I'm gonna give you my theory as a way of
Speaker 5:  asking you another question, which I also have about this. I'm here for it.
Speaker 5:  I think as, especially as
Speaker 5:  we became more enmeshed with digital tools,
Speaker 5:  life took on like a new level of informational chaos.
Speaker 5:  There is just more stuff coming at us now than there ever has
Speaker 5:  been. And that's true in our professional lives, but
Speaker 5:  it's also true in our personal lives. I think in a, in a new way
Speaker 5:  in the last, I don't know, several decades, that there's just more
Speaker 5:  happening around you and to you all the time.
Speaker 5:  And we're, we're still reckoning with that as people, right? This question
Speaker 5:  of like, we understand what is going on in the world in a way that we
Speaker 5:  are like evolutionarily not equipped to do, and what do we do with that?
Speaker 5:  All these really interesting questions. But I think one thing that I see
Speaker 5:  all the time is people crave systems. There there is this idea that
Speaker 5:  if I can just find a way to make this make sense,
Speaker 5:  everything will be better. Right? And I think, and you mentioned the, the
Speaker 5:  getting things done method in, in the book also. And I think that
Speaker 5:  speaks to the same thing where it's like, yeah, there is this swirling mass
Speaker 5:  of stuff in my life, and If you can just tell me where to put
Speaker 5:  it and how my brain will get quieter. And I think that's
Speaker 5:  meaningful to people. And, and again, i I, there there is a
Speaker 5:  definite sort of, we are people of our time and technology
Speaker 5:  thing that is all kind of swirling together there. But I feel like when I
Speaker 5:  see people who like really love bullet journal what it, what it says is like,
Speaker 5:  the world is insane and messy, but I have made this thing that
Speaker 5:  is like my world and it is beautiful and looks like me and it just
Speaker 5:  feels good. And it's why like, people get mad at all the bullet journalists
Speaker 5:  who are like spending all of their time organizing their pages and not time
Speaker 5:  getting stuff done. And it's like no, the the organizing the pages is actually
Speaker 5:  the point of the thing. Yeah. Yeah. As much as anything else, it's
Speaker 18:  Taking control, right?
Speaker 5:  Like making the notebook is the point. And I, I feel like that was one of
Speaker 5:  the things that just keeps coming up throughout history in your book is like
Speaker 5:  the act of making the thing is as much the point as anything else. Going
Speaker 5:  back and reviewing it is fine. Doing stuff with what you put in it is fine,
Speaker 5:  but the act of making the notebook in the first place is maybe the most
Speaker 5:  important part of the whole process. And I feel like there's so much of that
Speaker 5:  happening right now that yeah, we need structure around that more
Speaker 5:  than ever. Yeah. That's just a theory.
Speaker 18:  That's a and my answers to that is yes,
Speaker 18:  that's the short answer. Slightly, slightly more involved example, or
Speaker 18:  to sort of back up what you said. So I have a day job and I
Speaker 18:  do this, I write books and talk to
Speaker 18:  people about it. And so the level of
Speaker 18:  inputs into my life in terms of communication and things flying
Speaker 18:  at me from different directions. I've got two email addresses. I've
Speaker 18:  got the Instagram, I've got the Twitter, which I'm switching off shortly,
Speaker 18:  but I've got the, the Facebook, I've got
Speaker 18:  WhatsApp on the phone, et cetera, et cetera. It just goes on. And that's
Speaker 18:  before I'm in a room with anyone actually talking to them face to face.
Speaker 18:  And my way of dealing with this is to write a diary. Yeah. So
Speaker 18:  at the end of the day, I will put it all down in here and,
Speaker 18:  and it's, it's under control as you say. And I've turned this
Speaker 18:  ephemeral nonstop flow of craziness,
Speaker 18:  most of which is completely trivial, but has to be managed somehow.
Speaker 18:  And I've just turned it into a calm thing on the page. Yeah, I
Speaker 18:  completely agree. And as to how that makes me feel, the analogy
Speaker 18:  I use is, it's like having a shower. Yeah.
Speaker 18:  Showers are lovely. Yeah. Just great. I like to have a shower every day,
Speaker 18:  but if I can't, if I have to go a day without, that's fine. No one really
Speaker 18:  minds two days without it's, you know,
Speaker 18:  mentally I start to smell. So, and that's what I'm like with the
Speaker 18:  diary, that's really good. Now I can miss a day. Yeah. I can't miss two
Speaker 18:  days. I start to smell mentally and, and it really cleans me out. Sort of
Speaker 18:  that process of just dumping it on the page really, really
Speaker 18:  is refreshing and cleansing in that sense. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I like that a lot. Why do you think we haven't found a way to do
Speaker 5:  that digitally in the way that is satisfying and
Speaker 5:  valuable in the same way that we have in notebooks? Because
Speaker 5:  like, we pretty much do business on computers now there,
Speaker 5:  there's not a lot of paper notebooks out there responsible
Speaker 5:  for how capitalism runs anymore. Yeah. But I think I, I am
Speaker 5:  someone who has tried every note-taking app on planet
Speaker 5:  Earth. I I obsessively use them. I build these systems
Speaker 5:  and overwhelmingly the ones that feel the best. And as I talk to people,
Speaker 5:  the answer is you try them all and you eventually just get a nice notebook
Speaker 5:  and a pen and you start filling it. And there is, there is something about
Speaker 5:  that that we have not replaced. And I'm curious If you have thoughts on why
Speaker 5:  it has been so hard to replace.
Speaker 18:  I have lots of thoughts. I'm gonna give you the deepest one because please.
Speaker 18:  I think this is, I think your listener can cope with a, a sort of high level
Speaker 18:  bit of neurobiology. So when you write on
Speaker 18:  a notebook page, and they've done this with MRI scans and the
Speaker 18:  very clever way of using multiple manner I scans called voxel based
Speaker 18:  morpho. When you can look at multiple brains at once, when you write in
Speaker 18:  a notebook, you use different parts of the brain to when
Speaker 18:  you type or when you write something on your phone or your tablet.
Speaker 18:  And one of the different parts you use is the hippocampus. Now this is
Speaker 18:  right in the bottom of the brain and it's your mental map. So when
Speaker 18:  you drive to your place of work, you are using
Speaker 18:  your hippocampus. When you know where the coffee
Speaker 18:  cups are in your kitchen, you are using the hippocampus. Taxi drivers, cab
Speaker 18:  drivers have amazingly well developed. Hippocampus was
Speaker 18:  an early case study in brain plasticity actually. Right.
Speaker 18:  So this is very interesting. Why do you engage your hippocampus when you're
Speaker 18:  writing in a notebook? And it's because your notebook is a place,
Speaker 18:  right? And it has its own geography. So when you write things on the pages
Speaker 18:  of a notebook, you remember, or I certainly tend to remember, oh, that was
Speaker 18:  on the left hand side at the top. Oh, that was I, I wrote that in blue somewhere.
Speaker 18:  Now that was at the back of the notebook that was at the front. And I'm
Speaker 18:  thinking about the notebook in quite a different way to how I think about
Speaker 18:  a digital note and what they think the people who research this
Speaker 18:  is that when you scroll or you carry on writing and what you've written
Speaker 18:  on a screen just scrolls up, up, up top of the page and vanishes off
Speaker 18:  the top of your screen.
Speaker 18:  It just vanishes. It has no place in the geography of your lived
Speaker 18:  experience, unlike stuff which you write down in a notebook page. So I've
Speaker 18:  got my yellow notebook and I know that if I open it halfway through, roughly
Speaker 18:  speaking, I'm gonna find what happened in July. And I can't do that
Speaker 18:  with notes I've made on an iPad, but just because my
Speaker 18:  brain hasn't thought about them in that geographic way. So that's one reason
Speaker 18:  why you feel more comfortable and you navigate those notes
Speaker 18:  more happily than you do when they're digital.
Speaker 18:  Other reasons are to do with I think the sort of the sensory experience
Speaker 18:  of writing fingers on the page, the pen in your hand being a slightly richer
Speaker 18:  experience. It's more difficult as well, it's very easy to type. You
Speaker 18:  can type, you could roughly speaking type everything I
Speaker 18:  said to you right now, you'd get it all pretty much down. You can't
Speaker 18:  do that with the pen and ink. You have to filter, you have to pause the
Speaker 18:  ideas, you have to process them and paraphrase. And that gives
Speaker 18:  you a much richer, deeper understanding of what you
Speaker 18:  are actually listening to. You can type whatever
Speaker 18:  I say without actually listening to what I'm saying at all, but to write
Speaker 18:  it down, you have to paraphrase it and therefore you have to actually interact
Speaker 18:  with the ideas. So this is why teachers and academics much
Speaker 18:  prefer their students to, to write notes rather than to type them.
Speaker 18:  So there's a couple of answers.
Speaker 5:  Do you think there's a marriage there that we can make work? I mean, I keep
Speaker 5:  thinking about you, you start the book with moleskin, which is probably
Speaker 5:  the first notebook most people think of when they think of notebooks. And
Speaker 5:  moleskin for years has been building digital tools
Speaker 5:  and they have, they have a really beautiful calendar app. They have a really
Speaker 5:  interesting journaling system. Like it's, it's all very good. Nobody
Speaker 5:  cares about it the way that they care about physical moleskin notebooks.
Speaker 5:  And you know, there, there was this phase for a long time of like, maybe
Speaker 5:  we're gonna do smart pens where I'll write in a notebook,
Speaker 5:  but it will transcribe it digitally. And now there are things where like,
Speaker 5:  okay, you can write with a pen, but it's on your iPad and it will recognize
Speaker 5:  the text and make something out of it. And it feels like we're, we're poking
Speaker 5:  at this thing where the, the act that you're describing, I think is
Speaker 5:  absolutely the best one. But having a notebook
Speaker 5:  that is a bunch of words on a page that sits on
Speaker 5:  my bookshelf waiting for me to do something with it
Speaker 5:  feels like it's missing something. Like there is a best of both worlds here
Speaker 5:  that I think I desperately want to exist. And I don't know, maybe,
Speaker 5:  Maybe it just doesn't and can't and won't. But I am curious, like, do you,
Speaker 5:  do you think we can marry those two things?
Speaker 18:  I'm not gonna say never. Okay. But I've not seen it done yet in a way which
Speaker 18:  I think some people that sort of the moleskin magic paper, the
Speaker 18:  dotted paper, whatever, they, they make it work for them and, and good luck
Speaker 18:  and that's great. And some people also manage to make those
Speaker 18:  kind of posh tablets, the, the remarkable tablets work
Speaker 18:  in in a similar way. And again, go you
Speaker 18:  personally, I haven't ever managed to.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Last thing and then I will truly let you go. Tell me
Speaker 5:  just briefly about Moleskin and why you, you start the book with
Speaker 5:  moleskin. I wanna end our podcast with moleskin. Why is
Speaker 5:  moleskin so ascendant? What, what is it about
Speaker 5:  this company and this thing that has made Moleskin the
Speaker 5:  brand? The notebook, the thing in our sort of modern world,
Speaker 18:  It's the complete refinement she took, and I
Speaker 18:  I say she, Maria Seg Bondi, who was the woman who conceived
Speaker 18:  the, the moleskin notebook, who took the very simple basic notebook that
Speaker 18:  we knew she added to it. She added this little elastic
Speaker 18:  strap, the pocket in the back, the little page at the front saying, If you
Speaker 18:  find this notebook, please return it too. She added all of these things
Speaker 18:  to a very minimal product and she somehow made it seem even more
Speaker 18:  minimal. Mm. So, and the analogy
Speaker 18:  I make, she made, she made it minimal and she made it black. And that was
Speaker 18:  the most Italian thing you could do is like perol sunglasses, pr
Speaker 18:  little black dress, espresso, you know, that's what they do. They
Speaker 18:  make it minimal and black. And she did that and somehow she
Speaker 18:  just, she tricked us, If you like, she fooled us and thank God
Speaker 18:  that she did, I wouldn't have written this book if it wasn't for Moskin.
Speaker 18:  I think because she made us look again at this simple notebook and
Speaker 18:  think of it as something which had some material value, that had some material
Speaker 18:  beauty and was, could be therefore inspiring in a way
Speaker 18:  that your school exercise book couldn't be. Hmm. So she's, from that point
Speaker 18:  of view, she's my heroine creatively, she's also
Speaker 18:  for me a figure of awe because If you look at Moleskin's numbers, the company's
Speaker 18:  numbers through history, that company's profit margin
Speaker 18:  is ridiculous. It's like 43% profit every year, gross
Speaker 18:  profit. And it's a manufacturing company. No company does that, you know,
Speaker 18:  how did they do it? So I take my hat off to her and I can forget
Speaker 18:  quite easily about all of the ridiculous collaborations with
Speaker 18:  Evernote and Adobe and things like that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, listen, you gotta do some weird stuff
Speaker 18:  Because the, the key product is amazing. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Well, and to that point, actually, one of the things you, you say kind
Speaker 5:  of as an aside in the book is that
Speaker 5:  lot of changes as the iPhone has gone through a lot of changes.
Speaker 5:  had a really fun conversation, NELI and I grabbed Ben and Sebastian
Speaker 5:  hashed all this out for a long time. Let's hear it. Excellent. All right.
Speaker 5:  And Neli Patel is also here. Hi Neli.
Speaker 21:  I think we should just get them to pronounce Hali
Speaker 5:  Over and over again. You, you just did the thing that I wanted to do first,
Speaker 5:  which is how in, how is it halide or is it hali? Can we, can we
Speaker 5:  solve this for people in the world right now? You just said Hali Ben, is
Speaker 5:  this the official correct answer?
Speaker 20:  I alternate because it's based on halogen, right? Oh God. And so
Speaker 20:  Silver Hali halogen, as long as it's not Haliday, which is a Middle Eastern
Speaker 20:  name. No,
Speaker 5:  That's what it is now. Well,
Speaker 21:  Yeah, sorry. There was, there was actually someone who worked at The Verge,
Speaker 21:  John Porter, I think he has moved on now, but he, he once PR pronounced
Speaker 21:  it on a podcast holiday and we sent him a Happy Holidays Christmas card
Speaker 21:  and we'll never let him live that down. We continue to do this every year
Speaker 21:  because
Speaker 22:  That's very good. It's so good. That's very good.
Speaker 21:  Haylight or highlight, depending on how, how fancy you feel. No, no.
Speaker 5:  You guys, this is the worst. We have to pick one. Let's do this right now
Speaker 5:  here on the verse cast, can we name your app please?
Speaker 22:  What is your name
Speaker 20:  On 3 1 2. Allied. Allied. Okay. There we go.
Speaker 20:  All right, good. And we did, I, I just wanna point out that like when we
Speaker 20:  released, I want
Speaker 22:  To point out that you super cheated in what instead say it first.
Speaker 20:  I, I I think he went on, he went on two. You never go on
Speaker 20:  two.
Speaker 22:  We're a very
Speaker 21:  Good team actually, when it comes down to it,
Speaker 20:  I, I just wanna close this discourse on names that we were like, when we're
Speaker 20:  building keynote, no one can mess up that name. And then it was featured
Speaker 20:  in the keynote from Apple and they told us we're having trouble
Speaker 20:  because it sounds a lot like Keynote. Ooh. And So I think every time
Speaker 20:  we build a new app, it just needs to challenge someone.
Speaker 21:  Well the best part was that I was like, it's actually pronounced kno. And
Speaker 21:  then they were like, really? And I was like, no,
Speaker 5:  Happy kno everybody. That's what we're doing now. Okay,
Speaker 5:  So I think we, we have a bunch of stuff to talk about and we, we should just,
Speaker 5:  we've been getting into our feelings on this podcast about what a photo is
Speaker 5:  for years now, and we have invited you two to essentially do the same thing
Speaker 5:  with us. But my first question as we get into this, and I wanna talk a lot
Speaker 5:  about Process Zero and a lot about what has changed with iPhone photography
Speaker 5:  in particular and all this stuff, but I am desperately curious like when,
Speaker 5:  when you guys started building a camera app many years ago at this point,
Speaker 5:  did you know at the time how big a like, philosophical
Speaker 5:  exercise it was to build a camera app? I think we, we think about it as like
Speaker 5:  you, you add a bunch of filters and buttons, but it's really like
Speaker 5:  you, you are making decisions about the universe when you build a camera
Speaker 5:  app in a way that I think people are only coming around to. Did you know
Speaker 5:  this all those years ago when you started working on, on Haled?
Speaker 20:  So I guess like the origin story, I think like the
Speaker 20:  first, the first code commit for a hali was 2014
Speaker 20:  for about like day, it's pronounced
Speaker 5:  Day actually
Speaker 20:  Hall, I don't, I'm gonna switch three times over. Oh my god.
Speaker 22:  It
Speaker 5:  Was all over the place.
Speaker 20:  So for Halladay in 2014 it was like
Speaker 20:  three lines of code and then put away until like 2016.
Speaker 20:  And so I'd say that in 2016 none of this computational
Speaker 20:  photography was happening. It was to,
Speaker 20:  to put it simply, a lot of these apps were just wrappers around the, the,
Speaker 20:  the APIs that Apple gave you and it was just a more pretty veneer. And
Speaker 20:  so what we were doing at the time was, and then I connected with Sebastian
Speaker 20:  in 2016, like we were adding value like focus
Speaker 20:  peaking so that you could actually tell what was in focus. You could dial
Speaker 20:  in manual values, but for the most part until Apple released
Speaker 20:  raw that up there about it, it it was that you had
Speaker 20:  no real say on how the final image would look.
Speaker 21:  And what's interesting is, I think when it came out, so highlight is, is
Speaker 21:  now seven years old. It's, it, it came out in 2017,
Speaker 21:  that's exactly when the iPhone 10 launched that year. And with the iPhone
Speaker 21:  10, I think Apple started using the word smart HDR for the first time and
Speaker 21:  they kind of, they started using that very famous slide where it take one
Speaker 21:  photo and they kind of onion slice it into like 12 of them and it to try
Speaker 21:  to show you like, oh look, we look, we do a lot of stuff and there's a lot
Speaker 21:  of smart things happening here. And I think that was, you know, around the
Speaker 21:  same end that the pixel started, you know, talking, the Pixel team started
Speaker 21:  talking about like the Italian renaissance and how we can use science to
Speaker 21:  influence things. It was, it was a very early time where people were trying
Speaker 21:  to figure out like how do we get better images out of these tiny sensors?
Speaker 21:  And that's when everything exploded with like night mode and all those kind
Speaker 21:  of things when it basically turned photography from just
Speaker 21:  taking a snap to like a data science and it was like, okay, no,
Speaker 21:  if we actually just use these processors and like do a crazy amount of computation
Speaker 21:  on it, we can fundamentally alter the output and we
Speaker 21:  can just, we can beat physics, we can just cheat it. Like we can do zaps
Speaker 21:  of field, we can all these things that big cameras can because have giant
Speaker 21:  lenses and giant sensors we can shoot at night and we can totally take photos
Speaker 21:  with like bouquet. It's not real, but nobody cares because you're still
Speaker 21:  taking a photo at night, you're still taking a photo with what looks like
Speaker 21:  a shallow depth of field. And so we were kind of emerging
Speaker 21:  at the same time as that all emerging. So,
Speaker 5:  And and how much control over that stuff do you get? Like do you look at
Speaker 5:  that in those early days as like, oh my God, look at this incredible toolkit,
Speaker 5:  we suddenly have to play with all of the, the light that this thing is
Speaker 5:  capturing instead of just doing like a thing at the end of the pipeline?
Speaker 5:  Or is it like, oh, this is barely photography anymore.
Speaker 5:  What, what, how do we deal with this? Like what, how do you look at that
Speaker 5:  when those tools start to come available? I,
Speaker 20:  I'd say like around 2020 is when things started to converge of where
Speaker 20:  things were getting a lot smarter. Also, we had like this existential question
Speaker 20:  of why should our app exist when the first party camera's getting so much
Speaker 20:  better? And fortunately both Sebastian and I were already shooting raw
Speaker 20:  photography, which in a nutshell means that you're capturing the
Speaker 20:  sensor data as a file and then you can bring it into a third party app like
Speaker 20:  Lightroom and you can make different decisions on how you wanna process
Speaker 20:  the final image. And so around 2020 was like, we were starting to see like,
Speaker 20:  wait a minute, like what Apple's doing is great, you tap a button and anyone
Speaker 20:  can get a good photo. Like my parents who don't know anything about photography
Speaker 20:  tap a button and they got a photo of their grandchild, right? But If you
Speaker 20:  looked at the underlying sensor, apple's kind of underselling like
Speaker 20:  how much better the hardware was getting and then over time the sensors
Speaker 20:  were getting bigger and better, the optics were getting better. And so that's
Speaker 20:  when we started being like, wait a minute, like how can we build a feature
Speaker 20:  around this where it stands on its own?
Speaker 22:  One of the questions I have about RAW is what it
Speaker 22:  has come to signify
Speaker 21:  What is a raw photo? Yeah,
Speaker 22:  Yeah, exactly. Not, not quite that, but
Speaker 22:  people are like, I don't like my iPhone 15 camera or I don't like my iPhone
Speaker 22:  14 camera. And then you see in the comments on social media,
Speaker 22:  people say, oh you should shoot raw. And my reaction to that is
Speaker 22:  like, that is, that's a horrible suggestion, but all
Speaker 22:  it really, because you're gonna get this giant file and you actually have
Speaker 22:  to process it to a look. But what it really means is,
Speaker 22:  oh, there's a way to turn off this processing, right? Even inside of apple's
Speaker 22:  like pro raw system, you're gonna generate a file that
Speaker 22:  lets you turn off this ultra HDR look. And that just
Speaker 22:  means something to people. And the fact that the word is raw I think is
Speaker 22:  deeply fascinating. Like the word and what it means and what
Speaker 22:  you get are all kind of wrapped up in a mess. But you guys are
Speaker 22:  describing like, we're gonna take the sensor data and start
Speaker 22:  making different kinds of images with it.
Speaker 20:  I, I think we make an effort to say native raw versus pro raw because what
Speaker 20:  Apple calls raw in pro raw is not technically
Speaker 20:  raw. And If you read the comments on a photography website like a pet
Speaker 20:  aix, I'm sorry, but it'll be just constantly
Speaker 20:  that guy being like, you know, it's not really raw and like, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 20:  Cool. Awesome. Wait,
Speaker 22:  Explain the difference for people who, who aren't as deep in the weeds as
Speaker 22:  we are. What is, what is Apple's version of pro rah? What is your definition
Speaker 22:  of native
Speaker 20:  Raw? So technically raw is you have these
Speaker 20:  sensors that have voltage values from light converted to,
Speaker 20:  you know, these numbers, right? And then that's it. And then you need to
Speaker 20:  run an algorithm to take on the sensor. There's this Bayer filter which
Speaker 20:  are discreet red, green and blue values. So it needs to kind of mush
Speaker 20:  'em up in a blender. And it's all like, it's like basically like If you
Speaker 20:  were to buy the ingredients of making a cake and then the
Speaker 20:  jpeg is the final cake, well I guess pro raw
Speaker 20:  is kinda like a half baked cake. Like, like you get to pick the frosting
Speaker 20:  If you, If you like sprinkles whatever, raisins, I hate you.
Speaker 20:  But pro raw is Apple solution to what you're just talking about where it
Speaker 20:  felt like you needed a PhD, an image processing to take one of these native
Speaker 20:  raws and make them approximate anything that Apple has. And that's partly
Speaker 20:  because Apple, when they take a photo, they're actually taking a burst of
Speaker 20:  nine photos and then merging them together. So the concept of having any
Speaker 20:  of these Bayer underlying values just doesn't exist
Speaker 20:  anymore because it's all gonna be squashed together to create smart HDR
Speaker 20:  to reduce noise and do all these effects. I really wish Apple hadn't said
Speaker 20:  pro raw because it's, it's gonna haunt me for the rest of my life explaining
Speaker 20:  this to people. But it's like kind of halfway between the native raw
Speaker 20:  and the final jpeg.
Speaker 21:  And I think what is a really important thing to say there? 'cause I see
Speaker 21:  a lot of people saying something like, oh, like
Speaker 21:  this is just the same. Like If you just take a raw photo, that that in itself
Speaker 21:  is a really fascinating turn of phrase because If you say a raw
Speaker 21:  photo, a raw file technically is not a photo yet. So what, what Ben
Speaker 21:  said, you know, it's like you got this sensor data, red green two, green
Speaker 21:  two to one blue, one red subpixels to make up the pixels. All
Speaker 21:  that data needs to be combined. You can think of it as kind of a giant spreadsheet.
Speaker 21:  There's just like has all these values of what the sensor caught in that
Speaker 21:  moment in time from one photo, one important, one photo.
Speaker 21:  And that's not a picture like you have to process
Speaker 21:  a native raw file to get the photo out of it. So per definition,
Speaker 21:  arael has to be processed for it to be displayed on a screen. It actually
Speaker 21:  has too much information to even be displayed on a screen. And so a pro
Speaker 21:  profi is, is essentially already done that step. It has created an image
Speaker 21:  because a lot of the processing that happens on iPhone images requires it
Speaker 21:  to become an rrg B image, a bitmap essentially. And so it's a very deep
Speaker 21:  image with separate information for stuff like what Neela mentioned, like
Speaker 21:  the tone mapping, which you now have the tone control for, for iPhone 16
Speaker 21:  that's separately stored in the profile gain table. So you can now adjust
Speaker 21:  just how much that HDR effect is. You can adjust the white balance completely,
Speaker 21:  you can adjust the amount of sharpening. Noise reduction is something that
Speaker 21:  is baked in per se, and not just because Apple thinks
Speaker 21:  noise shouldn't exist, like notably native raw files have a lot of noise
Speaker 21:  because you have a tiny sensor, you can have a lot of noise, but If you
Speaker 21:  combine images you can think of it If you perfectly combine the same image,
Speaker 21:  noise is different for every frame. So you're gonna average out the noise
Speaker 21:  no matter what you do. If you're combining images
Speaker 20:  Behind the scenes, like when we're talking about raws, we've been trying
Speaker 20:  to call them digital negatives, which I
Speaker 20:  don't know if that's any better for casual users, but it's the same concept
Speaker 20:  of when you had film photography you would have a negative, but then a lot
Speaker 20:  of the work of great photographers would be during the development
Speaker 20:  where you would take the negative and print it on paper, you would dodge
Speaker 20:  and burn it to recover the dynamic range, which is now an algorithm that
Speaker 20:  Apple does for you. But like there's really cool videos of like Ansel Adams
Speaker 20:  with some of his majestic landscapes, he's kind of doing like analog
Speaker 20:  photoshopping where he is like, okay, I gotta bring back some of the sky
Speaker 20:  values and bump this part up. So this isn't particularly new,
Speaker 20:  but Apple gives you like, okay, you want it on or off or somewhere in between.
Speaker 20:  That's all right. You can have any color as long as it's black, like Yeah.
Speaker 21:  Well I was just gonna say, it's, it's just fascinating to me that a lot
Speaker 21:  of people say, I see all the processing that's happening and and maybe sometimes
Speaker 21:  don't even have a word for it. Like that's kinda like what you're alluding
Speaker 21:  to. Neli is like people just like taking photos and, and then they
Speaker 21:  take a photo with Disney that's like prefer it even though it, it lacks
Speaker 21:  this absolute like, I mean literally the best teams in the world right now
Speaker 21:  in in photography are working at Google, are working at Samsung, are working
Speaker 21:  at Huawei, at Apple, like to make this processing to do all this
Speaker 21:  processing engineering and they work from the silicon up to do like insane
Speaker 21:  innovations and then people, because they're like, haha, I'll download an
Speaker 21:  app and skip all that and get what of sometimes is an objectively worse
Speaker 21:  image If you were to objectively judge image quality. But
Speaker 21:  we find that people, yeah, people just seem to have a
Speaker 21:  current preference for authenticity through imperfection, I think. And that
Speaker 21:  is really interesting.
Speaker 5:  I just keep coming back to this idea that like, and, and we've talked a bunch
Speaker 5:  about this on the show, that there is this increasingly pervasive feeling
Speaker 5:  among people that their iPhone camera in particular is bad. And,
Speaker 5:  and I think like to your point, the the on any objective
Speaker 5:  measure of quality, it, it gets better and better and better. And yet people
Speaker 5:  seem to like it less and less at the end. And
Speaker 5:  I like that disconnect is so fascinating to me because, and and it goes back
Speaker 5:  to what you were saying about like the, the iPhone has decided that noise
Speaker 5:  is bad period, right? Like it noise sucks, shadows
Speaker 5:  suck, they should not be allowed and we will get rid of them at all costs.
Speaker 5:  And I think like to your point about imperfections, like I think that's right
Speaker 5:  and I think everybody has sort of ideas about what older photos look
Speaker 5:  like and there is a thing where like photos can be too good, but I also think
Speaker 5:  as the hardware has gotten better, the software has gotten
Speaker 5:  vastly more opinionated about how a photo is supposed to look
Speaker 5:  in a way that just feels sort of incongruous, right? And, and like maybe
Speaker 5:  what's happening now is we're getting some of that choice back where it's
Speaker 5:  like, oh the hardware's really good, you can do a bunch of stuff with it.
Speaker 5:  Here are some options. And it seems like maybe that's what you,
Speaker 5:  you guys have even seen as developers is some of those tools are becoming
Speaker 5:  available to you to make available to other people and that actually that's
Speaker 5:  what people want now is some, some choice back with all this great hardware
Speaker 5:  instead of just wild new ideas about shadows.
Speaker 20:  So actually can I just dial back, I just said that
Speaker 20:  process zero is rebranded raw and I can already see a thousand comments
Speaker 20:  on Pet Aix and I thank you for pointing out haunted
Speaker 5:  By the comment section on
Speaker 21:  Pet Aix. That's
Speaker 20:  What I'm getting from you. Yeah, yeah, I know it's, I I think that it, you
Speaker 20:  know, but that's between me and my therapist. Now the, the, the thing
Speaker 20:  what the value add here is that we do have opinions about, you know, there's
Speaker 20:  a million different ways that we could develop the raw. And what I think
Speaker 20:  with Process Zero is we decided we like noise. I have a
Speaker 20:  friend who works in visual effects and he calls noise analog
Speaker 20:  dithering. And you can't remove noise without removing these
Speaker 20:  details because that's what the, what was captured at the time. We have
Speaker 20:  opinions on sharpening our images are a little softer by
Speaker 20:  design. And If you look at, you know, you look at analog
Speaker 20:  photography actually last summer before we really went all in on this, I
Speaker 20:  was shooting with a Cannon AE one on 35 millimeter film
Speaker 20:  and I was like, oh, it just feels so warm. Like it's, it's so flawed
Speaker 20:  but I love it the fact that you can't get this crazy HDR in there.
Speaker 20:  And I think the challenge is gonna be as we're building out more features
Speaker 20:  and we start, you know, adding the ability like in the future If you wanna
Speaker 20:  recover dynamic range, okay, at what point do we allow users to make fake
Speaker 20:  looking images, right? And it's something we'll have to face in the
Speaker 20:  future.
Speaker 5:  That's a big question. And at what point does something become fake looking
Speaker 5:  is like back to big philosophical existential questions about photos. Like
Speaker 5:  where to draw that line is super messy.
Speaker 21:  I think one of the things that you're touching on that well too is like
Speaker 21:  at some point these cameras all started looking very similar, right? So
Speaker 21:  you get your photo out of Samsung phone of the Pixel outta the iPhone, they
Speaker 21:  all look like they boost the shadows way up and there there
Speaker 21:  could not be any reduction or clipping of dynamic range that is just considered
Speaker 21:  data loss. We cannot have any noise. We've all agreed on that. And I think
Speaker 21:  what the, that's simply the result of making a camera for the greatest common
Speaker 21:  denominator. Like this is a camera that needs to work for everyone. I think
Speaker 21:  at some point someone was mentioning like, oh I use my camera for like reading
Speaker 21:  like a serial number on the bottom of like a car or something, right? Like
Speaker 21:  at that point, like If you don't, If you get an artistic photo that just
Speaker 21:  has like really nice chicora rendering that's really cool for you, but like
Speaker 21:  this camera literally doesn't work for me anymore. And so that's a really,
Speaker 21:  really difficult position to be in. I often tell people like, wow, I, I
Speaker 21:  would, on the one side, it's a fascinating job to design the camera at Apple,
Speaker 21:  but at the same time I have to make a camera that works for my one and a
Speaker 21:  half year old daughter and like my 80-year-old father and
Speaker 21:  myself like who is like an incredibly pedantic annoying photographer that
Speaker 21:  frequents the pet Aix comment section. Maybe it's simply the time that like
Speaker 21:  cameras do allow, and this is what app skater to do, allow people to like
Speaker 21:  find their own style and shoot in a different way. And you see that now
Speaker 21:  with like the very on apple like thing of like adding so much control to
Speaker 21:  like what kind of like final output you get in your image. And maybe that
Speaker 21:  goes down to processing too because processing, I think people are becoming
Speaker 21:  aware of how many creative decisions are being made for you. And that's
Speaker 21:  fascinating to me because there was one time like in 2020 a year of unprecedented
Speaker 21:  times, if I wanna like pull an anecdote where people ran into
Speaker 21:  this 'cause they were all taking photos with their Samsung or Pixel or
Speaker 21:  iPhone and they woke up in San Francisco one day and the entire city was
Speaker 21:  orange. Like completely orange because there was a huge wildfire near the
Speaker 21:  place where I live now. Yep. And the sun was being filtered through it and
Speaker 21:  it was all orange and people took a photo with it and the craziest thing
Speaker 21:  happened, the camera recognized it as being like, oh the white balance is
Speaker 21:  way off, we're gonna correct for that. This doesn't really happen because
Speaker 21:  it's trained on everything that's happened before it. And it has, it's literally
Speaker 21:  all the smart stuff is based on precedent and we were in 2020
Speaker 21:  living in unprecedented times and so people started downloading
Speaker 21:  like a camera app like ours to you know, like try to correct that
Speaker 21:  set manual wide balance. And that I think was like beginning
Speaker 21:  to be the turning point around when people started like exploring options
Speaker 21:  like that and being aware of something like that existing. Like they were
Speaker 21:  aware that as they took a photo like, oh wait, it's doing something for
Speaker 21:  me and I don't like that it's doing that. And that
Speaker 21:  has become a greater awareness even in like Gen Z even in people who
Speaker 21:  don't know what a file is, they know that processing is a thing and
Speaker 21:  that that increasingly is making decisions for them to go on a long
Speaker 21:  rant. But yeah,
Speaker 22:  One question I have, and I, I've talked to you about this ever so slightly.
Speaker 22:  S
Speaker 22:  Apple designs the camera as a system. Samsung is a system, Google
Speaker 22:  is a system, you've got the hardware, the lens, and then you've got a processing
Speaker 22:  pipeline to lean on and they obviously know exactly what's gonna happen
Speaker 22:  in their processing pipeline. In the case of Apple, they're designing their
Speaker 22:  own chip as part of that processing pipeline and it feels like they
Speaker 22:  can make decisions about what they can handle
Speaker 22:  in processing at the expense of what the hardware can do.
Speaker 22:  And If you all are making an app that just pulls the raw data off the sensor,
Speaker 22:  apple gets to say, well we know there's gonna be some fringing, we know
Speaker 22:  there's gonna be some distortion in this lens, but we're gonna optimize
Speaker 22:  it to collect all the light we can because our pipeline can fix
Speaker 22:  almost anything except not having the light. Has that come up for you now
Speaker 22:  in these, in the newer versions of the phone where you can see that
Speaker 22:  optimization starting to shift against like quality
Speaker 22:  outta the lens for lack of a better term, in favor of just light collection?
Speaker 21:  Yeah, the, that was actually one of the craziest things I saw when we
Speaker 21:  started shooting a lot of native raw in. 'cause for a while I was just like
Speaker 21:  pro raw maxing, like just shooting on pro raw all the time. And then I was
Speaker 21:  like, okay, let's go back to native raw for a second. I noticed that the
Speaker 21:  output was just getting a little, was just getting a little worse. Like
Speaker 21:  if I were to objectively look at it, you know, I just take a this again
Speaker 21:  to clarify the difference between pro and and native raws. You get raw
Speaker 21:  sensor data, which you just, I just quickly throw in Lightroom to develop
Speaker 21:  it. Lightroom processes that sensor data and spits it out. There's actually
Speaker 21:  some corrections already baked into that. So some of the pipeline does raw
Speaker 21:  data at on the Apple iPhone and some of it then it starts
Speaker 21:  converting it to images so it can start merging geometric geometry, corrections,
Speaker 21:  those kind of things. For instance, your ultra wide camera will have a lot
Speaker 21:  of corrections because otherwise it looks like a crazy fish eye lens basically.
Speaker 21:  Right? And then, yeah, we noticed a few years ago, like the main
Speaker 21:  camera especially, which is the one that meets to gather the most light,
Speaker 21:  you know, the camera people use for 99% of the time it has more color fringing
Speaker 21:  than it has in the past. And we, we, we, I think we talked about this in
Speaker 21:  person briefly neli. I was like, no, like the crazy thing that's happening
Speaker 21:  here is they just, there's a realization there that like, oh
Speaker 21:  wait, it might be color fringing, but we can just fix that in the
Speaker 21:  pipeline if we get more light in, we can just
Speaker 21:  correct that out and the, the smart fuckable make up for what
Speaker 21:  would traditionally be considered a bad, the worst photographic lens, right?
Speaker 21:  If it just, it just becomes a data problem essentially.
Speaker 21:  And that is coming up a little bit and I wrote a little bit, I just published
Speaker 21:  a review of the iPhone 16 yesterday and I wrote like,
Speaker 21:  look, you gotta get used to processing because gadgets in our
Speaker 21:  phones, I can, I can see them going in one direction. David, I I'm, I
Speaker 21:  feel like you're like the pixel fold kind of guy, but like you're gonna
Speaker 21:  get devices that are thinner and folding and sometimes they fold three ways.
Speaker 21:  Now in China here, the devices are folding three ways. It's, it, it's, it's
Speaker 21:  going, it it's going that way. We're not going to opt for thicker phones
Speaker 21:  and bigger cameras and to make cameras work that are smaller and
Speaker 21:  thinner and tinier and fit into like very small headsets and ray band glasses.
Speaker 21:  We're gonna need more processing because the sensors, the images aren't
Speaker 21:  gonna get any better. That's just physics. So I fully believe
Speaker 21:  that, you know, as we go towards slimmer and foldable iPhones or whatever
Speaker 21:  the, our output on something like a process zero image is probably gonna
Speaker 21:  get objectively worse. That's just the way it is. But old fashioned
Speaker 21:  photography in that way, that's just, I don't know how long that's gonna
Speaker 21:  be around on these kind of devices as they get smarter and smarter. 'cause
Speaker 21:  they'll just start relying more on the fact that they're magic, hyper powerful
Speaker 21:  computers and they're not gonna rely on the fact that they're good at collecting
Speaker 21:  light 'cause they're just not.
Speaker 22:  Wait. So let ask you about that. Lemme send you all the way down the existential
Speaker 22:  rabbit hole. This is where I live. Welcome to the basement with me
Speaker 22:  at the end of this, right? You're, you, you, the hardware is just there
Speaker 22:  to collect light and everything else happens in
Speaker 22:  the processing stack. Everything else is an average of values from the past,
Speaker 22:  right? Is that, do you see that all the way at the end that it,
Speaker 22:  you just spin the dial all the way on the path that we're on and we don't
Speaker 22:  really care if the sensor is any good or the lens is any good as long as
Speaker 22:  we can collect as much massive light as possible.
Speaker 21:  See I think that's a great philosophical question because If you come down
Speaker 21:  to it every, you can solve it the way the Samsung moon photo situation happens.
Speaker 21:  Most of the world is completely been captured before and done before. If
Speaker 21:  you train a good enough model with a bad enough sensor, you can probably
Speaker 21:  take photos of 99.95% of the things out there and they'll be really good.
Speaker 21:  So like, I don't know, that seems kind of like
Speaker 21:  a reality that we're heading towards where the processing is just simply
Speaker 21:  good enough and the reality doesn't, the reality of capturing images just
Speaker 21:  needs to correspond to like what the internal logic can cor can, can
Speaker 21:  cohere together. And I personally philosophically find that a really big
Speaker 21:  problem. I want to make a camera that,
Speaker 21:  like If you go to on the, What is a photo thing, I was talking to Ben about
Speaker 21:  this, I was like, we should probably think about what we consider to be
Speaker 21:  a photo. And to me it is an image that's generated largely majority, at
Speaker 21:  least by photons that you have captured at a moment in space and time. But
Speaker 21:  I'm not sure if that is going to be the case. I think in the future, some
Speaker 21:  cameras, maybe not all of them, but some cameras are going to increasingly
Speaker 21:  rely on data sets of what the world should look like and what images should
Speaker 21:  look like and just use data, use light as data, not as like
Speaker 21:  visual aid as much.
Speaker 5:  What is allied for all the way at the end of that road? Like what's, what's
Speaker 5:  your job when we get all the way to the end of that?
Speaker 20:  Well I mean like the invention of the automobile
Speaker 20:  didn't put an end to horses. It's just horses were allowed to
Speaker 20:  be this fun thing, you gotta look at 'em and ride 'em and stuff, right?
Speaker 20:  But as far as utility for every day, you know, people stopped keeping barns
Speaker 20:  I guess. And I mean like look, you know, foot
Speaker 20:  photography didn't end painting, painting. The reason people look at
Speaker 20:  paintings is because the amount of skill and craftsmanship that goes into
Speaker 20:  it and being able to work within these constraints. And again, it was really
Speaker 20:  eye-opening last summer shooting analog because there's
Speaker 20:  just something about an analog photo and actually the removal of details,
Speaker 20:  right? And So I don't know if anyone tried to watch one of these
Speaker 20:  high frame rate movies like The Hobbit at 48 frames per second or, or
Speaker 20:  that HDR
Speaker 20:  Will Smith movie, the one with his clone, what was it called? Gemini Man,
Speaker 20:  there we go. Yeah. And like goes ultra high frame rate HDR and what
Speaker 20:  ends up happening with movies is when you shoot high frame rate ultra realism,
Speaker 20:  it breaks the magic because your mind isn't able to fill in the
Speaker 20:  details and it turns out 24 frames per second with a slow shutter, like
Speaker 20:  it feels more dreamlike and you're able to suspend disbelief, right? And
Speaker 20:  so with photography, there's just something about a photo that is less
Speaker 20:  perfect that, that feels magical about it. So
Speaker 20:  I think there's always gonna be that as an art form and, but as far as
Speaker 20:  something that you're gonna just tap a button and get a nice photo, you
Speaker 20:  know, I think that we are smart enough that we're never gonna enter that
Speaker 20:  kind of battle with a world's most valuable company.
Speaker 22:  Well lemme say this, just to put your definition of the test photons you
Speaker 22:  collected at a moment in space and time, right? I buy that, that's a pretty
Speaker 22:  good definition. Does that count if you're taking nine photos and
Speaker 22:  merging them that that moment has extended to nine captures, right?
Speaker 21:  Yeah, So I think, so the, the thing is like, let's say,
Speaker 21:  you know, and the same thing goes for cleaning up. Like let's say you use
Speaker 21:  AI cleanup to, to, to erase a part of the photo, I feel, I still think it's
Speaker 21:  a photo, but once you fill that in with the majority of a cleanup feature,
Speaker 21:  so like 50% or more of the pixel has become filled in by a model, I feel
Speaker 21:  like it se it's ceases to be a photo meaning in a meaningful way because
Speaker 21:  it has now been filled in by a data set.
Speaker 22:  You guys are are making a tool. It sounds very much like you're focused
Speaker 22:  on the creative and artistic aspects of photography. There's a whole other
Speaker 22:  conversation about can we trust these images that exists in the world. Have
Speaker 22:  you looked at the various watermarking features from C
Speaker 22:  two PA that say, actually this happened, right? This photo of Donald Trump,
Speaker 22:  it occurred. We're gonna mark it, we're gonna send it to Getty. Getty's
Speaker 22:  gonna know this was real, this photos were marked at the camera level
Speaker 22:  when they went to to Getty. Have you looked at doing that? Is that something
Speaker 22:  you're allowed to do on iOS?
Speaker 20:  That's all bullshit. Am I allowed to swear? Like if not, like write down.
Speaker 20:  Okay, good. You're allowed to swear. So, alright. Everything that Adobe's
Speaker 20:  pushing as far as like content authenticity is, it's just, it's
Speaker 20:  like DKS and anti DVD kinda stuff in the two
Speaker 20:  thousands. It's like If you look at it, the ability to just
Speaker 20:  strip the metadata, the fact that you can just point your camera at a screen
Speaker 20:  and take a photo, like it's not gonna do anything other than convince people
Speaker 20:  to sign up for Creative Cloud and use Adobe products.
Speaker 20:  I, I don't know, I i I don't know how much deeper you wanna get in that,
Speaker 20:  but I don't Right. Think it's a, a useful use of time. Although they do
Speaker 20:  have a verification feature where I think it does like a signature of like
Speaker 20:  you can, I think kinda like CS a detection, like
Speaker 20:  it'll get a signature of a photo you could drag and drop it to UI and whoever
Speaker 20:  first posted it, like it'll tell you who did that. That's pretty cool. But
Speaker 20:  the rest of the stuff is just a waste of time. Yeah.
Speaker 22:  I'm just curious. This is right next to the creative part of how much can
Speaker 22:  I change this or how much data processing can I do is the, how much can
Speaker 22:  I trust this? And it feels like both of those are unsolved.
Speaker 21:  Yeah. When we launched process zero, like I thought I was talking to Ben,
Speaker 21:  I was like, can we use the fact that we shoot a jpeg that is the process
Speaker 21:  zero component and like the raw the the sensor again the sensor single shot
Speaker 21:  raw Bayer data as sort of a pro proof of provenance, like a proof
Speaker 21:  like that. There are not a lot of data sets of generative ai, if
Speaker 21:  any. I haven't found any at least that work on raw files. Right. But consider
Speaker 21:  conceivably you could totally do it. That's the thing. So it's, it's, it's
Speaker 21:  not a good, you know, it'd be a fig leaf of authenticity. It would be like,
Speaker 21:  look, there is a raw file. You can see that it was actually taken. But
Speaker 21:  you know, like it's still, it's just a such a losing battle.
Speaker 21:  We the we at some point, you philosophically as a, as a photographer or
Speaker 21:  camera app maker or both or esteem member of photography,
Speaker 21:  common sections, you, you just go through the same existential crisis and
Speaker 21:  you just realize, okay, there's nothing stopping this.
Speaker 20:  And can I just back up to what you were saying about like editing photos
Speaker 20:  and where's the line that you're gonna draw. So in 2016, there was a
Speaker 20:  famous National Geographic photographer, Steve McCurry, and so he
Speaker 20:  got into hot water because people noticed one of his award-winning photos
Speaker 20:  was actually different on his website because there's like a dude in the
Speaker 20:  background who wasn't in the final award-winning photo and people started
Speaker 20:  digging into it. And like basically he would use what is iOS
Speaker 20:  eighteen's object removal feature before it existed. He did that equivalent
Speaker 20:  kind of editing. And this was a huge, like, y you don't do that if
Speaker 20:  you're actually taking photos. So I I,
Speaker 20:  and I guess this is also a question for you as journalists, like when you,
Speaker 20:  at what point when you're doing like an interview
Speaker 20:  or you're transcribing, you're pulling quotes, at what point is it okay
Speaker 20:  to remove the likes and the buts? You'll be doing a lot of that
Speaker 20:  with me and thank you,
Speaker 22:  But,
Speaker 20:  But at what point are you then editorializing what you're
Speaker 20:  trying to capture and telling a story that actually didn't occur and
Speaker 20:  effectively, you know, everyone has to have that level of journalistic integrity
Speaker 20:  if they wanna call it a photo.
Speaker 22:  So David and I are both gonna answer on three and we're gonna see if we
Speaker 22:  have the same answer.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 22:  I actually, I'll let David answer my, my quick version of that is,
Speaker 22:  that's norms, that's professional norms, that's what you're describing.
Speaker 22:  Yeah. Right. This guy was a professional photographer, he entered a professional
Speaker 22:  photography contest, he broke the rules, he got kicked out and they got
Speaker 22:  in trouble. You're a journalist, you get a bunch of quotes,
Speaker 22:  you go two sideways, you're over the line, right? Like the
Speaker 22:  journalist club will, if it still exists, will, will
Speaker 22:  get mad at you and your, your reputation will suffer. If you're a Getty
Speaker 22:  photographer, there's a, there's a list of rules of things you're allowed
Speaker 22:  to edit and most of them are like, you can change exposure and that's about
Speaker 22:  it, right? You can do some vignetting. If you look at New York Times photos,
Speaker 22:  all they're allowed to do is vignette. So they're all just vignette to hell
Speaker 22:  and back. Yeah. Because that's the only button they get. So like,
Speaker 22:  that's professional norms. I don't know what consumer norms are gonna be
Speaker 22:  and what we're seeing is an explosion of consumer photography and that
Speaker 22:  I think is really challenging. I dunno, David, what, what's your answer?
Speaker 5:  I, I, I think about the same. I mean, there's been a, a big discussion this
Speaker 5:  year about how people transcribe
Speaker 5:  Donald Trump. There, there's been all this stuff about sane washing Donald Trump,
Speaker 5:  where he'll, he'll go on like a nine minute ramble of nonsense
Speaker 5:  and then a, a reporter will, will essentially try to make it make sense,
Speaker 5:  which on the one hand is like good, useful journalism. Like here are the
Speaker 5:  words that he, he was trying to say. On the other hand, it, it makes somebody
Speaker 5:  who doesn't make any sense makes some sense. And I think I I
Speaker 5:  it's, it's a complicated thing. Like at what point is my job to make
Speaker 5:  something, make as much sense as possible So I can help my reader understand
Speaker 5:  and at what point is my job to represent something as it was
Speaker 5:  in all its messiness. Yeah. And it's like, it, I think it is kind of a perfect
Speaker 5:  analogy for what we're trying to do with photography. And I, I don't have
Speaker 5:  great answers, right? Because it's, especially when it's messy how
Speaker 5:  uny you're supposed to make it is really complicated.
Speaker 22:  And, and really the question is, can you make everybody believe in
Speaker 22:  the professional norm? The answer is like obviously no.
Speaker 20:  So I guess the closest that we have around ethics right now
Speaker 20:  is Apple's decision that they're not gonna allow fully generative
Speaker 20:  AI in iOS 18. And there was the interview with Gruber where they're
Speaker 20:  talking like, okay, we're gonna generate cartoons, but we're not gonna generate
Speaker 20:  photo realistic stuff. And so that's nice when you have someone who is,
Speaker 20:  you know, not enabling outright bad actions,
Speaker 20:  although then you have someone like Google who's also letting you like Yeah,
Speaker 20:  just change the background. Yeah. Type in what you want.
Speaker 21:  That does like, remind me of like that amazing quote that Neli got from
Speaker 21:  Apple's John McCormack that basically was like, okay, we believe a photo
Speaker 21:  is a thing that really happened, which is still not going as far as saying
Speaker 21:  like, a photo is a thing you capture with a camera or is light that is captured.
Speaker 21:  It is a thing that happened which solely fits in the model of having a generated
Speaker 21:  future where there is a super great Apple model that will just basically
Speaker 21:  fill in the blanks if the image data isn't good enough, it just needs to
Speaker 21:  confirm that a thing has actually happened. So it's like, yeah, like
Speaker 21:  surely we will continue to have journalistic standards and there will be
Speaker 21:  a few of these things like C two PA to work in
Speaker 21:  their niches, but I mean, there's no stopping the
Speaker 21:  train that's heading down the tracks of like the absolute apocalypse of
Speaker 21:  like what the meaning the meaningfulness of photos on the internet. I I
Speaker 21:  truly think, if I look at my daughter, she's one and a half years old now
Speaker 21:  when she's a teenager. I don't think she will believe any single image she
Speaker 21:  sees on the internet.
Speaker 5:  I think the, the piece of this that gets lost in a lot of this conversation,
Speaker 5:  I think is like, we, we talk a lot about the sort of really high
Speaker 5:  stakes photos and we talk a lot about like the
Speaker 5:  photos of a serial number, right? But I think like Sebastian, to your point,
Speaker 5:  you, you have a young kid. I, I think I have a young kid, Neil
Speaker 5:  has young kids, Ben, I don't, I don't know.
Speaker 20:  I got one. He is got hand foot and mouth disease right now, so Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Good times all around. But I think like Sebastian, to your point, your
Speaker 5:  kid will probably grow up in a world where they don't believe photos they
Speaker 5:  see on the internet. I think that's probably right. But the question of like,
Speaker 5:  will they believe photos about themselves from when they were kids? Mm. Is
Speaker 5:  is the other part of this that I think is like complicated and is, is such
Speaker 5:  a like normal everyday use case. We don't talk about in this context,
Speaker 5:  but the, the question of like, when I, when I take pictures of
Speaker 5:  my kid, what is, what is what responsibility
Speaker 5:  in, in air quotes, do I have to like truth and honesty versus like taking
Speaker 5:  a fun picture of my child having fun
Speaker 5:  I feel like is is such a like mainstream every single person
Speaker 5:  use case that we just don't talk about enough because it, I it feels
Speaker 5:  mely, but I don't know. And as you guys think about tallied, like people
Speaker 5:  download this stuff in part because they wanna make beautiful art that hangs
Speaker 5:  in museums and in part because they wanna take better pictures that are kids
Speaker 5:  and like, what, what is the job there in, in this world?
Speaker 20:  All of my son's photos are in native raw, so I can show him
Speaker 20:  the receipts
Speaker 5:  Afterwards. He can develop the negatives himself. Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 20:  Yeah.
Speaker 21:  No, but that's, that's a really good point.
Speaker 5:  But they hear, son, I've made you some negatives.
Speaker 20:  You know, it's important that every dad has a talk with a son
Speaker 20:  about noise reduction. It's dangerous world out there
Speaker 20:  and you know how to be prepared. Yeah.
Speaker 21:  But So I mean, to that point, like some part of me feels like, you know,
Speaker 21:  we're gonna go back and look at, we're gonna recognize this era of mobile
Speaker 21:  photography for looking a certain way. That's just a fact. And we're,
Speaker 21:  we're recognizing the first generation of Instagram photos by the heavy
Speaker 21:  filters, which also means people are going to look at the first generation
Speaker 21:  of Instagrammed photos and be like, oh, these are real, there's no generative
Speaker 21:  AI in them because you can see by how bad these filters are. This was before
Speaker 21:  the end times of photographic integrity, which is fascinating to me by the
Speaker 21:  way that those fake C pia filters are gonna go down in time as like a symbol
Speaker 21:  of authenticity, which at the time were derided as being universally
Speaker 5:  Deeply real Photos. Yeah.
Speaker 21:  Deeply unreal. Yeah, deeply real Photos must be real. And
Speaker 21:  I think we, we'd love to kind of in a same, in, in a way
Speaker 21:  provide that niche too, because we want to offer that extra tool
Speaker 21:  that just gives you a, a more authentic shot because it's a bit more true
Speaker 21:  to like what an old fashioned camera might have captured. It has a bit less
Speaker 21:  of that process look going on. But two, like I I
Speaker 21:  I also believe those photos are more representative of your memories because
Speaker 21:  they, they are more like the way you remember a moment. Like when I edit
Speaker 21:  my photos actually I tend to make the sunsets warmer and the cozy
Speaker 21:  times nicer. And the time when I walked in Tokyo alone at 3:00 AM
Speaker 21:  bluer and more cyber punky because that's just the way it felt. And I think
Speaker 21:  those aren't perfect representations of reality. And that greatest common
Speaker 21:  denominator of photography thing is kind of what's making
Speaker 21:  people pull towards that a bit more. And maybe also ironically making the
Speaker 21:  pull more towards generative things or, or more creative ways altering photos
Speaker 21:  because they're deeply unsatisfied with how, how
Speaker 21:  perfectly photos represent reality when they're sensing reality around them,
Speaker 21:  but not the world that they perceive per
Speaker 21:  se. Emotionally
Speaker 5:  Welcome back. Alright, so I'm in the middle of kind of a gaming
Speaker 5:  dilemma. I've been really a gamer off and on over
Speaker 5:  the course of my life. I, it's not something that it's kind of a consistent
Speaker 5:  activity, but I'll play a lot for a few months and then kind of put
Speaker 5:  the console away for a few months. 'cause whatever things get busy or I get
Speaker 5:  into something else, but then I always come back to games. And really
Speaker 5:  for me it's sports games that are the most consistent. Like I play
Speaker 5:  Madden every year. I like the NBA games 2K is really good.
Speaker 5:  I've been a FIFA player for forever. I like Fortnite. I like games that
Speaker 5:  I can kind of come and go to and play a whole bunch all at once
Speaker 5:  and then leave for a little while and then come back. I also like games that
Speaker 5:  I can play for like 15 minutes at a go. And the challenge I've always had
Speaker 5:  with a game like Elden Ring is I just wanna play it for hours.
Speaker 5:  And I feel like it never rewards you for just a couple of minutes of playing
Speaker 5:  at a time in a way that some of these more finite battle
Speaker 5:  royale or like football game sized games really are.
Speaker 5:  So all of this is to say I'm pretty happy with my gaming setup.
Speaker 5:  I haven't really felt the need to get a PS five or anything like that.
Speaker 5:  I'm still on a PS four pro. It works fine, everything's great. But more recently
Speaker 5:  I want something new. We've been talking a lot about
Speaker 5:  handheld consoles on this show over the last eight months or so I would
Speaker 5:  say. And there's just a lot of cool stuff happening. I also
Speaker 5:  travel more than I used to and I'm back to wanting something
Speaker 5:  I can play on the train or on a plane or in a hotel room when I'm not at
Speaker 5:  home. I also just spend too much time sitting at my desk. Like
Speaker 5:  right now I'm sitting at my desk, my monitor's in front of me, my
Speaker 5:  computer is underneath it. I have a Mac mini that I use for most things.
Speaker 5:  And then right off to the right is my PlayStation. And so having This
Speaker 5:  one space be the place that I sit for work all day and then to play games
Speaker 5:  at night, I just don't like it. And I want something that I can take and
Speaker 5:  sit on the couch while I hang out with the dog or play out in the backyard
Speaker 5:  when the weather's nice. So I'm really into the idea of a handheld console,
Speaker 5:  but I have no idea which one to get. So I enlisted two people
Speaker 5:  to help me figure it out. Sean Hollister and Alex Kranz, they both know this
Speaker 5:  stuff way better than I do. And together we are going to make a
Speaker 5:  decision about which handheld console I'm gonna buy. Let's get into it.
Speaker 5:  Alex Krantz. Hello in Texas. Howdy y'all.
Speaker 5:  Well this is, this is what we're gonna do here. Sean Hollister. Hello.
Speaker 23:  Hi. From the Land of Gaming Handhelds,
Speaker 5:  I have brought you here to do personal tech support for me because that is
Speaker 5:  what the first test is about, is helping David figure out which
Speaker 5:  gadgets he should buy. Good. I'm going to lay out for you my current situation
Speaker 5:  and then you are going to help me solve my current situation. So
Speaker 5:  my current situation is I have a PlayStation four, I've had it for a million
Speaker 5:  years. It's fine. It plays video games. I would like to
Speaker 5:  upgrade, but I don't think what I want is a PS five. I think what I want
Speaker 5:  is something handheld and portable because my PS
Speaker 5:  four like lives next to my computer in my basement and I'm spending too much
Speaker 5:  time sitting in this chair looking at this screen. And I would like to have
Speaker 5:  something that can like go out in the world with me and I travel a lot and
Speaker 5:  all these things. So I want something that is like primarily but not entirely
Speaker 5:  a portable handheld gadget. I would like to
Speaker 5:  play lots of games. We can talk about which games I do and don't care about,
Speaker 5:  but I have exactly one non-negotiable game, which is, which is
Speaker 5:  fifa, EA Sports FC is the new name of it. I will call it FIFA
Speaker 5:  until the day I die. I play that game more than I play every other game
Speaker 5:  combined and I need that game. That's it. That's literally like,
Speaker 5:  that is the entirety of where I am and I wanna buy something and I
Speaker 5:  want you to tell me what to buy.
Speaker 23:  Why? Why is that your game? Why is that your game? Because I have an
Speaker 23:  answer for you, but the answer has just been foiled by the fact that you
Speaker 23:  have picked a game which, and I quote runs a,
Speaker 23:  this program encountered E 1 110 0 B during
Speaker 23:  initialization. Okay. Error message when you try to run it outta
Speaker 23:  Steam deck. So I guess I'm not gonna tell you to buy a Steve Deck.
Speaker 5:  My worry was this is going to be the shortest The Vergecast in history because
Speaker 5:  I was gonna say all that and you were both gonna say Steam Deck and then
Speaker 5:  we were gonna hang up and move on with our lives if it were not for
Speaker 5:  This one game that I require. Is the world sort of that simple
Speaker 5:  at this particular moment?
Speaker 24:  Yeah,
Speaker 23:  It kind of is. And it Maybe it won't be in like, okay,
Speaker 23:  two weeks in, in, in two weeks or so through, is it three weeks? There will
Speaker 23:  be a Windows handheld with a battery that is bigger than any other
Speaker 23:  handheld on the market. And maybe that will solve the issue of Windows handhelds
Speaker 23:  don't have great battery life.
Speaker 24:  That won't solve all the other problems with the Windows handheld.
Speaker 24:  I'm gonna say David, you're, you're, you know, you're on The Vergecast,
Speaker 24:  So I feel very comfortable saying you like to tinker, you
Speaker 24:  enjoy a little tinkering. So
Speaker 5:  I, I do, when I don't, I will say what I'm, I am willing to tinker.
Speaker 5:  Like if it, if it's a matter of I need to like buy this thing and spend a
Speaker 5:  couple of hours like downloading and tweaking and doing whatever I need to
Speaker 5:  get it set up fine. I am not buying a thing
Speaker 5:  with the intention of screwing with it forever. Yeah. I would like this thing
Speaker 5:  to play video games and I want to be able to sit down on my couch and be
Speaker 5:  playing video games as quickly as possible. That's actually very important
Speaker 5:  to me.
Speaker 23:  Would you spend those two hours, hear me out? Would you spend
Speaker 23:  those two hours setting up your steam deck to dual boots
Speaker 23:  windows off of an SD card? Occasionally
Speaker 23:  with the one non-negotiable game that apparently you must have,
Speaker 24:  You can get FIFA on the steam deck without doing dual boot. I was,
Speaker 24:  I was looking this up.
Speaker 5:  Tell me more.
Speaker 24:  You will need to be comfortable diving
Speaker 24:  into the Linux side of Steam deck. Okay. And do some tweaking.
Speaker 24:  And also does it have to be FIFA
Speaker 24:  24?
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 24:  Oh, it can't can't be FIFA 23. Well
Speaker 5:  No, it actually, it, what's important is that it's going to be 25 in like
Speaker 5:  six weeks and it's, it's actually what I need is that one.
Speaker 23:  Do you have to play it online? Because it's the NH sheet That's, that's
Speaker 23:  the problem here. Ea Okay. Insisting on its own version of Anti Sheet instead
Speaker 23:  of the ones that actually work on the steam deck.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I need to be online.
Speaker 23:  Shit. Well
Speaker 24:  I feel like the other FIFA games have appeared in Xbox Cloud and
Speaker 24:  I feel like This one would also appear in Xbox Cloud.
Speaker 23:  That was my next thought. You
Speaker 5:  Make a very good point here, which is a thing that I should have said. I
Speaker 5:  don't need to be able to play this game on the first day that it is available.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I just need to play it at some point. Yeah. And what I have discovered
Speaker 5:  about the video game world is that those things are, are very different.
Speaker 5:  Like when things come to Game Pass and there's stuff that comes to PlayStations
Speaker 5:  Cloud stuff later on that isn't there, like day and date when
Speaker 5:  they release, like the reason I picked this game that matters is because
Speaker 5:  I, I can just like get lost down this impossible universe with any game that
Speaker 5:  I want. It's all very complicated. But just, just to tie off the one piece
Speaker 5:  of this, if, if all I was saying is I want a handheld thing to play
Speaker 5:  games on and I did not give you any specific games Yeah. Is the answer like
Speaker 5:  the steam deck and it's not even close?
Speaker 23:  Yeah, it really is. It really is. The steam deck.
Speaker 23:  We, we we're in this moment where all of these other
Speaker 23:  companies are like, we want a piece of that steam deck action, but we're
Speaker 23:  gonna build it on Windows because gamers tell us that Windows is where
Speaker 23:  all of the games are and they want to just be able to play the games they
Speaker 23:  already own. Which
Speaker 24:  Is true. Which
Speaker 23:  Is true. But the reality is that the Steam deck plays
Speaker 23:  Windows games and it plays more of them better
Speaker 23:  than a native Windows system plays Windows games.
Speaker 5:  What is the problem with the native Windows system?
Speaker 24:  Because Windows is built for computers for
Speaker 24:  laptops and, and desktops and things that you use with a mouse and a at
Speaker 24:  least 13 inch display. And then you put that on a seven inch
Speaker 24:  display and instead of a mouse you have a joystick.
Speaker 5:  Okay, that sounds awful. Now that, now that I'm thinking this through, that
Speaker 5:  sounds like a nightmare.
Speaker 23:  That part's kind of, that you can, If you wanna spend your two hours of
Speaker 23:  setup, you can certainly spend 10 minutes of them setting up
Speaker 23:  steam to launch every time you launch your Windows computer, enter launch
Speaker 23:  right into big picture mode. And then you have an interface that's similar
Speaker 23:  to the steam deck, but it doesn't have the ability to like
Speaker 23:  tweak the handheld very easily so that you get great battery life. The
Speaker 23:  chips won't give you great battery life to begin with 'cause there's all
Speaker 23:  that other overhead for all the other shit you don't need in Windows. Sometimes
Speaker 23:  you'll turn off your Windows system, you'll, you'll put it to sleep and
Speaker 23:  you'll turn it back on again and wake it up again and all of a sudden your
Speaker 23:  app will be gone. And where did it go? I wonder why it isn't full screen
Speaker 23:  anymore. It's this tiny icon on the Windows task bar. That's not great.
Speaker 23:  Sometimes it won't wake up from sleep, it'll have restarted itself.
Speaker 5:  I'm having like netbook flashbacks to 10 years ago as you're
Speaker 5:  describing this,
Speaker 24:  Sometimes for some reason I can't get it to stop asking for the password
Speaker 24:  when I open one of my Windows game consoles. And so then I have to like
Speaker 24:  figure out how to get the, the accessibility keyboard up, which
Speaker 24:  always takes at least five minutes and then very carefully
Speaker 24:  type in the password, which is super long because I like to be safe.
Speaker 24:  It's, it's my favorite thing to do, David, you don't wanna do that.
Speaker 5:  This is not the most compelling case you've ever made, Alex. But wait,
Speaker 5:  Sean, you, you alluded to maybe there is something coming that solves this
Speaker 5:  problem for me. Okay.
Speaker 23:  Not most of these problems. Okay. But, but the but the battery life, the
Speaker 23:  battery life problem
Speaker 23:  asus with the rug ally, the ROG ally, they're, they're gonna, they're gonna
Speaker 23:  hop on me. So the ROG ally came out a year ago
Speaker 23:  as like a steam dick, but worse in almost every way
Speaker 23:  except that it had a better screen, a variable refresh rate screen. It has
Speaker 23:  since been surpassed by the Steam deck oled, which has an OLED screen that
Speaker 23:  goes 90 hertz. I'm gonna stop getting into the weeds, but they're coming
Speaker 23:  out with a new version of that later this month that will have a
Speaker 23:  doubled battery in it and all kinds of other creature comforts.
Speaker 23:  It'll be more comfortable to hold in the year since they
Speaker 23:  shipped the original ROG ally, the UI has gotten a little bit
Speaker 23:  better. It's smoother. Like Tom Warren likes
Speaker 23:  his, I think he might prefer that over the steam deck. He is a notorious
Speaker 23:  Windows fan boy.
Speaker 24:  That's why he doesn't count.
Speaker 23:  I I think it's going to be very possibly the first Windows
Speaker 23:  handheld that I can recommend because they've gotten so many
Speaker 23:  things right. But it fundamentally still runs Windows and
Speaker 23:  Microsoft has not improved Windows in any meaningful way in the year
Speaker 23:  and a half, two years since Steam Deck came out.
Speaker 24:  They could though, right? Like, like we've been hearing a lot of rumors
Speaker 24:  that they're gonna introduce some sort of Xbox handheld in the next couple
Speaker 24:  of years that'll very likely run on Windows because technically the Xbox
Speaker 24:  runs on that. There's like the opportunity, I feel like a lot like
Speaker 24:  remember when a MD was having its big resurgence. Nvidia was the game
Speaker 24:  GPU and then a MD was like, we're gonna start doing this again. And the
Speaker 24:  difference was Nvidia actually did software and made the games
Speaker 24:  work really, really well. Whereas a MD didn't for at least a year or two.
Speaker 24:  Yeah. That's where the Windows handhelds are. No one's done those really
Speaker 24:  important software tweaks. So the steam deck is better, but
Speaker 23:  Microsoft would have to be like, we're gonna ship a different OS on it.
Speaker 23:  We're gonna ship a conversion to Windows that's so stripped down. You don't
Speaker 23:  recognize it as Windows anymore. Look,
Speaker 24:  If it opens ea origins then the like I'm fine.
Speaker 23:  EA is one of the achilles of the steam deck you brought up fifa. Fifa
Speaker 23:  EA games will notoriously, particularly If you need online, they will just
Speaker 23:  break on Steam deck because EA does not give a shit about
Speaker 23:  valves handheld and they'll just like change their stupid mandatory like
Speaker 23:  DRM app all the time. It used to be called Origin now it's like EA app and
Speaker 23:  games will just break there on Steam deck. But everything else works pretty
Speaker 23:  good. But
Speaker 24:  They do participate in cloud gaming. They, they, they, most of their stuff
Speaker 24:  is available on the various cloud gaming platforms and all of those
Speaker 24:  work on the steam deck and you can get 'em up and running pretty quickly
Speaker 24:  and then not have to like constantly go into the Linux backend to tweak
Speaker 24:  'em. Just the one time meaning
Speaker 5:  Like I could do like steam deck plus game
Speaker 5:  pass and solve my problem.
Speaker 23:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  Is thi is this a good idea? Yeah,
Speaker 24:  You could do that. Okay. You could even, you could stream your, your Sony
Speaker 24:  PS four from there so you don't have to like sit in front of it to play
Speaker 24:  the last of us.
Speaker 23:  Oh yeah. We can stream your Xbox and your PlayStation and
Speaker 23:  cloud to the steam deck. It does all these things.
Speaker 5:  I'm glad you brought this up because this is, this is a, a thing I have deeply
Speaker 5:  investigated and have come up with is a, is just a terrible nightmare that
Speaker 5:  I will not subject myself to. There are, there are things about
Speaker 5:  remote streaming your own console that are really great and they
Speaker 5:  immediately fall apart as soon as you get anywhere outside of your house.
Speaker 5:  Like it just doesn't. Yeah. Oh yeah.
Speaker 23:  Do you, do you need to play Fief outside your house?
Speaker 5:  I do. Like for me, honestly. Okay. The, the two biggest things
Speaker 5:  I'm trying to solve in switching from this console on my desk to
Speaker 5:  the handheld is I wanna play other places in my house than at this desk,
Speaker 5:  which is a victory for console streaming and I wanna play when I travel
Speaker 5:  in part because I'm addicted to this game. And it's set up in such a way
Speaker 5:  that the mechanics are, If you don't play every day, it's actually kind of
Speaker 5:  like, it's a real problem as I'm describing this. But this is where I'm at
Speaker 5:  in life and the console streaming thing is great for the first thing.
Speaker 5:  Like I can, I can sit upstairs on my couch and play my
Speaker 5:  PS four on like an iPad and it actually works passively well, total
Speaker 5:  non-starter trying to stream any stuff over the internet. I just,
Speaker 5:  it's just not even worth it.
Speaker 23:  This goes for all streaming. Yeah, I agree with that. All streaming breaks
Speaker 23:  down once you leave your house because you no longer have control over making
Speaker 23:  sure you have a good internet connection. If you're out there like on 5G,
Speaker 23:  If you have a great 5G signal and nobody else in the node is using it right
Speaker 23:  then, yeah, you could have a great streaming experience. But I, I would
Speaker 23:  sit, I would sit in, you know, a hospital waiting room or out in a cafe
Speaker 23:  and I'd be using that, that razor device, which could only really do cloud
Speaker 23:  streaming and I would have a beautiful streaming
Speaker 23:  experience that would drop out five minutes later and be completely unplayable
Speaker 23:  over and over and over again. I had that experience with cloud gaming
Speaker 23:  with a good cloud gaming service like GForce. Now great service. This
Speaker 23:  connection would not maintain that. Now if you're talking about going over
Speaker 23:  to a friend's house, who, which that your friend also has amazing
Speaker 23:  internet at home and you wanna stream from Xbox Cloud there. Great. That,
Speaker 23:  that could, that could, that could work great.
Speaker 24:  I was just assuming that David has like a hotspot with him at all time.
Speaker 24:  That gives him brilliant internet like 90% of the time,
Speaker 5:  To be honest, I do a lot. Yes. It's called, it's called an iPad Pro with
Speaker 5:  Cell Connection and it's actually like an unbelievably great hotspot. The
Speaker 5:  problem is, I'll give you the worst case scenario for my own
Speaker 5:  gaming usage is on an Amtrak train from DC
Speaker 5:  to New York. And at that point, realistically what I need is games I can
Speaker 5:  play offline, right? Which I think just rules out full reliance on
Speaker 5:  game streaming services. Like I actually, this is why I'm, I'm compelled
Speaker 5:  by the combination of Steam Deck and Game Pass. Like I,
Speaker 5:  I can do mostly online stuff and like I have, I, I don't need to be able
Speaker 5:  to play FIFA online while I'm on Amtrak wifi. That's like not possible in
Speaker 5:  the world that we live in. So I'm fine with that, but I need to be able to
Speaker 5:  do something on that thing when I have crappy connection and the idea of
Speaker 5:  just having like a brick in my hands when the wifi is bad feels
Speaker 5:  bad.
Speaker 24:  I do have one other suggestion and it is actually even
Speaker 24:  more basic than the steam deck and it's a switch.
Speaker 5:  I I'm glad you brought this up.
Speaker 24:  It's, it's like the steam deck gives you all of the
Speaker 24:  customization and gives you, it's like a Swiss Army knife. The switch is
Speaker 24:  like just a really good K bar. Like it's good for one thing
Speaker 24:  and that's playing the games that Nintendo is okay with you playing on it.
Speaker 5:  And one of those games is, is EA Sports FC 24,
Speaker 5:  the dumbest name game in soccer. But
Speaker 23:  You're still not gonna play it online on Amtrak, right? No,
Speaker 5:  But So I I have almost landed there except, and, and Kranz I'm glad you
Speaker 5:  brought this up because I wanna know what you guys think right now feels
Speaker 5:  like a stupid time to buy a switch. It feels like the end of a
Speaker 5:  switch cycle. They have already talked about the next one, like the switch
Speaker 5:  by all accounts is still very good, but this feels like a ridiculous time
Speaker 5:  to buy a switch.
Speaker 23:  It is absolutely the end of the switch cycle. They're they're, they're delaying
Speaker 23:  it a little bit. They're not like, they don't want to come out right away
Speaker 23:  and do switch too. They're biding their time probably 'cause they want
Speaker 23:  to get some great software lined up for it. And I imagine that that
Speaker 23:  software, If you wanna play a metro prime for or whatever the next game
Speaker 23:  is that Nintendo does, it probably won't work as well on
Speaker 23:  the current switch. 'cause the current switch is not only seven years old
Speaker 23:  in terms of its processing power, but also
Speaker 23:  was already weak to begin with. Like when you played Zelda
Speaker 23:  breath of the wild on day one on the switch and you go to the, the forest
Speaker 23:  where the master sword is like, it's choppy. It was choppy then
Speaker 23:  it was choppy seven years ago. You know, I was
Speaker 24:  Like, FIFA will look like a bunch of potatoes or on a big green field.
Speaker 24:  But, but you'll be, but you'll know what those potatoes are and you'll be
Speaker 24:  able to control all the little potatoes. So like if the control of
Speaker 24:  the potatoes is important and not how they look, the switch could be
Speaker 24:  an option. 'cause there's a lot of good deals right now because there's
Speaker 24:  a ton of different ones. Like I, I just recently picked up the, the new
Speaker 24:  Zelda one because somebody left it on a plane and I bought it at a thrift
Speaker 24:  store.
Speaker 23:  Have you played the new Ilda yet?
Speaker 5:  I have. So I actually have an OG switch and it
Speaker 5:  worked great and I loved it very much. And then it got to the point where
Speaker 5:  literally the battery lasts like six minutes. Like it's, it's fine.
Speaker 5:  The thing is seven years old, I got a lot of love out of it. I used it for
Speaker 5:  a long time and it just basically doesn't work anymore. And so now it's just
Speaker 5:  like a pretty yellow thing that sits over there.
Speaker 23:  Do not trade that in because if it's an original switch that the battery
Speaker 23:  is six minutes, it also means that it is hackable and you can do fun things
Speaker 23:  with it and it's worth money. Okay. So
Speaker 5:  I deal. Okay, well that's David's side business in selling
Speaker 5:  old gadgets is is a whole nother thing you and I should do on this show,
Speaker 5:  Sean. So yeah, So I think one of the outcomes I'm afraid
Speaker 5:  of is that the answer is just wait a year because there's gonna
Speaker 5:  be a new switch and they might fix windows and maybe we'll get the Xbox thing.
Speaker 5:  And it feels like in a weird way, we're in like a bad middle zone between
Speaker 5:  good things.
Speaker 24:  No, you need to get this steam deck with Ola and just be done and happy.
Speaker 23:  I think what you need to do is you need to unlock, you need to unlock
Speaker 23:  a mountain of amazing PC games you've been missing that are
Speaker 23:  incredibly cheap and brilliant and beautiful and ru on this
Speaker 23:  handheld with an amazing screen. That's what you need to do.
Speaker 24:  And it's also hackable,
Speaker 5:  Sean, I gave you one game, one game that I need to play
Speaker 5:  and you're telling me that I can have everything I want except the one game
Speaker 5:  that I need to play.
Speaker 23:  If you wanna play Fortnite on there, it doesn't do that either. So unless
Speaker 23:  you're gonna stream that, I
Speaker 5:  Literally, I almost wrote down that the two games were Fortnite and fifa
Speaker 5:  and I decided I could live without Fortnite because there are other good,
Speaker 5:  okay, David has an hour to kill Battle Royale games out there. I could, I
Speaker 5:  could take or leave Fortnite at this point in my life. I was
Speaker 24:  Like, you can just use our iPad.
Speaker 5:  That is, that is true. So let me float another idea by you,
Speaker 5:  which is that I, instead of buying one thing, I buy
Speaker 5:  several things and, and I just yes, acknowledge
Speaker 5:  that at least for this next phase of my life, the right thing to do is
Speaker 5:  get a PS five and a PS portal
Speaker 5:  for my house projects and then I get a steam deck for
Speaker 5:  travel. I have just quadrupled the amount of money that this is
Speaker 5:  costing. Is this the outcome?
Speaker 24:  Don't do that. Save your money. Just get like,
Speaker 24:  never ever, ever, ever, ever buy a portal unless you
Speaker 24:  just have zero computer skills. If you
Speaker 24:  have none whatsoever. If all you do, If you like, struggle to turn
Speaker 24:  your phone on, get the PSP portal. People
Speaker 23:  Love the portal. There, there are people who love the portal. It is selling
Speaker 23:  really well. I would never touch one except to like
Speaker 23:  to have the knowledge of having touched one because the steam deck
Speaker 23:  has an app on it. And the app is the PS portal. Yeah. That's in an app for
Speaker 23:  your steam deck. Yeah, basically it's, it's called chiaki
Speaker 23:  chiaki for deck. And it, it works great. Just make sure your PS five, your
Speaker 23:  PS four has an ethernet cable plugged into it or it will not work very well.
Speaker 23:  Okay.
Speaker 5:  Don't
Speaker 24:  Get the PS portal because that is, that's for like, that's for people who
Speaker 24:  love to game and don't have a lot of computer skills and so they're like,
Speaker 24:  okay, I just need to go play right now. And that's great,
Speaker 24:  but like you spend a little bit more money, you get the steam deck, you
Speaker 24:  spend a little extra time and you have just way more capability.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So, all right, so let me, let me play out this scenario. So
Speaker 5:  what's happening here is I, I'm going to
Speaker 5:  make sure that my PlayStation streaming setup is as good
Speaker 5:  as possible. I'm going to make sure that I have an ethernet port. I'm
Speaker 5:  gonna, I'm gonna plug my PlayStation into the Euro gateway and not
Speaker 5:  the euro in the basement. I'm gonna, I'm gonna make sure that my internet
Speaker 5:  connection for my PlayStation is as good as possible. TBD on whether
Speaker 5:  that's gonna be a PS four or PS five, we're gonna see how poor I feel at
Speaker 5:  the end of this episode, but that, that essentially becomes my like, dedicated
Speaker 5:  FIFA machine, which is an absurd place to have landed. But again, here
Speaker 5:  we are.
Speaker 23:  If you've already got the PS four, I mean, why not?
Speaker 5:  So that I'm, I'm relegating this thing to being my FIFA machine, and then
Speaker 5:  I'm going to download the app you just said for the steam deck for when I
Speaker 5:  wanna play FIFA and I'm gonna play FIFA on the steam deck through my PlayStation,
Speaker 5:  which seems ludicrous, but you're telling me will kind of sort of work. As
Speaker 5:  long as I have very good internet,
Speaker 24:  It'll work
Speaker 23:  Great inside your house. Remote is theoretically possible, but you'll play
Speaker 23:  it in your house realistically.
Speaker 5:  So I've, I've, that's my solution to the, how do I play on my couch
Speaker 5:  instead of in the basement problem. Great. For everything else,
Speaker 5:  I'm just going to broaden my horizons and play less FIFA and play more other
Speaker 5:  games. This is what you're telling me. This is, this is where I need to land.
Speaker 24:  I, I feel like you can find a really good FIFA clone, but like they all
Speaker 24:  have swords or something. I like, I feel like this exists.
Speaker 24:  Someone's made this game at Alpha.
Speaker 5:  So what is ironically possible is that because
Speaker 5:  EA Sports FC is no longer called fifa, somebody else is making a FIFA game
Speaker 5:  and maybe that FIFA game will be on the steam deck, which will solve all
Speaker 5:  of my problems all at once. This is, this is what I'm hoping for done and
Speaker 23:  Also you'll write about this experience hopefully for The Verge and then
Speaker 23:  EA will start taking care of its shit.
Speaker 5:  Okay, so ea very large company makes a lot of very popular games. Is there
Speaker 5:  any hope for EA on the steam deck ever? Like should I have any optimism for
Speaker 5:  that to be a thing? The steam deck's very popular. What are we doing here?
Speaker 23:  Yeah, I mean they just, they just break things willy-nilly and they don't
Speaker 23:  think about it. It's not like they don't want money. Yeah.
Speaker 24:  EA is like kind of notorious for being one of the worst
Speaker 24:  companies in the United States. Like I think when Consumerist existed it
Speaker 24:  was regularly beating cable companies Oh boy. For being the worst
Speaker 24:  because they just, they, they put money ahead of usability
Speaker 24:  frequently and so they could fix it, but I don't think they have a whole
Speaker 24:  lot of interest because most of their players, the bulk of their audience
Speaker 24:  is not, is, you know, it's on the switch. It's on the, the PlayStation.
Speaker 5:  Okay. One other steam deck question. The, the one other thing I forgot to
Speaker 5:  mention is I do wanna be able to plug this thing into a large screen
Speaker 5:  and play it. I don't think that's like the most common use case for me,
Speaker 5:  but I do want to be able to sit in front of a television and play it like
Speaker 5:  a console as I normally would. And for me with the switch, I have done that
Speaker 5:  way less than I expected because you have to have such specific hardware
Speaker 5:  to pull that off and like carrying around the dock is annoying. And I bought
Speaker 5:  the little plug thing and that helped, but then I lost that. And So I
Speaker 5:  want, I want something that is a little easier to turn into like a full fledged
Speaker 5:  console when I want to, is the steam deck good at that?
Speaker 24:  You're still gonna need a little dongle. Okay. To, to mirror
Speaker 24:  things.
Speaker 23:  Dongle or dock.
Speaker 24:  Yeah, you're gonna need a dongle or dock. I think the official one's like
Speaker 24:  what, a hundred dollars Sean?
Speaker 23:  It's less, it's, I wanna say 70, 80, something like that. But you can buy
Speaker 23:  much cheaper than that. I'd used like an off the shelf like $35
Speaker 23:  USBC hub that had HDMI that worked. I used docs
Speaker 23:  from like Js A-J-S-A-U-X, great company with an alphabet
Speaker 23:  soup name surprisingly 40, 50 bucks. And those docs are, do all the
Speaker 23:  things you'd want from a doc. It's really easy once you get one of those
Speaker 23:  things to get it up there. The question is, is your TV like 4K and
Speaker 23:  you're expecting 4K visuals from a console that normally plays at 800 because
Speaker 23:  it's not gonna look as good up on a big 4K tv
Speaker 5:  I will say, and Liam or producer can vouch for this. The least forge
Speaker 5:  casty thing about me is I don't care all that much about pixel density. So
Speaker 5:  the idea of playing like at, you know, medium settings and having it work
Speaker 5:  okay is completely fine with
Speaker 24:  Me. I just heard Neli screaming,
Speaker 5:  This is the last time you'll ever hear from me, me on The Vergecast. But
Speaker 5:  that is, that is where I'm at and especially with something like this, like
Speaker 5:  battery life is much more important to me than like getting
Speaker 5:  10 extra frames per second. And So I think again, the customizability of
Speaker 5:  the steam deck to be able to like dial that up and down as I want it seems
Speaker 5:  useful.
Speaker 24:  You wanna steam deck ole, like get the steam deck ole every
Speaker 24:  once in a while you'll plug it into the tv, you'll be like, oh, I did it.
Speaker 24:  This looks kind of shitty. And then you'll unplug it and go back to the
Speaker 24:  really pretty ole display and be very happy.
Speaker 5:  I do suspect my switch experience has been that I set it up in
Speaker 5:  such a way that it was gonna be really easy to dock. It was gonna be great.
Speaker 5:  And then most of the time I would sit on my couch in front of the TV and
Speaker 5:  just play on my lap and I, I would assume the steam deck will end up being
Speaker 5:  kind of the same way. Yep.
Speaker 23:  It's so good. My, we will watch, watch some shows together with my wife
Speaker 23:  and I'll, I'll have my hand held out and get to do some, some gaming at
Speaker 23:  the same time. It's great. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Are there any other like crazy wild card possibilities
Speaker 5:  coming that we know of that might win? Like you, you mentioned the, the
Speaker 5:  RIX seems like a possible improvement
Speaker 5:  if not sort of equal to the steam deck. Is there anything else on the
Speaker 5:  horizon that in three months I'm gonna be like, oh, this is the one I needed?
Speaker 5:  I don't
Speaker 23:  Think so, but there are two very different directions
Speaker 23:  you could go and I don't have one of them here in front of me, but one of
Speaker 23:  them is a 10.1 inch laptop with like
Speaker 23:  keys that actually feel good full size SD card reader. You could
Speaker 23:  actually shove the SD card all the way inside. We've got full size
Speaker 23:  USBA ports,
Speaker 24:  It has more ports than a MacBook
Speaker 23:  USBC ports. There's an OCU link port HDMI,
Speaker 23:  it is your doc built into it. And then you take these little things off
Speaker 23:  and you got joysticks a deep head and even even this,
Speaker 23:  this menu button in the center acts like an Xbox button, which for some
Speaker 23:  reason none of the other winds handhelds have. And this thing
Speaker 23:  is way expensive. I mean, it's twice the price of your steam deck.
Speaker 23:  It costs more than any of the handhelds, but it doubles as a laptop. It
Speaker 23:  has the power of one of those other gaming handhelds in a decent sized battery,
Speaker 23:  all this stuff. But Sean,
Speaker 24:  How's it, how is it to play?
Speaker 23:  It is a laptop first and a game
Speaker 23:  handheld second.
Speaker 5:  It's such a perfect gadget because that is both the stupidest thing I've
Speaker 5:  ever seen and I want it so bad.
Speaker 24:  Yeah, right. It's beautiful. It's
Speaker 5:  Like what if instead of the touch bar, we just put a PlayStation controller
Speaker 5:  in pieces, like I love it.
Speaker 23:  I I can't get, I can't get over the boss mode. Like, like you got this thing
Speaker 23:  and you're like, no, I can't show my game pad at work. Let's take this little
Speaker 23:  metal, let's take this little slip of metal outta the back of the thing
Speaker 23:  and and drop it on top boss mode. It's a physical boss mode.
Speaker 23:  Yeah. Okay, moving on from that. Okay, so your, your other
Speaker 23:  possibility If you could embrace, you could embrace software
Speaker 23:  piracy and you could buy one of these things, which is
Speaker 23:  looks like a Game boy advance sp this is the Vernick feg
Speaker 23:  but actually just comes with thousands of pirated games and, and so
Speaker 23:  you could play all your Game Boy Advance and PlayStation games on this.
Speaker 23:  Maybe you delete the pirated games first and dump your own ROS or something
Speaker 23:  like that,
Speaker 5:  As I always do.
Speaker 23:  As you do. Yes. I
Speaker 24:  Feel like Berg's already gonna get wrecked for you just saying. Yeah, it
Speaker 24:  comes with all of the pirated games on it. Every
Speaker 5:  Time Sean talks about one of these, there was, I think you did a, you did
Speaker 5:  a TikTok Sean talking about the, the new Amber Brunick thing and every single
Speaker 5:  comment was like, Sean, be cool man. Stop telling people about
Speaker 5:  gimme my freak.
Speaker 23:  It was
Speaker 24:  TikTok shop is all over this thing. Like it's been
Speaker 24:  snitched on enough.
Speaker 23:  Just to illustrate though that the ea the ea FIFA game
Speaker 23:  is not a steam deck problem. The top comment on EA sports
Speaker 23:  FC 24 is EAFC 24 not launching on
Speaker 23:  PC after anti sheet back to EA f Oh. So it's not a steam deck
Speaker 23:  thing so much as it is an EA doesn't care thing.
Speaker 5:  Interesting. Okay. So it it truly is ea is like, there are ways
Speaker 5:  you could get around the rules that we have. So we're just taking our ball
Speaker 5:  and going home. Yep. That doesn't feel like it's getting better anytime soon.
Speaker 5:  That, that does not give me hope for the, for improvements coming here, which
Speaker 5:  also means, listen, there's, there's a lot of sports games. This means I
Speaker 5:  can't play anymore, but now I'm gonna have to get into like cool nerd games.
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be great.
Speaker 24:  You, you can play 'em streaming.
Speaker 5:  That's true. Steam deck plus game pass I think is starting to feel like the
Speaker 5:  reales answer I have here.
Speaker 24:  You'll have Halo and fifa, like you'll be the,
Speaker 24:  the hit of every frat party you go to. Okay,
Speaker 5:  Last question and then, and then we have to go, am
Speaker 5:  I stupid for buying a steam deck right now in the same way that I might be
Speaker 5:  stupid for buying a switch right now? Where are we in the steam deck cycle?
Speaker 24:  We're fine, right?
Speaker 23:  We're mid, yeah, we're, we're mid cycle. We're not late
Speaker 23:  yet. The thing that, the thing that valve needs, they've, they've told us,
Speaker 23:  like told me to my face, what they need to see is they
Speaker 23:  need to see a major improvement in performance without
Speaker 23:  sacrificing battery life from a chip manufacturer before
Speaker 23:  they start building the next true steam deck. And I've heard this from
Speaker 23:  other companies too, like as with the, with the R-O-G-L-I-X, they were like,
Speaker 23:  we don't think we can get it right now, so we're gonna ship the wrong LIX
Speaker 23:  with the same chip.
Speaker 24:  And I don't think Qualcomm has changed that calculus at all. Yeah.
Speaker 24:  With the snap track and,
Speaker 5:  And even if it has, we're a ways away from that actually appearing inside
Speaker 5:  of a product.
Speaker 24:  Yeah, I think, I think we're probably a good, we're at least a year out.
Speaker 24:  I think you'll have one beautiful blissful year before you get FOMO at
Speaker 24:  least.
Speaker 5:  Okay. And that's, I mean, honestly in Gadget world, that's just, that's all
Speaker 5:  you can ask for.
Speaker 24:  It's like a year is an, is is an eternity in gadget world. I mean,
Speaker 5:  Listen, I've made it this far into the PS five cycle without upgrading. Like
Speaker 5:  it turns out I can, I can manage my FOMO on, on This one. I
Speaker 24:  Am so impressed.
Speaker 5:  Thank you. That's actually the other question I should ask is like, am I
Speaker 5:  being ridiculous? Should I just buy a PS five and move on with my life?
Speaker 23:  Ooh.
Speaker 24:  I mean, have infinite, If you have infinite money, yes.
Speaker 5:  If I buy a PS five, I almost certainly will end up buying a portal
Speaker 5:  and I, I hate myself for it, but it will probably happen
Speaker 24:  Then I say don't, because I wanna save you from the portal.
Speaker 23:  You could buy a used Steve Deck LCD for the price of a portal and also have
Speaker 23:  a portal built into it with an app.
Speaker 5:  Oh, well that's very compelling.
Speaker 23:  But PS five, like If you do love that I'm sitting on
Speaker 23:  my couch with my 4K Oli TV experience, it's
Speaker 23:  hard to beat the PS five for that. I'm playing Spider-Man two on it right
Speaker 23:  now on a just a gorgeous new Oli panel that was deep discounted
Speaker 23:  recently and wow. The pop of that city, the lights
Speaker 23:  at night. It's, it's, it's, it's, it's really something.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I, and I do love that, but I think I, I am increasingly coming
Speaker 5:  around to like, having a thing with me is
Speaker 5:  more important than the sort of very best possible experience.
Speaker 5:  I I would love to have both, but I don't think you can really have both right
Speaker 5:  now in the world we live in.
Speaker 23:  And If you, If you really want to have that thing with you, I don't think
Speaker 23:  there's anything that beats the steam deck. There's just so much you can
Speaker 23:  now take with you that you can't the same way through the window as handhelds.
Speaker 23:  You can't really with Android. All
Speaker 5:  Right, well we have ended where we began, which I find very frustrating,
Speaker 5:  but also sort of telling I'm gonna buy a steam deck. Yeah. I probably should
Speaker 5:  have bought a steam deck a really long time ago. I'm gonna buy a steam deck
Speaker 5:  and I I will start yelling loudly at EA and I'll report back.
Speaker 24:  I'm so excited for you. Everybody's excited about the EA though.
Speaker 5:  Do you have any immediate setup tips before we talk again? I will have purchased
Speaker 5:  a steam deck. What, what should I do? Immediately outta the box with my brand
Speaker 5:  new Steam deck O lead.
Speaker 23:  I have so many nerdy suggestions. I
Speaker 5:  Don't want nerdy suggestions, Sean. I say this with love, I want, I want
Speaker 5:  get
Speaker 23:  To, I know I was like
Speaker 5:  Playing games well as quickly and seamlessly as possible.
Speaker 5:  Like I am worried about the steam deck because I'm worried it's so fidgety
Speaker 5:  and finicky that I'm gonna spend my whole life goofing with the joysticks
Speaker 5:  and not playing games.
Speaker 24:  So, so Steam Deck has this, like on the steam deck they have compatibility
Speaker 24:  for games and you can also see it on the Steam software. So like you can
Speaker 24:  just go download steam ahead of time, find some games you like, make sure
Speaker 24:  they're compatible and then it'll be just out of the box ready to go. Anything
Speaker 24:  that's like yellow or red, you'll have to mess with a little bit. That's
Speaker 24:  where you have to start tweaking things. Like I try to play Crusader Kings
Speaker 24:  on it. Don't, that's it's not for the Steam deck. It's terrible.
Speaker 23:  There's even a tab in the store where you can just like, only show me games
Speaker 23:  that work well with the Steam deck. And for the most part they do.
Speaker 24:  They Yeah, and it's, it's a lot of stuff, right? Like, it, it's, it's a
Speaker 24:  ton of stuff. The ones that don't is stuff that's like mass effect, which
Speaker 24:  is an EA game. So you know why it doesn't work. Well,
Speaker 5:  I will say the other game in my life that I have loved with my whole heart,
Speaker 5:  the way that I have loved FIFA with my whole heart is portal. And the idea
Speaker 5:  of having a steam thing that will let me play the portal games forever is
Speaker 5:  very exciting.
Speaker 24:  And it will just straight out of the box, you'll be, you'll be off to the
Speaker 24:  races having a great time. Yeah. It, it really is so easy to just get
Speaker 24:  going on the steam deck provided you already own games.
Speaker 23:  Elden Ring plays well there, Ori and The Will of the
Speaker 23:  Wisps. If you haven't played that yet, play that on the De Lid. Haven't.
Speaker 23:  Okay. Oh my God, it looks brilliant. On the deco lid, that game is made
Speaker 23:  for HDR Persona five. Have you played any persona games?
Speaker 5:  Bits and pieces, but never, never super deeply. Okay.
Speaker 23:  Get Persona five or Persona five, Royal, whichever one is better for your
Speaker 23:  budget. Play that on Steam Deck. It's, it's, it's epic.
Speaker 23:  We could, we could spend the rest, you spend, spend another hour talking
Speaker 23:  about games to play on.
Speaker 24:  Yeah, I was about to say have, have you played Final Fantasy remake yet?
Speaker 24:  Like beautiful on the Steam deck.
Speaker 5:  Okay. All right. My list is long and none of them are the only game that
Speaker 5:  I needed, but you know, we're doing the best we can here, you
Speaker 24:  Can get FIFA 23 fairly easily on, on the Steam deck.
Speaker 5:  Okay. That might help. Maybe that's like my gateway drug out of being obsessed
Speaker 5:  with fifa. I'll just play old games enough to satiate me and then
Speaker 5:  go play Better Games. You get
Speaker 24:  Ted Lasso in that one, you'll be fucked.
Speaker 5:  All right, thank you both. This was very helpful. I'm gonna go spend a bunch
Speaker 5:  of money. Right.
Speaker 22:  Hi, I'm your friend Eli. David Pierce is here.
Speaker 5:  Hello.
Speaker 22:  Alex Kranz is on a break, but for our first
Speaker 22:  segment, Charlie Harding from Switch on Pop is joining. I Hey Charlie.
Speaker 21:  Hey guys. Thanks for having me. We
Speaker 22:  Have a lot of AI music copyright to talk about. There's some
Speaker 22:  lawsuits, it's always Drake is involved.
Speaker 22:  It just seems to be the way of the world. There's a bunch of new phone events
Speaker 22:  coming that just got announced. We shock about, there are new party speakers
Speaker 22:  from ultimate years. That's very important to me. And we got a lightning
Speaker 22:  on, we got a, we got a full show before, before the 4th of July. This is
Speaker 22:  America's technology podcast. But before we begin,
Speaker 22:  I have to issue a correction.
Speaker 22:  There are some words that I only read and I
Speaker 22:  never say out loud.
Speaker 21:  Ooh. Which ones
Speaker 22:  Is that? There are lots of those words. Tons of 'em. I was a, I was
Speaker 22:  a small nerdy child in the middle of Wisconsin who read a
Speaker 22:  lot of books that the other children in Wisconsin were not interested in.
Speaker 22:  Wisconsin's. Just a whole universe of vocabulary words. What
Speaker 5:  Is like your main one from when you were a kid that you, you were like 26
Speaker 5:  and all of a I feel like Chameleon is like the classic of the genre. Oh,
Speaker 5:  that's a good one. Genre, right. Where like half the people in the world
Speaker 5:  grew up thinking it was Chama Leon. For me it was learning that Hermione
Speaker 5:  name is Hermione and not Herion as I called her. Oh, that's good. However
Speaker 5:  many books I read before I saw the movies. Did you guys have these that you
Speaker 5:  grew up with?
Speaker 22:  I still
Speaker 5:  Discovered way late.
Speaker 22:  I still don't know whether it's Dearth or Darth
Speaker 22:  and I don't want find out.
Speaker 5:  Fair enough. Don't, don't email us about it. Don't ruin this for
Speaker 22:  Lie. Don't tell. Don't I don't. And I don't know if it means a lot or not
Speaker 22:  enough
Speaker 21:  On Switch on Pop. We have an ongoing uncertainty about whether it is
Speaker 21:  homage or homage. That's good. And we have been written many
Speaker 21:  emails that it's both and so we've refused to use the word from that
Speaker 22:  One out. Niche and niche. Very confusing. Mm, both
Speaker 22:  acceptable also have been told it's both. So there's a lot of these. Yeah.
Speaker 22:  One of them in recent times is risk
Speaker 22:  five, which is, I would say not a thing that comes up
Speaker 22:  in casual conversation for anyone. Even the people who are working on risk.
Speaker 22:  Five Bryant just walking around the office saying Risk five.
Speaker 22:  I I said it was risk V the other day. All right, I'm sorry. I mean,
Speaker 22:  this is your correction. You got one on me. I, I apologize.
Speaker 22:  I don't know what kind of slash shot nerds are. Reading it out loud.
Speaker 22:  I mean, you're my people and you're listening and you know, like we have
Speaker 22:  a bond here. You're listening to a podcast in which the word is said out
Speaker 22:  loud and you, the audience know that I've
Speaker 22:  mispronounced there's something special there. Precious. I I want to protect
Speaker 22:  it. I'm just saying we are the only people
Speaker 22:  who know
Speaker 21:  How do you know they're right and that you aren't now
Speaker 22:  Also spread the truth also. Good question, Charlie. Am I being gaslit by
Speaker 22:  an internet conspiracy
Speaker 5:  Words? I would also like to pause that with all Roman
Speaker 5:  numerals. The, the letter and the number are both
Speaker 5:  correct. Like when the iPhone 10 came out and it was the iPhone
Speaker 5:  X, it was the iPhone X. I don't care what anyone said, I got a
Speaker 5:  lot of crap for that. And it was the iPhone X because it was, it was the
Speaker 5:  iPhone and then the letter X, you call it whatever you want. I, I
Speaker 5:  submit that both should be allowed at all times.
Speaker 22:  So I would, I I I support this In theory it's Superbowl Excel.
Speaker 22:  Unless
Speaker 5:  It's more than one letter than
Speaker 22:  Well, no, but Super Bowl xl. Like they ob they were like hypee for it. Yes,
Speaker 5:  Right. Yeah. They did a thing.
Speaker 22:  That's your moment. But I was one of those slash taught nerds who was like,
Speaker 22:  it's Meko is 10, so I'm sorry. Like I, you
Speaker 5:  Know, even though it's not, it's OSX.
Speaker 22:  We got fun. Anyway, that's your correction. I'm just telling you what we,
Speaker 22:  what we share as a group is special and I'm, I'm sorry that I pushed the
Speaker 22:  boundary of it, but I'm also saying no one says these words out loud.
Speaker 22:  It's just not a thing that happens and I feel nothing. Charlie
Speaker 21:  XCX has entered the chat.
Speaker 22:  What is the, what is XC, X in numbers?
Speaker 21:  It isn't a real one,
Speaker 22:  Isn't C and Roman numeral
Speaker 5:  CI is a hundred. So that would be a hundred. It would be 90 and then 10 more
Speaker 22:  Allows you to put them in this order.
Speaker 5:  It's just Charlie CI think.
Speaker 22:  I don't know how Roman numerals work.
Speaker 22:  Speaking of things that are bad at math ai,
Speaker 22:  it's true. That's good. That's good. Big week in the AI
Speaker 22:  landscape. A weird week for me emotionally. I'll explain why in
Speaker 22:  a second. The major labels have sued two AI companies that you may or may
Speaker 22:  not have heard of, UDO and Suno. These are classic Silicon Valley
Speaker 22:  names. We should all be proud. They're music companies. They're AI music
Speaker 22:  companies. UDO is the company whose tool was used to
Speaker 22:  make BBLD Drizzy. We'll have Charlie explain that entire chain of events.
Speaker 22:  And then Suno has a deal with Microsoft. It's in copilot
Speaker 22:  and you can ask it to giant music in copilot. How would
Speaker 22:  you train an AI tool to make music? You might ask, as did the lawyers
Speaker 22:  at the Recording Industry Association of America. And the answer is you
Speaker 22:  just put a bunch of music in them and you train the model on
Speaker 22:  a bunch of music, including what appears to be an a, a remarkable
Speaker 22:  amount of the recording industries. Music, not just music that's out
Speaker 22:  in the world. The companies are sued. There's a lawsuit.
Speaker 22:  The RA is mad, the RIA is already mad. They
Speaker 22:  say that they asked the companies what was used to train the models. The
Speaker 22:  companies Suno deflected and said their training data was confidential.
Speaker 22:  Business information
Speaker 22:  fine. UDO made the same statements. And then Suno also said,
Speaker 22:  our stuff is transformative and designed to generate completely new outputs,
Speaker 22:  not memorized and regurgitate preexisting content.
Speaker 22:  We'll get to that in a second. 'cause that is actually a very funny claim
Speaker 22:  based on what you can do. The RAA put tracks in lawsuit, which we
Speaker 22:  will listen to it straightforwardly, can just make Johnny be good
Speaker 22:  in a song called Prancing Queen, which is my favorite. Deeply hilarious.
Speaker 22:  There's just a part of this where these companies knew
Speaker 22:  that what they were doing was training on copyright work and they kind of
Speaker 22:  assumed that they would get away with it or at least be able to like pay
Speaker 22:  the money and move on.
Speaker 5:  Can I ask a, can I ask a very possibly dumb framing question
Speaker 5:  about this? Because I, I want, we're gonna get into the weeds of like a very
Speaker 5:  specific music case, but a lot of what you just described,
Speaker 5:  the sort of basic outlines of like how these companies trained their data
Speaker 5:  and what they're being accused of doing and who's mad feels
Speaker 5:  identical to me to every other conversation we've had about these AI models,
Speaker 5:  right? Yes. Like it seems to me that If you change Johnny B. Good
Speaker 5:  and Suno to the New York Times and Chat
Speaker 5:  GPT, we're functionally talking about the same thing. So like, I want to
Speaker 5:  get into the deep into this in, in weird ways, but like, is there something
Speaker 5:  different about the fact that we're doing this with music than the fact the
Speaker 5:  way we've been doing this with like the web for the last year or so?
Speaker 22:  Yes. And it's that the music industry is organized
Speaker 22:  and aggressive when it comes to protecting its rights.
Speaker 5:  So the difference is lawyers,
Speaker 22:  The difference is lawyers and also the, the history of music and the internet
Speaker 22:  is lawyers. Like, the reason I'm so
Speaker 22:  conflicted about this is that I went and became a copyright lawyer
Speaker 22:  because Napster came out when I was in college and I was
Speaker 22:  radicalized because I thought everyone was stupid, which is what
Speaker 22:  should happen when software comes out when you're in college. Yeah. I, I'm
Speaker 22:  assuming there are some kids out there today who are radicalized by the
Speaker 22:  presence of new software, but that wouldn't, it wasn't for me. It was Napster.
Speaker 22:  I went off and became a copyright attorney. I sucked at it. I don't ever
Speaker 22:  want anyone to think I was good at this as a practicing attorney. I was
Speaker 22:  garbage. But the thing I did was I worked at a law firm that defended other
Speaker 22:  college kids who got sued for using kaza against the RIAA
Speaker 22:  and the RIAA was suing college kids and actually
Speaker 22:  suing the universities to get the IP address of the college kids on their
Speaker 22:  networks who were using the tools and then identifying the college students
Speaker 22:  and suing college students. It was my roommate's computer, it wasn't me.
Speaker 22:  Yep. I swear this is like a lot, right? That's a lot that that's
Speaker 22:  just a lot to like the universities are caving and not protecting their
Speaker 22:  students. All this stuff is happening and they were running this program
Speaker 22:  at breakeven. They just wanted $5,000 settlements so everyone would be scared
Speaker 22:  and stopped doing it and they won that. That worked sort
Speaker 22:  of, now we're back to it, right? But like the movie industry
Speaker 22:  is not quite as good. It's stopping the Piy as the music industry was and
Speaker 22:  they ran that program to kind of like shut it down in chill. Napster
Speaker 22:  in Ster and Kaza and all the other ones, they ran ster all the way up to
Speaker 22:  the Supreme Court. That decision was, is 20 years old now. The
Speaker 22:  RAA versus crosser
Speaker 22:  great. Then they did the iTunes store and they got deals
Speaker 22:  with Steve Jobs and then other music stores and then they did Spotify and
Speaker 22:  Apple Music and streaming. And all along the way they have an
Speaker 22:  extraordinarily litigious and extraordinarily protective of their copyrights
Speaker 22:  because people have an emotional connection to music that they can trade
Speaker 22:  on. This is true in a way that even Hollywood doesn't, like when
Speaker 22:  Disney's like, we must protect the copyright to the Avengers, people are
Speaker 22:  like, go fuck yourself. Like right In a way that the music industry, when
Speaker 22:  it's like you are stealing music, you are making it so artists don't get
Speaker 22:  paid. There's an emotional resonance. That argument tends to
Speaker 22:  have. Charlie, I'm curious how you, how you see that changing over time.
Speaker 22:  But they've been good at it and they've run the playbook over and over and
Speaker 22:  over again. Music is also a closed ecosystem of like four big
Speaker 22:  companies. And so you see things like interpolation where
Speaker 22:  an artist uses a bit of a song from another artist and fans get
Speaker 22:  mad and then writing credits get distributed and money flows inside of
Speaker 22:  a closed ecosystem. None of that is true about the web. None of that
Speaker 22:  is true about the media. So If you are like a writer at a media company,
Speaker 22:  nothing like no one cares. Like there's not some big apparatus
Speaker 22:  designed to make it as seem like your work is emotionally resonant
Speaker 22:  and should be protected in the way that the music industry does. So I think
Speaker 22:  that's a huge difference here. The other difference, and this is where
Speaker 22:  I really, Charlie, I'm very curious for your take
Speaker 22:  here, is that the outputs of these systems are
Speaker 22:  just the songs, right? And they're, the
Speaker 22:  lawsuits are about training, right? All copyright lawsuit, all copyright
Speaker 22:  is dumb. Like it's a dumb legal system because it, it just
Speaker 22:  regulates copies. And so they're like, you made a copy to do this thing
Speaker 22:  and you didn't have the permission to do the thing with the copy that you
Speaker 22:  made. So copyright infringement weird. All
Speaker 22:  computers do is make copies. We've talked about this so many times in the
Speaker 22:  show, so they're not talking about the outputs, but I think the outputs
Speaker 22:  are so convincing. Like in order to get to the thing can
Speaker 22:  just make Johnny be good. It is obvious that you made a copy of Johnny be
Speaker 22:  good. Charlie, what do you think? Man,
Speaker 21:  I feel like the music industry is the one place that copyright becomes part
Speaker 21:  of public conversation in a very frequent way. People
Speaker 21:  talk about when Pharrell is
Speaker 21:  borrowing from Marvin Gaye, people talk about when
Speaker 21:  Steroid to Heaven might be of, might have been copied by another song. People
Speaker 21:  constantly are debating in social media, Hey, you kind of sound like you
Speaker 21:  borrowed this other person's thing. They should get a credit on it. There's
Speaker 21:  no thing in journalism where someone's like, Hey, you know, NELI kind of
Speaker 21:  used someone else's texts. Maybe we we should give David some extra credit
Speaker 21:  on that piece. That Neli plagiarized, I'm sorry, I'm obviously not accusing
Speaker 21:  you of I do
Speaker 22:  That all the time.
Speaker 21:  This is Hypothe.
Speaker 22:  Don't
Speaker 5:  Think you understand specifically. Neli does that all,
Speaker 22:  I have God mode Google Docs access and I just lift everybody's copy left
Speaker 22:  and right.
Speaker 21:  There's just no other creative industry that where there's this like level
Speaker 21:  of actual infringement that happens that then there is this internal
Speaker 21:  litigious system where these major players are constantly trading credits
Speaker 21:  back and forth and the public is in on it often debating
Speaker 21:  whether or not their, the artists that they stand
Speaker 21:  is making original work. This is part of popular discourse and it happens
Speaker 21:  in music. So it's really different when the music industry
Speaker 21:  is going after AI than if the New York Times is because I've just
Speaker 21:  never been in a circumstance where I'm talking about, that article was completely
Speaker 21:  lifted from this other article, but we constantly talk about is so-and-so
Speaker 21:  writing in their own songs.
Speaker 22:  Right. I'll give you a a dumb example from movies. The movie,
Speaker 22:  the Dark Knight is basically an interpolation of the movie
Speaker 22:  Heat except with Batman. Yeah. Right. Like many of the
Speaker 22:  shots are the same. Christopher Nolan is out there being like, heat is the
Speaker 22:  greatest cops and robbers movie ever made. Like I just wanted to make heat,
Speaker 22:  but with Batman and then you like watch both movies, you're like, oh shit.
Speaker 22:  Like dude just made heat with Batman. Yeah. And that's great. And I think
Speaker 22:  everyone's like, this is the best. Like this is so cool. Right? And then
Speaker 22:  you get to, I dunno, Miley Cyrus is writing flowers, which the
Speaker 22:  lyrics just reference
Speaker 21:  Bruno Mars,
Speaker 22:  Bruno Mars. And people are like, should she have to pay Bruno Mars? It's
Speaker 22:  like, why? Like why like the melodies aren't like they she's just
Speaker 22:  saying some of the same words. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Right. But the expectation
Speaker 22:  is that there, there should be some economic exchange of value.
Speaker 5:  Well, and I, I would, I would think then that the existence of
Speaker 5:  that exchange of value is also how you get to something like this, right?
Speaker 5:  Where it's, it's not just everybody's sort of yelling and then
Speaker 5:  nothing ever happens. It's that we actually have a system by which this
Speaker 5:  gets solved, right? Where, where we have people get songwriting credits and
Speaker 5:  then they get paid for it. And there's like the music industry has built
Speaker 5:  ways for all of this to work and like you said, is very
Speaker 5:  good at picking fights with those who do not play inside of that system.
Speaker 5:  And so like now I'm just thinking, okay, the difference between the music
Speaker 5:  industry and the, the others who are fighting against
Speaker 5:  open AI and others like just groups of authors or whatever, is
Speaker 5:  not only does the music industry have a system by which it
Speaker 5:  understands how everybody is supposed to get paid. That has existed for a
Speaker 5:  long time and everybody kind of sorta understands, but also
Speaker 5:  is able to marshal that whole system against anyone who wants to
Speaker 5:  exist outside of that. And part of what we've been saying forever is like
Speaker 5:  all the money is on the side of the AI companies. Like who, who is going
Speaker 5:  to be able to run a lawsuit against Google all the way to
Speaker 5:  the end. And there probably aren't that many creative industries other
Speaker 5:  than the music industry that might be able to do it.
Speaker 21:  They've done it before. Yeah. And they have one major concessions,
Speaker 21:  right? That we wouldn't have content id if not for music labels going after
Speaker 21:  YouTube. Right.
Speaker 22:  And they, and the music labels have gone after YouTube, right? Universal,
Speaker 22:  this is where Drake gets involved. There's fake Drake that we've, we've
Speaker 22:  talked about endlessly on the show. Shout out to Laser Bong a song that
Speaker 22:  has been just aggressively censored from e every major
Speaker 22:  platform. Boyd, does TikTok not want electronic music
Speaker 22:  about bongs on its platform?
Speaker 5:  Sue about that. Record labels
Speaker 22:  Like Yeah, you want to talk about government censorship? Yeah. All right.
Speaker 22:  The Chinese government is like no bongs for American teens. Just
Speaker 22:  saying it. The piece of that puzzle that's super interesting to
Speaker 22:  me is Universal was mad about fake Drake. They went to
Speaker 22:  Spotify, apple, they said, don't have these, don't have this song. And
Speaker 22:  Spotify and Apple Control the catalogs and their music service they can
Speaker 22:  pull down YouTube is open access, right? So anyone can upload anything.
Speaker 22:  And then there is continuity and they have these other copyright management
Speaker 22:  systems on YouTube, but it's not the same catalog control where you can
Speaker 22:  just delete the song the way that Spotify and Apple Music could just delete
Speaker 22:  the song. So they had to come up with some other system and YouTube did
Speaker 22:  give the concessions, right? They put out a list of like AI
Speaker 22:  principles they would work on about safety, about this other stuff. And
Speaker 22:  a lot of it was we are gonna work directly with Universal and the rest of
Speaker 22:  the music industry to figure out what tools are valuable and what tools
Speaker 22:  aren't. And even to allow some creators to like do some of this AI music
Speaker 22:  generation. 'cause we think it's cool and then we'll obviously we'll figure
Speaker 22:  out how to pay them. This is implicit if you're like co announcing that
Speaker 22:  tool with universal music, universal music is gonna get paid. Yes.
Speaker 22:  Like the, the heat death of the universe could occur in Lucian Grange,
Speaker 22:  the CEO of Universal Music would get paid. Like he's good at it. Yes.
Speaker 22:  These two companies did not do that. There's a quote from one of the VCs
Speaker 22:  in Suno, a Rolling Stone profile from March, and he, he's, he just says,
Speaker 22:  rolling Stone. If we had deals with the labels when the company got started,
Speaker 22:  I probably wouldn't have invested in it. I think they needed to make this
Speaker 22:  product without the constraints.
Speaker 5:  Wild thing to say out loud. Incredible
Speaker 22:  Thing to say out loud.
Speaker 21:  They said the quiet thing out loud because Yeah. Behind all of this, they
Speaker 21:  haven't ever really quite publicly emitted that they are using copyrighted
Speaker 21:  works. They've talked around that in every way they possibly can without
Speaker 21:  denying it. And this is sort of like the big Yeah, this is the, this is
Speaker 21:  the smoking gun,
Speaker 22:  Right? And then the other smoking gun, and this is the part we should just
Speaker 22:  listen to some of this music is the output of the models themselves. Right?
Speaker 22:  Which is, I mean, let's listen
Speaker 22:  to it and we can talk about it. David, take us through it.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I have, I have brought some sound thank you to Andrew and Liam for
Speaker 5:  getting all of this together. We have three examples
Speaker 5:  and I, I will just roll through all three. Stop me when you
Speaker 5:  have feelings about this. The first thing we'll do is
Speaker 5:  this is just titled Real Chuck Berry in Riverside.
Speaker 5:  So let's just listen to this first. A
Speaker 22:  Second by the way. And this is all fair use, no copyright infringement intended.
Speaker 22:  All right. YouTube. All right, go ahead. No,
Speaker 25:  But he could play a guitar just like a ring in a bell. Go,
Speaker 25:  go,
Speaker 25:  go, go, go
Speaker 22:  Try. That's enough. Stop before the robot sensors arrive. Great
Speaker 5:  Song. I can We love it right from
Speaker 22:  Love it. If you don't know that song one, go watch Back to the Future.
Speaker 22:  Incredible movie that you should just watch and two like stop, go get
Speaker 22:  cultured. Know what you're doing.
Speaker 21:  Johnny. Be good. Chuck Berry. Yeah. And rock and roll one of them.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And now we have a song from UDO,
Speaker 5:  which is not called Johnny Be Good, but just listen
Speaker 25:  Power just like go,
Speaker 25:  go,
Speaker 25:  go
Speaker 25:  down, go,
Speaker 25:  go.
Speaker 5:  So I mean it's,
Speaker 22:  So that one is non copier infringement, just sciences face. Yeah. Because
Speaker 21:  You can't
Speaker 22:  Can't, he owns this. You can't copyright the AI work.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Okay, so that's one. Next we have a
Speaker 22:  James Brown. Can can we just, I just wanna ask Charlie a like a hard question.
Speaker 22:  Charlie's a professor of music at NYUI believe, right? Yes.
Speaker 22:  All right, professor, let's say you didn't have
Speaker 22:  Johnny B. Good in the training data. Yes. But then you had the entire
Speaker 22:  architecture of rock and roll that is built on Johnny B. Good. That's good
Speaker 22:  question. Yeah. Could you back your way into Johnny B. Good
Speaker 5:  Monkeys and typewriters and Shakespeare, right? Like that's the, is that
Speaker 5:  the, the theory
Speaker 22:  Here, but like you, you don't need, do you need the seed crystal when you
Speaker 22:  have the whole diamond mine of rock and roll?
Speaker 21:  It's a really good question because you know, If you look at this era of,
Speaker 21:  of music where r and b rock and roll
Speaker 21:  be are sort of like rockabilly are all kind of one entity. The music is
Speaker 21:  drawing on 12 bar blues, a very standard song structure. They're
Speaker 21:  often in the same keys that play well on guitar. They're using a lot of
Speaker 21:  the same kind of guitar licks. They're mostly using pentatonic scales. They're
Speaker 21:  using a lot of the same language. And you might think, yeah, you could just
Speaker 21:  sort of back into that. But the precise rhythms, the exact
Speaker 21:  words, let's be clear. The copy is worse. It does not
Speaker 21:  sound nearly as good as the real Johnny be Good. You could never
Speaker 21:  get to that same place without having heard that Johnny B. Good. I feel
Speaker 21:  confident. And if these two songs, one being a
Speaker 21:  real song and the other being nobody owns the copyright and it's made by
Speaker 21:  an ai, if, if there were a copyright case made against
Speaker 21:  the copy, it would definitively lose.
Speaker 21:  I I have the many of these cases, many of these music copyright cases are
Speaker 21:  not clear. They're often fought over eight notes
Speaker 21:  sometimes. Yeah, six notes. Sometimes a general feel in
Speaker 21:  the case of blurred lines and got to give it up. This is
Speaker 21:  a direct copy of the Rhythm and the words and
Speaker 21:  most of the melodies. So no, you had to have heard this song in order to
Speaker 21:  make Johnny be good twice. By
Speaker 22:  The way, If you want more on eight notes and how complicated it is. Charlie
Speaker 22:  and I did an entire episode of Decoder pulling that Apart. We'll link that
Speaker 22:  in the show notes somewhere, but let's move on. Let's listen to the next
Speaker 5:  One. It's very good. All right, next up we have James Brown, first Real,
Speaker 5:  James Brown.
Speaker 25:  Wow. I feel,
Speaker 25:  feel good.
Speaker 25:  I the classic
Speaker 5:  An A
Speaker 22:  Timer and another one where If you're listening to The Verge House and you
Speaker 22:  if never heard this song, like, I don't know what you're doing. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Go listen to Switch song. Go it. Exactly. You need it very badly. You're
Speaker 5:  right. Go to school
Speaker 22:  And then come on, come on home.
Speaker 5:  And now we have AI James Brown.
Speaker 25:  Wow. I feel good. I knew that I won.
Speaker 22:  That's spicy.
Speaker 25:  I feel good.
Speaker 25:  I knew that I would not
Speaker 25:  So good.
Speaker 5:  Okay, so This one I actually think is very fun because it, it is a little,
Speaker 5:  it's like a little tiny bit further away from it in the way that the first
Speaker 5:  one just is Johnny B. Good but worse. This one is like one
Speaker 5:  tiny tick. Yeah. This is a further away from being just the thing.
Speaker 22:  This is a lounge band with pretension where everyone's like, just play,
Speaker 22:  just play it the way that, can you stop it All right. Like we get it.
Speaker 22:  You, you, you, you thought you had something. I have one question about
Speaker 22:  this. And it, it actually felt the same way about Johnny B. Good.
Speaker 22:  The way these models work, right? Is you ingest a bunch of data into them.
Speaker 22:  They set a bunch of model weights and then they like statistically make
Speaker 22:  the next bit, right? They're just sort of like assembling the thing around
Speaker 22:  the prompt, which means they're kind of just assembling ones and zeros
Speaker 22:  to make a sound wave here. Which is pretty wild If you think about it. Like
Speaker 22:  that makes sense with words, right? What is statistically the next word
Speaker 22:  in the sentence around this prompt? When you get to like, what are the
Speaker 22:  ones and zeros of a sound file and you get to statistically hear the next
Speaker 22:  ones and zeros. That's pretty weird. It's actually a pretty weird way
Speaker 22:  to make an audio recording. And the thing that strikes me about
Speaker 22:  these, This one in particular, but the other one a little bit,
Speaker 22:  the instruments don't sound real at all. To me. Those horns sound so fake.
Speaker 22:  Not like synthesizer fake. No, but almost exactly like what you
Speaker 22:  would expect If you asked a computer to statistically produce a horn
Speaker 22:  section. Mm. Like it's almost played again. You're like, just listen to
Speaker 22:  it. It's so weird.
Speaker 25:  Wow. I feel good. I knew that I not,
Speaker 22:  Do you hear how like weird and thin it is?
Speaker 25:  I knew that I not
Speaker 25:  so
Speaker 25:  good.
Speaker 21:  It doesn't sound like an ensemble of tho it sounds like this weird
Speaker 21:  synthesized thing where the, the beginning of the sound or the end of the
Speaker 21:  sound is exactly lined up. The sound is, yeah, there's this
Speaker 21:  artifact in quality to it. This is like the pope's jacket version of
Speaker 21:  sound. Yes. It's like you got it close, but all the lines are
Speaker 21:  wrong. Why does he have seven fingers? Right.
Speaker 22:  It's a, it's a statistical approximation of a hand, right? Yeah. But as
Speaker 22:  expressed as a horn section, which is really weird to like just on its face
Speaker 22:  and you can, you know, people are like, it'll get better and blah blah blah.
Speaker 22:  But like you can act, to me you can hear a meaningful difference
Speaker 22:  once you know what you're listening for and it's like, oh, this
Speaker 22:  is a fake instrument. It's not a and it's not a fake instrument. The way
Speaker 22:  it's synthesizer is a fake instrument. Right. It's just fake. Like it doesn't,
Speaker 22:  it doesn't make any sense
Speaker 21:  Over the top all of all of it. Right Now, I don't know if this is a solvable
Speaker 21:  problem. I imagine it probably is is that everything sounds kind of
Speaker 21:  grainy. There's like this this top level, his kind of over the entire
Speaker 21:  recording of any AI output. It sounds maybe equivalent
Speaker 21:  to neli those files that you were not downloading
Speaker 21:  in college, but like the really low bit rate MP threes when
Speaker 21:  mp threes were actually noticeably worse. Yeah. That's what these sound
Speaker 21:  like. All of them have this artificial sheen on top
Speaker 21:  that sound very lo-fi in addition to artificial instruments.
Speaker 22:  Just a side note, I can't listen to the song in between days by the Cure
Speaker 22:  without mentally inserting the weird compression
Speaker 22:  artifacts at the high end. 'cause I listened to a shit MP three of that
Speaker 22:  song so many times that the symbols are just forever distorted in my brain.
Speaker 22:  There
Speaker 21:  There's literally a plugin and guitar pedal called Lossy
Speaker 21:  that is made to recreate the sound of early
Speaker 21:  two thousands mb threes.
Speaker 22:  That's very good. So If you
Speaker 21:  Need it, I can run it for loss. It's
Speaker 22:  The elder millennial button basically. Yeah. So that's the sound.
Speaker 22:  Yeah. Talk about the actual music here. Is this right with trying to
Speaker 22:  be good? You're like, that's straight copy infringement. This is weird,
Speaker 22:  right? It's like slant rhyme. Yeah. What do you think?
Speaker 21:  I think that it's the exact same rhythms.
Speaker 21:  I'd have to look at the notes. I think they're quite close. They're the
Speaker 21:  exact, if if they're in, they, maybe they're in a different key, but they're
Speaker 21:  like the same intervals moving in the same direction at the exact same time.
Speaker 21:  That would almost certainly lose in court
Speaker 21:  if these were, again, if I should be clear, the AI companies
Speaker 21:  are not being sued for the output. Yep. But these outputs, If you were to
Speaker 21:  try to make a case, I'm sure a judge would rule in favor
Speaker 21:  of the James Brown estate because it is the same
Speaker 21:  line. Well, it's more or less the same line. It's an interpolation of the
Speaker 21:  line. There's slightly different words, but it's the same rhythms, same
Speaker 21:  melody that almost always is going to, that's always, always gonna
Speaker 22:  Win. And here the the output is proof of the input. Right.
Speaker 5:  They're, they're not suing for the output. That's right. But the output seems
Speaker 5:  unusually important here in that respect. That it's, it's like
Speaker 5:  if, if UDO is doing the thing that it claimed to be doing,
Speaker 5:  which is, which is transforming stuff into other stuff,
Speaker 5:  we have a very different kind of fair use case. But reading through the RA's
Speaker 5:  lawsuit, like the thing they did over and over and over was just go reproduce
Speaker 5:  songs that exist in the world. Yep. And that's how we're fighting about training.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like I, I went through and pulled a bunch of the prompts that they
Speaker 5:  use to get songs and we did the, the same thing. They're so funny. They're
Speaker 5:  so funny. Like to get to get the Green
Speaker 5:  Day song, I think it was American Idiot. The prompt is Pop punk, American
Speaker 5:  Alternative Rock, California 2004, Rob Ceva. Perfect
Speaker 22:  To get and the Way and that produced a Pastiche of American idiot.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 22:  Amazing. To
Speaker 5:  Get My Girl By The Temptations. It was my tempting 1964 girl
Speaker 5:  Smokey Sing Hitsville Soul Pop Got My Girl by the Temptations.
Speaker 5:  This one you'll enjoy Neli to get All I want for Christmas is you by
Speaker 5:  Mariah Carey, my girl. The prompt is Mariah Carey. But with
Speaker 5:  a space between each letter so that it's not, 'cause presumably these things
Speaker 22:  Are trained because it's reading for pronouns, artist names.
Speaker 5:  So it's m space, a space all the way through the name Contemporary, that's
Speaker 22:  How I spell it.
Speaker 5:  A Grammy award-winning American singer songwriter, remarkable vocal range
Speaker 5:  that produced all in What for Christmas is you. I mean, there's,
Speaker 22:  There's means of, so it's what they're proving is that it's set, by the
Speaker 22:  way, the argument in response that I'm sure we're gonna hear, because this
Speaker 22:  is the argument opening I made about the Times lawsuit was one, no
Speaker 22:  human prompts like this and B, these prompts are so weird. They represent
Speaker 22:  a hack of our system, which is remarkable. But I'm
Speaker 22:  confident based on how open AI replied to the times that that is what these
Speaker 22:  companies will
Speaker 5:  Reply to. There is one very good one that the prompt was create a
Speaker 5:  song by an artist that rhymes with truce string bean that produced a Bruce
Speaker 5:  Springsteen song.
Speaker 22:  That's very good. It's fantastic. So I, so that question I asked Charlie
Speaker 22:  about the, do you, If you have the entire history of rock and roll, do you
Speaker 22:  need the first song right Or do you need Chuck Berry? Okay, maybe you
Speaker 22:  don't, maybe you do. Right? Like I think this third example is
Speaker 22:  the funniest example because I can't figure how you would get
Speaker 22:  to this without specifically one thing. Go ahead,
Speaker 5:  David. I'm glad you agreed because I left this for last for precisely this
Speaker 5:  reason. So here is, I won't even spoil it. Here's the real one.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, okay. Right.
Speaker 22:  Everybody's
Speaker 5:  Heard it a million times. That's our boy, that's our voyage jd,
Speaker 21:  The longest lasting digital career that I never expected to happen. No,
Speaker 22:  No,
Speaker 5:  Go ahead. And here, here is the ai, I I just wanna say this was created by
Speaker 5:  a prompt on UDO. This is in theory a completely
Speaker 5:  synthetic new work of art.
Speaker 5:  Oh,
Speaker 25:  It's so good.
Speaker 22:  It does sound like a Jason Derulo song. Like my critique of Yes. Does this
Speaker 22:  sound like real music aside?
Speaker 5:  It's even got the little like vocal riff at the end. Like it's, it's, it's
Speaker 22:  Random. Does Jason Derulo sound like sympathetic music?
Speaker 22:  That's your problem?
Speaker 21:  This one's interesting though because you know, NELI, you've talked a lot
Speaker 21:  about the issue that likeness is not copyrightable, right? Yeah. And so
Speaker 21:  there there's a question of like, If, you know, we we're going back to this
Speaker 21:  hypothetical, there is no suit that's suing over this particular Jason
Speaker 21:  Dillo riff. Someone could just, I could say Jason Dillo on a song probably,
Speaker 21:  and it's not, you can't copyright that. So
Speaker 22:  You Wait, hold on, hold on. Oh, this is weird. So these tags,
Speaker 5:  Did we have this fight the last time with the Metro
Speaker 22:  Boomin tag? Yes. With the Metro Boomin song? So Metro Boomin's producer
Speaker 22:  tag was the copyrightable expression in the fake Drake song.
Speaker 21:  If it's exactly, if it's exactly the recording of the tag though, right?
Speaker 21:  Because it's, it's, it was, the issue was that the actually kept in
Speaker 21:  the sample of the producer tag. Right? And, and
Speaker 21:  reproducing a recording, you can copyright that. So
Speaker 5:  We could start every episode of The Vergecast with Neli singing Jason
Speaker 21:  Derulo, Jason Darulo, and get
Speaker 22:  Away with this. And we will,
Speaker 21:  I think you probably would have a lot of issues, a lot of nasty letters.
Speaker 22:  I'm saying in terms of ways to boost this podcast profile after 13
Speaker 22:  years, Jason Daro suing us is high on my list.
Speaker 21:  That's wonderful. This, but this, this definitely proves that like you had
Speaker 21:  to have had access. There is no monkeys in the back writing Shakespeare
Speaker 21:  that ends up on Jason Deo. It just doesn't happen. It's not possible.
Speaker 22:  Actually, I don't know. I think If you, If you took the worst impulses of
Speaker 22:  the music industry and fed them into an ai, you might produce Jason
Speaker 22:  Derulo.
Speaker 21:  This one's also important though because everything else we've heard has
Speaker 21:  been written by artists Pre Copyright Act of
Speaker 21:  1974 and probably also reflects some of maybe who the lawyers are
Speaker 21:  writing these, you know, these cases because
Speaker 21:  you know, we're talking about the cases reference Frank Sinatra.
Speaker 21:  Right. And to bring in Bruce Springsteen, actually that's
Speaker 22:  By 74, right? It's like Springsteen, Mariah Carey, green Day Johnny or Chuck
Speaker 22:  Berry. The
Speaker 21:  Early ones are all Chuck Berry like the Temptations. Right?
Speaker 21:  Are
Speaker 22:  You getting it? Like the judges
Speaker 21:  Are old. I'm seeing everyone. Yeah. And, and that's actually potentially
Speaker 21:  very advantageous in knowing the judge and who you might go in front of.
Speaker 21:  But then to show that also they're taking all the latest music as well.
Speaker 21:  Like we're, we're bringing in Jason Daro. Yes.
Speaker 22:  Like, judge, have you heard Your Honor, are you familiar with Jason Daro?
Speaker 21:  I wanna bring Jason Dillo into the courtroom. Jason Dillo,
Speaker 22:  By the way, another total side note. There's an incredible Katie Apollos
Speaker 22:  piece about hardcore Jason Dillo stands and what their
Speaker 22:  stand culture is like that I will dig up and put in the show notes.
Speaker 21:  Oh my gosh, that sounds fun. It's
Speaker 22:  Truly one of the funniest things I've ever read on the internet. Just because
Speaker 22:  A, it exists and B, because Katie is good at finding things like that, that
Speaker 22:  exist.
Speaker 21:  Have you all tried running these prompts by the way?
Speaker 22:  No. Have you?
Speaker 21:  Yeah. You can go to UIO and to Suno and you can run the prompts that
Speaker 21:  the, that these lawsuits are alleging and you don't get
Speaker 21:  the same songs obviously. But like If you write Make a jazz crooner
Speaker 21:  song about New York baritone voice, you'll definitely get
Speaker 21:  it's Frank Sinatra. There's just like, there's no other song but Frank's
Speaker 21:  and I don't think that that really is hacking the systems.
Speaker 21:  It's really easy. The other thing I get a lot, by the way, are
Speaker 21:  random prompt, Hey, that sounds strangely like Crazy
Speaker 21:  Town by Butterfly. My prompt was actually,
Speaker 21:  I tried to make a rap about American founder Thomas Butterfly
Speaker 22:  By Crazy Town. Yeah. Crazy.
Speaker 21:  Yeah. Sorry. Thank you. Butterfly by Crazy.
Speaker 22:  There's a band called Butterfly that had a song called Crazy Town that would
Speaker 22:  be perfect
Speaker 21:  In another universe. So I like uio. I'm sure there is. I tried to, I tried,
Speaker 21:  I did try to hack these systems a little bit and I wrote, I want you
Speaker 21:  to write a rap about American founder Thomas Jefferson about not throwing
Speaker 21:  away his shot nasal male rapper boom bap. And what I got
Speaker 21:  was basically Butterfly by Crazy Town.
Speaker 22:  Just like total random.
Speaker 21:  Yeah.
Speaker 27:  Cropping
Speaker 22:  Out the No
Speaker 21:  Tom
Speaker 27:  Jeff never slept tion
Speaker 27:  hypocrisy. Oh God.
Speaker 27:  Like fireworks.
Speaker 22:  I'm, I'm, I'm sorry to, I'm sorry for listening to this. And we subject
Speaker 22:  to you
Speaker 21:  That really is Butterfly by Crazy Town. I think it's also a little bit of
Speaker 21:  a, who is that song? Superman.
Speaker 22:  Yes.
Speaker 21:  Oh wow man. Who, who's Superman by
Speaker 22:  I'll be Your Kryptonite Orite that A horrible
Speaker 21:  Kryptonite. Yeah, kryptonite. Three doors down. Is that who? It's by three
Speaker 22:  Doors down. It is by three doors
Speaker 21:  Down. Oh, it's got a little bit of that. It's just, you can so easily
Speaker 21:  hear references that are not even the thing that you prompt. And I just,
Speaker 21:  I have to say that If you, right now, If you go to the homepage
Speaker 21:  of UDO, the two most popular attracts are exact
Speaker 21:  sound alikes of Eminem and Snoop Dogg. So people are doing this
Speaker 21:  like people are trying to make sound alikes.
Speaker 22:  So the argument from all these companies is, look, training is fair use.
Speaker 22:  And that's the argument for OpenAI. That's the argument for Google. It's
Speaker 22:  the argument for Suno and UDO, the
Speaker 22:  organization of these cases is different because the plaintiffs are different.
Speaker 22:  Right. The New York Times is situated differently than the major labels.
Speaker 22:  People have different emotional relationships with different kinds of work.
Speaker 22:  But this is the argument, like when Google eventually goes and Sues opening
Speaker 22:  eye for training on YouTube, the weirdness of that argument is Google
Speaker 22:  telling open ai, the training on YouTube is not fair. Like that's
Speaker 22:  what's gonna happen here. Mm. It's all the same argument and it's all kind
Speaker 22:  of in a
Speaker 21:  Circle. Wait, so Google can do it and it's fair use, but Suno and UIO
Speaker 21:  cannot do it because it's not fair use. This is,
Speaker 22:  This is the trap the industry has set for itself
Speaker 21:  And our giant,
Speaker 22:  What's that line Consolidated? Yeah. Right. It's like it's all the same
Speaker 22:  VCs in all in all different directions. Kind
Speaker 21:  Of like the music business.
Speaker 22:  That's true. There's that line though that's like, you have to be perfect
Speaker 22:  every time and I just have to get through once. Mm. Yeah. It's like
Speaker 22:  I can't, I don't remember exactly what it is. That's what, that's like
Speaker 5:  The hacker creed, right? Like you have to stop me every time. All I have
Speaker 5:  to do is fi I just have to get through once. Yeah.
Speaker 22:  Yeah. And that is, that feels like that copyright situation for AI
Speaker 22:  right now, this is a house of cards and
Speaker 22:  maybe, maybe the Times will win, maybe the
Speaker 22:  record labels will win Mary, maybe Sarah Silverman will win. Like
Speaker 22:  there are so many of these, maybe Google and Open Eye reach an
Speaker 22:  agreement about training on YouTube and then a bunch of YouTube creators
Speaker 22:  sue and maybe they win. Like you can just game it out a hundred
Speaker 22:  different ways. The at some point someone is gonna win a lawsuit that says
Speaker 22:  training is not fair use. Yeah.
Speaker 21:  The fair use argument here, I feel like is notable, I feel like is
Speaker 21:  quite different than what the New York Times can claim. Because part of
Speaker 21:  fair use is for example, the effect on the potential market. Right.
Speaker 21:  And with New York Times, they're gonna have to argue, well, you know, you're
Speaker 21:  using our articles and other people are taking that and
Speaker 21:  creating texts and putting it on other pseudo journalistic sites. Right.
Speaker 22:  I I, I'm, I'm pretty sure the times assuming for both the output and the
Speaker 22:  training.
Speaker 21:  I see. Okay.
Speaker 22:  So I I I I think these cases are all different. This is what I mean, like
Speaker 22:  the, the strategy for one doesn't work for all of them in the same way.
Speaker 22:  Right?
Speaker 21:  Right. In the case of music, the marketplace argument like does is
Speaker 21:  it going to affect the marketplace? Is I I think they have a very strong
Speaker 21:  argument here. I think the RIA has a very strong argument. They're basically
Speaker 21:  saying Suno and nio, you are charging users money
Speaker 21:  to make songs that you are allowing them to upload to the exact same
Speaker 21:  place where we also have all of our songs into Spotify, apple Music,
Speaker 21:  et cetera. And so you are actually changing the marketplace
Speaker 21:  for music, having used all of this output. But
Speaker 21:  is that, is that not part of the argument you're saying?
Speaker 22:  I I think we have to find out how that shakes out.
Speaker 22:  Right? Like I, I don't know. They gotta get
Speaker 22:  assigned a judge, right? Like Right, right now what they've done is they
Speaker 22:  put out a complaint in a press release. There hasn't been a reply to that
Speaker 22:  complaint or an answer. They haven't been assigned a judge. Like they haven't
Speaker 22:  done any discovery. Like we just don't know a bunch of stuff. And we certainly
Speaker 22:  don't know where they're gonna put their focus. But that part where
Speaker 22:  copyright law is just about making copies and in the history of computing,
Speaker 22:  every single copy has been litigated down to, again, I bring it
Speaker 22:  up, I think I bring it up MA every time. MAI versus peak systems. You go
Speaker 22:  look it up. This is, are you a third party software
Speaker 22:  seller allowed to load software into a computer's memory
Speaker 22:  without permission? Crazy. A court, a crazy court case.
Speaker 22:  Yeah. Can you put a disc in a computer and load software from the disc to
Speaker 22:  the hard drive without my permission got litigated and they lost.
Speaker 22:  Crazy. They lost. And then we had to get all the way through caching our
Speaker 22:  ephemeral copies on your ISPs network
Speaker 22:  equipment or those copies that should be litigated. This is,
Speaker 22:  it's, it's dumb. Like it is a very dumb rationale, but
Speaker 22:  it litigates the creation of copies. So here it's did you have
Speaker 22:  permission to make a copy to train your model
Speaker 22:  of all these songs and e every time you didn't have permission. By the way,
Speaker 22:  we want this statutory maximum of $150,000, which
Speaker 22:  essentially ends up being a pretend amount of money. It
Speaker 21:  It's gotta be bigger than the US GDP.
Speaker 22:  Yeah. It's like crazy, right? Like, did you have permission to copy every
Speaker 22:  song in the world? And If you didn't, every song in the world times $150,000
Speaker 22:  is what we're asking for.
Speaker 21:  I'm gonna run this
Speaker 22:  If you didn't have that permission, can we do an analysis that says that
Speaker 22:  use is fair use? Right. So fair use is what's called an affirmative
Speaker 22:  defense to copyright infringement. Where you, you, you admit it like I
Speaker 22:  did, I did it. But under this other rationale, it's That's fine.
Speaker 22:  And so that's like the winding path here is,
Speaker 22:  well first they won't even cop to having made the copies, which
Speaker 22:  is why the music industry is putting out, well here's just Johnny B. Good.
Speaker 22:  Like you can't output Johnny B. Good unless you copy Johnny B. Good on the,
Speaker 22:  on the front end. Right. Okay. So first we gotta get them to copy to making
Speaker 22:  the copies at all, which they claim is proprietary business information.
Speaker 22:  Sure. Then it's was that copy allowed,
Speaker 22:  they obviously didn't have permission. This is why they're in a lawsuit.
Speaker 22:  And then it, and then it's, is it fair use? And then we run the analysis.
Speaker 22:  And the analysis is like the purpose and character of the use, the amount
Speaker 22:  of the use, the nature of the use, the, and then the last factor
Speaker 22:  is the effect on the market, right? On the output side. I think the market
Speaker 22:  argument is really strong.
Speaker 21:  Right? Right. So the question is, 'cause this case, this is something I
Speaker 21:  actually don't understand. Maybe you can explain with your copyright law
Speaker 21:  degree. Can, can, is there like some
Speaker 21:  wall between the input and the output in, in this argument that says,
Speaker 21:  well, there's no marketplace for, you know, that
Speaker 22:  Emoji, it's like this with the hands. Yeah, it's the hands are up. Like
Speaker 22:  I'm just that emoji right now. Yeah. I don't
Speaker 21:  Know. 'cause 'cause I was trying to say, oh, well if there's a clear change
Speaker 21:  in the marketplace for songs, which are all outputs, but it sounds like,
Speaker 21:  you know, we don't know what the responses are gonna be, but they could
Speaker 21:  say, well there isn't currently a marketplace for training data in this
Speaker 21:  kind of way. And so it's not affecting that marketplace. But
Speaker 22:  If you, there will never be a market If you just set the rate in
Speaker 22:  zero. Right? Right. So if you're like, I want really high
Speaker 22:  quality music for my high quality music
Speaker 22:  AI program, I'm gonna go pay a bunch of artists, but then these guys
Speaker 22:  come along and steal it. But you've just, you've actually preemptively destroyed
Speaker 22:  the market. Sure. You've never allowed that market to set some rates. And
Speaker 22:  I've heard from publishers who are taking the deals with opening AI disclosure
Speaker 22:  of Vox Media has a content licensing deal with opening ai.
Speaker 22:  I've heard from other publishers, not our company, that one of the reasons
Speaker 22:  they've taken these deals is to create that market, right? Hmm.
Speaker 22:  So that the times can go to court and say, this has an effect on the market.
Speaker 22:  Look at this market, look at the money that's moving around.
Speaker 22:  And so some of these publishers are, are playing kind of a strategic game
Speaker 22:  to say we should create a market to help that factor along. I think that's
Speaker 22:  fascinating. Hmm. The, but I don't think that the AI company,
Speaker 22:  I think they thought they could just buy forgiveness. And what's crazy
Speaker 22:  to me is when it was Napster or YouTube or Google search,
Speaker 22:  even buying forgiveness worked because people liked the companies,
Speaker 22:  they liked the products, they liked the experiences they were having. And
Speaker 22:  here people, I mean, I'm con you, if you're listening to
Speaker 22:  this and you have a, a very different view of this, lemme know, but our
Speaker 22:  audience is pretty loud with us that they don't like these companies and
Speaker 22:  they don't, they, they perceive this as a moral problem. And I,
Speaker 22:  I think that's just a very different position for them all to be in. Which
Speaker 21:  Brings us to your moral quandary. It seems like you flipped sides from 20
Speaker 21:  years ago.
Speaker 22:  Yeah. The idea that I'm sitting here being like the RIA as a point is crazy.
Speaker 22:  Like I, it's bananas and Sarah Jung and I have been like all day,
Speaker 22:  every day like slacking. Like who have we become? You know, this is like
Speaker 22:  the horseshoe theory of copyright law, politics.
Speaker 22:  It's weird, man. And I, I think one of the pieces of the puzzle, and
Speaker 22:  I'm curious how you see this in the music industry itself, Charlie, one
Speaker 22:  of the pieces of the puzzle here is that the internet just blew the
Speaker 22:  bottom outta the music industry. Like there's no, there's no way to
Speaker 22:  be like a middle class musician anymore. There's no guaranteed way to make
Speaker 22:  money. You're like, you're playing the same algorithmic game as everyone
Speaker 22:  else. You're beholden to some labels. You don't have any power as an individual
Speaker 22:  against these platforms. So now this next group of people
Speaker 22:  who's come and taken your work for free and is gonna extract value
Speaker 22:  from you. Well sure. Like the enemy of my enemy is
Speaker 22:  my friend. It's, it's kind of the vibe. But I'm wondering If you see that
Speaker 22:  reflected in the actual music industry.
Speaker 21:  Absolutely. I mean, the public perception here is so different than what
Speaker 21:  was happening back in the Napster era. Back in the Napster era, the labels
Speaker 21:  were enemy number one. Selling out to labels was, was a big, you know,
Speaker 21:  they were, they were, they were the worst players today. I actually think
Speaker 21:  they've done a very effective job of using their proxy Spotify and let
Speaker 21:  Spotify be the enemy. And everyone's like Sony Music. Who are they? Like
Speaker 21:  Warner, UMG. Like they have labeled deals, but they are not, they're, they're
Speaker 21:  not the, the topic of conversation of who's really screwing who now they
Speaker 21:  basically help set the rates of what gets paid out in streaming. And
Speaker 21:  it's the distributors now that really are taking all the heat. And so they're
Speaker 21:  actually in a better, I think, place of public perception in terms of within
Speaker 21:  the music industry. I, I see
Speaker 21:  songwriters, producers, fans totally freaked
Speaker 21:  out about what's going on. When you go and scan through a lot of the,
Speaker 21:  the YouTube comments of some of these AI songs.
Speaker 21:  The, the sentiment is we are screwed. Music
Speaker 21:  is over. I give up. I am not learning an instrument. Like
Speaker 21:  it's, it's sort of, it, it is not, the future is bright. We're gonna create
Speaker 21:  new beautiful music. Like my creativity is going to blossom.
Speaker 21:  I think that there is a, a real existential fear that is exists within all
Speaker 21:  of the, you know, the AI world. But you're, you're getting into like our
Speaker 21:  human emotions and the beautiful creative output, hopefully beautiful. I
Speaker 21:  mean, listen how you feel about pop
Speaker 22:  Music, whatever Jason Deru
Speaker 21:  Don't bring Jason into this.
Speaker 22:  We gotta get derulo on the po I don't
Speaker 21:  Well and really do.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's obviously like reading through the RA's lawsuit like that is
Speaker 5:  they talk about the creativity and, and human emotion of it all. Yes.
Speaker 5:  But is the, is the end of this just they're trying to get
Speaker 5:  checks in the same way that there are absolutely a lot of folks out there
Speaker 5:  just trying to get checks. Like, well, 'cause part of me, like I I think
Speaker 5:  obviously that's the answer. But also part of me wonders if the labels are
Speaker 5:  feeling the same way that you do, which is that, oh, this is not just a thing
Speaker 5:  we need to make money off of tomorrow. This is like an existential crisis
Speaker 5:  for our business down the road. Or if they're like, whatever, this is just
Speaker 5:  a new turn, we have to make sure we get
Speaker 21:  Paid. This is an existential crisis because they are already losing market
Speaker 21:  share to, you know, people who are not on major labels. Major
Speaker 21:  label listening is down, right? As an overall
Speaker 21:  share of all listening, it's still a lot of, it's still the majority of
Speaker 21:  listening. But so they recognize that flooding
Speaker 21:  the streamers with more and more independent music has not necessarily been
Speaker 21:  good for their business. And with more flooding, it's just going to bring
Speaker 21:  everything down to everything as valueless entirely. If you own music
Speaker 21:  and it gets played a lot on streaming, there's a lot of money in it.
Speaker 21:  Like there's billions and billions and billions of dollars in streaming.
Speaker 21:  How it's distributed is not always fair. And people get upset about this,
Speaker 21:  but they very much need to figure out how to, how, how, how to enter and
Speaker 21:  participate in this marketplace. And I think kind of like a content ID system,
Speaker 21:  they want to figure out how to properly license. You wanna use Jason Doll's
Speaker 21:  voice? Dre Duro says yes and it costs this, and now we've got Jason Dollo
Speaker 21:  copies and that's okay.
Speaker 22:  By the way, if all of the artists who would let his voice go deep fake to
Speaker 22:  make like commercials. Jason
Speaker 21:  Dillo. Yeah. Jason
Speaker 22:  Daro. Look, I, it's, I'm not, I'm not even saying I've, I've talked a lot
Speaker 22:  of Jason Dillo related ish on this episode. I'm aware of it. I just know
Speaker 22:  that he is a commercial mastermind. Yes. But that man's gonna make a bag
Speaker 22:  no matter what happens. Yes. Friend of the pod, Blake
Speaker 22:  Reed, he is a professor at Colorado Law, teaches copyright, telecom, all
Speaker 22:  this stuff. He wrote me a note last week or the week before
Speaker 22:  and he said something really smart that I've been thinking about. And it's
Speaker 22:  related to what you're saying, David, copyright law is like a
Speaker 22:  economic system, right? We create scarcity and then we can like charge
Speaker 22:  money for things. 'cause you're not allowed to just like freely copy them.
Speaker 22:  So If you do something bad in the world of copyright law, the
Speaker 22:  answer is you pay money and you fix it. And you, you even out the
Speaker 22:  economic problem that you've created, right? Olivia Rodrigo
Speaker 22:  might have sung four notes to the Taylor Swift song. The answer is, Taylor
Speaker 22:  Swift gets a writing credit and then some money flows to Taylor Swift. And
Speaker 22:  that is the end of that story, right? And it's just an economic problem
Speaker 22:  that you've solved by redistributing money. AI is a moral problem. This
Speaker 22:  is the thing Blake pointed out to me is like, the money doesn't solve the
Speaker 22:  perceived moral issue here. So the labels might get paid, they might find
Speaker 22:  some business model that lets some license the music into perpetuity or
Speaker 22:  whatever. But the thing you're seeing in the YouTube comments, the thing
Speaker 22:  our audience is feeling, the thing I think a lot of artists are feeling
Speaker 22:  does not get solved by money. Right? It it, it's like another problem.
Speaker 22:  And so like you, you see these deals come up and get signed and whatever,
Speaker 22:  and everyone's like, eh, it's still pretty icky, right? And there, there's
Speaker 22:  something there that I think is important. I haven't quite puzzled it out.
Speaker 22:  I actually want to do something with that idea. If you have further
Speaker 22:  thoughts, let me know what you think about it. But that gap is the gap,
Speaker 22:  right? We can move a bunch of money around, like the VCs in Hollywood
Speaker 22:  and the recording in in Streets Association of America. God bless
Speaker 22:  them, they will move the money around. Lucian Grange will get paid.
Speaker 22:  Is that gonna solve the other problem? Right? Like, and that's, I think
Speaker 22:  that's really hard. There's
Speaker 21:  Two things that musicians need to not fear. One is that because
Speaker 21:  the output of all of these models cannot be copywritten, this
Speaker 21:  music is kind of in this weird limbo space. Like maybe it's going to def
Speaker 21:  it will definitely find some streams, but it probably won't be synced on
Speaker 21:  television and film because no TV producer is gonna
Speaker 21:  wanna have a song where they like don't really understand the rights associated
Speaker 21:  with that song. And if they have the right to it, and does it also secretly
Speaker 21:  contain a vocal sample of James Brown that has been stolen. Like
Speaker 21:  so nobody wants to, any rights holder doesn't want to use this music that
Speaker 21:  can't be used in a weird way. So I think composers and people who are putting
Speaker 21:  stuff on TV, in film, I think that they're still very much a business for
Speaker 21:  them until these much bigger legal issues get sorted out.
Speaker 21:  The other places that music is about human connection. And I don't say this
Speaker 21:  in some like wishy-washy way. It's like there is no fandom
Speaker 21:  for Olivia Rodrigo without an Olivia. Rodrigo. Like you need the person.
Speaker 21:  The time that the music industry tried to create like an avatar
Speaker 21:  racially strangely coded, what
Speaker 21:  was that guy's name? It was terrible. They tried to do like their NFT
Speaker 21:  avatar Pop star and it was an utter failure both because it was
Speaker 21:  completely racist and because why would we develop a relationship to this
Speaker 21:  thing? And so the the fandom side, the pop stardom side of
Speaker 21:  pop music, I don't think is ever gonna go away. What
Speaker 22:  About Uni miko, right? Isn't that she's, she's like the cartoon
Speaker 22:  character. I just learned that she's officially code named CVO
Speaker 22:  one.
Speaker 21:  Yeah, there are the, there are these avatar characters that are finding
Speaker 21:  some fandoms online. Yes, that's gonna happen. I'd still just like, that
Speaker 21:  doesn't, that's not Olivia, that's not Taylor, that's not Gaga. I'm sorry.
Speaker 21:  It's just different. All
Speaker 22:  Right, we gotta end it. They're not Jason Derulo.
Speaker 21:  They're not Jason Deo,
Speaker 5:  Welcome back. Do you remember when you first heard about
Speaker 5:  podcasts? If you've been listening to this show, The Vergecast since
Speaker 5:  2011, Maybe it was that, or If you were a listener
Speaker 5:  of the End Gadget podcast before even that, maybe that's
Speaker 5:  where you got into it. Or really to be way less self-absorbed
Speaker 5:  and much more realistic about it. Maybe it was Serial in
Speaker 5:  2014 that turned you and frankly millions of other people
Speaker 5:  onto the idea of Radio on Demand. That's when podcasts
Speaker 5:  became a thing. But I bet that for most people, the farthest
Speaker 5:  possible distance back you could go would be this moment in
Speaker 5:  2005 when Steve Jobs got on stage at WWDC
Speaker 5:  and before he announced that Apple was switching to using Intel chips and
Speaker 5:  before he said that Leopard would be the next version of Mac Os, he explained
Speaker 5:  to a lot of people why they were about to start seeing podcasts in
Speaker 5:  iTunes.
Speaker 28:  As you know, the podcasting phenomenon is exploding right now.
Speaker 28:  And podcasting, of course is a concatenation of iPod and broadcasting.
Speaker 28:  And what is podcasting? You know, it's been described a lot of different
Speaker 28:  ways. One way has been TiVo for radio.
Speaker 28:  You can download radio shows and listen to 'em on your computer or put 'em
Speaker 28:  on your iPod anytime you want. So it's just like television programs on
Speaker 28:  TiVo. And that's true. Another way it's been described is
Speaker 28:  Wayne's World for radio, which means that anyone
Speaker 28:  without much capital investment can make a podcast, put it on a
Speaker 28:  server and get a worldwide audience for their radio show. And that's true
Speaker 28:  too. We see it as the hottest thing going in
Speaker 28:  radio.
Speaker 5:  A fun fact from that one, by the way, jobs talked about how there were 8,000
Speaker 5:  podcasts available at that time in 2005. And that was a huge
Speaker 5:  number. He was really excited about it. Now that number is somewhere between
Speaker 5:  three and 5 million podcasts. Lots changed
Speaker 5:  anyway. A lot of people credit jobs with mainstreaming, both
Speaker 5:  the word and the concept of podcasts, which is probably at least a little
Speaker 5:  true podcast, was the Oxford Dictionaries word of the year
Speaker 5:  in 2005. It beat out, in case you're wondering, bird flu,
Speaker 5:  reggaeton, life hack, whole bunch of other stuff. But jobs
Speaker 5:  didn't create the concept or the word. The concept,
Speaker 5:  I think is the one of those two that is trickiest to figure out. Technically,
Speaker 5:  you could argue that the idea of a podcast is just like radio and we've had
Speaker 5:  that around forever. But I think you can make a pretty good case that the
Speaker 5:  thing we now know as a podcast became a thing in about
Speaker 5:  2003 and it involved a guy named Chris Leiden.
Speaker 29:  It was a very exciting coincidence for me. For one thing, I, I had
Speaker 29:  been Ignominiously bumped out of a wonderful job in public radio
Speaker 29:  and looking for something new. Charlie Nessen at Berkman Center said,
Speaker 29:  come and think with us. Dave Weiner arrived a few
Speaker 29:  weeks later and he said, well, Charlie told me
Speaker 29:  David Weiner was coming. Charles
Speaker 5:  Nessen, by the way, it was the creator of the Berkman Client Center for Internet
Speaker 5:  and Society, which was kind of an early internet think tank at Harvard that
Speaker 5:  actually still does a lot of really interesting digital work. Dave Weiner
Speaker 5:  is one of the Internet's earliest and longest tenured bloggers. His blog
Speaker 5:  just turned 30 last week. He's also a key creator of RSS, which
Speaker 5:  is the technology that spreads feeds of content around the internet. And
Speaker 5:  he's just a guy who cares a lot about web publishing standards. At the time,
Speaker 5:  If you wanted to start a blog calling Dave Weiner was like calling Gordon
Speaker 5:  Ramsey for tips on how to open a restaurant. And Chris Leiden hit him
Speaker 5:  up.
Speaker 29:  I wrote to Dave Weer saying six months ago, I couldn't spell blog
Speaker 29:  now I want a B one. And we went through the blog cycle very, very
Speaker 29:  quickly. But then he said, you know, radio, I know
Speaker 29:  programming what the world needs is an MP three file that can
Speaker 29:  go worldwide instantly. I said, sounds good to me. And we got
Speaker 29:  to work. It only took, oh, a couple of months let's say.
Speaker 29:  And he said, I think we got it. I said, now what day? He said, well, that's
Speaker 29:  obvious. You're gonna do a conversation with me and we're gonna put it out.
Speaker 29:  And we did
Speaker 5:  Leiden and Weiner ended up publishing that conversation in July of
Speaker 5:  2003. And I just wanna play you the first 30 seconds or so of it,
Speaker 5:  which I found by the way, thanks to James Cridland
Speaker 5:  over@podnews.net. He did a great whole big
Speaker 5:  thing on the history of the Word podcast and we're actually gonna talk to
Speaker 5:  him about the future of podcasts later in the show. Anyway, here, it's
Speaker 29:  Dave Wener. I feel like a new immigrant in this blogger world where you're
Speaker 29:  a kind of founding father. Walk me around it, and
Speaker 29:  I'm not talking about the technology. I wanna know what kind of democratic
Speaker 29:  experiment this blog idea really amounts to.
Speaker 30:  Well, gosh, it changes all the time. I mean, when we first
Speaker 30:  started doing this, it was just a bunch of people sort of
Speaker 30:  writing Hello world and being amazed that
Speaker 30:  it was possible to do that and and then the next
Speaker 30:  step was recognition of other people and say, wow, there's somebody else
Speaker 30:  doing this and learning how to
Speaker 30:  communicate. And
Speaker 30:  gosh, I don't know how to answer that question. I mean, it is what you make
Speaker 30:  of it. Everybody brings something different to it and different set of expectations
Speaker 30:  and everybody molds it to be whatever it means to them.
Speaker 5:  They don't call what they're doing there a podcast, but I mean that's a podcast
Speaker 5:  right there. Like it's two dudes talking tech. It's all very meta.
Speaker 5:  The sound quality is good, but kind of messy. That's all
Speaker 5:  the hallmarks of podcasts all in one place. And I think the thing
Speaker 5:  that whiner says at the very end, it is what you make of it turned out to
Speaker 5:  be more prescient than maybe either of them realized at the time,
Speaker 5:  but still they weren't calling it a podcast. Nobody was, they were calling
Speaker 5:  these things audio blogs, if they were calling them anything. There were
Speaker 5:  a handful of them out there, but none of them were podcasts until
Speaker 5:  Ben Hammersley showed up. Ben, I should say right up front is
Speaker 5:  not exactly psyched that he is part of this particular slice of podcast
Speaker 5:  history.
Speaker 31:  It's a fucking bane in my life because there's absolutely no
Speaker 31:  honor in the origin story, right? That,
Speaker 31:  you know, when I die, I want to be remembered for, I
Speaker 31:  don't know, a 20 year project or something, or saving
Speaker 31:  orphans from a burning building or, or something,
Speaker 31:  something like that, rather than a word that was invented in a sort of deadline
Speaker 31:  frenzy that I didn't even realize I was doing until a few
Speaker 31:  months later.
Speaker 5:  In 2004, Ben was working on some early RSS in publishing tech
Speaker 5:  and was also writing about the burgeoning tech industry for The Guardian.
Speaker 5:  And in February of 2004, he published a piece called Audible Revolution,
Speaker 5:  all about the cool stuff people were doing online with audio
Speaker 5:  at the time, there were people building software that could automatically
Speaker 5:  record radio streams over the internet and make them available for listening
Speaker 5:  later. The iPod obviously was everywhere, and people were also
Speaker 5:  building software to take all those streams that you had downloaded and put
Speaker 5:  them onto your iPod one step at a time. All of this stuff was
Speaker 5:  starting to come together. Ben actually interviewed Chris Leiden for the
Speaker 5:  piece that he wrote, and Leiden talked about how audio over the web was gonna
Speaker 5:  change people's relationships with their audience. It was gonna democratize
Speaker 5:  media. They had all these big high-minded ideas about what audio
Speaker 5:  might do, but it's right there in the second paragraph of
Speaker 5:  the story that Ben Hammersley does. The thing, actually, lemme just read
Speaker 5:  you the first two paragraphs with the benefit of hindsight. It all seems
Speaker 5:  quite obvious. MP three players like Apple's iPod in many pockets,
Speaker 5:  audio production software are cheap or free, and web logging an established
Speaker 5:  part of the internet, all the ingredients are there for a new boom in
Speaker 5:  amateur radio, but what to call it audio blogging,
Speaker 5:  podcasting, gorilla Media. There it is
Speaker 5:  that almost everyone agrees is the first published use of the word
Speaker 5:  podcasting. It's a big moment. Of course, Ben had absolutely no
Speaker 5:  idea what he was doing when he wrote that word.
Speaker 31:  The Guardian at the time was a print first paper, as in you
Speaker 31:  wrote for the paper and you had a print deadline when the physical printing
Speaker 31:  presses would run at six o'clock. And If you
Speaker 31:  missed that deadline, the the words weren't going to go onto the
Speaker 31:  page. And that meant that
Speaker 31:  every day, this sort of working rhythm was that there was this big rush
Speaker 31:  to get everything done by quarter to six or
Speaker 31:  whatever. And I'd written this article and about five
Speaker 31:  30 or so, you know, just before the print deadline, I go to
Speaker 31:  an email from my editor saying, we've put it on the page
Speaker 31:  and it's very nice, but it, it's kind of a line short and it doesn't look
Speaker 31:  very good on the page. You know, the, the text hasn't gone green
Speaker 31:  in the typesetting program. Can you write me another sentence
Speaker 31:  just to pad it out? Right? Just to make it fit beautifully on the printed
Speaker 31:  page. And So I wrote an extra sentence and emailed it over, and the sentence
Speaker 31:  is this sort of like mildly meaningless sentence of, but what do we call
Speaker 31:  this new phenomenon? And then I sort of invented three words and put them
Speaker 31:  in there and then sent it off. And then I went to the pub.
Speaker 5:  Look on the one hand, thank God we call it podcasting and not
Speaker 5:  Gorilla Mediaing, you know what I mean? But Ben doesn't even
Speaker 5:  remember how he came up with podcast. Everyone now says it's a port
Speaker 5:  manto of iPod and broadcast, which is what Steve Jobs said in that clip earlier.
Speaker 5:  And Ben basically just said, yeah, that seems reasonable enough, but
Speaker 5:  he doesn't even remember coming up with it. He also, at the time,
Speaker 5:  had no idea, truly no idea what he had done.
Speaker 31:  And it was only a few months later that I got emails from, from the Oxford
Speaker 31:  English dictionary saying, where do you find this word? We
Speaker 31:  we're trying to find an earlier citation for it than, than your piece. And,
Speaker 31:  and we can't, where did you get it? And I, you know,
Speaker 31:  pulled it out the back of my head on a, on a deadline panic. I, I had no
Speaker 31:  idea. And I looked on all of the RSS related
Speaker 31:  development mailing lists and so on, which, which is what the place
Speaker 31:  where it would've been. And I couldn't find any trace of it either.
Speaker 31:  And So I said, well, clearly I just must have made it up. And then they
Speaker 31:  said, great, because it's word of the Year. And then, you know, and
Speaker 31:  then it became the thing that Apple took on and that's what they called
Speaker 31:  their app and that's what it became known as. And you know, the rest is
Speaker 31:  history.
Speaker 5:  Ben made very clear several times when we talked that he didn't invent
Speaker 5:  the idea of a podcast and nor does he deserve credit for what podcasts
Speaker 5:  eventually became. But all these years later, he does
Speaker 5:  seem to kind of like the word he came up with. It's got that nice plosive
Speaker 5:  p you can use it as a noun or a verb pretty easily.
Speaker 5:  It's a good useful word that way,
Speaker 31:  But also that within it, there are context clues that Normies could understand.
Speaker 31:  Hmm. So, you know, the iPod was the biggest thing in the world
Speaker 31:  at that time, and that's where the pod bit comes from. And
Speaker 31:  although it was super fiddly at the beginning to, to take these podcasts
Speaker 31:  and put them onto your iPod pretty rapidly, some software came out there
Speaker 31:  and made that simpler. And then soon after that, apple made it possible
Speaker 31:  within iTunes. And to
Speaker 31:  say it's kind of like TiVo for radio
Speaker 31:  that you listen to on your MP three player is a pretty good
Speaker 31:  sentence in 2002, 2003. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 31:  To sort of, not, not necessarily just huge techie circles or, or even like
Speaker 31:  super early adopters, but to sort of, you know, the, the whoever
Speaker 31:  comes after the early adopters, those people, you know, they, they could
Speaker 31:  understand it. And so it, I think it becomes one of those things where
Speaker 31:  a, it's a fun word to say, but also it kind of has meaning within
Speaker 31:  it that somebody who's used to new
Speaker 31:  technologies can kind of understand straight away. And,
Speaker 31:  and so, and it becomes a self evidently good idea,
Speaker 31:  right? And then when you have a few years later you have these
Speaker 31:  very successful professionally made podcasts, which take full advantage
Speaker 31:  or start to take full advantage of the, of the fact that they're at liberty
Speaker 31:  to use as much space or as little space as they need, as much time as little
Speaker 31:  time, different episode lengths or that sort of thing
Speaker 31:  that people started exploring that and, and being able to self commission
Speaker 31:  and make, make programs that were something you would never, ever
Speaker 31:  have heard before on regular ball cross radio then,
Speaker 31:  then suddenly becomes its own its own thing very rapidly and people
Speaker 31:  start to see the value of it hugely tied in with
Speaker 31:  the call it Skagit on the market at the time. So I think it, it, it
Speaker 31:  sort of catches that lightning of all of those different things happening.
Speaker 31:  At the same time,
Speaker 5:  Most people do seem to agree that Ben coined the term
Speaker 5:  podcast, or at least used it first. But there is one other person in the
Speaker 5:  equation who definitely deserves credit. That's Danny Gregoire, who's a
Speaker 5:  software engineer who used the word in an email to a list of folks working
Speaker 5:  on and with an app called ipo. IPO was one of those
Speaker 5:  things that could automatically take recorded audio and put it on your iPod.
Speaker 5:  The list at the time was brand new and IPO was an app started by
Speaker 5:  a guy named Adam Curry who had an audio blog of his own at the time called
Speaker 5:  Daily Source Code. Adam was a longtime radio guy, he'd also
Speaker 5:  been an MTV VJ for years and he'd also been an
Speaker 5:  early internet entrepreneur and for years at this point he had been chatting
Speaker 5:  with Dave Weiner and others about the whole concept of putting audio
Speaker 5:  files in RSS. But Adam was one of the very first people to
Speaker 5:  have kind of a whole vision of how this on demand internet
Speaker 5:  radio thing should actually work.
Speaker 32:  Now it was end of 2003 when a friend
Speaker 32:  of mine said, look at this cool thing I have. I said, what do you have?
Speaker 32:  And it was the iPod. And I looked at this iPod and
Speaker 32:  it was like literally like lightning bolts because it
Speaker 32:  looked, I don't have any, I, it looked exactly like
Speaker 32:  this transistor radio my grandmother had given me when I was seven years
Speaker 32:  old. This little, little Sony transistor radio nine volt battery.
Speaker 32:  I'm like, yeah, you can call this a digital Walkman or you know, whatever
Speaker 32:  you want, but this to me was a radio receiver. And right away I'm like,
Speaker 32:  oh, let's hook it up to this RSS thing.
Speaker 32:  So again, with my very poor scripting skills, I
Speaker 32:  tried to rig this together with Apple Script. And then Kevin Marks
Speaker 32:  who I think worked at, I dunno if he worked at Google, he worked in Silicon
Speaker 32:  Valley somewhere. He basically said, oh, here's the script that you need,
Speaker 32:  and boom, I was like, okay, it works. So I could create a blog post
Speaker 32:  and then this little script would be looking to, to find some, a new item
Speaker 32:  in my blog post with a file attached to it. It would download the file.
Speaker 32:  It would, because you still had to sync your iPod back in the day to
Speaker 32:  your computer. And so it would trigger an update and then in the morning
Speaker 32:  you'd walk in and there would be your iPod with, as the album
Speaker 32:  would be basically, we didn't have the name podcasting yet. It would be,
Speaker 32:  you know, kind of the blog name or the, you know, the, the show name.
Speaker 32:  And then it would have these episodes under it. And I immediately started
Speaker 32:  to just get the word out there because I needed software
Speaker 32:  developers who could create this for real,
Speaker 5:  That thing he's describing. That script was ipo. It would watch
Speaker 5:  RSS feeds for audio files, it would download them, sync them to your iPod
Speaker 5:  and you're done. That's just a podcasting app, right?
Speaker 5:  Adam Curry made a podcasting app, that's all it was. And
Speaker 5:  in fact, his show, daily Source Code was in part a podcast
Speaker 5:  for its own sake, you know, entertainment and content and whatever. But it
Speaker 5:  was also in part sort of an ongoing beta test of how all of
Speaker 5:  this podcasting technology stuff might.