# Transcript
ID: 21df4be7-3faf-43bb-86ef-ef5f4d608bdb
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7201974140045927629/-1505402745094791194/s93290-US-3046s-1731842433.mp3
Description: For the third episode in our series about the future of music, we talk with Ge Wang. Ge is a professor at Stanford, a co-founder of Smule, the conductor of Stanford’s laptop orchestra, and has been at the center of technology and artistry for most of his life. We talk about how humans can use AI without giving in to it, what it means to truly play with technology, and the value of art and creativity and friction when it feels like all those things are being taken away.
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of music apps
Speaker 2:  you play on your phone with your mouth. I'm Iran David Pierce, and
Speaker 2:  I am at Union Station in Washington, DC. It's like
Speaker 2:  4 54 in the morning and I'm on my way to New York to go do some
Speaker 2:  planning meetings with a bunch of other VERGE folks. I've been at The Verge
Speaker 2:  for like two and a half years now, and there are a bunch of coworkers that
Speaker 2:  I've just never met in person. It's weird post pandemic
Speaker 2:  universe we live in, but I'm gonna go meet some of them in person. This is
Speaker 2:  the third and last episode in our mini series about the future of music.
Speaker 2:  We've talked about Track star and TikTok. We've talked about autotune, and
Speaker 2:  today I'm talking with a Stanford professor named Ga Wong. GA
Speaker 2:  is fascinating. He's been in the music world for a long time, but
Speaker 2:  he's also an academic. He's also a former
Speaker 2:  entrepreneur who built a company called SMU that you might have heard of.
Speaker 2:  He's just been in the music world thinking about this stuff For a really
Speaker 2:  long time, So I wanted to talk to him about AI and about
Speaker 2:  virtual reality and about what it means to make music now
Speaker 2:  in a world where increasingly technology mediates all parts
Speaker 2:  of this process. We had a really fun conversation. It's
Speaker 2:  not at all what I expected, but I really enjoyed it and I suspect you will
Speaker 2:  too. All that is coming up in just a sec, but literally this train is best
Speaker 2:  to leave without me. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  Welcome back. Let's get into my conversation with Ga Wong. I
Speaker 4:  wanted to talk to GA because he sits at a really unusual place in the
Speaker 4:  music slash technology universe. A bunch of years ago, he
Speaker 4:  co-founded a company called smu, which is still around. You might have heard
Speaker 4:  of it. They make a bunch of really popular music based apps.
Speaker 4:  One is a karaoke app called, I think S Mule that's still really popular.
Speaker 4:  There's also one called Magic Piano, which is kind of like Guitar Hero or
Speaker 4:  Beat Saber, but it's for playing piano. GA also wrote
Speaker 4:  a whole programming language called Chuck, which lets you write code that
Speaker 4:  outputs as music. It's very cool and kind of
Speaker 4:  wild to watch someone work with. He's now been at Stanford
Speaker 4:  for a long time, also teaching in the Center for Computer Research in Music
Speaker 4:  and Acoustics, which is a very cool thing that I just learned exists.
Speaker 4:  He's also written a book about design. He's been teaching about music and
Speaker 4:  technology for years, and in his free time, he's also the conductor
Speaker 4:  of Stanford's laptop orchestra, which is exactly what it sounds
Speaker 4:  like. It's a bunch of students on stage using their laptops and other
Speaker 4:  gadgets to make music, frankly, that you've never heard before. Here
Speaker 4:  is just a glimpse of what that sounds like,
Speaker 4:  That sound If, you can imagine it is being made by GA himself who is
Speaker 4:  standing on stage holding a glove connected to his
Speaker 4:  laptop, and it's changing the sound as he moves his
Speaker 4:  hand in space. It's wild. You should watch it. Their concerts are very cool.
Speaker 4:  I wanted to talk to GA about the future of music because I figured he would
Speaker 4:  just see it all from an unusual perspective. He makes music,
Speaker 4:  he teaches about music. He's a programmer and an engineer, both for fun
Speaker 4:  and by training. He's started companies before. He's seen kind of
Speaker 4:  all sides of this, and I figured he'd have cool ideas about how we
Speaker 4:  make music, how we can interact with computers to make music, and
Speaker 4:  probably would have some like neat new AI apps that he was into that we might
Speaker 4:  talk about. Our conversation went really differently from
Speaker 4:  that, and it went really differently in a way that I really love. Actually,
Speaker 4:  what we ended up talking about more than anything was what it means to be
Speaker 4:  creative in a time when everything is being optimized and simplified
Speaker 4:  and made more convenient and more efficient and more engaging.
Speaker 4:  Absolutely. Everywhere you look, this is much more philosophical
Speaker 4:  than a lot of the stuff we talk about in this show, but I really like the
Speaker 4:  way he talks about what it means to be human and be
Speaker 4:  yourself among all of this technology, and I hope you enjoy it too.
Speaker 4:  So let's just dive in. To start with, I asked to try and frame
Speaker 4:  the way he sees the world a little bit. One thing I've heard him say a few
Speaker 4:  times in interviews and stuff is that he makes computer music,
Speaker 4:  but it's 2024, right? Pretty much all music is made with
Speaker 4:  and on computers. So what does GA's version of computer music
Speaker 4:  look like now and how did he get so obsessed with it in the first place?
Speaker 6:  Since I was a small child, I've had a fascination with computers, probably
Speaker 6:  through video games. Actually, I still remember the first time I saw a video
Speaker 6:  game. I think I was seven or
Speaker 6:  eight in Beijing. You know, I had not seen a computer
Speaker 6:  up to that point. I was thinking it was a big deal when we got a nine inch
Speaker 6:  colored television. You know, this is in the, the early eighties
Speaker 6:  in China, and the first time a, a win. My mom, I think, took me to
Speaker 6:  an arcade, a video game arcade. I don't know if if
Speaker 6:  listeners still know what those are,
Speaker 4:  They've seen 'em in movies at the very least, you know? Yeah. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Those are places where you go and you put like coins into and you can play
Speaker 6:  games, and there's these giant machines, arcade machines, and that's the
Speaker 6:  first time I saw like a video game. And something about the pixels
Speaker 6:  I think really kind of drew me in, not unlike a
Speaker 6:  moth to a flame. I guess that's, it's not entirely like a
Speaker 6:  bad analogy, but I'm like, Ooh. And I think ever since then I've been
Speaker 6:  fascinated with just computers. But I think over time, I think
Speaker 6:  I've really come to love computers and computer science as a discipline,
Speaker 6:  but perhaps in a strange way, and I'll try to explain that. So I'm all
Speaker 6:  my degrees are in computer science. My, my, my, my bachelor of
Speaker 6:  science is in cs. My PhD is in computer science,
Speaker 6:  and in some ways I'm kind of a strange computer scientist,
Speaker 6:  but I think I say strange because I, I tend to build things that
Speaker 6:  with computers that nobody quite asks for.
Speaker 6:  Interesting. And that solves no problems that seem to exist, for
Speaker 6:  example, a arena, right? This is something that was
Speaker 6:  designed back in 2008 for, for the iPhone. And
Speaker 6:  you know, I, let me, So I can play a little here. So I can hear
Speaker 6:  this.
Speaker 6:  So I'm holding my phone as I'm at a sandwich and,
Speaker 6:  and I'm blowing into the microphone located at the bottom of the phone, and
Speaker 6:  I'm using Multitouch to control the pitch, and vibrato is controlled by the
Speaker 6:  tilt of the phone. Oh, cool. So I'm barely even seeing the,
Speaker 6:  the screen, but you know, it's a kind of a physical thing.
Speaker 6:  So So, I'm gonna try to play a little Diddy with this,
Speaker 6:  For example. So that's, that's me blowing literally into my, well, thank
Speaker 6:  you very much. That's me literally blowing into my iPhone
Speaker 6:  and into Aina. And this is an app that I would say is took a lot of,
Speaker 6:  you know, it took software engineering, software design, interaction design,
Speaker 6:  signal processing, all the sound is generated live on the phone
Speaker 6:  using, you know, you know, the sound part is written in the programming
Speaker 6:  language. Chuck, which is was my dissertation
Speaker 6:  at Princeton. Oh. In which I'm still developing, right? Like
Speaker 6:  20,
Speaker 6:  actually 20 some years later. I'm still working on, and myself and a large
Speaker 6:  team of people and a community of people working on Chuck. Right. Just explain
Speaker 6:  what
Speaker 7:  Chuck is, just real quick for people who don't
Speaker 6:  Know. So Chuck is one of these tools that I've been talking about. So Chuck
Speaker 6:  is a programming language for music synthesis,
Speaker 6:  and you're writing code to generate sound, but also to write code, to
Speaker 6:  kind of either to algorithmically figure out
Speaker 6:  or generate like kind of the music that's coming next, or
Speaker 6:  it's actually could be mapped from human interaction. Hmm. In this case,
Speaker 6:  in Karina, it's human interaction, human computer interaction. And
Speaker 6:  I am using my physical interactions to actually actually control
Speaker 6:  the sound that's happening. And so, and a lot of times it's a mixture of
Speaker 6:  the two where it's, there's some amount of automation,
Speaker 6:  but also like, it's a, it's really trying to also figure out what is an
Speaker 6:  interesting way to kind of put human interaction into the loop
Speaker 6:  of, of thing that we're building. Again, nobody asked for,
Speaker 6:  I solved no problems that exist. And I think in a way that's kind of
Speaker 6:  been the, a running through line If, you will, for my
Speaker 6:  students and I, and in my research group is that we, you know, we think
Speaker 6:  about engineering, we think about technology, and we think about, well, what
Speaker 6:  kind of problems can we solve with this? Right? And while
Speaker 6:  yes, problem solving is something that we, we as humans need to do, and,
Speaker 6:  and, and I'm, I'm interested in doing myself, I also feel like as an
Speaker 6:  engineer, we can build things that isn't always motivated by
Speaker 6:  kind of a practical use utility.
Speaker 4:  Tell me how you go through that as kind of a creative process. I think
Speaker 4:  I spend a lot of my time talking to engineers
Speaker 4:  and developers and stuff who say, you, you know, some of the stuff you just
Speaker 4:  said, and then they, they like small leap to, and now I
Speaker 4:  make B2B database management software and or
Speaker 4:  like, and So I made yet another AI chat bot,
Speaker 4:  right? And I think there, there is this easy way to work backwards from like,
Speaker 4:  okay, what is the problem I can solve that will help people? And I
Speaker 4:  think using technology in service of
Speaker 4:  going the other way and saying like, what, what can I just
Speaker 4:  make is just such an interesting and different kind of creative process.
Speaker 4:  I'm curious how you have sort of, especially you, you have to teach this
Speaker 4:  stuff to students. Have you I do refined the process of how to do this stuff
Speaker 4:  for people.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean, I, I teach this, I wrote a whole book about it, artful
Speaker 6:  design technology in search of the sublime. And it's really this, this idea
Speaker 6:  of looking at tool building as, as engineers, but also
Speaker 6:  as critical engineers. Hmm. You know, critical tool builders.
Speaker 6:  And the critical part is really has to do the question, why are you even
Speaker 6:  doing this thing? Right. Why did I design aina? And it
Speaker 6:  wasn't because like I went out and and figured out what do people
Speaker 6:  need? You know, it's like, Hey David, what do you need? And you're like,
Speaker 6:  well, I need to blow into my phone.
Speaker 4:  I need a flute app. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I need a flute app and I need to all also in the same app, I need to be able
Speaker 6:  to listen to other people around the world blown to their phones. Right.
Speaker 6:  That's what missing. That's a, that's a deficit. No, that did not
Speaker 6:  happen. It. And so it wasn't really kind of this traditional
Speaker 6:  idea, at least traditional. Now when we think of engineering, we think of
Speaker 6:  this as like, okay, that's a, what is a need? What's the problem?
Speaker 6:  State the problem and so can find a solution. This is
Speaker 6:  not need-based, designed, at least not in that sense. So why was this
Speaker 6:  designed? This is what some people actually might call, you know, for, for
Speaker 6:  perhaps lack of a better word, value space design. Hmm. And
Speaker 6:  value based design is saying, well, you don't design out of a
Speaker 6:  necessarily a clear and present practical need, but out of
Speaker 6:  something you just, you really deeply as a person believe in.
Speaker 6:  And so for something like ING and perhaps for a lot of the other tools that
Speaker 6:  my students and I build, perhaps one of the values that core values that
Speaker 6:  we are trying to speak to in these design is just simply that music making
Speaker 6:  is good. And that's the belief music making does a person good.
Speaker 6:  And it's not about getting to a product necessarily, but
Speaker 6:  about actually the process of playing. And sometimes
Speaker 6:  and often learning an instrument, not unlike learning
Speaker 6:  to play like a, a well made, perhaps challenging video
Speaker 6:  game.
Speaker 6:  'cause there's a, there's a great satisfaction in that if the game is well
Speaker 6:  made, it does not matter if it's difficult. In fact, you might appreciate
Speaker 6:  the difficulty. 'cause then you, once you feel like you're learning
Speaker 6:  the system, you really can then express yourself. You using the system
Speaker 6:  and then the challenge and then, and able to overcome the challenges eventually
Speaker 6:  of the game becomes hugely gratifying.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Has that started to feel like
Speaker 4:  a, a, I don't know, dying phenomenon
Speaker 4:  to you, the idea that in, in this world of incredible convenience
Speaker 4:  and efficiency where everything is available to you, you know, with all at,
Speaker 4:  with a push of a button or like a plugin in an app, that doing
Speaker 4:  something just for sort of the, the joy and
Speaker 4:  pleasure and slog of doing it is worthwhile. Like
Speaker 4:  that that almost feels like a, a sort of beautiful, deeply
Speaker 4:  anachronistic way of looking at the world right now.
Speaker 6:  Well, unfortunately it is. It feels
Speaker 6:  anachronistic. It feels like it, it's out of time. It's not something that,
Speaker 6:  you know, in this convenience driven,
Speaker 6:  optimization driven, competition driven
Speaker 6:  fabric of a society we live in,
Speaker 6:  it is, it feels deeply anachronistic to build things that are playful,
Speaker 6:  that are interesting for their own sake.
Speaker 6:  But at the same time, I feel like it's what makes us,
Speaker 6:  us, and I don't even mean, I don't mean just building things. So, I mean,
Speaker 6:  just anything I think that you feel like makes you, you,
Speaker 6:  whatever that may be, I like to at least offer the possibility that
Speaker 6:  it actually is something that is, that you, you wanna do and
Speaker 6:  you and you care to do. In fact, you would probably forego a lot
Speaker 6:  of practical needs in order to do, it's like a passionate hobby.
Speaker 6:  And the passionate hobby is usually not about getting to the
Speaker 6:  result. It's not about optimization. Right. And So I think this gets to this
Speaker 6:  idea that yeah, while this idea of building things for its own sake or doing
Speaker 6:  things for its own sake is feels like it's out of fashion, but it's also
Speaker 6:  not, in a sense, I think we actually still do these things.
Speaker 6:  They're just usually not in engineering contexts. You
Speaker 6:  know, for example, when people cook for themselves because they enjoy
Speaker 6:  cooking, there's a deep joy going to the pantry, work up,
Speaker 6:  find the raw ingredients and make a mess of things as you concoct a
Speaker 6:  dish and that dish, doesn't that taste different because you know,
Speaker 6:  'cause you made it right. Yeah. It, it it does, it has to. Especially if
Speaker 6:  you're someone that enjoys cooking. And I think tools are, are,
Speaker 6:  are no different. And I think the danger of
Speaker 6:  being in, in, I think in, in a world or a society where the things,
Speaker 6:  the tools we make are only about optimization, only about
Speaker 6:  convenience, only about reducing the cost of labor is that we
Speaker 6:  actually, in, in those tools, those tools can actually alienate us
Speaker 6:  from who we actually are. Because, you know,
Speaker 6:  well, let's, let's go back to music and let's put, you know, let's talk about
Speaker 6:  music and ai, right? Yeah. Today we have
Speaker 6:  AI that can produce really impressive images,
Speaker 6:  video music. Well that's a, that's
Speaker 6:  a tricky word to use. Even songs are tricky words to use. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's like, you know, what is this song? But let's, for all intents persons
Speaker 6:  say AI can generate quote unquote songs. And with just a
Speaker 6:  prompt. It's, it's like this, this almost age old thing that people
Speaker 6:  thought they always wanted, which is, if I have a musical idea in my mind,
Speaker 6:  I just want this thing realized, wouldn't that be great? You know, and I
Speaker 6:  don't, maybe perhaps I don't have any music education. I've never taken time,
Speaker 6:  but I just want this idea realized in my head it wouldn't, wouldn't that
Speaker 6:  be great? And in a way, AI kind of does that
Speaker 6:  somewhat today, but then I think the question lies what is,
Speaker 6:  what does it mean? Hmm. And you know, and I'll draw another analogy here,
Speaker 6:  and this is something that I call, I guess it's kind of the bubble gum effect.
Speaker 6:  And what do I mean by that? Right? So If, you ever chewed gum, David?
Speaker 6:  Sure.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Okay. So when you chew a piece of gum, when you first pop the, the gum in
Speaker 6:  chewing gum or a bubble gum, right. How do you feel?
Speaker 4:  It's great. It's delicious.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's, it pops Yeah. It's like the taste is great. How long do you usually
Speaker 6:  chew that piece of gum?
Speaker 4:  I mean, it depends on the gum, but some, some somewhere between like
Speaker 4:  10 seconds and three minutes and then, and then it's over.
Speaker 6:  And when it's over, what do you do with that piece of gum?
Speaker 4:  Throw it away.
Speaker 6:  And do you, after that, how much do you think about that particular piece
Speaker 6:  of gum?
Speaker 4:  Never for one second ever again.
Speaker 6:  Okay. So I think that's analogy I'm trying to
Speaker 6:  draw here is that yes, maybe it's so easy
Speaker 6:  that I can go to a generative AI system
Speaker 6:  and say, render me an image of Barney, the dinosaur
Speaker 6:  withdrawing cash from a ATM, but only
Speaker 6:  broccoli is coming out. I think actually AI would
Speaker 6:  generative I today would do a rather impressive job. Yeah. They seem be like,
Speaker 6:  whoa. Yeah. Yeah. That's, that's it. And I may go and share this with my
Speaker 6:  friend and be like, Hey, check out, look what I made. And then that I think
Speaker 6:  there's, there's actually that social function of that. But
Speaker 6:  then more likely than not, I'd probably be like,
Speaker 6:  great onto the next thing. Yeah. That took all of three minutes,
Speaker 6:  five minutes. The timer probably takes to chew a piece of gum, whatever.
Speaker 6:  Think about that thing again. Maybe a little bit more than the piece of
Speaker 6:  gum I discarded. And I think that's what I mean by bubble
Speaker 6:  ification. In fact, it is kind of almost the, in the limit of the, the,
Speaker 6:  this kind of push of automation. It unquestionably pushed automation
Speaker 6:  to basically try to reduce the cost of labor down to zero in
Speaker 6:  like every case we possibly can.
Speaker 4:  Right. Well, there's a, there's a, there's an argument inside of that.
Speaker 4:  I think that, that you hear a lot with kind of anything creative, which is
Speaker 4:  that the process matters, right? That, that
Speaker 4:  the, the provenance of something and where it came from and the story of
Speaker 4:  the thing and the, the person who made it that stuff is, is
Speaker 4:  sort of indelibly connected to the thing in a way that you don't
Speaker 4:  always understand even. But yes. Matters in some way that it's
Speaker 4:  very hard to quantify. And thus it's very hard to talk about. In some ways
Speaker 4:  that stuff matters and I really buy that premise.
Speaker 4:  But I also, what I wonder then about AI is
Speaker 4:  if what AI is going to create is like some entirely other
Speaker 4:  thing that like maybe what we want from AI is not to
Speaker 4:  make songs that sound like Taylor Swift, but something that sounds completely
Speaker 4:  different. And this is part of why I think your work is so
Speaker 4:  interesting and why I'm curious about how you're thinking about and using
Speaker 4:  ai. Like you, you've made a career out of making computers make noises that
Speaker 4:  they're not supposed to make. And, and, and I think what, what those
Speaker 4:  ultimately make is something different, right? Like you're, you're not writing
Speaker 4:  code to make Taylor Swift songs. You're writing some, you're, you're making
Speaker 4:  something else. And I feel like If, you approach AI
Speaker 4:  as that kind of tool,
Speaker 4:  both to sort of bend it to your will, but also to try to figure out like
Speaker 4:  what sound it makes,
Speaker 6:  I guess my general life philosophy can be
Speaker 6:  summed up or at least in aspirations that there should be room for that too.
Speaker 6:  Okay. And I mean this both in, in a way, like, what I mean by that
Speaker 6:  is that I'm, I think about this in, in terms of music, I think about the
Speaker 6:  terms of actually like people in a society,
Speaker 6:  there should be room for that too, as long as the thing is
Speaker 6:  not like harmful and dangerous. Sure. But also it also
Speaker 6:  means that I guess there sh you know, it's really what I'm trying to say
Speaker 6:  is that it should be a pluralism. Mm. We should have room to, to
Speaker 6:  to have capacity to have a pluralism of, of foil
Speaker 6:  of what I would say of values, aesthetic, social.
Speaker 6:  In fact, that would be my notion of what part of what a a, a
Speaker 6:  a, a civil society might have, but also
Speaker 6:  one of maybe a necessary condition for humans to be able to
Speaker 6:  like flourish, you know, is is this idea to have a
Speaker 6:  capacity for pluralism. And so yeah, in that sense,
Speaker 6:  I think there's room to think about how c can, can we explore, use AI
Speaker 6:  to explore the realm of untapped sounds.
Speaker 6:  But how we do that, first of all, I think is really important because it
Speaker 6:  does go back to what you're saying about the meaning that we ascribe to
Speaker 6:  things that we might call art.
Speaker 4:  All right, we gotta take a break and then we have lots more to talk about.
Speaker 4:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. So to go back to the idea of computer music,
Speaker 4:  one of the things GA has talked a lot about over the years is the idea of
Speaker 4:  finding new ways to interact with technology and computers
Speaker 4:  like that glove I mentioned at the beginning, that's a new way of
Speaker 4:  using a computer. If, you boil it all the way down and the way he thinks
Speaker 4:  about it is more explicitly playful and more
Speaker 4:  exploratory instead of just trying to like figure out how to use an app
Speaker 4:  most effectively to get work done. It's just a totally
Speaker 4:  different approach to all of this stuff. But that can be a hard
Speaker 4:  shift to pull off, I think, to go from trying to learn
Speaker 4:  how to use a technology to figuring out what's
Speaker 4:  possible with it. But that shift, that transition is I think
Speaker 4:  what God does all day with his students. So I asked him about
Speaker 4:  it. I saw something that, that you either
Speaker 4:  wrote or said about your music and ai AI class where one of your goals was
Speaker 4:  to teach them how to play with ai. We don't talk about AI that
Speaker 4:  way. What, what does that look like? What does it look like to play with
Speaker 4:  these kinds of systems?
Speaker 6:  Well playing? What does it look like? Well, I ask my students, for example,
Speaker 6:  to build interactive tools with AI that they can
Speaker 6:  deploy into their everyday lives, but also often would involve human
Speaker 6:  interaction. Hmm. My students have built instruments that
Speaker 6:  basically track the opening and closing of your hand to,
Speaker 6:  to, to generate singing sound. And turning your hand changes
Speaker 6:  the pitch of the sound, opening and closing your hand kind of
Speaker 6:  articulates the sound.
Speaker 6:  You can't do that with a prompt based system right now.
Speaker 6:  Right, right. That's not what that's about. But this means you need to un
Speaker 6:  go to the process of learning how to use that instrument. And
Speaker 6:  another one, it's, and it's, it's, it's playful. I mean, that's playful and
Speaker 6:  it's interactive. Another playful one is, one of my students made this thing
Speaker 6:  called auto riz. Okay. It, it, it's a, it's a
Speaker 6:  computer vision system that basically is been trained to
Speaker 6:  classify between like to recognize a seductive look
Speaker 6:  and it plays like cheesy seductive music when it, when it detects
Speaker 6:  it.
Speaker 6:  And that's all it does. It's like by the mission of the creator of
Speaker 6:  auto riz. Like, this is such a, this is so dumb.
Speaker 6:  And yet it's really, it's playful. Yeah. It's, it's,
Speaker 6:  and and, and the definition of play is actually something that is
Speaker 6:  not about the outcome, it's about the process. Right.
Speaker 6:  Right. Because If, you are like, I'm playing, but if you're worried about
Speaker 6:  the outcome that's gonna be produced, well that's like, that's work
Speaker 6:  actually. If, you need to walk away from an, an activity with a productive
Speaker 6:  outcome. That's, we'd usually call that work, but play is
Speaker 6:  almost exactly the opposite of that.
Speaker 4:  Right. There's, there's a difference I hadn't really thought about
Speaker 4:  there between thinking about these technologies,
Speaker 4:  AI or otherwise as tools versus thinking about them as instruments.
Speaker 4:  And I think we talk about AI in particular as a, as a tool, right? It is,
Speaker 4:  it is a hammer and your job is to go find nails. And, and that's, that's
Speaker 4:  what it's for. and we don't necessarily know what all the nails are, and
Speaker 4:  that's the exploratory phase, but you're looking for nails. But what you're
Speaker 4:  describing is something very different, which is like, here, here is a thing
Speaker 4:  with a set of capabilities, right. It it can, it can, it can do a
Speaker 4:  bunch of things. And where all of the interesting stuff
Speaker 4:  lies is figuring out what
Speaker 4:  to do with those things and how they mix together
Speaker 4:  and new unexpected combinations of those
Speaker 4:  capabilities that turns into something which is so different from I have
Speaker 4:  a hammer that hits nails and I have to find more nails.
Speaker 6:  I go find more nails. Yeah. Right. Let's, let's put it this way. Let's say
Speaker 6:  we make a Venn diagram, which means let's draw a circle. And that circle
Speaker 6:  represents us that, that the sets of things that we, the AI is potentially
Speaker 6:  good at doing Sure. Or would be good at doing. Let's draw another circle.
Speaker 6:  Let's call that a set of things that humans do wanna do and are
Speaker 6:  perhaps can be good at doing like ping pong or making music or
Speaker 6:  whatnot. And the Venn diagrams that, let's draw these two circles, but that's
Speaker 6:  also, they're intersecting. So there's a region where it's in,
Speaker 6:  basically in space where it's in both circles. It's the stuff that humans
Speaker 6:  are good at doing and AI will be good at doing. I feel like we're kind of
Speaker 6:  automatically and almost unquestionably
Speaker 6:  stuck in that intersection with ai, is that we're
Speaker 6:  constantly looking for things that humans already do. And now we
Speaker 6:  just want to have a AI do that same thing.
Speaker 6:  And in fact, the more the, the quote unquote better an
Speaker 6:  AI can do it, the, the more progress surely that this must be,
Speaker 6:  you know, this, some have called this the touring trap. Actually. It's this
Speaker 6:  idea that we have been set down this
Speaker 6:  path where progress in AI is judged by how
Speaker 6:  indistinguishable a system is to humans.
Speaker 6:  Right. And the danger of that is that that becomes kind of the
Speaker 6:  dominant and perhaps almost the only way we can imagine of
Speaker 6:  thinking about progress in ai. But If, you go back to the Venn diagram, there's
Speaker 6:  a whole region, what AI could potentially do that is good at doing
Speaker 6:  that does not intersect with a sphere, the realm of things that humans are
Speaker 6:  good at doing. You know, how do we explore that perhaps far
Speaker 6:  more vast region of what AI can do?
Speaker 6:  I think that takes exploration, takes play, it takes imagination. And I think,
Speaker 6:  and often in my courses, what we learned is that actually when you
Speaker 6:  remove this external obligation to be useful
Speaker 6:  or competitive, and you can simply be yourself and play,
Speaker 6:  you actually produce things that are so different potentially.
Speaker 6:  Hmm. Arguably will certainly be different, but probably also like that's
Speaker 6:  gonna be more, you more expressive. So the, in my
Speaker 6:  courses, I'm trying to help people use ai, but to try to explore the
Speaker 6:  unexplored space, but also explore the space where AI and humans intersect.
Speaker 6:  But AI is doing things that humans aren't doing. Humans are
Speaker 6:  doing things that AI aren't doing, and it's not about a collision
Speaker 6:  or the actual overlap, but about a kind of like a, A-A-A-A-A
Speaker 6:  critically thought through, but, but like a, like a beneficial amalgamation.
Speaker 6:  Hmm. A a a union of, of two different parts.
Speaker 6:  And what I like about that, even though it's not the way we think of
Speaker 6:  ai, is you, you've, as you're noting what I like about that is it,
Speaker 6:  you know, it, it still keeps human curation and I would say human intention
Speaker 6:  and also what we might call human wisdom
Speaker 6:  in the loop. You know? And, and the idea is that if AI could just generate
Speaker 6:  me, even if it's a new piece of music, but I don't have, you know, the provenance
Speaker 6:  as you said of like, where did this come from? What was the story behind
Speaker 6:  this?
Speaker 6:  I did not come up with this, but I re and I can, I do know who said this,
Speaker 6:  but it's been said by someone, it's on, on, on what the
Speaker 6:  role of art is. The idea that art perhaps is this thing that
Speaker 6:  humans endeavor to try to understand their emotions,
Speaker 6:  but mostly they fail at that. Mm. But that's art, you know, it's a thing
Speaker 6:  we, we try mostly fail at to try to understand ourselves.
Speaker 6:  And so if we, we, we feel like that's, you know, that's what
Speaker 6:  art could be,
Speaker 6:  then yes, the provenance matters and matters
Speaker 6:  fundamentally
Speaker 6:  to know what is trying to be communicated, what is trying to be expressed
Speaker 6:  or even more so. And, you know, if we think of art as a, as a like a lens
Speaker 6:  to see things, you know, if I, if I make a piece of art isn't
Speaker 6:  just saying, Hey, this is what I see, you know? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's part of what the artist perhaps sees, but it's also
Speaker 6:  an invitation for the experiencer to say, well, If you,
Speaker 6:  like, you can look through this lens too, and you see the world around, you
Speaker 6:  see yourself and what do you make of it? Hmm. Now that's,
Speaker 6:  that's, you know, a, a good piece of writing is absolutely
Speaker 6:  that, you know, good art in any medium I think is, is
Speaker 6:  is also a lens, but there's film writing music,
Speaker 6:  and so that requires this, I think the human
Speaker 6:  in the loop, if we buy that definition that artists, this,
Speaker 6:  this thing we do to try to mostly try and fail to understand our own
Speaker 6:  motions.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I will say my, my worry with
Speaker 4:  that way of thinking about it would be that AI in particular
Speaker 4:  runs the risk of kind of undermining that. Because
Speaker 4:  if If you think about AI as sort of the, the like lowest
Speaker 4:  common denominator of all of its training data, what
Speaker 4:  you're getting is basically this mush of all of
Speaker 4:  its inputs that is kind of going to
Speaker 4:  give you mush back and it's gonna give everyone the same kind of mush.
Speaker 4:  and we end up in this place where, okay, you, you have this collaborator
Speaker 4:  that has incredible access to incredible amounts of information,
Speaker 4:  but it, the, like, it it, that's actually not useful in some of the ways
Speaker 4:  that you're talking about that maybe having access
Speaker 4:  to every song ever made is actually a hindrance to making great new songs
Speaker 4:  instead of just making the same kinds of songs that are the average
Speaker 4:  of every other song ever made before.
Speaker 6:  Well it, it's, I mean the, what you're saying is that it's, it's still,
Speaker 6:  it's exactly square in that region of the intersection. That's
Speaker 6:  true.
Speaker 4:  I'm still in the middle of the Venn diagram. You're
Speaker 6:  Still right. That's really in, you're the middle of that Venn diagram. That's,
Speaker 6:  that's kind of where we are in a way that's like artists, all the
Speaker 6:  artists I know generally don't want AI to, maybe they want help
Speaker 6:  to do part of their work, but they don't want AI to do the work
Speaker 6:  in the moment that core writing part is actually done. For me,
Speaker 6:  the activity ceases to be like an activity. It just, it's just
Speaker 6:  like a checkbox. Right. And what meaning I might
Speaker 6:  derive from the activity as time consuming as activity may be,
Speaker 6:  is I think as, as you articulated, is the worries that
Speaker 6:  that would be lost. You know, that that, that meaning
Speaker 6:  and the meaning of doing that activity may be lost. And I think it is
Speaker 6:  this way of thinking that I think that we're talking about is very much counter
Speaker 6:  to the prevalent thinking in ai, which is, I I unfortunately,
Speaker 6:  I I I'd say is unquestioning uncritical
Speaker 6:  like race for optimization race to like,
Speaker 6:  for AI to outperform humans without asking what do we really want from that?
Speaker 6:  And when is that actually good? And when is that not good?
Speaker 4:  Okay. We have to take one more break and then we're gonna talk about where
Speaker 4:  everything is headed from here. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  We're back, I don't know if I'm saying this now to warn you
Speaker 4:  or to get you excited or maybe a little bit of both, but
Speaker 4:  things in this conversation are about to get pretty head until now.
Speaker 4:  We've been talking a lot about what you might call capital a art stuff that
Speaker 4:  is explicitly creative done for the sake of creativity.
Speaker 4:  I think that stuff encounters one set of issues as we look to AI
Speaker 4:  and the future of technology. But then all the way on the other
Speaker 4:  side of the spectrum, you have like navigating government
Speaker 4:  bureaucracy and filling out forms. One thing God mentioned to me was
Speaker 4:  figuring out the healthcare system, terrific use of ai, right? I think
Speaker 4:  that's the kind of stuff that almost everyone would be psyched to turn
Speaker 4:  over to some kind of machine. There are tough questions about
Speaker 4:  whether those machines are good enough to be trusted, how we can rely on
Speaker 4:  them, how they fit into businesses, all that stuff. But in general, that
Speaker 4:  feels like a good use of technology. And then there is this
Speaker 4:  whole messy middle where it's stuff like, I don't know, writing
Speaker 4:  emails. There is something meaningfully human about
Speaker 4:  writing an email to your team at work, but all these AI tools
Speaker 4:  are promising to write that email for you. But then on the other side
Speaker 4:  there, AI tool is saying they'll summarize it for you and at some point it's
Speaker 4:  like, what are we even doing here? Are there any humans in this loop
Speaker 4:  anymore at all? So maybe the three parts of the spectrum here
Speaker 4:  are art, life and nonsense. We're happy to give up nonsense
Speaker 4:  to technology, we're reluctant to give up art and I guess it's
Speaker 4:  case by case on life. So how do we draw the lines
Speaker 4:  between those things though? And how do we decide where it's worth outsourcing
Speaker 4:  and offloading and embracing AI and where we shouldn't? And then maybe
Speaker 4:  most importantly, how do we protect the stuff that's worth protecting
Speaker 4:  on that spectrum? That is the next question I asked. Go Wong.
Speaker 4:  He answered by talking about email.
Speaker 6:  So this is actually the other thing that maybe we don't think about. Like,
Speaker 6:  first of all, I don't, for me, I remember the first time I used an email,
Speaker 6:  it was when I first got to college in 1996, this was the Duke University.
Speaker 6:  And I got an email account and I was like, oh dang, this
Speaker 6:  is so convenient. And I wrote my dad, I was like, dad,
Speaker 6:  oh, I'm writing you an email. I don't have anything to say. I don't write
Speaker 6:  you an email. Okay. Bye. It was like an email with no purpose except to say
Speaker 6:  I'm, I, it's so fun to email. I don't know anyone today who is like,
Speaker 6:  email is so fun. No, no, no. This is, that was, that was
Speaker 6:  1996 for me now in 2024 where like, and also
Speaker 6:  email's not something I do my job without. Right. In fact, this
Speaker 6:  interview was set up through email. Yeah. In fact, I imagine you probably
Speaker 6:  like me, are are are inundated by emails and unfortunately on like a
Speaker 6:  yes unfortunately So I thing that was fun and useful and
Speaker 6:  convenient to begin with because of that
Speaker 6:  convenience. You know, you would think like, oh, it's a labor saving thing.
Speaker 6:  Hmm. And it was for email, but because that labor was
Speaker 6:  saved and we are all using it, we've all saved that labor. Suddenly
Speaker 6:  it's like, oh, we have more time to do well more work. Like
Speaker 6:  between now and say. When you first used email, do you feel like your
Speaker 6:  work has gotten any lighter or any easier? No. No. I
Speaker 6:  don't either. No.
Speaker 4:  All of the studies on this are so alarming that it's like you go back and
Speaker 4:  everybody is like, oh, due to all the increased efficiencies,
Speaker 4:  we're all gonna work for like six hours a week. And it's like, yeah, I do
Speaker 4:  the job y'all used to do in six hours a week and now I have 40 other hours
Speaker 4:  of stuff to do.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And maybe it's like almost, it's like, I mean there's so many different
Speaker 6:  reasons why that is not like, yeah. It's like, oh, now this thing is
Speaker 6:  so, so, so if we apply that analogy to AI and just email
Speaker 6:  today, it's like, if AI does save us more time on the email,
Speaker 6:  does, do you think that'll just give us more time to actually, I don't know,
Speaker 6:  live our lives to make our cook be with our family?
Speaker 6:  You know, go outside. No, I, IIII would
Speaker 6:  be very not Yeah. Like given like where we are with email, I
Speaker 6:  would, I would be very skeptical of of that possibility.
Speaker 6:  I think, however, what might happen is unfortunately with
Speaker 6:  LLMs and kind of this generative AI technologies that we
Speaker 6:  might produce, not just email, but like writing that is deemed good enough
Speaker 6:  for a certain purpose and now we just need to hire less people to do them.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. For example, and this now starting going back in that creative realm,
Speaker 6:  like for example, like script writing for a TV show,
Speaker 6:  you know, and I I I, I have a, I have an uncle who has been in the industry.
Speaker 6:  He, he lives near LA and he, he was talking about, you know, there was a
Speaker 6:  time when the writing room for a TV show would actually be on
Speaker 6:  set talking to, you know, the, the the production team, the, the, the
Speaker 6:  actors. And in that process actually
Speaker 6:  really got both everyone involved to even be like, really figure out what
Speaker 6:  this is about, what each pers each character actually could be about.
Speaker 6:  It opens up all kinds of imagination for where things
Speaker 6:  could go. And then you have the case where, well now we just hire
Speaker 6:  like a kind of interchangeable room of human writers to
Speaker 6:  write like kind of each episode. And in fact we'll get, we'll do the lowest
Speaker 6:  bidder. And then with AI you can kinda imagine, well now
Speaker 6:  that labor has been saved, well we don't need to hire even those interchangeable
Speaker 6:  room of writers. Right. Instead, let's have one person who prompts and
Speaker 6:  oversees and curates the output of the AI system.
Speaker 6:  And the result might not be good, but it might be good
Speaker 6:  enough Yep. To make entertainment
Speaker 6:  that people will pay for. And I think that's a huge,
Speaker 6:  well it's a huge loss of livelihood, but also a huge cultural loss
Speaker 6:  in terms of the kind of art that is being made.
Speaker 6:  'cause now we have shows that we'll be like, well that's entertaining, but
Speaker 6:  is a real, like, entertaining doesn't mean it's good
Speaker 6:  entertaining doesn't mean it's, it's thoughtful or
Speaker 6:  interesting or, or you know, all of or playful. It just means it's
Speaker 6:  something. Okay. It's better than being bored. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's something
Speaker 6:  To do. It's, it's content, it's TikTok to use. Yeah. It's like, it's, yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's use this dreaded like content word, which just means
Speaker 6:  stuff that you can do. And you know, I think the fear
Speaker 6:  is that we'd have, we live in a world where we'd have
Speaker 6:  content that is serviceable
Speaker 6:  often, but that may be sublime never. You know,
Speaker 6:  and, and that's a, a a world of generic and
Speaker 6:  age of generic. And yes, we, a lot of kind of our
Speaker 6:  popular culture is things that are already kind of generic
Speaker 6:  things right now the generic things are still made by humans. Right, right.
Speaker 6:  But like yeah,
Speaker 4:  Humans can do bad work too. It is, we're we're just as bad as anything.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yes. But at least like, but if we make, we have
Speaker 6:  machines do all of that, how does that change the truly like
Speaker 6:  sublime, the truly expressive things that humans still do? Will
Speaker 6:  that how I can, I don't know how I'll alter, but I can't imagine this not
Speaker 6:  altering it. Yeah. Right. I, I think, and then on this
Speaker 6:  point of where this intersects with livelihood, you know, I think
Speaker 6:  the fear among a lot of artists, you know, myself
Speaker 6:  included, if I, if I were to count myself as an artist, yes. Part of that
Speaker 6:  is that is livelihood, but it's not only livelihood.
Speaker 6:  The fear isn't just that we'd be replaced by a machine.
Speaker 6:  The fear is that we'd be replaced by something that is far more generic
Speaker 6:  and far less interesting. But that's acceptable
Speaker 6:  to the, the, the, the powers that that be because good
Speaker 6:  enough is it might be good enough to make someone a lot of money.
Speaker 4:  Right.
Speaker 6:  Right. That's the larger fear of, of it's not, isn't just
Speaker 6:  livelihood lost, that's a huge issue, but livelihood lost
Speaker 6:  in favor of something that's actually more generic and less interesting.
Speaker 6:  That seems like undesirable on like multiple levels
Speaker 4:  That maybe our standards go down far enough that we don't care
Speaker 4:  anymore,
Speaker 6:  Our standards go down. Yeah. We don't care anymore. And also that people
Speaker 6:  that otherwise have tried to, it's difficult that it is
Speaker 6:  to pursue any kind of art that there may not, may
Speaker 6:  not be room to do that anymore.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 6:  Even if someone wanted to.
Speaker 4:  Well, and I think it, it, it strikes me that that comes all the way back
Speaker 4:  around to the idea of how to approach these tools,
Speaker 4:  right? Because I think the, the sort of glass half full version of
Speaker 4:  that future you just described is that actually rather than using
Speaker 4:  AI to pull everything down to this lowest common
Speaker 4:  denominator average of everything, we learn to play it like an
Speaker 4:  instrument and we learn to use it to expand that Venn diagram and this whole
Speaker 4:  universe of things that we can't do, but we learn how to do
Speaker 4:  with this tool. Like that If you If you wanna paint like a beautiful future
Speaker 4:  of ai. It's, it's that sort of spirit of play that you're
Speaker 4:  describing comes to everyone in all disciplines of ai,
Speaker 4:  right? Like that's, that's the hope. That's the only thing that might work.
Speaker 6:  That would be nice except, I mean there, but there's every reason unfortunately
Speaker 6:  to, to, to think about the challenges to that scenario where everyone has
Speaker 6:  a tools to play. One is just human nature itself, including my own,
Speaker 6:  which is the kind of playfulness we're talking about is
Speaker 6:  actually investment. Yes. Of time and effort
Speaker 6:  and probably a lot of frustration and confusion. It's part of the process
Speaker 6:  of doing anything I think worthwhile that you, you
Speaker 6:  derive meaning from whether there's a difficult video game or learning a
Speaker 6:  new thing or getting better at an instrument. All of these things come with
Speaker 6:  its, its challenge or, or like basically climbing up to, to to, to a mountain,
Speaker 6:  right? I say climbing the mountain and the other C cha. So that's one
Speaker 6:  challenge is that we actually like, you know, we actually, we need a
Speaker 6:  supportive environment where we do actually can do that, have the time
Speaker 6:  and to do that and, and have the will and the desire,
Speaker 6:  the motivation to do that. But as, as we're saying, like life is
Speaker 6:  not getting easier for, for, for most people. In fact, it's kind of getting
Speaker 6:  harder for most people. And I would love for that timeline to come to pass.
Speaker 6:  But it's, it's difficult. It's, it's, it's increasingly a higher and higher
Speaker 6:  privilege to be able to have time to do things just because,
Speaker 6:  you know, that's, that's the, the, the hard part of our reality.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And it's only gonna get harder. For example, like I mentioned, the
Speaker 6:  instrument where you use your hand and computer vision and AI to kind of
Speaker 6:  track the opening and closing your hand to, to sing
Speaker 6:  that needs a different way to think about AI that needs a
Speaker 6:  different human computer interaction. That is perhaps not,
Speaker 6:  I'm not saying get rid of prompt based engineering. I'm saying yes,
Speaker 6:  there should be room for this other ways of working with ai. That's,
Speaker 6:  that's interactively at the very least different and actually speaks to all
Speaker 6:  these other dimensions of, of who we are, including our bodies, our physical
Speaker 6:  bodies, but also all the, all the things that, that that humans
Speaker 6:  are, you know, or could be our capacities. They should be more
Speaker 6:  comprehensively considered in in how we do.
Speaker 6:  Unfortunately, I think there's way more evidence
Speaker 6:  to the contrary that AI is not headed in a
Speaker 6:  direction of inclusion, rather extraction.
Speaker 6:  It's as in how can we extract value from people
Speaker 6:  Yeah. With this thing. And it's not a tool for human
Speaker 6:  wellbeing, it's not a tool for human flourishing. It's a tool for maximizing
Speaker 6:  profit,
Speaker 4:  Which involves removing humans from loops in every exactly possible way.
Speaker 4:  And like you mentioned, all of the easy money in this space is at the middle
Speaker 4:  of that Venn diagram. Like there might be other things in other places
Speaker 4:  someday, but like If, you wanna make a lot of money right now it's at the
Speaker 4:  middle of that Venn diagram and it's, how do I take a job humans used to
Speaker 4:  do and take it away from them?
Speaker 6:  But you don't ask, okay, so now we have this and if everyone actually used
Speaker 6:  this thing like email what now? Right. They don't think
Speaker 6:  that's a cultural question that requires, but no, it's, it's
Speaker 6:  that that's not being considered. And yes, I get, having
Speaker 6:  been a, a startup co-founder, I can get that. It's nev
Speaker 6:  starting a business, a startup or running a business is not an easy thing.
Speaker 6:  It's an exceedingly difficult thing. I've been there and yet
Speaker 6:  I think with ai there's an like an added dimension of of of
Speaker 6:  just social accountability. Yeah. Because the things you use are gonna
Speaker 6:  be used by people that you are never gonna meet, but whose lives that you
Speaker 6:  will affect and influence, you'll affect not only their lives and
Speaker 6:  affect their communities and affect their families,
Speaker 6:  their kids.
Speaker 6:  And while you may be like, well how do I survive even to the next
Speaker 6:  quarterly call? Yeah, I get it.
Speaker 6:  Been there. But I think there's an added dimension of
Speaker 6:  of of, i I think social responsibility to think what if everyone,
Speaker 6:  it's not just like, what if the things we made went awry? It's
Speaker 6:  like, what are the things I make actually worked and a lot of
Speaker 6:  people used it. Then what, how does that change the very culture
Speaker 6:  we're living in? I think the through line in all of these is kind of this,
Speaker 6:  this question a cri a kind of insistence to
Speaker 6:  critically question what we do and a aesthetic social,
Speaker 6:  cultural dimension in addition to all the other dimensions that I,
Speaker 6:  well I would mention in there and also another through line is, is
Speaker 6:  play and expression. You know, can we help humans
Speaker 6:  feel tools for people to, to feel more like themselves?
Speaker 6:  That's, I think that's what play is and I think if we can do that,
Speaker 6:  I'll take those as victories. You know, if someone is playing music for
Speaker 6:  the fun of it, like inside the room for no, no one for no one
Speaker 6:  in particular, I think that's a win already. And I think there's
Speaker 6:  things that if we just did it actually makes us, you know,
Speaker 6:  in however small ways makes us feel more ourselves. And,
Speaker 6:  and I, that's my, I still hold out hope if only
Speaker 6:  because hope must be there that we can
Speaker 6:  use technology as a tool for perhaps above all for humans
Speaker 6:  to be more themselves, to feel more themselves. And, and,
Speaker 6:  and to do that you need to feel included, feel safe, feel
Speaker 6:  free to be yourselves and I think feel understood, you know, that's, I think
Speaker 6:  that's, that's my hope. But, but it's my gosh, there's so
Speaker 6:  much work to be done and so many challenges and that's not the way that the
Speaker 6:  world is going, but it's, it's a thing that's, I think it's, it's worth,
Speaker 6:  it's worth working towards.
Speaker 4:  Alright, that is it for the first Vergecast Today. Thank you again to Goong
Speaker 4:  for being here and thank you as always for listening. I'll put a whole bunch
Speaker 4:  of links to all the stuff we talked about in the show notes, the Aina app,
Speaker 4:  all the S Mule stuff, the laptop orchestra, some of the funny stuff his students
Speaker 4:  have worked on. We'll put it all in the show notes. You should check it all
Speaker 4:  out. It is weird and I mean that in the best possible way.
Speaker 4:  Also lots more on all of this stuff, future of music and everything else
Speaker 4:  in this series at The Verge dot com. It's a good website. We like it.
Speaker 4:  As always, If you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or other songs that
Speaker 4:  you think I should learn in that Karina app that's really cool. You can always
Speaker 4:  email us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or call the hotline
Speaker 4:  eight six six VERGE one one. If, you have thoughts on anything that God and
Speaker 4:  I talked about today, anything from this whole series, really anything at
Speaker 4:  all? Call us. we love hearing from you. This show is produced by Liam James,
Speaker 4:  Wil Poor and Eric Gomez. The Vergecast is a VERGE production and part of
Speaker 4:  the Vox Media Podcast network. We'll be back with your regularly scheduled
Speaker 4:  programming on Tuesday and Friday. The news just keeps happening,
Speaker 4:  y'all just a lot of news. But I did manage to squeeze in a
Speaker 4:  conversation about 13th Century Florence for Tuesday's
Speaker 4:  episode. So that one's a fun one. We'll see you then. Rock and roll