# Transcript
ID: 7eb3a3de-34c3-4e35-a656-e2c3227d24ee
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7564135760097143623/4104133127964329517/s93290-US-5772s-1731064658.mp3
Description: Nilay and David talk about the election, and how The Vergecast plans to cover and talk about the next four years of the Trump administration. But only for a minute. Then it's onto our reviews of the new Mac Mini and MacBook Pro, which reset Apple's desktop and laptop lineup in an excellent way. After that, Sean Hollister joins the show to discuss his review of the PlayStation 5 Pro, the news about backwards compatibility for the Nintendo Switch successor, and the state of Nintendo's fight against emulators. In the lightning round, we talk about really expensive domain names, oddly named smart home standards, and cloud gaming whales. Which apparently exist.
Speaker 3:  Hello and welcome to our cast. The flagship podcast is spending millions
Speaker 3:  of dollars on domain names. It's, it's cut. We're gonna talk about,
Speaker 3:  it's a real thing that happened. It happens every day. You know, you just
Speaker 3:  dunno about it. And that's why this podcast is hard pivoting away from
Speaker 3:  politics towards the buying and selling of domain names. I'm your
Speaker 3:  friend Neli David Pierce is here.
Speaker 4:  Hello. You know what I love about that is I, I genuinely think we have some
Speaker 4:  real serious competition to be the flagship podcast of the domain buying
Speaker 4:  industry. And this is why I love technology.
Speaker 3:  But you know, they got real estate podcasts out there.
Speaker 4:  That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 3:  We we could we cyber state, is that a word?
Speaker 4:  I wrote a big story a few years ago about like the ongoing
Speaker 4:  primacy of the.com and got to interview
Speaker 4:  some truly fascinating characters. People who just like
Speaker 4:  bought a bunch of TLDs and just like screwed off to the
Speaker 4:  Caribbean and now make millions of dollars selling domain names. It's
Speaker 4:  the greatest.
Speaker 3:  There's we one, we should do this. We should just pivot to this. Yes. So
Speaker 3:  If, you want to front our domain arbitrage business,
Speaker 3:  you know, that's a lightning round sponsorship opportunity. Two, we
Speaker 3:  are gonna talk about a specific domain name later, which is very interesting.
Speaker 3:  And three, the entire.io
Speaker 3:  TLD is like vanishing. Yeah. Which is like a big story
Speaker 3:  because a bunch of crypto and AI startups have.io names.
Speaker 3:  We'll come back to that as well.
Speaker 4:  Do you own any silly domains?
Speaker 3:  You know, I went through a period where I, I had a hover account. Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  that was my form of sports betting
Speaker 3:  and now all those, oh the, the credit cards expired and the domain names
Speaker 3:  went away and so it goes,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, there was a period I would say, of maybe three or four years where
Speaker 4:  every couple of months I would get an email from hover being like, your
Speaker 4:  domain name is about to renew. Do you wanna renew it? And it would be straight
Speaker 4:  up for a domain. I had completely forgotten that I owned. So that's all
Speaker 4:  I had. I had a phase, I would say it was like a, it was like a shopping phase
Speaker 4:  and I bought a bunch of domains and now they are slowly winnowing
Speaker 4:  away but I still own a bunch of them. I bought a domain for
Speaker 4:  Anna to write her like a thing for her birthday one year. It was one of
Speaker 4:  the coolest thing I ever did. So she just has her own website that is just
Speaker 4:  like a love letter. I wrote to my wife one time.
Speaker 3:  Aw, that's very sweet.
Speaker 4:  Coolest thing I ever did. And now I paid 10 bucks a year and I guarantee
Speaker 4:  you she hasn't looked at it in five years just wasting money. Now
Speaker 3:  You gotta bring it up like every anniversary. Yeah, exactly. Do you know
Speaker 3:  how as you get older you realize like the deep lore of your friends is just
Speaker 3:  that you were jerks like If, you like look at it with fresh eyes. You're
Speaker 3:  like we were just pretty mean to each other. We, I had a friend.
Speaker 4:  That's how men interact. That's what we
Speaker 3:  Do. Pretty much. I had a friend, they dated as a person,
Speaker 3:  this person not very bright and thought the word debacle was debacle.
Speaker 3:  And I owned debacle.com for a long time
Speaker 3:  and I couldn't make it a thing because ultimately the core of it
Speaker 3:  was just being mean to someone. You can be like, I got this great story about
Speaker 3:  debacle and you're like, no, you're just a jerk.
Speaker 4:  I think we're past the statute of limitations on it though. It's time to,
Speaker 4:  it's time to really turn that
Speaker 3:  Everyone, everyone is like long since married. Yeah, but I'm just saying
Speaker 3:  I'm just prefer I'm, I'm putting around that story, the self-awareness.
Speaker 3:  Yeah that was just the heart of your friend's lore sometimes is
Speaker 3:  like, oh you are super rude when you were 25 years old.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. That's how it goes. Alright. Right. We got a lot talk about there's
Speaker 3:  new Mac minis, there's PS five pros, there's
Speaker 3:  upgrades to the matter standards. I got a lightning round and we on sponsored.
Speaker 3:  We should start with the obvious news in America
Speaker 3:  today, which is that I think I know when the Jeep Wagoner
Speaker 3:  ass is coming.
Speaker 4:  That's exactly where I thought you were going. This is good. I'm glad we're
Speaker 4:  on the same page here today.
Speaker 3:  I've, I've gotten wind that it's December. So If you're in the market for
Speaker 3:  Jeep's first ev it may or may not be December. No it's obviously the election.
Speaker 3:  It happened on Tuesday. It's a big deal. Donald Trump won. Again If you haven't
Speaker 3:  heard, we're not gonna dwell on it too much. We didn't dwell on the fact
Speaker 3:  that I wrote an endorsement of Harris last week. We try to keep
Speaker 3:  politics off of this show. I have a whole other show to ran
Speaker 3:  to my politics. So we can do that over there. I will say, you know, we have
Speaker 3:  a big audience. I'm sure some people are very happy. I know a lot of our
Speaker 3:  audience is very upset. We're gonna cover Trump the same way we
Speaker 3:  covered him the first time, which is he's gonna make a bunch of decisions.
Speaker 3:  A lot of them will be tech policy decisions and this time around we
Speaker 3:  have a bunch of familiarity with how he approaches tech policy
Speaker 3:  and so do the big companies, right? The big companies, their CEOs are all
Speaker 3:  writing him congratulatory notes. Jeff Bezos is like, throw
Speaker 3:  me a blue origin contract. Tim Cook probably doesn't want
Speaker 3:  20% tariffs on the iPhone. Right? Elon Musk
Speaker 3:  wants side loading to happen on the iPhone. This is a thing that he has said
Speaker 3:  that the app store review process is censorship.
Speaker 3:  This is a lot of competing tech billionaire stuff in a very
Speaker 3:  transactional way with a character they're familiar with. And it's gonna
Speaker 3:  lead us to covering a lot of stories. Just the tariffs alone.
Speaker 3:  Most of our products are not made in the United States. Right. The idea that
Speaker 3:  we can instantly impose tariffs and have that manufacturing move here
Speaker 3:  seems farfetched.
Speaker 3:  If you'll recall the last time this man tried to move technology manufacturing
Speaker 3:  to the United States of America, we spent a lot of time pointing out buildings
Speaker 3:  in Wisconsin were empty some familiarity.
Speaker 4:  How many weeks do you think it's been at this point since
Speaker 3:  Google announced a website for the track? One of the first things happened
Speaker 3:  in Trump won was Congress immediately repealed a rule
Speaker 3:  that imposed privacy regulations on ISPs. And then we made a
Speaker 3:  character If, you will recall out of a Jeep Pi I I know who the new character
Speaker 3:  it's gonna be. It's gonna be Brendan Carr. He, he wants to be the head of
Speaker 3:  the FCC. It's every like in all likelihood he will be, we wrote a
Speaker 3:  profile of him in the 2020 election 'cause he very much was advocating for
Speaker 3:  the FCC to be in charge of section two 30, which kind of makes no sense.
Speaker 3:  It's all gonna happen again, right? So we're gonna just cover
Speaker 3:  the world as it stands and the people and the characters are doing stuff
Speaker 3:  in that world. Sometimes that will I think cross over to the show. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Many times. I I care a lot about broadband deployment. I
Speaker 3:  I know our audience does too. We talk about the FCCA lot on this show. It's,
Speaker 3:  it's all just gonna happen again and we'll bring it up on the show as it's
Speaker 3:  relevant. But I don't think we're gonna make this a show about Donald
Speaker 3:  Trump's tweets. Does that make any sense? No.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I I think, I mean you mentioned kind of what we've learned versus the
Speaker 4:  last time we did this and I think one big change is
Speaker 4:  we're just clearer on what's real and what isn't. And I think this is true
Speaker 4:  of any political situation that like the, the question of
Speaker 4:  what someone says and what is real are very rarely the same thing. And
Speaker 4:  I would say it's just that the volume with Trump is so much higher.
Speaker 4:  And so we've, we've learned in in ways how to sort of suss
Speaker 4:  out what matters and what doesn't. But I think like it or not, like
Speaker 4:  I chose not to become a political reporter on purpose and yet we are at a,
Speaker 4:  at a moment in time where like I think you could argue that tech
Speaker 4:  companies and in particular a handful of big tech companies are going to
Speaker 4:  be more central both to the
Speaker 4:  running of the government itself but also like what
Speaker 4:  the, that government is interested in than ever. And I mean
Speaker 4:  you look at what Elon Musk has been in the Trump campaign already. Like these
Speaker 4:  things are intermingled in ways they've never been before.
Speaker 4:  And I think part of what we're gonna have to do is both figure out
Speaker 4:  what all of that means and try to cover the ramifications
Speaker 4:  for regular people, right? Because it all, so much of it is
Speaker 4:  yelling and political nonsense and like I think we don't,
Speaker 4:  this show in particular, we try really hard not to care about that.
Speaker 4:  But like this stuff is going to matter in every other thing that
Speaker 4:  we cover in new ways and I think we have to figure that
Speaker 4:  out.
Speaker 3:  I'll just keep giving examples 'cause I think that's a useful way to talk
Speaker 3:  about it. The Google antitrust case where they're paying Apple to be the
Speaker 3:  default. That's case started in the first Trump administration, right? It
Speaker 3:  got finished in the Biden administration. I'm sure Apple wants the new Trump
Speaker 3:  DOJ to drop the antitrust case against them. But I am equally sure
Speaker 3:  that Andreessen Horowitz, which promotes what it calls the little tech agenda
Speaker 3:  and which spent a bunch of money on Donald Trump wants that case to be
Speaker 3:  pursued to the finish line 'cause they would love to side load crypto apps
Speaker 3:  onto the iPhone. There's just a lot there. I have no
Speaker 3:  idea how it's going to shake out, but just to bring
Speaker 3:  it all back around, the fact that there is this week a p os emulator
Speaker 3:  on the iPhone is the result of government action. Yeah. Like
Speaker 3:  there's just a lot of stuff that is true about the products we use and how
Speaker 3:  they work and how they work together that is related to what happens over
Speaker 3:  there. and we just have, keep an eye on it because all of these people are
Speaker 3:  gonna start kind of nakedly lobbying the Trump administration
Speaker 3:  and their interests aren't actually aligned. So there's just a lot of sort
Speaker 3:  of inherent conflict which will result in stories and then I think
Speaker 3:  ultimately result in changes to the products that we all use that we like
Speaker 3:  to talk about in the show. Yep. There's a whole bunch of other stuff and
Speaker 3:  we will bring it up when it's necessary. I'm eager to hear from everyone.
Speaker 3:  We have all gone through this together before. Yeah. Like If, you want me
Speaker 3:  to just start roasting foxcon every day? Like I, I can deliver, I just
Speaker 3:  don't want to scream into the void for four years. So let us know. We got
Speaker 3:  email addresses, we got voicemail lines. We want to yell at me personally.
Speaker 3:  I'll, I'll take it. We are here to serve the audience but
Speaker 3:  we're gonna, we're gonna try to figure this one out and make sure we are
Speaker 3:  constructive as opposed to just being noisy. If that makes any
Speaker 3:  sense.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Alright. Hard pivot away from presidential politics.
Speaker 3:  Let's talk about some tiny computers. Tiny computers. Speaking of
Speaker 3:  20% tariffs, the Mac Mini now cost $5,000
Speaker 3:  but it's made by hand in your bedroom.
Speaker 3:  That joke has layers. I'm just putting an After that joke has layers.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, there's somewhere in North Carolina I think
Speaker 4:  there either is or is not a factory.
Speaker 3:  Mark Robinson has been sentenced to manufacturing the, the Mac
Speaker 3:  Mini in your bed.
Speaker 3:  All right. All the Macs came out last week. They were announced last week.
Speaker 3:  We have reviews the M four Mac mini, the MacBook Pro 14, we
Speaker 3:  have the baseball review and Tony is reviewing the high-end model. Let's
Speaker 3:  start with the Mac mini. Chris Welch reviewed it, he's in love. I,
Speaker 3:  as I was reading his review, I had to stop myself from buying a computer.
Speaker 3:  I don't need
Speaker 4:  Same, I I haven't fully stopped myself yet. I still
Speaker 4:  have it in my cart but I'm not looking at the tab anymore. So I'm considering
Speaker 4:  that a victory. But I would say by the time you're
Speaker 4:  listening to this, there is like an over 90% chance that I have
Speaker 4:  bought this Mac mini. I mean they did it. It is the thing, right? It is,
Speaker 4:  it is what we hoped it would be. And I think
Speaker 4:  the, the one thing I've been surprised by actually is
Speaker 4:  how much smaller it actually is And, and it seems to like
Speaker 4:  be meaningfully different in terms of like where you can put it and how it
Speaker 4:  fits on your desk and like the little places you can stash it and for
Speaker 4:  something like this, which is a designed to be a computer you mostly never
Speaker 4:  like touch or look at or interact with. That does matter, right?
Speaker 4:  I think I still don't know that that is like the most important thing in
Speaker 4:  the universe. I don't think you should upgrade just to get a slightly smaller
Speaker 4:  Mac mini.
Speaker 4:  But also everything else about it is good. The performance is right.
Speaker 4:  It has a lot of io. I've heard a couple of people say they wish the front
Speaker 4:  ports were thunderbolt instead of just regular USBC. The back ones are thunderbolt
Speaker 4:  but fine. Like this thing is $600. And I think in, in
Speaker 4:  a time when Apple products are are getting, I would say a
Speaker 4:  more expensive at dubious additional value, this one
Speaker 4:  is like a, just an unabashed victory.
Speaker 3:  I think Chris's line is this is easily the best value in the entire MAC lineup.
Speaker 3:  Now I think
Speaker 4:  That's probably true
Speaker 3:  And the thing that really cements it for me is the base model. The $600 one
Speaker 3:  has 16 gigs of ram, which has kept me from buying
Speaker 3:  a Mac for quite some time, right? Mm. You go, I go into the configurator,
Speaker 3:  I look at eight gigs of RAM in the default I go add the RAM to get to 16
Speaker 3:  gigs. And then I'm always like, this is so expensive. This is the most expensive
Speaker 3:  ram in history. I'm not buying this dumb computer. Right? And I just have
Speaker 4:  It. Which is still true by the way. Every, every one of the upgrades on all
Speaker 4:  of these new MacBooks and is like lunacy.
Speaker 4:  It's like I, I know what these things cost and you're trying to charge me
Speaker 4:  200 bucks for a little more storage. Like
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah you have it. Chris has it in the review. You can buy two base model
Speaker 3:  MAC minis for a dollar less than,
Speaker 4:  Than the upgraded
Speaker 3:  One. Than the upgraded
Speaker 4:  One. That's so stupid.
Speaker 3:  Yes. You can buy two base model MAC minis with 16 gigs of
Speaker 3:  RAM and 256 gig SSDs for the price that
Speaker 3:  costs to upgrade a single Mac mini to 32 gigs of RAM and 512
Speaker 3:  gigs of storage. It's actually a dollar less.
Speaker 4:  That's just, that's stupid. But again, to your point, the good
Speaker 4:  news is, and I think this is true of both the MAC Mini and the new
Speaker 4:  MacBook Pro, which we should also talk about is that the base model is excellent
Speaker 4:  and I think Apple, apple for years has given you base models
Speaker 4:  that are like almost there. But that you, you always kind of want
Speaker 4:  one step up from the base model. Yeah. Of almost every Apple product. The
Speaker 4:  thing they try to sell you is the one level up. Either it was like the iPad
Speaker 4:  that only had 64 gigs of storage or this one that had eight gigs of ram,
Speaker 4:  which is a perfectly fine amount of ram. No super wrong. It's not what so
Speaker 4:  like how
Speaker 3:  Will you unleash the power of Apple intelligence with only eight gigs of
Speaker 3:  ram
Speaker 3:  my friend?
Speaker 4:  Very few things have made me feel more vindicated than everybody getting
Speaker 4:  access to Apple Intelligence. But, but this time
Speaker 4:  these are the right models for most people. The base model is
Speaker 4:  the one that most people should buy and I think that's very much to Apple's
Speaker 4:  credit that like it, it just built the computer people should have and If,
Speaker 4:  you just click buy and don't check any other boxes. You're going to get an
Speaker 4:  excellent computer.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And what's also great is a bunch of the outgoing computers, like the
Speaker 3:  M two errors and M three errors are being sold now in
Speaker 3:  16 gig base configurations for the same price. Which again I think
Speaker 3:  is because Apple just wants you to use Apple intelligence but is also proof
Speaker 3:  that that extra eight gigs of RAM did never cost them anything. Right.
Speaker 4:  But it is, I I actually think, I mean we for a couple of years
Speaker 4:  I think had a long debate about when the M1
Speaker 4:  came out, right? The M1 MacBook Air and it was like an obvious giant
Speaker 4:  upgrade from the previous ones and then the M two came out and we were kind
Speaker 4:  of like, well maybe the better buy is actually the M1 air
Speaker 4:  which is getting cheaper because the M two is out and and the performance
Speaker 4:  increase isn't necessarily there. And I think that question
Speaker 4:  might be complicated, right? Like is the, is the increase from the
Speaker 4:  M two or the M three to the M four super meaningful? I think the
Speaker 4:  increase from eight gigs to 16 is meaningful. Yeah. Again, eight gigs is
Speaker 4:  fine for most people. That's
Speaker 3:  Super. Isn't the argument by the way. I know, just to lay it out, I'm aware
Speaker 3:  of the argument that David is too embarrassed to make that some of you'll
Speaker 3:  put in the YouTube comments but the disc is so fast that going to swap
Speaker 3:  doesn't really matter. If you have eight gigs of ram. I I know, I know. I'm
Speaker 3:  aware of the argument. Apple executives have looked me in the eye and made
Speaker 3:  the argument and I'm just telling you that it's still not good.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. I'm sitting here on an M1 Mac mini with eight gigs of ram and I
Speaker 4:  can tell you that that argument is not true. And yet eight gigs of RAM is
Speaker 4:  basically fine. Just close some tabs, you'll be fine. But
Speaker 4:  anyway, going to 16 as the base is, is
Speaker 4:  really important. And I actually am, am like eager to now go get my hands
Speaker 4:  on one of the M twos with 16 gigs a couple of years in and
Speaker 4:  see, 'cause we're gonna end up with like, you know, there's the, the Walmart
Speaker 4:  version of it that is deliberately, substantially cheaper and kind of the,
Speaker 4:  the like entry level MacBook Air, when that thing has like an M two and
Speaker 4:  16 gigs of ram that is going to be a very, very compelling computer
Speaker 4:  for a lot of people. And I just think like again, If, you want one
Speaker 4:  of these beastly machines that's gonna last you forever. Like I feel very
Speaker 4:  good about both the air or about both the new pro and the new mini,
Speaker 4:  but especially as we get to this 16 gig of RAM baseline, even
Speaker 4:  a couple of generations old is gonna start to last a really, really long
Speaker 4:  time.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I am, well first of all, the M1
Speaker 3:  air, the Walmart special M1 air is now down to 6 49
Speaker 3:  and it still says built for Apple Intelligence and I just have to, for as
Speaker 3:  little as Apple Intelligence does, it's not gonna go great on that computer.
Speaker 3:  No,
Speaker 4:  I would not buy that If you want an AI machine but given a minute and that
Speaker 4:  thing will be $649 and it will be an M two and it will have 16 gigs of
Speaker 4:  ram, right? Yeah. Like when we get to there, that gets really exciting.
Speaker 3:  Becky has an Intel MacBook Care like a rose gold one and it
Speaker 3:  is dying and I told her today to buy an M three
Speaker 3:  air 16 gigs of RAM for just about a thousand dollars. I think it's a little
Speaker 3:  over a thousand dollars. Like this is the best buy in computing right now.
Speaker 4:  I think that's right.
Speaker 3:  You don't need an M four for the stuff we're doing. No. And this
Speaker 3:  computer is gonna last forever with 16 gigs of Ram So I. It's true that of
Speaker 3:  in the sort of MacBook Air zone picking the chip is sort of not as
Speaker 3:  important as the ram and that the fact that 16 gigs is becoming more prevalent
Speaker 3:  in all of their spots is really good. Yeah. For the Mac Mini
Speaker 3:  this is like, you just push the button. You don't need like, and this is
Speaker 3:  why I've been so close to buying one all day. 'cause they've reduced the
Speaker 3:  pain of like going into the configurator and adding more money to the base
Speaker 3:  price. Right. Genius. It also is proof that that X-ray gigs of RAM cost
Speaker 3:  him nothing.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. That was always just pure naked money grubbing
Speaker 4:  from Apple. The, the one financial question
Speaker 4:  I am dealing with as I go through this is do I spend the extra $200 to get
Speaker 4:  the touch ID keyboard because I'm, I'm sitting here, I have
Speaker 4:  a Logitech keyboard that I really like. I have a, a Logitech mouse that
Speaker 4:  I really like that I will never give up because the Magic Mouse is an awful
Speaker 4:  piece of hardware that no one should use.
Speaker 4:  Touch ID is awesome and goes a very long way. And especially
Speaker 4:  if you're never gonna turn the thing off because the power button is on the
Speaker 4:  bottom, which did not bother Chris Welch at all.
Speaker 4:  It's like the touch ID thing with the Mac Mini goes a really long way.
Speaker 3:  Do you have an Apple watch?
Speaker 4:  I do.
Speaker 3:  So I unlock my Mac with my Apple watch. I've never even thought about needing
Speaker 3:  to unlock it with Oh,
Speaker 4:  That's interesting. I have that set up with my phone, but I actually don't
Speaker 4:  think I have it set up with my Mac.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I sit down at my am mac at home and I just like hit the button and
Speaker 3:  I unlock. It's great. Okay. Alright. That's gonna, I've I've never, unless
Speaker 3:  you wanna buy stuff on your Mac, but I don't, I don't use Safari in that
Speaker 3:  way.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no it's really, it's purely a login thing. Alright. Right. This is
Speaker 4:  good. You've solved this for me. I can keep my, I can keep my computer. Thank
Speaker 4:  you. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  We should talk about the MacBook Pro and it seems Antonio
Speaker 3:  reviewed this one for us. It does seem like Apple finally created some
Speaker 3:  differentiation for the base model MacBook Pro. They've added
Speaker 3:  the correct ports, it has more performance than the air. It's no longer this
Speaker 3:  weird tweener where it was like the base model pro is
Speaker 3:  just for people who don't wanna MacBook Air. Now it's like, oh, this is a
Speaker 3:  meaningfully good computer and then If, you want to go up from there? You
Speaker 3:  can continue to go up from there.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Again, it's back, it's back to the thing of like Apple always wanted
Speaker 4:  you to buy one above the base. And I actually think that was even more true
Speaker 4:  on the pro than others, which like, weirdly, they
Speaker 4:  were caught in between the, the Base Pro had a touch bar for like way
Speaker 4:  too long. And finally it seems like they just sort of scrapped the whole
Speaker 4:  thing. and we like the, the pro line now makes sense in order all
Speaker 4:  the way up. And again, the, the base now starts at
Speaker 4:  I think 1599. Yeah. Clear upgrade from
Speaker 4:  the air in terms of price, but also in terms of like what you get performance
Speaker 4:  wise and all that stuff for battery life. Right Now you've been a pro guy
Speaker 4:  forever, right? Like I'm, I'm an air guy and to me this does not make me
Speaker 4:  wanna a pro anymore. And I suspect for you this is like, this is exactly
Speaker 4:  the pro that I'm looking for and I feel like good for Apple for mostly getting
Speaker 4:  that right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I think, I think that's correct. I I mean I, I have,
Speaker 3:  I'm a 15 inch I guess now it's 16 inch laptop person
Speaker 3:  and always have been. So again, you know, Becky needed a computer and I was
Speaker 3:  like, you should just get a new medical care. And it never crossed my mind
Speaker 3:  to say, oh, you should spend a little bit more money on the pro. Whereas
Speaker 3:  before that was always kinda like, yeah, it's like a, it's a little bit more
Speaker 3:  money. It was like, it's sort of 13 9 9 or something right before 29. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I think that's right. And you get 'em on sale and it was like slightly better
Speaker 3:  and the screen was a little better and the performance was basically the
Speaker 3:  same. Like they really did, I think for one minute the
Speaker 3:  M1 pro and the M1 air, the difference was the pro had a fan
Speaker 3:  so it didn't throttle as hard. Yeah, that's right. And that was the entire
Speaker 3:  performance difference in these computers. Yeah. And so they were just like
Speaker 3:  smushed together. And now I think Apple has enough M series chips
Speaker 3:  in enough configurations and enough display configurations to
Speaker 3:  meaningfully differentiate the products. And so, you know, eventually
Speaker 3:  there'll be an, is there an M four air? There's not M four air.
Speaker 4:  No, I got Right.
Speaker 3:  So, you know, eventually there'll be an M four error, but then they'll put
Speaker 3:  an M five in the pro and like now they just have enough products
Speaker 3:  like at every level of the computer to actually pull them apart and create
Speaker 3:  differentiation. And I think that M four Pro, if you're,
Speaker 3:  you know, a college student who's interested in editing video or like doing
Speaker 3:  photos like this thing is a meaningful improvement over the air without breaking
Speaker 3:  the bank. Yeah. Do you need a nano texture screen? Like, I don't know, but
Speaker 3:  like, but I, I think it's actually interesting to see
Speaker 3:  Apple, right? I mean this company is defined by, its like mastery of the
Speaker 3:  supply chain. They're using their supply chain mastery to actually create
Speaker 3:  reasonable gaps between their products in a way that I don't think they could
Speaker 3:  quite get to before.
Speaker 4:  I agree. And also it, it makes the whole lineup easier to
Speaker 4:  explain, right? Like I feel like on the one hand you now have the, the air
Speaker 4:  and the mini, which exists kind of on the like regular person
Speaker 4:  computer side. And then you have the studio and the pro
Speaker 4:  as the sort of obvious upgrades. Although
Speaker 4:  the mini in the studio are closer to each other than they should be. But
Speaker 4:  the studio will get an upgrade and like you get what they're going for and
Speaker 4:  then the, the studio and the pro are like for people who mostly need these
Speaker 4:  four professional reasons and they have some upgrades that go with it. You
Speaker 4:  know, more ports, more power, like all that stuff. And then the Mac Pro
Speaker 4:  just like exists off on the side. But that there is now
Speaker 4:  a, a sort of consumer desktop and a consumer laptop and a professional
Speaker 4:  desktop and a professional laptop has not been the case with Apple's
Speaker 4:  max in a very long time. And this, this is like the cleanest this
Speaker 4:  lineup has felt to me in a very long time.
Speaker 3:  Right. And then there's the iMac, the desktop for receptionists. Like yeah
Speaker 4:  We, we basically don't talk about the iMac anymore. It's like the iMac
Speaker 4:  is If. you want an iMac buy an iMac, it's the iPad Mini of
Speaker 4:  Macs
Speaker 3:  Pilots. Pilots are walking onto planes. The iMac trapped in their thighs.
Speaker 3:  Exactly. I really am gonna take apart my old iMac make it a
Speaker 3:  display and then iMac mini for I just need to create the time
Speaker 3:  for like no one in my family is like, here's what we're gonna do. We're gonna
Speaker 3:  give you a full afternoon to disassemble a 10-year-old computer and
Speaker 3:  turn it into a display.
Speaker 4:  I will say we, we got a lot of people after we talked about this what
Speaker 4:  last week saying they have the same problem. There are a lot
Speaker 4:  of people out there sitting with like functionally useless
Speaker 4:  IMAX that are still big beautiful displays that you just kind of
Speaker 4:  stare at it and you're like, why can't I use you and So I think
Speaker 4:  if we can solve this for people, this is yet another side business that
Speaker 4:  we're gonna start where we're just gonna fix computers,
Speaker 3:  We're gonna call the I Fix It folks. We're, we're good friends with them
Speaker 3:  and we're gonna, we're gonna figure out a way to, to do this as a community
Speaker 3:  and that means David's gonna drive a van around the country fixing your
Speaker 3:  iMac and turning it into display. It's gonna be great. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I'm into it.
Speaker 3:  It's a new sponsorship opportunity. If, you thought the lightning round was
Speaker 3:  exclusive? David's iMac repair van
Speaker 4:  Sponsor the iMac van.
Speaker 3:  It's gonna be incredible. Last little bit of Gadget News,
Speaker 3:  we should talk about the Kindle color. Soft it. Oof.
Speaker 3:  That's it. That, I mean that's, that's kind of the whole story.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Tough, tough, tough beat for Amazon, which
Speaker 4:  came out with this whole lineup of new Kindles including the Color Soft,
Speaker 4:  the first color Kindle. And a bunch of people were like, Hey Amazon, why'd
Speaker 4:  you take so long to do Color Cobo and books and others have been doing color
Speaker 4:  for a while. And Amazon Pan Spin came on this show
Speaker 4:  and said basically in as many words, because it took us this long to get
Speaker 4:  it right, this is, we we did it, everybody else did bad color
Speaker 4:  and we did good color. And then a bunch of people started getting color softs
Speaker 4:  and it turns out they have this weird like
Speaker 4:  faded yellow band at the bottom. And there are, there are a bunch of
Speaker 4:  reasons I've seen for why this might happen. There's, there's some
Speaker 4:  speculation that it's, it's a UI thing that just doesn't fade
Speaker 4:  properly when you switch out of like the library view into a book.
Speaker 4:  It just doesn't pull that color off the screen.
Speaker 4:  Amazon seems to have kind of freaked out at this.
Speaker 4:  Like If, you look at the Kindle color soft page right now, the reviews are
Speaker 4:  really bad. There's a ton of 'em. People hate this thing. And there have
Speaker 4:  also been a couple of other issues like it was supposed to ship with a dark
Speaker 4:  mode and then Amazon just didn't ship it with the dark mode.
Speaker 4:  There was like a, a feature that was advertised that just doesn't exist on
Speaker 4:  this thing and they had to delay shipping. Like this thing has actually turned
Speaker 4:  into kind of a mess in a way that for Amazon,
Speaker 4:  which has basically like ruthlessly executed on
Speaker 4:  slight improvements to the Kindle for 15 years is very
Speaker 4:  strange. And it's super weird because I'm sitting here with like the new
Speaker 4:  paper white, which I love to bits like that that thing is, it's excellent.
Speaker 4:  It is everything you would want like a super simple kindle to be
Speaker 4:  and the color soft kind of just looks like a swing and a miss. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  But I mean the paper white is an incremental improvement, right? They
Speaker 3:  made the page turn speed a lot faster. Yeah, but it's the same product
Speaker 3:  and you this point you're making about Amazon sort of relentlessly improving
Speaker 3:  the same tiny iterations. I think people buy them and they just expect
Speaker 3:  them to work. Like you expect
Speaker 3:  99.9% similar functionality out of any
Speaker 3:  Kindle.
Speaker 4:  A hundred percent. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like I expect, I was like, do you want a new one? And she literally, she
Speaker 3:  looked me dead in the eye. She reads her Kindle every night. She looked me
Speaker 3:  dead in the eye and said Stop buying me Kindles 'cause it's
Speaker 3:  the only gadget I can buy or should care of anything else. And she was like,
Speaker 3:  stop it. Like I'm good. Yeah. I will let you know when this one catches fire.
Speaker 3:  And that was the end of that conversation.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I think like the, that's the, the new paperweight in is
Speaker 4:  that but slightly better in a bunch of ways, which is to some extent, like
Speaker 4:  it's what Becky and what a lot of people want from a paperweight, right?
Speaker 4:  Like go faster when I press the thing to change the page.
Speaker 3:  Right. The color soft is the big change's
Speaker 4:  Supposed to be the new thing. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And you have to get that right.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And especially if you're gonna come out and be like, oh we, we took
Speaker 4:  a long time to do this, but we think we've gotten it right. There have been
Speaker 4:  all these, also
Speaker 3:  You're in our DRM jail, so you'll only eat when we feed you.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. It's, it's a tough look and I think it's gonna be
Speaker 4:  really interesting. There's this new scribe coming out in a few weeks with
Speaker 4:  a bunch of like flashy AI stuff. Like they, they
Speaker 4:  pitched this as the biggest rev to the Kindle line ever.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Panelists was here. He was like, I I set 'em free.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And if If you, if your big first swing goes like this,
Speaker 4:  that is tough. I,
Speaker 3:  They said why? It's just like manufacturing error. Did they somebody step
Speaker 3:  on 'em like
Speaker 4:  They haven't said they've, they've essentially just acknowledged that it
Speaker 4:  is a real problem. Our review unit has one enter the Shefsky has been using
Speaker 4:  it and has seen the yellow bar. His stance so far seems to be that
Speaker 4:  it is worse in photos than in real life, but it is still
Speaker 4:  very much real and there and Amazon has acknowledged to
Speaker 4:  lots of people and according to people on Reddit, which take with a grain
Speaker 4:  of salt, Amazon has actually been calling people who have had, who have
Speaker 4:  left bad reviews and bought the thing to see what's going on. Like
Speaker 4:  you get the sense the company is scrambling that this has
Speaker 4:  been such a big problem, but Amazon has acknowledged that this is a
Speaker 4:  real thing and is an issue and that they are trying to fix it. Is
Speaker 3:  It a hardware issue or a software issue?
Speaker 4:  Unclear.
Speaker 3:  Wow.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's a bad look. I mean right now I'm just gonna, I'm gonna open,
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna open the Kindle Color soft page and I'm just gonna like,
Speaker 4:  so the reviews are truly, truly, truly brutal
Speaker 4:  in a way that like the Kindle is every, everybody is like, it's a Kindle.
Speaker 4:  I like my Kindle. The Color Soft, which I would remind you
Speaker 4:  is $280 way more expensive currently
Speaker 4:  at 2.6 stars on Amazon.
Speaker 3:  Oh it is a hardware problem.
Speaker 4:  It is. We
Speaker 3:  Have a quote. The company is making adjustments so that new devices will
Speaker 3:  not have the yellow band. People who already own a unit can contact Amazon
Speaker 3:  for a refund or replacement in the statement from an Amazon spokesperson
Speaker 3:  to us, we take the quality of our product seriously. Customers who notice
Speaker 3:  Jail Bank can reach out to customer service team for replacement or a refund.
Speaker 4:  Could be either way. Maybe hardware, maybe. Yeah, who knows.
Speaker 4:  But yeah, Amazon claims there's a fix, so we'll see. Right now you also
Speaker 4:  can only get delivery. I'm seeing delivery for two weeks from now, which
Speaker 4:  is a thing that has started showing up. Amazon seems to have like frozen
Speaker 4:  shipping on this while they try to fix it.
Speaker 3:  I feel so bad for 'em. They're such a struggling company with so little money.
Speaker 4:  I know, it's awful. Hopefully, hopefully they get it together. Real upstart
Speaker 4:  ebook company. Hope they can get it together.
Speaker 3:  It's funny 'cause this was, this really was the first like
Speaker 3:  revitalized Amazon hardware. Here we go here off the chain
Speaker 4:  And there was so much enthusiasm for it. Like I I I was actually really surprised
Speaker 4:  at how excited people were about the Color soft because on the one hand it's
Speaker 4:  not a giant sort of leap in functionality for most people.
Speaker 4:  It's just like now your book covers are in color, but a for people
Speaker 4:  who like carry these things around and have them sitting on their night table
Speaker 4:  like that alone is meaningful. But also I heard from a
Speaker 4:  lot of like comic book fans and people who love graphic novels and people
Speaker 4:  who are like this, this actually changes the kind of thing I can do on this
Speaker 4:  device. And again, it's, it's 80 or $90
Speaker 4:  more than the Paperweight. Like it's not a small choice to buy this thing
Speaker 4:  instead of a different Kindle. And it, it just, I feel
Speaker 4:  for all the people who have just like thought this was the thing they'd been
Speaker 4:  waiting for and it turned out it
Speaker 3:  Wasn't. This is why you gotta stick with the boos Palmer man.
Speaker 4:  I dunno. Do you want one? I have a, I have a Palma two right here. What do
Speaker 4:  you think? Can I just quickly preview my Palma two review for you? Yes.
Speaker 4:  I picked it up to do some testing and play with it and do some reviews
Speaker 4:  and an hour later realized I had picked up the original one instead of the
Speaker 4:  second one.
Speaker 3:  That's perfect. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's where we are.
Speaker 3:  That's very good.
Speaker 3:  We're back. Sean Hollister is here. Welcome Sean.
Speaker 6:  Hi.
Speaker 3:  It's the Voice. The voice of a new generation has returned once again to
Speaker 3:  the Vergecast.
Speaker 6:  I'm almost 40.
Speaker 3:  Sean, you're not supposed to admit this. I don't know. It's this is, this
Speaker 3:  goes on YouTube. You have to say you're 18 years old and you can't read
Speaker 6:  It. It, it's good because, because look at my, look at my complexion. It's
Speaker 6:  just fine.
Speaker 3:  I have a lot of additional YouTube jokes to tell and I'm just not gonna tell
Speaker 3:  'em. If, you sponsor the lightning round. I'll call you personally and tell
Speaker 3:  you the jokes I was about to tell. They're not, they weren't about Sean,
Speaker 3:  they were about YouTube. That's the
Speaker 4:  Worst argument you've ever made for sponsoring the lightning round. No one
Speaker 4:  is gonna sponsor it
Speaker 3:  Now. We're gonna have more incoming now than we've ever gotten and, and we
Speaker 3:  still will not know how to accept the money. We're gonna figure it out one
Speaker 3:  day. It's not today.
Speaker 3:  All right, Sean, you're here because you reviewed The PS five Pro, which
Speaker 3:  the review the embargo of which was the day after election day.
Speaker 3:  So while everyone else is like glued to the screens, watching counts go up,
Speaker 3:  Sean, I believe you were just moving back from your television one inch at
Speaker 3:  a time to see when you could stop telling that
Speaker 3:  The PS five Pro had in increased resolution in bloodborne.
Speaker 6:  I, I wanna tell you that you're incorrect, but that was literally exactly
Speaker 6:  what I was doing. I I, I was walking up really close to my TV
Speaker 6:  to see all the glorious pixels and then continually walking backwards
Speaker 6:  until I couldn't see the difference anymore between a 4-year-old
Speaker 6:  PlayStation and a brand new PlayStation.
Speaker 3:  I love this. This is what we do here. First, tell people what The PS five
Speaker 3:  Pro is and then explain why you were doing exactly that.
Speaker 6:  Okay, The PS five Pro is Sony's new game console,
Speaker 6:  which is basically a PS five with B storage,
Speaker 6:  a little more memory and a substantially faster GPU,
Speaker 6:  the GPU itself, 62% faster by tariff
Speaker 6:  flops. You get rendering performance increases of like
Speaker 6:  45%. So it's not quite enough to take your games from aa.
Speaker 6:  They weren't 4K before to suddenly they are 4K
Speaker 6:  except there's also AI upscaling on board because of course everything has
Speaker 6:  AI in it now. And so with that, you can
Speaker 6:  theoretically get a best of both worlds experience
Speaker 6:  where if previously your PS five game was running at 4K,
Speaker 6:  but only 30 frames per second, now you can run it at a smooth 60.
Speaker 6:  Or if your game was previously lower resolution
Speaker 6:  at 60 frames per second, you can now get higher resolution and more detail
Speaker 6:  at the 60 frames per second. And so you put your existing games
Speaker 6:  in this and if they've been patched to PS five Pro
Speaker 6:  enhanced, then all of a sudden they look better or they run smoother and
Speaker 6:  that's great. Right? It's it's, it's PS five but better. Yeah, it's also
Speaker 6:  $700.
Speaker 3:  That's a lot of dollars. It does have the little like rib on the side.
Speaker 4:  It does look nice. Yeah, it's got like a little racing stripey thing. I'm,
Speaker 4:  I'm, I'm into that. But wait, Sean, this is the thing I've been trying to
Speaker 4:  figure out about The PS five Pro. It feels like there there could be
Speaker 4:  three different GA kinds of games for this. One is like
Speaker 4:  game that is not aware of the existence of The PS five Pro. It's
Speaker 4:  just, it's just a game. It's a PS four game. It's a PS five game. The other
Speaker 4:  one is like a game that already existed that has been like
Speaker 4:  upgraded in some way to be ready for this. And then there are like
Speaker 4:  theoretically games made with The PS five Pro in
Speaker 4:  mind. Do all three of those things exist in The PS five Pro
Speaker 4:  World? Like if I put in a game that just does not care about The PS five
Speaker 4:  Pro at all, is it gonna look better?
Speaker 6:  In many cases it won't look
Speaker 6:  better if it doesn't know that you've got a PS five pro in there. But there
Speaker 6:  are so many edge cases here. This is a very
Speaker 6:  difficult review to write. Okay, so we, we we, we have let, let's start off
Speaker 6:  with the, with the obvious. Like are there new games that are only for The
Speaker 6:  PS five Pro? Will there be exclusive games that old wrote on this?
Speaker 6:  Probably not. Sony has not said anything to suggest that that will happen.
Speaker 6:  They will probably save those for The PS six, whenever that comes
Speaker 6:  out. And even those theoretically, maybe they'll let those
Speaker 6:  run on a PS five and a PS five pro as well. You could
Speaker 6:  theoretically now have a be in a place where games are like PCs, you
Speaker 6:  get your new PlayStation, they look a little better. You play above the old
Speaker 6:  PlayStation, they look worse. It's all X 86 under the hook. Now it's
Speaker 6:  possible. It's all a OD chips under the hood. Now it's possible. Has
Speaker 6:  Sony actually done that? Not quite. They would of course like you to buy
Speaker 6:  games again and again and buy the updates for those games. So to some
Speaker 6:  degree that's not happening.
Speaker 3:  I mean there are barely even PS five only games, right? I mean I'm, I'm,
Speaker 3:  I'm looking at the list of PS five only games and it is just not that
Speaker 3:  many.
Speaker 6:  There aren't PS five only games, but there are a lot of PS five only versions
Speaker 6:  of games. Yeah, If, you put The PS five disc in like you were getting a different
Speaker 6:  and better experience than The PS four version. Absolutely a hundred percent
Speaker 6:  like that is a much bigger difference also than the difference between PS
Speaker 6:  five and PS five Pro. Okay, so the second question is,
Speaker 6:  you've got your no exclusives, no exclusives for this, but then
Speaker 6:  you do have games that do not necessarily
Speaker 6:  need the patches. They don't necessarily need to develop or put in the extra
Speaker 6:  legwork to make a game run better because
Speaker 6:  some PS five games have an unlocked frame rate.
Speaker 6:  Now most of the time you're like a console experience, it's gonna be a smooth
Speaker 6:  60 or it's gonna be a smooth 30 FPS. The developers decided we're going to
Speaker 6:  lock it there. So you don't have up and down in terms of the performance.
Speaker 6:  You, you got a reliable frame rate. But because there's
Speaker 6:  so much difference in power between PS four and PS four Pro
Speaker 6:  and PS five and now PS five Pro, some developers are like, well
Speaker 6:  no, if we leave our games in this pclike state
Speaker 6:  where If you just throw more performance at them, they'll be better. There
Speaker 6:  are a handful of games like that Digital Foundry tested, you know, cyberpunk
Speaker 6:  2077 and it's like, oh okay that works.
Speaker 6:  But there's this other wrinkle in here, which is that If, you have a
Speaker 6:  TV with a variable refresh rate on it,
Speaker 6:  especially one that can go all the way up to 120 Hertz.
Speaker 6:  You put a game on this with that unlocked frame rate
Speaker 6:  and now your game that was only running 30 frames per second could
Speaker 6:  run 40 or 47 or something like that. If, you play this
Speaker 6:  exact same game on a TV with a locked number of Hertz,
Speaker 6:  a locked refresh rate, you're only getting the 30 or the 60 If, you
Speaker 6:  can't hit the 60, you're at 30. You know, so we're in that place
Speaker 6:  where If, you have the best TV and you have an unlocked
Speaker 6:  frame rate game, then you don't need a PS five pro enhanced
Speaker 6:  patch to get some excellent enhancements out of it. Most of
Speaker 6:  the time though, you're gonna want these patches
Speaker 4:  Is the market for what you just described, 11 people
Speaker 4:  like, I don't know, I'm not, I'm not a
Speaker 4:  guy with a variable refresh tv, but like, but that's your fault.
Speaker 4:  That's a personal failing a David, you don't disagree.
Speaker 6:  Listen, nobody should buy this unless they have a
Speaker 6:  65 inch variable refresh rate
Speaker 6:  HDR probably ole TV that they
Speaker 6:  sit at least that no more than eight feet away from, you know, they're sitting
Speaker 6:  close to this screen, preferably like five feet,
Speaker 6:  maybe three, three would be good. I I I I'm sitting
Speaker 6:  in front of a 32 inch 4K monitor that, that OLED
Speaker 6:  monitor. It's a beautiful Alienware monitor and I I, I like The PS
Speaker 6:  five Pro a lot on this screen. So, but
Speaker 4:  That's, that's actually I, I think a good point because you and you, you
Speaker 4:  make the same point in the review, which is that you basically find
Speaker 4:  yourself using it like a gaming pc. This is not like a
Speaker 4:  plop it in the TV entertainment center, sit back on
Speaker 4:  the couch and game kind of thing. This is like
Speaker 4:  sit three inches from the screen until your eyes bleed kind
Speaker 4:  of quality. This
Speaker 6:  Is the same argument we had about the steam deck. I mean people
Speaker 6:  love the idea of a gaming pc but they don't want all of that
Speaker 6:  hassle, right? And the steam deck is like, here is so much less hassle. Take
Speaker 6:  it with you. It just works for the most part. Even though it's running Linux
Speaker 6:  under the hood, these Windows games just work. Just start 'em up. We, we
Speaker 6:  guarantee that these ones will work and Valve doesn't always guarantee them
Speaker 6:  properly. PS five Pro, plug that into your desktop monitor,
Speaker 6:  pick up your dual sense controller. It's amazing controller and these
Speaker 6:  games just work and they look beautiful, right?
Speaker 4:  This is why I bring this up because I think If, you look at it that way,
Speaker 4:  you're no longer competing against a much
Speaker 4:  cheaper, almost as good PS five, you're competing against a way more
Speaker 4:  expensive, way more fiddly, way more complicated gaming pc.
Speaker 3:  Wait, so Sean, you mentioned this in the review, you said this is like the
Speaker 3:  power of a mid-range gaming pc, right? It's somewhere in there.
Speaker 3:  Is that so much more complicated and expensive,
Speaker 6:  A mid-range gaming pc Yeah,
Speaker 3:  You have to run Windows.
Speaker 6:  Exactly that. That's really it. That's really that and, and,
Speaker 6:  and, and ports. I mean Sony has ported a lot of good
Speaker 6:  games to gaming PCs now it's, it's various port
Speaker 6:  studios like Nixies have done this and some of
Speaker 6:  them are great and some of them are really, really not great. I
Speaker 6:  booted up the last of us part one on both my
Speaker 6:  PS five Pro and my gaming pc. And trust me, the gaming
Speaker 6:  PC has more oomph under the hood. The graphics card in there, you're gonna
Speaker 6:  get more frame rate, more textures. I proved that out by playing Alan wait
Speaker 6:  too. But with Last of Us part one, it is not a good port on
Speaker 6:  pc. The little girl's hair in the beginning of the game, it looks
Speaker 6:  like Medusa like tentacles on my PC because there is some kind of
Speaker 6:  bug. She is also a vampire apparently because there was, she has no
Speaker 6:  reflection in any of the mirrors on pc, on The PS five Pro The
Speaker 6:  mirrors show the entire world, including her. Also it took
Speaker 6:  like a minute to load the game fully on
Speaker 6:  less than that, maybe 30 seconds to load the game on PS five Pro. I spent
Speaker 6:  15 minutes compiling the shaders for the game on pc
Speaker 6:  after which point it still didn't work properly.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, so is it worth it? I mean I look, I have a PS five, I play one game
Speaker 3:  on it. I I throw interceptions in Madden. I do that for about an hour every
Speaker 3:  night before
Speaker 4:  On frame tv, which feels important to say out loud at
Speaker 3:  This moment on my, my 77 inch Sony Master series Ole, which does have
Speaker 3:  VRR actually. Okay, there you go.
Speaker 3:  No one in my house enjoys when I do this. There's a lot of swearing tv
Speaker 3:  but this isn't a game. I doubt they're gonna update Madden. The the only
Speaker 3:  thing they're gonna update madness with like is more interstitial advertising
Speaker 3:  to buy their weird cards. That's those the only updates this game.
Speaker 3:  Is this worth it for me? This it feels like not at all worth it to me.
Speaker 6:  No, no wait for a PS six oh
Speaker 3:  Max plays Abot. My 6-year-old plays the hell out of astronaut, which is
Speaker 3:  the best game in the world. And the astro bot dual suns controller is
Speaker 3:  actually delightful 'cause the light around the touch pad glows in different
Speaker 3:  colors when you play the game. The whole thing's delight.
Speaker 6:  We played the hell out of Astro Bot. I did not notice a difference.
Speaker 3:  Alright,
Speaker 4:  Are there games that you feel like it's worth it? Like is is there a game
Speaker 4:  that it's like, if I play this game for hours a day, this upgrade
Speaker 4:  is, is that meaningful all on its own?
Speaker 6:  You would have to be an Uber fan and it might need to be something competitive.
Speaker 6:  And this is one place I did, I didn't get to try like Call of Duty
Speaker 6:  on this with like in in like intensive multiplay. I don't even know if there
Speaker 6:  is like a fast refresh mode. But let's imagine for
Speaker 6:  a moment you have like imagine Call of Duty or or
Speaker 6:  or or really competitive fighting game comes out with an
Speaker 6:  120 hertz mode and all of a sudden
Speaker 6:  this is like the best way to play outside of a pc because you actually have
Speaker 6:  like lowered latency from the, from your inputs into the thing. Or if they
Speaker 6:  also like let you use a mouse and keyboard, maybe that's what they need to
Speaker 6:  do. If they take this thing and they're like, it is your gaming pc every
Speaker 6:  game you throw it will be better because we are issuing a mandate that every
Speaker 6:  developer has to have unlocked frame rate and resolution and
Speaker 6:  graphic setting options on all of their games. And we're gonna let you plug
Speaker 6:  a mouse and keyboard into it. And it basically is a pc except
Speaker 6:  it's a really cool and quiet and SM compact.
Speaker 3:  This is like Microsoft's dream of the PC for years. True. You were describing
Speaker 3:  the world's wildest surface rt.
Speaker 6:  If you're a Final Fantasy seven Uber fan and like all you wanted
Speaker 6:  for your entire existence since 1997 or whenever it
Speaker 6:  was, was to see Final Fantasy seven turn
Speaker 6:  into a you come to life around you. This still isn't that
Speaker 6:  because it's not vr, but, but it's, it looks better than
Speaker 6:  PS five for that. It's pretty muddy on PS five and in the 60 hertz mode.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I do like the idea that this is a weird incursion into gaming
Speaker 3:  PC world. It, it makes it make more sense to me. Whereas
Speaker 3:  when there's a PS four and The PS four Pro came out a little bit later,
Speaker 3:  there was just some like obvious reasons that I would want my, I would wanna
Speaker 3:  upgrade my console at that time. 'cause that's what got you 4K back
Speaker 3:  then. Did
Speaker 6:  You upgrade David?
Speaker 4:  I only got a PS four Pro. I still have a PS four Pro. I bought that
Speaker 4:  just because it was like, there was like a Black Friday sale. So I ended
Speaker 4:  up with it. But again, I I played that on a 10 80 p
Speaker 4:  computer monitor for a very long time. Do you have eyes I say these
Speaker 4:  things primarily just to piss off me. Like this is, it's great
Speaker 6:  So I asked because all this means all of us are PS four pro owners. All of
Speaker 6:  us bought into this last gen when the, when the pitch was
Speaker 6:  like, now you get HDR and now you get like
Speaker 6:  4K, which is like, but
Speaker 3:  It was like fake 4K contrived,
Speaker 6:  Right? Yeah. Checkerboard rendering. But like, but the, the
Speaker 6:  thing about, the thing about the, you have to be a certain feet amount of,
Speaker 6:  number of feet away from your PS five. Like not see the difference. You have
Speaker 6:  to be within eight feet to see, like really see the difference with PS five
Speaker 6:  Pro that worked in the favor of The PS
Speaker 6:  four Pro because at the distance you were away from the screen,
Speaker 6:  you could tell that it was 4K, but you could not tell that it was
Speaker 6:  contrived checkerboard rendering. At least I couldn't, maybe you couldn't,
Speaker 6:  Neil. I could
Speaker 3:  Not. Okay. But I but I you, this is not my, as everyone
Speaker 3:  knows, evaluating video games is not the thing that I do because I play two
Speaker 3:  of them and I'm horrible at one of them. So
Speaker 3:  like, it's, it's, don't take my word for it. But yeah, I, I agree with you
Speaker 3:  broadly that The PS four Pro made sense to me
Speaker 3:  'cause it got me the two features I wanted to use on my tv, right? Right.
Speaker 3:  I want all the lights on my TV to be lit up as everyone knows. And so it
Speaker 3:  got me the 4K and it got me the HTR and that was great. This one is like
Speaker 3:  I, whatever, it's more pixels. Like I always play in higher resolution mode
Speaker 3:  versus higher performance mode because I, that, that's the trade off I'm
Speaker 3:  willing to make and I'm not willing to make this trade off. The idea that
Speaker 3:  The PS five Pro is actually meant to go up against
Speaker 3:  a mid-range gaming PC and be simpler and faster and have a better library
Speaker 3:  of more optimized games. Kind of like,
Speaker 3:  kind of re-contextualize the whole product.
Speaker 4:  I agree. And makes it way more like $700 seems a lot
Speaker 4:  less
Speaker 4:  wildly expensive.
Speaker 3:  Is that how Sony is talking about it?
Speaker 6:  No, absolutely not.
Speaker 3:  Well, maybe they should start.
Speaker 3:  All right, so that's BS five, four. Anything we missed, Sean? Anything that
Speaker 3:  like stood out to you apart from that, how is the weird detachable disc drive
Speaker 3:  thing?
Speaker 6:  The detachable. Okay, so it doesn't, it does not come with the disc drive,
Speaker 6:  which is like, how do you call it the pro when it
Speaker 6:  doesn't have this feature? How do you, how do you release this console to
Speaker 6:  an audience of nit pickers who are gonna care about those graphics in that
Speaker 6:  frame? Right. But you think they magically don't care about,
Speaker 6:  about physical media. Like Yeah, people care about physical media
Speaker 6:  if they're nit pickers and So I did have to special order the disc drive
Speaker 6:  and put it on this thing. It was so easy. Yeah, they're
Speaker 4:  Hard to find, right? The, yeah. Test drives are not easy to get your hands
Speaker 4:  on.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I went, I looked at GameStop, I looked at Best Buy, I looked at Sony's
Speaker 6:  side, I looked a bunch of places, eventually found one at Walmart, not a
Speaker 6:  close Walmart, but I did, I did order it, it got to me next day. So
Speaker 6:  good. Good for you. Walmart. And I guess I'll scalp
Speaker 6:  it now. No, I'm not gonna scalp.
Speaker 4:  You probably could.
Speaker 6:  I really could. They're hotly in demand. Sony did not make enough
Speaker 6:  of these things, but, but yeah, it, it, it, it clips on really easily
Speaker 6:  once it's on there, it looks like an original PS five.
Speaker 6:  And it's, and it's, it's smaller, you know, it's, it's, it's, and it's, and
Speaker 6:  it's fairly quiet and not that warm.
Speaker 6:  Like I'm using it, it's under the desk right now. I'm using it as a foot
Speaker 6:  warmer while we do this. It's, it's, it's currently Ray tracing at Wake two
Speaker 6:  and it's, it's enough to warm up my feet a little bit, but it's not,
Speaker 6:  they're not super toasty. And I would say it's,
Speaker 3:  This is how we're measuring heat and thermals on every product from
Speaker 3:  now on. Like, did it make my feet super toasty
Speaker 3:  under the desk? It's very good.
Speaker 6:  It's quieter than the original Steve Deck was. The Steve original Steve Deck
Speaker 6:  had a really noisy fan. This is quieter that
Speaker 3:  Have they added Dolby vision to The PS five yet. If, you wanna play
Speaker 3:  Blu-rays on it. I don't think they have. Don't all this extra processing
Speaker 3:  power and I just want Dolby vision support. And then I would buy a new PS
Speaker 3:  five Pro with this disc drive and I would use it as Blu-Ray player.
Speaker 6:  I bought the Samsung Go LED TV this time. So, I don't have Dolby vision either
Speaker 6:  way.
Speaker 3:  Oh
Speaker 6:  My God. Sean, sorry,
Speaker 3:  Everyone, can everyone just check in with me? Just send me a note
Speaker 3:  and I'll help you out. I'm doing my best out here, Neil.
Speaker 4:  I have a 42 inch P series TCL I'm looking at, can you give
Speaker 4:  me a once over,
Speaker 3:  I walked into a new neighbor's house the other day and he
Speaker 3:  showed me the TV about the mantle and he goes, it's, it's not, it's like
Speaker 3:  a different kind of frame tv. And I was like, I can't, I have to get outta
Speaker 3:  this house because he, he hadn't bought it because I,
Speaker 3:  there's a bunch of competitors to frame TV now and I was like, I gotta go,
Speaker 3:  I gotta get outta here. I just immediately call. I don't know you well enough
Speaker 3:  to react to what you just said to me the way that I want to.
Speaker 3:  And I don't have control over my emotions. So, I have to just leave.
Speaker 4:  That's good.
Speaker 3:  Other gaming news. It seems like everyone keeps expecting Nintendo
Speaker 3:  to actually announce what should be called the Super Nintendo Switch
Speaker 3:  Hint. But instead they've announced an alarm clock and then on,
Speaker 3:  I believe it was on election night, announced that the forthcoming switch
Speaker 3:  successor would be backwards compatible. Well no, you,
Speaker 4:  You forgot one. I forgot one. There was also the music app, which was, I
Speaker 4:  forgot the music app. There was like 24 hours of excitement of people being
Speaker 4:  like, oh my God, I keep hearing there's a Nintendo thing happening. This
Speaker 4:  is gonna be it. This is it, this is it. I am in Slack with Andrew Webster
Speaker 4:  being like, we have to have a plan. This is the biggest thing. And then they
Speaker 4:  announced the music app.
Speaker 6:  Some, some guy was like, I had had this leak that it was gonna be the Switch
Speaker 6:  the next morning. And Andrew Webster, he was like, my heart can't take it.
Speaker 6:  He, our games entered he, he was so ready to write about the switch too.
Speaker 6:  And then the next morning the leak guy was like, I just got used by Nintendo
Speaker 6:  so hard. It
Speaker 4:  Is my favorite. I have come all the way around. I hope Nintendo does this
Speaker 4:  for five more years. Just don't, don't ever launch the new switch.
Speaker 4:  Just keep doing silly stuff. There was also a museum launch in there somewhere.
Speaker 4:  Andrew got an invite to go to Japan and it was about a museum and not the
Speaker 4:  Switch to like, it's so funny. This is the best. Do you
Speaker 3:  Think they know that everyone's expecting the switch to, so every other team
Speaker 3:  in Nintendo is like, let's do our announcement first. Pay attention
Speaker 4:  To it. They have to. They have to know. And this is now the funniest bit
Speaker 4:  from a tech company in a very long time and I love it so much.
Speaker 4:  But this week we got actual switch news, not the switch news we were expecting
Speaker 4:  but actual real switch news.
Speaker 3:  But it was like, but and this wasn't an announcement, right? This is like,
Speaker 3:  this was like in a briefing, like buried information,
Speaker 6:  Right? I think it was like a financial briefing and then, and then Nintendo
Speaker 6:  was like, I guess nobody noticed so we'll we will tweet it now. And they
Speaker 6:  did
Speaker 4:  On election night in the middle. Literally I'm sitting on my couch
Speaker 4:  talking to people during election night. We're we're tracking the returns
Speaker 4:  as they come in and somebody just drops this tweet in Slack and is like,
Speaker 4:  did they just announce backwards compatibility for switch games,
Speaker 3:  Right. Can I read you this tweet? As rich cast listeners know,
Speaker 3:  I like explaining how the journalism sausage is made. And this one is
Speaker 3:  particularly good because at 8:26 PM
Speaker 3:  on November 5th,
Speaker 3:  the Nintendo account just tweeted, this is for Alcala, which is the president
Speaker 3:  of Nintendo Chura for Alcala. But it just says this is for Alcala
Speaker 3:  Badass, no other names.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna start all my tweets like that from now on.
Speaker 3:  Does it not say I am the president of Nintendo? It just says this is for
Speaker 3:  Akwa. It's
Speaker 4:  Very good. You know who it is.
Speaker 3:  What time is it
Speaker 3:  At today's corporate management policy briefing, we announced that Nintendo
Speaker 3:  Switch software will be playable and the Assessor Nintendo switch. What is
Speaker 3:  the corporate management policy briefing? They had an offsite,
Speaker 3:  that's, that's what I'm taking away from this. They had an offsite and they
Speaker 3:  distributed some pamphlets and they're like, shit, this is gonna leak for
Speaker 3:  a cow. Get on the horn.
Speaker 4:  It's either that or like an internal company newsletter that like only goes
Speaker 4:  to the accounting department and they were like, ah. I hit all staff instead
Speaker 4:  of accounting, like I guess we'll just share this with everybody now.
Speaker 3:  It's very good. I, from now on am signing every tweet from
Speaker 3:  The Verge accounts. Is this is Patel.
Speaker 3:  It's very good.
Speaker 4:  It is good. But wait, Sean, if I, if I understand the news correctly, basically
Speaker 4:  what they announced is that whatever is coming after the Switch
Speaker 4:  will be able to play switch games, which is a
Speaker 4:  big and somewhat unusual deal for Nintendo. Is
Speaker 4:  that, do I basically have that right?
Speaker 6:  Let's talk about the impact of this for a moment. So this could be one of
Speaker 6:  two things. Let, let's go, let's go optimistic first. The Nintendo
Speaker 6:  switch, the original 2017 Nintendo Switch launched with like 12
Speaker 6:  games, all of which were basically like Zelda and everything else.
Speaker 6:  We had a headline on The Verge, the Nintendo Switch launch games lineup is
Speaker 6:  disappointing and needlessly confusing. That is where the switch
Speaker 6:  began before it became the juggernaut that it is today, which has
Speaker 6:  one of the biggest libraries of any console ever released.
Speaker 6:  It is amazing. And so that Switch two, having that lineup
Speaker 6:  on day one would be phenomenal.
Speaker 6:  The thing is, we don't know if this means it will have a cartridge slot or
Speaker 6:  not. Oh, interesting. So if it doesn't take the Switch
Speaker 6:  cartridges,
Speaker 6:  then you're gonna have to own these games digitally or buy them again or
Speaker 6:  whatever you have to do there. And now we're back in The PS five Pro.
Speaker 6:  Why don't they think we like physical media space? I don't know which it
Speaker 6:  is. They didn't say.
Speaker 3:  I mean I'm at, I buy the games digitally 'cause I'm lazy,
Speaker 3:  right? Like Astro Bot is available,
Speaker 3:  I'm just gonna download it.
Speaker 6:  I've started doing that like
Speaker 3:  That. Yeah. See, see
Speaker 6:  At Luigi's Mansion, I got Echoes of wisdom digitally,
Speaker 6:  but I have so many cartridges
Speaker 3:  The Bluey game is on the switch at our house. 'cause
Speaker 3:  no one was letting me drive to the store. I was like, here, now we're doing
Speaker 3:  this. Right. So, I, I, I think more regular
Speaker 3:  consumers have these like hybrid libraries and I think it's important for
Speaker 3:  'em to say like you can just keep using this library. 'cause once it's digital,
Speaker 3:  it's just there, right? I mean there's a million, and don't get me wrong,
Speaker 3:  there's a million other problems with this, including preservation and emulation,
Speaker 3:  which we will talk about in a second. But I think from just a pure convenience
Speaker 3:  or your library will be here with your new switch, I think
Speaker 3:  it's starting to become an expectation. Just like absent an iPhone, our expectation
Speaker 3:  like I bought all this stuff, I'm gonna get the new device, it's just gonna
Speaker 3:  be here.
Speaker 6:  I want that so much and I want it to be portable and preservable
Speaker 6:  and it's nice, you know, it's nice when you fire up your PS five pro and
Speaker 6:  you're like all these PS five games are there and all your PS four games
Speaker 6:  that you've bought in your digital library. But it's what's extra nice when
Speaker 6:  you can take all those discs that are on your shelf and also stick them in
Speaker 6:  there. Why not both? Hopefully both.
Speaker 3:  I mean it's Nintendo, they're gonna do some weird stuff. That's you, you
Speaker 3:  know, it's true. No matter what here, the Switch,
Speaker 4:  Historically speaking, Nintendo has kind of gone on both sides of this, right?
Speaker 4:  Like if I remember like the, we you played most or
Speaker 4:  at least some we games, but then like you're talking about complete break
Speaker 4:  to the switch,
Speaker 4:  like yeah, just, and like, you know, you go all the way back and like the
Speaker 4:  N 64 was very much its own thing. It's not like those giant ass cartridges
Speaker 4:  went on to the next thing. So I guess it, it would be hard to
Speaker 4:  put odds against what it seems like Nintendo might actually do here.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, like the, the portables, it's been pretty good in the portable space.
Speaker 6:  Like If, you bought a Nintendo DS Light, you
Speaker 6:  could play DS games on that. You could also play Game Boy Advance Games on
Speaker 6:  that, which was basically an entirely different system. You couldn't put
Speaker 6:  original Game Boy cartridges in there or Game Boy color cartridges. But you
Speaker 6:  go back a generation before that, the Game Boy Advance, you could put Game
Speaker 6:  Boy, advance Games, game Boy Color Games, original Game Boy games into that.
Speaker 6:  They would all work. You go up to the DSI, all of a sudden you've got just
Speaker 6:  DSI and Ds. You don't get Game Boy anymore. So they, they kinda like, they
Speaker 6:  try to do like one to two generations usually of backwards combat. And then
Speaker 6:  occasionally, like you said with this N 64, they're just, we're done. But
Speaker 6:  even like the Game Cube, you could stick a Game Boy player onto the bottom
Speaker 6:  of that and stick your cartridges in. So maybe there'll be some offbeat solution
Speaker 4:  That's the most Nintendo possible outcome here where they're like, well here's
Speaker 4:  the thing, but we'll also sell you this weird arm attachment that lets you
Speaker 4:  play all of your other games. It's made of card for, did
Speaker 3:  You ever have the Nintendo robot for the Nest? This just made me think about
Speaker 3:  the original Nintendo robot. No, they made a robot and it pushed the
Speaker 3:  buttons on the, it was really should go look it up. It was, yeah, it was
Speaker 3:  ridiculous. I wanted ones, I wanted one so bad and I finally got
Speaker 3:  one and it was so disappointing. Like, so deeply
Speaker 3:  disappointing. Shocked, shocked. We are talking about emulation,
Speaker 3:  we're talking about this stuff. Sean, we should end by talking about your
Speaker 3:  story
Speaker 3:  you wrote about Nintendo going after YouTubers who are
Speaker 3:  streaming games, talking about game preservation. There's a lot of action
Speaker 3:  in this front lately, and that's all right next to, I dunno,
Speaker 3:  companies like Amick, which are just selling hardware emulators free
Speaker 3:  and clear on Amazon with apparently no repercussions. Talk about this story
Speaker 3:  then. Let's talk about that bigger picture. What is going on with Nintendo
Speaker 3:  on YouTube right now?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so Nintendo and I, I've written one story, but there's, there's more
Speaker 6:  in the works. I think Nintendo seems to have decided
Speaker 6:  it wants to make an example out of one
Speaker 6:  particular YouTuber. And it may be targeting others
Speaker 6:  as well, though we think there may be a copyright troll
Speaker 6:  on the loose and that's what a future story is gonna get into. But
Speaker 6:  this, this one guy is named Russ Crandall. He runs
Speaker 6:  a a, a YouTube channel called Retro Game Core. And
Speaker 6:  the weird thing about Nintendo targeting him is that he is known
Speaker 6:  for advocating against piracy. He shows up all kinds of
Speaker 6:  like genuine switch cartridges in his videos to show you that he's not just
Speaker 6:  like ripping games off the internet, although he, yeah, maybe he does some
Speaker 6:  of that on the side, but he wants you to know that
Speaker 6:  you can do this somewhat legally or so He says, by
Speaker 6:  making your own backups of your games, putting them onto
Speaker 6:  flashcards, If you want to, and then taking around your entire library of
Speaker 6:  switch games with you that you have on genuine cartridges. This is possible
Speaker 6:  now through a particular device that Nintendo really does not want the
Speaker 6:  world to know about. And so in a, in a new example of the
Speaker 6:  Streisand effect, they decided to target this guy.
Speaker 6:  He is not somebody you would necessarily want to target if
Speaker 6:  you're Nintendo though, because he's a very
Speaker 6:  interesting and likable person, I would say, who has, who
Speaker 6:  has a, an audience that understands him as an
Speaker 6:  educator who like teaches them how to use things rather than boasting about
Speaker 6:  how he pirates stuff. He also happens to be a New York Times bestselling
Speaker 6:  cookbook author, A 22 Veteran of the US Navy
Speaker 6:  and all kinds of other things that, yeah, you can read about my whole story.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's a good story. But I, it does seem like if you're
Speaker 4:  Nintendo and you wanna go like full scorched earth on
Speaker 4:  this kind of thing on the internet, like you can, you can use
Speaker 4:  copyright to pick that fight, but that doesn't seem like
Speaker 4:  what Nintendo is doing here. It has instead picked
Speaker 4:  a small series of very specific fights with
Speaker 4:  a couple of emulators and now with this one YouTuber, it's not
Speaker 4:  like the stories we've heard over the years about you, you know, companies
Speaker 4:  that just go and issue mass copyright strikes for everyone using
Speaker 4:  footage of any of their stuff, which is a thing that has happened a few times
Speaker 4:  on YouTube over the years. That's not what Nintendo is doing here. And I,
Speaker 4:  it, and I, it's hard for me to figure out what it is doing.
Speaker 6:  I wanna say that the common theme here is
Speaker 6:  Nintendo is just ridiculously less tolerant
Speaker 6:  of people cutting into its current gen console
Speaker 6:  profits. You wanna talk about old games, you wanna talk about, you know,
Speaker 6:  you want, you wanna play show off emulators with Game Boy games or SNES games
Speaker 6:  or N 64 games. You wanna build emulators for those things.
Speaker 6:  Nintendo's generally gonna leave you alone. But once it's started,
Speaker 6:  once we started seeing not only Nintendo Switch emulators and
Speaker 6:  Nintendo switch games all over YouTube playing on Nintendo Switch emulators,
Speaker 6:  but the very latest games, the Zelda that's going
Speaker 6:  to come out this week or just has come out this week here it is
Speaker 6:  running in, you know, at a high resolution on a pc.
Speaker 6:  Look how much better it looks than it looks on the actual switch
Speaker 6:  hardware. Hmm. Maybe you should be playing it here on a PC instead.
Speaker 6:  Or maybe you should take your whole library of switch games and play them
Speaker 6:  on a steam deck, which is not only looks better than it does
Speaker 6:  on the switch, but is portable like a Nintendo switch? Is the steam deck
Speaker 6:  better than a Nintendo Switch? Wouldn't want people to walk away with that
Speaker 6:  idea in their heads. This is where Nintendo started stepping
Speaker 6:  in. And so we saw a while back before,
Speaker 6:  before, before it fought against Yuzu and Rio Jinx
Speaker 6:  the two big switch emulators before it did that. There was a while,
Speaker 6:  I wanna say maybe about a year ago, where a bunch of folks showing
Speaker 6:  off switch games on Steam Deck started getting
Speaker 6:  little notices from Nintendo that maybe they might not want to do that. And
Speaker 6:  some of the, some of the folks who were, you know, the,
Speaker 6:  the YouTubers who were more wanted to stay on Nintendo's good Grace, it just
Speaker 6:  went ahead and voluntarily started making some of those disappear. But they
Speaker 6:  told other creators in their sphere, Hmm, Nintendo
Speaker 6:  did this thing to me and Word got around that this was happening. I think
Speaker 6:  Linus Tech Tips did a video at one point where they were like, we're going
Speaker 6:  to call out this trend and here we're gonna, we're gonna blur out all of
Speaker 6:  our footage of switch games. We're gonna be like, Hey look, you know, look
Speaker 6:  what we can do in Nintendo. You're not gonna go after us. Right? And I don't
Speaker 6:  think they did, but After that kept
Speaker 6:  on a pace on YouTube and we kept seeing more and more,
Speaker 6:  here's how you emulate your switch games on Steam Deck. Nintendo went after
Speaker 6:  the emulators, the software that's making all of that
Speaker 6:  possible. And Yuzu was the biggest emulator
Speaker 6:  and there were whispers in the community that they were testing
Speaker 6:  their emulator on games that had leaked out early
Speaker 6:  games that were not even out yet. A new, a new Zelda
Speaker 6:  Tears to the Kingdom, allegedly they had it and were making sure
Speaker 6:  the game was ready for it before it launched at retail.
Speaker 6:  And so that regardless of whether, you know, Nintendo could pin them,
Speaker 6:  that on them or not seems to have
Speaker 6:  inflamed Nintendo's fury for to, to go after them
Speaker 6:  legally. And so Yuzu went
Speaker 6:  down, Rio Jinx went down. There are lots of forks of these
Speaker 6:  emulators floating about the internet, but they are more in
Speaker 6:  the, in the, in the, in the, in the dark re regions of the space. Now
Speaker 6:  they've slunk back into the shadows for the most part. They're trying to
Speaker 6:  keep a way lower profile.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's funny, one of, you know, a a VERGE trope, a thing The
Speaker 3:  Verge believes is that copyright law is the only law on the internet, especially
Speaker 3:  when you have a platform, because it's the one law everyone agrees
Speaker 3:  can restrict speech. And so you've got a process on YouTube where a
Speaker 3:  big company can can just say like, remove this speech
Speaker 3:  and you can fight it. It sounds like from your story, Crandall Retro Games
Speaker 3:  is gonna go fight it, but it's expensive and hard.
Speaker 6:  Actually, I, I think, I think he's not, I don't think he's gonna fight it.
Speaker 3:  He's not going to,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, we, we started out in my story, I say that he's waffling
Speaker 6:  and as of my last communication with him, he was waffling,
Speaker 6:  but I re I rewrote this draft a few different times. Originally when I
Speaker 6:  spoke to him, he said he was 70%, 5% likely to fight this.
Speaker 6:  He talked to, he talked to lawyers like, yeah, I've got a fair use case.
Speaker 6:  I don't think he wanted to go to court over it, but he can at
Speaker 6:  least submit the counter notice to the
Speaker 6:  DMCA takedown, which lets YouTube off the hook and then, you know, puts the,
Speaker 6:  puts the spotlight on him and then wait and see if Nintendo sends him
Speaker 6:  a cease and desist or goes ahead with a lawsuit. He was in that place where
Speaker 6:  he was like, maybe I'll try my like 75% likely. I was talking to him
Speaker 6:  later and he is like, well maybe it's 50 50.
Speaker 3:  I mean it's expensive and complicated. Yeah, right. And you gotta, you gotta
Speaker 3:  be buttoned up. I mean this is a thing we talk about with independent creators
Speaker 3:  all the time, go be successful. But then there's a whole
Speaker 3:  universe of infrastructure that you don't have. 'cause you don't have like
Speaker 3:  a media company. Like we have lawyers, like we get letters like
Speaker 3:  this all day long and I'm just like, cool, our lawyers will see you
Speaker 3:  now. And then our lawyer's like, Howard, do you wanna fight? I'm like, fight
Speaker 3:  all the way because you know, you get to say that sometimes
Speaker 3:  and that's fine, right? Like that's the infrastructure of having a big company
Speaker 3:  around and like having a reputation and like a lot of the lawyers on the
Speaker 3:  other side are repeat players. So now everybody has relationships, solo creators
Speaker 3:  on platforms are just sort of at the mercy of whoever wants to go after them,
Speaker 3:  including Nintendo. And then they have to make big meaningful
Speaker 3:  decisions about whether they wanna like fight for
Speaker 3:  emulation software being displayed on screen is fair use. Like this is very
Speaker 3:  confusing.
Speaker 4:  Well, and this is what the emulators themselves have gone through too. The
Speaker 4:  question of like, yeah, even if we think we're right and we would win at
Speaker 4:  the end, can we literally afford the fight?
Speaker 4:  And I think the, the bet a lot of companies make, not just Nintendo, but
Speaker 4:  one of the bets it seems like Nintendo is making and has been right so far,
Speaker 4:  is that the emulators are going to decide they can't afford the fight,
Speaker 6:  Right? I talked to a lot of emulator developers for a previous
Speaker 6:  story about what happened to Yuzu and what was happening to Vu Jinx.
Speaker 6:  And every one of them told me no I would have to roll over if
Speaker 6:  Nintendo came after me because there's no way in hell I'd
Speaker 6:  have the the resources to fight anything.
Speaker 3:  Or, and, and honestly litigation is exhausting,
Speaker 3:  right? Like, Nintendo's gonna, you, you fine, I'm gonna fight, I'm gonna
Speaker 3:  spend the money, I'm gonna hire the lawyers. Nintendo's gonna come a after
Speaker 3:  you and say, give me every piece of
Speaker 3:  email that has ever mentioned anyone involved in the development of this
Speaker 3:  emulator. Show me your, all of your history, your dms on
Speaker 3:  GitHub. Like whatever it is. Like, I don't know if GitHub has tms, but you
Speaker 3:  understand what like, show me like involve all of these other people
Speaker 3:  because these are all, almost all volunteer projects in one way or another
Speaker 3:  with lots of different contributors. And it's like, oh, this is gonna be
Speaker 3:  exhausting and not everyone's gonna play ball. And it's all like, yeah, I,
Speaker 3:  I feel for these communities when they come up against this stuff. But it's
Speaker 3:  also just very true that the only mechanism we have
Speaker 3:  in the United States to to handle anything is copyright law. And copyright
Speaker 3:  law is like the Bluntest instrument and you know, YouTube's approach to
Speaker 3:  copyright, right? Like you get three and you're dead. Like that's it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think a lot of people need to know, like they, a lot of people don't
Speaker 6:  know. Nintendo does not serve you with a
Speaker 6:  copyright strike. The copyright strike is a YouTube platform
Speaker 6:  feature where YouTube can make it easier
Speaker 6:  on themselves so that they don't have to face down any
Speaker 6:  lawsuits from Nintendo. They can say, Hey creators,
Speaker 6:  we're going to make this three strikes and you're out rule so that you
Speaker 6:  police yourselves that way we don't need to get involved very often. We'll
Speaker 6:  automate it as much as we can come to us if there's a problem.
Speaker 6:  And maybe we'll reach out to Nintendo on your behalf like they did in this
Speaker 6:  case. YouTube did reach out to Nintendo according
Speaker 6:  to, according to Russ Crall and to see if they would
Speaker 6:  pull their strike willingly once they knew who Russ was and what kind,
Speaker 6:  what Russ stood for. And Nten was like, no, we're not gonna, we're not gonna
Speaker 6:  pull
Speaker 3:  This. That sounds about right. By the way, that entire system is called Notice
Speaker 3:  and takedown. It's in the digital Millennium Copyright Act in every platform
Speaker 3:  has it. YouTube just has one expression of it. And
Speaker 3:  YouTubers running into that stuff when they make the video about it is like
Speaker 3:  when they, when they get their wings, like right, more
Speaker 3:  people are familiar with copyright law because if YouTubers complaining about
Speaker 3:  copyright law then like no the speed limits in their own towns. And this
Speaker 3:  is all just a thing. Anyhow, it's fascinating Sean,
Speaker 3:  you're gonna be writing about this more. 'cause it feels like emulation is
Speaker 3:  a real crossroads.
Speaker 6:  It really is. While I cannot personally write
Speaker 6:  about the Apple aspect of it, it is fascinating,
Speaker 6:  utterly fascinating that this was the year that that
Speaker 6:  Apple said, Hey, you can go ahead and put Retro
Speaker 6:  Game emulators on our iPhone platform.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back with the lightning round unsponsored, although
Speaker 3:  there might be some news on this front.
Speaker 3:  You can sponsor David's mobile repair van David
Speaker 3:  will come to your house and take any iMac you have and turn it into
Speaker 4:  A monitor. David's iMac mobile is still very much up for sponsorship.
Speaker 3:  Have you seen the little board? I think Wes Davis heard about it. There's
Speaker 3:  a little board that lets you turn the Sunflower iMac G four into yes, a monitor.
Speaker 3:  And he has, he has, he did it to his like 20-year-old. Im actually four.
Speaker 3:  And I immediately went on eBay and looked at 20 inch. I'm actually four,
Speaker 3:  which are 20 years old. And they are so expensive. Really?
Speaker 3:  They're crazy expensive.
Speaker 4:  I mean they're just like beautiful furniture. They're they're, they're one
Speaker 4:  of the only gadgets that old that I would happily just like put up
Speaker 4:  on that mantle behind me. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Well I think you gotta, we will link Wes right up, but he was like, why did
Speaker 3:  I do this? 'cause it looks awesome. Yeah, it's good enough, but you can just,
Speaker 3:  it's just an honor. It's great. All right, lightning round. We promised some
Speaker 3:  hot domain name chat, David, what she got.
Speaker 4:  I'm so excited about this. So
Speaker 4:  the other day, this week, Sam Altman just tweets
Speaker 4:  chat.com and you click on it and it goes to chat GPT.
Speaker 4:  It turns out there is a whole fascinating story behind the fact that If,
Speaker 4:  you go to chat.com, it leads you to chat GPT and the,
Speaker 4:  the story in a nutshell is Dharmesh Shah, who is the
Speaker 4:  CTO of HubSpot, bought chat.com
Speaker 4:  for $15 million, 15 and a half million dollars like
Speaker 4:  last year. And then two months later sold it for, we
Speaker 4:  don't know exactly how much, but he said a profit and enough of a profit
Speaker 4:  that he was able to give $250,000 of profit away
Speaker 4:  due with that, which you will, my guess is it was substantially
Speaker 4:  higher than 15 and a half million dollars. I cannot prove that. But based
Speaker 4:  on what I know about domains and the fact that chat.com would be
Speaker 4:  very highly in demand to a large number of people,
Speaker 4:  I suspect that was very expensive and that he made a tidy sum of money in
Speaker 4:  two months on his 15 and a half million dollars domain name purchase.
Speaker 4:  Anyway, it is now the domain name that
Speaker 4:  leads you to chat GPT. Just to clear up a thing that has gotten
Speaker 4:  very confusing on the internet chat. GPT, not rebranded, still
Speaker 4:  called chat. GPT Still a thing a lot of people know, I
Speaker 4:  still hate the fact that GPT is like a term that has entered the
Speaker 4:  public lexicon that we all just say now. Hate that,
Speaker 4:  but it's still called chat GPT. But chat.com now goes there
Speaker 4:  and I think that is going to be the kind of product domain
Speaker 4:  for that thing going forward, which is fascinating in a bunch
Speaker 4:  of different directions. It says something about how important websites still
Speaker 4:  are in the world. It says something about how important.com domains
Speaker 4:  still are in the world. It says something about why OpenAI
Speaker 4:  raised six and a half billion dollars. 'cause domain names are expensive.
Speaker 4:  Like it's just, there's just a lot going on in this one purchase. But
Speaker 4:  this all happened about a year ago and it just rolled out this week. And
Speaker 4:  I think is is now going to be one of the
Speaker 4:  bigger domain names for a pretty long time.
Speaker 3:  It does seem like Dharmesh also got shares of OpenAI, which is fascinating
Speaker 3:  because, oh, interesting because it's not a public company, but it's about
Speaker 3:  to become a for-profit public company. There's a lot here. He should read
Speaker 3:  it. He put, he put up a tweet being like, it's, it's everything. Here's the
Speaker 3:  whole thing. And then he, and then there's a long prompt for chat GBT
Speaker 3:  that helps you. He is like it, it's a prompt that GBT oh one does a really
Speaker 3:  good job of reasoning through. And that ends with how much do you think he
Speaker 3:  sold the chat.com domain for what percent of that was in shares of
Speaker 3:  OpenAI provide an approximate range and show reasoning, but he doesn't show
Speaker 3:  the answer so it can just hallucinate whatever you want.
Speaker 3:  It's very good.
Speaker 3:  So I mean that's wild all the way around. It's not
Speaker 3:  like chat GBT the most successful consumer product in a long time
Speaker 3:  was struggling for with brand recognition. It is also now
Speaker 3:  baked into iPhones or will soon be baked into iPhones. So the idea that they
Speaker 3:  need a domain name is just like pure vanity. It feels like, like they have
Speaker 3:  the distribution that they want, but it does seem like as they go towards
Speaker 3:  being this new kind of for-profit company that they're going to,
Speaker 3:  they're just gonna become more consumer friendly in a variety of different
Speaker 3:  ways.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean I've, I've been saying this on this show for a while now, but
Speaker 4:  I think the, the thing that is happening right now is that
Speaker 4:  OpenAI is being lapped as a product organization by a lot of other folks.
Speaker 4:  Like Apple is building better products around chat GPC right now
Speaker 4:  than
Speaker 3:  OpenAI. Let's not be So you sound
Speaker 4:  Drunk. That's what I'm, that is the lowest bar in history
Speaker 4:  and it's still the case. Like this is, this is where we are and I think
Speaker 3:  Gimme one example of Apple building a better product around CHE V than
Speaker 4:  That. It's easier to get to chat GPT on on iPhone,
Speaker 3:  But that's just a pure distribution advantage that
Speaker 4:  That, but that's my point, right? I like the, the better example is Google
Speaker 4:  is doing much more interesting stuff on top of Gemini
Speaker 3:  If. you had said that first I wouldn't have accused you of drinking on the
Speaker 3:  job, David,
Speaker 4:  This is why you gotta lead with the hot take and then pull it back. This
Speaker 4:  is, this is what we do here. No, but I I think the actual real example is
Speaker 4:  Anthropic and Claude. Yeah. Anthropic is just building
Speaker 4:  vastly better consumer products on top of Claude
Speaker 4:  more quickly than OpenAI, even though OpenAI typically has been first to
Speaker 4:  a lot of the underlying technology. But you're starting to see this shift
Speaker 4:  where, like you said, chat.com becomes just a more
Speaker 4:  understandable way to get to this thing than anything else. Like
Speaker 4:  one thing somebody said to me a long time ago was that just being able to
Speaker 4:  put a simple domain name on a billboard goes a really long
Speaker 4:  way. Like just, just to be able to, just like you can imagine the
Speaker 4:  billboard, right? That it's just like a pure white billboard and it just
Speaker 4:  says chat.com on it. Like that's powerful in a way that like
Speaker 4:  openai.com/chat gpt is not powerful. And
Speaker 4:  there's just a bunch of little things like that. They've, they've launched
Speaker 4:  this new set of models that are starting with oh one instead of GPT dash
Speaker 4:  four oh Turbo. Like they're getting slowly better at
Speaker 4:  putting this in front of people in a way that is slightly understandable
Speaker 4:  that only goes as far as your products go.
Speaker 3:  I will say chat.com 100% sounds like a 1990
Speaker 3:  dating site. That's, I mean that's just what that sounds like.
Speaker 4:  I mean it does great
Speaker 3:  And I met my wife there to be honest.
Speaker 4:  Rename Chadic bt to plenty of Fish and we'll be good to go.
Speaker 3:  Shout out to Casey for the wife joke.
Speaker 4:  Wait, do you wanna know, by the way, I, I plugged all of this into Chad
Speaker 4:  GBT, all the stuff Dharmesh said to do, I just did. Yeah. And the, it gives
Speaker 4:  a lot of thoughts and then the conclusion it draws is Dharmesh
Speaker 4:  likely sold chat.com for around 20 to $30 million with 25 to
Speaker 4:  50% of that amount in open AI shares. Ordinarily that's based
Speaker 4:  on nothing. And I wouldn't believe it, but that, that's what he told us to
Speaker 4:  do. So I think you can take that as something like the truth. And if that's
Speaker 4:  the case, and he did it a while ago, which it sounds like
Speaker 4:  he did, that man has made a ton of money on this domain
Speaker 4:  name because like what, what happened to the valuation of OpenAI with this
Speaker 4:  new fundraising? What is, what like this was, this is a
Speaker 4:  damn good domain name purchase. If indeed it is what
Speaker 4:  Chate says it is, it's
Speaker 3:  So much better than debacle.com, which I simply let expire
Speaker 4:  You're missing out.
Speaker 3:  Do you think they're gonna rename chat GBT to just chat? No,
Speaker 4:  I don't. I think chat g bt is actually against all odds, a very good brand.
Speaker 4:  People know what it is. I think it, it actually explains itself better than
Speaker 4:  like Claude. And so there there is a, it it is
Speaker 4:  sort of Kleenex in the AI world right now where like people know
Speaker 4:  it better than any other AI product. And
Speaker 4:  like If, you can make Google work for 25 years, you can probably make Chad
Speaker 4:  GBT work for 25 years and yeah, I I think they work Is that,
Speaker 6:  Is that a problem for them? I I thought the famous thing about Kleenex was
Speaker 6:  that Kleenex did not like that Kleenex was
Speaker 3:  Generic. Oh, you were saying Kleenex, I thought you were saying K Clean exe.
Speaker 3:  And I was like, I don't know what David's talking about
Speaker 3:  Kleenex. That's what you've been saying.
Speaker 4:  Oh boy, we all need to go outside.
Speaker 3:  Has has it been a weird few days? Is my brain mush?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no.
Speaker 3:  Have I had to earn unearth stories from 2016 to 2020 and be like, oh, I used
Speaker 3:  to know a lot about this. Yes. Clean doe. Yeah, it's,
Speaker 4:  It's a classic,
Speaker 3:  It was a defra program that everyone loved.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. No, but Sean, to your point, I think, I think there is something to
Speaker 4:  that. I think it is, that's like real sort of champagne problems stuff
Speaker 4:  when you become so big that other people start associating knockoff
Speaker 4:  products with your product. Like everybody wants to have that problem, even
Speaker 4:  though that problem is kind of annoying. And I think,
Speaker 3:  And even though that, just to be clear, that problem is also fake. Kleenex
Speaker 3:  owns its trademark. They have not lost the rights to the word Kleenex.
Speaker 4:  But the idea that you go see any tissue in the store by
Speaker 4:  any brand and you're like, oh, it's Kleenex is like, you can see how that's
Speaker 4:  a problem for Kleenex, but I don't think Kleenex is upset about it. I think
Speaker 4:  they're doing fine.
Speaker 3:  There's a well a fine, there's a, they made like a musical
Speaker 3:  about it or one of these companies with one of these names like this made
Speaker 3:  an entire musical about how you're not supposed to say it, you're supposed
Speaker 3:  to say something else, which is why they all say facial tissue. Amazing.
Speaker 3:  That is a, this is a horrible tangent and now it's time to talk about the
Speaker 3:  matter. Smart Home standard, which is my lightning run
Speaker 3:  matter. 1.4 is out, we're two years into this. I will tell
Speaker 3:  you that I needed a smart plug for our Halloween decorations and I bought
Speaker 3:  just the regular Miros home kit ones and the Miros matter ones
Speaker 3:  and the matter ones were so finicky that I just sent 'em back and I was like,
Speaker 3:  well this still isn't ready. And that's kind of where I'm at with matter.
Speaker 3:  But Matter 1.4 is out. Jen Tooey wrote about it. She's been tracking every
Speaker 3:  ounce of changes to the standard is always with matter updates,
Speaker 3:  there's more devices. So there's heat pumps and solar panels. They did
Speaker 3:  robot vacuums. All this stuff is all happening. They still don't have security
Speaker 3:  cameras. The reason I wanna talk about it is, one, the vocabulary is
Speaker 3:  amazing and I need to explain to the vocabulary to
Speaker 3:  explain the thing that is good about Matter 1.4. So
Speaker 3:  in the matter standard, every smart home ecosystem is called
Speaker 3:  a fabric.
Speaker 3:  You follow me on this? So Apple Home Kit is a fabric,
Speaker 3:  Amazon Alexa is a fabric,
Speaker 3:  I don't know why they picked fabric. I'm guessing it's because the radio
Speaker 3:  standard is called Thread. Yes. But they don't all run on thread.
Speaker 3:  It's very confusing. They're all called fabrics. And the big thing, the
Speaker 3:  big, big thing in matter 1.4 is multimin
Speaker 3:  across fabrics, which is yet more vocabulary. But
Speaker 3:  all it really means is that when you set up all of your devices in Apple
Speaker 3:  Home and then connect to Alexa,
Speaker 3:  they all just go over there. So you don't have to set them up in two places
Speaker 3:  at once. Which is a thing you would've thought they would've figured out
Speaker 3:  from the beginning of matter.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I just assumed that was how it already worked.
Speaker 3:  None of this, none of this worked at the beginning of matter. Like okay,
Speaker 3:  the border routers between wifi and thread weren't incompatible that
Speaker 3:  the auth was in Compat, like none of this stuff worked. So they've got, they've
Speaker 3:  had the standard on the market, which is, you know, apple
Speaker 3:  kinda like really pushed this. They've worked with Amazon, they've worked
Speaker 3:  with Google to get the standard out. It's built on HomeKit in a lot of ways.
Speaker 3:  And the idea is all of these smart home devices should be compatible with
Speaker 3:  everyone's ecosystems. And for about two years what that has meant is
Speaker 3:  there's more devices, but they're really only com only compatible
Speaker 3:  with the one you choose to make them compatible with. Right? If, you have
Speaker 3:  Google home stuff and Alexa stuff in your house and HomeKit you kinda like
Speaker 3:  pair your smart plug to one so you have more choice because
Speaker 3:  the matter accessory makers can just make one thing, but you don't actually
Speaker 3:  get more compatibility.
Speaker 4:  What you just described is directly against the whole point of matter,
Speaker 3:  Right? So they have finally done the thing,
Speaker 4:  They did matter, now
Speaker 3:  They did the thing they're calling it God enhance to multi admin.
Speaker 3:  It lets the thread, border routers thread is the lobe power wireless
Speaker 3:  signal that all this stuff's supposed to run on. So the border routers that
Speaker 3:  bridge from thread to wifi are now compatible. So you can an hero and
Speaker 3:  a home pod mini and all this other stuff and they will bridge the thread
Speaker 3:  and make one big thread network instead of multiple thread networks, which
Speaker 3:  is what they've been doing up until now. They're doing
Speaker 3:  a better job of managing wifi routers that have thread routers in them. All
Speaker 3:  this stuff needed to exist. But the main thing is
Speaker 3:  bridging multi admin across fabrics, which is just platforms. And that means
Speaker 3:  you can set it all up in HomeKit and then you can buy an Amazon Alexa and
Speaker 3:  be like, I already have a matter, I already have all this stuff and it, we'll
Speaker 3:  just figure it out. Now is any of that gonna work?
Speaker 3:  Will it import your rooms and your device names and all the stuff
Speaker 3:  that you need to like really make that work? Un unclear. Jenna's very
Speaker 3:  good reporter. She asked the matter people this and they did not
Speaker 3:  say,
Speaker 6:  I really, really like Jen's whole quote in this story. I
Speaker 6:  I'm, I'm hearing it in her British accent right now. Matter will make
Speaker 6:  everyone play together nicely this time. Promise.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, Bluetooth is gonna work great next year. That's, that's where matter
Speaker 3:  is. It's in the zone. And I forgot to mention, by the way, the reason I've
Speaker 3:  been pointing out it's called fabric this entire time is this is called fabric
Speaker 3:  sink,
Speaker 4:  Which is nothing. This thing should be called like needle or sewing machine.
Speaker 4:  Like there's a bunch of, there's so many things we could do here, but if
Speaker 4:  you're gonna commit to this stupid bit, you have to commit to it correctly.
Speaker 3:  And the quote from the call
Speaker 4:  It like color match. Like I listen, I have ideas
Speaker 6:  Poly in
Speaker 3:  The quote from the Connectivity Standards Alliance spokesperson here is if
Speaker 3:  a new device shows up on fabric A, it can automatically be added to fabric
Speaker 3:  B.
Speaker 3:  However, it is unclear whether the correct name and location of the new device
Speaker 3:  will automatically go to the other platforms. If, you have to enter this
Speaker 3:  manually that will be up to the platforms to implement. So another year
Speaker 3:  matter 1.5, everybody Bluetooth is gonna be great next year,
Speaker 3:  but this is the thing, we're so close, it's all coming into focus now,
Speaker 3:  right? You buy a smart home device, you just add it to one system,
Speaker 3:  suddenly you can just talk to your Google home and access that device. This
Speaker 3:  is the thing everybody wants so close.
Speaker 4:  We are in that funny moment now where it's like, if we could just
Speaker 4:  pretend that every smart home gadget that had ever been made didn't exist
Speaker 4:  and start from scratch, we could build the good things so quickly.
Speaker 4:  But because we did the good things so late, everybody is having
Speaker 4:  to back their way into making this make any sense in a way that is just
Speaker 4:  gonna make it worse for everybody for a long time. Like every, every story
Speaker 4:  about matter getting better makes me wanna buy smart home products less
Speaker 3:  Because
Speaker 4:  I'm like, this all sounds great and I have absolutely no belief that any
Speaker 4:  of it is coming to anything that I own. Ever.
Speaker 3:  Look David, you just keep looking at your garbage TV and I'll let you know
Speaker 3:  when it's time. All right. By the way, I wanna say thank you to the dozens,
Speaker 3:  if not two dozens of people who wrote to me and
Speaker 3:  Joanna about smart garage door openers and the people in particular who
Speaker 3:  mentioned the Rat Go product, which stands for Rage Against the Garage Door
Speaker 3:  opener. Amazing, incredible hobbyist project name. It is a hack
Speaker 3:  that gets past the Chamberlain security plus protocol, which it is true that
Speaker 3:  Joanna stood on a ladder and installed one of the things and she has a Chamberlain
Speaker 3:  thing, which drms the button, the button
Speaker 3:  on a Chamberlain. This is the power of Monopoly. The button is DMed
Speaker 3:  with a, the security protocol. So it's awful.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 3:  All ridiculous. But there's a hack called the Raco Rage against the garage
Speaker 3:  opener. And now she's ordering one of those, I believe.
Speaker 4:  Love that.
Speaker 3:  This is our community, you're our family. All right. No matter what happens
Speaker 3:  out there, we've got your back
Speaker 3:  and Joanna is literally texting me photos of herself on a ladder. It's very
Speaker 3:  good. All right, Sean, what do you got?
Speaker 6:  I also have a maros in my garage that I need to install and hopefully get
Speaker 6:  around the Chamberlain TRM button. But I've also got a
Speaker 6:  story about Nvidia, a company that made
Speaker 6:  $16.6 billion in pure profit last quarter
Speaker 6:  has decided to cap the game streaming hours on GForce. Now
Speaker 6:  its cloud gaming service for its whales. I don't know why
Speaker 6:  they're doing this. They are doing it in the best way possible, believe
Speaker 6:  me, I I I will tell you all about it. So first off, it's a 100
Speaker 6:  hour cap per month. So you have to play more than like three
Speaker 6:  hours every single day of cloud gaming, which is a lot of cloud
Speaker 6:  gaming to get to this cap. Mm. And they're not
Speaker 6:  going to instill that monthly cap until
Speaker 6:  January 1st, 2025 for new
Speaker 6:  users. And I think it'll be, yeah, 2026
Speaker 6:  for existing users before they lose their plate types. So If, you get in
Speaker 6:  now, or if you've already been a user, you don't have this monthly cap until
Speaker 6:  an entire year from January. In addition to that,
Speaker 6:  while some people were worried that they would lose their founders' memberships,
Speaker 6:  that they would suddenly have a cap on their founders' memberships that were
Speaker 6:  promised to have a certain quality of streaming for the rest of their lives,
Speaker 6:  as long as they maintain their monthly dues. And videos come out very recently
Speaker 6:  in an FAQ and they says, founders, as long as you keep paying, you won't
Speaker 6:  have a cap either. So founders are taken care of, existing customers
Speaker 6:  are taking care of for a year. New customers can get taken care of for a
Speaker 6:  year if they start early. Lots of lots. They, they,
Speaker 6:  they've gotten out ahead of this. They're telling everybody, it's clear,
Speaker 6:  their messaging is clear. They're doing a good job compared to most of the
Speaker 6:  companies that we needle for this. But I don't understand why
Speaker 6:  they're doing it at all, because the only people they're going to hit with
Speaker 6:  this are the whales who I would assume
Speaker 6:  are their most vocal and passionate supporters of this
Speaker 6:  service.
Speaker 3:  Once you got a whale man, you just keep going after 'em.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, just keep raising prices. That's the way
Speaker 3:  It goes. You've never run a casino,
Speaker 6:  But they're not, they're not charging more. Look, why don't they, why don't
Speaker 6:  they, why don't they say, Hey, you know, well, well, well you can pay more
Speaker 6:  for the unlimited, but they don't have that as an option. They're just like,
Speaker 6:  no, we're capping it for everybody.
Speaker 4:  So I. Actually, in a funny way, I think doing what you
Speaker 4:  just described ends up being a worse PR move to basically
Speaker 4:  say, oh, you want the unlimited thing now you have to pay more for it. You're
Speaker 4:  gonna piss people off more that way than doing what Nvidia did.
Speaker 4:  I still, I have two thoughts on this one. Maybe Nvidia should make
Speaker 4:  better chips that do all this stuff more efficiently. This sounds like an
Speaker 4:  Nvidia problem, not an anybody else problem. You got a bunch of money,
Speaker 4:  maybe you should make better chips. Nvidia, that's just thought. I think
Speaker 4:  number two, and this was everywhere in the comments on this story,
Speaker 4:  and it was my reaction too, is just like, oh God,
Speaker 4:  another really great reason to not bet on cloud gaming is, is
Speaker 4:  like everywhere you turn, it feels like something about this deal is
Speaker 4:  not living up to its potential. And it's, I mean, it, it goes back to the
Speaker 4:  same stuff we're talking about with even just downloading digital games.
Speaker 4:  Like there, there is this sense that all
Speaker 4:  of this could be ripped away from me at any time. And none of these companies
Speaker 4:  are doing anything to make that not feel like the case. And
Speaker 4:  even this, I, I agree with you that this is a relatively small thing and
Speaker 4:  it will not hit that many people, but it's just another one of those things
Speaker 4:  that's like, maybe don't bet too much on this
Speaker 4:  being a good thing for you forever.
Speaker 6:  I wrote a piece three years ago that the only way cloud gaming is gonna
Speaker 6:  succeed is if it removes all of this friction. And
Speaker 6:  it theoretically could, like once upon a time you could just press
Speaker 6:  a button on a web browser and you'd be playing a game instantly in your web
Speaker 6:  browser. No problem. On a Chromebooks
Speaker 4:  Thing, you can do Assassin's Creed. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But, but, but I wrote, I I just put, laid out a list of bullet points there.
Speaker 6:  These are all the things that go through people's minds. Yeah. Before they
Speaker 6:  sign up for cloud gaming. What if my connection isn't good enough? What if
Speaker 6:  my home networking gear isn't good enough? What if I live too far away from
Speaker 6:  the servers? Will it actually have the games I wanna play? Will there be
Speaker 6:  enough of them to justify the fee? Will developers bother to port new games
Speaker 6:  over? Will they run as well as if I just bought a console or pc? Will I need
Speaker 6:  a special controller, a dongle? Will I go over my data cap? Will I be able
Speaker 6:  to play with my friends who are in different platforms? Will I lose access
Speaker 6:  to my games if they lose a distribution deal or shut down the servers? Will
Speaker 6:  I have to wait in line to play the games? Can I get my save games? What about
Speaker 6:  the outages? Are they hiding how well these games will run? What if the company
Speaker 6:  decides it no longer wants to be a game company? Which has happened to several
Speaker 6:  of these platforms now. There's just so much
Speaker 6:  uncertainty going in. And just one more piece here from
Speaker 6:  Nvidia.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You've sold me. I'm buying a $700 PS five Pro. I'm
Speaker 3:  sitting two feet away from it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Every time, every time we talk about this stuff, I'm like, I'm all
Speaker 4:  in on Blu-rays again, I'm all in on game cartridges and I'm buying a console.
Speaker 4:  Like it's, it's the only way. Turn off all the internet and just let me play
Speaker 4:  games offline. It's gonna be fine. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Homesteading. But for video games, yeah. I'm gonna grow them myself
Speaker 3:  outside.
Speaker 6:  It's too bad though. 'cause, 'cause 'cause it works so well and those people
Speaker 6:  that Nvidia are capping know it. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Is GForce nine a success? I mean, you mentioned how much money they're making,
Speaker 3:  but they're making money selling H one hundreds to meta. Is, is GForce now
Speaker 3:  a success for them?
Speaker 6:  We don't know. I mean, I'm guessing it's it's got, it's gotta be a cost for
Speaker 6:  them. You know, because they have, they have massive
Speaker 6:  hardware investment and, and, and infrastructure investment to stand this
Speaker 6:  thing up. Theoretically they could say, oh yeah,
Speaker 6:  we've got a data center that can do this AI thing, or it could also do that
Speaker 6:  GForce now thing. Maybe they're starting to build it that way. But last time
Speaker 6:  I looked there were special cloud gaming
Speaker 6:  specific data centers for this thing laid out in a
Speaker 6:  particular way with particular chips. So
Speaker 4:  It also kinda makes you wonder if they're capping it at a hundred hours a
Speaker 4:  month, what are the whales playing like the, the, the
Speaker 4:  top 1% of GForce now users, like how many hours a month
Speaker 4:  must they be playing for Nvidia to decide that it has to have this hard cap?
Speaker 4:  It's gotta be a lot like If. you have If, you have a bunch of people who
Speaker 4:  are at like 102 hours. You're not introducing this cap. They're like,
Speaker 4:  they found somebody who is just like, has the