# Transcript
ID: 34e71979-de90-456a-a888-5dd82bec16fd
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-762096955406828610/5917599941658685726/s93290-US-5720s-1717147769.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss Google's algorithm leak, OpenAI content deals, and more tech news from this week.
Speaker 3:  immediately starting there. Hi, I'm your friend. Neli Alex. Cranz
Speaker 3:  how the Facebook algorithm works. Like this is true insight into the
Speaker 3:  Google Search algorithm. So you gotta talk about that and the fallout across
Speaker 3:  the web from that
Speaker 3:  Google Search continues to be bananas. There's a bunch of open AI news.
Speaker 3:  I know people want us to talk about Fox Media's deal with OpenAI, which
Speaker 3:  I will to whatever extent that is interesting. Then we got a lightning round
Speaker 3:  unsponsored for now, Sam.
Speaker 3:  But there's one piece of news that I think
Speaker 3:  dominates the week
Speaker 5:  Y. Yeah, you definitely think it dominates the week.
Speaker 3:  And that is The. Verge has received a review unit
Speaker 3:  of the Sony Field seven ULT speaker. It's
Speaker 3:  enormous. It's, this is a medium sized one. It's so big. If you're
Speaker 6:  Not watching this on YouTube, just imagine Neli pulled a grenade launcher
Speaker 6:  out from underneath
Speaker 3:  The table. I love it so much. It's
Speaker 3:  3 99 and as as many of you know, I think the internet
Speaker 3:  has eras and I think technology has eras. We've talked a lot about the end
Speaker 3:  of the Google Search era on the internet. What that might mean, perhaps with
Speaker 3:  the dawn of the AI era. Certainly we were in the mobile era for quite a long
Speaker 3:  time. The social era, this is the ULT era. And
Speaker 3:  what I mean by that is if the eighties were dominated by Megabase in the
Speaker 3:  nineties were dominated by Megabase, I would say that the twenties, the,
Speaker 3:  the two thousands, 2010s kind of a stumble through
Speaker 3:  Sony's extra base era.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it wasn't pleasant. There was no,
Speaker 3:  You know, it didn't hit. We're now in what Sony has called the
Speaker 3:  ULT era.
Speaker 5:  Ooh, I like
Speaker 3:  These candles. That's what the buttons, that's what the button says on it
Speaker 3:  right here. ULT.
Speaker 6:  There's a ULT button. Wait, that changes
Speaker 3:  Everything. There's a T button and it lights up. I'm just gonna turn this
Speaker 3:  guy on here. It's so big. There we go. I in
Speaker 3:  fact
Speaker 5:  Can't see Neli through the speaker.
Speaker 3:  I'm told that if I hold this play button down for five seconds, we get
Speaker 3:  royalty free demo music. You hear that YouTube
Speaker 3:  royalty free
Speaker 5:  And you guys can't see the the, the lights, but they're there.
Speaker 3:  There she goes.
Speaker 3:  Now, I don't know if you can see the amount of the speaker that's currently
Speaker 3:  lit up, but it's, it's both drivers. And then
Speaker 3:  on the front,
Speaker 3:  the ULT button is rainbow blinking. And when you push that,
Speaker 3:  yeah, you get massive base. Ultimate vibe. This
Speaker 3:  is the most important product in technology.
Speaker 6:  Do you think if you press the ULT button right now, the podcast
Speaker 6:  would explode.
Speaker 3:  Let's find out.
Speaker 3:  Wait, you gotta wait for the drop to come back.
Speaker 3:  Is this English?
Speaker 5:  It's ish.
Speaker 3:  Oh, there's another song.
Speaker 7:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 3:  Oh. Got so much quieter when I pushed the ULT button.
Speaker 3:  Does it just, it just makes little drum hits when you push the U.
Speaker 3:  Can you hear that? Yes. It's like a Tim,
Speaker 3:  I don't know man. Like I'm trying to sell this and it's not going great.
Speaker 3:  The
Speaker 5:  Handles are great. We're turning into QVC or TikTok.
Speaker 5:  I, this is on our TikTok store right now. Now we do have a good handle for
Speaker 5:  $400.
Speaker 3:  It won't burn down your house
Speaker 5:  That we know of. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Anyway, look, all I'm saying is we went from the Megabase era to the
Speaker 3:  extra base era, which again, I think was a failure. I don't,
Speaker 5:  I mean the ULT era is is not bumping so
Speaker 5:  far. Well
Speaker 3:  It's just, I mean the first song is good
Speaker 6:  Extra is not more than mega. And so what happened is in the mega
Speaker 6:  era, everybody went deaf and so couldn't hear the extra era.
Speaker 6:  So, but now we have Ultimate, which all the deaf people in their forties
Speaker 6:  can
Speaker 3:  Hear now. So it's back it look, it has powerful sound with an ex
Speaker 3:  balance speaker unit and 30 hours
Speaker 3:  of battery life. It
Speaker 5:  If it just, also the windows rattle though, is it really
Speaker 3:  Big? I just think it's funny when you try to make a spec sheet for a product
Speaker 3:  that is insane and you're just like, or be lights
Speaker 3:  next to a bullet point. Look, it's the ULT era. I've never been more excited
Speaker 3:  about a product in my entire life. That's The Vergecast everybody. People
Speaker 3:  have been
Speaker 6:  Wondering about when we're gonna give a 10 outta 10 and I think it might
Speaker 6:  be happening it's, it might
Speaker 3:  Be time. By the way, this is the medium sized one. Oh my god,
Speaker 3:  this is the seven. There's also a 10.
Speaker 3:  I cannot wait for that one to arrive. They also sent us two sevens. Chris
Speaker 3:  Welsh just has one in his house taking up most of his home. All right. There's
Speaker 3:  a lot of news this week. A lot of it is about
Speaker 3:  AI and what it is doing to the internet. If you've been listening
Speaker 3:  to our show or reading The Verge or listening to coder, whatever,
Speaker 3:  you know that we've had a thesis for a while now, stretching
Speaker 3:  back into the middle of last year that the internet was about to get flipped
Speaker 3:  over. Not just by AI but by search in general,
Speaker 3:  by social platforms falling apart. I dunno if you're aware,
Speaker 3:  they changed the name from Twitter to X, like something's
Speaker 3:  happening. Yeah. And one thing that we really wanted to do
Speaker 3:  was pay a lot of attention to what things were like now so we could
Speaker 3:  properly describe how they changed, which meant we did a lot of SEO coverage
Speaker 3:  last year. Covered the culture of SEO, the community of SEO,
Speaker 3:  why, why the web looks like an SEO disaster. How Google
Speaker 3:  fights back against SEO Mia Sato did a lot of that reporting for us.
Speaker 3:  I think I've radicalized her, like you make someone care about SEO for eight
Speaker 3:  months. They come out a different person on the other side. But Mia's doing
Speaker 3:  a great job of that reporting. We had a great feature from Amanda Chicago
Speaker 3:  Lewis. The SEO community is still mad about that. Featured an alligator
Speaker 3:  party. We, we will link all this up. You can read it. The, the point I'm
Speaker 3:  trying to make is we felt like it was changing. I think that hunch was correct,
Speaker 3:  right? Ye
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean Google kind of sucks now, right? I'm using coy,
Speaker 3:  So Google sucks now, right? There's other search products. Google is rolling
Speaker 3:  out AI overviews and then over the
Speaker 3:  long weekend
Speaker 3:  a bunch of SEO people discovered that
Speaker 3:  the API documentation for Google Search had been
Speaker 3:  inadvertently made public on GitHub for quite some time.
Speaker 3:  And there were a couple blog posts, one that was just like, here's how I
Speaker 3:  found it, here's who showed it to me. That one's really interesting. And
Speaker 3:  then there's another one that's more of a deep dive into here's what it says.
Speaker 3:  And then there was a little bit of back and forth about is this real? Like
Speaker 3:  can we trust what we're seeing? Because some of what the
Speaker 3:  documentation revealed is that Google has not been telling the whole truth
Speaker 3:  about how search works for a very, very long time. And so some of the
Speaker 3:  headlines in these posts are like, is Google lying to us? And some of the
Speaker 3:  copy in these posts is like, Google has been lying to us. Google was initially
Speaker 3:  just totally dead silent, which is weird. Like usually we
Speaker 3:  at least get a no comment. But Mia sent a bunch of emails, we sent some
Speaker 3:  texts, Hey, is there anything? Do you want to deny that this is real
Speaker 3:  dead silence? Then yesterday, Wednesday, Google
Speaker 3:  confirmed the leaks. They said, this is real. And they said,
Speaker 3:  and they said, we would caution against making inaccurate assumptions about
Speaker 3:  search based on out of context Tator and complete information. Basically
Speaker 3:  they're saying, yeah, this is real. But no, it's not super real. It's a
Speaker 3:  lot. David, you have been covering search and how it works and
Speaker 3:  thinking about it. You use the most browsers and search engines of anyone.
Speaker 3:  I know there's some real explosive
Speaker 3:  information here, but it's still not clear how much we should take seriously
Speaker 3:  and how much Google is lying. It's just a lot of angry people are
Speaker 3:  suddenly like, oh, this is what I've been angry about.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's a weird moment because Google Search has always been
Speaker 6:  a black box. Google has very deliberately not
Speaker 6:  revealed how Google Search works and what it cares about. In
Speaker 6:  part because it's so complicated that it's actually a hard,
Speaker 6:  borderline impossible thing to sit down and explain to somebody why
Speaker 6:  something is where it is in search results. Like I don't think any individual
Speaker 6:  person at Google knows the answer to that question. It's just not how the
Speaker 6:  system works anymore. But also because the more
Speaker 6:  Google reveals about how search works, the more tools it is
Speaker 6:  giving people with which to game Google Search, which has been the cat and
Speaker 6:  mouse game they've been playing forever. And so what has been happening
Speaker 6:  is people have been asking Google what
Speaker 6:  is going on? What systems and rankings does Google care about? What
Speaker 6:  can I do to make my stuff rank higher in Google Search? And Google has given
Speaker 6:  a lot of answers that these 2,500 pages
Speaker 6:  of internal API documents say are essentially not true.
Speaker 6:  Like there, there are a series of things that Google has in these documents
Speaker 6:  that it has explicitly said out loud. It does not consider in search ranking.
Speaker 6:  Are those two statements completely mutually exclusive? No. Which is why
Speaker 6:  this gets so weird, right? Like there are, I forget the exact number, but
Speaker 6:  it was right around 14,000 individual things
Speaker 6:  referenced in these pages, which is basically like 14,000 different signals.
Speaker 6:  How those are ranked which matter more, which matter less,
Speaker 6:  whether they're all even counted how old this information is,
Speaker 6:  what some of the terms actually mean. Very hard to know because a lot of
Speaker 6:  them are terms we've never seen before that Google has been saying for years
Speaker 6:  didn't exist. But what what seems to be true is
Speaker 6:  you don't have a, a heading in your API for
Speaker 6:  a thing that you don't care about. Yeah. And so for things that Google
Speaker 6:  has for years said that it doesn't care about, there is now
Speaker 6:  evidence that it is at least a piece of data that Google collects. And one
Speaker 6:  of the wild things is that people who do SEO spend a lot of time testing
Speaker 6:  theories and they've been testing theories and people like the,
Speaker 6:  the guy who broke the story, Rand Fishkin, have gotten
Speaker 6:  crap from people in the community for running tests and saying things like,
Speaker 6:  oh, it seems like Google Search really cares about clickthrough rates. And
Speaker 6:  people at Google saying, no, no, no, no, we don't care about clickthrough
Speaker 6:  rates. You're an idiot. And this overwhelmingly makes it look like Google
Speaker 6:  cares an awful lot about clickthrough rates. And so now we're in this place
Speaker 6:  where I think a big part of what we've been seeing from the SEO community
Speaker 6:  is people who are like, oh, not only has Google not been telling us the truth,
Speaker 6:  they've been lying to our faces and making like gaslighting us into
Speaker 6:  believing the wrong thing about how Google Search works. And it's
Speaker 6:  a weird like existential crisis when that happens.
Speaker 3:  And the thing I'll just like try to chain together is we started paying attention
Speaker 3:  to this story last year. 'cause we wanted to know what
Speaker 3:  this ecosystem was like, right? Like we wanted a picture
Speaker 3:  of maybe like the last days of disco, right? Like here's what it was
Speaker 3:  like before the comment hits. And I thought the comment would be AI
Speaker 3:  or the end of social networks or Google keeping more traffic inside a
Speaker 3:  featured whatever the comment is. And it kind of feels like the comment is
Speaker 3:  actually just knowing that Google wasn't telling the whole truth, right?
Speaker 3:  Like the headings in these blog posts, like legitimately there's a, a trade
Speaker 3:  publication called Search Engine Land that we've been watching a lot of the
Speaker 3:  coverage of this on that site. It's one of the bigger SEO trade publications
Speaker 3:  to exist. And the headings are like, how does SEO move on from here? One
Speaker 3:  of the subheadings in their piece where they run the Google statement was,
Speaker 3:  did Google lie to us? That's just a subhead. That's just a straight H
Speaker 3:  two on their story. Because that,
Speaker 6:  Which by the way, people do in order to be ranked higher in Google, you put
Speaker 6:  questions people might Google in an H two. I'm serious, right? And that is
Speaker 6:  like push this all the way down and it's like what's inside this
Speaker 6:  document is how the internet works, right? Yeah. Like people have built the
Speaker 6:  internet to try to figure out how to game the stuff that is
Speaker 6:  inside these 2,500 pages. And like you, you can reverse engineer the
Speaker 6:  internet out of Google's API, which I think is why this feels so huge. Like
Speaker 6:  your your point about the Facebook algorithm that you've been saying all
Speaker 6:  week, like this is the, on the order of leaking the Facebook algorithm like
Speaker 6:  it is, and in the way that understanding the Facebook algorithm would
Speaker 6:  essentially help us understand a decade of our online relationships. Like
Speaker 6:  this is the internet in 2,500 pages of like weird inscrutable
Speaker 6:  API calls. And
Speaker 5:  I think that's hard for people who aren't in the SEO business or our
Speaker 5:  business, which is kind of the SEO business to fully wrap their
Speaker 3:  Hands up. We make websites, if you make a website, you care about this a
Speaker 3:  little bit. Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We have to, right? Like it's required. I I I edit buying
Speaker 5:  guides. I I have to care a lot about SEO and people who don't care about
Speaker 5:  SEO. They like, I go and I tell my friends, I'm like this huge document,
Speaker 5:  like cash of documents drop. This is huge. And they're like, why are you,
Speaker 5:  what is SEO
Speaker 3:  Elon? Musk says I'm gonna open source the Twitter algorithm and this is front
Speaker 3:  page news. The API calls or fields
Speaker 3:  basically of what data Google collects to run ranking algorithm
Speaker 3:  leaks. And it's like us like freaking out. Yeah. And it's kind of nowhere.
Speaker 3:  And I, and like to David's point, we
Speaker 3:  don't know how these things are ranked. That's true. But we do know that
Speaker 3:  Google has said for years it does not collect some of this data or care about
Speaker 3:  some of this data. And it definitely does. What are you gonna do with that?
Speaker 3:  Rand Fishkin the same person you mentioned, David has gone spent a long time
Speaker 3:  saying it seems like that this thing called dwell time is important.
Speaker 3:  So you click through a Google result, you land on a website, you're there
Speaker 3:  for however long you come back to Google, you go to the next one, that time
Speaker 3:  you spend in the website. He is like, that seems important. And Google has
Speaker 3:  basically said no. Yep. They're tracking that too. Yeah. The one that I think
Speaker 3:  is the most explosive, which we don't really know how to understand,
Speaker 3:  is click data from Chrome and it's there
Speaker 3:  somewhere. Right? So one thing we know that Google does,
Speaker 3:  which is a little shaky, is when you search
Speaker 3:  for a website, I think the example that came out in one of the antitrust
Speaker 3:  trials was Vogue or Cosmopolitan. It was some magazine like
Speaker 3:  this.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it was one of those. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And you get the website and right below it in the search result, you get
Speaker 3:  their headings like beauty, fashion style coverage, met gala.
Speaker 3:  Those headings are generated by what people click on in those websites in
Speaker 3:  Chrome. Yeah. And Google has forever
Speaker 3:  said it does not use data from Chrome to impact search.
Speaker 3:  And then you look at these API docs and you're like, oh, it's in, there's
Speaker 3:  data from Chrome. Like it's potential that Google is actually
Speaker 3:  using that for search. And they have sworn up and down to every regulator,
Speaker 3:  to every SEO professional to everyone that these things are not the same.
Speaker 3:  What are you gonna do with that?
Speaker 6:  It's such a funny example too because like of course Google does that,
Speaker 6:  like thi this to me, so much of this leak is things that you
Speaker 6:  would obviously assume Google is doing except that Google has been denying
Speaker 6:  doing it for years. That it turns out, in fact Google is doing, like
Speaker 6:  I'm in the business of knowing which links are good. And I also run
Speaker 6:  a browser in which billions of people click links every day. Like
Speaker 6:  at some point you'd be insane not to let one affect
Speaker 6:  the other. You have maybe the best possible data stream, which is the
Speaker 6:  links that people go to and how long they spend there, which is literally,
Speaker 6:  that is all you could ever want to know in search rankings. And so
Speaker 6:  the idea that they are spread apart and not, you know,
Speaker 6:  in any way correlated out of the goodness of Google's heart, I think has
Speaker 6:  always been sort of silly to people. And so to some extent
Speaker 6:  it's like, it, it just confirms what your instincts tell you in
Speaker 6:  a lot of this league. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I keep going back to Neli. Earlier you said this was kinda like a
Speaker 5:  comment hitting, and I feel like it's definitely a comment for the SEO community,
Speaker 5:  but for the rest of us, we've kind of been in more like high
Speaker 5:  waters rising as apocalypses, right? Like the Google,
Speaker 5:  the Google experience for 90% of people has just been like, okay, the sea
Speaker 5:  levels are rising now and and it feels like this was maybe that
Speaker 5:  big push in the water. Oh, now it's covering Manhattans. Dang it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean it, it, it does feel like the dam is breaking. One
Speaker 3:  of the things that we were talking about when we did our decoder episode
Speaker 3:  recently about Google Zero was the stuff leaks. 'cause people are mad.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And so if you were an SEO operator and you
Speaker 3:  uncovered a bunch of secret data that Google was
Speaker 3:  collecting, you would not tell the SEO community.
Speaker 3:  Right? Like you would, you would definitely keep that to yourself. But instead
Speaker 3:  what's happening is people are mad and they're like, look at all these lies
Speaker 3:  or look at what we perceive to be lies. Yeah. And there's
Speaker 3:  just a lot of the, the ideas that people have had about
Speaker 3:  how Google Search works, one of them is domain authority. So a very
Speaker 3:  funny thing that happens is every year I publish Best Printer
Speaker 3:  2024 by a brother laser printer and it goes to the top of the
Speaker 3:  rankings, it goes to the top of the search rankings one, because I have the
Speaker 3:  right answer, which is you should write brother laser printer and never think
Speaker 3:  about it. Two, because I'm the best person to write about printers in world
Speaker 3:  history. No one else has WR written a better printer post than me. I'm sorry.
Speaker 3:  That's just the truth. Certainly these two can try and
Speaker 3:  I don't mean that because there's not better writers than me. I mean, those
Speaker 3:  writers are not wasting their time. Do they have better things do writing
Speaker 3:  about printers? Right. You're the perfect, the perfect
Speaker 3:  middle of good at your job and also interested in printer posts has ever
Speaker 3:  existed. I mean, like the whole staff is better at this than me. I just won't
Speaker 3:  nn diagram.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Right. That's fine. And it, and then
Speaker 3:  everyone tweets it and shares it and people write about it. 'cause it's a
Speaker 3:  joke and it's funny and it's at the top of the list. And then the SEO o community
Speaker 3:  says things like The Verge is just taking advantage of their domain authority,
Speaker 3:  which Yeah, yeah, that's true. That's totally what we're doing. And then
Speaker 3:  Google's like, we don't have domain authority. That's not a thing we keep
Speaker 3:  track of. And then you look at the thing and they track something called
Speaker 3:  site authority and it's that dynamic authority. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Right. It's just that dynamic which is like, okay, like
Speaker 3:  we understand that you don't want people to game search.
Speaker 3:  We have been very critical of SEO forms at game search.
Speaker 3:  Again, decoder this week is just about
Speaker 3:  people gaming search and putting small businesses outta business.
Speaker 3:  But if you're not honest right then, and if you
Speaker 3:  deny the things are happening, then the backlash is really strong. The
Speaker 3:  example I keep thinking about is what if every Instagram
Speaker 3:  influencer woke up today and was like, Instagram
Speaker 3:  has been lying to us for a decade. Like, how'd that go for that platform?
Speaker 5:  Adam, er just like immediately like, Hey guys,
Speaker 3:  He's not making it better.
Speaker 5:  I'm here with a video on why the lies were worth it. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Exactly.
Speaker 5:  Now I gotta go to the Met Gala.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, exactly. I mean kind of. Yeah. He is like, my glasses are getting more
Speaker 3:  expensive every day and
Speaker 5:  They look fabulous.
Speaker 3:  They're very good. What would happen if every YouTuber, I always joke that
Speaker 3:  every YouTuber gets their wings and they make the video about how term had
Speaker 3:  at YouTube, what, what would happen if every YouTuber was like, they've been
Speaker 3:  lying to us for a decade. That's, that's where Google is landing with the
Speaker 3:  web with these links. We're gonna have a lot more coverage of them now that
Speaker 3:  we know they're real. We're gonna pull 'em apart. We're gonna talk to some
Speaker 3:  experts. I have people from other
Speaker 3:  companies in my inbox saying things like,
Speaker 3:  if some of this is real, then Chrome is essentially spyware.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's, I mean it sounds like last week we were having this whole conversation
Speaker 5:  about copilot and how everybody was very upset because they felt like copilot
Speaker 5:  plus PCs, all this stuff that's hap Microsoft is doing is horrible.
Speaker 5:  And it was, it was essentially key loggers and it's like, okay, well now
Speaker 5:  we basically have confirmation that Chrome is a key logger.
Speaker 3:  Well, we almost,
Speaker 5:  We
Speaker 3:  Right, right. We there's like a field.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It's like if you were to make a spreadsheet and one of the things in spreadsheet
Speaker 3:  would be like my friend's bank account numbers, and you're like, but I never
Speaker 3:  filled it in. Yeah. I just kind of wanted, in case someone
Speaker 3:  told me their bank account number.
Speaker 5:  Sure. I do that all the time. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  People my friends have gone out with on dates. Like I just,
Speaker 3:  I just keep, maybe maybe that's a page I wanna have in my notebook. Right.
Speaker 3:  But again,
Speaker 6:  I, I, I would encourage anyone who is alarmed by this
Speaker 6:  to go to your Chrome history, think about all the cookies that you
Speaker 6:  have. I mean, like, of course it's a key, like what the hell is a browser
Speaker 6:  if not a key logger? Yeah. That's, that's literally its job
Speaker 6:  is to know all the links that you've been to and all the things that you've
Speaker 6:  typed inside of them. And I think to some extent, again, I just keep
Speaker 6:  coming back to this idea that like Google is going to say, okay, we, we run
Speaker 6:  a search engine. Wouldn't it be cool if we knew all the links people would
Speaker 6:  go to when they weren't on Google? And then somebody on Chrome is like, what
Speaker 6:  if we just built an awesome browser and they just, it would be the most,
Speaker 6:  like, have you met Google thing in history? And to
Speaker 6:  be fair, if any company could accidentally keep those two things apart, it
Speaker 6:  is Google, but like, just strategically, it, it, it would be
Speaker 6:  absurd for Google to do this and not actually connect those
Speaker 6:  dots together. Right.
Speaker 3:  Again, and I think from some of the antitrust trials, David, you covered
Speaker 3:  some of them. Google's been pretty open. Like our engineers wanted a bunch
Speaker 3:  of click data to make the search engine better and that's engine,
Speaker 6:  So we gave about $20 billion.
Speaker 3:  Right. Okay. Well a bunch of people run Windows. We don't
Speaker 3:  have to pay Microsoft, we just have to make a browser and put it on there.
Speaker 3:  And now we run the biggest browser in the world and we get all the clicks.
Speaker 3:  Like that is exactly what you would do. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I think, I think the thing is the, what's different here is that everybody
Speaker 5:  should understand this, right? Like, I understand that Google is reading
Speaker 5:  my, my emails because I signed up for Gmail in like 2004,
Speaker 5:  2005. That was part of the deal, you know, it reads my
Speaker 5:  emails to deliver me ads. So I understand that most people don't, and a lot
Speaker 5:  of times they have these moments when stuff like this happens where it's
Speaker 5:  like, oh shit, they have so much more information about me than I ever thought
Speaker 5:  they did. And it's just this moment for a lot of people where it's just like,
Speaker 5:  oh, I didn't, I never intellectualize this. I never like fully
Speaker 5:  comprehended how much these companies have about me.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And then on, on the flip side, you have people who are trying to build
Speaker 3:  businesses saying, Hey, it looks like you are doing this. And Google's saying
Speaker 3:  no. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And just flat out lying to them in a way that's like,
Speaker 5:  you know, I don't think they Google has any interest in rebuilding trust
Speaker 5:  with the
Speaker 3:  SEO people. Right. Actually, one of the funniest things about this is that
Speaker 3:  it's such an antagonistic relationship. Yeah. I often make the comparison
Speaker 3:  to platforms. Like I think the web is essentially Google's platform and certainly
Speaker 3:  a lot of these businesses are building their businesses on the platform
Speaker 3:  known as Google Search, not the web. Right? Right. They're, they're, they're
Speaker 3:  search dependent businesses. And Google does not have like
Speaker 3:  warm and fuzzy platform creator relationships
Speaker 3:  with these folks. No. Like Adam er is like, I'm gonna sit down with creators,
Speaker 3:  like, look at all these great creators. He's got a great sweater on. Right.
Speaker 3:  Neil Mohan, who runs YouTube loves, loves a creator breakfast. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Right. Like every platform that depends on creators has that relationship
Speaker 3:  that extracts more value than it pays them. That's life and platform
Speaker 3:  world. They, they try to mollify the creators all the time. Google does not
Speaker 3:  try to mollify website owners.
Speaker 6:  No, because I mean, at this point, the, the internet is reliant on Google.
Speaker 6:  And what Google says is, Hey, run our ads on your site and you can have some
Speaker 6:  money. Does that seem good? But what I think is so interesting about this
Speaker 6:  is like the, the YouTube, the sort of social platform example is really interesting
Speaker 6:  because what those companies by and large have done
Speaker 6:  is be inscrutable on purpose, right? Like you,
Speaker 6:  you look at Aer responding to people who are like, why
Speaker 6:  didn't my post do numbers? Why is this one working and this one not working?
Speaker 6:  And they never really answer the question except to say, you know,
Speaker 6:  do good work and, and keep posting and whatever. And so what you see
Speaker 6:  is like, the people who are successful on these platforms are the ones who
Speaker 6:  are constantly running experiments in public. Like, do, do you remember Mr.
Speaker 6:  Beast's whole thing where he was like, if I have my mouth open in the thumbnail,
Speaker 6:  it gets more clicks. Like YouTube didn't tell him that these are the experiments
Speaker 6:  he's running in public. What Google has done that is so wild is it's,
Speaker 6:  it's as if Neil Mohan called Mr. Beast and said, shut your mouth. It doesn't
Speaker 6:  help.
Speaker 3:  And,
Speaker 6:  And,
Speaker 3:  And
Speaker 6:  Instead, so it's like, okay, it's one thing to not be told the rules
Speaker 6:  of the game and figure them out for yourself. I actually think that relationship
Speaker 6:  is like odd but fine. Right? And it's like, here,
Speaker 6:  here is a, a black box, it's your job to figure it out. That is sort of the
Speaker 6:  internet we live on. But for Google to have spent this long
Speaker 6:  denying the existence of what people are finding on their own and sort
Speaker 6:  of making people question what they're finding with their own two hands in
Speaker 6:  front of their own two eyes is just wild. Yeah. And again, we should say
Speaker 6:  there is a lot about how all of this works that we still don't know. I think
Speaker 6:  a lot of it is going to start to come out very fast because there are a lot
Speaker 6:  of people who do these experiments who are now armed with a
Speaker 6:  tremendous amount of new data. And so I think we're gonna learn a lot about
Speaker 6:  how Google works really, really quickly now. But it's just, it just feels
Speaker 6:  so weird to hear the people who do this for a living be like, yeah, I've
Speaker 6:  been asking these questions and being publicly lied to about how my job
Speaker 6:  works for a decade. Yeah. That just feels crazy.
Speaker 3:  Also, we should know there are pending antitrust lawsuits against Google
Speaker 3:  and lots and lots of regulators around the world who have been asking the
Speaker 3:  same questions and getting the same kind of answers. Well,
Speaker 6:  Which is another place a lot of this information is coming from, by the way.
Speaker 6:  Like the, there was this thing called Nav Boost that came up a bunch in the,
Speaker 6:  in the API, which talks a lot about how click through rate and the stuff
Speaker 6:  you're talking about, like the, the long and short clicks, whether you come
Speaker 6:  back very quickly from a search result or stay on the page a while,
Speaker 6:  all of that is part of a system Google has called Nav Boost that came up
Speaker 6:  in the antitrust trial and made some noise where it's like, okay, this is
Speaker 6:  actually overriding a lot of our other rankings is what you do
Speaker 6:  once you interact with a search result. And that is very different
Speaker 6:  from what Google has told people.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Actually my favorite part of all this, my favorite thing because it's
Speaker 3:  such a good name, let's be honest. How do you get me, you give something
Speaker 3:  an adorable name. Google has spent
Speaker 3:  years positioning search as a utility, right?
Speaker 3:  Not as a business that they run, but as the water or
Speaker 3:  electricity of the internet. It's just a neutral utility. You just stop.
Speaker 3:  You just use it. And we don't have any ideas about it. It's just we set the
Speaker 3:  robots to crawl the internet and they,
Speaker 5:  They're just a baby.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. They just find the stuff and they show it to you. And when you try
Speaker 3:  to cover search as anything other than a utility, the
Speaker 3:  attitude from Google is like, why would you do that? Right? We wanna teach
Speaker 3:  people how search works. And we're like, no, there's like a culture of search.
Speaker 3:  Like the same way that there's a culture of TikTok, right. And that's been
Speaker 3:  a disconnect. But they have done that on purpose, right? Because if you treat
Speaker 3:  something like a utility or a neutral algorithm or just the right
Speaker 3:  answer that the Google brilliance of page rank has discovered across the
Speaker 3:  web, then maybe you don't poke at it too much. And inside these
Speaker 3:  documents we find things like Nav Boost as part of a
Speaker 3:  system that is called Twiddles. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  TWIs.
Speaker 3:  And the way, so to think about it is like the big Google
Speaker 3:  algorithm is like the backend and right before it displays your
Speaker 3:  result, the Twiddles show up and they twiddle the
Speaker 3:  result.
Speaker 5:  We just twiddle
Speaker 3:  A little thought. And so nav boosts is a twiddler, it's like categorized
Speaker 3:  as a twiddler. It's like we went and found some other stuff and we're just,
Speaker 3:  we gonna shuffle that around a little bit. And there's a bunch of those.
Speaker 3:  And like lots of Google systems are built as Twiddler, so they have plausible
Speaker 3:  deniability that the core search ranking algorithm
Speaker 3:  doesn't take these factors in. Right. But right
Speaker 3:  before they show 'em to you
Speaker 5:  Just a little twiddle
Speaker 3:  Twiddles baby. And it's like, I'm not that stupid.
Speaker 3:  You know? It's like it's one system that displays a search result at the
Speaker 3:  end where it happens. Like I don't think they can run around being like we
Speaker 3:  were always telling the truth. Yeah. It's just these, these twiddles are
Speaker 3:  outta control, right.
Speaker 5:  They, they have no control over it. They're just a baby. I, that's, it's
Speaker 5:  my favorite thing that everybody does now when they screw up, they just go,
Speaker 5:  I'm just a baby. No, no,
Speaker 3:  No. It's my first day running search
Speaker 5:  Who can say over
Speaker 3:  Yourselves? Anyhow, we are gonna learn a lot more about this. I,
Speaker 3:  we often try not to oversell things. I'm just telling you the, the web, the
Speaker 3:  people who make the web are a flame because of these
Speaker 3:  documents. Because they do make Google seem, if not outright a
Speaker 3:  liar as though they have been socially engineering a community of
Speaker 3:  people who make things into not believing what they see as David is saying.
Speaker 3:  You know? And I think the backlash there is going to be ferocious.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Especially as search traffic declines, especially as user
Speaker 3:  behavior changes around ai, especially as the AI results continue to tell
Speaker 3:  people to eat glue. Like it's not, there's not a lot of
Speaker 3:  trust left in this ecosystem. And it's, it's, to me,
Speaker 3:  it's weird that there's not more coverage of it. It's not as sexy as the
Speaker 3:  Facebook algorithm or Elon saying is an open source, the Twitter algorithm.
Speaker 3:  But like David said, this is the architecture of the internet. Yeah. I
Speaker 5:  Think it is. That's why it's so hard for people. It it is so ingrained in
Speaker 5:  how most people function that it's shocking to
Speaker 5:  them to a where point where it's like, I, I can't even process this. I have
Speaker 5:  to go. Yeah. Like most people, I don't think fully grasp how much the goog,
Speaker 5:  the Google and most people don't fully grasp how much Google affects
Speaker 5:  their online experience. They just don't. They know it. They see it and everything,
Speaker 5:  but it's just like, just gloss over it. And now it's like, oh,
Speaker 5:  you're having to actually reckon with this and think about this. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's why I always like to talk about cooking websites because the, if you
Speaker 6:  want the, if you want the single cleanest example of how Google
Speaker 6:  changes the way a webpage works, go read a recipe
Speaker 6:  site. You, you will see everything you need to
Speaker 6:  see, you'll see the H twos, which Google wants because they're gonna be questions
Speaker 6:  that people might be Googling. You're gonna see the jump to recipe thing.
Speaker 6:  But then you're also gonna see 2000 words of nonsense about their lives
Speaker 6:  because you have to actually stay on the page a long time in order for Google
Speaker 6:  to believe that that's a successful search. They want images that's very
Speaker 6:  important to Google. Like you, every single pixel of that
Speaker 6:  page right down to how the recipe is structured is made for Google. And
Speaker 6:  anyone who runs a food blog will tell you that the fundamental tension is
Speaker 6:  like, I did this because I like food and I actually work for Google. And
Speaker 6:  that feels crappy to a lot of people.
Speaker 3:  And now Google's gonna take that stuff and show the recipes to people in
Speaker 3:  ai.
Speaker 6:  Right. But I do think, what one more thought on this that I've, I've been
Speaker 6:  seeing a lot of increasingly in the SEO world and I think is a really interesting,
Speaker 6:  like internet question is one way to read
Speaker 6:  a lot of what we've seen in these leaks is that SEO
Speaker 6:  is dead and no longer will work. Like there,
Speaker 6:  lemme, I, I copied this one paragraph out from the thing that Rand wrote.
Speaker 6:  He said, Google no longer rewards scrappy, clever SEO savvy operators
Speaker 6:  who know all the right tricks. They reward established brands, search measurable
Speaker 6:  forms of popularity and established domains that searchers already know and
Speaker 6:  click from 1998 to 2018 or so, one could reasonably start a
Speaker 6:  powerful marketing flywheel with SEO for Google in 2024. I don't think that's
Speaker 6:  realistic, at least not on the English language web in competitive sectors.
Speaker 6:  Hmm. Like there is a, there is a real defeatism to the idea
Speaker 6:  that Google cares a lot about the sites that already exist, the places people
Speaker 6:  already go, what has been going on for a long time. And the idea that
Speaker 6:  you can come and be new and good and smart and people will find you because
Speaker 6:  that's how Google works
Speaker 3:  Is a dying theory. Yeah. I asked this question to
Speaker 3:  a lot of just media people, website
Speaker 3:  CEOs and decoder. I asked this question to Sundar, why would anyone make
Speaker 3:  a website? You're a new creator. We're we're all gonna quit our jobs at a
Speaker 3:  OL, which you should do. Can't recommend it
Speaker 3:  enough. Best decision I've ever made.
Speaker 5:  I, I don't plan on doing it, but
Speaker 3:  You should go get a job at AAL just to quit. Just to quit. But that's, you
Speaker 3:  know, that's how we found out The Verge. We all worked at Eng Gadget 2010.
Speaker 3:  2011. We had this idea for The Verge, we all quit and we're gonna start
Speaker 3:  a new thing. We started a website, like a big
Speaker 3:  desktop website. We didn't even have a mobile site. We started a
Speaker 3:  big hairy desktop website with like forums and features and all this
Speaker 3:  stuff. And then the mobile web came and we shrunk down the thing and whatever.
Speaker 3:  But it was never a question that we would start anything but a website.
Speaker 3:  There were 12 of us. We had a big idea. We wanted to do a thing. What we
Speaker 3:  were gonna do was start a website. I think if you get to that place in
Speaker 3:  2024, maybe some people are gonna start a substack. I don't think they think
Speaker 3:  of those things as websites. Those are newsletters or independent newsletter
Speaker 3:  and ghost or whatever. Mostly what they're gonna do is start YouTube channels
Speaker 3:  and TikTok channels. Yeah. The,
Speaker 5:  The only people I see who are kind of doing that sort of thing, like Right,
Speaker 5:  leaving their jobs, whatever and being like, I'm gonna start a website are
Speaker 5:  already established brands. Right? Yep. Like the folks who are over at oh
Speaker 5:  four, KU 4 0 4 who are from Vice, these folks just said, I'm gonna go and
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna start a new thing. And I, they all take that model from Deadspin
Speaker 5:  that became defector. Yeah. And, and that works.
Speaker 5:  But that is,
Speaker 3:  You have to have an audience already. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The, the, that worked because they have that audience, right? Like most people
Speaker 5:  don't have that audience and don't have that scale. And I think Casey's written
Speaker 5:  about that a lot of like, he has to work to get platformer out. He has
Speaker 5:  to like really put in the effort because scale is hard
Speaker 5:  and it's much, much harder now because of Google.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And I, those sites are all great. I don't think they like four
Speaker 3:  four is on ghost. Yeah. Right. So they're taking advantage of some, some
Speaker 3:  infrastructure for newsletter that exists that lets them be a different kind
Speaker 3:  of thing. But the idea that like we coded our
Speaker 3:  website from scratch, you wouldn't do that. We're like, build a product that
Speaker 3:  is a website. I didn't do it. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  But you, you people would do that in 2024.
Speaker 3:  We, it was just not a good investment in 2024 for the reason David is saying.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And there's, you know, many things have changed in the past 13 years,
Speaker 3:  but the idea that the new creators
Speaker 3:  on the internet will not go to the open web, but instead
Speaker 3:  we'll go to a closed video platform, I think is very dangerous.
Speaker 3:  And I don't know the right answer to get people back to making
Speaker 3:  open searchable web properties. If the biggest search engine is like,
Speaker 3:  screw it, like Hearst, we'll just everyone can go read Dash Meredith,
Speaker 3:  like whatever. You know, like maybe that's the right outcome. And maybe that's
Speaker 3:  just the closing of the web. But I, again, the reason we started
Speaker 3:  covering it last year is 'cause I was like, oh, the comment's coming and
Speaker 3:  the more we covered it we're like, oh, the comment's coming. Like we should
Speaker 3:  capture this moment. And it feels like, again, I thought the
Speaker 3:  comment would be ai. I thought I did not expect it to be like
Speaker 3:  everyone is this mad and, and it just feels like, ugh. We'll we'll see
Speaker 3:  how it goes. We're gonna cover a lot more of it. I think the other browser
Speaker 3:  makers, regulators, there's just flood
Speaker 3:  of negative emotion about how Google has behaved
Speaker 3:  that it might, it just, it feels like it's coming to a head. I
Speaker 5:  I do have one question for you guys. Yeah. Especially you David. 'cause you
Speaker 5:  use a lot of different search engines. Are any of them good?
Speaker 5:  Like do any of them when you go, when you search something actually give
Speaker 5:  you those unique results that used to be like, Ooh, yeah, now I know
Speaker 5:  what I'm doing on this, this search engine?
Speaker 6:  Yes and no. Coy, which is the one you mentioned, which is also what I use.
Speaker 6:  It's 10 bucks a month. It's excellent. I cannot recommend it enough. Paying
Speaker 6:  for a search engine feels ridiculous, but it's worth, it has a thing
Speaker 6:  that it calls small web where it actually deliberately built
Speaker 6:  a like crowdsource database of sites that aren't
Speaker 6:  The Verge and aren't like big mainstream news sites, the
Speaker 6:  kind that dominate search results but are like people's blogs and little
Speaker 6:  alternative news sites and local newspapers and all the kinds of cool stuff.
Speaker 6:  And you can, you can toggle the search just to that. Yeah. And I think
Speaker 6:  the, the sort of big omnibus search is never coming back
Speaker 6:  from what it is now. It's you, you, it's just interface changes really.
Speaker 6:  Like I think Cogi stuff is better than Google, but mostly just because it's
Speaker 6:  a nicer thing to use than Google is at this moment. Especially
Speaker 5:  In Arc.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But where we are now is like the, the only
Speaker 6:  solution is going to be to artificially decide
Speaker 6:  which part of the web you wanna look at. Because all of the
Speaker 6:  signals for the rest of the web are, are starting to break
Speaker 6:  away from that. Like find and explore new things
Speaker 6:  vibe because that's harder to do and harder to measure than,
Speaker 6:  oh people generally believe that Neli is right about
Speaker 6:  which printer to buy. And that's actually like a pretty easy thing for a
Speaker 6:  search engine to believe and send you to over and over again. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And we will continue ruthlessly using our domain authority.
Speaker 5:  We will I love it
Speaker 3:  To break big printer.
Speaker 3:  David, I can't remember if it was you who said this to Casey, might have
Speaker 3:  said it to me in passing. We used to think of surfing the web as a fun thing
Speaker 3:  to do and all of Google's messaging at IO was let go do
Speaker 3:  the Googling for you. Yeah. Which makes it seem like work. And it's
Speaker 3:  like, no, this is how I wasted time. Do you know how much I didn't pay attention
Speaker 3:  in law school because I was just browsing the web in class.
Speaker 3:  Like that's a, it's weird that we've made the web this unpleasant and the
Speaker 3:  platforms figured it out. And hopefully we can get some of that back. I dunno
Speaker 3:  if we can, we're gonna keep running a website. We're not. We do have a TikTok
Speaker 3:  for as long as TikTok, but that's good. All right. We're gonna keep using
Speaker 3:  our domain authority to crush big printer. Hell
Speaker 5:  Yes. Just
Speaker 3:  Ruthless, ruthless domain authority abuse. But that's our mission here
Speaker 3:  at the bridge. We gotta take a break. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Media signed a content
Speaker 3:  sincerely doubt that is true. I'll do my best. I'll, it is more likely that
Speaker 3:  I will see someone else's contract before I see our own companies.
Speaker 6:  Oh, that's interesting. That's a, that's a fun reporting tactic. Can I, can
Speaker 6:  I bully my boss before I can bully somebody else?
Speaker 3:  That's good. The, our company's very good at being like, no, you can't just
Speaker 3:  report on our own company. Other companies. Like here's the stuff like Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It, that's just the way of being a reporter.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That, that's fair. But so I, I am curious for you as like a, a newsroom
Speaker 6:  leader, how you even think through what a deal like
Speaker 6:  this means.
Speaker 3:  Sure.
Speaker 3:  We do a lot of disclosures on this show. Famously,
Speaker 3:  I think I've had journalism professors talk to me about the fact that our
Speaker 3:  disclosures are a running joke with the audience. Like we wanna be really
Speaker 3:  transparent about where information comes from.
Speaker 3:  Reasons to not trust us. If you don't wanna trust us, like
Speaker 3:  my goal is always to just empower the audience with information.
Speaker 3:  That's the top level. So like if you're listening to this and you've listened
Speaker 3:  to the show, that's why we do disclosures. That's why they're a joke. Like
Speaker 3:  I want, the only currency we have as a news organization is trust.
Speaker 3:  So we're trying to, that's why we have the background policy, right? All
Speaker 3:  the spokespeople have to use their names when they talk to us because
Speaker 3:  we don't wanna pretend we know something that they just told us. If, right,
Speaker 3:  if Google or Apple or Microsoft or whoever wants to talk to us and get some
Speaker 3:  information on our pages, they need to be accountable for it, not us. And
Speaker 3:  that's just trust. That's just who are you gonna trust? Where does a trust
Speaker 3:  go? Who do you have to trust for to believe this story?
Speaker 3:  So that's the top level right next to that, which I
Speaker 3:  think the audience doesn't see as much because why would you
Speaker 3:  is our newsroom has to not think about it.
Speaker 3:  Like that's actually what independence is, right? Is not, I know
Speaker 3:  that our company has a deal or an investor and
Speaker 3:  I'm just going to like, I'm gonna think about it as I write the story.
Speaker 3:  The goal is they don't think about it at all. Right? And we just go do the
Speaker 3:  reporting and we publish what is true or what we believe or what we
Speaker 3:  think people should know, right? And that that the, in any
Speaker 3:  traditional newsroom, that's the what is called the firewall,
Speaker 3:  right? So we do stuff, our sales team, there's advertising over it there.
Speaker 3:  We just came back from an ad break,
Speaker 3:  right? Like in that team. But we don't know what the ads are. I don't know
Speaker 3:  what ads just played. I get so many emails. What the crypto ads? I don't
Speaker 3:  know man. Yeah. Like I think crypto's stupid shit. Like what do
Speaker 3:  you want me to do? Like that's that team. And if we open the door and start
Speaker 3:  telling that team what to do, the danger, and this is a danger that is proven
Speaker 3:  out over and over again in newsrooms around the world. If we open the door
Speaker 3:  and start telling them what to do, they're like, Hey, that door's open, right?
Speaker 3:  We're gonna start telling you what to do. So we just keep the door closed.
Speaker 3:  This is why you have the firewall. It works in both directions.
Speaker 3:  So for me, and I understand open eye in particular is pretty shady company.
Speaker 3:  I feel like our entire episode last week was like, this company is pretty
Speaker 3:  shady. We're gonna talk about Tim. I was like, I just wanna talk
Speaker 3:  whatever.
Speaker 3:  Fine. But like that's the commercial side of our company. And I
Speaker 3:  understand, like I've talked to a lot of media executives, like I'm running
Speaker 3:  around covering Google Zero. I've been talking to a lot of media people lately
Speaker 3:  and I can talk about that bigger question David, of like, are these good
Speaker 3:  deals? Are these like a good idea broadly? 'cause I think I've done some
Speaker 3:  reporting, I have some thoughts about that. But the thing that
Speaker 3:  like when our press release went out, like no, we're not gonna change our
Speaker 3:  recover open ai. Yes. I think when it's appropriate we'll disclose it.
Speaker 3:  It's not like a, like Comcast is an
Speaker 3:  investor in our company, right? Like we disclose it every time we whisper
Speaker 3:  about Comcast 'cause they're an investor. This is a licensing deal. Like
Speaker 3:  we have a lot of those across our company. And I don't wanna just get into
Speaker 3:  a situation where I'm like, disclosure Yahoo
Speaker 3:  licenses and RSS feed of the Dodo. Like what do you want?
Speaker 3:  Like I think that door can get too open. We can overread it so we'll just
Speaker 3:  first cast would go a little long. It would go a little long. And
Speaker 3:  I want to preserve our independence. So what independence really means to
Speaker 3:  me is yes, we'll disclose it. Yes, we'll earn everyone's trust. But I would
Speaker 3:  prefer it if we were just covering open AI without thinking about it.
Speaker 3:  And so that's, that's the balance I'm trying to strike. I'm open to people's
Speaker 3:  thoughts about how much you need from us to continue having that trust.
Speaker 3:  But it is in many ways, like more of a normal
Speaker 3:  deal than people are expecting. Right? Like when,
Speaker 3:  when we did a Netflix show, I think there was less outcry,
Speaker 3:  but like I was the producer of a disclosure. I made a Netflix show.
Speaker 3:  Every time you should watch, you should watch a Netflix show. Like David
Speaker 3:  and I are gonna make one just so that we, that like way messier, right? Like
Speaker 3:  I'm going to meetings at Netflix about our show that I was not allowed to
Speaker 3:  talk about until our show was made. So I wanna make sure we like find the
Speaker 3:  right balance. And I understand there's just a lot of feelings about O
Speaker 3:  AI and open AI in particular, but like at
Speaker 3:  the end of the day,
Speaker 3:  the goal for all of these media companies is to just get some
Speaker 3:  control back out of a situation that felt out of control.
Speaker 6:  In what situation is that?
Speaker 3:  Well, they took everything anyway.
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 3:  Right. That's the situation. And we can talk about that broadly. I just want
Speaker 3:  to separate the two things. Like our newsroom is independent.
Speaker 3:  OpenAI did not buy any control of our newsroom. We will
Speaker 3:  be very honest with everybody when we think the disclosure would
Speaker 3:  affect how you perceive one of our stories. And I think that,
Speaker 3:  you know, around copyright law, like that makes sense to me. We're gonna
Speaker 3:  write a story about the New York Times lawsuit against open ai. That is a
Speaker 3:  great place for disclosure open AI launches a new GPT feature. Like, I dunno,
Speaker 3:  you tell me. Maybe we need to do that every time. But like I I, I don't wanna
Speaker 3:  overread it as though to make it seem like we're doing something
Speaker 3:  we're not. So that's it. That's like my top line. Like we will have
Speaker 3:  a disclosure. I love a disclosure disclosure. Comcast is an investor in Vox
Speaker 3:  Media. I'm in an Netflix show.
Speaker 6:  Disclosure, Alex. Cranz is the last remaining Paramount Plus subscriber.
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 3:  True. Hi, look, I, this is our brand and
Speaker 3:  we're gonna do them. I just, the thing that I am
Speaker 3:  trying to be careful about is separating
Speaker 3:  how people feel about these deals broadly and what it means for our
Speaker 3:  newsroom. Right?
Speaker 6:  Bullet. Let's talk. And
Speaker 3:  What it means for our newsroom is the status quo. Like it is not changing.
Speaker 3:  We are gonna operate without fear or favor. And
Speaker 3:  again, my goal is to earn everyone's trust by being as transparent as we
Speaker 3:  can be. And I just wanna make sure that we're not so transparent that we
Speaker 3:  actually go in a full circle and no one believes us. So like you
Speaker 3:  tell me where you think the line is. I'm open to the feedback. I, I ask for
Speaker 3:  it from our staff today. I'm asking for it from the audience today. But the,
Speaker 3:  the main thing is not changing, which is I want, I, I would prefer it
Speaker 3:  if our reporters were not worried about an opening ideal or thinking
Speaker 3:  about it and we just covered the company like we have been for a long time.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And this is the thing we should say, like a, a thing I've learned about
Speaker 6:  the media business over the years is that it's very unusual in the sense
Speaker 6:  that like, that tension you're describing between the work that we do and
Speaker 6:  where the money comes from is like good and healthy and should always exist.
Speaker 6:  And the, our editorial and sales team should always like, hate each other
Speaker 6:  a little bit. Yeah. It's like
Speaker 3:  A useful
Speaker 6:  Thing. But also like we have tech company ads
Speaker 6:  all over our website. Yeah. Like that is, that is a, it's, it's a not dissimilar
Speaker 6:  thing. And it is, it is just something you have to navigate and get comfortable
Speaker 6:  with. And like people always like sending us the stuff where I, we will,
Speaker 6:  we will make a vergecast about how terrible Facebook is right before a Facebook
Speaker 6:  ad. Like it's my favorite thing. It's so fun. But I do
Speaker 6:  wanna talk about the broader piece of this because I think the, I think you're
Speaker 6:  right that the reaction I saw out there was less like, you know,
Speaker 3:  How, dare I say one more thing? Sure. We're not gonna start publishing a
Speaker 3:  bunch of Hey high content who, hello. No,
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 5:  Think people see partnership and they're like AI
Speaker 6:  Content except for the printer post.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. I'm the only person who's put AI content on the website. Both
Speaker 3:  posts are about printers You disclose. I wish you people would get mad
Speaker 3:  at me about it and make that post go even more viral.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  No one will do it. We will only
Speaker 6:  Use AI to ruin our domain authority in Google Search. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's what we're for it. I'm sure we're gonna end up building
Speaker 3:  some ai, like there's one thing that all of us want, which is we would like
Speaker 3:  better alt texts on our images to make them more accessible, to make the
Speaker 3:  site more accessible. We would like our site to be better for screen readers.
Speaker 3:  Right now it's not a very manual work. If we can use some of these tools
Speaker 3:  to make that better or make our start more accessible, that's a great outcome.
Speaker 3:  Right. I dunno if that's gonna work. Right now our creative team tells me
Speaker 3:  like, this all text is not good enough and
Speaker 3:  AI, everybody, it's just not good enough yet. But if we can start to build
Speaker 3:  that stuff, that's great. So I, there's that part of it, which I think is
Speaker 3:  interesting. I don't know what that looks like. I haven't talked to our product
Speaker 3:  team about any of that stuff yet. But the other part where The
Speaker 3:  Verge is just The Verge that's gonna remain exactly the same today as it
Speaker 3:  was yesterday.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Okay. Let, let's talk about the broader side of this because I think
Speaker 6:  there are, there are two pieces of the should media companies
Speaker 6:  be making deals like this with OpenAI question that I find very interesting.
Speaker 6:  We should talk about both of them. The first is, haven't you
Speaker 6:  idiots learned your lesson from making these deals with companies like
Speaker 6:  Facebook and Google and everybody else who promised you money to save journalism
Speaker 6:  and in fact forced you to do a bunch of stuff, pulled out the rug and kind
Speaker 6:  of screwed up the industry. The second is,
Speaker 6:  aren't you guys, don't you realize that AI is out to put all of you out of
Speaker 6:  jobs and just take your information, use it in training data,
Speaker 6:  and then get rid of you? Why are you ushering in the
Speaker 6:  journalism apocalypse? And I think to some extent those are like two versions
Speaker 6:  of the same question, but I think are like the big picture things going
Speaker 6:  on here. Like, are we contributing to our own downfall or are we chasing
Speaker 6:  money at the expense of doing anything that is
Speaker 6:  smart or long-term thinking?
Speaker 3:  I mean, the media industry never does anything.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. This is the media industry's not known for for really good business.
Speaker 3:  No. But think like a vanity project.
Speaker 6:  The thing we have talked a lot about on this media show is that we, the
Speaker 6:  media industry as a whole probably should have spent more time over
Speaker 6:  the last decade building Facebook competitors than making
Speaker 6:  Facebook videos. And I think, like my hope is we have learned that
Speaker 6:  lesson and that the next minute of the journalism industry will be learning
Speaker 6:  that lesson and executing on it. Which is, I think part of why we're so excited
Speaker 6:  about the Fedi verse. 'cause it's a thing that opens up possibilities for
Speaker 6:  new kinds of media products.
Speaker 6:  Is there a fear that open AI and the like
Speaker 6:  AI search engine stuff that is inevitably coming is
Speaker 6:  just the next pivot to video and everybody falls for it and gives up on
Speaker 6:  building new things for five more years?
Speaker 3:  Yes. Okay. So here's I just, I'm gonna
Speaker 3:  bracket our company because they did not
Speaker 3:  talk to me, which is like, that's the firewall. Yeah. But
Speaker 3:  Nick Thompson, who is the CO of the Atlantic, has published a bunch
Speaker 3:  about why the Atlantic did the deal. He made a video about it. You can go
Speaker 3:  watch on LinkedIn.
Speaker 3:  Nick used to be the editor-in-Chief of Wire. David used to work for Nick.
Speaker 3:  I did. I love Nick.
Speaker 3:  Nick knows, he knows, yeah. He gets it. I,
Speaker 3:  Nick and I are friends. He, he knows, he un he understands what he's doing.
Speaker 3:  Axel Springer has signed one of these deals. The Financial Times has signed
Speaker 3:  one of these deals. A lot of these companies are signing these deals. My
Speaker 3:  understanding of the deals from the reporting, not from the digging
Speaker 3:  around our company, but from the reporting is twofold. One,
Speaker 3:  we just spent a whole bunch of time talking at Google.
Speaker 3:  Google is a fair use argument. Right? We're gonna come and index all of your
Speaker 3:  information. We're gonna show it to people in return, you'll get traffic.
Speaker 3:  And everyone said it's a little, little squeaky, but okay. And then Google
Speaker 3:  won a bunch of cases against different media organizations that did not
Speaker 3:  like this idea. Yeah. We're gonna index every book in the world and show
Speaker 3:  it to people. And the book publishers are like, no, you're stealing our stuff.
Speaker 3:  And Google won that case. Google, we're gonna index all the images on the
Speaker 3:  internet. A bunch of porn publishers said, no, that's, we don't want you
Speaker 3:  to do that. And they were not the most sympathetic defendants in the world.
Speaker 3:  Google won that case. Google said, we're gonna put every episode of South
Speaker 3:  Park on YouTube. And Viacom said no. And then they started posting episodes
Speaker 3:  of South Park to YouTube on their own and they lost their case. That was
Speaker 3:  not a great legal strategy, but that's what they did.
Speaker 3:  But that all of Google, that whole platform dynamic
Speaker 3:  was We're gonna take your stuff and we're gonna pay you and we'll, you'll
Speaker 3:  get something, you'll get, you'll we'll pay you an exposure. Yeah. In that
Speaker 3:  look around. So I, I thi I think
Speaker 3:  a lot of the reaction right now is, well, we cannot let that happen again.
Speaker 3:  We need some rules. I think a problem for
Speaker 3:  all these companies is that OpenAI and Google and whoever
Speaker 3:  else, philanthropic,
Speaker 3:  perplexity, you name it, they've all taken it anyway. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  They, they have it llama scraped on the internet. Every Facebook video
Speaker 3:  we've ever made, OpenAI
Speaker 5:  Is in llama built a tool to scrape YouTube Yeah.
Speaker 5:  For more data. Like Yeah. Like that's just how it's done. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I think, you know, Abson our own company, I know nothing about
Speaker 5:  the deal beyond have
Speaker 3:  One. We
Speaker 5:  Have to keep saying. Yeah. Yeah. We have one. There is
Speaker 3:  Disclosure,
Speaker 5:  There's
Speaker 3:  There it's box has a content and technology deal with opening.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think you're right. Where it's like, it, it is a thing of they everybody,
Speaker 5:  it's already been taken. It's already gone. Everybody, it's already like
Speaker 5:  the cat is outta the bag. What? Right. Genie's outta the bottle. Whatever
Speaker 5:  euphemism you wanna use there, it's happened and now it's
Speaker 5:  okay, what do we put a price on that? And a lot of these companies, we we're,
Speaker 5:  we're starting to hear more about the price there. We're starting to hear
Speaker 5:  what it is and that might not end up being the right price. Right? Like,
Speaker 5:  like these deals might not be the right deals, but they are deals,
Speaker 5:  they are Right. Money where
Speaker 3:  There wasn't money. I think a really interesting thing is how do you set
Speaker 3:  the right price? What is the value? They've already trained on it. Yep. What
Speaker 3:  is the deal for now? One of the things that has come out about these deals,
Speaker 3:  which are all like, from what I understand, they're all basically the same
Speaker 3:  structure. I think the, the News Corp deal is like
Speaker 3:  $250 million over five or 10 years. Right? Most of the other
Speaker 3:  deals are $10 million over five to 10 years, something like that.
Speaker 3:  I think it's five.
Speaker 3:  The main thing that has come out about them is that they govern how much
Speaker 3:  can be displayed, how the information is displayed, how it's attributed,
Speaker 3:  what links are in it. And you look at that and I, what
Speaker 3:  I see is a honestly a reaction to Google, which has gone from,
Speaker 3:  we're linking to your stuff to we're gonna cut out your stuff and put it
Speaker 3:  in featured snippets to we're gonna have our AI rewrite whatever and just
Speaker 3:  show you the answer and never send you a click. And then you'll eat glue
Speaker 6:  And there's nothing you can do about it because we're indexing your website
Speaker 6:  every single day.
Speaker 3:  Right. And there's nothing you can do about it. 'cause there's no contract.
Speaker 3:  Right. So I, what I have heard and what I see is like that control,
Speaker 3:  and I, I think Nick again, Nick Thompson, that former editor Wired, who knows,
Speaker 3:  has been public about this in his announcement in the Atlantic. That control
Speaker 3:  is the thing. Because if you go beyond that, you don't have to
Speaker 3:  go invent some copyright Yeah. Argument. You have a breach of contract claim
Speaker 3:  and that's much easier to litigate. The other thing that I see happening
Speaker 3:  all over the industry, and we made an entire decoder episode with Sarah Jang
Speaker 3:  and I about how all of AI rests on a totally shaky
Speaker 3:  copyright fair use argument that could blow up at any moment. Yeah. Like
Speaker 3:  open ai, your business could blow up at any moment because you have weird
Speaker 3:  ideas about copyright law. No one can afford to litigate these ideas.
Speaker 3:  So the New York Times sued OpenAI, someone famously,
Speaker 3:  they've spent a million dollars in that lawsuit so far. Public company. We,
Speaker 3:  we just know the answer to get nothing.
Speaker 3:  Like they haven't, they haven't achieved an outcome yet. Yeah. They're just
Speaker 3:  done. And they could lose and they could lose. So that's a coin flip. The
Speaker 3:  New York Times big public company, they run a very successful video game
Speaker 3:  service. Maybe the most successful online game service of all is the New York
Speaker 3:  Times the word all just paying the bills for this lawsuit. Most media
Speaker 3:  companies do not have just some cash cow cooking website or gaming service
Speaker 3:  to fund a lawsuit about their journalism. And so I think they're all looking
Speaker 3:  at the Times lawsuit. They're saying, well this is gonna take five years,
Speaker 3:  this is gonna take 10 years. It might go to Supreme Court, they might lose,
Speaker 3:  hopefully the Times wins if they win. Our contracts will expire right
Speaker 3:  around then and we'll renegotiate with the strength of this
Speaker 3:  copyright precedent. And if they lose, we'll just re-up our deal. Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  I, I see that playing out as most media companies cannot
Speaker 3:  afford to go litigate these deals. And, and
Speaker 3:  importantly, no one can afford to sue Google. Yeah. Like Google's
Speaker 5:  Got infinite money
Speaker 3:  And I, I know everyone's talking about Open Eye and whatever dis disclosure,
Speaker 3:  open Eye has a constant technology of Fox Media. I would just, we just spent
Speaker 3:  that whole first segment about Google, which
Speaker 3:  is the thing, it's the 800 pound gorilla. Everyone on the web
Speaker 3:  operates in the universe of Google, including OpenAI. Right.
Speaker 3:  OpenAI has made Google dance to borrow a Dallas
Speaker 3:  quote, but they're still, it. Like Google's the big profitable,
Speaker 3:  ultra high margin company
Speaker 3:  and OpenAI doesn't make a dollar as far as I understand. Right. They're,
Speaker 3:  they're still losing money. So you just, there's a, there's a difference
Speaker 3:  there in how these companies are perceiving their antagonists. And I think
Speaker 3:  they can get OpenAI to come to the table and eventually what they're gonna
Speaker 3:  do is they're gonna go to Google and they're gonna say, pay us and competitor
Speaker 3:  is paying us. Our traffic is dropping and if it continues to
Speaker 3:  drop, we're gonna let, we're gonna pull the plug on you indexing our website.
Speaker 3:  And I dunno how long that's gonna take. Maybe it'll never happen because
Speaker 3:  the threats are effective. But you just see that's where the trend line is
Speaker 3:  headed. And
Speaker 5:  Then you'll see, you'll only get the URL for buy this one printer in Eline
Speaker 5:  Hotel
Speaker 3:  Recommends, I'll sell you one link, Google. But
Speaker 3:  that's, that's like broadly how I see the, the, the, the dynamic of this
Speaker 3:  playing out is the copyright. I care a lot about copyright law. The
Speaker 3:  copyright argument is so uncertain on both sides of the coin that people
Speaker 3:  are trying to buy some certainty so that they have leverage to go
Speaker 3:  negotiate against the real power in the ecosystem.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That makes logical sense to me. I also think it might be
Speaker 6:  wildly optimistic about who is actually going to extract
Speaker 6:  anything from Google.
Speaker 3:  I like our media executives. I think they're brilliant. It it should be clear.
Speaker 3:  I I think Nick is very smart. Most media executives
Speaker 3:  are not No,
Speaker 6:  I I mean it's
Speaker 3:  Like a players,
Speaker 6:  Even the thesis is good, right? Like I, I, I buy the thesis as far as it
Speaker 6:  goes. I just think there is not a lot of evidence that
Speaker 6:  says anyone can pick a fight with Google and win
Speaker 6:  because we are in this spot. I mean, like you, you keep harping about Google's
Speaker 6:  zero. Like when that happens
Speaker 6:  and people have nothing to lose by picking that fight with Google, they might
Speaker 6:  start to pick that fight with Google. Right Now if I
Speaker 6:  just say you can't crawl my website
Speaker 6:  anymore, overwhelmingly I go straight outta business. Yep.
Speaker 6:  Yep.
Speaker 3:  That's what I mean, that's, this is what I'm saying. Like the trend lines,
Speaker 3:  right.
Speaker 6:  But the trend, that trend is so slow. It's so, so slow.
Speaker 3:  It's, it's slow and it isn't slow. I think for some publishers it's, it's
Speaker 3:  super slow. For others it's not. Right. Yeah. I,
Speaker 6:  We'll
Speaker 3:  See you're, if you're seeing shakiness in your Google results and you're
Speaker 3:  seeing AI overviews and you're like, maybe Google Zero is real, or
Speaker 3:  you're a mid-size publisher, right. Which are not getting these
Speaker 3:  deals right now, that's all the big publishers are getting these deal. But
Speaker 3:  somewhere down the road, the mid-size publishers, I assume will get the deal
Speaker 3:  or we offered a deal or go ask for a deal. Who knows at point Point,
Speaker 3:  right. The trend line of our Google traffic is going down, are investment
Speaker 3:  in caring about you is no longer worth it. And they're paying
Speaker 3:  us money. Like I I I just, that is,
Speaker 3:  it's a destabilizing factor in all these conversations where there have never
Speaker 3:  been destabilizing factors for about a decade. Yeah. And so we'll just see
Speaker 3:  like the last time this happens, this is the negative argument.
Speaker 3:  I'll give everyone the negative argument. David wrote about this, he wrote
Speaker 3:  about Google Amp at the beginning of last year because I was like, we gotta
Speaker 3:  start with what Google has done to the web. Google did AMP because Facebook
Speaker 3:  showed up and said do instant articles and put all of your articles directly
Speaker 3:  into our platform and they'll load really fast and be native on the web and
Speaker 3:  we'll send a shitload of audience to them. And Google freaked out and did
Speaker 3:  amp and then all the publishers had do AMP and this was a disaster just broadly
Speaker 3:  all the way around a disaster. And then Facebook was like, we hate news.
Speaker 3:  And they're like, actually what we hate is text. All of you make videos and
Speaker 3:  we everyone pivots video. This equal growing disaster Amp
Speaker 3:  turned out to be a huge mess and he couldn't do anything good. It actually
Speaker 3:  spread misinformation. 'cause all the websites look the same. I could go
Speaker 3:  on about this for days and days and days.
Speaker 3:  Google is there again. Yep. They're afraid of
Speaker 3:  something. And so like the ripple effect of that I think is interesting.
Speaker 3:  And I think what most of the publishers that I've talked to, what they're
Speaker 3:  interested in is can we make them not copy in instant articles amp
Speaker 3:  but copy payments for search? Because
Speaker 3:  that's what they all want. One thing that we haven't talked a lot about on
Speaker 3:  the show is a bill in the United States called the JCPA, the
Speaker 3:  Journalism Competition Preservation Act. It's funny, you would
Speaker 3:  think that the publishers could all get together and,
Speaker 3:  and do and say, we're gonna pull our content from Google Search. They have
Speaker 3:  a lot of leverage. If they do it all together, you get a lot of leverage
Speaker 3:  what's left. They can't because that would be collusion under the antitrust
Speaker 3:  laws. Yep. Which is incredible. So the
Speaker 3:  JCPA is, I think it's a Klobuchar bill that would create an
Speaker 3:  exemption for publishers to bargain with large
Speaker 3:  platforms like over a billion in revenue. One of those numbers that like
Speaker 3:  makes it Google and Facebook. Yeah. Like it's one of those ways of saying
Speaker 3:  Google and Facebook without saying Google and Facebook, it would create a
Speaker 3:  con an exception to antitrust law. So they could bargain as a unit
Speaker 3:  against large platforms
Speaker 5:  Or they could just like rule that Google has built
Speaker 5:  a monopoly.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. There's a lot of that. Yeah. There's, there's just a lot of these ideas
Speaker 3:  floating around about how you equalize the bargain power. Yeah. Yeah. Anyway,
Speaker 3:  I that's, I I just see the bigger picture, which is
Speaker 3:  the raw deal is real. Like people got burned
Speaker 3:  super hard by the raw deal of the platforms. Most of which
Speaker 3:  were, were will give you some money with no contract that says where the
Speaker 3:  money will come from the Facebook news partnerships or the Google news
Speaker 3:  initiatives. Or it was make a thing for us that we want
Speaker 3:  Facebook video or it was, we're gonna take your stuff for free and pay
Speaker 3:  you an exposure, which is Google Search And I, what I see now is
Speaker 3:  we have a contract. Yeah. Right. We're just not doing this. Again. You're,
Speaker 3:  you're gonna pay us money. We're gonna tell you what you can take. And if
Speaker 3:  you don't pay us enough money, we'll see you. And if you take too much, we'll
Speaker 3:  see you. And that has a little bit of teeth. I dunno if it'll work again,
Speaker 3:  I know a lot of media executives, Alex used to work for some of the worst
Speaker 3:  media executives in the game.
Speaker 5:  I sure did.
Speaker 3:  And it's not like they're not all, this is not an
Speaker 3:  industry that can see the long game and it's an industry that's under pressure.
Speaker 3:  So it might be making mistakes. But I, I see the difference here. I don't
Speaker 3:  dunno if these are good ideas. I don't know if they feel great. Right. Like
Speaker 3:  there's a lot of the response yesterday and to all these other deals is do
Speaker 3:  these feel great? No, but I, I think I can identify the
Speaker 3:  differences and I think at least what I see
Speaker 3:  is well, they took the shit anyway. Yeah. But some money is better than no
Speaker 3:  money. Yeah. I mean, and a lot of the deal for a long time was no money.
Speaker 5:  That that's definitely where I'm sitting. It's like somebody is better than
Speaker 5:  no money. But also one I wanna just point out, this is
Speaker 5:  a lightning round and we've been on Eli's lightning round
Speaker 3:  Sorry, sorry, sorry.
Speaker 5:  For a while. And so I wanna take over for my lightning round. Oh yeah. Okay.
Speaker 5:  You got one which is also about open ai. Of course it is. Because
Speaker 5:  I called it, I just, back when, when
Speaker 5:  OpenAI, there was the coup and a bunch of the board members were like, we,
Speaker 5:  we don't like Sam. We're firing him. Everybody
Speaker 5:  gathered around. Sam was like, no, you are baby. We love you. Come back.
Speaker 5:  He's now back in charge. More powerful than ever.
Speaker 5:  Right. Like that, thats, that's the reporting allegedly like information
Speaker 5:  just said, open ai, CEO cements control. So like that's happening.
Speaker 3:  They started, they fired all the safety people or pushed him out and then
Speaker 3:  he started c they committee, he's the head of the safety committee. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Woo. That's, that's a choice. Sam. But Helen Toner, who was one of
Speaker 5:  those board members who, who voted to have him kicked off,
Speaker 5:  kicked out and then left because he won,
Speaker 5:  was on a podcast this week and was like, yeah. We just didn't trust him.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like he, he just was so consistently not telling us
Speaker 5:  the truth. We, we just lost all trust in him. And that is
Speaker 5:  really, really interesting to think about as he does
Speaker 5:  cement more power, as he does get more powerful as he does put himself in
Speaker 5:  charge of safety at the company. And all of those people who were in charge
Speaker 5:  of safety have left. And as that company is still technically run by a
Speaker 5:  nonprofit, that's whole job is to protect us
Speaker 5:  all from ai. Like, oh buddy. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's not working for you.
Speaker 3:  I'm actually, I'm curious. It's been
Speaker 3:  like this Carl Johansen situation has not, there's been no new pieces
Speaker 3:  of information. It's been pretty quiet on that front. Yeah. That's not gonna
Speaker 3:  just end. No. Right. It ends with a settlement or a statement or
Speaker 3:  an apology. Well,
Speaker 5:  She's gonna do a partnership with OpenAI as well. Like no,
Speaker 3:  She has some great ideas for all text. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But like the, the backlash to
Speaker 3:  AI in general, but I'll give you this little data point.
Speaker 3:  I think there's a real gap in how people feel about the thing and then what
Speaker 3:  people are doing. We've never gotten so many
Speaker 3:  sort of like unhappy notes about a decoder episode is when we had the CCO
Speaker 3:  of Adobe on. We had some happy ones too. People wanna hear from that guy.
Speaker 3:  He doesn't get a lot of interviews. I asked him what he thought a photo was.
Speaker 3:  He doesn't know. But then we got a lot of people who are like, screw this
Speaker 3:  guy. Yeah. We just don't like Adobe. We don't like ai. Like they're ruining
Speaker 3:  everything. His comments about AI are offensive. Weird.
Speaker 3:  Weird. Right.
Speaker 5:  There's real backlash to AI hack right now. There's
Speaker 3:  Some negativity. One thing he told me in that episode was
Speaker 3:  generative fill is used as much as layers. They
Speaker 3:  launched this tool and it is used on the order of layers in photo,
Speaker 3:  which is basically people open the app. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's how you get layers. You, you open the app,
Speaker 3:  Like you open the app and then like people use it. And so there's a real
Speaker 3:  gap and I think Sam kind of embodies the gap. Yeah. Right. Which is
Speaker 3:  he's just the face of boy, we're not being very careful with this.
Speaker 3:  He's the face of I can do whatever I want 'cause I'm so silicon
Speaker 5:  Someone's gonna call him the bad boy of AI soon. I'm sorry, I just,
Speaker 3:  No, there's nothing about his demeanor that supports bad boy. Yeah. I'm sorry.
Speaker 3:  It's
Speaker 5:  Just not It's coming. Don't worry. You
Speaker 3:  Can't, it's not gonna happen. I'm sorry. There's Brace Yourself. They're
Speaker 3:  much better contenders for Bad Boy than Sam Hallman,
Speaker 3:  but like he's the face of that gap. Yeah. Which is
Speaker 3:  actually the revealed behavior of many people is that the tools are useful,
Speaker 3:  they can be helpful people like them. Like I'm
Speaker 3:  the nation's foremost hand ringer of what is a photo. And I definitely use
Speaker 3:  Generative Eraser in Lightroom yesterday. That's for a family photo that
Speaker 3:  I shared with no one.
Speaker 5:  I would use it all the time.
Speaker 3:  DID noise in Lightroom I think is magic. I, I've talked about it and
Speaker 3:  it has re-contextualized how I think about some of my old cameras. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  We, we
Speaker 5:  Talked about this earlier today where I think a lot of people don't realize
Speaker 5:  how many of the tools we actually use are already ai. Right. Like, like Grammarly
Speaker 5:  is using some sort of ai. Photoshop
Speaker 5:  is all ai and if you've been using Photoshop for the last 10 years,
Speaker 5:  you've been using ai. Yeah. It's in there something. And, but, but I think
Speaker 5:  you're right where it's Sam Altman has become the kind of this, the center
Speaker 5:  point and and everybody's talking about him and they're talking about they
Speaker 3:  Don't
Speaker 5:  Trust him, they don't trust him and they don't trust the kind of AI he's
Speaker 5:  doing. Yeah. Which is very specific kind. Right. It's, it's taking over your
Speaker 5:  search. It's providing just easy generative content
Speaker 5:  in a way that most AI tools that people use have a very specific purpose
Speaker 5:  and are used for very specific things. And he's built the libo
Speaker 3:  And, you know, open this incredibly byzantine corporate
Speaker 3:  structure was all meant to box in the
Speaker 3:  bad things
Speaker 5:  You box in the Libo and keep the libo
Speaker 3:  And like keep it safe. And he's torn all that down. Yeah. And now OpenAI,
Speaker 3:  instead of being this weird non-profit with a profit center that supports
Speaker 3:  the non-profit is feels like just Sam Altman's company.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I
Speaker 6:  Mean it's called Open ai. Like I, I would just, I would just point out
Speaker 6:  like their whole thing was being the good guys for so, so,
Speaker 6:  so long and they made it so far on big
Speaker 6:  promises of being the good guys and then just like on a dime
Speaker 6:  turned and went the other way. Yeah. The
Speaker 3:  Second the money
Speaker 6:  Wild how fast this has happened. Right.
Speaker 3:  GPT-3 0.5 hit, they're like, oh, people like this we're evil now.
Speaker 5:  Just, it's, they just cut on their little evil helmets. But so the
Speaker 3:  Interesting thing is they don't, again, they don't have any revenue.
Speaker 3:  Right. Like, this company is not wildly profitable. They, they might be on
Speaker 3:  a path to it. You don't need revenue. They make all this
Speaker 6:  Noise about revenue is not important. You've, you've been covering tech too
Speaker 6:  long to know that, to not realize that revenue is not important. As long
Speaker 6:  as people will keep giving you money, you don't need revenue.
Speaker 3:  Which is why I think they make all this noise about a GI all the time, right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. They're like, we're we built the future. Yeah. People
Speaker 6:  Will keep giving you money.
Speaker 3:  The number one, the funniest the GBT apps are at now, right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. For everybody. And I was just looking at the top one in lifestyles
Speaker 3:  in Astrology app and I was like, oh, this is actually a perfect use case
Speaker 3:  for ai. Yeah. Like, you'd be like, I'll just make some shit up about your
Speaker 3:  future.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. We should talk about that. So wdc is coming up, there was some reporting
Speaker 3:  this week that Apple has made the deal to sign
Speaker 3:  with OpenAI that OpenAI will power this stuff. Interestingly,
Speaker 3:  there's some back and forth about whether it will run locally on the phone,
Speaker 3:  which would match Apple's privacy promises or go up to the cloud,
Speaker 3:  which is fascinating because
Speaker 5:  More powerful.
Speaker 3:  More powerful. But where will it run? There's some reporting, I think Mark
Speaker 3:  Gerin and Bloomberg reported that they're gonna put M two Ultras
Speaker 3:  or M three Ultras in a data center and have a virtual black box
Speaker 5:  Oh boy. For
Speaker 3:  Privacy.
Speaker 5:  That, that works out every time.
Speaker 3:  Who knows?
Speaker 6:  It gives real like beeper running Mac Minis on your behalf. Exactly. Vibes.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And then you've got open eye the mix, which is like, where's this model
Speaker 3:  gonna run? Can it run on the M two Ultra or M three Ultra or whatever.
Speaker 6:  I mean no, you can't fit the thing on your phone. I'm very confident that
Speaker 6:  you cannot run GPT-4 oh on your phone locally. Right.
Speaker 3:  But can you port it to arm like this thing Right, right now runs on
Speaker 3:  Nvidia H one hundreds.
Speaker 6:  A lot of them. Yeah. Like a lot of them.
Speaker 3:  And you know what two companies hate each other with the
Speaker 3:  Fury of a thousand Burning Suns So Good is Nvidia and Apple.
Speaker 3:  Yep.
Speaker 5:  But they're also two of the best people at making processors that can handle
Speaker 5:  AI stuff. Right. Except
Speaker 3:  For GPUs. One of them is really good. One
Speaker 5:  Of is really good at using the other one. Oh,
Speaker 3:  The other one just took the training wheels off. Its,
Speaker 5:  I I can play Crusader Kings on the laptop.
Speaker 3:  So I'm just very curious about how all this will play out. Because if you're
Speaker 3:  gonna run GBT four, there's a chance you're running it on a bunch of
Speaker 3:  H one hundreds in a Microsoft data center, which is a
Speaker 3:  real weird place for Apple to be. Well
Speaker 5:  Hagerman's piece this week about, about the the deal was also kind of
Speaker 5:  interesting 'cause it seemed to be like they're not gonna go full out
Speaker 5:  with all the AI tools. It, what we're gonna see from them at
Speaker 5:  ww DC as far as AI goes is gonna be a lot more Adobe like
Speaker 5:  than Yeah. Scarlet and
Speaker 3:  Voice. Like, I don't, I don't think they're gonna chat bot and I think that
Speaker 3:  is the right move. Yes. Oh,
Speaker 6:  That's so fun. I totally disagree. Yeah. Really? Yeah. I think they're going
Speaker 6:  to go full hard with Siri and I think that's the
Speaker 6:  open AI play is just take the Siri you
Speaker 6:  can talk to and plug it into GPT-4 Oh and instantly it's the best Siri
Speaker 6:  has ever been.
Speaker 6:  Then how you scale that down to like
Speaker 6:  turning off Bluetooth, which is a thing that I can do on my phone
Speaker 6:  that does not require the internet is becomes a really interesting
Speaker 6:  AI challenge That's big.
Speaker 3:  You just described like the promise of big speed. I mean,
Speaker 6:  What do you, what I use Siri for almost exclusively is playing
Speaker 6:  music, adding reminders to the reminders app and setting
Speaker 6:  timers. And none of those things require
Speaker 6:  pinging GPT-4. Oh. They just don't. But
Speaker 6:  I think Apple, like everyone else is going to have to convince
Speaker 6:  investors that it has a chat bot play
Speaker 6:  in order to survive. Not survive, but you know what I mean,
Speaker 6:  it's Wall Street wants to see that you have some big newfangled
Speaker 6:  idea and so they're gonna do it because they feel like they have to, all
Speaker 6:  the interesting AI stuff is going to be the like, on
Speaker 6:  device stuff. And that's the thing that we're already seeing Apple do well
Speaker 6:  just by putting AI features into apps, you're gonna see a lot of it with
Speaker 6:  photos. There's a lot of noise around AI generated
Speaker 6:  emoji. That's the kinda thing you don't really need open AI for that actually
Speaker 6:  Apple has been working on for a long time. The the only reason I
Speaker 6:  can see that you would strike a deal like this with open AI is if you wanna
Speaker 6:  blow out the like, conversational aspect of things
Speaker 5:  Just lies so much in the face of Apple's security stuff.
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But so does the Google deal. Like, so, so
Speaker 5:  It's fine. That's true, that's true. But the Google deal, like we didn't
Speaker 5:  know the terms of the Google deal for years. Right. And whereas this was
Speaker 5:  a fairly public deal with AI really
Speaker 6:  Close. I mean, it's just been better reported on because Open AI is the luckiest
Speaker 6:  company in the history of the world.
Speaker 5:  Just like, just holes everywhere. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  By the way, it's only the M two Ultra only M two. This was driving me crazy.
Speaker 3:  I kept saying M three Ultra, they only 'cause they're on the M four now,
Speaker 3:  so I just assumed. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They just got a lot of M two Ultras,
Speaker 3:  M two Ultras where they stopped with the,
Speaker 5:  They're like, is this as good as an H 100 Open ai?
Speaker 5:  Tell us.
Speaker 3:  I think Apple knows that the idea of the behind is an external perception
Speaker 3:  of the company and they're watching,
Speaker 3:  they're watching companies kinda light their brands on fire
Speaker 3:  and not, they're just never gonna do that. I think they're
Speaker 3:  cautious to the extreme in that way. Maybe. And I think this, I think this
Speaker 3:  crush ad disaster for them, which was not even about
Speaker 3:  ai, it was an iPad ad Yeah. That everyone
Speaker 3:  decided was about ai.
Speaker 3:  I think they saw that and they were like, no, like we are, we're gonna do
Speaker 3:  some stuff in photos and some stuff in emojis and well, there
Speaker 5:  There's gonna be stuff in search, so
Speaker 3:  I'm sure Yeah. There's gonna be like some like light dusting remember last
Speaker 3:  year where they were like, the keyboard has AI in it now and it's like, this
Speaker 3:  keyboard is dumb. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 3:  Real bad. It's like still pretty bad. They're gonna do that kind of thing.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And I think it might be everywhere they might announce more features,
Speaker 3:  but that last turn where it's like, do you want to bang an
Speaker 3:  iPad? Like I don't, I don't know if we're gonna get there this time.
Speaker 3:  I I think they're very comfortable with the perception that they're quote
Speaker 3:  behind because they're, I I think they're watching Google. I think they're
Speaker 3:  watching the reaction to their own advertising and saying this stuff is not
Speaker 3:  ready and the culture around it is too negative. That is just my sense
Speaker 3:  from, you know, just talking to folks. But I don't, I don't know if I don't
Speaker 3:  know what they're actually gonna answer.
Speaker 6:  I look forward to we're gonna be there live. Yeah. And we're,
Speaker 6:  we're doing a podcast in Cupertino and I am going
Speaker 6:  to spend a lot of time gloating on that show about how right I was. And I'm
Speaker 6:  really looking forward to it.
Speaker 5:  I I really hope David's wrong, just so I can gloat.
Speaker 5:  I just, that's it. But I hope you're right for you spiritually, David,
Speaker 6:  I just, I think if you're worried about the stock
Speaker 6:  price of your company and I know that they are, you look at it what is
Speaker 6:  happening at Microsoft and you say, oh, we need
Speaker 6:  something like that. And what they'll say is they'll make a lot of noise
Speaker 6:  about like all the stuff you can do inside of apps and then it will come
Speaker 6:  around too. And also it wants to be your best friend.
Speaker 6:  Let's hang out.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Also, Sirius Hornet. Now Tim Cook will be like, woo.
Speaker 3:  Can you imagine? Just imagine Tim Cook being like
Speaker 3:  in Siri warning now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Just flirty with Siri. I. love
Speaker 3:  It. Looks Kevin a ru Dead in the eyes. This you all right, we gotta, this
Speaker 3:  is the lightning round has ended up in strange places, but it's
Speaker 3:  been a good one. We'll be right back. We have yet another Unsponsored Lightning
Speaker 3:  round.
Speaker 3:  your call.
Speaker 3:  Mega Bass, ultimate Sound or whatever. Power Vibes, whatever. It's
Speaker 3:  Power vibes. ULT. All right. Kranz, you got I I I ran you
Speaker 3:  over in the last one. You get the first one? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So it's, it's gonna be a gadget and that Fitbit
Speaker 5:  has a new watch for kids.
Speaker 3:  The
Speaker 5:  Ace. The Ace, the Ace LTE. And is it a way for
Speaker 5:  you to track your children with GPS? Yes. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Do you feel uncomfortable about that? I don't know. I'm not you if you do,
Speaker 5:  this probably is not an exciting gadget for you. But
Speaker 5:  it seems really cool because it like gamifies fitness in what appears
Speaker 5:  to be a really nice way Victoria Song went and got to check it out. I've
Speaker 5:  heard from some other people who have gotten to check it out and everybody's
Speaker 5:  just like, no, this thing rules and I kind of want one for myself. Yes. And
Speaker 5:  like, that's the hallmark of a good ass gadget for kids. Yeah. Like
Speaker 5:  you, you can take the, the band and replace the band and there's like a little
Speaker 5:  tamagotchi kind of thing in the watch. And so when you replace the band,
Speaker 5:  it'll like change it'ss a appearance and stuff. It's,
Speaker 5:  it's sick. Like all,
Speaker 6:  All adult fitness trackers are like, let's talk about your VO two max and
Speaker 6:  this one's just like, make the cool little guy go and like, that's how you
Speaker 6:  get me to do stuff. Come on.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Like this, this thing just kind of rules
Speaker 5:  except for it's too expensive though. It is way too expensive. It is $229
Speaker 5:  and 95 cents.
Speaker 5:  And it's
Speaker 6:  Also called the Ace LTE, which is like the least cool
Speaker 6:  kid name I've ever heard.
Speaker 5:  It's real bad. And also you need a data plan to,
Speaker 5:  to get the full richness of it called the Ace Pass.
Speaker 5:  Oh boy. And it is not cheap. It is like
Speaker 5:  $10 a month. Ooh,
Speaker 3:  That's
Speaker 5:  Tough. So you,
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna stick with just putting an air tag.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Just somewhere in my phone. You can, you can alternatively stick an
Speaker 5:  air tag in your child and give them a 20-year-old Tamagotchi. There you go.
Speaker 5:  And done. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  We are not yet, we have not yet hit the, let's put an air tag on her. What
Speaker 3:  if
Speaker 5:  You glue the air tag to the ka tamagotchi. I see. That's the or 3D
Speaker 5:  print some sort of case. I bet Sean could do that for you. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  No, there's a, there's infinite. This is the, the entire Etsy economy is
Speaker 3:  weird. AI generated crap and then 3D printed stuff.
Speaker 5:  It's beautiful.
Speaker 6:  That's real. And please you can put your air tag on anything. There is a
Speaker 6:  case for it. If you wanna attach your air tag to a thing, you can find
Speaker 6:  a case for it on Etsy. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  All right. David, what's yours?
Speaker 6:  I just wanna talk about this like slightly weird Discord blog post
Speaker 6:  this week. The company basically announced
Speaker 6:  its pivoting back to video games.
Speaker 5:  I didn't know it left.
Speaker 6:  So this is the thing. So in 2020 when Discord was
Speaker 6:  like really feeling itself and there was noise that Discord was gonna be
Speaker 6:  acquired for I think like $10 billion. It was, it was the, the work
Speaker 6:  from home moment. The world was weird. We try not to talk about that period
Speaker 6:  of 2020. Very often Discord like announced that it
Speaker 6:  was going to be more than just a gaming thing, right? It wanted to be a,
Speaker 6:  a community app for the future of the world. And
Speaker 6:  Discord actually has like gotten a lot of things about building a community
Speaker 6:  app, really. Right. There are a lot of things about it that are very clever.
Speaker 6:  I don't think that worked except that people started planning like crypto
Speaker 6:  and crimes in Discord
Speaker 5:  More. Yeah. It turns out there's a lot of like shitty communities out there.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And not a lot of like Fortune 500 companies running on Discord. So
Speaker 6:  anyway, so the company pivoted back and is now about gaming again, but then
Speaker 6:  made a bunch of small changes that don't really change anything. And then
Speaker 6:  said they want to be easier for connecting either
Speaker 6:  before, during, or after playing a game. And I would just point out that's
Speaker 6:  all the time. That's still just everything. So I think
Speaker 6:  I'm just in a strange place where it was like, I forget who it was, but somebody
Speaker 6:  in our Slack was saying like, this is not a message to users. This is a message
Speaker 6:  to investors of like, we get it, it's fine. We're we're running away from
Speaker 6:  crypto. Please stop doing crimes in Discord. And, but
Speaker 6:  I just thought it was very funny. It's like Discord is like, we will remain
Speaker 6:  Discord. Just like, please only only do games here. Please. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I did learn new things from that blog post. I didn't know you could have
Speaker 5:  Discord on like the PS five.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Just clearly I don't use that
Speaker 3:  Feature. It's a app. Like ultimately you can deploy web app anywhere. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But like, like sometimes you're like, what if I deployed this on the PS five?
Speaker 3:  And you're like, w why?
Speaker 5:  It's 'cause it's got a sick process.
Speaker 3:  Looks cool.
Speaker 6:  I mean, discords a really good chat app. Part of me wishes it's great. They
Speaker 6:  had gone more mainstream and instead of like the
Speaker 6:  50 WhatsApp group chats I'm in, I was in a bunch of discords. Like, I feel
Speaker 6:  like I'd feel cooler, but alas,
Speaker 5:  No, I'm in a couple of, a bunch of discords.
Speaker 3:  You're not, you're fine enough crimes, you're fine.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 6:  Don't do enough crimes. Youre no crimes. I don't do enough know NFTs or crimes.
Speaker 5:  Oh no.
Speaker 3:  Alex, I'm guessing you're in at least one PL related Discord.
Speaker 5:  I, I am, I'm not,
Speaker 5:  but, but I did think of the, just putting that out. Some crimes have definitely
Speaker 5:  happened in some Discord
Speaker 3:  I've seen by the way, Jason was on a decoder a while ago,
Speaker 3:  basically previewing all us if you wanna listen, talk about it. I was, I
Speaker 3:  had spent a lot of time being like, crimes happen here. And he is like, I
Speaker 3:  need it to stop. Like more or less. And he
Speaker 3:  said to me a really interesting stat. He is like, most discords are like
Speaker 3:  three people. It's just like three or four friends hanging out in a Discord.
Speaker 3:  And that's like the vast majority of Discord activity. And
Speaker 3:  then the big ones are like for other stuff, right? But we talked about why
Speaker 3:  they make games and their app platform and all this stuff. And he is like,
Speaker 3:  we just do that to dog food, like features for the big games.
Speaker 3:  All right, I'm gonna pick one. I wanted to pick, I fix it.
Speaker 3:  And Samsung breaking up and other repair companies are starting to say they
Speaker 3:  can't fix Samsung stuff either. That's boring. What I want to pick
Speaker 3:  is X the platform formerly known as Twitter now hiding likes.
Speaker 6:  Wait, what? I missed this.
Speaker 3:  It's very good. So they're not hiding likes. They're hiding who likes something?
Speaker 3:  So, you know, people used to go on Twitter and like likes something you can
Speaker 3:  see all their public likes. They're hiding that. They're hiding replies.
Speaker 3:  They're doing this because bros keep liking porn.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That's not, that's all the funniest stuff on
Speaker 5:  Twitter. That was the best like when Tim, Ted, Tim Cruise. Ted
Speaker 5:  Cruz, yeah. Like was like, I love this. It's
Speaker 3:  Very good. Yeah, you do. It is the funniest sign of a platform in decline
Speaker 3:  that it's user base is now so stupid. They don't
Speaker 3:  even have fake accounts to like porn. No,
Speaker 5:  I was hearing about there's, there's some, apparently some, some male reporters
Speaker 5:  who love to, to like models on the Instagram and they don't know that they
Speaker 5:  get the little, the emoji also is shared on threads.
Speaker 5:  So that's pretty good. Be be thoughtful if you're gonna be horny. Don't
Speaker 5:  be horny on Maine. Look,
Speaker 3:  How do you increase Android phone sales by a burner phone
Speaker 3:  to do horny stuff? All right. Are you listening to me? Google?
Speaker 3:  That's what the pixel is for horny stuff.
Speaker 6:  It's pretty good. Actually
Speaker 3:  Buy a burner pixel
Speaker 5:  Just for the horny stuff.
Speaker 3:  A refurb pixel five with that beautiful red case.
Speaker 3:  It's, it's available to you. It's just an idea. Have to increase your sales,
Speaker 3:  save your company
Speaker 3:  Twitter X is saying you soon you'll be able to like, without worrying
Speaker 3:  who might see it. We want to encourage people to like more edgy content.
Speaker 3:  They use the word edgy. Wow.
Speaker 5:  We want you to like your porn more often.
Speaker 3:  I'm if you are the sort of person who describes your own work as edgy,
Speaker 3:  not edgy, like, I don't know. It's like, it's like Sam Altman is the bad
Speaker 3:  boy of it's like he can't be, but he would love it. He would like it
Speaker 3:  so much that he'll never get it. Yeah. Elon wants Twitter to be edgy so much
Speaker 3:  he'll never have it.
Speaker 3:  I just think this is truly one of the funniest changes any social platform
Speaker 3:  has ever made. There's like other reasons, right? Like I'm, I'm confident
Speaker 3:  Elon wants the weird racist who now populate Twitter to be able to like
Speaker 3:  weird racist posts without seeing it like, yep. Yeah. There's there's a
Speaker 3:  deep dark.
Speaker 5:  Will you be able to
Speaker 3:  Like weirdness there,
Speaker 5:  Go into the likes and look at the likes still?
Speaker 3:  No other people can't see them at
Speaker 5:  All.
Speaker 3:  Right? Like you yourself will be able to see who liked your posts. Okay.
Speaker 3:  You can see the like counts for posts like public like counts man. But you'll
Speaker 3:  not see who likes someone else's post and you will not see others. You'll
Speaker 3:  not see what other people like.
Speaker 5:  I cannot wait for one of those creators of edgy content to
Speaker 5:  get fed up with their edgy followers and just put 'em all
Speaker 3:  On the, the saddest little black book in the world. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The saddest little black book. It'll be so good.
Speaker 3:  It's, I mean it's truly deeply, wonderfully hilarious. I love it. The platform
Speaker 3:  and decline just doing the weirdest stuff you can add.
Speaker 6:  I just really like the idea of ultimately doing
Speaker 6:  good healthy things by removing engagement metrics in
Speaker 6:  the service of making your platform easier to be sketchy on. Like
Speaker 6:  I think that's great. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I Twitter is gonna end up, X is gonna end up I think
Speaker 3:  as a porn platform. Like I think they will find a way to
Speaker 3:  subsume only fans because it's the last thing left for them to do.
Speaker 6:  It's video first now supposedly.
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah. Linda has, she appeared. She had not appeared anyway
Speaker 3:  anywhere since the code conference from what I understand, which went great
Speaker 3:  for her.
Speaker 5:  Can you repeat the question?
Speaker 3:  And she appeared and said X is now a video first platform for creators
Speaker 3:  and everyone went, what? You don't make any videos.
Speaker 3:  Elon Musk never makes a video on his video first
Speaker 5:  Platform. But if you wanna make corny videos, you can
Speaker 3:  And secretly like them. Yep.
Speaker 5:  Ted Cruz is just gonna be ecstatic.
Speaker 3:  All right. I'm just saying. And we are in a new era of the internet, right?
Speaker 3:  I dunno what's gonna happen to the web, but I know this is the ULT Power
Speaker 3:  Sound era, and I'm convinced this is the horny
Speaker 3:  burner Android phoner for when you're
Speaker 6:  Urged to like, something is irresistible, but you don't want anyone to
Speaker 3:  Know this. The Pixel six A be
Speaker 5:  Like, I just gotta hit that heart.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, you want them to know, but you don't want anyone else to know.
Speaker 3:  That's actually a great, like opposite of what happens on iPhone stays
Speaker 3:  on iPhone messaging for Google when you want them to know. But no
Speaker 3:  one else to know the Google picks Android.
Speaker 5:  You're just doing Google's job today. It's
Speaker 3:  Pretty good. I'm trying, man. I'm trying to help everybody. All right.
Speaker 3:  It's someone give us some money somehow.
Speaker 3:  Well, lightning Round's available for horny pixel sponsorship.
Speaker 3:  All right. That's it. We're way over time. I appreciate you all. We do want
Speaker 3:  your feedback. I I'm very sincere about this. I know people have a lot of
Speaker 3:  feelings. We are here to earn your trust in whatever way that this previous
Speaker 3:  segment earned your trust. Send us a note. You can reach out to us. You can
Speaker 3:  call David at some phone number. Eight six six
Speaker 6:  VERGE one, one. Call the hotline.
Speaker 3:  See it. Call us. We'll, we'll answer your questions. We're again, we are,
Speaker 3:  we are not trying to hide the ball here at all, but we are trying to go home
Speaker 3:  to our families. So that's it. That's ver chest rock and roll.
Speaker 8:  And that's it for The Verge Cast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 8:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one. One. The Vergecast is the
Speaker 8:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 8:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.
Speaker 3:  All right. Alex just made a huge discovery on the ULT seven or
Speaker 3:  whatever this is called. Tell us what the ports are.
Speaker 5:  Okay, we got, we got a light button. We got, we got a
Speaker 5:  battery button with a minus sign for battery care.
Speaker 3:  Okay.
Speaker 5:  Key control. I don't, I don't know music.
Speaker 3:  That's for karaoke.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Echo guitar. We got a
Speaker 5:  guitar input, right?
Speaker 3:  This thing rules this. I don't know what, I don't know.
Speaker 5:  There's a lot going on down there.
Speaker 3:  There. These are all fully karaoke controls and then you can play a guitar
Speaker 3:  through it.
Speaker 5:  I sure.
Speaker 3:  I dunno what Battery minus care does.
Speaker 5:  I really wanna know, but probably not Today on The. Verge cast
Speaker 3:  2, 3, 4, 5.
Speaker 3:  Boy, can I, there we go. There we go.
Speaker 5:  It's got some pneuma energy, right? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It always starts in the middle, which I really like.
Speaker 3:  I love you.
Speaker 3:  This thing fills me with pure joy. You're so happy. Like every other tech
Speaker 3:  company is like, we gotta do some AI stuff that the robots are
Speaker 3:  gonna bang you. Like
Speaker 3:  Let's just threaten everyone. Ooh. And